this episode of gabbing with Gabby is
brought to you by the Breeders direct
Seed Company in my opinion the Breeders
direct seed company is your Premier
Source for clones and seeds and they are
the only place that you can get the
Gabby Staten Island collection so visit
breeders direct for all your seed and
clone needs
[Music]
what's up everybody this is Gabby Staten
Island and we've got Nick wolf and the
Slovenian Hobbit here we also have our
special guest Kevin Geor JRE today and
so today we're excited to talk with
Kevin and have him tell us his stories
and how he began in cannabis and
Kevin has a very long history in
cannabis um from hustling in the drug
war um working in the Bay Area in
Oakland and Humbolt he's run
dispensaries nurseries and many grow
operations he was I think you you made
the ganier program found and yeah he
founded it um he's won golden tarp
Awards and he excuse me I invented the
golden tarp oh you invented the golden
tarp invented the golden tarp yeah and
then he's been doing International um
Consulting and business development in
cannabis for many many years so again
we're very excited to have you on the
show Kevin um one thing I want to say
before we started is
that I had heard your name before I knew
about Wonderland
Nursery but I didn't really know that
much about you and I saw some clips over
on the first smoke of the day and
honestly I was just blown away Way by
those clips and I I friend requested you
on Instagram and I guess you followed
back and you know I asked you if you
wanted to do the show and I was so
excited when you said that you did so I
have not watched the rest of the first
smoke of the day because I always like
it to be as much of a surprise when I
record my podcast but I am going to
encourage everyone at some point to go
check out the first smoke of the day and
the interview that Kevin did with them
so anyway Kevin we're just going to give
you the mic and tell us your
story um you know we were just talking
be like before we get into the story
story we were talking about this really
cool event that I went to this weekend
that was called the high tea and it was
put on by Nick founder of essential
extracts and they had it over at the
ganier campus in southern humble and it
was the second year they did it and it
was so interesting because I I like tea
but I'm not hyper knowledgeable about
about it and they have a group come in
I'm trying to remember their name but
they're uh Americans but they've spent a
lot of time in China as tea importers
exporters and so their knowledge of tea
was really comprehensive and they bring
all these really interesting varieties
of tea and what they do is they get
together with Nick's team which is Alex
Shera Tyler and Lindsay who uh prepare
the food and then um this G named Sarah
Jane does the the tasting bar and then
Lena Burns does the hookah bar and so
Lena's a uh she was uh one of there two
like true Frenchie apprentices that
turned Master that's Belle out of um
Mendo and Lena out of humble and both of
them were Frenchie's um full-time you
know developed worker and then became
masters of their own so like her
knowledge of hash is unbelievable and
her ability to create good hash Sarah's
and her fella fantastic
at um flavor uh component and then Alex
and his team are phenomenal in Chef so
what they do is they take a look at the
tea and then they match the food
pairings and the hash pairings with it
so it's these crazy flavor Centric
profiles and it's over the course of
like you know eight hours so every hour
another flight of hash comes out another
flight of food and another type of tea
and so and you can you can smoke what
was previous but you keep getting these
fresh
experiences and it's held up like set up
in at the ganier campus in soam and so
Derek's spot is I think like 240 acres
on top of a
mountain and so when you're up there man
you basically just swept Into the
Wilderness of Humble County and you're
drinking all this aged tea and you're
smoking all this hash and you're eating
all this food and
you're you're you're kind of like sucked
into a Vortex of of gustatory
goodness and when you leave you're kind
of sad that it had to end because wish
you could spend every day just drinking
really good tea and smoking really good
hash and eatting really good food in in
an environment filled with people that
were you know vibing the same so if they
ever do another one man or if if you
ever get a chance to go to one of those
type of pairings you know I'd recommend
it it's just an absolute I was going to
ask is fascinating experience was it
open to the public or was it by
invitation only it was invitation you
you you paid to get into
it but the the concept doesn't have to
be you could create one of your own
where you you know you one of your
friends is is good at the The Culinary
one of your friends is good at the the
hash collection meaning like assembling
the hash to match the food and then you
get somebody who's really knowledgeable
about the Tea end of it and
it's just really fun because the the
thing with the tea was it's such an
ancient
culture and when I was in Asia what I
noticed was the Tea Ceremony matches the
presser ceremony matches the hash
consumption ceremony and so there's
these periods through the day where you
pray you you take tea and you smoke and
we kind of we kind of and it's it's
ritualistic but ritualis in a in a
really healthy way so I think that you
know the ability for people to be able
to sit down and enjoy these things in
this regard because for at least 15
minutes you know you stop what you're
doing you give thanks you drink tea
which clears your head um kind of opens
you up and then the Cannabis makes you
connect into the the
universe that sounds incred favorite
combination oh my God you're talking
about something that is happening here
in my area with a family member of mine
you know he has a he has one of the
oldest Buu Gardens in Slovenia you know
uh he's a professor of Art and he has a
SAA in the B garden and he's doing Tea
Ceremony since uh two years now like tea
ritual like we say and uh you know
everything you tell now is like home you
know to me like we are
I'm the European correspondent here
so first of all it's really big honor
for me to talk to you I mean I've been
listening to it's my pleasure man we
we're all C
like I got lucky then I spent the
majority of my career hiding right so
the majority of your career when you're
in the hustle is you know you making
sure nobody knows who you are except
everybody you hustle with so you develop
a really good strong like name
reputation but I was never really on
forums I didn't I I I use social media
kind of on a minimal level if you really
take a look at my output it's low what
what's high is my engagement and me
being involved with other people's work
in that regard because it it makes it
fun but if if I have to do it myself it
feels
forced and because I and and it's
nothing it's not against people who live
online if just purely if you're living
in cannabis with licensed Opera even in
the past like large operations you're
running a large operation you don't have
time to be online all day
so it it just never fit my life and then
when I get older because I'm older the
online lifestyle wasn't so critical it's
just a really great tool to meet people
and I I use it in kind of like a duality
where I'm a a sports freak and I don't
mean like I like watching sports I like
I like sports science and I like being
athletic and so the internet lets me
keep track of all these people around
the world that I got to train with and
got to work with so I get like all my
sports related connections and then I
get um hobby stuff and then I get
cannabis so it lets me have like a
really diverse Global friend
base but I I just kind of look at it
like that so I don't I don't get so
triggered so online stuff doesn't like
you know like it to me it's it's not
real if if for most people if they shut
down their Instagram their whole game
ends that day and it doesn't end my game
at all because I have functional
physical businesses and operations and
I'm I actually work in the industry
globally so for me the enjoying the
conversation is what I dig and that's
why you know as I took a look when you
guys first popped up and then I saw the
interview you did with Mark and then I
saw there was wolf on the other day and
and and I love wolf he it [ __ ] genius
and he's just an interesting Dude too
because he's such a salty
bastard and and he has to be because he
is he's salty as hell but I love him
because I respect what he did was he
really really really did his homework
and he did create that initial what we
would call Sea a green where ultra high
density planting sites and he developed
cultivars that fit that that that
methodology and then his knowledge of
lighting is is is primo so like I got
lucky that when it comes to lighting I
was able to spend time with brilliant
light scientists from around the world
on
projects so it it allows me to get
access to information I otherwise
wouldn't but for the average individual
that isn't hanging out with light
scientists from the Bill Gates
Institute um wolf is probably the most
accessible smart person you can get and
and he's not afraid to really break the
information down because he's not afraid
to you taking it and suddenly surpassing
him you'd have to spend your whole life
studying it in order to catch him and
it's not like he's paused either so I
that's what I love about you know good
guest so when I saw the good guest and I
was checking it out and I think I said
you Gabby like oh you know good show and
then that's kind of began our
conversation
and I just think that you know the
intent of what you're trying to do is
good and for me being able to be on
podcast with people that want to explore
the world wein is critical and it's and
like I said it's it's not that I think
there's a rank in cannabis it's it's
just that most spend their time in their
house so your your totality of what you
see is relatively small it doesn't mean
your product isn't phenomenal it could
be the best in the world coming out of
your one lighter in your bedroom and
that's real it's just really about
exposure
to a totality a bigger picture and I
think that that's kind of what I got
lucky to have is that my
career was built during like the peak of
the drug war and when I got into medical
cannabis I was already around 40 years
old by that point so I already had you
know since I was what 12 so I already
had you almost 28 years of playing in
the sandbox before I got into medical
cannabis and medical cannabis to me is
not that I had a 215 which is the
medical recommendation in California I
had that in
96 because I knew Dr mcara we were
friends so I grabbed the
215 but it was to protect me from having
like an ounce in my pocket I knew it
wasn't going to protect me on the level
I was at because my plant counts were
insane so
it wasn't it was a little different
reason and so I never considered myself
medical I just had a 215 I knew the
architects of that era we were friends I
had
access it was when I got into running a
dispensary that I officially said I'm in
medical cannabis because the emphasis of
your work
changes and you get into the dispensary
end of it and you think you're going to
be doing like storefront sales and you
don't really understand that you're
becoming a a semih hospice
and you start to see this reality of
people who use cannabis in this
essential method essential need and it
changes your perspective of what you
do and because I was already what I
would say successful I didn't get into
medical cannabis because that was my
time to come up I was already up I
actually lost money going into medical
cannabis because I had to give up all
the Crooked hustling I was doing which
was really where the money was but I I
knew there was like this two-part reason
there was one that it was the only path
forward because I knew that the world we
were in was going to
change and once I get involved in the
medical end of it it was it was this
catharsis of um helping people that you
don't know that have no ability to help
you back it kind of links you into The
Human Experience in a way I'd never been
linked in and it it made my life really
kind of
like rich in a in a way I never
experienced I wanted to say you know you
have this kind of uh thing that you live
in your your life a way of life and then
because of the system you see the way
and you choose the way to do it in
another way like from from your
perspective from my perspective and your
perspective would be the term from
illegality to legality how to make it
legal now you know and and you are you
know of course from From perspective
Europeans now we are just legal not
legalizing decriminalizing now the
system that you have now is like you
already have 10 years of legalization
behind you we don't tot it's different
perspective yeah it it is it is and I
knew that I knew that it's like
everything you do in life right you you
can't take skills from one it's called
extrapolating where you take something
from something and apply it to something
else and the problem is that there's
these assumptions that the skills or the
information transfers lineally and it it
it's not linear it it's big gaping holes
of lack of understanding and so when I
got that opportunity to take over that
operation and it was it was neat too
because the operation I took over was
one of the second or third dispensaries
in the state of California it was one of
the oldest operations in the country and
it was failing the management was
confused and it had a great team the
people that I like ended up you know
running were good people they were about
the job they were good with people but
your management was off and they didn't
understand really at at a bad
fundamental level they didn't understand
drug dealing they didn't quite
understand like what the needs of the
people who come in the store
are and how these little things we do
make that experience so much different
and so when I came in I took over the
spot as the cultivation director but I
really kind of ended up becoming like
cultivation director SL operational
manager and I changed the way we
operated the business and so I took a
business that was going bankrupt and
failing and the first two years I ran it
we won best dispensary in Northern
California two you know for two years in
a row and I always tell people that I
said listen I have never had a day of
retail experience in my life never
worked in a restaurant never worked in a
store never I don't have I spent my
[ __ ] life in the do
game what people need to understand is
that we we do understand people pretty
well on terms of how they want to be
treated and if you understand how people
want to be treated you can do your best
to satisfy you're never going to do
perfect all the time you're going to
fail and you're going to make mistakes
but if you put the effort out people
forgive you for your
failures because they see that there's
an effort that is
genuine and what happens is they learn
to kind of meet you in the middle and
then they teach you how to help them
better and so I allowed the people that
came in the business to kind of guide me
as to what they wanted and needed and it
allowed me to better understand and I
think like you know one of the jokes was
that I took my office I took my desk out
of my office and I put it in the
lobby so I had an empty desk in the
lobby that I sat at to do all the you
know
conversation and what it did is it
allowed anybody who came in the business
to access somebody
that when you talk to people at a
counter you you don't feel powerful
because you feel there's a filter but if
you can talk to the manager and you can
get access to them and the same
information from the manager's mouth is
coming out of the workers mouth
it validates the worker so now when
people come in they start to understand
that the people that are at the counter
are intelligent too so like that's the
sin of like when I came into the
business nobody wanted to talk to me at
first right so I laughed so I had my
secretary go to the store go to Staples
right the office by said go get me a
badge here write this and it said
cultivation director in my name right
and I put it on I said watch this [ __ ]
people look at you then they look at
your badge and it says cultivation
director instant you're smart so I said
every said we all need badges that just
say bad [ __ ] on them anybody
looks at this thing automatically thinks
you're you're elevated and now the
conversation is different because the
issue with cannabis is that because
people spent so much time in seclusion
semi seclusion working with it
developing it they've developed some
unbelievably strong relationship
ties but their overall knowledge of the
picture in many cases most is kind of
skewed and so when they come into stores
they always want to tell everybody I
know more than you because you're just a
worker in a store and I'm this person
who knows all this what happens is the
worker and the the customer can't find
common ground to communicate and
neither's left happy the bud tenders
like these jobs suck and the people who
come into stores are always saying the
bud tenders you're stupid and it's not
true it's just
this kind of conflict it's like your
transmission isn't working correctly
because the clutch isn't stopping the
flywheel and you're not able to shift
the synchronizers aren't working so
you're just grinding grinding but when
you can align everything everything
meshes and I I think that's what I was
really trying to do most was create that
meshing and it
relationship yeah and it hadn't been
done because the the world of cannabis
even in storefront was all this you know
secrecy still and what it did is it
created a lack of information
transmittal so you you weren't creating
information in the facility and getting
it into the hands of the public and so
what I did is I kind of ripped the doors
off the place and let the people come in
and then I left the place and brought
the information into the public and it
wasn't about information about the shop
it was just really how do you look at a
topic and and I don't think I'm
omnipotent like it's funny I'm outspoken
on stuff and and sometimes I'm I'm prone
to add a little bit to it where when I
say all I really mean the majority right
and so when I say everybody does this
people like no there's an outlier I'm
like I know but if you can find an
outlier it means most and so I kind of
work on these
generalities but what it does it makes
it simple to make decisions and move
things
quickly and it allowed me to be able to
help people understand these are the
things that are inside dispensaries
these are how we use these products if I
was you on a budget this is how I would
approach it and and I didn't try to send
you to my store I wasn't worrying about
it drugs don't need to be advertised
they they just have to be
presented and I think that's where a lot
of people in retail don't quite catch
dope dealing that you don't really sell
drug drug you just provide them and they
sell themselves and people give you
money as an exchange for this rare item
and if you can get cool about the
process you you have Word of Mouth your
story sounds so similar to
mine and you know this is like a
reoccurring theme that you know we all
you know even Sasha it's like we're so
similar 6,000 miles away yeah but I
opened up my hydro store the garden
spout in
2002 and when I opened up my
store the general practice when you
walked into a grow shop was you said as
little as possible to the people that
worked there you grabbed your [ __ ] and
you got out okay and when you got out
you like looked both ways to make sure
nobody was following you and you used
your cousin's car yeah exactly yeah and
so when I opened up my shop I did
something a little bit different it was
actually very different nobody had done
it at the time um first of all my store
was in downtown Willets you know right
in the center of town and when you were
driving north or south through Willets
you basically had to drive by my store
and I had a th000 watt grow light on a I
think it was called the Omega Garden the
spinning garden with a th000 watt light
in the middle of it and and the it was
on that little cam in the
plants but like people that were driving
by like they were just blown away but
what they were seeing a high press
sodium light in a window at a grow shop
this was this was pretty unheard of at
the time and another thing I did was I
put a coffee bar in my
store so when people came in I gave them
an espresso or whatever they wanted and
they had a place to sit down and I made
it a place where the customers felt
comfortable talking to us totally and
and that was something that had never
happened at a grow store before you were
actually told exactly the opposite is
don't talk to us please don't mention
cannabis specifically Tomatoes we're
growing tomatoes everybody was a [ __ ]
tomato farmer but you have to be bold in
order to break through
dogma
and for me you know I got lucky in that
regard I really believe it that I just I
entered public Canabis at the right time
because I was already grown and I
already had a good reputation in the
hustle which is why the the legal worked
for me so well because once I get in the
legal I was able to reach out to all the
people I had done business with in the
illegal and it instantly allowed us to
start moving plant material at large
quantities and so all of that stuff was
I really believe because I was 40 and I
already you know I already fought a
couple felonies and already I already
had a lifetime of like struggle and
grind and then real money so when I got
into this it was more like an education
of what's the future going to be I just
didn't realize I was going to get this
education on medical cannabis the way I
did and it was this incredible
experience but out of that facility is
where the the plant ACDC came from that
was the first CBD plant development in
the
country and over the next couple years
you know I mean I ended up personally
releasing hundreds and hundred hundreds
of thousands of free CBD based plants
globally so at one point in time I was
like this I was I was like this this
genetics stallion in hemp because all
these countries around the world began
their hemp programs with genetics they
got from us and people couldn't believe
that you know I was giving it away for
free but I I I had this idea that when
we started the
project it was it was it was originally
designed to help the doctor's wife
and he had this idea that if we could
increase the cannabinoid stimulation and
get the ECS activated with with
cannabinoids in acid form we should be
able to see an overall health
increase and once we started to see it
because remember you're running a shop
right so we have uh canopy and we have
customers so now we bring in data
collection and we bring in other people
to work with the patients so we can
really start to find out what's the
cannabinoids doing and what the other
things around you doing and it it just
gave me this Insight that was
unbelievable because no one in history
up to that point had ever had this
happened right so even even the Israelis
who like find these molecular compounds
I talk to them because they do not have
the number of people coming through
their programs we did like we dwarfed
people in in what was taking place and I
was I was just a facilitator I didn't
come up with the idea I didn't do the
breeding I just said to the doctor when
he approached me I said wow this is so
interesting I don't think canabo therapy
could do that much so I was totally
wrong but I believed it could do 10% and
I said if we could just get 10% of
what's coming out of your mouth to
happen it's worth it and it ended up
being 200% 300% greater than what came
out of the mouth so I took this
risk for a a a very limited benefit for
what but but the benefit if 10 people of
100 have a better life it's worth the
risk but it it was this it was the
Forerunner of it and no one knew no one
knew what to do with the plants like
they run the program doctor created for
his wife but no one knew how to monetize
it because nobody wanted pot that didn't
get you high there was no alternative
canono medicine at that time this is the
beginning like [ __ ] day one
[ __ ] and I realized though from the
patients and what was happening because
the people we were working with weren't
cannabis smokers they were people who
were in horrific levels of inflammatory
pain they had internal uh stomach pain
they had they had um pain in the
intestines they had they had rheumatoid
arthritis they had all these issues of
aging and falling
apart they were the ones that we really
came into the program and adopted it
most and so what I saw was this Sudden
Change in validation for people who
consume cannabis Psych Pro actively
because they started to understand that
if I can drive a benefit from something
who am I to say you're wrong with the
way you derive benefit so I knew that if
I drove the genes into the system and I
got people to benefit in a non-
psychoactive manner then the work that I
do which I'm interested in which is what
I do as a farmer as a nursery operator
is psychoactive cannabis it would allow
that to exist so I had an agenda of
benefit but really was a benefit of how
do you get people to reverse their
stance on the drug war right so like I'm
born in 66 that was when Nixon as a as a
um when he was in the Senate puts out
that first note then I'm I'm I'm
teenager in
1980 when Reagan comes in 83 I catch my
first uh multif felony right for
distribution uh cultivation I get
dragged out of high school and spend
[ __ ] the the 11th grade in car erated
I get out of high school and my
neighborhood's a crime Zone and my
family's in organized crime so like I
grew up going to prison to visit
relatives and which wasn't traumatic and
then when I was locked up it wasn't
traumatic either it was normal and the
problem was all my friends were about to
go do life sentences and and I watched
it happen they either got killed or they
killed somebody or they caught you know
M multi multi- deade sentences for
criminal activity RICO Act [ __ ]
and I didn't want it right I was 18 I
was like [ __ ] like is this is this and I
loved weed but I was like if
this this can't be my life like I really
don't want to spend the rest of my life
in goddamn prison and and everyone I
mean I when I get to be 18 we used to
swing by the prison and go visit our
friends through the [ __ ] fence at the
medium security prison because we knew
their yard time and we would roll up in
the car and [ __ ] yelled to each other
through the
fence like it was that normal and so I
go in the military so I could go get an
education in dive Salvage so I figured
you know what I'm going to do I'm going
to go get a job as as a salvage diver
and I'm gonna go work globally on oil
rigs that's how I'm going to get out of
the crime of my neighborhood when I go
in the
military and become a
diver it was the peak of the drug war it
was 1985 right so they start loaning me
out to the DEA and the
doj to go be the diver that they drop
out of helicopters on these [ __ ]
vessels so all of a sudden I'm 19 years
old and I'm looking at hundreds of tons
of weed I'm looking at [ __ ] tons of
cocaine and I'm just like this is crazy
right and I'm dying because I mean it
was so opposite of what I had done but
when I was on one of those drug
raids they raided a a Canadian group
that had never been busted but were
always being looked at so they had like
a 200 foot ship it was sterile but they
were International killers and I'm in
the galley the kitchen and I'm hanging
out in my wet suit and [ __ ] because I I
done I just got done doing the hull
inspection and all the other [ __ ] and
they bring all the crew members into the
galley to hold them while they search
the whole vessel right so there's Ships
coming and there's [ __ ]
helicopters and I'm chilling and the
captain says me
yo um we're all salvage divers too like
we're all divers we start talking diving
and [ __ ] and I grown up around [ __ ]
criminals right so I wasn't tripping on
the fact that these guys were all
criminals and the captain says to me
what did you do before you went in the
military and I looked around and I was
like the same [ __ ] you guys do but at a
smaller level and he was like you know
why did you stop and I said because I
caught a case and I said and my whole
neighborhood's all doing life we call it
life on the installment plan where you
basically you're in prison for two
you're out for three you're in for four
you're out for two you're in for [ __ ]
three you're out for two you're in for
six and so a lot of my partners ended up
doing this just a life of [ __ ]
incarceration and and I just said I I
just didn't want to do it and he was
like herb is the
future he said it's way better he goes
you don't want to be a diver you don't
want to do dive Salvage you don't want
to work for the oil companies they're
they all suck he goes you're a you're a
piece of [ __ ] hamburger to these guys
and what you want is you want to go back
to what you did before and he said just
trust me the world will change and so it
caught me because I was far more
comfortable speaking to him honestly
than I was anybody I worked
with so all the people that you know
you're around in your life if you're if
you're raised in a criminal family where
like you learn not to [ __ ] rat as a
little kid and you're used to seeing
relatives pull [ __ ] robberies and
[ __ ] and you're used to seeing stolen
goods and you're used to having family
members in the newspaper for [ __ ]
shooting people um you're okay with that
but when you go into the normal world
it's really difficult so I I mean I can
function mentally in that world but in
terms of operationally it's so different
because our world is what it was and I
was more comfortable talking to the team
that was being raided than the guys that
they had put me with to do the
raiding and it just it it all clicked so
when I got off of that mission and went
back to Hawaii I bought my first like
plant science books because I started
growing around 80 so 78 I start smoking
the neighborhood's
trafficking I get lucky in this weird
way that my neighborhood was where all
the fishermen would go go out into the
bay and get the weed from all the boats
so ship all the herb was being still
shipped in through vessel right and so I
got to see
quantity that was from Global from
people that had their [ __ ] together so
they'd be able to tell you this is good
and this is not good the good batch
usually comes in around then when it
comes in we'll come by and grab you and
we'll show it to you so I got this crazy
education from these older
criminals about quality drugs you know
and and they knew where the Bales were
coming from and so they would say hey
this is Mexican weed I remember when the
first indoor came out in that early 80s
out of Pennsylvania so in 84 I think was
the first time I saw
indoor and it was gorgeous and I said
whoa that's crazy because everything was
it was a change and so you you had this
background so then I started growing in
like 1980 with my friend Gary but I
didn't have a a green thumb I had a
brown thumb I killed every than I
touched so when I realized that I wanted
to get into cannabis I only really
understood like you grow it or you sell
it I didn't understand the million
things that were going to emerge from it
but I said all right let me go get some
books and I started to study plant
science and the day I got out of the
military in ' 89 I used the government
vehicle in uniform to go to Berkeley
indor Garden to go buy all my grow
lights and spark up an Oakland because I
was ready and I love that place I was
[ __ ] good Victor was was cool as [ __ ]
that was at the time when you had to
have a driver's license to buy
hydroponic equipment because they made
you register all your [ __ ] oh and I I
showed up Victor was still there but I
didn't have to show ID yeah NE I didn't
have to either because it was this weird
thing I walked in the store the first
time because I I just wanted to check it
out and I was in the service then and
they had a major Plumbing Leak water was
[ __ ] spraying out of the the wall and
and because I had all this work on on
shipboard water and and and dewatering
and so I understand [ __ ] water flow
well so I said hey wait a second I said
I think I could just [ __ ] fix this
for you while I'm here until you get a
plumber to come in so I shut it all down
and he was so happy that his store
wasn't get when he got [ __ ] up that he
remembered me and so when I came back he
had them put the lights on his [ __ ]
tab nice so like I paid for it but it
was all under Victor's name so so at
that time I didn't have to worry about
you know the the follow through and then
I spark up in Oakland and my my boy AEL
who uh he's passed but he was like older
brother he hooked me up with some of the
Oakland Hustlers so I had a a Jamaican
partner named Greggy I had another
brother named Ricky and I had this white
chick named Sue and Sue is where all the
ultra high level products were coming
from like out of the mesino area so
through Sue I got to see my first real
Exquisite California
outdoor it was I mean stunning right so
I had a pipeline to that through Ricky
it was it was good quality and gregy
same thing they both had really good
access and I had so had this killer
group that I could [ __ ] with and then I
ended up tying in with this dude named
alandro and I was trying to do business
with him but I was being filtered by
this cat we called jailbird Pat so me
and Ja Pat with buddies but he was
always in and out of the joint and I
said to him I said listen I said you're
you're slowing down my [ __ ]
distribution business so why don't you
just sell me the contact let me just buy
it from you tell me how much this
[ __ ] guy's phone number's worth and
then give it to me and then I'll just go
to the guy direct so me and Pat worked
out a deal on how much the connect was
worth and then I tie into alandro when I
tied into alandro alandro was tied right
into the Mex
Pipeline and so what I started doing
with Al was having the people from
Mexico come in to NorCal and I would
gather what I considered really good
commercial samples and we'd show it to
them so they could understand the
quality level we needed to beat that
product so it allowed us to start
steering what was moving into the bay
and then I was pushing that [ __ ] into
the east coast and we got it to a point
where I could only really I only had to
work like three days a month right so I
could do three days of work in the bay
and then not come home for a month so
for a good like year and a half I was
only home for like little touch points
because I was busy [ __ ] around as a
young dude with money and I I would go
to the Bay hook up with alandro we'd
[ __ ] tear it up in Rage because he
was a a [ __ ] nut and then I had a
warehouse that I rented and that's where
we would go and put all the units CR
everything up get it set [ __ ] ship it
out on Monday and then I'd
go so all that barrier time you know it
it was incredible but so much of it was
really the the and I still I just still
hear those that guys voice in my mind to
this day you need to go
back and I'm grateful because I think I
would have had a really good life doing
what I was doing but I would never have
had the exposure to so many diverse
people see I think that that you can you
can make money doing a lot of [ __ ] but
being in cannabis it touches so many
different
demographics that it allows me to have
this [ __ ]
Network that's just absolutely mind
bended to me that I'm touching people
that are happy with nothing and people
who are worth 20 billion
dollar and they're both cool for example
huge range I saw that you have been in
Afghanistan last year or two like like
Pakistan Pakistan yes that's so
inspirational for me in this time that
somebody from the
KOB uh uh high class people like you are
directly goes to
Pakistan and do does this like
that I mean oh no it was my it was it
was my privilege my brother it was my
privilege because I this the real [ __ ]
you know this is the real [ __ ] because
I've been traveling but now in my time
because I have little kids and I'm a
lone parent and you know in this time I
cannot travel you know I'm I'm stuck to
the the place because I have a library
of Coles in the neighboring country
which is like few meters away you know
but it is a privilege to be with
somebody that is uh down to earth so
much that he can Ste travel and he's
interested in other cultures and other
perspectives and other kind of uh uh how
you look at the columus plant and and
you give back to them as well right
you're not you're not just going there
and stealing their genetics and proping
I'm not Ste I didn't steal
any so I need you know like I rub some I
rub some [ __ ] feathers the wrong way
and and it's just because in life if you
do what you do you will you you can't
worry about being somebody who pleases
every single person with every action
you do or you'll never [ __ ] do
anything right so like anytime you do
anything there's going to be an opinion
on
it but the stuff that was in cannabis
was when I was a kid and I started like
I remember I was in I was I was a
cannabis freak since I was
12 the idea that I had this dream as a
kid that one day I would go to Every
cannabis producer region on Earth and I
would just get to see it I wasn't I
wasn't trying to do anything profound I
just wanted I just wanted to see the
world that built our world and over the
course of my life I kind of did but
Pakistan was you know the Untouchable
because you know I'm American and like
holy [ __ ] we nonstop war and conflict so
when the pakistanis reached out to me
and said you know we'd love to have you
come over and I'm like for what like
what's what is it that you want me to do
and they said we really just want to
expose you to our world and hopefully
when you leave you'll be able to bring
that good memory back with you and let
other people know and their
desire wasn't just cannabis Centric at
all it was that can it which is was
important it was that cannabis was the
vehicle the tool that was going to
create the connection between us because
what they want is they wanted to be able
to show Pakistan as a totality where
when you went to the Village to look at
the weed how did the people treat you
when you had food with the people after
looking at the weed how did the people
treat you while you were looking for the
weed what was the country like and so it
was such a elegant beautiful idea that
the land race genetics team and let's be
friends Pakistan had that once they laid
it out to you know over the phone I was
like I'm down I would love to go and the
irony is that as soon as I'm getting
ready to get on the plane I get all
these texts on my phone and I still got
don't one if I still kept it it opens up
with they're gonna cut off your [ __ ]
head and and I'm laughing because you're
about to get on a plane to go to
Pakistan right and people are say to you
they're gonna cut up your [ __ ] head
and I'm cracking up and I'm like no
they're not gonna cut off my
head and what I don't think people catch
is that because I I go to all these odd
[ __ ] locations over the course of my
career that most would not go to
and it's it's really learning about risk
mitigation like you learn how to weigh
your odds and so if you live in the
hustle and then you do dangerous deadly
[ __ ] for a job you start to kind of
learn like where you feel safe and where
you don't and when you don't feel safe
you're really pretty honest with why and
so you logically Move Yourself to
position assurity where you say I think
the the odds are good I'll come back
with my [ __ ] head attached to my
shoulder but if I didn't feel that
there's no point in going because you're
not there to be a martyr to get your
[ __ ] head locked off on a video so
what I what I knew was the people that I
was speaking with they were really clear
about their agenda and their agenda was
to highlight the beauty of the country
through
cannabis
specifically once we started really talk
they weren't aware that there was this
man in Humble named Douglas fur so Doug
fur is this local back to Lander you
know 1968 gets here one of the original
back to land
groups and they're raiding cannabis in
like late October then because
everything they were growing in
California was what [ __ ] Southeast
Asian Mexican and Colombian the
broadleaf [ __ ] hadn't really come into
Cali until
7880 that's when it really first started
coming in
and the the impetus was if we can get
plants that finish a month earlier than
the raid we'll have our crop out of the
ground so Doug and his buddy connect
with a rug dealer out of Eureka who was
Pakistani and they fly to Islam Abad and
they travel out to the Tia Valley and
they gather the jeans and then he ships
that kilo back in 10 packages or 12
packages and six of them arrived and six
of them didn't make it so half a key 500
grams a pound um of seed makes it to
Doug direct into Humble County and what
he did that was different than anyone
else that had received any Afghani lines
Pakistani lines was he shared the stock
with the
locals and what it did is it kickstarted
the broadleaf revolution in our
area and it lets people harvest on time
and then you get into that mid 80s Zone
and indoor is on fire and it was those
plants that could flower under those
conditions because the equatorial just
don't Thrive commercially in those
situations right so all these things
line up and it also lines up with where
America changed its desire of effect so
like America in the 60s and 70s was
looking to get high and spiritually
uplifted you get into like 1980 when you
get into the Reagan Era and if you take
a look at drug usage and and general
tone you start to see that disparity
between people who made money rising up
in the chart and people who were
typically workers who made good money
dropping in the chart so 1980 in America
is like a critical date because it's the
change of the
society's state of
mind and that's when you started to
notice cocaine and heroin re explode and
cannabis mirrors these other drugs and
so we went from having taii weed
Colombian and Mexican which you get on
import into broadleaf and people didn't
[ __ ] that they weren't getting their
old type of high because the new
consumers coming in felt weight on them
remember the end of the 70s America was
a [ __ ] hole we we we we were in
hyperinflation we had the the Iranian
issue where our Embassy had been seized
we had you know he had debacle in the
Vietnam War so like the public sees
their country negatively and because of
it they see the world negatively and it
starts to change drug usage so what I do
is like to this day I look at what's
taking place in the society around me
and I use that to interpret why are the
things that people consume
popular and it's Critical with drugs
because it mirrors it so clearly and so
it helps me understand Trends are we in
Trend that's Rising is it is it is it
flat or is it declining and it helps me
understand genetic development where is
it worth getting into that direction or
do I think it's going to have a quick
Peak and
so that that time period was so
tumultuous but it let you kind of see
these transitions from the 70s and then
we get into the 80s the drug walk kicks
in the valuation explodes cannabis is
worth a thousand in Humble it goes up in
some cases you know
six and the the money pours in it
changes completely but Doug is a really
nice down toe dude who still lives in a
cabin who still lives off grid who still
makes tea for you in a in a with a
[ __ ] like a propane torch you know
and the idea that I was going to get to
go to Pakistan and walk the ground that
my friend walked just really caught me
so I told the team in Pakistan I said
hey we need to call this like the
footsteps of Doug
fur and they all got caught up in it too
where we
like they could understand what I was
trying to do which was start to connect
the dots so that we could tell the story
so that PE people could see the
relevance and understand that a few
people went to these countries and
brought back the genes that launched $50
billion doll
Empire and
the people that that gave us the seed
stock in all intents and purposes got
[ __ ] because they never made any
longlasting benefit from the
relationship and so what we tried to do
was recreate the footsteps of Doug fur
but instead of just Doug walking the
silk route into Pakistan I wanted the
silk route to extend into the United
States and let the pakistanis walk into
our our lives too so I said hey I think
I have an idea how like we can frame it
and it it went really well and they
brought in a you know team of people
from uh Europe they brought in my buddy
Danny from Green walrus who does you
know does the documentary work and he
came in with John who's a
filmmaker and our other partner who's a
filmmaker as well who now does Major
League Baseball stuff but in film and so
they were able to capture so much like
some of the footage that was
captured it's it's all inspiring and so
what you got to do was look
at not just weed we we traveled for 1300
miles through the kurakura mountains so
you know you're you're we're walking the
silk route you're seeing the roads that
the hominids and the Andals merged on
you're finding all this native cannabis
running wild in the mountains that
humans are not playing with every
village you went to had a crop Kevin
farmer was kind the tell me just how it
how it is to look at the mountains there
you know to see this This
Magnificent you know it's crazy just
explain the feeling you man tell tell
because I was in these places not in
this but Mongolia I was but this is very
similar you know it's just so the
environment has so much
impact live I live in the mountains of
humble right so I'm on I'm in I'm in the
Pacific range
and and I've been to Colorado a bunch
and you know and and and seen that type
of
elevation but Pakistan was the first
time I ever really understood
verticality where we were walking around
at 10,000 feet and when you looked up
there was another 15,000 above you yes
and you look down these canyons and
there was miles of distance to the to
the base and you look up and there's
miles above you
and
it it helped me understand the mountain
culture similar as like all my part A
lot of my good friends and like what I
call family are Polynesian right so
Samoan Hawaiian talaan
Tongan
and that's boat culture those were
ancient Navigators and sailors and they
sailed these massive Outriggers all over
the ocean and just but it's boat culture
and boat culture is you learn to shut
the [ __ ] up and work together or they
throw you off the boat and so it's this
teamwork type environment because you
have to be a team player on a [ __ ]
canoe out in the middle of the
ocean I don't see that in many cultures
because we just don't have the need but
in the kurakura mountains I saw it again
and what I saw was that you had to be
nice to strangers because if you were a
stranger in those places you definitely
needed a way out of the environment
it was so
massive that there there's no photos no
pictures until you see the the the
Hooper Glacier you don't quite catch
what a glacier looks like you don't
realize it's an ice flow coming out of a
mountain and every little Ripple in it
is like 150 feet tall the fins that are
on the top of these things you know
you're talking 10-story building
Ripples and massive moving through these
regions it just made you feel so
insignificant and vulnerable and why
were you at such an elevation that's the
b Pakistan is the rooftop of the world
so once you get off of like you go to
you know the coast what that karach you
go down to the the ocean part they
didn't go that that far we spent our
whole time up in those hindukush
Himalaya kurakura Mountain Range once
you get into those you're at base
elevation 10 grand but there's no
cannabis growing at 10 ,000 ftct sure
there is it is yes
10,000 coming from yeah all this is
coming at 10 the best sheet is coming
from there yeah oh it was incredible and
the native herb was it was crazy looking
because when you get to see Wild
cannabis what you get to see is these
plants that are built for survivability
and what is survivability for cannabis
not too much um biomass which would te
technically rot and so what you have is
you have big giant trikes on small brck
small small flower
sets but just insane Aromas and you
would just see anywhere where there was
water that deposited you'd see this and
in your mind you can see the people
moving across the silk route eating seed
[ __ ] it out seed moving around
animals eating seeds [ __ ] it out
people getting seed to eat and dropping
it and you realize that it was this
massive gene flow through this entire
region and it's humbling it it allows
you to understand that you know that and
everywhere we went I asked every village
like how long have you guys been making
hash how long you've been working in you
know in this your family and they said
well we all got here you know 1500 years
ago 1,00 years ago 2100 years ago and
everyone said the same thing herb was
here when we got here so our families
only know herb and you're talking to
hashme ERS who when you're talking to
them they're telling you the first
memories I have as a child is helping my
dad beat hash in the shack and their dad
had beat hash and their grandfather had
beat hash for [ __ ] 2,000 years so
when they held resin in their hands and
they moved it in their fingers and it
was just so familiar and and it just
helped you understand how much we we
[ __ ] up the entire education of
cannabis because the drug war took all
this information out and removed
it Hey Hey Kevin do you mind uh
describing some of the Tarpin that you
were finding on the living cannabis up
at 10,000 ft like what were some of the
most memorable ones that you that you
experienced there you know what's funny
is like the wild
populations you know you saw a myriad of
Aromas present because it it was it
survival but when you're talking about
like fixed populations and remember now
like so India doesn't do any culling of
male or female so it's total open
population but Pakistan and
Afghanistan they select males so they
leave all the females they select the
males and so what they do is they go
through the males in the field and they
they leave the ones that have the best
characteristics but it's not as a single
planets this one had great Aroma this
one had great survivability this one
right here had great flower set this one
had um you know in in in incredible
braze
so it's they they they don't go after I
was in discussion the other day about
this but it was about like fenal hunting
in the idea that cannabis we feno hunt
and I said they don't do that in a and
people say yes they do fenal hunt a but
most a is in beeding right so if you're
if you're hunting
plants that
are able to reproduce on themself which
is considered a perfect plant you're
finding a plant but it's through seed
production and the genetic movement it
is not just that single organism
cannabis we go through huge populations
to find a plant the problem is that
you're having to go through huge
population to find a plant that means as
a breeder you're not doing a good job
that's poor breeding because you're not
able to neck the traits down so when you
go into like open pop it's everything's
everywhere and and you'll but you'll see
still patterns with clothes pop you see
what the farmers like so Farm chooses
the males they want to work with
and what I noticed from the my journals
was that the Aromas
matched the crops that were grown around
them so when we first come down like
into nger Valley it's when you started
to get like into all the mangoes and
fruits because there was more of apple
and fruit that they were around and then
as we start to go into the areas where
had you know like Walnut and and and
other types of nut tree there was other
profiles and then um the the the potato
other profiles and so when I journaled
the whole thing and then looked at the
picture like what was the big
clusters what you had was you had what
we would call like the traditional
earthy profiles that we we associate
with
broadleaf and then you get into what we
would call fuel here but I also call it
chemical but chemical that was turned up
and I mean like Hairspray that had been
blasted in your face and then lit on
fire smells that were penetrating like
you know an acre away from where you
shook the plant people were like whoa if
the wind move that stuff was coming and
so it was these really interesting sets
and then we noticed that like around a
lot of the the potato was those the Deep
volatile sulfur which is you know septic
tank ratting meat
um Decay really heinous foul Aromas but
what I didn't see in that sounds
delicious it was great it was great but
what I didn't see in the hash was any
fuel profiles and I asked them why and I
said with all this chemical and fuel why
don't I see it in the product they said
because we off gas it we allow the
plants to sit at Harvest we let them sit
out in the cold and I said and that
process is do what he goes it's letting
us get a lot of these other volatiles
off the plant that we don't like as a
consumer and I said why don't you like
that type of effect and he's like it was
hysterical because it was so honest he
said oh we'll get too high and fall off
the mountain and die yes and you you
it's hard to explain this to somebody
but like we were at the hunza Inn which
is this killer spot in hza and me and a
bunch of the Pakistani Brothers went
hiked up the the mountain early in the
morning and we're like struggling to
climb this mountain and all of a sudden
it was time to go to school for the kids
and all these kids come skipping down
the mountain like a bunch of [ __ ]
goats and there's old men carrying
children on their back and I mean like
we're climbing like we're fighting for
our lives and these guys are skipping
down this [ __ ] and if we anybody falling
you die and we're cracking up because
they're so acclimated to it but they
don't like to have reduced awareness
because they just know that you can't
make mistakes in that type of situation
so they said no we gas all that off and
it opens up this and what it was was it
was hash that had you know like
traditional hash that you almost never
see with all these subtle fruit and
floral
influences that's the first time and
I've seen a lot of [ __ ] hash I've
never seen hash when they broke up a a
chunk of it you thought were in a fruit
and a flower
shop and it was because they had off
gassed all these other masking agents
that they don't like as a impact and it
revealed all this other stuff
so it was it was just really it was a
beautiful experience and I I I really
hope that that and that's what we we
tried and we did because they did it
again last year I just couldn't make it
out because I had my farm running so
they were able to get people who saw the
trip believe that it was a healthy safe
experience went back with them on the
journey and they went over to some
different
regions and it's the beginning of it to
where you start being able to bring
value to the people who are trying to
bring value to the farms and the farmers
and it starts to get us in cannabis in
the US to realize for so many of us that
we're not we're not the [ __ ] like the
story we're we're a chapter of the story
we're the ones that have best internet
but we don't we don't own the Cannabis
World in any way shape or form in terms
of like usage or knowledge because
really we're us like Australia are the
last on the [ __ ] list so Eastern
Europe has had [ __ ] herb in it for
six 7,000 years we only only you know
herb comes into the United States you
know through through hemp in the eras
when they had to create hemp's rope but
drug cannabis really kind of comes into
the US in the 19 unds from Mexico and
that begins the American smoking culture
and musicians and that Southern
California feel instantly it gets
demonized by the media so that's when
they start to use marijuana as a
negative word and I always tell people
if you take a look at the paper in
America and it tells you the Mexicans
are going to take your [ __ ] jobs
realize that was the headline in 19
[ __ ] 10 too so in 1910 it said
Mexicans going to steal your jobs then
they they realized that they could get
the blacks caught up in it too you know
and at that time we're talking you know
America's racist like just coming out of
the [ __ ] slave area basically so you
got these slave master mentality running
the country they're like oh we can go
[ __ ] to Mexican and as a benefit we can
[ __ ] the black so they swept the black
up and they use a narrative to go
against the black they sweep the Mexican
go the narrative there they use uh
marijuana as his derogatory term and all
this usage of cannabis had nothing to do
with cannabis it was the fact that the
people that were running the US were
[ __ ] brutal
racists and demonized the substance to
get an agenda and then when you know the
industrial cronies figure out the value
of it and they realize it's a
replaceable product for for
petroleum Hurst who didn't want to lose
the forests right you know so Rand
Randol Hurst is the newspaper magnate so
he has the ability to create anything he
wants in the news he's also the world's
largest Timber holder and so hemp was a
direct threat to H's Timber [ __ ]
production Dupont had just came out with
nylon not that long before and he was
like oh [ __ ] you I'm not losing this
patent and Rockefeller was was
basically Rockefeller is a unique
[ __ ] guy and if you really look at
Rockefeller and the the the the way he
was raised by his dad where his Dad
tried to [ __ ] him over every day him and
all his brothers the dad was trying to
teach him how to be ruthless brutal
businessmen so rockefeller's background
is just [ __ ] brutal and he was the
right guy to be brutalized because he
internalized that brutality and then
exemplified it in his business practices
and when
he gets broken up as a as a monopoly by
the US is when almost every Oil Company
in the United States is formed because
he owned the [ __ ] country I mean [ __ ]
his choke hold on oil was similar to
Hershey's choke cold on chocolate so at
one point in time in the US I think like
95% of all chocolate sold was from
Hershey so when you have a control like
that you know it it also takes a certain
type of individual so rockefeller's just
[ __ ] lunatic to me when you really
look at the way he approached business
and cracks [ __ ] down and he switches
into education the educational system he
switches too same thing it's
anti-cannabis but it's also anti-
expression because what he wanted from
the educational system was [ __ ]
workers to work in the factories so the
US educational system was
developed and I'm not an educational
expert but like mean you could read this
[ __ ] was really developed to get people
from agrarian lifestyle into factories
how do you get people to work in a
factory you got to bring them in a
building you got to let them piss on a
schedule you got to make them hold the
hand you put standardized information in
front of them that's designed to figure
out who's good at running the job who's
good at working on the job and if you
don't fit into that window you're [ __ ]
and cannabis to me was a drug that
allowed people to transcend the
brainwashing and I think that that was
one of the things that you know we
really don't talk about in terms of why
it was so easily demonized by so many
entities is that they realize that not
only does it compete with these products
but herb allows you to see people in a
more human way and so when and it it
does bring races together when you're
all smoking weed they're not Mexican
black Asian and white you're just four
people and and I think that Herb's
ability to create these these internal
Ties That Bind based off of decent
decency is a [ __ ] problem
when you're trying to segregate Nations
so that you can have internal conflict
and now we just use the internet now we
just throw some [ __ ] on the net everyone
loses their [ __ ] minds nervous
breakdowns I mean like fullon nervous
break I I watch this [ __ ] I'm just like
wow you're losing your [ __ ] mind what
are you doing in the rest of your
day I mean so but it's always been done
and herb is this substance that
inherently brings I think really nice
traits out in people and and that's kind
of what I wanted to be able to do like
through that those medical era was to
get people to be able to benefit from
the plant in its totality even though I
barely understood it so I had I just
know that when you have benefit derived
by individuals with very little
reciprocity required meaning that all
they have to do is basically show up and
be decent it allows you to make massive
massive cultural
changes and and I had really no idea of
the totality of cannabis usage in terms
of how it was used historically where I
mean [ __ ] like we knew it was a thing
but like when you go to Pakistan every
single Farm Has a Field that they
harvest for the seed for food and then
the resin for medicine and you're and
the seed is critical they stack [ __ ]
bags of that [ __ ] up because they need
it for the winter
so it's a it's it's a life-saving food
source in their world for two three
th000
years did you try any dishes that were
specifically uh designed around cannabis
seeds no no we we ate cannabis seeds but
they don't they don't have that same we
do we weave all these things like and I
would say you have like bong and stuff
in India but that's just the milk milk
drink of that you're and honey that
you're drinking cannabis in but
otherwise
it was they integrated the smoking with
the tea with the prayer so the the the
the prayer was Heavy where like if
because Pakistan's the the most Muslim
country in the world and so you get to
see people who are very religious
Believers of their faith and and how
they enact it and how they practice it
and the the the prayer is just to stop
and say than thank you and that I'm
insignificant so it's a it's a it's a
moment of humility and then the t is
tranquility and then the Cannabis is is
like uplifting changes your tone and so
you notice through the course of a day
the prayer the the tea and the smoke all
kind of went
together and they they wo it in in this
really seamless
Manner and that was what was so
fascinating was that they had it with
them for so
long that it was normal so like they
didn't smoke flour but I mean there was
nobody we bumped into that didn't have a
[ __ ] ball Ash in their
pocket I mean like it was really
interesting I mean I got to smoke a lot
of [ __ ] good Ash when I showed up
they had half a key for us so they had
500 gram [ __ ] balls and then new me a
p in numi man he had a a a [ __ ] bag
from Tia that was a goat ball right like
goat ball hash they took the testicle
ball sack off of a [ __ ] goat and they
because that's that was the original
Ziploc bag right so humans have been
used whenever you see people drinking
water in the past they were using like a
goat skin that was sealed and and they
would carry it they would drink out of
the goat now we consider that [ __ ] just
impossible well the reality was for
thousands of years you were drinking out
of [ __ ] goat skin so the goat balls
aren't fresh in the bag they've been
going for a while but the bag because of
the way it holds the temperature and it
also has microbial life it interacts
with the hash and it's almost kind of
like a semif ferment and and I've really
I've had people ferment stuff but I've
never been over to like maloi and try to
maloi cob in maloi so I don't know
you've never fermented a goat ball sack
before yeah they doing
something but like you know you're
cracking up and you're like I'm going to
smoke the goat ball hash and it was just
[ __ ] phenomenal right so you know
you're dying because we're showing
pictur this [ __ ] and all the new people
in cannabis are losing their minds
because nobody's wearing rubber gloves
th this isn't sterile and clean how
could these people survive and you're
like well they've been smoking this [ __ ]
for [ __ ] thousands of years I think
if there was a rob' be dead by now
[ __ ] kill it with fire it's crazy
yeah it was it was just really just so
pure and
simple and and and humbling you know and
the the Muslim culture was really
interesting because I've never really
been exposed to
it and the the way they approach
visitors and tourists and
strangers was one
of absolute reverence to the individual
so no matter where I went and so it
wasn't orchestrated because we [ __ ] we
traveled 1300 miles you can't bribe
everybody for 1300 miles so no matter
where we went the locals that would bump
into you were amazed that especially cuz
me cuz I'm [ __ ] white right they they
haven't seen a white person in 20
[ __ ] years like maybe some for some
of these people ever like they wanted to
touch you and see if the [ __ ] was coming
off your arm yeah it was this purity of
like why are you here and I'm like oh
I'm here to visit the country and and
they're like and you're having a good
time I said I'm having a great time and
it almost made them look that they were
going to cry because they wanted to see
the image of their country Change 911
[ __ ] them up when we you know Bin
Laden was in the caves when we went to
war and did all that that that reap that
Havoc it just destroyed the Pakistani
economy and so many people had to leave
the
country to go find survival and success
but they also are Pakistani and so years
later they can look back at their
country and say wait a minute how do we
do something for our native
home and that was how land race Pakistan
and let's be friends Pakistan kind of
came to existence was grown men who were
sharp who are Pakistani by descent who
wanted to be able to do something
positive for their country and their
people and you could tell the purity of
the the desire from the way you were
treated and the way everyone around them
was treated it was just it was a
beautiful beautiful experience it really
was it was it was 10 times greater than
I thought it was going to be and I had
dreamt of walking in Pakistan my whole
life you said that you filmed it um is
is that film is it being produced or is
it already released no I'm not in
control of the film part Danny Danny's
team did all the film work so he
releases Clips but I believe at some
point you know how it is when you do
film it's the
editing that's brutal right when you
when you when
you with the podcast when you gotta edit
down you gotta cut you gotta cut and
clip and break and then and then put it
all together in a form that allows
people to want the the the sit down time
it's it's comprehensive but
Ralph brought they brought drones and
the Drone footage is absolutely all
inspiring like the quality of the
footage that they took it was like Nat
Geo level [ __ ] gorgeous because is a
really really talented filmmaker and
so's John he he's uh read films online
and he just got an award for his um his
uh short he's been doing some like
horror shorts and he's doing good man
he's a talented young guy and so you had
and and Danny Danny's infectious with
his enthusiasm for what he does and so
what you had was you had a really good
like media team capturing it so I know
at some point it'll come out and what
we've tried to do is just basically
anytime they release a clip then we just
all Network up to push it out so people
can get a view of these regions in a way
that you normally can't are there some
of these clips on your Instagram or um
can go to and I would say go to GW smoke
break and then and then there's if you
go over to um what I'll do too is I'll
I'll share you over um a deal you can
send me the link later and I'll add it
to the show one of the guys that we were
with there is a professional
photographer really talented so a lot of
the stuff you see me sharing all the
time that's him sending me footage of
him exploring Pakistan cool and so I
just told the guys I said yeah let's
just create this this window so that
people who want to see something
beautiful Ken and then we did the
collection I gathered up all the stock
for him and it was beautiful we got to
do it as a team right so it was talented
pakistanis Europeans and myself all
looking for outliers out of all these
fields and then I was able to get uh the
a chunk of the collection sent back and
I was able to give it out and provide it
to people and so I brought a bunch of it
to the high te but I I gave it out all
over the place so that people could get
access to things that you normally can't
and you get to experience a world that
doesn't exist today in terms of flavor
profile so it gives you what I always
call like new paint it gives you new
paint to be able to work on things that
are existing and work like and we'll use
like the Oreo clone right so the Oreo
clone is probably one of the best plants
you could ever grow in
every it it just does it grows as well
but it's kind of bland and so it has
incredible agronomic
qualities but it's kind of like purple
punch purple punch is a sexy sexy girl
but she's got no flavor I think purple
punch has no flavor but I think Oreos is
nice I think Oreos is
underappreciated I like Oreos as a light
smoke but if we looked at it as a how
does the market look at it right bigger
picture than just me and you
low on the appreciation people don't
like it so I like a lot of stuff people
don't like though yeah but that's okay
what we do is we use those products that
carry such incredible traits and then we
repaint them so when your house looks
like [ __ ] you don't burn it the [ __ ]
down you just repaint it and I think
that that's the way you approach
genetics is that what we've done now is
we've steered towards agronomics and
coas more than we've steered towards
experience because the vast number of
people who shop shop off of price and
potency so when the metrics of purchase
of price and potency the majority and
and I'd say everybody does it but no
[ __ ] majority
do that changes what fits into the
system and when you're trying to pitch
money to build an operation you got to
let these people know you're gonna get a
100 grams per square you're going to get
it every 62 days or they don't give you
the money so once you commit to
this process you're kind of stuck in it
and what it does it only there's only so
many cultivars that give you 29% in 62
days that the market will take and and
then then the buyer has to be able to
put it on Instagram too or otherwise
it's not [ __ ] real so you take all
these new varieties that have been
steered and pushed and you bring back in
the Vigor you bring back in and outcross
from separate genes genes that are
completely unrelated and you get in my
opinion a degree of like semiosis you
get a a higher level of vigor right so
it's not true F1 because they're not
inbred lines right so your line and this
line isn't inbred but genetically
they're as [ __ ] far apart as you get
and what it does it allows you to start
to see
what the things from Pakistan part to
the things that we have now and when I
use these tools over the last couple
years you know what I get out of it
almost always is a way better um water
usage where the plant only has to water
half as often as it did prior so the the
uptake mechanism changes dramatically I
get an ability to produce at a lower
food load so the plants have been built
on Lower humus levels because really
it's this this calcium rich
Sandy I'd say Sandy LOM but it's like
Sandy Lish clay it's this gritty man the
soil is gritty it's all it's all Glacier
so very little biological matter to give
you nitrogen so
nitrogen nitrogen you get it from animal
deposition when they take the fields and
compost but but where's your where is
all your biological material that's
going to break down and form it you
don't have it so the plants adapt to
that and I also see um better cold
hardiness and I also see um uh profiles
that we just don't
have so the ability to create a profile
that's a chokey sulfur that when you
smoke it that [ __ ] is grabbing you and
shaking you like a dog and you're not
going oh I'm gonna take another one
you're trying to find oxygen in the room
and your nose and your mouth is you're
running that kind of stuff is like old
School experience for when you're a kid
and that's kind of what I get out of the
hybridization using it and so I do pure
preservation where I take and if you're
doing preservation for anything that's
like this you really need like 10,000
plants so I know that these aren't true
preservations they're steered
preservations but at least we're holding
something and we're able now to be able
to connect like the farmers of gazy
Afghanistan people in Oregon the farmers
from from nager Valley Pakistan to the
people in southern humble you know that
this is where this came from and the the
ability for you to use it as a tool is
critical and the only way that you can
really hold things is in
seed right because if you're holding
cologne the idea of holding cologne
forever do that [ __ ] your whole life and
tell me that's how you want to spend
your whole life where you never-endingly
have a [ __ ] house full of plants that
are priceless that must be tended
continuously how many times you gone on
vacation how many times you it it's like
I've been doing my whole life that's
what got me into commercial Nursery work
it's what we got me into cryo banking
it's what the the basis of the Grateful
head is it's this idea that I just
[ __ ] do not want to hold plants at
scale personally and so we can S1 stuff
but you're having the [ __ ] genetic
and and selfing is fine when we're doing
we're steering for production needs
we're trying to create breeding lines
but for preservation you want as much
gene pool as possible and what I learned
from the the pakistanis and the afghanis
which and I also learned that from a
redwood propagator which really changed
my view of preservation was that you you
you have to make selection but you have
to include as much as material as
possible because you don't know where
the alals that are needed for resistance
in a problem in the future live so when
you start to narrow a line your it's
it's kind of like genetic drift right
but it's accidental genetic drift is
where you and I are breeding a project
and we have traits of interest that are
are are Focus over the course of the
project we lose focus and we start to
move the selection away from those
original selections
and what happens over the course of so
many years is the thing that you're
working with is the same gene pool but
the traits that you wanted are no longer
present that that [ __ ] isn't in it so
people like you could take anything and
get anything out of it I'm like no you
[ __ ] can't it doesn't work that way
if that shit's not present anymore
because in the Gene transferral and
movement of the breeding it left it's
not
present so what we want to be able to do
is have as much as possible so the way
the pakistanis worked it is even if they
have let me get this plugin so we don't
lose power even if they had their
favorite plant right they didn't just
use the favorite plant they just threw
in one or two more handfuls of seed into
the
bag so every female yielded seeds but
they would just always throw a little
bit more of their favorite [ __ ] so they
had a little more of their favorite [ __ ]
cycling through but what they know is
that when you make a mistake with
Agriculture and you focus on agronomics
and you don't focus on survivability
what you get is [ __ ]
starvation and so it was this really
really clear picture where for the first
time I could see it in person and it was
the same with sharing jeans no farmer
hoarded anything if your neighbor wanted
your [ __ ] they got it if there was
better genes in Afghanistan and similar
regions they brought it in it didn't
make a difference nobody hoarded each
person every village I'm like what's
your lines and they said oh we have we
have just common Gene poool and we share
and we always try to steer towards best
diversity best outcome you know what
this this is because in these kind of
cultures everybody relies on the
neighbor everybody relies this is the
survival in this regions you cannot
survive without being uh you know
normally this is not the Western culture
and culture means like you have your
door closed and lock down but in these
cultures like also my culture was like
this in Yugoslavia even now we don't
have our door locked yeah we we have a
very different
culture all right questions this way
this way other we're just running on oh
man you honestly we're talking about it
and you know you're similar to Michael
wolf seagull that you talk and you don't
breathe but honestly for us this is
great we're just sitting on the couch
listening to you and and even when I
want to ask a question I realize I
should probably just shut up because if
I say anything I'm just going to throw
you oh we lost him
again due the technical
difficulties we had to stop the
recording here but we got back on a week
later this episode will be continued
next
week this episode of gabbing with Gabby
is brought to you by the Breeders direct
Seed Company in my opinion the Breeders
direct seed company is your Premier
Source for clones and seeds and they are
the only place that you can get the
Gabby stattin Island collection so visit
breeders direct for all your seed and
clone needs
[Music]