[Music]
What's up everybody? This is Gabby
Staten Island and I'm here with my dog
Ray. Say hi,
Ray. Ray.
Hey. Oh, she's super interested in the
smells here today.
And um anyway, I wanted to do another
one of my dog walking videos. My dog
walking videos have been
wellreceived. Last one was when I
announced the Gabby Staten Island Sour
Diesel and so here it
is. Anyway, like I was
saying, wanted to make another video for
you. And today, the video is not as
pleasant as before. I'm not announcing a
new
clone. Not uh talking about an upcoming
podcast. Um, basically want to talk to
you about a beef I have with somebody,
somebody pretty high-profile
that is well-loved in the industry. And
I think he's well- loved
because of the genetics that he has. But
people really don't know who this guy
is, who he is for real. And so today I
decided I'm going to I'm going to tell
you what my beef is with this
guy. So first of all, what I want to say
is when I made this podcast, I made it
originally to respond to videos that
other people made about me. Um they
weren't negative. It was stuff that
Notso Dog was saying and he was just he
wasn't saying things the way I feel it.
You know, he was kind of quoting me or
telling people how I feel, but he wasn't
actually telling it accurately. So, I
made a response video to Noto Dog, who I
love dearly, and you should check out
his podcast, the Notso Dog and Crybaby
podcast. I love what they do. Anyway,
um so I made this channel first to
document my weed story. Thought it was
really important to do because to
be to be honest, I've been forgetting
some details. Um, but I want to be
clear, there's a difference between
forgetting
something and remembering things
differently,
right? So
anyway, when I made this channel, I made
it
to respond to people's videos,
particularly Noto Dog, Crybaby. Like I
said, I really like those guys. Highly
recommend you check out their
podcast. And
um so I made my own channel. I made a
response to those guys and it caught on,
you know, like right away I was getting
a good response from people and I
decided to just keep doing
it and uh really appreciate the support
I've been getting from all you guys. So,
at the same time that I made this
podcast, I also did something else and
that was I contacted my
grandmother and I told her that I wanted
to document my family story because I
have an 8-year-old daughter that um
unfortunately my mom died so she never
got to meet her mom and or her grandma
and I never knew my great-grandparents
on my mom's side or either side but so I
was talking to my
grandma and Um, I told her that I wanted
to document my family story, make like a
podcast, but it would be
private. And the whole idea is to
document my story for future
generations cuz obviously my story goes
way beyond um, cannabis, right? And she
was, you know, pretty touched by it. And
you know, she said she wanted to do it,
but one of the things she said was she
didn't want to tell the whole story
because some of the stuff with her
parents, it was
sad. And I reminded her that on my dad's
side, everyone was wiped out in the
Holocaust. And we can't not tell the
stories just because they're not happy
stories,
right? So, you know, she agreed and
she's currently um writing down the
story every day. so that we can, you
know, record stuff. She wants to be
prepared. And by the way, she's 98 years
old. I'd appreciate it if you all send
her your best wishes. I'm pretty lucky
to still have her. I got this beef and
it's with VA
Skunk. And I want you guys to know
what's going on. I I think it's about
time that I let the world know that me
and VA Skunk were not cool. because
everybody seems to think like we're best
friends because we did this podcast
together and um we have a history,
but we don't like each other at all. You
know, honestly, I can
say I don't respect this guy at all, you
know. And I've been
trying. I've been trying, but he makes
it really [ __ ] hard. That's the
reality. He doesn't make it easy.
So, I'm going to tell you what's going
on. I'm going to tell you the story.
We're going to have uh it can be judged
in the court of public opinion. And um
the first thing I want to say is I
invited him to do the
podcast. I invited him to do it and we
could have heavy days moderate. Okay?
That way we could both tell our story
publicly. And to be honest with you, he
was a chicken [ __ ] That's the way I see
it. You know, he he'll say, "Oh, I just
don't want to do it. I got no time for
it. I don't want to do your podcast. I
actually I was going to do it on the
Heavy Days podcast and I put that in the
text message cuz it's not like I'm
looking for viral views. Like I just
think it's about time that people know
like this is what's going on and this is
what I think of this guy."
So he refused and so I'm going to tell
my story myself and you know if he wants
to clap back on another podcast or do
his own thing that's fine you know
because like I'm prepared like I don't
think he has any reason to act and treat
me the way he does and you know I can
tell my story if he wants to tell his
story he can do that and then like I
said it can be judged in the court of
public
opinion. So, you know, I'm going to
briefly talk about the beginning of our
story cuz it's been told before on the
podcast with Heavy Days. Um, I really
like that podcast. The reason why I
suggested that Heavy Days moderate was
because I didn't want it to be like one
of the team on my
podcasts. And um, Heavy Days is a friend
of VA Skunk. So I figured like he can't
say that we're biased when we have his
friend do the moderating, right? But of
course he refused. And so anyway, I'm
going to go back and the way the story
begins is met VA skunk in Golden Gate
Park. Um I sold him weed which he loved
and you know that's how it all began.
sold him weed in the panhandle and he
sold my weed when I was first living in
California and like I didn't know
anybody like to the point where I lived
in Sonoma County and I drove down to
Golden Gate Park to sell my weed you
know that shows like what desperate
times it was cuz like it's one thing
when Jerry was in town then it was super
easy to sell the weed but you know when
the dead were on the road wasn't so
easy. So, um, anyway, I met him in
Golden Gate Park and he sold my weed.
That's how we became friends. Um, we
used to go see Jerry at the Warfield
together and, you know, we had lots of
good times together, you know, like lots
of good memories.
And so, you know, I told him, you know,
cuz he was traveling with the dead
still. I wasn't. I was basically just
based in uh Northern California. And
when Jerry came to town, I would see
him, but I wasn't like traveling the
whole country to see him like Jason was
at that point. It was actually the
reason why I came to California was so I
didn't have to do that. And um and
besides, I had a garden, so I couldn't
just like go away. You know, when you
got plants, they kind of like they keep
you home.
So anyway,
um I told Jason that, you know, when the
time came that he wanted to settle down
and get a place that I would teach him
how to grow and I'd give him
plants. And you know, when Jerry died
sadly in 1995, that's what happened.
Jason
um Jason got a place and I gave him
plants and I helped them grow. I mean, I
can't disagree about it being the most
high quality indoor I've ever seen. I
mean, the guy puts us Gabby grows
incredible wheat. He always has. I mean,
this is the man who taught me everything
I need to know on day one, cuts and all.
And so, you know, I was so like elated.
I couldn't believe it. It was like my
lucky day. I should take a step back,
and I hope you guys will tolerate this
cuz it's off the cuff. I'm not too
scripted, although I have some notes
that I'm going to talk about later.
Um, so I think it was like 1992 or
1993, Jason introduced me to one of his
friends from Virginia. I won't mention
him out of name out of respect. Um, he
introduced me to this guy and I showed
him some weed that I had and you know,
he showed me some weed that he had and
we decided to make a trade. And you
know, Jason introduced us, but you know,
I had a clone that I eventually traded
him, and that's how I got the Super
Skunk, the not the Sensei Seed. You
know, this guy made an F2 or an
F3. And so I what happened was I drove
in my car across country with a couple
of um cuts of my strain called the
Francine. I named all my strains girls
names at the time. So I drove Francine
across
country. I met this guy. I believe it
was in New York City and we made a
trade. He gave me the skunk. I gave him
Francine and he actually gave me a
couple of clones of the skunk. And then
I took those plants up to Massachusetts
and I traded Greg for the Chem Dog, the
one that we now call the
91. And
um Greg got this plant. I believe later
on that plant's been called the mass
super skunk, but you know, reality that
thing came from Virginia and through my
hands. And so I drove those clones
across country again. And you know, I
tell the story and I'll be brief that
when I drove it across country, I would
keep it in a Dixie like a Burger King
cup or something like that. And it was
like one of those big soda cups and it
had a lid on it and if somebody drove by
I could just, you know, quickly cover it
or if I had to go into a gas station or
something. Hey, what's up, Ray? I could
cover
it. And so, um, drove that across
country. Probably took me like 5 days
cuz I I was driving by
myself. Ray really wants to say
hello. Anyway, so I drove it across
country. This is 92 or 93. And Jason
wasn't even growing.
So, you know, I have these plants now
for years before Jason starts growing.
You know, Jerry died in August of 99
1995. And, you know, took a minute till
Jason came to California, got a place,
and started growing. So, I'm not sure
exactly when it was, but um you know, I
had those plants for years before
um he ever did. he got his place and
um we were partners and you know I think
I made a deal with Jason that you know
the only thing I asked was that he sell
me the weed you know which I don't think
he had a problem with. Um, so
anyway, my point is is that I gave Jason
the Skunk and the
Chem91, you know, in I think
1995, late '95, something like that. And
I taught him how to grow, taught him
everything that I knew. When I did
settle down, he brought the Super Skunk
back over to the house. Now, I lived in
Sonoma County, same spot he was in. And
he he stood up on his his offer and he
he showed me what he knew and he knew
quite a bit. You know, he'd been growing
wheat for a while. Uh, and also brought
the Kim 91 over. And of course, he was
like I was like, "What about the Kim
dog?" And he's like, "Oh, you don't want
to mess with that one." I'm like, "Yeah,
that's the best one. I want to mess with
that one." He goes, "Well, you know,
it's really hard to grow. It's going to
break your heart." He's got a thick New
York accent. And I'm like, "I I can deal
with a little heartbreak. You know, I
want the best weed." And it doesn't
rude. you know, you can't smoke in a
bubble before 11. I was like, you're not
going to convince me. Like, we're going
to let's get that one going. So, we did
and I got, you know, good success,
beginner's luck, rooting it out. You
know, as soon as someone says you don't
want this one, that's the one you want.
Yeah. Yeah. Why you holding out, man?
This one's the best, but she's hard to
deal with. You're like, bring her on.
Yeah. Yeah. So, he kept his word,
though. Yeah. And all those years later,
I mean, that's rare, too, in this
business. Yeah. Yeah. Well, you know,
word was different back then. I'd say a
bit, you know, like, well, quite a bit
actually. You know, that was your bond
and it would have been odd not to. And
we all So anyway, getting back to the
story.
Um, Jason grew those plants and, uh, you
know, he held the Chem91 at least for 30
years, you know, so far. I'm sure he's
going to keep it a lot longer. And I
think he should be praised for it, you
know, like for some reason I think he
doesn't think I give him credit for it,
which I do. I'll just explain later, you
know, what my issues are with it. But
yeah, I don't know anyone that's holding
on to strains. Maybe not so dog has held
on to some strains that long, but it's a
really [ __ ] long time to hold on to a
cannabis strain without using tissue
culture and definitely deserves props
for it.
Um
anyway, so I'm gonna jump forward in
time because, you know, most people know
that part of the story. Most people know
about I shouldn't say most people, but a
lot of people. There's other podcasts
where they talk about it. And um so I
don't need to to go in all that too
deeply, but what I want to talk to you
about
is how I lost the
skunk. And before that, I'm going to
start telling you about the beef that I
have with Jason. Let me tell you how the
story goes, like how Jason and I stopped
talking. And so this is about 15 years
ago. And we, you know, agreed to do a
breeding project together. And I gave
him a bunch of genetics. I gave him
seeds that I purchased in
Amsterdam and um then I also gave him
some clones that I had. I gave him the
cherry pie and I gave him the Master
Kush. Um both of those clones were
highly desired at the time and I believe
he still has both of those strains. Um
and he actually told me that he still
has these seed packs which really kind
of bummed me out. But anyway, I know my
story is rambling. I'm sorry. I'm a
little high on sour diesel and I'm a
little upset about this stuff to be
honest with you. But
so anyway, we're supposed to do this
breeding project together and I give him
this genetics and a month goes by which
isn't really that long, right?
Um but the next time I see him, you
know, he comes to my store. I had a grow
shop in Santa Rosa, the Garden Spout. He
comes to my store and you know the way
he tells the story and you know I don't
want to dispute this because you know I
was going through some [ __ ] but he said
like he came to the store and I was in a
bad mood and yeah like totally possible
I was in a bad mood and I was a little
short with him maybe. I don't think I
like raised my voice. I think I just
might have been
like I might have been rude and I'm not
um defending it, you know, like I'm
actually if I was rude, I'm sorry about
it. Ask Jason. I say, you know, what's
going on with that breeding project? He
says, I have no intention of doing that
with
you. And that [ __ ] super pissed me
off. And I was already in a bad mood.
So, like we got into an argument about
it and we didn't speak for over 15
years.
Now, I want to point out I had purchased
a greenhouse. It was a small light depth
greenhouse that had a motor on it that
it would cover the the greenhouse
automatically so you didn't have to drag
a tarp. And I gave him all these
genetics. He never returned them.
greenhouse, you know, that was like 2500
bucks wholesale because I I owned a
hydro store. I think it was like a
$5,000 greenhouse and never gave me my
seeds back. You know, the clones at the
time, I don't know that I needed those
back, but the seed packs were from
Holland that I had been saving for
years. So, um, one of them that I
remember was, um, from TH Seeds. He was
the sage and sour, which I really want
those seeds even today. And uh later on
you'll hear that he actually still has
those seeds. Um but anyway, I got pissed
off
and you know, he got upset, you know,
because words were said and we didn't
talk for 15
years. With that, it's time to light
another joint.
And when I finally saw him 15 years
later, I realized or to myself, I said
that our friendship mattered more to me
than, you know, the gen. First of all, I
thought he did the breeding project.
Turns out he never even did it. Um, but
like I felt like he ripped me off, took
my genetics, did a breeding project, and
never gave me anything. And I only found
out like short amount of time ago that
he just never did anything. But still,
he had my greenhouse, didn't return
it. Anyway, so 15 years I'm thinking
this guy, he like stole my [ __ ] you
know, made did a breeding project,
didn't give me anything, and took my
greenhouse and didn't give me anything.
And uh like I said, Jason might have a
different side of the story, but uh he's
not here today to tell it, you know. So
the bottom line is we didn't talk for a
long time. And when I saw him, I was
like I thought to myself, hey, you know
what? This guy's an important part of my
history. And despite everything that
happened, I still have love for him. And
I told him that. And um I wanted us to,
you know, be friends
again. And you know, he
agreed. And
um eventually
uh well you know we talked about like us
doing a collaboration together in the
future and he hooked me up with Breeders
Direct who Michelle from Breeders Direct
is his girlfriend and that's been a
really good thing for me. You know like
I've been selling clones on the Breeders
Direct website and I'm grateful for
that.
Um, we talk about doing another
collaboration
because I think that's
what the market wants that the market
would really appreciate, you know, me
and him working together again. And and
then me and me and me and my buddy Gabby
have some good news, too. We're uh we've
decided to uh team up and and start
working on providing some genetics
focusing on clones and we're going to do
some seed collaborations together with
uh some breeding projects. Chem dog
heavy of course. Um and so, you know,
I'm super [ __ ] excited about that.
I'm super excited to be working with
Gabby. We've had literally 30 solid
years of knowing each other as of
February this year. We met in February
of 1993. all those years ago. And so it
just I mean we talk a lot more now and
it just feels good and um I'm [ __ ]
excited. I know my friend Gab is excited
and you know we're ready to just get it
going on and kind of you know put the
put the old school and the Kim and the
Kim kind of stuff, the gas back in
what's available out there for folks.
You know, they're definitely hungry for
it. So yeah, that's it. Wow. This collab
that sounds really awesome. When did
this first uh come into life? You know,
when did the wheels start turning on
that one? 30 years ago. Yeah. 30 years
ago. It's exactly what I was saying.
We planned this all up 30 years ago.
Yeah. I mean, Gabby, he's, you know, uh
he owned a chain of not a chain, but you
know, several hydro stores for a while
and then that petered out and went went
down. Now he's uh selling clones, you
know, and selling genetics. And so we we
we we definitely work together on that
level. You know, we have a few
collaborations going. So he's still
fully involved. It's some of us are
lifers, you know, this is what's at, you
know, and so we talked about it and, you
know, he agreed that it was a good idea
and I gave him a whole bunch of genetics
again. He did he did breed with these
genetics. He told me that he's gotten
seeds from these genetics already. He
later on told me that he thought most of
the genetics were garbage, but he's
like, "Except for this one." And then
his Michelle, his girlfriend, says, "Oh,
yeah, and that one was really nice,
too." And like I know the strains that I
gave him, you know, they were they were
good. There was one that I really liked,
the deep end butter and he didn't like
it because it wanted to go into flour
real fast. Like it would just flower
under veg. And I understand that's a
problem when you have a hard time
getting a plant to veg. When I grew them
under 24 hours light, they would veg. If
I grew them under 18 hours light, they
would flower. But the thing about this
plant is it would finish in six weeks
and produce beautiful purple buds even
when it's hot and it had a loud turpp
profile. I thought it was an excellent
candidate for breeding, you know. So
that's the only one that he could say,
"Hey, you know what? This is why I don't
like it. This is why I'm not going to
breed with it." And I would get it. The
other ones for fire, he bred with them.
And
so I want to tell you guys something
that happened with me and Jason and
Bridges Direct that when this happened,
it was kind of like our friendship took
a turn for the worst and never got
better. And so I made a mistake. And I'm
going to be honest with you guys about
it. And I was already honest with them
like immediately after the mistake was
made. And you know, I don't think that
it's the type of thing that the reaction
should have been what it was, but I'm
going to let you know and we'll let the
court of public opinion decide. So, I'm
selling clones on the Breeders Direct
website and I'm talking to the clients,
you know, like people will message with
me message me on Instagram. somebody
purchased clones from Jason and you know
he was worried about his order. It was
taking a couple of days to be honest
with you. The guy was like um very
impatient but
um Jason wasn't
responding and so I responded to to
because he messaged me directly and so I
responded. And I was like, "Hey, you
know, I I'll help you take care of it."
And um I did, you know, um Michelle and
Jason responded and he eventually got
his
stuff.
Um so I became friends with this guy and
if you know a lot of people that message
me on Instagram, we become friendly, you
know,
because that's what I do. I make friends
and
um you know I had sold him a bunch of
clones through Breeders Direct.
Everything always went through Breeders
Direct. He brought
like I don't know at least eight
different strains off of me. Every
purchase goes through Breeders Direct.
And um then he asked me if I could get
other genetics and I was like, "Yeah, I
can get them, but I can't get them. Like
I don't have them and I have to buy a
flat and get my
dog." So anyway, he wanted these
genetics. I knew another nursery that
had them and I actually wanted these
genetics to sell on Breeders Direct. And
so I made a deal with him outside of
Breeders Direct. And the deal was that
he pays for the genetics. Like he pays
for the
flat and that I would send him a few
clones of it and then he'd have the
genetic and then I'd have the genetic
and I could sell the rest, you know,
through Breeders
Direct. And so I made the deal with to
do that with him for like three strains
and he like immediately paid me.
And so he sent me the money. I hadn't
even gotten the clones yet, you know,
might have been like a couple of days
later that I spoke with Jason about it
and I told him, I was like,
"Hey, this is what I did. I got these
clone. I took this guy's money and
um you know for these clones which I'm
going to get from this nursery and then
I'm going to keep the rest and sell
them. Now I said I'm not making any
money on it. He's literally paying for
the
flats. But, you know, I just wanted to
be open with you guys. And if you think
that I, you know, owe you something, I'm
happy to give you the commission even
though I'm not making money on
these. And Jason was like, "Well, you
know, you should have spoken to Michelle
first. She probably would have given you
the money for the clones. Um, but yeah,
let's talk to her about it." Now, I
should make this point.
I wasn't allowed to speak to Michelle.
Like Jason had this thing where I had to
only communicate via email with her. I
was allowed to speak to him on the
phone, but I wasn't allowed to speak to
her. Okay? So, I had to send this email.
And in the email, I said, "Hey,
Michelle." And I could actually look it
up, but I'm paraphrasing. Said, "Hey,
Michelle, you know, hope you're doing
well. Just wanted to let you know that I
did something and I want you to know
about it."
Um, I spoke to Jason about this and I,
you know, let him know that I purchased
these clones with money that I got from
X. And, you know, they were pissed. And
to be honest with
you, I think I should have spoken to her
about it first, but if I was trying to
be sneaky, I wouldn't have told her
about it at all. Right? you know, I out
of my own valition, you know, before the
clones hadn't even been shipped yet. I
even told them, I said, I can send the
money back, you know,
um I told them what I had done cuz I
realized like, hey, I should have talked
to them first. And you know, they were
pissed about it. And frankly, Jason
didn't talk to me at all via phone or
text message for over six
months. I think it was it was longer
than that. Um, he was so pissed that I
did this because he said that when I and
it's in an email, right? So, like it's
not like he said, she said, like you can
read the email and he said that I threw
him under the bus and that I made it
sound like he knew what I was
doing, but he didn't. He knew what I did
and I told him because I would speak to
him on the phone and I wouldn't speak to
Michelle. Okay. So, I I was never making
it out like he knew what I was doing and
he was cool with it. It was like he knew
what I did and I talked to him about it
and we talked about that I should talk
to you about it and that's what I'm
doing. Right. So, anyway,
um that like forever changed my
relationship with
Jason. He he didn't communicate with me
and if he did it was really short and
you
know do I think I made a mistake?
Absolutely. I owned it and I apologized.
I tried to make it right. You know, you
know, like I said, I think it's pretty
clear that I didn't have an intention of
stealing
clients. So Jason doesn't talk to me,
won't respond to my messages. is I ask
him for a meeting after meeting, he
won't do it, won't take my calls, won't
respond to my text messages. So, I'm
getting frustrated. And you know, one of
the big reasons why I'm frustrated is
because I don't have the Chem
Dog. Okay? I
mean, I lost everything. I not only
don't have the Chem Dog, but I don't
have any of my genetics. Okay? I lost
some in unfortunate events. Um, myo
house burned down. I'm going to tell the
cardboard box story about the skunk in a
little bit, but um, I lost all my
genetics and
um, you know, I've been wanting the chem
dog back, but I've been struggling to
ask Jason for it because he's so
difficult and honestly so [ __ ] tight
with that stream.
So eventually he's ignoring my text
messages and I've already given him a
bunch of genetics for a collaboration
project. Okay. And he's informed me that
he's bred with them already, that he's
gotten seeds. He told me he was going to
send me some like over a year
ago. I gave him these seeds. I I gave
him these genetics. I thought we had an
agreement to do a collaboration. And
proof of that is if you go on the Heavy
Days podcast that I did with him, we
actually talk about it. We talk that
we're doing a collaboration. So, like we
we actually announced that we intend on
doing work together. And then me and me
and me and my buddy Gabby have some good
news, too. We're uh we've decided to uh
team up and and start working on
providing some genetics, focusing on
clones, and we're going to do some seed
collaborations together with uh some
breeding projects. Chem dog heavy of
course. Um and so, you know, I'm super
[ __ ] excited about that. I'm super
excited to be working with Gabby. We've
had literally 30 solid years of knowing
each other as of February this year. We
met in February of 1993. all those years
ago. And so it just I mean we talk a lot
more now and it just feels good and um
I'm [ __ ] excited. I know my friend
Gab is excited and you know we're ready
to just get it going on and kind of you
know put the put the old school and the
Kim and the Kim kind of stuff, the gas
back in what's available out there for
folks. You know they're definitely
hungry for it. So yeah, that's it. Wow.
This collab that sounds really awesome.
When did this first uh come into life?
You know, when did the wheels start
turning on that one? 30 years ago. Yeah.
30 years ago. That's exactly what I was
going. He never told me that he doesn't
want to. And you know, he says,
"Yeah, like we don't have a
collaboration
agreement." And I'm like, "All right,
whatever. That's fine." I said, "Well,
can I get some of those seeds?" Right. I
gave you the genetics. Ray sees I'm
upset. She wants to make me feel better.
Um, I gave you these genetics. You bred
with them. How about you give me some
seeds? He says, "We don't have a
collaboration agreement." So, I say,
"Okay, how about the Chem Dog? Can I get
a cut of the Chem Dog?" And he's like,
"We don't have a collaboration
agreement." Which wasn't the question.
Bottom line is like he brags on podcasts
about how he kept this strain for 30
years and that he's given it back to so
many people but he's never given it to
me
ever. Okay. And I can't remember and I'm
sure he'll correct me but I can't
remember him giving me a single clone.
And you know like I just recently you
know in the last few years gave him a
whole bunch of genetics. Okay. I think
like six or seven different strains.
He's never offered to give me a clone.
Even when I showed interest in a plant,
I was like, "Oh man, that's really
nice." You'd think he'd be like, "Oh,
you want one? No problem." Because
that's what I did. Okay. And
um so he's never given me a single
clone. And when I ask him for the Chem
Dog, he just dodges me. And so I don't
respond. You know, like we don't like
communicate very much for a while. Then
I'll drop him another message and uh ask
him about the Chem Dog. Hey, you know,
I'm going to do a breeding project. I
really would like to include the chem
dog, you know, and he either ghosts me
or says, "Hey, you know, we can have a
meeting, but it'll have to be on my
schedule." And I'm like, "Hey, no
problem. Let's schedule a meeting. Tell
me when's good." Then he'll be like,
"Okay, how about tomorrow?" And I'm
like, "Sure, tomorrow's fine." Then
tomorrow comes along and I message him
like, "Hey, can we have a meeting?" and
he freaks out because he's too busy and
and can't do it or really doesn't want
to do it because he doesn't want to talk
to me about giving me the
chemog. And
so, literally, it's been like six or
seven months that I've been periodically
asking him when I can get a cut of the
Chem
Dog. And, you know, he doesn't want to
give it to me. And in the meantime, and
I know he recorded it a while ago, but
um the first podcast of the day episode
comes out and you know, he talks about
me and he talks about how he's given all
these people the Chem Dog back. Um which
by the way, he lost it too and had it
given back to him. But he, you know,
only for a couple of weeks he lost it,
but you know, still he lost it. And you
know, Ben from IC Collective gave it
back to him. If it wasn't for
Ben, Chem Dog wouldn't have it. Excuse
me, not Chem Dog. Uh Jason VA skunk. And
so anyway,
um he doesn't want to give me the Chem
Dog back. I keep messaging him about it.
Doesn't want to give it back.
And a few weeks ago, the clone, he
decides to release a couple of
them. Okay. And so he puts it up for
sale and I'm like I'm I'm just like in
shock. I've been asking him for a cut,
you know, for six, seven months. Doesn't
want to give it to me and then he just
puts it on sale. And so I put an order
in for it and then I sent him a text
message with a screenshot of my order
and I said, "Hey, I guess I gotta, you
know, pay 500 bucks to get the Chem Dog
back, right?" And so he never processes
my order. And I think it's like a couple
of days later, I'm like on the phone
with a friend and he's calling me up.
So, I take the call and I'm like, "Hey,
uh, I'm surprised to hear from you."
He's like, "Why?" And he makes it out
like, "Why would I be surprised to hear
from him when like I never talked to him
and he's like been super pissed at me
over something that I I think is
seriously blown out of proportion."
Okay. Um, now, nonetheless, I apologize.
He calls me up and I say, "Yeah, I
ordered that clone." He's like, "Yeah,
I'm just going to send it to you." And
I'm like, "Oh, great." You know, I'm
like just so happy at this point because
I'm like, "I'm finally going to get the
Chem Dog back. Jason's finally going to
give me the Chem Dog." Um, and then we
start talking about some personal
problems he he has. And I'm not going to
get into it, uh, his private business.
Um, but what I will say is that I talked
to him
for eight hours over the course of a
couple of days, like trying to like help
him and be a friend. And in that time,
like we didn't really talk about the
Chem Dog, you know, like at the end of
the first conversation after like six
hours, you know, he's like, "I got to
go." I was like, "Hey, wait, you know,
can we just talk about the Chem Dog for
a minute?"
Um, like I said, I was trying to be a
friend and he said, "Well, okay, you
know, I'll get you the clone, but I
don't want you to sell it for 3 to four
months, and when you sell it, I want you
to agree to sell it for the same price
as me." And to be honest, I was a bit
takenback by this because
like for him to put restrictions on me,
I felt would be is kind of ridiculous.
Um, number one, he's selling the clone.
Number two, um, I gave him the clone,
and when I gave it to him, I asked him
to not give it to anyone, and he did.
Now, I'm no longer upset about that. I'm
actually glad that happened. And I think
that that's why a bunch of good genetics
were made. But he's asking me to agree
to not sell it and to not and to charge
a certain price for it. But when I gave
it to him, he didn't follow his
agreement. Right? The other thing is
he's selling it to the public. And so I
asked him, I said, "Hey, you know, when
you sell it to these people, do they
have any agreement to not sell it or to
sell it for a certain price?" And he
says, "No, cuz I'm selling it to the
public, but you're my friend, and you
know, I should be able to ask you to not
be my competition."
And
so while I thought it was completely
wrong for him to do
that, I um I agreed. I said, "Hey, you
know what? I wasn't planning on selling
it anyway. I just really wanted it for
breeding. I'm surprised that you're
selling it. You know, I just wanted it
to breed with
it." And
um so I I agreed. And so the next day or
maybe a couple days later, he flew from
Montana to LA
and I believe he fulfilled all the
orders that were taken for the Chem
Dog, but he didn't ship me mine, you
know, and um he had a really busy week.
He's off to
Barcelona, you know, the end of this
week. So, you know what? I I didn't make
a big deal about it. you know, I just
figured, all right, just gonna
wait.
And but, you know, it's [ __ ] with me.
You know, it really just bothers me that
he like knowing that he shipped it to
other people, but like he didn't send me
one even after I agreed to um abide by
his terms, which I think were over the
top.
So not next thing that happens is
Instagram [ __ ] trolls me. So like I'm
already upset at Jason and on the top of
my feed on Instagram comes a post from
2017 from the podcast saying this is VA
skunk's first garden and he's growing a
super skunk. The video, the pictures on
the podcast were from Jason's first
garden, which I completely help him set
up. Gave him the
genetics. And
uh I comment on the post, I say, "I gave
him all of
that." Okay, it was a super skunk.
Everyone knows that I gave him the
Chem91, but probably few people know
that I gave him the Super Skunk.
And you know, he's said that Staten
Island, which is what he called me, um,
gave me these
cuts. And so me saying that I gave him
that isn't
like a jab on him or anything like that,
but I get a response and I'm reading it
now. It says, "The super skunk, lol.
It's too bad you killed it. Wish we had
that one still. It died in a hot
cardboard box in front of your house.
one of the worst things ever happened in
modern cannabis. Kind of a bad
memory. I sent him a message. I'm going
to read you that
one. I said, "Buddy, I feel like you
just called me out publicly on Instagram
for killing the VA skunk." I said, "I
gave you those genetics. That's not me
calling you out or publicly saying
anything negative about you. I want us
to be friends and work [ __ ] out. So, I
just want you to know I I said I just
want you to be real and let you know
when I see these posts. It triggers me.
It's been upsetting me because I've been
doing breeding. I'm getting ready to
flower the red grape leanese and Cali
nest I have and I would have liked to
cross it with a dog, but I don't have
it. You shipped it out to others this
week, but not to me. I even tried to
order it from you because I really need
it and it stings. I'm just being real.
I'm probably not going to be able to
breed with it this round, and who knows
when I'll be flowering these males
again. Jason's reply is, "I'm sorry you
feel that way, but that's my story to
tell. LOL. It's not like I went on
Instagram today to tell that story, but
you prompted it. I don't speak for
marketing purposes. Yours are my own,
but I have tons of story, a whole bucket
full." So I
respond,
um, I'm getting it
back. Oh, yeah. So I say, I'm getting it
back. And his response, and this is on
Instagram, says, "Great. I'll believe it
when I see it. And if it's true, I can't
wait to get my cut
back." This just kind of [ __ ]
triggers me even more. And there's two
reasons for it. Number
one, why is it his
cut? Because he hooked me up with
somebody and then I did a trade with
them and drove across country and
somehow it's his cut. And he's talking
about the skunk, by the way. Okay, which
I grew for I grew it for over two years,
maybe three years before he ever had it.
And you know, I had it till we both lost
it to, you know, he didn't have it
either. I'm I don't know why he didn't
have it. Maybe cuz he just had a
flowering room, but you know, I you
know, and for me it's like, bro, why are
you calling me out on Instagram? You
know, like I'm not calling you out on
Instagram, you know? I I just
uh I just posted that I gave you
something which you've publicly said a
million times that I gave it to you.
take a sip of water and light up my
joint
again. So
anyway, we start sending messages to
each other
and it's a super long text thread and
I'm not going to read it all. However,
what I will say is anything that I leave
out, if Jason wants to talk about it or
post it, I'm fine with it. Okay?
because I'm only leaving things out that
I just feel are redundant and
excessive on, you know, like it's just
not necessary to make the
point. So, here's some of the
messages. Gabby, the constant
questioning me is getting old very fast.
It's far too timeconuming and seems out
of touch with what's actually happening.
You seem traumatized from, I assume,
your home life. You seem very defensive
and honestly too easily triggered. It's
becoming clear that you are looking for
a sparring partner outside of your home.
Maybe to take out the frustration. I'm
sure you're feeling with the treatment
you're receiving at
home. This comment is so [ __ ] out of
line and like I'm not going to talk
about the [ __ ] like the private [ __ ]
that he said to me about him, but like
this is what he's saying. And then when
he throws that out of left field, like
we're talking about something completely
different, okay? And then he feels like
he's got to say that it's just he's just
being an [ __ ] That's just the
reality. He's just being an [ __ ]
Says, "If I feel like responding to a
comment you place on a post from 2017
about pictures from my garden, then I'll
do so. If you feel slighted by that,
then that's something you need to
address personally. It's just a comment,
dude. how your feelings got entangled in
a comment is beyond my understanding.
I'll say it again. That story is part of
cannabis history. It's been told a dozen
times says, "I see your text about when
you neglected that clone. I'll never get
over that. You never even said you were
sorry. And by reading the text, it
doesn't sound like you even feel that
way." That's hurtful in ways I'm not
sure you'll even understand. But yeah,
let's talk about how a comment triggered
you. Of course, you never considered
that making a comment on pictures I took
of the super skunk might open up a bad
memory that absolutely involves you, but
maybe you should have. Maybe you really
are wrapped up in your own movie so that
you can't see that. Okay, so
um let me respond to that by
saying I did lose this clone. Okay, I
had a problem at home that I was renting
and the landlord had to come to fix an
outlet and so I had to have an
electrician come in and so we got like
you know the plants and I put this plant
in a cardboard box
outside and it got
fried and I regret it and I'm
sorry but not to
Jason I'm sorry for myself now also So
Jason makes it out like I was the only
person on the universe that had this
clone. But what about his friends in
Virginia? What about Greg that I gave it
to? You know, I mean, I gave it to
Jason. I don't know. Like I said, maybe
he only had flowering rooms, but um you
know, I wasn't the only person that had
this
plant. Okay.
And you know, I don't feel I owe Jason
an apology because I killed one of my
plants. you know, it sucks and you know,
I'm happy to talk about it, but like the
way he was talking about it, you know,
it's different if I tell the story. When
he tells the story, he could be like,
"Yeah, that was an unfortunate demise."
Instead, he calls me out like I'm a
[ __ ] idiot, okay?
And you know, whether I am or not, like
him calling me one publicly like that
was just it was ridiculous. I I said it
wasn't your story to tell as you said.
It was you talking [ __ ] about me
publicly. Jason was getting a cut of all
my sales through Breeders Direct and him
trolling me online like this and keeping
the dog from me for over 6 months.
Like I the way I feel about him, I just
can't be giving him a commission on my
sales that I do through Breeders Direct.
And so, you know, I sent Michelle a
message privately. I sent it directly to
her, which is something that I'm not
allowed to do. Jason only wanted me to
communicate with Michelle like in a
group email, you know, in an email
message that I
um that I CC him in. And this is the
type of controlling person that he is.
Um I felt like that's a conversation
that you should have one-on-one. And I
also felt that
um you know it was fine to do it you
know it's all there in writing you know
like there's
nothing nothing weird about it anyway.
So this is where it all comes from. The
proof is by what he says here. He says
he says I wasn't going to send that but
then Michelle told me that you didn't
want to work with me in an email.
Firstly, talking to my girlfriend before
you speak to me about it is completely
inappropriate and it was a huge mistake
on your part. You and I will deal with
it when I have time. Have a nice
evening." And then he says, "I don't
want to talk." And no, I say, "I don't
want to talk to you at all. You want to
talk about inappropriate? Now you're
threatening
me." Jason's response, "Bullshit. That's
my story to
tell. It's been told. If you don't like
it, that's something you have to deal
with personally. Making a big deal about
that is going to be a big mistake
letting you know. And there's not going
to be any discussion between you and me
until I'm
ready. Okay. And um I respond, "Okay, I
have a good story to tell as well. I can
tell a story about how you refused to
give me the Chem Dog." Jason's response.
Does it seem like I care about your
story, Gabby? Now, I want to tell you
that I am skipping some text. There's
nothing that I have a problem with you
guys knowing. Well, I I should say some
something. Jason says personal [ __ ]
about my family, you know, and like says
completely inappropriate, inaccurate
comments. So, like, yeah, those I prefer
not be shared. You know, like I mean if
if I were to read it to you, you would
think Jason is a complete [ __ ] if
you're if you're not already thinking
that. Like who starts bringing up
people's family in a fight that has
nothing to do with that. Okay? And you
know what? He's doing it because he has
no legitimate ground to stand on. He's
grasping at straws. And that's also why
he's not here to tell his
side. and so skip some texts. So,
congratulations on opening up a can of
worms that you're not prepared to deal
with. Good luck with that. Don't text me
anymore. This is what he's saying to me.
He says, "Oh, don't forget about the
partner story where you're never even
said I'm sorry for killing the clone."
And I respond, "Okay, I'm supposed to
apologize for killing my
genetics."
Um, right. Get
down. Okay. So
again, like Jason for some reason thinks
I killed his clones, the clones that I
had for years before he ever had it.
Like it was super unfortunate that
um that I didn't take care of those
plants better. I accept full
responsibility, but I don't owe Jason,
sorry, Ray really wants to get in the
picture again. I don't owe Jason an
apology. I just don't
like like for losing my own genetics. I
have to apologize to someone else. Okay.
I said this to Jason. Okay. Said, "I'll
give you an opportunity. I know you
won't accept it cuz you're a big man
only in a small room. We should do a
podcast together. Both tell our story.
Start off on the good parts. Then we can
get to where we are now. And then we can
let it be judged by the court of public
opinion. You don't think people are
going to be are going to think you're an
[ __ ] for withholding the dog from me?
I said, 'We can have heavy days
moderate. Jason's response, I'm not even
remotely interested in doing your
podcast at this point, dude. I say, no
problem. I'll tell everyone that I
invited you, but you were a chicken
[ __ ]
Jason. And so, we skip some stuff here,
right, Jason? So, I showed you gratitude
by mentioning you your name 10 years
ago.
I will tell the story the way it is. I
tell the
truth that that it deserves. I'm not
your marketing agent. I could care less.
I speak from my heart. And when someone
brings up a bad memory, I mention it.
Why are you on a post from 2017 giving
yourself credit that you're not even
sure if you deserve? You should tell the
world that you're sorry for killing the
super skunk. Comprende,
homeboy, you have a you have a choice
only cuz I'm giving you one. You can
either end our friendship or you can
make an enemy. It's up to you. I'm ready
for either. Don't make the wrong
decisions,
Gabriel. Then he says after some more
[ __ ] you actually pissed me off
today. Now I'm your [ __ ] problem. And
his response is, "Oh, a jester. Oh no.
That would be you saying I'm sorry for
killing one of the most legendary clones
you were priv privileged enough to have
thanks to my [ __ ] efforts and my
friends. But you couldn't do that
yourself. You couldn't do that yourself.
Entitlement stopped you again. Or maybe
saying that you for allowing my
girlfriend and you to work together for
the last year. Yes. And I kept it alive
for 30 years. No thanks to you. Lol. Do
the math, [ __ ] You [ __ ] up. Your
anger and weird self-entitlement.
Complete ego egoomaniacal [ __ ] has
brought me to a major problem. Has
brought a major problem right to your
door. You made an enemy with your words
and actions and lack of actions. You
killed that plant being a lazy larf on
your
couch. So, first of all, I think I said
this before, I'll say it again. Pretty
awesome that Jason was able to keep the
91 for 30 years. I mean, now I don't
think he's the only one to do that. You
know, there's people on the East Coast
that have it. You know, some that I can
mention by name, like JJ. Um, maybe they
had it for 20some years. So, the [ __ ]
what? Um, but uh, yeah. So, props to
Jason for holding on to that clone for
30 years. You know, maybe if he returned
it to me, I could thank him for it, but,
you know, he doesn't want to give it to
me. Like even when I tried to buy it for
500 bucks, he didn't take my order. So,
I'm not going to thank him for holding a
plant that I gave him that he's
withholding from me. And so, like,
that's just one question I have for you
guys. Like, how do you feel about the
fact that I gave the Chem Dog to Jason?
He talks about how I gave it to him,
taught him how to grow, and he refuses
to give me this plant back.
The other thing is, and I told him this
too, because I made a video about the
Gabby Staten Island sour, this new sour
that I found that I think is super
awesome. In this video, and you can
check it out on Instagram. I'll put a
link in the comments. I talk about how I
I don't know where this clone came from,
but that I think it's a really great
clone, and I'm going to call it the
Gabby Staten Island Sour Diesel. And
this is all really a joke at Jason and
not so dog. And so if you guys think I
have it had it coming, you can let me
know. Jason didn't seem to be bothered
about it when I talked to him because I
sent them both the link to the video.
And so first with not dog, the most
common question I get about the three
sour cuts that I have is, is that the
not so sour? It's so [ __ ] annoying
cuz like what the hell is the not so
sour? It's not like he bred it. It's
just the clone that he's had, you know.
And the other thing that gets me, and I
I'll be honest with you, it strikes a
nerve with me. You can tell me if I'm
right or wrong,
but Jason calling the Chem Dog the
Chem91 the VA cut. Like, what makes it
the VA cut? To be honest, I think it's
disrespectful to Greg. Not to me. I
don't want it to be called the Gabby
cut, you know, cuz that's not what it
is, you know? You know, and if you want
to talk about a cut, you can say, "Yeah,
this is the Chem91." The provenence is,
"I got it from Gabby who got it from
Greg." You know, or other people can
say, "I bought it from Jason who got it
from Gabby who got it from Greg." That's
the provenence. But attaching your name
to a historical clone like
that, it's just super arrogant, you
know? And that combined in the fact that
like he's keeping it from me because
like he feels because he's held it for
30 years like it's like he's the only
one entitled to it, you know?
So, I don't think we should call the 91
the VA cut. I think it's disrespectful
to Greg and I think it feeds Jason's ego
which is out of
control, you know. And so I uh I made
this joke that I'm calling this clone
the Gabby Staten Island. Mostly because
I didn't know what else to [ __ ] call
it. I already have two other sour. And
when I asked the person that I got it
from what the provenence on it, they're
like, "I don't know. We just got it from
a grower." So, you
know, like I said in my video, I make it
clear that calling it that is kind of
just a joke. I'm going to stick with it
because at this point it's like it is
what it is and and I tell everyone that
I'm not taking myself seriously that I
haven't bred it. I haven't even flowered
this plant yet. Okay. I you know my
buddy flowered it. I've seen the flower
and I got the clones from the tissue
culture lab that he got them from. Um
but yeah, it's a [ __ ] joke. And
um anyway, to get back on
track, Jason and
I were not cool, you know. I'm never
going to be cool with this guy again. I
I can't even see it happening.
Like, you know, and and honestly, I know
he feels the same way, you know, and I
don't know what his [ __ ] problem is.
I I just think like he's got his head so
far up his ass that he can't realize
when he's being an
[ __ ] you know, like trolling me on
Instagram. Like, you know, if if me
making a comment on a post, which by the
way, it's not like I was searching for
this post. It came on the top of my
feed. If that triggers him to the point
where he's going to call me out publicly
like
that, I I just think that's [ __ ] up,
you know? and I killed the plant there.
I say it for the record. I apologize to
every one of you except for
Jason. Yeah. So, that's the story.
That's why you haven't seen Jason on my
podcast. That's why when you ask me if I
have the Chem Dog, I, you know, either
say no and dodge it or, you know, like,
or if you ask me if I'm releasing the
Chem Dog, I don't say I don't have it. I
just said nothing about it, you know.
But now you guys all know that, you
know, Jason doesn't want to give me the
Chem Dog. Now, having said that, another
number of people have stepped up to say
they're going to give it to me. And
actually, I should point this out. My
feeling is is Jason should just give it
to
me. You know, like when I asked him for
the Chem Dog, it should be like, "Sure,
Gab, no problem. I'll send you a couple
of them." you know, instead it's like 6
months of dodging me, you know, and then
when he eventually releases it to the
public, he says, "I can have it if I
agree not to sell it for 3 4 months, and
then I agree to only sell it for a price
that he agrees to when he already broke
his agreement to me when I gave him the
clone." It's just
ridiculous, you know?
So
anyway, the reason why I made this
podcast is because Jason [ __ ] trolled
me and then he threatened me. And you
know, I read you the messages where he's
like, "You're opening up a can of
worms." It's like, and now you got to
deal with my [ __ ] [ __ ] He can um
say, "I killed a clone." Which I already
said that I killed the clone. So like,
there's really nothing that he can say
that's not going to make him look like a
[ __ ] [ __ ] And that's why he
didn't do this podcast. And that's why
he's probably not going to [ __ ] say
anything, you know? And like
honestly, I'm doing this to document my
weed
story. Jason being an [ __ ] to me is
an unfortunate part of my weed story. 15
years from now, I don't want to make the
same mistake with Jason again, you know?
I you know so I think it's important to
document your weed stories good and bad
and you know I'm not here to talk [ __ ]
about other people's you know second and
third hand this is the [ __ ] that
happened to me oh I remember what I was
going to say and you know
um people really kiss Jason's ass and a
lot of people actually try to kiss mine
And if you've ever contacted me and you
start like thanking me profusely about
like my involvement with the Chem Dog, I
always stop you. You know, I always say,
"Hey, look, I don't think I did that
much. You know, like I drove the plant
across country, you know, I don't have,
you know, like I'm part of the story,
you know, but like the people really
responsible for it is Greg." And you
know, while Jason deserves props for
keeping a clone for 30
years, doesn't mean like it's his
[ __ ] clone and only his and like
nobody, you know, other people have it,
you know, same exact [ __ ] clone that
he has, you know,
and you know, I just think the way he
acts about this
clone, it's
[ __ ] it's beyond materialistic.
It's like he thinks he owns something
that really can't be owned, you know,
and he owns something that was given to
him, you know,
like Yeah. So, please do not call the
Chem Dog or the 91 the VA cut because
that's just feeding this guy's ego and
his ego is already a [ __ ] monster
balloon.
Anyway, sorry I had to take this podcast
on a
negative spin, but
uh felt it had to be told.
[Music]