[Music]
Hey, what's up everybody? This is Gabby
Staten Island coming to you from
beautiful California and I've got
another video that I want to make for
you.
Um, many of you may have seen
the short that I put on Instagram. I
made a hourong podcast about the whole
story. But before I get into it, I
wanted to make this video. So, I I made
the video about me and VA a couple of
weeks ago and didn't release it. Um, I
wanted to make sure that I got it all
right.
And like I said, the other day I made a
short video
um 15 seconds on Instagram which got a
pretty huge response and most of it was
positive. Positive in the sense of
people were glad that I was getting the
news out there. Um, obviously the topic
is kind of negative and people were
disappointed in VA skunk, but um, I did
get a small amount of people that said,
"Hey, you know, I don't know that
Instagram or YouTube is the place for
this." And people were saying that they
didn't know if I should do it on the
craft growers network because they felt
that I've been keeping it positive and
having good stories and that this would
bring it down. So I wanted to respond to
those couple of things prior to putting
out this video. So when I made this uh
podcast channel, my goal was to tell my
story because people like Noto Dog, who
I love dearly, were quoting me or giving
my opinion and not doing it exactly as I
would have. And so I decided to make my
own podcast. I decided that I wanted to
tell my story and have a place where it
lived forever. And then of course this
grew beyond my wildest dreams where it's
become a place for many people to tell
their story. But like I said the
original goal was to have a place to
tell my
story.
And you know something that you guys
don't know is that I'm also recording
with my family. Something that I thought
would be really good to do would be to
have my dad and my grandma and my aunts
and uncles, you know,
record podcasts, which would be private,
where we talk about our family history,
and the whole idea would be to pass it
to future generations. For example, my
seven-year-old daughter never got a
chance to meet my mom, and we want her
to know about my mom. I can tell some
stories, but I also wanted my mom's mom
to tell some stories and her sister
about them growing up. And so I have I'm
lucky I have a 98-year-old grandma and I
asked her if she would do this with me
and she said yes. She got really
emotional about it and was crying. But
one of the things that she said was that
she didn't want to tell the whole story.
That she wanted to leave certain parts
out because they were sad stories. And
to be honest with you, I don't even know
what she's talking about. I don't know
anything about my great-grandparents on
my mom's side. Um I don't really know
much about my grandma's life when she
was growing up.
And I told her, I said, "Hey, you know,
you know, I understand that it's
difficult, but I reminded her that on my
dad's side, pretty much everyone was
wiped out in the Holocaust. Um, my
grandfather and his brother and my
grandmother and her sister were the only
ones from a very large family that were
able to escape the Holocaust."
And so what I told my grandma was, hey,
you know, the sad stories are important,
too. We can't just not tell the stories
about the Holocaust because it's sad,
right? And she agreed. And so we're
doing this together. And so in regards
to me telling my story, the stuff that's
not positive, it's the same thing, you
know, like I can sugarcoat my story or I
can tell my story accurately. And that's
what I want to do, okay? I want
to I want to tell my story. I want to
document it so that I can remember it
and so that anyone that's interested can
hear it. But I I can't just leave out
negative stuff or drama
because people think it brings down the
vibe. It just sucks. I I don't feel like
I can do that and be true to myself and
and that's what I want to do. And you
know, when I made this podcast, one
thing that I told myself, and I think it
was a little bit of a defensive move,
was I said, "I don't care if people like
it. I'm making this for
myself. And you know, my opinion is that
the podcast became like a runaway hit
and I've gotten pretty much nothing but
positive
feedback.
Um,
so, you know, now it's a little bit
different. I don't have that defensive
mode like, oh, if people don't like it,
you know, there's already so many people
that enjoy it and I don't want to do
anything to turn people off.
But like I said, I can't be true to
myself and be true to my story if I
decide to leave the sad parts out. So,
you know, I decided I'm going to release
this
podcast. And, you know, if you guys
don't want to listen to the drama, don't
listen. Um, I hope you guys will respect
what I'm trying to do here. Something
that I've some of the feedback that I've
gotten from my podcast is that people
have told me that they feel that I'm
genuine and that they're getting to know
who I am.
And this is who I am. You know, if if
I'm not happy about something, if I'm,
you know, upset at somebody, those are
all real feelings. and how I react and
express this. This is who I am. So
that's what I want to do. I want to be
genuine. I want to be true to my
story. And I I hope you guys will will
listen to it and not think that I'm
bringing down the channel or my show too
much because I kind of feel like it's
what I got to do. And It's unfortunate.
I've known Jason since
1993 and he means a lot to me still even
with all this. Um, you know, something
that I tell my kids, it's only people
that you care about that can hurt you,
right? So, if somebody was talking [ __ ]
if somebody wronged me and I don't care
about them, then it doesn't affect me.
But when you care about somebody the way
I do for VA skunk and they hurt you,
then it hurts much more. And and that's
just the reality. And so I'm going to
tell this story. I hope you guys um will
appreciate it for what it is. I made
this channel to tell my story and I
haven't had a chance to do it because
I've been so involved in interviewing
people like Jorge Cvantes and Kevin Jri
and you know all the great people that
we got to interview. But I am going to
try to put a little bit more effort into
telling my
story and um I'd like to say I'd
appreciate I appreciate all you guys for
all the support and I hope you'll
continue listening and supporting our
podcast. Thank you.