what's up everybody this is Gabby Staten
Island with my friends wolf and Cosmic
Charlie and we're doing the gabbing with
Gabby podcast today and I invited them
um to join because it's far more
interesting to have these guys with me
then Tamia has talked to
myself um so we're going to talk about a
few things today but I think the first
thing I want to start with is doing a
little bit of a response to the Noto dog
and crybaby podcast that's on the
future uh man I should remember future
cannabis oh man that sucks hold on you
might have project the future cannabis
project exactly see that's what I knew
there was a reason why I had wol here so
the the the the future cannabis project
to great podcast they have a bunch of
different shows that they put on there
and um one of them that they do is the
NATO dog crybaby podcast which I've been
glued to every week um and you know I
I'm really honored they mention me a lot
on the podcast and I hope that they
invite me to be on the show soon and I'm
trying to get NATO dog to do this
podcast uh you know do a podcast with me
as well because he's part of my story
but I did want to get out this response
to their latest podcast
where so NATO dog in not the last
podcast but the one before one of the
things he talks about is how he believes
the next set of Elites are going to come
from um hom grows um small farms or
accidents and you know after the podcast
I called him up and let him know that I
didn't agree with him and so the first
thing I'm going to do is I'm going to
play a video for you guys of what he
said and
um you know then I'm going to respond to
it um it was actually what crybaby
said and so here's that video Gabby
actually disagreed with me so much he
like called me up to to tell me about it
um right after the last show or whatever
but I think the next Elites are all
coming from small farms and small and
and garage siiz grows and bedroom grows
and and tent grows and stuff because
those people are going to be
specifically looking for what we want
right and it's crazy to see someone and
you know I I like Abby so like but it's
crazy to see someone who so much of what
they love is based on absolute random
[ __ ] we picked up a [ __ ] bag at
this show and it was dank and we [ __ ]
and it's all of those things
it's crazy to see someone who's just vly
[ __ ] against the idea that that would
happen again especially when there's
probably some nod to using all of these
random happen stance you know lines to
make these new [ __ ] Killers so the
thing that um I wanted to talk about was
crybaby saying and I'm going to read it
here crazy to see someone who's vly
against the idea that this could happen
again meaning that I am vehemently
against the idea that um the next Elite
strain would come
from um a hom grow or a small
farm and that's just not the way I feel
at all you know I called NATO dog and I
told him that I wasn't so sure that
that's where it would come from and you
know I'm going to talk about why in a
minute but you know I think the first
thing that I'd like to discuss before we
even go there is what is an elite strain
how do we Define an elite strain and
also what is a strain of historical um
significance so let's start with wolf
why don't you tell me uh what you what
how you would define an elite
strin yeah so I think that I'll start
off first by talking about the uh like
the history of the elite strains I guess
or what what that's meant in the past
and so I would like the first ones that
come to mind would be things like OG
kush or chem dog or um like Girl Scout
cookies or anything that kind of Hit the
market uh with a like a splash almost
like something that really made waves
with people and um like if somebody had
that when they were coming to the the
smoke sesh then they were the one that
everyone was kind of like oh they have
that they have that new stuff or that
that's something special and it's not
just you know whatever the the green
stuff was or the purple stuff was that
you would get the the No Name like it's
just you got option A or option b
typically whenever I
was um like purchasing anything back in
the
day and then uh so then what do I think
uh like the future of Elites are so
again I think that it does really come
down
to what people
[Music]
are like what people are looking for um
and I think that sometimes when people
will say like oh uh the elites
are whatever sells the most I I don't
know I I think that it's really area
dependent and it's just considering the
use of social media now and how
information can travel it's going to be
whatever has the the best almost
uh
marketing that's what's going to be the
elite because it's sad but it doesn't
matter if it yields well or if its
potency uh you know is across the board
for everyone's endoc canabo system or
even if the tur profile is crazy yeah no
it doesn't I mean like as long as it I
feel like one of the biggest things is
it has to be glamorous you know it has
to be something that's very photogenic
and
very nice to look at uh with with like
the smoking end of it kind of being
secondary almost to what looks good um
but I mean there are still there's a lot
that's that looks good and smokes good
and grows really well and for me like as
a cultivator the elites are the ones
that grow well yield well and have easy
trimming because trimming is just one of
the biggest expenses for a um like for
each pound that you produce trimming is
going to be a significant percentage
then it's going to be labor labor and
trimming are pretty much even neck to
neck in terms of the the cost per pound
and then you know organic or synthetic
after that is kind of set like tertiary
almost to the those two Front Runners in
terms of price per what your uh
production unit is so in the end I feel
like the elites are going to be the ones
that can continue with this downturned
Market to be able to make people
profitable well before I let tosmic
chime in um prior to those strains there
was Panama Red Colombian gold and and
ttic those would have never been
referred to as Elites at the time though
Elites is only something that's a
current term those would have just been
what's
available right but what made that um
and I don't want to give up too too much
of what I think but there was you know
also marketing right that stuff became
something that people heard of and and
wanted you know like everybody wanted
the Panama Red of the Colombian gold or
or the tie stick because the word got
out for sure that that's that's part of
it so go ahead Cosmic I want to hear
what you got to say as well as your
kitty he keeps attacking me so yeah if I
look off screen that's what's happening
I'm trying to sh I always kind of viewed
like the strains especially before or
you know um legalization happened you
know recreational or even medical is you
know people didn't necessarily know the
Growers or even there wasn't necessarily
any Brands around you know really what
the brand was was the strain name and I
think a driving force between you know
behind the popularity not just you know
the potency and the tpin and everything
like that but is how much profit it
could bring the grower when they um
decided to grow that particular cut
because again they were breaking a lot
of laws you know there was a lot of risk
involved and so they're not going to be
wasting any time with strains that don't
produce a lot or you know wolf as you
said are you know taking a lot of time
to trim they're labor intensive you know
you're losing a lot of weight that way
so I think that the you know um our
original strains that we know very very
well you know like white widow or bub
kush or you know any of those kind of um
Elite strains it's because they were
really profitable for the the grower to
risk you know um any kind of jail time
or any kind of um you know um anything
that happened that way so it does have
to do with you know the brand
recognition or you know the strain you
know because that's what the people know
oh you know um I want to get some AK-47
or train wreck or you know whatever it
is um but it also has to do with how
good of a cultivator it was for the
grower for sure I point wholeheartedly
with that because it's like the like
Elite is uh it has to be tied with the
capitalistic nature of the the market
like you have you can only have an elite
strain if it makes you money otherwise
it by all other metrics it's not it's
not going to meet any of the bars
required to make it Elite um if it
doesn't produce well enough for uh for
profitability yeah I I think both of you
guys make really good points
because um you know while some people
may hate to hear this you know it's kind
of what you said if a strain
isn't profitable if if if it doesn't
make Financial sense then you know
people aren't going to grow as much of
it and then it's not going to get out
there and it's you know it can never
reach that Elite status you know
something that's a little bit contrary
to this is actually the chem dog and
something that you know NATO dog does
doesn't really mention in his podcasts
is we grew a very limited amount of chem
dog and the reason why is it didn't
produce as well as the skunk you know or
other strains that we grew and you know
it's actually surprising or it it maybe
it took more time and effort for it to
reach that status of an elite strain
because not that many people got their
hands on it you know and
you
know I'm going to get to what my
definition is of of an elite strain but
one thing in Elite strain is not is what
you or I think is the best right it it's
not like well I think this strain is the
best it's elite right that is um that's
just someone's opinion right um to me
what makes a strain Elite is when it has
when there's a large market for
it and it
lasts okay it has staying power okay um
so you know for instance probably the
most elite
strain in my lifetime would be the sour
diesel okay because that strain was
grown for the longest time by the most
amount of people
okay and had the highest demand and
actually still today it has a high
demand and another thing that that I
think goes into play is for instance if
you ask random people on the street do
they know the sour diesel most people
even if they don't smoke weed they
probably have heard of the sour diesel
hem dog not so much I think run would
beat it out nowadays though
out of people that actually smoke but
yeah but the the other thing about that
is that runs is a more it's more modern
right so it's fresher in people's mind
but that was something that I was going
to move on to a little bit later is I
think while it's extremely controversial
to say this and particularly in craft
cannabis um in our group on Reddit and
uh Discord a lot of people would be
offended that that I would say this but
Lemon Cherry gelato and runs are Elite
strains they are right you know those
strains get so much hate right people
like uh you know doesn't get me high all
this weed all tastes the same because
it's a million in one crosses with
gelato and
runs it's true like and and I think it's
a big mistake that breeders are doing
today is just crossing these strains and
a lot of the Canabis is becoming very
similar but you can't deny a couple of
things number one Lemon Cherry gelato is
pretty weed photogenic you know it's
photogenic has a great nose Okay um
maybe it doesn't get me as high as other
strains like OG but for the average
consumer that [ __ ] gets them high right
and you know Lemon Cherry gelato if
you're a cult cator you can sell more
Lemon Cherry gelato or runs than
anything else that you grow okay I don't
care how fire your OG is today but you
can't sell it like you can sell packs of
Lemon Cherry gelato so your weekend
Warriors OG Kush is too strong like
exactly you know that's what I was
saying like the majority of the people
don't require something that's much more
poent you know so like I said I think
it's controversial to say but Lemon
Cherry gelato and r
those are the Elite strains of today you
know that that's what I think I I don't
think you'll find any controversy in
this in this group right here like maybe
I didn't get maybe I didn't get a wide
enough panel right because I'm not
looking for like we were talking before
the show I'm not looking to just have
people on that agree with me but um I
think there just a lot ofter of it an
opposing opinion because I feel like we
see this a lot within our the uh craft
marijuana Reddit so um people I think
hate on strains that they don't have
access to and I think that it's about a
status symbol because of how much status
matters to people in general so when you
don't have access to something that
other people have access to you feel as
though you're not you're not at that
level uh and and to grow something that
is an elite cut within the commercial
side of things is to grow something that
is like runs Lemon Cherry gelato
um God there's there's just too many now
like uh just because we talked about
those I'm think I'm blinking on so many
more but there's like so all the candy
strains but yeah any any candy strain
anything that is like a cookie strain or
anything that's like a stizzy strain or
anything that's like uh a preferred
Garden strain or something that is like
one of these larger brand names that
people can find in a dispensary but then
they go oh I want to grow at home so
what do they do they buy seeds typically
and they don't understand that the pheno
selecting process of these different
Elite cultivars requires the pheno
hunting of hundreds if not thousands of
different seeds and so they go well this
isn't what I wanted and it doesn't look
as good as that well screw those guys
they they must have some secret thing
that they're keeping from me and it's
like it's just the cultivar uh and
cultivar meaning specifically like a
tried and true tested U production crop
like um not a seed is not a cult
a a clone is a cultivar so when you when
you have people that don't have access
to these things I do feel as though
there is a little bit of stigma that's
raised where they say oh well you know I
think Girl Scout cookies has gotten the
most hate where everyone say Oh Girl
Scout cookies or cookies is it's not
it's
not but it's it got such good
recognition because if you smoked
cookies in like 2009 that was the best
cannabis you've smoked in a decade
because it was smooth and flavorful and
it wasn't crazy racy high like super
silver haze or headband or something
where you were like smoking that and you
were just not functional for part of the
day but you could like smoke it with
your friends you could be social it
tasted good it looked good and like I
don't know that that's what an elite
cult guard to me is and when when people
get frustrated at the fact that they
don't have access to it I feel like
that's when it starts to have this
uh hate towards it I don't know about
that um you know again it's good that we
don't agree on everything uh examples of
of why I don't believe or agree with
that uh one clear one would be the chem
dog right almost no one has it and I
never see any hate I've yet to see one
person say oh the chem dog is
met wasn't buil on it that that's where
the of course it was comes in an empire
was built on it not maybe not not as big
not as big as you know the the cookies
crew or jungle boys all these different
people though but that's where the it's
just those guys are
big it's hating on the big
guys succeeded in in using those Elite
cuts to be successful well I mean I kind
of agree with people saying that maybe
they're bored of the Lemon Cherry gelato
you know because there's so much stuff
that's similar um although if there was
10 different strains that were all
similar to the chem dog I'd be in heaven
right now right but I mean GMO is my
favorites me too you know I'm smoking we
were going to talk about what we're
smoking this is some GMO sauce turps
that's what I what I can what I consume
so um we want to do a little talk about
what are we smoking I don't want want to
get too far off the
subject nice what's that animal
tsunami oh
sweet um I want to
finish uh my thought process on and my
response to the NATA dog crybaby podcast
and then we can go off on as far of a
tangent as we go but I just want to make
sure I don't forget what the purpose of
of me recording this today was
so my thoughts
on why the next Elites aren't going to
come from or are less likely to I
certainly do not vehemently oppose the
idea that the next Elite could come from
a hom grower or a small breeder um
but I think you know what we had to do
and I think we begun to do it was Define
what is an elite strain and so for me an
elite strain is a strain that has a
large market demand and Lasting time
right and so you know back in the day
the only way that we got new genetics
were from these accidents or from small
briers or a seed that somebody gave them
that they had held on to for 20 years
and somehow popped you know that was the
only way new stuff happened today we
have many breeders including Cosmic and
I and I'm not sure if wolf does breeding
but um you know you know we have a lot
of people that are trying hard to make
new generics right so to me I think
that you know hard work pays off and
saying that the next Elites are all
going to come from accidents or you know
small Growers that find the seed
somewhere
I just don't think it's as likely today
because of how many people are putting
the work in the other thing is is and
and we talked about it before is how the
strains get
marketed
okay in order to get the wide market
demand okay and the lasting power you
have to have marketing behind it and
while it's
unfortunate these big
companies that's what they do I mean
cookies is a marketing company right and
you know they did a good job of
marketing and that's why you know at
least you know the original
cookies
has you know in my opinion that is um an
elite strain with historical
significance I I think that's the first
question that you have to answer when
you say when's where's the next Elite
going to come from well what is an elite
strain so I told you what it means to me
um I think Nick and Cosmic um also did
it but I asked on my Instagram page and
I also asked in our craft group and so I
want to read you some of the responses
because most of them it's exactly how I
feel so and I'm not going to read you
their handles I'm just going to read the
comments so most likely a personal
cultivator that finds something by
accident but sells early on for a big
price tag
Elite strains are Elite due to their
being passed only to the most trusted
friends Growers with the condition that
the plant does not get distributed
indiscriminately this could basically
render Elite strains defunct terms since
the market could make the equivalent of
yesterday's 10K Cuts available to at
least a th000 Growers at $10 per cut
with little to zero legal issues here it
says in my opinion true actual Elites
meaning high quality not value hype will
be
accidents um like they have always been
and then judged and held by the
community so so far we got a couple of
people that believe that small Growers
an ACD but uh this is more of what I
believe let's go here the era has come
to a close strains no longer rise to the
top due to flavor and effects they they
likely used to The Growers used to grow
what the people demanded now strains
become popular through marketing and low
cost per pound production
okay
um honestly I think the next big strains
will come from breeders who are Market
aggressive and get the hype train
rolling hard from Instagram accounts
with a lot of followers sad but
true and
then um let's
see I'm sure hobby Growers find them but
don't have the following to get them out
there then someone says I think like
that person said I think hom grow is
going to find something and he's going
to sell a cut to somebody who does have
a following and they're going to claim
it's
theirs um I've got a few bag seeds for
the win hobby Growers rule but you know
in the end I think what's going to do it
is the marketing so if a small hom
grower were to toate or find the next
Elite
strain you know probably his best path
to get it done would be to team up with
somebody that's got the marketing behind
it you know
so um
and yeah I guess I want to just finish
this by saying
discussion I'm certainly not vly opposed
to the idea that um the next uh you know
big hit in cannabis could be an accident
or something that's found by a homeg
grower or or bred by a small farm I hope
that's what happens and part of me
making this podcast um is to encourage
everyone to grow you know and I think
everyone should grow I think everyone
should save seeds I think um if people
are interested in it you know doing some
breeding you know and pheno hunting this
is all extremely personally rewarding to
the people that are doing it and I I
think it's a great idea so uh you know
to be honest I didn't like the the
way my opinion was described you know I
just felt like it made it sound like I'm
all for corporate cannabis and that I
think that corporate cannabis rules and
and they're the ones that are going to
make the best weed moving forward
and I think logically it makes sense
when you think about your average person
now especially in states where you know
uh recreational is legal you know
they're not going to going to you know
someone's cousin who has you know who
has some some nugs or something they're
going to be going and finding you know a
actual legal uh establishment to make
their purchases at and the you know the
products that they offer are coming from
those corporate cannabis you know
companies so I mean
it's it's really honestly they do have a
lot of power there because you know
they're already getting their products
out and for example when you know um the
location near me Mr Nice Guy um I I
think I went in there you know before a
flight one time and I was talking to one
of the bud tenders and I mentioned I was
going you know to a place in Oregon and
they're like oh well why don't you go
check out one of our locations there so
when you think about that you know a lot
of times those companies are going to be
dealing with the you know same
Distributors you know so if that
distributor gets you know a cut of
something then you know their ability to
get it out to a wide variety of people
and get that name recognition is
it's way more powerful than you know
just someone who's you know selling buds
out of their
house it makes me think of the idea of
marketing being exposure where if if
you're exposed to something that's the
best way to market for it and so like
yeah any any any legally compliant area
that also has uh multi-state operators
in it are going to have the best
marketing and those are already kind of
painted in black and white we know
exactly which companies those are and
exactly what sort of flower they produce
and who they Market towards and so those
are how we're going to see them like
that's that's where the elite cuts are
like it's just within within that
category but it doesn't I don't believe
that it means though that the only Elite
strains are going to come from those
companies I think they're going to be
marketed by those companies and that's
where the popularity is going to come
from but I don't think that they're the
ones that are finding them absolutely
yeah well I mean
I think there's a a good chance of
either right um I think that if you know
a small grower finds the next great
strain their best route is to take it to
um a bigger company with marketing but
like we said before there are a lot of
people out there today trying to do good
work in
breeding
and to me the idea that an accident or
somebody with far less experience you
know um with with also a lot smaller
library of
genetics is likely to produce the next
Elite I just think it's less likely when
we found the chem dog and the sour
diesel and all these other strains there
was no corporate cannabis in the United
States you know even when we were living
under 2115 it was still all you know
non-commercial in the sense of like it
wasn't a company there's you know so
right you know there there was no Brands
so
um I just think that it's naive to think
that just because a homeg grower or a
small grower cares more that they're
going to be able to do something more
than what a company with
resources you you know so and we got to
remember too all three of us are
enthusiasts you know your average person
who likes to smoke a joint every now and
then you know they're not going to be
able to keep with those names hell I
mean even someone who's in the community
it's it's tough to keep up with all
these different strains that are coming
out all the time you know so there
weren't as many strains back in the day
no there really
wasn't I mean I honestly think that the
best strains are going to come from
people with
the with the drive to want to create
something better uh or something
something different or something unique
that also then have the resources and
understanding of how to do that at a
small scale to keep it very much uh
focalized upon what their goals are and
so like someone that makes me think of
that it would be like Cosmic because you
have the ability to tissue culture all
of these different strains that you're
bringing in so that you can have a vast
genetic library and a very small
footprint with a very limited resource
draw that you can then tap into it any
time to try and pull flavor profiles out
of to incorporate into the next wave of
new genetics also with tissue culture
you have the ability to Shell pheno
hunting projects um without interrupting
other projects you can kind of just slip
in feno Hunts anywhere you want and have
the backups ready to go and ready to
call um depending on how your process
goes and it's going to be uh I feel like
any company you know or any individual
or any group that has the ability to do
tissue culture is going to be one of the
very big parts of the future of elite
genetic selection just because of the
overhead reduction because pheno hunting
at commercial scale is ridiculously
expensive and that's also one of the
reasons why I don't think that the
commercial industry actually has the
resources to produce all of the elite
genetics I think that they will find
some in the pheno Hunts that they do but
to do a 100 light feno hunt like so if
you're going to then try to sell packs
out of that to pay for the overhead of
that run you you need you need a miracle
of a buyer to be able to take that many
different looking packs um as well as
like some of it's just not going to
produce and you have to be able to have
that factored in and so you know like
the the cost of running a 100 light
facility or 100 light room for that
matter is going to be in a lot of cases
if you don't have enough to cover that
overhead you're not going to be able to
turn on the electricity the following
month it's it's that that much cost so
when a homeg grower who's a hobbyist has
the ability to feno hunt 20 or 50 seeds
at a time and do that four or five times
a year uh I mean regardless of how long
the actual total fenal hunt and
selection process takes that person's
putting in a lot more work for a lot
less money than some of these commercial
cultivators and if they have the ability
to tissue culture it on their own then
that person's a game changer in and of
themselves they can make waves by
themselves as long as they have Partners
within the commercial space that they
can then get the um their genetics into
the hands of so that it can reach a
larger um a larger
Community you know I think that
um Cosmic is kind of
like he's
the he's he's an exception to the rule
at least at least for today and the
reason for it is like you said he's
doing the tissue culture but he's still
you know working on a fairly small scale
and you know most um people will be and
you know what me including me are little
intimidated by the idea of tissue
culture you know can send it to you
it'll it'll walk you through the whole
thing I've done nodal tissue
culture I used to or no sorry marem is
the hardest Nole Nole is the hardest but
Nole is great because then you can proof
things out you can make sure that you
have clean and healthy genetics to start
with and you don't have to put a lot of
money and time into it yeah so honestly
isn't that isn't that tough you know
um the hardest part is getting equipment
because of how expensive it is yeah it's
exciting and you know you're not
gonna you know I think and you know Nick
can uh chime in I think it's just like
in any part of growing or even I know
you're a musician like you keep
learning right so like I'm never going
to stop learning about
cultivating and you know I'm never going
to you know you're never going to stop
learning about tissue culture there's
always going to be things left to learn
y right so and you know what I say is
the day you've got nothing left to learn
you know you might as well leave this
earth you know life life is pretty
boring you know for those that think
that they know everything never be the
smartest person in the
room I mean sometimes you are but it's
unfortunate yeah but don't choose to be
right exactly you don't choose to be you
know it's it's funny because like we
started this whole conversation right
talking about Elite genetics and where
those are going to come from and it
seems as though to me like the elite
genetics are going to come from groups
of people having conversations like
these because you have to be able to
have the intelligence to produce Elite
flow in order to determine if it's an
elite cultivar and so without the
ability to understand all these
different processes how are you going to
make an educated choice on your
cultivation techniques that produced
that time and time again well you know
in the past it was
accidents you know like and you know
happy accidents are great you know
people win the lottery sometimes you
know but if you're counting on winning
the lottery as as you know you're plan
to for the future that's just you know
and
yeah I believe that that finding the
next Elite strain is
work it's you know that's just the way I
see it I I see it's work
and you know I hope the next Elite
strain is what my pallet and my head
thinks is an elite strain right
but I'm different than most people you
know and you know this is something that
NATO dog was talking about and you know
since we've gone this long already I
want to make sure that I
say I love their podcast I love them I
don't think that they meant anything at
all by the way
they Mis misook my opinion on the matter
right
um I
think I think it's a great thing for
people to experiment with cannabis like
you know and to keep learning breeding
is a is a really awesome thing to do but
it it's just more work than the average
hobbyist is capable of
to search through everything to to find
that
Elite you know I
mean like I said back in the day that's
all we had you know like uh NATO dog
tells the story about how he got the
meno perss
from
he he met a cancer patient and he gave
him some
weat and the cancer patient gave him
some seeds that he had for like 20 years
or something
and um
when uh Francis grew it and show him the
showed him the weed it turned out it
wasn't even the same thing the guy
thought he was giving him turned out to
be something completely different but
um you know I think those days are just
gone like those stories I I think are
less likely
like you know unfortunately I have SE I
have seat 20 years old what' you say
what about the super boo cut I feel like
that's a great uh contemporary story
that's very similar to that so my answer
to that is I love the super boo I'm not
I don't know the story um the name is
one of the worst names in cannabis
history um but I love the weed I have um
I know people that that tried growing it
on a commercial scale
here it to me it checks every box okay
Strong Nose good high looks great yields
great this strange should be an
elite people hate it out here nobody
likes because it blew up it just went
everywhere tur profile oops every yeah
you know they don't like the tur profile
I love it because I want different stuff
right I want you know I want to like I
want to experience a new flavor like
that every day you
know part of the reason why we like the
chem dog is cuz it was
different right super boo that shit's
different and I love it but the people
that I know that that grew it out here
they had to stop and they had to start
growing runs again because they can't
sell it it's like tell the story about
it tell the story about it oh okay so
right it's um the guy that bred it is
called Blockhead Buds and it's a um like
it's a single cultivar of the block
Berry breeding project that he made and
he gave the seeds to mobile J if you
know who mobile J is and he um so he's
just a really popular Michigan grower I
believe and he popped them thinking that
they were going to be boof because of
the cross that went into it I think it
has like um it's like Tropicana cookies
and uh I forget the other one um but of
course at the time with Calo being all
played out and orange turps just kind of
not really being a big seller and most
of the orange turp uh cannabis coming
out like green and kind of fluffy
looking kind of like old CIO would look
like then he just was like well this is
going to be super boof and so he grew it
out and it ended up being the like
heaviest yielder he's seen in a while
and czy the hit the markets well and
then um everyone started wanting to grow
super boof and it's funny because like
the actual breeder cut of blockberry is
way better and um even even the crosses
off of that now are just like they're so
much better than what the super boof is
but it it like the super boof because of
the timing on it all and um how it hit
the market it kind of almost uh it it
became so popular that it became a
problem well I it never actually became
that popular over here in
California um no but it was a Nationwide
popularity thing so it was like uh it it
was just being grown in every state as
it was coming online because it was uh a
tested yielder that could use the Athena
program so anybody that was coming
online could just uh know how to feed it
plug and play and and hit you know just
just plug in 3.0 EC follow their
parameters out of the handbook that was
just released and hit three three a
light no problem it was just easy easy
plug and playay I told my buddy I still
think he should grow it
and the reason why is because he yielded
so much more than the runs that even if
he took a lower price for the herb he
still comes out on top the thing is is
on top of taking a lower price it was
still harder to sell for sure you know
coming back to the eliteness of runs you
know like I mean I wish the elite [ __ ]
today was OG cuz this old guy this is
what I like to smoke right so like I
can't you know even with people that
have the genetics they don't want to
grow it because you know you get a lower
price and harder to
sell you know so in in the right Market
it no longer becomes about grams per
square foot yield it becomes about
dollars per square foot purchased pretty
much in every in every market right but
a lot of people don't think that way
they think oh I can produce 3 lbs of
light and it's like yeah but if you're
producing 3 lbs of light and you either
have to sit on it or sell it low and if
you can do two pounds of light sell it
all and sell it high then it if you're
moving that product then you're doing a
lot better I'm glad that you brought
this up
because leads me back to like some old
thoughts of mine like so back in the day
there was a time when we had the chem
dog and we had the skunk
right and we would always grow at least
three4 of our garden in the skunk and
then a quarter of the garden the chem
dog and the chem dog would be for us to
smoke and it would also be like to share
amongst our close
friends but we never sold it on a
commercial level you know
and you know at least not till it passed
my hands and VA skunk's hands when
um you know it got to some of the you
know guys that were like selling it at
the dispensaries and stuff like that
like Ben um trying to remember IC
Collective okay Ben started selling the
stuff like more you know on a mass scale
but prior to that I felt like nobody
even really knew what the chem dog was
besides a small group of people because
we didn't sell it you know and that's
that's why it's so interesting that it
actually made that Elite status and I
guess in thinking about this the person
that's really responsible for this and I
should ask him to come and talk with me
with us is Ben from IC
Collective because he was the first
person to bring it to
dispensaries you know and and to really
get it out there you know prior to that
it was headstash weed so but my point
was
was the how much Financial sense it
made was a
decision even back in the day when we
were getting you know over 6,000 a
pound that's czy you know so
like yeah I mean I can tell stories
about that but I had a very small
grow okay but was getting over 6,000 a
pound so it makes it easy you know but
even then it's like we have to grow the
sour because not sour the skunk because
it gives us so much more you know and
so you know there's a lot of hate about
like growing you know like choosing
strains like the Lemon Cherry gelato
because of like the financial sense that
it makes to do it right but that
was a factor even back then
so today there's way more people that
are just growing for
themselves that you know they don't have
to make the decisions on the financial
aspects of
it okay you know they have their 4x4
tent they don't sell the weed they grow
it they smoke it they give some of it
away if there's stuff left over they
throw it in the trash they don't even
[ __ ] care right those those people
are growing because they love
cannabis and you
know it's funny because somebody asked
me what the best clone I
had you know you know to for them to
grow and I asked them if you know they
need to if this is a financial matter or
if um it's just for them personally and
he says it's just for me it's for the
love of the plant I said well now you
made it impossible for me to answer your
question right because now it's personal
preference it's all subjective right how
how can I tell you what you're going to
like the you tell me what you like the
best right and you know but
um and I love that you know and I think
that there's so many more people today
that are growing you know small gardens
for their personal or For the Love of
the plant um I think that's awesome and
I also think that that's why maybe NATO
dog and crybaby think that like these
guys can be responsible for the next big
thing you know um I think I said it
before there's a there's a good chance
that it comes from something like that
but you still got to team up with a
bigger company to Market it if if it's
going to be something that's
remembered you know for a long
time
so any I um sorry I was looking up a
quote really quick because this made me
think of something and uh I thought the
rest of your life was calling no so it's
a it's a Margaret me quote that says
never doubt that a small group of
thoughtful committed citizens can change
the world indeed it's the only thing
that has ever done so so that's why kind
of I think that like these small
dedicated hom Growers home breeders
people that just have a love for the
plant they're going to be the ones that
that make the selection they might not
bring it to Market but I think that
that's going to be at least 90% of who
make the Selections in terms of what is
the next big thing to come to Market see
so you almost agree with NATO
dog you think that's where it's gonna
come from it's always come from that
there name one strain that came from a
large group that they hunted themselves
name one
well the answer that I was going to give
doesn't fit that completely but to me
it's still valid is the Girl Scout
cookies right like that clone wasn't
found by them but it was found by [ __ ]
right in his garage in San Francisco one
person one garage one grow but when
people think about it in the end it took
it took cookies to make that an elite
right but that that's not the that's not
the question right the question is who's
finding the strain it's not who's
bringing it to Market mhm
well yeah I mean to me I I kind of
considered them both and now so let's
say given
that okay now we're going to get back in
into debating the original topic
so yes there is a good chance that
someone like Cosmic here is g to find
the next um
the next great strain he's going to make
the next great strain or or find it from
a hunt
but like how many seeds or clones you
know can heo hunt
versus somebody larger that has like
like Capital behind doing this you know
I I feel like that's where I that's kind
of where I was bringing up originally
when we were talking about it how like
the overhead to actually run aeno hunt
in a large facility is so extensive that
a small individual that has the ability
to tissue culture is going to be at a
greater Advantage because they can have
so many more strains than a small space
with a small overhead ex ex that a
commercial operator could use that same
formula as far as
efficiency you know so small operator
could still set up the tissue culture
right here um could could still set up
the tissue culture and do it efficiently
and so you described like a um you know
a
large uh pheno hunt right but whether
it's a large or small company they could
do a smaller feno hunt more
often okay and still get some type of
results from that right so
but you know they you know I would think
it would be a a good thing for Farms to
say I'm going to dedicate this amount of
space for R&amp;D you know we're going to
test out as many strains as we can okay
so that we know what we're going to put
into the larger future rooms and
absolutely yeah and you have to do that
and Factor it in ahead of time because
people that are just like oh we need to
do a feno hunt right now because we got
to get something new in the market those
are the people that are like their their
next quarter is riding on that feno hunt
in order to gain a higher pack price to
recoup the loss that they're running
during that feno hunt because they are
selling a pound here and a pound there
because they're only producing a pound
or less per strain that they're hunting
and even within that you have to you
know cherry-pick the different uh the
different flower that's going into the
packs one thing that can simply be done
is is it can be turn into fresh
frozen you know I mean you're you're
talking about then still margins that
are so so close at a commercial scale
when you're when you're talking about
the actual like total kilowatt hour
usage per run versus how much you can
gain for concentrate that's and it's
limited because then you also have to
have someone that you can sell it to for
concentrate that's because you're
probably doing this offseason when most
of the concentrate operators are running
right now like uh in in the fall uh as
every as the Harvest is completed for
outdoor so you there's a lot to think
about there and and
you do have to find an outlet for the
product otherwise it is going to be very
very cost prohibitive yeah I
mean it it costs right if it didn't cost
everyone would do it right for sure I
just think that it's you
know I think it's beneficial to
everybody for sure you it's to say that
there's a lot of variables that go into
it but um one thing I do want to bring
up too is you know Finding you know a
very special plan it's almost like
playing the lottery and yeah the
genetics that go behind you know
whatever that you know um new strain is
you know kind of dictates the level of
you the potential of that plant if you
will but when it comes down to it
finding that really special feno it it
can be like winning the lottery and you
know you can statistically win the
lottery with just one ticket you know
like it's uh very unlikely but it's been
known to happen you know so um I always
when I do like a fenal hunt of like are
we going to win the lottery this time
are we going to find something that's
just extremely unique or are we just
going to kind of find the best
representation of both
parents doing it but yeah I mean getting
those strains out there it's there's a
lot of variables it's not just finding
plan it's what you do with it you know
finding the plant is step one it's not
the
end well I've thoroughly enjoyed this
conversation I think we should kind of
bring it to a close shortly anything
else you guys want to
add n yeah I feel real life calling to I
gotta get back to it all right yeah me
too well I really wanted to thank both
wolf and Cosmic for helping me out I
hope we can do more of this in the
future um together
because I think it's way more
interesting when when we don't all
exactly agree you know so um I know wolf
and I are going to try to do a podcast
where we discuss the benefits of organic
versus inorganic
gardening um won't tell you what side
either of us are on maybe you can figure
it out but uh but yeah we're trying to
find people on both sides of the debate
to have a a good discussion about it so
anyway thanks guys and uh we'll do this
again soon thanks all right see you guys
later see you