[Music]
what's up everybody and welcome to your
weed stories on the craft Growers
Network today we're super excited to
have what I am comfortable calling a
legend in cannabis as well his name is
DJ Short he's one of the most well-known
breeders from the US from the past so um
like I said he was responsible for the
blueberry and the flow and we're super
excited to have him on the show so
welcome
DJ hey thank you great to be here thanks
and before we started I wanted to take a
moment to acknowledge that this week we
lost skunkman
Sam and
you know
he's he's a very what is it called when
people want to choose one side or the
other polarizing polarizing figure
exactly thank you Francis he's my uh my
dictionary he's a very polarizing figure
as is Neville I think a lot of people
have felt throughout the last years that
they either have to choose one side or
the other and frankly I think that
they've both contributed tremendously to
our community and they should both be
honored and you know I I don't think now
is the time to discuss any controversies
I think that we need to all send our
best wishes to their families and you
know for a second just think about he
did make tremendous contributions to our
cannabis community and uh NATO dog you
were saying something before we started
I think uh it's a valid point that if
you want to say it again yeah I mean
well I'll do two points one I was
talking to a friend and I kind of feel
like Neville was sort of like the the
Johnny apple seed of our community right
and uh Sam skunkman and Rob Clark were
sort of like the Luther bbanks in a way
um because you know Neville was the
first person where you could just like I
mean and Gabby and I did this a ton you
could open up a catalog and there was an
order sheet and you could write down
what you wanted and you could send that
dude money and you could get seeds and
that was impossible before you had to
know someone right uh Neville was the
first person where it was like here's a
catalog right and here's an address you
know and um and so he made it very very
much easier to get
seed you know because before it was
really a who you know m you know you had
to know someone you had to know someone
in your little circle uh and Sam didn't
do that he was a bit different but he
did when he was fleeing persecution in
America he did bring an enormous amount
of genetics um that he both had worked
on and things he had gotten from his
friends over to Europe and then when
those things blended with what the
Europeans were doing that was sort of
the
foundation for all these you know like
me or Gabby or kids looking through
cataloges and being like ooh there's
there's people of a certain generation
that have all those first cataloges
almost memorized because you would sit
there and smoke a joint and read and
dream you know and uh so those guys
created a lot of
dreams and um you know I mean I think uh
you know there's uh yeah there's there's
controversy and stuff like that but I
think that I think that when somebody
passes or something like that they have
they have you know maybe they wives
children loved ones friends people that
have known them forever and we're all
flawed so it's better to focus on what
people's contributions were what the
positive things about you know people's
lives were and uh it's all easy to tear
each other down it's a lot better I
think to like lift each other
up and so that's kind of uh that's all I
have to say about the Vietnam War uh
thank but but I will say and then we
won't touch on it when I first went to
Amsterdam like you know there are beefs
in cannabis there are conflicts and I
would say that like that was one of the
oldest ones and so we weren't there we
don't have to rehash it but um we can be
a cantankerous bunch and we don't all
get along all the time you know so kind
of like Sasha our Slovenian Hobbit Sam
was a bit of a Hobbit you know he he
wasn't in the public eye and
so I think it's kind of unfair
to to even try to choose sides when most
of us don't even know a fraction of the
story you know we just know what the
people that were more vocal said from
from our perspective right basically
everybody in this room both Sam and Sam
and uh and Neville did a whole bunch to
make good genetics more accessible to a
lot more
people and they played a huge role in
that they really did I think there's no
denying that well I'll say on you know I
got my first copy of that catalog it was
a mograph
sheets right just just standard paper
sized with the list on there I think
they were what 30 bucks for 10
seeds and at the time I was I I
understood the value of the land race uh
genetics I had some friends that were
going over to Amsterdam Europe other
places and always put feelers out say
hey find me these land race but it was
right around that era that they
disappeared pretty much everything they
were selling was some cross they did
they weren't selling the bag seed per se
um collected from country of origin
so that little um
ju or what do you call it bifurcation in
the road where making our own seed as
opposed to land race kind of happened in
that
era so that's just another little little
side point to that like I said I I tried
but I wasn't interested in in other
people's work I saw the the the flaw in
that or I saw the value in in those land
races and that became the focus at the
time but they weren't selling like I
said land race uh
varieties straight from the country