ladies and gentlem two man in the
house what's up l in the house hold on
let me go outside drink a beer and hang
out with everybody what's
up what is up
Gabe my boy Gabe we know each other
since March 15 1981 we joined uh Staten
Island Jud
together do you remember that teacher
used to beat the [ __ ] out of us send it
Toca
Senda I [ __ ] remember everything I'm
crazy I can't ladies and gentlemen I
can't [ __ ] it I just want everybody
to know it took us an hour and 47
minutes and 22 seconds for me to figure
out how to wear a computer but yeah I
talk you about 1982 you know okay one
thing I want you to hold the camera up
higher that way I'm not looking up
straight up your [ __ ] nose
drink drink drink drink
drink Al righty while stew is swallowing
what I want to say is this is one of my
oldest friends and he's the first person
to give me marijuana and so he's about
to tell the story about the first time I
smoked marijuana he smoked marijuana a
couple days before me so go ahead still
yeah so
1984 um um I think it was September
member 13th I don't September 13th yes
yeah it was it was right it was right
the week after what do you call after
after uh high school anyway ladies and
gentlemen we we um two days before that
Mark sua his mother smoke pot whatever
it was you know he was attendant for I
think it was uh 16 pilter streets I
think it was Susie Milan's house holy
[ __ ] I remember everything [ __ ] crazy
um anyway ladies and gentlemen what we
did was I me and my mark I said Mark I
see you have pot he said yeah so we go
in there he SS out a little he he goes
into his mother's he goes all the way
down and he grabs his [ __ ] weed that
was a under the [ __ ] bench what what
a brown thing remember
that can you hear me I can't hear
you yeah I hear you I just put it on
mute so that there wouldn't be an echo
but hold the camera listen hold the
phone so I can see your ugly face all
right like that better you know ladies
give me a give me a pen and paper this
[ __ ]
I I can't stand the future I like give
me a pen and paper I like it better it's
actually the present it's not the future
it's the present yeah but it's not me
I'm all about I'm I'm I'm about 1975
that's what I like also just so you know
guys bro we smoked weed in 1985 or 84
1984 September 13th don't
13th tell so I smoke yeah Mark was more
about me he goes on the thing you know
he was about he was he was nice yeah was
okay he was about 5'7 313 lbs um anyway
I don't know why I'm bringing that but
yeah I'm giving you the whole story so
he smoke pot and I'm
like yeah it's all right so I see this
this guy Gabe Gabe had like this
curliest hair you know like Wy here no
Gabe was all about Bo Gabe was like a
Bobby doll you know you know that's what
you are you you're like a Bobby doll you
you all about looking great for the
girls I didn't give a [ __ ] you know you
all about looking good and stuffff like
that so I say to him now I did September
13th September 15th I see Gabe I said
Gabe I spoke pot you did not spoke pot I
said yeah I spoke pot he goes you did
not spoke pot I said yeah I did so
anyway I said you want to try it
because yeah I didn't realize I would
start a [ __ ] guy be the pothead of
America you
know anyway so we go in there goes are
you telling
yeah we spoke by by commercial weed
ladies and gentlemen and let me tell you
how terrible it was and Gabe now is an
expert in that stuff he knows how good
it is to me you know whatever we did
stuff so I go in there and and we stole
the weed from Mark SAS ma right right
right he goes into the uh the drawers
and he grabs his stuff and then we smoke
and that smoking and Gabe's like we're
really doing it man let me see your face
bro we're really doing it man and like
I'm like you know there's good but and
he's like really we really we really Hi
man I don't remember you got so excit
you were more excited than me about it
because I was always drunk to be honest
ladies and gentlemen I was drinking for
eight years old in fact here's even
another story um during a Super
Bowl we his mother wanted me to hang out
with him Super Bowl I wanted to hang out
with my brothers because even though I
was it
was yeah I was drinking so his mother
kept his mother goes why do you want to
go to hang out with us hey he want come
at me I want to hang my brother cuz I
want potatoes I want potato chips and
pretzels no man I want to drink [ __ ]
whiskey at 11 years old you know what I
mean so but we go in there and Gabe is
Gabe smoking next thing I know [ __ ]
Gabe I don't know if you remember this
you enjoying yourself like I'm smoking
gab has pinky up man this is the
greatest thing
ever remember that whole thing you and
I'm like this [ __ ] he really
likes this [ __ ] and by the way it's
commercial weed you remember that [ __ ]
and then was bad do you remember I mean
now I know it should do you remember
this is a great story too not great
story quick thing do you remember how
excited it was that you thought you
discovered America like you Christopher
Columbus you said Ste you know what I
got today so what I got chocolate Bole
weed remember that so we smoke it and
you like loving it I'm like there's a
[ __ ] difference and you're like man
it's so good it's good
stuff that was your thing you were
[ __ ] pothead you loved it from the
beginning you remember that and and
you're the one responsible for all of
this yes I am oh also let me tell you
another story
so I wasn't big smoker was like he was
but then gave is do you mind me doing
this or no no go ahead say anything you
want all right all right so here's the
thing so now we're in high school we're
in the old days guys you could smoke
cigarettes outside in the courtyard so
apparently you know gabes to me let's
get some pot so I I go over and stuffff
like that get some pot um trying to get
it for especially gab gab I'm a drinker
he's a pot the same thing whatever but
um
apparently next thing noge goes no Ste I
really can't hang out with you we got to
do it quietly I said what do you mean um
the the vice Dean or something like that
uh caught you I said what are you
talking about caught you my mom doesn't
want to hang out want me to hang out
with you you're a big poad I a pothead I
don't a small
pot [ __ ] guy you were getting it from
me yeah and and I got in trouble for
your mother and your mother said my my
mother she even said to my mother one
day at that time CU my mother goes to me
goes too what's going on with the drugs
said m i you I said I'm a trick I ad met
I'm drinking he's the [ __ ] pothead
not me you remember that got in
trouble but here's the thing I I want to
tell the story has nothing to do with
that because it's the funniest Story of
My Life and gentlemen not funny story I
have a lot of crazy story so um my
nephew comes over so I'm not really a
pothead but every once in a while I want
Edibles so my father dies you know
whatever my nephew starts hanging out
with us at the house so one night I said
to him you know I want to do an edible I
don't want to go in my room I want to
hang out downstairs in the big house my
mother's all the way outside I want to
hang out 80 80 in TV relax whatever it
was right so anyway apparently
this my big word by the way apparently
um um we're out downstairs and the glass
table the glass table lands on top of me
my nephew stupidly cuz he just goes
upstairs leaves me alone he promis me he
stay with me leaves me alone so
apparently lands on top of me all a
sudden this 249 year year old woman
comes downstairs runs down I don't know
why she she hears everything she doesn't
sleep anyway she hears everything she
comes downstairs she goes still
St man I call myself that lands on top
of me uh the glass table lands on top of
me all the time she goes why is that
stop how is yeah I want to know what
your mom wants to know how is a glass
table on top of you it's one thing to
fall on top of the glass table but how
is the table on top of you because I'm a
silly duck I don't know what the [ __ ]
somehow I was sitting down the glass you
know the glass on the table you know how
sometimes it tilts somehow it lands at
top of me and somehow there 24 49y old
woman hears it she comes downstairs
Maring like a [ __ ] and she goes
Ste so what she
goes what happened why is the glass tee
on top of you and then she looks at me
and she goes and why are you naked I
said so I'm naked now on this edible and
she goes you didn't even realize it yeah
I didn't realize she goes why are you
naked and then my nephew says to me the
next day he go funny as hell he goes you
know what you said is what he say he
goes Mom I'm I'm not naked as I put my
shoulders up like big shot I'm in my new
suit can you imagine tell you 249 year
old woman this now listen one thing this
is your mother so don't be disrespectful
and calling her a [ __ ] because
she's a father she's a yeah you said
she's a [ __ ] no I said me the
[ __ ] listen I'm I'm drunk but
she's she's a fatherfucker not a
[ __ ] right but what I'm saying
is is how funny that she goes why are
you naked I go mom and I put myself up
like I'm in my new
suit I'm telling you ladies and
gentlemen if you want to see the best
reality show me and my mother would be
the funniest character in the
world all right I'm gonna stop this hold
on a second I love you st is did is good