what's up everybody this is Gabby Staten
Island coming to you from beautiful Sona
County California and I wanted to talk
to you about some an exciting
announcement that I'm going to make at
least it's exciting for me and I hope
you guys are excited about it too or get
excited about it um so as many of you
know I've been doing some podcasting on
the craft Growers Network it actually
all started off on I made a channel
called Gabby Staten Island where I
wanted a place to tell my story and then
I realized that I want a place where
many people can tell their story not
just my story you know while a lot of
people want to tell their story there's
a lot of people that don't realize how
interesting their story is and how much
people would enjoy and benefit from
their stories perfect example is Sasha
from Slovenia he sent a comment on one
of my
Instagram uh posts and you know I
started talking with him and then the
conversation went to man you really need
to tell your story and at first he was
surprised he didn't think people would
be interested in his story but you know
the response has been
tremendous and so I think we've proven
that you know there's a lot of people
that don't know that they should tell
their story and I hope we can convince
them to do it here I've talked to a few
small hom Growers and asked them if they
wanted to tell their story on our
Channel and the response is always like
well I just have this one tent why would
anyone want to hear from me and what
I'll tell you is is that if somebody
posts a video of their hom grow that's
going to inspire more people to grow
than if we post a video of a giant
corporate cannabis farm right because
when they see your tent with four plants
growing in it they say to themselves man
maybe this is something that I can do
you know it makes it more
approachable so yeah I definitely think
that homeg Growers
can Inspire more people to grow and so
we want to hear your stories and you
know we want to hear everyone's Stories
We want you to tell us how uh cannabis
is a part of your life and um if you
grow how you
grow so yeah that's my idea and we're
going to give everybody a place to do it
here um what you're going to need to do
is you're going to need to have some
type of um online service like Dropbox
or Google Drive where you can um put the
videos and send it to me because you
can't email me a 5-minute
video and yeah just try to have your
garden clean um maybe think about what
you're going to say um for a few minutes
before you post the video but um don't
be too intimidated by it and don't think
people won't be interested and you know
one thing I'll tell you is that like for
instance if a small grower were to make
a video and post it to YouTube you know
probably no one would see it very few
people people but our Channel we already
have thousands of views on all of our
videos and so by giving us a video that
we can post you're instantly going to
expose it to thousands of people and I
hope that this idea becomes catchy and
you know this is a place where like I
said before we can inspire people to
grow and share their stories anyway let
me know in the comments what you think
and um if you have any questions you can
you know put them in the comments or
send me a PM and please follow us and
subscribe on Instagram and YouTube and
help our Channel grow