[Music]
hello and welcome to another episode of
The Way We Grow podcast today our guest
is Autumn or at autum grows drow on
Instagram uh she is a home grower and a
commercial uh
cultivator um I'm your host Nick wolf or
Mr Wolf grows on Instagram in Reddit and
so autumn how are you doing today what's
new in your grow world I'm doing pretty
well thanks for having me here by the
way
um I'm excited to talk and um yeah I
just started a new soil grow um when I
first learned I learned doing Rock wol
so now I'm learning soil it's pretty
interesting cool and what type of soil
are you using in
it um it's Pete Moss perlite and it's
actually my co-workers kind of like
setup um okay like their Blend or
something exactly yeah um okay cool I
can look for it he definitely sent it
over to
me so it sounds like you're using like
sort of like a living soil setup or
something with a is it like a water only
system for that
or no um I'm using nutrients as
well oh okay yeah cool just using a
different substrate rather than uh than
uh rock wall
yes yeah Co cool awesome well um I'll
just get right into some of these
questions um so what was your first
experience growing did you um did you
start uh growing other plants before you
uh started growing
cannabis um so I kind of go back to like
high school or middle school when you
learned in science class to grow a seed
in a bag with the paper you know um I
did that but I never did it at home so
my first grow actually was Cannabis over
a year ago oh nice and um it actually it
led me to growing vegetables and
fruits now so I grow
both nice yeah we uh we like to say that
cannabis is the gateway drug to
gardening um you it feels like if uh if
you weren't um growing vegetables or
fruit or anything like that before you
all of a sudden get interested because
you see how fast and vigorous like a
cannabis plant can grow and you're like
oh I can do other things now and uh
abolutely it just leads you into the
garden as as a whole yeah that's awesome
um so what uh what got you into growing
cannabis then did you um I mean were you
a a user beforehand were you just
interested in it like what got you into
it so it starts back in high school um I
actually sold cannabis in high school I
was kind of like your high school plug
per se um okay yeah so um I started off
with that and then um La last year I
started smoking jungle boys flow and I
really liked it I enjoyed the taste I
was curious to how they grow it so I
started watching videos on YouTube and I
was like I need to do this myself um
I've always wanted to grow at home but I
never had like the uh equipment or room
so finally last year I had everything
ready to go um I was luckily able to
finance equipment through
Amazon so it made it a lot easier for me
to start and just get equipment um
through the stages than getting
everything at once and uh it was just it
was hard financially to get started so
having that Finance helped a
lot okay cool and so is that just kind
of like a payment plan thing where you
get to like uh like pay it off over time
kind of absolutely yeah it's uh through
Amazon it's called a
firm and you can pick um your APR and
what you want to do for your um payment
plan um so it's really affordable that
way to
start okay um well I didn't even know
that that was like a thing that but
that's really cool um I mean it it does
help people get into it uh if they can't
necessarily like cuz it it is really
expensive to get into it especially like
some of the lights and even uh the
different nutrients and if you have if
you want different like control
equipment or um monitoring equipment
that can get start to get really pricey
really quick oh yeah and as a home
grower just wanting to get into it I
could understand not necessarily having
all those funds around I think I I put
mine together slowly but surely as well
where it was like I think I started in I
I built a tent out of just like um some
spare Lumber that was around and uh like
moving blankets and myar blankets on the
inside for like the reflective surface
and then a like I I found like a $100
LED light on Amazon I think it was like
5 years ago or five and a half years ago
now and it was kind of a piece of crap
but it still worked and I still got I
grew ruts and it was awesome nice turned
out really nice was that when you first
started growing at
home that's like when I first started
growing uh where I was like really
putting effort into trying to learn
about how to
um like best grow cannabis cuz before
that uh my partner and I had like had
some plants grow at one apartment that
we lived at and we had uh you know
always been users and before that my my
dad grew and I like had one plant I
think in high school or something it was
uh but in earnest it was only like 5
years ago
okay yeah um but okay so let's see you
evolved pretty quickly in 5
years I a lot of reading and a lot of uh
time on like forums and listening to
videos and more reading um and and then
applying those practices as as much as I
could so I I tried to immediate get into
like the commercial space and from there
it was just kind of uh every place that
I worked at I learned something new and
I was able to apply it and uh when I had
a home grow it was
um yeah it was all applied at home so I
could kind of reaffirm the actions
rather than just seeing how other people
did it um I could understand sort of the
processes behind it but um yeah I feel
like in a a lot there's so much
accessible information nowadays that
it's easy to learn a lot in a short
amount of time if you um if it's like
not only your hobby but you put your
professional time into it as well as I'm
sure you know like so
um back back to back to your story so
you um you know you you started growing
at home uh just a little over a year ago
and um uh tell us kind of your process
of how you figured out how you wanted to
grow and then um the processes you used
cuz you were pretty successful ear early
on i' I've been kind of following your
story since you started on Instagram
when you were first um helping manage
someone else's cannabis account so let's
uh like talk about a little of uh like
where your processes came from so it did
start when I started smoking jungle boys
flour um that's when I started really
researching like the Athena nutrients
line which is what I use and using rock
wool um I kind of CAU copied what jungle
boys
does um I first started off with the 4in
cubes and um when I met my mentor Matt
um which I found him off YouTube
searching Rock Roll grow um his were
really um he just had a lot of
information and more like scienti
scientific
facts and I liked that about his page so
I actually reached out to him and said
hey could you help me uh grow uh it's my
I'm on my first grow I'm growing in 4in
cubes using
Athena um could you help me from start
to finish and he was more than willing
to help me um he would call me email me
text me just tell me everything that he
knows and I listened to everything he
told me and I was successful that way um
I believe growing
in general that it's important to have
help in other
resources yeah absolutely so what what
were some of the um like the first
methods that you were told would work
for you and like uh when you said that
you followed the the Athena method or
the jungle boys method are are you
referring to kind of like their their
handbook and sort of what they had like
described about in there and then um
yeah what like how did you how did you
go about that first grow
so I actually they have a YouTube video
on how to grow and how they do it so I
kind of just rewinded it and just paused
and and just wrote down everything list
by list like what do I need to start um
and then uh when I went to a hydroponic
store my first time I bought Athena
products there and they gave me a free
handbook when I bought Athena and um oh
that's cool I started learning more
through the handbook yeah
okay um so what do you think since since
you have been growing for uh you know a
somewhat shorter amount of time and it
seems as though you've made uh
significant changes in your grow from
like each of your grows uh how how do
you feel like those changes have gone
and sort of what has been like the
things that you've learned from those
different uh
changes so I feel like each grow I
advance and I just learn more and more
um in general even with my
setups um right now I don't have a
proper drainage system for my plants but
uh I make it work I have little caddies
they sit on and they have drainage trays
so I have to manually uh drain out the
trays and I get a lot of floods because
of that but luckily they're up
above they're up above and I've learned
uh throughout growing of how many
irrigation shots that I should be giving
my plants so that way I don't get so
much
runoff um okay and these words that I'm
using I would have never used in my very
first grow like I I would have no idea
to say irrigation shots and runoff it's
just stuff like kind of words you just
learn over time okay yeah for sure I
mean it I feel like it it is a really
um there there's so much spe
specifically within like the commercial
or the cultivation culture of cannabis
where um we have these terms that we've
created as a community over like however
many decades of growing and even some of
those terms have changed and evolved
over time but a lot of it was because it
was almost like you had to talk about it
this way um because it was illegal and
you didn't want people to know exactly
what you were talking about but even now
there seems to be a lot of like not
necessarily proprietary but it it feels
like uh like a lot of it is just
um very unique to cannabis and to to
cannabis cultivation shots might not be
I don't I don't know if that's referred
to in other forms of like Horticulture
or agriculture where they use um drip
emitters and cuz like there's some
tomatoes that are grown on rock wool and
there's a lot of other crops grown on
rockwool and hydroponic systems and
stuff like that but um yeah it's very
it's a great point where like a lot of
people hear this stuff uh if they're
trying to get into cultivation and they
don't really understand these different
terms
um what do you think was one of like the
the other than the terminology what do
you think was one of the biggest
learning curves you had like getting
into growing um like what were some of
the things that you were found to need
the most of your attention when when
learning about
it um I think it's really important to
know each stage for sure um and know
when your plants are ready to switch um
and it's really important to have a
handbook or some kind of uh
dosage uh for your
nutrients um I feel like that helps uh
protect you from any deficiencies if you
have something to look at and measure by
uh I believe that's really important
and um also like learning the steps that
you need to do for each stage um my when
I first
grew uh I didn't really realize there
was all these steps that you needed to
do at a certain day or
week um now that I am in a commercial
setting I have learned more of like for
instance day 10 is the day that we like
to skirt our plants or
lollipop um okay some other might think
you know differently or do things
differently that's fine but I've just
learned throughout you know growing that
there's a bunch of different times and
certain days that you should do things
to not stress your plants out and to
have a better grow yeah that's very true
and I feel like so much of it is
somewhat subjective um like for me I I
don't like to do any of the skirting
until the um the plants have finished
stretching and like finished their
flower set
I agree I think you know depending on
the different the like depending on the
setup it could uh it could be beneficial
um cuz I know one thing I've seen when
pruning early in the stretch is you get
a little bit of a a vegetative response
so like the plants will um sometimes get
a little bit taller than they might
otherwise um so if you have a large
space or if you have a canopy that needs
to be filled up still that might be
beneficial but if you have a smaller
space or a lower ceiling height or
something then you really want to make
sure that you're just getting the plants
to stretch as much as they will based on
your irrigation practices or the the
genetic potential of the plant or
otherwise and um and that way when you
prune they kind of just stay right where
they are already that makes a lot of
sense cuz this grow I listen to what my
bosses say and skirt at day 10 and uh I
have some sativas this is my first time
growing sativas so it's pretty fun and I
was expecting really tall plants but my
Strawberry Cough ended up being really
short and that's it could be because I
skirted too
early you know and um I I think also
some of the genetics like uh when they
when they say like sativa or Inda it can
sometimes be a little misleading cuz um
it's like some sativas now are so far
bred away from where they were that's
it's sometimes like the the effects that
are described as sativa versus the
growth pattern um because uh I I usually
like to describe it as like equatorial
versus um
uh I forget the other one but basically
like if it's near the equator versus
every uh latitude that it goes up um and
gets further away from the equator I
feel like they get squatter and squatter
um just based on the the lighting cycles
and stuff but um yeah sometimes I feel
like that might be a little bit bit
misleading with in terms of what you
would assume the structure to be as a
grower um when someone says the tee are
indicia
um so uh let's talk then about like what
your current grow right now so um why
don't you go over sort of what you're
doing for your uh hydroponic setup and
then what you're doing for your um with
the rock wool and then how it differs
from what you're doing with the uh the
potting mix based
grow so in my experience right now I
want to say Hydroponics is easier um
it's just less headache uh even with
nutrients uh I use three different
nutrients core um bloom and grow just
three things and then with the soil I'm
using like 8 to 10 different things and
it just kind of feels like I'm more like
a scientist in soil growing but but I
feel like it's it takes more time to you
know measure everything out you know get
everything precise and and for my
hydroponic grow it's super quick I can
whale out everything super fast and have
my reservoir ready in like 10 minutes
but it took me like half an hour just to
do four gallons for my soil
grow uh just adding all the little you
know things
nutrients when when you're doing when
you're using the um Athena for your
Hydroponics are you using the Athena
Proline yes okay cool yeah that
three-part fertilizers are really easy I
love it um it it does make life really
easy um and then
so when you're doing the um Athena uh
are you running like any uh like
supplemental CO2 anything else and then
like what are you running your EC at and
kind of what are some of the targets
that you shoot for um cuz a lot of your
grows do look really nice and for
someone that has only been growing for a
little over a year it's it's really
great to see people that have success
because it shows that other people can
do this too at at home without you know
if they enjoy smoking cannabis or if
they enjoy consuming it and they uh
don't want to keep spending the money
but they also enjoy like the hobby of
gardening I feel like it's really
important to uh for people to see that
they can and be successful in their
grows at home early on oh yeah it's very
doable for sure but I think uh having a
mentor definitely helped me learn things
a lot quicker understand things better
um if I didn't have someone to guide me
I probably would be a little held back
and maybe not know as much as I do now
for sure um I was running
CO2 and it's kind of kind of uh
expensive to be honest uh I was running
through it like every week a 25 lb tank
and I was spending $45 every week on it
and it just became too expensive um I
didn't notice a huge difference not
having
it but it did hurt me because when I ran
out I didn't have an exhaust in one of
my grows and I experienced some mold
problems
um and I lost probably like I don't know
I I yielded one and a half pounds and
I've could have gotten like at least 2
lbs so I feel like that hurt me a little
bit and set me
back um but instead of running CO2 I got
an exhaust and hopefully no mold this
time cool yeah I mean definitely if
you're if you're running CO2 in a tent
and it's uh it's really hard if you're
um especially if you're like getting
into the beginning of summer or
something along those lines where the it
everything starts to heat up and you
have all that transpiration um yeah it
it it becomes really hard to mitigate
mold if you're not exhausting that that
extra humidity um and and usually I find
like especially with tent grows uh that
exhaust is so important that CO2 can
sometimes you know you do run into like
where you're just running through it so
quickly or the fact that the tents are
usually you know mesh and they're
semi-permeable you have a little bit of
loss through the zippers and and the
different ducks and whatnot um so it
does it it does become a little bit like
hard to to keep up with the cost of it
even if it does get you a little bit
more uh like chunky chunky flowers at
the end of it um so I get that I've
always wanted to run CO2 at home but I
feel like you do have
to you would have to then like have this
whole setup and uh was something that I
never was able to do yeah yeah you need
like uh air conditioning and you need um
definitely dehumidification and all
these different things and all that adds
on to your electrical cost yeah so I
don't think it's that important uh even
though if you look at videos on YouTube
they're always like oh use CO2 it's
going to help your yield and it might
but it's going to cost you a lot more
yeah absolutely like in a commercial
space where you have the ability to uh
air condition and and um control
humidity and and other environmental
factors then it it almost uh would make
uh it would make less sense to not run
it you you almost have to run it in
order for the all the equipment to run
it Peak Performance um and and for you
to increase your yields by by that
amount you know I I always think
like it's not like you get like this uh
this double return though or like you if
you can add CO2 and then Peak every like
all the other uh parameters out like
your ppfd and your temperature and
humidity and uh the differentials uh for
all the different settings for day and
night and whatnot I just you still
probably won't double your output um if
you add CO2 but if if you're able to get
everywhere everything else to that point
then it seems like it's still worth it
no matter what um but yeah not not
necessarily in a home grow that's that's
a a totally different situation
that's what my my mentor taught me to do
cuz he does that at his home grows but
he has an open space so it makes it a
lot better to use if you have an open
space I
believe like a like a room or something
that he has like sealed off or something
exactly like you were saying with the
tents it's just not
it so yeah yeah I I wouldn't use CO2
again unless I have open space or a
bigger grow going on
but it was fun to learn fair
enough yeah absolutely it's it's it
doesn't hurt you know it makes me think
of those like
uh those exhaust bags or I forget what
they're called but they're basically
like a a mushroom block that you can wet
down and hang inside the grow and it cuz
mushrooms produce CO2 so you're all just
making making CO2 with mushrooms but
what's funny is I bought one of those
bags I bought one of those bags and then
my mentor was like just get a tank and I
returned the bag i' never even used it
um oh I don't know how much they
actually produce um because I've I've
seen people where I think at one point
on uh like the build-a soil uh YouTube
channel he had his 10x10 tent uh being
and he exhausted into it from a mushroom
tent so it pulled all the CO2 and cooler
air into that tent and I was like that's
not a bad idea especially if you're in
like Colorado like he is and you're all
that extra humidity into the tent as
well to compensate so what a great idea
like that's that's not a bad idea yeah
right makes me want to like grow some uh
oyster mushrooms and some shiitake
mushrooms yes um I want to do that too
yeah right and I so I I had grown um
organically at one point in like a 30
gallon uh pot and used a local um like
super soil uh living living soil blend
in indor up and it um It produced so
much CO2 that like the parts per million
at the surface of the the substrate were
like 800 um and so it like made it it it
did its own thing because it had all the
uh fungal colonies in the substrate
already basically acted like a giant
mushroom block that's crazy um so that
was pretty cool that's really cool um so
yeah how much did you yield off your
plant if I can ask you remember um off
of it was one plant under in a 4x4 area
and I'm pretty I I only weighed like a
quarter of it because by the time that I
had it all all dried and done I had kind
of just like divied it up and then
realized I hadn't weighed it so I
weighed what was the remaining quarter
of it and it it was like 2.1 lb out of
that one space the one uh area and it
was under a 340 WT LED
so it was pretty good for for that
little over um 2 G per watt yeah uh and
that was pretty nice uh and it was like
one single plant too in this giant pot I
think I vegged it for like a month and a
half it was crazy wow um but it was fun
yeah um so you have uh so tell us a
little bit more then about your
hydroponic setup uh What uh like what EC
are you running and what are some of the
other targets that you usually look for
so in early veg I start off with 1.0
EC um at my
job they start off 3.0 and run it all
the way
3.0 from start to finish um but I was
taught to start at like 1.0 and then
kind of work your way up slowly to 3.0
EC um but for the run you see a
difference between those two methods
sorry sorry for a little Sidetrack but
do you see a difference between those
three two methods I do I see less stress
and uh kind of like I didn't really have
deficiency but just more stress for sure
and um I had some yellowing going on but
nothing too concerning when I was just
pushing 3.0 from the start to to end um
I like to ease up I feel like that helps
better for the plants or they like it
better that's awesome yeah definitely I
feel like I hear that a lot so it's it's
good to just have one more uh anecdotal
evidence to say so I feel like
commercially they kind of just they
start at 3.0 just to like push it and
get it you know going uh cuz commercial
is just Bam Bam fast let's get these in
and get them out you know but at home
you can have the patience and start off
slow with your EC and you know get all
the way to 3.0
um but with my EC run off and all the
plants get a little bit of extra
treatment too because you got you know
got the time to take to um to hang out
with each plant individually basically
yes and and for the runoff um I was
taught to not go over 9
EC um but I've also been taught to not
go over seven e see so I mean I've gone
over nine and
yeah I had it I had some run off EC
mhm wow and I noticed uh it was kind of
towards the end uh like around week five
or six where my runoff was that high and
it was good the colors were coming in
great but the leaves were just kind of
getting a little crispy burnt uh
tips but I mean it's part of like the
fade per se so mhm
um but right now I'm having my EC at or
EC runoff at 7 I'm trying not to go past
that and my plant seem pretty happy with
that
nice yeah you know I um I've seen EC
like yeah way in the runoff way over
nine and it was uh like it I think
sometimes it depends on the size of the
substrate as well so if you like have um
like a 4in uh Rock wo and you have a
really high EC coming out of it there's
and you're also getting a pretty big
dryback then um typically like I I think
like at the point of dryback the EC and
the substrate is going to be more than
what the runoff EC is going to be just
because of the lack of water and as the
water like goes away and any salts that
are left in there it just keeps
compounding how um how much uh salt is
felt by the roots in terms of the
osmotic stress and so if you have a
bigger um pot though
and you can have like you know if you
have 9.0 EC runoff in that but then it's
not drying back as far usually that
still means that like the the the PO
water EC isn't spiking up past uh or or
to the same point that the smaller
substrate was so I could see how like
especially in rock wall just how dry
sometimes they can get between the end
of the day and and the first irrigation
yeah you could probably get some pretty
darn High ECS in there and get a little
bit of that tip burning and stuff I
could see that did you did you find
though that um when you're getting that
little extra stress in the plants did
you feel as though the um the turpine
profile or any of the other like uh um
like secondary metabolites and tertiary
metabolites like the uh the triome
production and the cannaboid production
uh increase um because sometimes I see
like the triome production just goes
crazy when you get all these really far
dryb backs and high ECS and
sometimes uh like that you can start to
get these really pungent days where they
start to really
smell um
yes um I
noticed
like how would I say it just like more
colors coming in and yeah more
smells
um and it seemed like I was getting a
lot of moisture too in the buds and
maybe that's why I had some mold issues
too um okay when you when you say like
you were getting a lot of moisture in
the buds what do you what do you mean by
that you could just like were you seeing
stuff on the buds or no but you could
just tell like that they were wet by
when you would de like when you take off
a leaf it just seemed super like wet you
know what I mean uh than my other grow
when I when I pulled off leaves from my
other grow it was kind of more like a
dry when the leaves came off it just
like Snap off but with the high you see
the leaves felt more
wet interesting um almost like they were
a little bit more leathery or something
uh like they had a a kind of a a thicker
um like the leaf was almost thicker or
something
or um I guess when you know when you
pull a leaf off and sometimes they come
off like super
crispy and then sometimes they come off
and you you get like a little like uh I
guess they they say it's like the
plant's blood or whatever when you pull
off a leaf but I felt like I feel like
it's just the moisture kind of like okay
I I see what you're saying like almost
uh like where you break it off at water
water will come out of the plant or
something okay yeah definitely like it
has um like there's there's a high uh uh
water pressure in the in the stem yes
that's the word I'm looking for when you
when you see that H when you see that
happening do do the plants usually have
a lot of turer like where all the leaves
are kind of preying up towards the light
yes yeah okay definitely so like uh yeah
like uh the turer of the plants is
usually based on like the how much
internal water pressure is in the
vascular structure of the plant so yeah
if you pop leaves off then I've
definitely noticed that as well like
sometimes I've just been popping leaves
and I I'll get like splashes on my
glasses and I'll be like what is that
I'll wipe it but it's like plant juice
it kind of just makes my glasses all
smudged and shmeed and so I'm just like
yeah I I totally have experienced that
as well
um so okay then so uh are does that mean
then you're ramping up your grow at home
up to 3.0 EC um is that like kind of
where you where you'll you'll end at
before you and then um do you taper it
back down then from there towards the
end of the grow um yes so that's what my
my teacher taught me to do to uh just
lower your EC um every other day or so
and just kind of go by each like
point and come down to like 1.0 or
1.5
um
but I've only done that I feel like
once um the other times I've just kept
it at 3.0 till Harvest day um nice and
it was smooth it didn't taste hard harsh
um I've never flushed my plants
before I might try that this time just
by flushing it with maybe just some AR
water at the last 3
days um I just want to try different
things to see what
happens um sure if I can get a better
taste colors
smells stuff like that um I did move up
to 6 in hugos now I started off with the
4 in cubes on my first grow and
then uh my mentor told me if you want to
grow commercially you should try the 6in
cubes so I tried those and I've noticed
way bigger plants with the 6
in um and just bigger
colas for sure do you do you notice
um cuz sometimes I feel like going from
a 4 in to a 6in cube you can um you can
tend to overwater a little bit uh early
on with the 6-in cube if you're used to
watering in a 4-in cube and and the dryb
backs that a 4in will'll get um even
early on in veg um did you find that you
were getting like excess Leaf production
or longer inter nodes between the
different flower sites on the plant um
as it grew or did you feel as though it
just kind of um you didn't notice too
much of a difference in that in terms of
like how you felt as though like if it's
like generative leaning where it's like
a lot of flow production versus
vegetative leaning where it kind of has
more leafy flowers and longer internodes
and stuff like that I feel like with the
6 in it was more of a leafy intron noes
um yeah uh I just overall it's just they
seem like bigger plants in 6 in um but
maybe that's just cuz I used four my
first grow and now that I'm evolving
maybe I'm just getting bigger plants who
knows for sure I I always say that to
people when they're like uh they'll
Implement uh you know early on in their
grow career they'll add something new to
their grow or they'll change something
and they'll go oh this change made me a
better grower and I always tell them I'm
like no the fact that you you grew one
more time makes you a better grower yes
usually it's just the experience that
helps uh people get better and they're
just taking the experience from each
successive uh Harvest and applying it to
the next one and usually yeah it's uh
sometimes it's a culmination of both
though like if you if you were doing
something either to hinder yourself or
if you do Implement something that is uh
beneficial to the grow um it can be then
in conjunction with the increase in
skill as well so I yeah that's a it's a
good point
um so okay then uh I feel like that kind
of gives us a good picture of how you
grow hydroponically with your rock wool
um so tell us more about your your new
setup that you're trying out with the um
the potting soil the uh the Pete based
media so it's a little
like uh I'm kind of going at it blindly
a little because my
coworker uh has or he has this tent that
he let me borrow behind me um it's the
same one I use for my hydro grow uh
they're both gorilla tents my hydro has
the uh 4x4 and the soil grow I'm doing
is a
5x5
um with the 4x4 I'm using ion LED lights
8 20 watts and okay with the soil it's a
fluence LED lights I'm not sure how many
watts though um it's probably like 7 720
or 780 if if it's the one that I see
right behind you there m
yep
yeah cool um so as
nutrients it seems like I have
everything individually uh some are in
liquids and then some are in powdered
form uh the nitrogen is in powdered form
it's like a
soybean
base nitrogen
um and then I have phosphate carbon
silica and they're all in liquid
forms okay what brand is it that you're
using I have no
idea it there's no brand name or it's
just in random bottles like
this oh okay and this is from your
coworker
yes okay so it sounds like they make
n okay yeah so it's a little different
um interesting yeah he he said it's kind
of like a secret that someone his mentor
came up with the nutrients and
everything so he doesn't really tell me
much about it but he just tells me the
measurements yeah so I'm kind of going
at it blindly
have you taken like an EC or a pH
measurement of the um the solution that
you're
adding um no but I've uh tested my EC um
with just carbon and
nitrogen and my EC or it was PPM it was
at like
700 PPM I think that's like 0.5 EC or
something starting off
low um I think it's um depending uh some
of the ppms you know I always forget if
it's you double the PPM uh you multiply
it by a, uhhuh yeah double and then
divide by 1,000 so 700 be like 1.4 PC is
it yeah um I'm pretty sure um but uh so
is that and that's just two parts of it
and then you add all these other parts
as well yes they're like all these
little bottles separate things
um it's a lot it like a milliliter of
this a gram of this m so it's just a
bunch of little tiny things okay and
when you're watering these um are you
watering to them to runoff or are you uh
avoiding runoff with this so I'm doing
runoff um and then I'm also doing some
flushing with the soil um like once a
week
flushing um I started them off in rock W
cubes like the starter
plugs so I kind of had to do some
flushing to get the salts out and then
start with the
organic nutrients okay um yeah but it
it's a lot to have like eight different
types of nutrients going on and having
to measure like of an eighth of a
teaspoon and times that by how many
gallons I'm doing so it's kind of a
headache to be honest
but I mean I anything that was over like
however many parts always kind of I I I
like shied away from them earlier on
like at one point I think I was mixing
like 10 or 12 different parts at this
one grow I was working at and then we
we'd like mix them all and then hand
water all the plants with it and it was
it just seemed like such a hassle and
then home like it's time consuming
absolutely
um and it just you know I I never saw
anything that I was like so blown away
with that I was just like wow this is
this is the truth this is exactly how we
should be growing this plant um and then
I saw like living soil where it was just
water only and that I was just like oh
well this seems really easy um but then
re amending it started to become
something that did require
like if you wanted to do it at scale or
uh at a very like either professional or
scientific level of of of understanding
exactly what was going on so that you
could make like a fully
educated uh adjustment or um addition uh
if it's like a dry Amendment or um some
sort of tea or something you would need
to do all these like substrate uh
saturated Pace tests and then even
compare it to like sap analysis of the
plant and other things like that so that
you could understand sort of how those
uh nutrient packets were impacting the
soil and then how that was over time
translating to the plant and so you
could kind of TR like if you were doing
it consistently you could see the trends
over time of what was in the plant and
then there were some resources online
that you could see where those targets
were that you would want and you could
increase or lower than what your
nutrient package was that you were
adding to the substrate but that's
something that's like it's only
available to do that at a commercial
level because each one of those tests is
like either $100 or more and if you're
doing it weekly or monthly then that
that also it's it's like the CO2 in a
hom grow it's like that's almost it's
untenable you can't necessarily afford
that if if the if one of the ideas for
homeg growing is to grow your own
medicine um then like increasing the
price of it almost makes it in some
cases especially when you have readily
accessible cannabis in a medical or a
recreational Market sometimes it ends up
being cheaper especially with the
commercial race to the bottom um where
everyone's just trying to get as much
product sold for the lowest amount and
it sometimes doesn't even matter if it's
super high quality yeah I can agree for
sure yep well so how how are you liking
this uh
organic grow style um I mean other than
the time consuming
part um yeah I really don't like the
timec consuming part uh that is not it
for me I don't like it um but so when I
first started I cut clones off my hydr
grow and nurse them into veg and put
them in the soil and I noticed cuz I was
just using carb and carbon
um not nitrogen at first so I started
noticing yellowing and deficiencies and
I was like oh no I'm already messing up
the soil grow but uh my coworker was
just like oh just add nitrogen the
yellowing should go away quickly and I'm
like really okay so I added nitrogen the
next day I noticed the yellowing just
kind of slowly going away um but within
a day the yellowing was almost
gone um that's awesome yeah fast acting
for something that's uh like an an
organic system it makes me want to know
like what it is it sounds like almost
like a soy hydrate or something like
that where it's like a Amino based
nitrogen Source um maybe something
that's like right there readily
available that's pretty cool it kind of
sounded like what you were saying too
like with the living soil and kind of
adding like your own ingredients and
seeing how the plant reacts it's kind of
like that yep mhm yeah I could see how
it you know it's probably good for all
new Growers to use something that
requires them to pay attention to the
plants needs and um and then find a
response
appropriate uh that kind of uh addresses
those needs and so that you can see the
progress of the plant from your
additions cuz I feel like sometimes when
it's um like if you if you do
Hydroponics and you do it correctly or
if you follow directions and you're not
necessarily trying to be so easy uh yeah
like if if if you follow the directions
in the most cases they work really well
but a there's a lot of directions out
there that
are unique to the specific nutrients or
unique to a specific um environment um
and so a lot of these different recipes
are somewhat subjective because they
need to follow specific parameters but
if you like follow all the instructions
you should be good um
as as you don't try to get fancy or you
know try to be like I'm going to double
this or half this just because I want to
see what happens like sure see what
happens but it it probably um you're
going to see like what a deficiency
looks like or a toxicity looks like um
but yeah with like a organic row or
something where you do like I'm adding
this for nitrogen or this for calcium or
this for magnesium or this for potassium
phosphorus uh all the different
constituents
um I could see how that could be pretty
helpful especially if you like do it
long enough where you go okay I'm just
going to pull a bunch of phosphorus out
of the the nutrient package and let's
see what happens um so you can then like
document it almost and be like I know
that this works uh when I have the
phosphorus at X level and if I bring it
down to Y level um this is what happens
and so if you then see that happening
you can go oh I need to add more
phosphorus um I like that you put it
that
way in kind of like a learning way of
growing cuz you're adding one
component um at different times or
whatever not like how with Athena it's
all together in one so you're not going
to really have to stress about
phosphorus or silica separately or
whatever and like you're saying you
could add a bunch of phosphorus and if
the if the plant loves it then you know
okay cool it loves that check off the
list um yeah it's more like a science
experiment exactly uh yeah there's a um
I've brought it up in the last podcast
but I might as well bring it up again
but there's a uh a term uh or a theory
or a law it's called Le Big's law I
believe um but basically what it is is
uh it's kind of like the law of minimums
almost where you can only
achieve your greatest results uh based
on what is the the lowest
um uh available nutrient um in like a
growth system and so like sometimes
it'll be described as like staves in a
barrel so like a wine barrel where all
the different staves that kind of go
around the outside of the barrel are all
tightly compressed together but they're
all at the same height and so you can
fill the the wine and the barrel up to
that height but if one of those staves
is cut lower then even though all those
other levels are all the way up at the
top the wine can only fill up to where
that lowest Stave is um so it like if if
you if that's your uh if that's your
limiting factor then even if you have
all these other elements within them
grow at their Peak or at their their
uh like ideal levels um you'll never be
able to see what results that those can
truly provide if there's something else
that isn't at its uh most ideal level in
in sort of that
same specific environment that you're
providing all these things in cuz like
sometimes like more humidity in one
environment is not as good as more
humidity in another environment whether
it be like CO2 lighting heat um
absolutely uh exhaust all these
different things that can have an effect
on that yes um but but it's it's cool to
see a newer grower like yourself using
these different tools of a hydroponic
grow and then a hand mixed
painstaking organic grow because it it
it'll round you out as a grower though
be it it's it's great to see other
people doing that because I felt like
that was one of the ways that I learned
the most is uh just going to different
styles of growing almost every second
grow I would switch it up like I i' do
the first grow
it would either work or it wouldn't work
that well I'd do it again the second
time and i' usually get it to work and
then I'd go okay this is boring I'm
going to do something else switch it up
um and then I yep and then it like
started at Hydroponics and ended at
Hydroponics for me because it's so easy
uh like you you use cocoa
right yeah at work we use cocoa um have
you done Rock grow at the
facil yeah so at the facility that I
manage we've done uh cocoa and we do
Cocoa now and we have for quite some
time but um we've done Rock wal as well
where we did uh the slabs where you have
three plants per slab um on the 4in
cubes and that worked really well we've
done um where we've done uh 4in cubes
for veg uh and then we set those on top
of cocoa pots and let them roote into
the cocoa pots and um go about it that
way but there is like a a little bit of
a intense osmotic gradient between rock
wool and Coco where the Coco wants to
pull all the water out of the rock wool
so you have to provide all these little
irrigation shots early on to make sure
that it roots in correctly and usually
that keeps it a little bit too
vegetative early on and you don't get
that uh it's not as easy to build the EC
early in in flower in the substrate
makes sense um which usually we we aim
for to get that generative response of a
lot of flower sets and stuff
um yeah I just want to say it's really
cool to see um another person entering
their cannabis cultivation journey and
uh using these different methods to to
learn from yeah I like to learn all
different aspects every way you can do
it let's learn it and find the best way
to do it that's my
goal for sure at my job they
uh um they they grow uh everything in
Rockwell right um even our moms are in
Rockwell Cubes but uh just recently they
started switching over to uh Coco for
the moms um just because the six inch
hugos aren't big enough to hold those
moms and our moms were flopping over
every day and it was just a mess
and so I think now you have to if
they're that big
yeah so yeah switching over to Coco I'm
I'm I'm assuming they're liking it
better I haven't been up in veg since
they've done that but all the moms now
are in Coco no more rock wool for
them so cool Coco Coco can also be a
little bit cheaper um you can get a
little bit of a larger substrate size
for the same price as rock wol so like I
think those 6 in especially if they're
groan I think those are getting up there
in price now above like four bucks a
piece and I think you can get a like a
two gallon cocoa pot for uh like a buck
50 to two bucks a piece so um you can
get a lot more a lot more substrate out
of it and uh a lot more runtime out of
each mom um but I always personally
suggest even in uh hom grows and
Commercial spaces to keep your mom uh
lifespan to no longer than like 8 weeks
at the max I usually shoot for like
between 6 and 8 weeks sometimes they'll
go into 10 weeks but that's usually if
it's like a yeah it's usually if it's
like a
um like something that I'm needing to
keep around for genetic preservation or
something um yeah some of the larger
moms actually you know like sometimes
they'll go up to to to like uh what like
90 days um if like it's a instant a much
larger pot and if I up poot it like once
a month um
it really depends on kind of what what
time of year it is and how long we need
to keep moms around for but I like to
keep them around for as little amount of
time as possible um sometimes you just
get like fungus nap populations yes yes
we have a lot of fungus Nets and um they
have us top down the
moms every week uh there's probably
like I don't know like 30 different
strains of moms there's just a lot going
on in veg at my job for sure you guys
have around like 30 30 cultivars on your
list at any given time
yes okay they like that because it uh
that's a decent list yeah they said more
strains better because it helps uh push
product quicker than just having 10
different strains the same strains if
they have 30 different strains or more
for sure then
are they are they usually growing all
30 yeah like at any given time yeah and
they keep their moms pretty that's
impressive yeah they keep their moms all
the way till like I think the most 8
months they've kept their moms oh wow
yeah yeah those are huge uh are they I
assume then that they're in probably
like uh High Bay rooms with like um
high-intensity discharge lighting like
CMH or HPS
um I think they just use gavita bar
lights oh really yeah that's that's
pretty cool yeah awesome do they have a
pretty big growing area for each Mom oh
yeah um there's
probably I want to say like eight maybe
eight to 10 different tables of the long
tables okay and probably like like
longer than a 4x8 table
yes I think so okay like a like a custom
uh drain table is yeah exactly um okay
they're feeding like at
least like three to four different
strains per table and like uh I want to
say 10
different well the three strains three
to four strains per table and like 10
plants per
strain okay so like uh okay wow Al those
are going to be really those are big
plants like um what do they have like
two two across per like two across on on
the table yes yep okay yeah those are
big moms then that's pretty cool um yeah
we have like uh we have uh two tiers uh
on on our tables in both our like veg
and our mom room and so um but they only
have like I think 38 in and 48 in or no
46 in something like that uh that's like
the the total height from the tray to
the light so we have to like splay them
out as much as we can and keep them
really short and you have to top them
down every
week uh we try to top them down every
week yeah but we are also like a very
small team so sometimes they they'll
grow into the lights and we'll usually
just be like well those are going to get
pruned and then they're going to grow
again and they'll be okay um yeah uh I I
would love to have large High Bay
ceilings in a veg space cuz then you can
get really really big moms oh yeah
they're like
trees yeah so what made you decide to um
enter uh from just homeg growing into
the uh the cultivation
space um I really want to make this a
career so I started looking on
Craigslist zip recruiter for cultivation
jobs I found a trimming
job um for this brand highkey on my
shirt um High key is our dispensary that
we grow for um my boss is married and
his wife runs highkey and he runs the
grow operations called fifth
period
um
and I originally actually applied to be
a trimmer for highkey and when I told
them I trim my own flower at home I grow
at home they're like hey we need a
grower for cultivation would you be
interested and I'm like hell yeah that's
exactly what I want to do cuz I was
going to start off trimming and work my
way to cultivation because that's
typically how it
works um but I got lucky and just hopped
right into
flower nice how do how do you like the
um the cultivation space what's uh what
are some of the the things that you like
about it what are some of the things you
don't like about it I feel like
everybody has their their way of viewing
a cultivation job um it can be very
grueling yes so I didn't I mean they did
tell me in my interview like hey it's
it's a lot of work it's like a farming
job I'm like yeah let's do it like I do
it at home I'm ready to do it for a
career so I didn't realize they had 15
different rooms in
flower so yeah uh it's a lot of work a
lot of work uh I lost 20 lbs just the
first like two to three months working
there just sweating and busting ass I
literally like feel like I'm running
with my head cut off
there um it's one of the like best
workouts for a job that I've had I and I
used to be a chef and same felt like the
kitchen kept me fairly fit and then yeah
doing this
is it's it's at least not making me uh
feel like I need to go to the gym all
the time where I'm like feeling like oh
I feel like I'm sitting around all the
time or something like I'm moving all
the time at work and
yeah from the different
heat yeah yeah just tired yes I don't
want to do anything after working
basically I used to go hiking all the
time I used to hike like 6 to8 miles now
I don't even want to do that I'm like uh
work is a lot so um yeah I didn't expect
that I did not expect the grind um I was
definitely told in my interview to
expect it but I did not um so whoever
wants to get in the commercial field
expect to bust ass and sweat like a
crazy
person yeah I literally come out of the
rooms my hair is just
yeah yeah it gets pretty crazy sometimes
I feel like also
uh if you're just like doing some of the
really repetitive tasks like moving
plants or um like we use uh these cocoa
pots that you hydrate so you have to
like go in and you have to break them up
so the cocoa gets nice and fluffy after
you hydrate it like a pillow
that pretty much but it like your
shoulders and your back afterwards when
you're like bent over the trays cuz like
some of our trays are pretty blow to the
floor in in some of the low ceiling
rooms um you don't sit in stols like
well so we sit on stools but it's still
like yeah you're bending forward because
yeah in the low ceiling rooms where we
have the two-tier veg space that will
hydrate these pots on cuz we transplant
directly into them out of the Clone room
can I interrupt you real quick um what's
you say tiar are you talking about like
uh stacking
stacking I guess like like two two TI
where there's like uh lights and then a
tray and then lights right below that
tray and another tray below it um you
have three so yeah so well two tiers so
we have um two uh but it's it's in a
room that has I think their like 8 and
1/2t ceilings and so there's very
limited space and so we have like the
the bottom tier is only about like yeah
that like five four five in off the
floor wow and so like you're still in
the stool but you're like kind of
squatted in theol bent over breaking up
the cocoa pots yeah and then breaking up
the cocoa pots after you do like a 100
or 200 of those your shoulders are just
dying and that can really really be uh
tiresome and a huge workout sounds
tiring sounds super
tiring yeah but I mean as you know it's
it's it's a grind and and if people are
looking to get into into it it's
something to really be aware of that um
especially in like I I want to say like
a hydroponic grow where you're moving a
bunch of plants around it can that can
be a lot of fast-pace movement and then
if you're working in like uh commercial
grow that uses Organics and like let's
say you're you're moving plants into
transplant into beds or something or or
let let's say you're just using large
like 7 to 10 Gall pots um for the entire
Cy
and you have to move those pots
imagine yeah it's like you know you're
picking up 40 to 50 lb sacks of dirt
basically each time cuz they're usually
semi-saturated and and I complain now it
is a a lot of work yeah you know it's
but it's a lot of work for anybody that
wants to get into it and it's it's good
to hear you reiterate that because it is
it's but it's a lot of fun also I feel
like when
you time flies get into a good routine
yeah
time flies and you get into a good
routine of it and you start to see all
the improvements that are being made
through your attention to detail and the
repetition of the different tasks as
they kind of as day in and day out you
start to find your groove and be more
efficient at different things and Def I
love little efficiencies are really nice
I could speak on that with uh using the
sprayer to spray your
plants we use like a paint sprayer MH
and the hose oh my goodness I hate it I
struggle with that hose every time and
it's a nightmare um it gets caught on
everything and you have to prime it so
it can get loose and it's just a pain in
the butt and I hate it but um my
co-workers have taught me little like
Nicks and knacks how to like tuck it in
and keep it away from the table so it
doesn't get caught and like kind of walk
with it and just little tricks to like
make time more efficient and not
struggle with a hose so much and do your
job and get out of there quicker cuz
they expect us to spray every room in 10
minutes or 10 minutes per room it seems
fast
um and I come out of those rooms
dripping sweat cuz of those hot suits
and the
mask and yeah spraying is when you're
spraying pra like early flour so it's
really hot and he there yes oh yes yes
and then when we do our L3 spray which
is uh when we spray on the plants with
the lights off we use this little like
green light and it's like on a timer so
when you're in the middle of spraying
the green light will turn off and then
you're in a pitch black room and you're
in that mask in the suit and you're
trying to like not knock into stuff pull
your phone out start looking around it's
just a pain in the butt been there um
but it's it's fun I've I've definitely
uh got quicker I used to take 20 minutes
per room now I'm down to 12 minutes a
room I time myself and I try to do
different things to be faster and that's
something I feel like is important in
the commercial industry is there you
have to always look for ways that are
more efficient and faster and that's
what they want they just want you to
push push push you
know yeah absolutely I mean it's um like
I said earlier on it uh the the pack
price just keep on dropping oh yeah and
uh if they keep going down but
especially in oron the cost of living
keeps going up yeah I mean organ kind of
is terrible right now yes it's a little
bit of a joke but your price per pound
is sad
I I won't Dell on it too much yeah cuz
our our product keeps getting better and
uh it keeps going down in price so it's
uh it's frustrating cuz frustrating you
know cost of living yeah cost of living
goes up and uh everything else keeps
getting more expensive but for some
reason people want better cannabis for
lower prices and it's like one of those
few commodity I I guess a lot of
Commodities people want like the best
for less but uh everyone's looking for a
deal it then sucks to be yeah even me
when I go shopping for
cannabis I I don't blame you I I
definitely don't go for like the highest
pric stuff anymore because I just can't
afford it and um like I'll usually only
ever
look for like uh concentrates every once
in a while but it yeah they're they're
just really expensive and I usually like
to just price them out because I can
compare them then to what like we're
producing at the the grow that I work at
and what they're selling for and like it
makes me think of like the uh back in
the days of like Ford Motors when they
first started they made cars that uh it
was like one of his philosophies or
whatever to make cars that were
affordable enough for his employ emplo
to purchase um which is a little funny
cuz then it's kind of like Falls in line
with the saying of don't get high on
your own Supply um like he's he's just
having his employees pay the bills for
their own salaries but you know maybe
that's a conversation for a different
podcast I have a Ford
so for sure I um I used to have a Bronco
and it was a it was a fun car but
Broncos are nice uh fix or repair daily
right f d yeah um Fords aren't that
great yeah no no um well so uh do you
feel as though um in your home grow do
you feel as though there's anything
unique that you do that you um have
developed through your your few grows
that you've done that you're like this
is something that I'm going to continue
to do because I really like the outcome
of it regardless of what I've heard
other people say or
um even if you feel as though it's just
something that you might have developed
uh through your own
experiences um so I really so this time
in this grow it's kind of hard to see
with the bright light but in my hydro
grow uh this is my fourth time growing
in hydro and um my first time topping
twice uh the other times I just topped
the main stem once and that was it and
this time I topped the main stem and
then the sides so they could all catch
up together um it was something I was
kind of nervous about doing when I first
started growing cuz it just feels weird
to chop at your plant um when you first
start growing it's like uh I don't want
to touch it you know so um when I
learned commercially that it's fine to
top your plant more than once or not
even top a plant because it's not
catching up to the
others um I learned you can really you
know change your yield that way and I've
already seen it like all my tops are at
the third net pretty
much um in my other grows I noticed that
a lot of my colas didn't make it to the
third net I always use three
Nets um I was also taught by my teacher
Matt that using three Nets is you have
to do it uh if you don't use three Nets
you're going to see a decrease in yield
um um is this um in order uh to like
scrog and and bring the branches out to
fill the canopy exactly yeah for sure if
you're if you're scrogging that's
absolutely you got use the one to spread
it out and then two to capture all the
branches as grow up to make sure that
you're supporting them I agree with that
I feel like um I I've now been really
trying hard to get away with only two
trellis Nets um at work but we uh don't
do a like we don't train the plants at
all once once they're in flower we just
let them grow um same with my job and
let the the side branches kind of fill
yeah fill the canopy so usually the two
Works uh on smaller plants but then I I
tend to need three on anything that's
too big because it just you got to get
those tops so they don't flop over
exactly the flopping over you do not
want so that's why I was taught to
always use three and um I was also
taught to uh wait to defa
at the end of week five just because
okay the plants need those lower leaves
for mobile nutrients and to help
photosynthesize um for sure so what I
used to do was wait till uh the end of
week five and just de at once but my
mentor told me what I could do is wait
till the end of week five take off one
or two leaves that are towards the top
that are covering
colas and you just take one or two
leaves off every day to not have any
stress to your plants cuz deing all
those leaves at once causes way too much
stress and uh sets back your growth is
what I was taught and um so he said yeah
just go ahead and pick off one or two
leaves every day till the end of uh week
seven and they should you should have
all the leaves off by then it's like
almost a month of deing one to two
leaves a day so I'm going to try that
this grow and like one one or two leaves
per plant yeah mhm and you start from
the top and go to the bottom so I'm
going to try that this grow and see if I
get better
response and yield
maybe
um what else I actually tried some crop
steering at
home uh it's something I just learned
recently from the commercial
field um they push crop steering really
hard commercially and I've read that it
helps yield as well so I've been trying
to learn different techniques uh to do
it here at home I mean I don't have a
sensor to tell me my dryb backs and
whatnot but you can just feel your block
and lift it up see how dry you're
getting um so with this grow I kind of
did a crop
steer kind of little run just to
see um in veg I did uh ventive is that
how you say it ventive uh vegetative
vegetative yeah vegetative there's
vegetative and generative um growth yes
so yeah in veg I did vegetative where my
EC uh was low but I had more runoff I
was watering more and then now that I'm
in flower I'm kind of letting the EC
stack and uh I have it on irrigation
settings to where they're only getting
like three to four shots right now
um of
water and uh in veg I hand water so I
have more of control to like water more
and get that uh I have a hard time
saying ve vegetative I can't say
vegetative vegetative yeah a vegetative
steer so I've been working on crop
steering it it's something new to me uh
something I'm interested in learning I
know it's uh something valuable to learn
in the commercial field yeah so I'm just
trying to implement it at home uh so I'm
doing I'm always doing different things
every grow for sure I yeah I like to
tell people that do want to get into the
commercial space to to learn about uh
what crop steering is and then um I
always offer like reach out if you have
questions because it is it is a
frustrating thing to learn uh especially
when you don't have substrate monitoring
cuz when people will say things like
stack your EC in the substrate or um
lean towards a vegetative steer or lean
towards a generative steer or um you
know like uh do a do a vegetative
environment but a generative irrigation
um those are things that when I first
heard about them I didn't have any idea
talk um but then over time like yeah as
you learn about it you go okay so like
you can you can call it like uh heavy
stress versus low stress where heavy or
heavy stress leans towards generative
and low stress leans
towards um vegetative and um yeah it and
and then knowing how there's irrigation
practices that lean towards one where
generative is uh like higher E's
uh larger dryb backs vegetative is lower
e se's um lower dryb backs or smaller
dryb backs and then the environment
where uh a higher um vapor pressure
deficit is generative and a lower vapor
pressure deficit is vegetative and then
how you can use both of those different
things in combination with lighting and
CO2 and do you do this at
work I do yeah so yeah we have to in
order to make sure that we're getting
the yield that we want out of each of
the rooms um but then to know how to
combine them is is hard did you first
start uh with your company like as a
group like for starting crop steering or
was something that they already did
before you worked
there so the owner of the company had
already started implementing these
practices um he he took over the company
from his parents um and started
implementing a lot of these different
technical practices that he learned with
uh other grows and also uh he is just a
a consumer of knowledge and a retainer
of knowledge and can usually apply all
that knowledge really accurately um and
so we were able to to use uh his
experience as well as my experience and
knowledge and we kind of worked on it
together and him doing a lot of this the
fiddling with stuff in the backgrounds
with a lot of Hands-On and doing most of
the the Hands-On stuff and then using
different um did you guys run into any
issues while doing that
or I mean we've definitely seen um how
like uh large plants uh or starting with
large plants and flower can be a problem
in some cases because they just can kind
of get away from you if you if you uh if
the substrate is is improperly sized um
or your IR ation practices aren't geared
exactly towards
uh reducing the stretch and stuff like
that
um it I mean it's it's been a huge
learning curve
because we we change a lot of variables
within the grow whether it be substrate
or lighting or um temperature parameters
or humidity parameters to try and just
find little tweaks here and there to to
Really perfect it and
then we'll we'll we've been trying to
also run more strains per room rather
than just doing monocrops because we
only have uh all of our rooms are like
12 light equivalence uh rooms and so we
we only grow eight plants per room um
where it's like nine nine plants per
light and it uh we tend to um like
especially with the changing market and
we have a we have a huge Library where
we keep like over 120 different
cultivars on hand at any time um and
then we'll usually be flowering out
anywhere from like 10 to 15 different
cultivars at any time amongst four rooms
um and so like trying to keep all
everything like within a balance is kind
of what we've been aiming for where
we're trying to find like General
practices that can be applied across a
multitude of
scenarios uh versus dialing in a recipe
for a specific specific cultivar in a
specific room to to like perfect that
cultivar like we want to we want to get
the the best iteration of it out of a
general approach that allows for the
best possible outcomes without having to
make too many fine adjustment tweaks
specific to a a plant or specific to a
room I guess because we we then can take
these ideas and apply them outwards
towards uh helping other people with
their grows um whether it be home grows
or commercial grows I'm sure also helps
with like setting up a room and knowing
which plants can you know be together
for that for crop steering
too um yeah but I know that also each
table you can change too do you use grow
you use grow
link uh no we use um open sprinkler for
all of our irrigation and then uh aoya
for all of our monitoring okay um
and uh those two in in conjunction with
uh we use one more uh thing called gr
Tronics but they're actually going out
of business so we need to find a
different application for that so I I'm
assuming once you figure out like which
plants need uh what when you're crop
steering uh it'd be easier to set up a
whole
room where you know every plant needs
the same amount of shots and you're not
just like doing different shots per
table and it's just like you know
everything's on the same route like cuz
we're using the same irrigation schedule
per table yeah um yeah so we we do try
to match uh like cultivars with like
cultivars um in terms of if they are uh
leaning more on the like I want to
stretch and be big and bushy plants or
if I'm short and squat and um because we
don't want to like shade out half of the
table with uh another half of the table
or something like that yeah um and then
yeah the water consumption is is going
to be vastly different but I've I've run
into new cultivars where I haven't seen
them grow before and I don't have the
data on it so I'll just throw it in
there on a table with something else and
just put like one light worth yeah just
like nine plants and like right now I'm
running um sherb uh cocktail number
seven on a table with uh our beach
grapes number 12 that we hunted in house
and the sh cocktail number seven and
Beach grapes went in at the same time
but the sh cocktail of course is three
times the the height uh of the of the
beach grapes and I because it was a new
cultivar I've been steering that table
with data from the uh sherb cocktail
because I wanted to see how it responded
to the irrigations and stuff cuz I've
already seen the beach grapes and I can
kind of gauge if it's lean if it's going
a little bit too vegetative based on the
leaf growth and the the flower
morphology or if it is leaning towards
like a generative or if it's kind of a
nice mixed medium of the two um and
oddly enough they're they're roughly
using about the same water um I think
the beach grapes are getting just
slightly overwatered um and leaning a
little bit vegetative but it's it's
surprising to me that the biomass of the
Sher cocktail has got to be at least one
and a half times the beach grapes
overall in terms of like if I were to
cut down both plants wet right now I I'd
say the Sher cocktail is going to be
like 1 and 1/2 times the weight um but
it's it's not
transpiring at 1 and 1/2 times what the
beach grapes is which is really
fascinating um so is that something you
do though do you match like cultivars
with uh like
irrigations if that makes
sense um I mean ideally that would be
where we try to to match cultiv bars on
the same table yeah absolutely and
usually we do that based off of
structure because uh like size plants
usually use about the same amount of
water but then there are plants that are
just not heavy drinkers um they don't
assimilate the uh the nutrients as fast
and so they don't need as much water and
maybe their stamata like the density of
their stamata on the leaves might be
lesser or something than the other
plants where they they just don't have
the ability to transpire as as greatly
as some other plants do it makes me
think of like mac 1 Mac 1 is a really
slow grower it seems like I water her
half as much as some of the other plants
that are moms um cuz we handw waterer
all our moms so that we like pick up
each plant make sure that it gets a good
dry back so that we're don't not running
in into any um like hypoxia related uh
root issues where they're just like
going Anor robic or anything like that
um yeah there's it's it's really
fascinating to see how different
cultivars react differently and how you
can then try to find matching um
cultivars to put together so that you
can grow them under the same irrigation
strategies and in the same environment
um and that has been a huge Challenge
and that's where it's like we we haven't
really been we haven't really been
leaning towards
making like recipes for cultivars that I
heard a lot of people would do with
their irrigation practices and
environmental practices because yeah in
today's market you have to have so many
flavors available that you can't really
dedicate
all of your space to like so we have
four flower rooms we can't just have
four cultivars available yeah it's not
it's not it it doesn't really work for
us
um even at like the lower the lower
packs that we we produce you know each
Harvest is only 30 to 36 lb so um but
even amongst that like nobody wants 30
lbs of one strain in Oregon at this
point of high quality weed because I
think everywhere they're going to sell
it for more yeah yeah absolutely and
it's it's unfortunate cuz the price
keeps going down uh to the grower but
then the price in the dispensary is
consistent or goes up for some of the
high quality like top shelf stuff and
um yeah it's it's a weird market right
now for sure um it's almost like one of
those things where we just have to like
hold on and hope that things adjust and
uh not necessarily like improve as
though like we know what that could be
but it something needs to change
so you know speaking of change um now
that you've worked in the Cannabis
industry for a little bit and you've
been doing your home grow and you've
been an active participant within the
community posting on Instagram looking
at what other people are doing
interacting I don't know if you go to
since you're in um in like kind of an
area where there's a lot of uh cannabis
events and stuff I don't know if you're
like attending any of these I think you
went to MJ bus
uh this year um so like by immersing
yourself more into the industry and the
community um where do you feel as though
some changes could be um like what would
you want to see change in the community
I guess and or the industry as a whole
uh homow commercial anywhere in
between um well back when we were
talking about remember how I mentioned
strawberry cough and I thought it would
be
tall um cuz it's a sativa but I was
going to mention is that because
nowadays we only have poly hybrid
strains
and nothing's truly sativa nothing's
truly Indica now it's just pretty much
all hybrid I want to change that
or go back to like uh where you can just
smoke straight indica or you know get
some straight SA
uh I think uh
consumers think still that they're
getting sativa in Indica but it's it's
not everything's hybrid no and I think
yeah there's there's not a lot of
commercial producers that would want to
grow a sativa that takes 12 to 14 weeks
to flower cuz right that's almost two
full flower cycles of something that is
more of a a squatter um non-equatorial
so realistically Inda um yeah
so profit Wise It's not smart to do
that yeah you can't charge twice for a
sativa um and that's one of the big the
big things cuz it it does take about
twice the amount of input um makes sense
but I I hear you cuz there are some
people that are still doing it and
they're you know they're just uh making
it a small a small part of their crop
but it's also one of the reasons why I
am so uh heavily advocate advocating for
hom grow is because somebody at home can
absolutely take their time to grow out
something like Panama Red where they're
going to flower it for 120 days that's
just to me I'm I'm like when I think 120
days in flour that is crazy I I don't
keep like for I I feel like I will cut
from a
mom clone like take that clone it veg it
flower it out
and like that whole cycle of like even
growing the mom to make that cutting Al
together that doesn't take 120 days yeah
and uh but of course I'm thinking of it
from a commercial standpoint and from
like a production standpoint but for
like the home grower who wants Panama
Red like go for it that's
awesome yeah just more
patience yeah um to get but it sounds
like you want more of that the industry
in terms of you want it to to be less of
a a poly hybrid yeah uh cess pool so to
speak because when I was uh a dispatcher
at like a black market uh delivery
company uh we would lie to customers the
customers would say oh I want OG Kush
and we didn't have that uh we were just
like okay and just write down OG Kush on
the back and then give them whatever you
know and and a lot of consumers think
they're getting what they're ordering or
they think they're getting a straight
indica or straight sativa and that's
just not how it is these days and I
didn't realize that until I became a
grower yep so you when even when you
were like working through as dispatching
for like this elicit service um you you
didn't realize at the time that it
wasn't uh yeah that they weren't
necessarily being truthful about what
they were providing people yeah and I
felt awful lying to customers and
telling them oh yeah you're getting uh
Paris OG that's what you're getting but
it and they asked me oh is it good uh
and I'm just like sure you know and I
felt bad lying but it's part of like
their sales tactic and um and even if
like we had a strain that said like
Paris OG and we ran out of that strain
even though it wasn't
pariso they would lie and be like oh
yeah we still have it and then just grab
another thing off the shelf and just
package it and and I'm just I don't know
I think it's not fair to lie to
Consumers about what you're giving them
because some people look for something
specific you know and um some consumers
want that specific strain and that
helped them in whatever moment that they
were you know dealing with and that
helped them and people look for that you
know and I feel like
nowadays it's all a lie because like
you're not getting straight Indica
you're not getting straight sativa
anymore like that's that's not a thing
anymore so I I dislike that a lot I can
agree with that I feel like uh truth and
marketing is something that needs to be
a thing but like you said as a grower to
have to grow it for way longer because
it's a sativa and it kind of ruins
production in a way or you know like
just sets you back financially for
people that are trying to you know push
their product off the shelf and they're
having to spend more labor and time to
grow something that takes longer I I
totally see why it you know the industry
only has poly
hybrids but I don't think it's fair for
consumers for sure yeah I mean I I feel
like there are some poly hybrids uh or
other hybrid strains out there where
they do try to uh breed for the effects
um of something that would have been a
traditional sativa um but to put it in a
plant that is a a more squat easy to
control plant something that isn't going
to take 120 days um cuz even that alone
it's a very hard thing to do to to keep
a plant alive that long especially
through a flowering period where you're
you know after a certain time you don't
want to spray for pests and after a
certain time you you know if you have
too
many uh temperature and humidity
fluctuations especially with with the
flower structures of some of these
equatorial plants being so large
um you risk mold and you risk other
pathogen and and and rot and just a
multitude you know nutrient deficiencies
other things as well just when you grow
something for that long um that is such
a high demand plant cuz cannabis you
know it it's it's it just eats so much
compared to something like a cactus or a
a a little bonsai tree or something
where you can feed it once a year or
something
um so I I do I do see how like the poly
hybrids could become something where it
is
like it's almost like devious to tell
people it's a sativa when it's not but
if if that's where like a lot of these
things that are like indicia
sativa um high
THC um I feel like a lot of it is like
we we just got it wrong as an industry
and we need to probably lean more
towards uh a complete more holistic
understanding of how all the different
constituents um come together in you
know whether it be like an Entourage
effect or however else people would like
to describe it um and then also to
understand that every person's
endocannabinoid system is unique and
different and so uh by finding something
that that does work for them you know it
could completely like you could
completely find a tpine and cannaboid
profile now in something that only takes
9 weeks to grow um and then find that
same tpine and cannaboid profile in
something that takes 12 weeks to grow um
that's I that's completely possible now
with the genetic diversity that we have
available
but it I feel like as a grower you know
that something that's a sativa or
something that is like a an equatorial
land race of some kind is supposed to
take a long time to grow and as a grower
you're looking at it and saying well
who's growing these long sativas and
where can I get it um whereas I feel
like definitely for like a hom grower or
Not a Home grower but just a consumer
but just a consumer right someone's just
like I just want something that makes me
you know feel productive or artistic or
uh upbeat or like want to go a hike and
they're like that's a sativa or someone
who's just like no I just want to sit on
the couch play video games get the
munchies because I need to eat because I
haven't eaten all day um like and and
then they go and that's an indicia um so
I feel as though there's uh just a lot
of different misconceptions in terms of
what sativa and Inda are because like
Inda as an like as the term indicia it
actually means of India and sativa just
as the as the term itself means um
cultivated so there's other plants that
use these
um monikers within their naming
schema to uh designate that it is a
cultivated plant or that it is a plant
that has uh of Indian descent um outside
of cannabis and so I know that's
sometimes where like yeah and this is
sometimes where like a lot of people are
uh like
because of the illegality of cannabis at
least this is my explanation because of
the IL illegality of cannabis we have
used certain terminologies that are not
accurate makes sense to other aspects of
Agriculture and cannabis is
so truly related to agriculture it it is
agriculture in a sense I wish youd make
it that to use these yeah right but to
use these termin these terms that have a
an agricultural meaning to every other
agricultural uh industry in the world
and then are used differently in
cannabis does tend
to confuse a lot of the the public when
it comes to Consumers because they're
given these different terms as this is
what this means this is what that means
even if it was something that was
developed like in the shadows and in a
in an alist Market in a in a time where
you know saying hey let me get some of
that really awesome cannabis that puts
me to sleep you know no one's going to
listen to you when you say that if
you're like picking up a dime bag or a
dub sack back you know 15 20 years ago
they're like oh yeah I got it just like
they do
now yeah exactly yeah um but yeah I I I
see how like a little bit more like
honesty and a little bit
more um or maybe just education feels
like yeah feels like education is
heavily needed not only for the
producers and the purveyors of cannabis
but also for the consumers for sure yeah
cuz when I worked in um the being a
dispatcher that was like my number one
questions I would always get from
consumers list like oh what's your best
sativa what's your best indica and I'm
just like uh you know so I think people
really need to
educate uh consumers that it's not like
that and I didn't even realize Indica
meant from India and sativa was meant
like cultivated so that was really cool
that you taught me that thanks for that
yeah absolutely I I feel like it's
important for people to know that there
these terms are used outside of cannabis
and they're they're not uh solely
designated to the Cannabis industry um
even though we've appropriated them into
something that they aren't uh originally
which it it's very fascinating the
Cannabis industry appropriates a lot of
different things that um it may not be
the best to appropriate yeah um but you
know I feel like a lot of a lot of
different groups and industries do that
um so considering that you started your
growing Journey so recently um I feel
like you're a great person to ask what
were some of the pitfalls that you found
early on in growing that you were able
to learn from
um that you would want to then relay
that information to another new grower
who's just getting into it so that they
can avoid it like so that they can learn
from your mistakes basically don't buy
CO2 that is a waste of time uh for a
home grow for sure a tent for sure I
mean my teacher Matt he was like why AR
using CO2 and I'm like honestly cuz it
was just expensive for me like if I
could afford it I would do it but I
really just can't so it's if it's
something you can afford do it but it's
not
crucial
um what else um I think that a lot of
people should try rock wool grow a lot
of people are
afraid to grow in rock wool I talked to
a lot of soil Growers um soil growing is
you know more
common and a lot of soy Growers have
told me they're afraid to grow in rock
wool and uh they don't want issues
problems and it's funny because I'm
experiencing the opposite I haven't
experienced any issues or problems in
rock wall but I have seen some
deficiencies and issues in
soil so um and I think yeah I think a
lot of people should just try different
ways of growing um not just be stuck to
one thing um expand your knowledge and
learn different ways of how to get
better
um
and for me I watch YouTube videos every
day of how to grow and different uh
stages and what to do and um I watch a
lot of uh drying and curing videos just
because I want to perfect that stage um
I think drying and curing is the most
important step of
growing um a lot of people
people might say otherwise but I mean
you can grow a beautiful flower and then
dry it and cure it terribly and then it
ends up being a mid instead of you know
top shelf and I think that sucks cuz you
put in all this hard work you're
expecting oh I grew this [__]
beautifully it's going to be perfect and
then when you dry it and cure it you're
like what the heck so yeah my first dry
I experienced uh that uh hay smell
and I was petrified and thought you know
my Harvest was ruined but luckily like
uh it went
away so I mean it was okay um I feel
like I'm still learning how to properly
dry and cure um I had mentioned to you
that I threw my trim in the freezer with
popcorn nugs and I checked on it like a
month maybe almost two months later just
to make some
edibles uh make cannabis butter out
of and I saw the popcorn nugs in there
and they were looking beautiful and I
was like ooh so I went to go pick them
up to see if they like crumbled and they
didn't they were perfect um they were
still kind of sticky
too so I don't know it got me on an idea
of like can I cure this
way so I don't know I mean for sure I
might just try one I think low temp
curing is a thing yeah yeah I mean I
liked how looked the flow tasted better
the color was still there it seemed like
the
tricomes were still you know intact like
like when I compared my dried cure to
like what I did in jars to the freezer
cure it just looked so much different
smelled different um the freezer cure
was
better so I am a little nervous yeah I'm
a little nervous to you know cure in the
freezer but I'm going to try it not my
whole Harvest but I'm going to try like
a jar or something I don't know what to
do yet and you're going
to and just so like the listeners know
but um like it sounds like your plan is
to dry it fully put it in a jar and seal
it in that jar yes uh at room
temperature and then put that sealed jar
in the freezer yes and then when you
want to check on it you're your plan is
to then pull it out of the freezer let
it sit at room temp until it comes to
room temperature and then open the jar
to to test the buds just to avoid any
sort of uh condensation or moisture that
could form on the flower itself
yes yeah cool I mean I try I think it's
a great idea cuz I've heard of other
people saying that they'll store um
cannabis that they want to come back to
uh long term either in the fridge or you
know I feel like I might have even heard
it in the freezer before but it was one
of those things that I was like well I'm
not going to be trying that because
anytime I did grow at home it was uh I
couldn't couldn't keep the flower around
long enough I just I wanted to smoke it
all um I feel like those are all great
little tidbits of advice for new Growers
um yeah what do you think you think I
should just try it and see what
happens I'm a little nervous yeah I
think you should I think you should try
it that method um yeah drying
in the tent try to do my 6 put like one
really nice flower in there um you know
and and then the rest Just Popcorn nugs
or stuff that you wouldn't mind making
into Edibles uh like you're talking
about just because that way it's not
necessarily a huge loss to lose one one
nice bud but then you can see how that
one nice Bud turns out um yeah I
definitely suggest you know getting it
fully dried all the way to where like
you could smoke it if you wanted to but
you want to C it to help reduce a little
bit of the harshness let the enatic
process continue um awesome so yeah I'd
say I'd say try it why not I mean all
these things that we experiment with as
hom Growers that
um that can be documented and relayed to
other Home Growers um if it is helpful
then why not especially you know it
makes me think of like if somebody can
only grow one crop a year outdoor um but
they want it to stay fresh because they
really like fresh flour um versus
something that's been cured uh at a
higher temperature uh for a longer
period of time cuz even some people like
that sort of peppery cannabis where
everything off gases other than the
kopine where it's like just really
peppery and spicy but I I know some
people like that especially in like
hashes and stuff um but if somebody
wanted fresh flour and they were able to
take all this outdoor that they grow and
dry it up really nice nice and then trim
it up and manicure it to what they like
and then get it into some airtight
container that they can then freeze uh
and then pull as they need to throughout
the year to supply what their needs are
um I feel like you know somebody can
easily grow what they need in a year in
an outdoor plot if they have the ability
for it um and it's a lot cheaper so it
might it might be a great way for people
to keep flower around for longer and
enjoy fresh cannabis throughout the year
um so I'm I'm sure that there's a a a
niche opportunity there for other people
to learn from this and to apply it in
different ways yeah cuz I tried Googling
it keep a good log of it yeah yeah I
tried Googling it and there's not much
on Google about it um I saw a lot of
like Reddit comments on it and other
people have tried it they say use a
frost free
freezer um I've even came across people
uh drying in a
fridge so I don't know I mean sure I
just want to do like what makes the best
cure uh because I noticed like I told
you when I looked at my cured buds in
the mason jars and then I looked at the
cured Bud from the freezer the color was
better The Taste the smell was better
from the freezer so I was just like I
guess it's more fresh like you're
saying so yeah I mean can tpin off gas
so rapidly
um uh even at lower temperatures there's
some that will just off gas over time
and uh so so like it seems like the only
way to combat that is completely
limiting light exposure um completely or
or reducing the temperature
significantly um reducing the oxygen
contact so that's another thing too you
know if you keep it in a sealed jar
through the uh enzymatic process a lot
of the oxygen is going to be used up and
so you won't even have like an oxidative
Factor on the on the turpins after a
certain amount of time if it was like
cured properly in the jar um and you
like just got it to that last point
where it was still just like that last 1
or 2% of curing and just throw it right
into the freezer at that point and it
sounds like it would work perfectly um
so that's awesome I feel like uh you
know it seems like from what i' I've
gathered so far from our conversation
some of the stuff that you do is you you
try new stuff out and you try to
remember what works and what doesn't
work yeah and then you try to say how
can I apply what works and then how can
I understand how it works um and I feel
like those aspects for a grower are so
important because they allow
for uh a a more thorough understanding
of the processes of growing and curing
and all the different aspects of of what
um cultivating and producing cannabis in
tail and um like if you're always trying
to improve those things and glean the
best practices out off of them it it
helps just in in so many different ways
and it it really
like I feel like the culmination of
knowledge and and information as as the
uh as a cultivation Journey continues
can you can like really make these Leaps
and Bounds in the quality of what's
being produced that I feel like a lot of
people go how did you do that like how
did you get this good so fast or
something it's like just
repetition applying what works and
removing what doesn't it's it's like
there's not I don't I don't mean to
oversimplify it but there are some
aspects of it that can be really
simplified down to use what works remove
what doesn't work take time and have
patience and you'll learn from it and I
think
uh change is is good um a lot of Growers
get stuck in their you know routine and
how they do things and I think that's
what works but I think if you're open to
change and open to learning different
ways then you're going to be the best
grower out there because you're not just
stuck in being stubborn and like oh this
is right like there's no really right
and wrong way like you can evolve and
change and get better every time
there there are so many times where
people have asked me how how did you
grow that flower like when they've seen
something on my Instagram or something
and I'll say I do it this way and
they'll say oh you know I've never never
wanted to try Hydroponics because I've
been growing in living soil for 20 years
and I've been happy with the results I
think I grow like the best cannabis I go
well just because you've been doing
something for 30 years doesn't
necessarily mean that you've been doing
it correctly or that the best um
that you can't learn anything else uh
like it it does sometimes that fixed
mindset does hinder a lot of a lot of
Growers I feel like um so it's good to
always be learning and always be trying
new things and applying those those
Lessons Learned From trying out new
things yeah and definitely abolutely
that's great advice Growers need to
reach out and get help and and not be
prideful and be like oh like this is how
I learned and this is how I'm sticking
to it like no like ask for help that's
how you can learn and and get
better
absolutely absolutely well this has been
a wonderful conversation and interview
and those are actually all the main
questions that I have but I do always
wrap up the podcast with a couple of the
um kind of ubiquitous questions just
that I feel like every cannabis podcast
needs to ask um so uh since we didn't
touch on this uh earlier on in the
podcast what was your first cannabis
smoking
experience or your first one that you
remember um my first one was with my
sister uh she gave me a pipe and I
smoked out of it I didn't know to use
like the carb part so I didn't know what
I was doing okay I just inhaled and you
know I didn't really feel high I don't
think I did it right but
uh um I just started smoking with
friends in high school and learning
different ways to smoke and how to like
create things to smoke with like I even
smoked out of a pizza by cutting through
the crust all the way and you pack the
end of the crust and then you hit the
other side it it's weird but you know
like fun ways to smoke I've done it out
of a strawberry out of a potato you know
made your own bong out of you know a
water bottle with a
pencil um but my funniest smoking uh
memory would be uh I was at Sunset
Cliffs uh a really famous place in San
Diego for great views so I'd always go
there to
smoke um it's by the beach and uh me and
my friends hot boox my
car and I get a knock on my window and
sure enough it's a cop and I'm like [__]
oh no and it's literally like chichin
Chong movie like I had to roll roll down
my window and the smoke just like flew
on his face and he yes and I was just
like oh no I'm [__] and and he's like
oh what are you guys doing just chilling
and we're like yeah we're just chilling
and he's like oh it sure smells like it
and then he just said like you guys
could just stay here get you know let it
wear off wait for an hour and then you
can go home and I was like oh thank God
I got a nice one so I was lucky for that
I've heard I've heard a few stories like
that where they the cops just were like
um just don't leave for an hour or if
one of you didn't smoke and they're
sober and can drive get they usually
nice about it yeah
um yeah cuz I feel like it's since it is
just like a uh a decriminalized thing
now especially in California where
you're only going to get a fine they
just have to they know like well at the
time it was illegal when I was when I
was
it was illegal so oh yeah
definitely yeah well okay well that's
definitely a a fun a funny story and and
uh one that I would have also just been
kind of yeah I would have been [__]
bricks that would have been quite
nerve-racking first thing I did was grab
my keys at the ignition I threw it I was
like oh my God I'm not going to get a
DUI for smoking
so I was petrified but we we used to put
our keys in the G gas cap oh um if we'd
hot boox our car so we'd like take them
out pop the gas cap put them in there
cuz then they're outside of the car
that's smart and um and I know my one
buddy got uh rolled up on one time and
same thing they were like hot boxing
roll down the window smoke poured out
and the cops like were you guys planning
on driving and they're like no we were
just using this to smoke in officer and
he's like well how do I know that show
me your keys and they're like they're in
the gas T and and or in the gas cap and
the cop was like oh that's pretty smart
all right I'll let you off this time and
it's just like I can't believe that that
worked I mean obviously he could have he
could have made up the story but that
was the one that I heard every time I
heard that I was like oh put it put it
in the gas cap did you ever play like
where they called it baseball where you
had to smoke and then you pass it to
your friend and you have to go in a
circle and then then you can exhale when
you get it
back uh you know I I feel like
potentially at one at one point when I
was younger we did something like that
um I feel like it was always just like
puff puff pass and you'd hold it in as
long as you could anyways because
usually it was like seven or eight of
you sharing one joint or one blunt and
it was going to you know you only are
going to get three maybe four hits off
of it before it's gone so you really
would try to conserve and and get the
best effects possible out of it yeah
um but yeah that's that's a those are
funny stories um so just a couple more
of these questions here then uh so who's
or what is your favorite strain of all
time uh whether it be one that you've
grown that you really enjoy growing or
one that um you've smoked that is just
like your favorite smoke so I really
love any
OG uh strains especially the original
strains back in the day like we spoke
about finding those good oldie strains
um I love Skywalker OG Paris OG King
L um I even like uh Blue Dream Sour
Diesel the old
strains okay um from like 10 years ago
or so exactly um I wish they would bring
those back to more in the
industry um and for growing I really
enjoy growing Green Crack it's what I'm
growing right now it's a resilient
strain uh it doesn't stress out ever you
can top the crap out of it and it's
still going to grow super tall
and it drinks a
lot so I don't know I love it it it's
beautiful uh it's fun to grow it's
easy I I remember living in uh
Sacramento I was going to Sacramento
State uh many years ago and um at the
time medical uh like 215 uh was
available and so I had my medical card
and there was this dispens that had
green kraak and it was like it seemed
like there was more tricomes than weed
or than than like actual flower good um
whenever we would get it and it was it
was crazy and I look back on it now now
that I've grown for as long as I have
and I'm almost positive that they were
dumping like all the different keiths
that they would get from their different
trimmers onto the bags of Green Crack
because it was the most expensive one
that they were selling and it was you
know they were like claiming 40% THC or
something and this was back in like 2009
and so I always like think back on that
and I'm like this is yeah they
definitely were doing something to it um
but I really liked it I can say it
worked really well as medicine it's the
first plant that started getting super
Frosty right away before the others so
cool well maybe it does just look like
that I've never actually seen it grown
because it was one of those ones that
was uh it wasn't available in the um
commercial Market when I started can you
see
good or the light is the light too
bright I know it's a
little it's a little choppy but the
overall canopy looks
great yeah the it's the one the tall
ones in the back are the green crack and
they're just loving
it well I'll tell anybody to go to
um at Autumn grow drw on Instagram and
you can see updated pictures of her grow
um and the the green crack and the other
uh strawberry cough and other things
that you're growing yeah um and I'll
just tell them to go there to see it
because it's going to look a lot better
yeah um especially if you're listening
on Spotify or apple podcast and you
aren't seeing any of the video recording
but if you are go over to YouTube and uh
listen up there on our premieres um so
uh just uh one more question actually uh
so favorite strain currently sounds like
it's green crack um but if you've uh if
you've kind of gained an appreciation
for a specific breeder uh since you've
started growing um who would you
currently say is your favorite breeder
if you had to choose
one um I'm going to go with jungle boys
I love them okay they're my favorite um
they're basically all I smoke when I do
go buy flour and wax um I really like
710 Labs though for some concentrates
um and yeah I wanted to shout out my
mentor Matt
Brett um he's taught me everything I
know and he's amazing and he'll help you
guys grow and he'll answer any questions
you
have nice and uh do you know his
Instagram off the top of your head yes
it's cannabis science uncore on
Instagram and then he has a YouTube
channel uh just cannabis science
on YouTube cool yes well awesome I think
that that that about wraps us up there
so autumn again thank you so much for
joining me today for this conversation
and to kind of help shed a little bit
more light on uh the different growing
methods that you use and your growing
Journey so far um you know I feel like
uh when people hear that new Growers are
getting this much success in a hom grow
and being able to do it with um you know
Financial restrictions and working
around those to still make it work um is
it I feel like it makes a lot more homeg
Growers hopeful about being able to do
this and find success in it so that they
can either grow their own medicine start
a new hobby or even use it as a way to
Pivot into the um the cultivation space
professionally so I feel like you
exemplify a lot of those different
aspects and um so yeah thank you again
so much for joining me and uh I really
appreciate you being here today thanks
for having me yeah absolutely
all right thanks everybody
[Music]
oh