[Music]
hello and welcome to another episode of
The Way We Grow podcast a production of
The Craft Growers Network I'm your host
Nick wolf today our guest is Matthew
Gates he's also known as sink angel on
Instagram and you can uh find his
library of Pest management information
on his YouTube channel zenthanol um
Matt how have you been it's been a while
since we
talked I've been really good I've been
happily
productive um and I often give that
answer to people actually when they ask
me how I'm doing uh and I've been really
happy uh to hear especially right now
it's February it's going to be for for
people who have seasons unlike myself
living in Southern California um you
know you you are still kind of either
it's still really cold and it's about to
be spring so is the perfect time um for
people to be re-evaluating how they go
about it what happened last year what do
we do this year that kind of um
reflection is really
important for sure and where where do
you find most of your um your
professional efforts Focus these days um
do you do you do a lot of uh cannabis uh
uh Consulting work or are you also
working with other like perennials or um
Nursery plants or anything like that I
do work in both of of those uh Fields
but most of my work lately has been in
cannabis and um in fact just today I was
working with somebody who was dealing
with
um uh a few different things actually um
but a lot but it was really execution on
a strategy that um should be working but
wasn't uh so it was really it was just
like a matter of kind of drilling into
the execution and um I think we figured
it out so that was good it's awesome I I
always like it when you get like a
little puzzle like that and you have to
figure out you know it seems all the
pieces fit but there's something that's
not that's not working you got to narrow
it down to something I I see that all
the time in
cultivation um so you know a lot of
people will know you for the
approachability of your um like press
pest primer videos as well as your other
integrated Pest Management resources
that you have on your YouTube channel
and then you do always provide a very uh
uh insightful look into Pest Management
when you do or are on the panel of the
growing with my fellow Growers podcast
and um but you know this this is the way
we grow uh podcast and you I really like
to dive into people's history with uh
growing plants in general whether or not
that be cannabis and considering that
your professional life is more heavily
focused on the um cannabis side of of uh
Pest Management applications um where
did you start with growing plants in
general was it something where um you
had house plants growing up or a
vegetable garden with Mom and Dad or
yeah take us take us back to when young
Matthew Gates was entering into the
world of
plants if you go before my existence um
into my parentage you've got uh my
father who grew up uh in
Kentucky uh zinzinnati Kentucky you know
as they would often refer to it when
because that's what it used to be called
now it's Cincinnati or I mean some
people would say that's not Kentucky
right but he would always say it this
way
um and and he you know he has a farm
background and so um although we didn't
really do any of that with me growing up
personally um I think there is some of
that influence that maybe should be uh
talked about a bit that sort of
appreciation but really you know my
enjoyment my like interest in like plant
biology and what eventually become like
an ecological appreciation too is um
through insect life mostly um I also
like to reference things like Pokemon uh
giving yourself for as a person born in
the
9s um I think having like a virtual ual
world that um you can kind of play
around with Concepts as a CH as a child
uh and also then reinforce those things
out in the environment um Satoshi Tajiri
who is uh the creator of Pokemon uh by
some regard uh got the idea for Pokemon
for doing exactly that going to caves
going to Fields catching bugs as a kid
um so I think there's a thematic
relevance there um for sure uh but it be
but then but then as I like grew to I
enjoyed insects and things like that
because they have like this sort of
alien sort of physiology very different
than our our bodies and then because
most bugs eat plants that's where the
Avenue kind of comes into it so and I
think I've been benefited now like a
fungi and all all other kinds of life
forms you know it's all good all very
interesting to me but that's where it
kind of started so the the draw was
really through the aspect of insects and
their activity around plants not
necessarily plants uh at first exactly
you know I think that's what I think
that's what directed my attention first
yeah that makes a lot of sense I mean as
a someone else who was born in the 90s
Pokemon was a huge part of my early
childhood and still continues to remain
a part of my life even to this day I
still enjoy playing the games every once
in a while and you know they're very
nostalgic but also I I see how there is
like the aspect of uh you know if you're
out in the grass and you find a bug and
you pick it up and you look at it that's
pretty much exactly what Pokemon or
these other you know uh
animated uh animal games are very
closely similar too so that makes a lot
of sense um so when you were then
growing up uh what other uh you know
taking the idea of uh you got brought
into plants through your enjoyment or
your uh your excitement with bugs um
where did that then kind of go from
there uh well basically I had a few
different options um you know growing up
for what I could do as a career uh that
I was planning on anyways uh but
eventually I came to the conclusion that
I wanted to work in agriculture since I
already had this affinity for was
essentially the enemy for so many
people um so fortunately because a lot
of people don't like or don't like
pathogens or that kind of a thing um and
they avoid even thinking about it uh you
know I was happy to take on that role
and be that limb that somebody doesn't
have you know um to sort of
efficaciously deal with something but
also I think you know growing up another
aspect of that a strong aspect for me at
least was like with cannabis for example
I had friends growing and I had friends
um who would ask me questions because
you know I'm the guy who knows those
sorts of things
um and so there was a happy Synergy
there too uh and especially
because a lot of times people get what
are by most regards really common pests
but sometimes people would get something
really odd and I was Happ I was I was
very interested I think to to see things
that were not as common um in other
crops and other plant life and that kind
of a thing so um that is kind of where
that took off and I did spend a couple
of years in the People's Republic of
China in the early
2010s and I worked in tea and I worked
in um sorghum and a couple of other like
grain crops and vegetable crops too like
tomato I would go all around but I
mostly spent my time in Beijing tenen
and uh Shanghai and
hungo um which is like the North and
kind of the southeast part of China of
of the people
Republic for sure and um that was an
interesting experience too for sure no
not a lot of cannabis going on over
there for me at least I would imagine
not I did you see any hemp or anything
because I know that that was um somewhat
of a a large crop at one point in China
but I'm not really sure when that would
have been I don't really have my my
history that well down on that no I mean
there that exists and it's there and um
and I'm not I'm not totally read up on
all the details but there seems to be
like a gray you know some kind of a gray
Market uh for for example I know like
for research
chemicals um and like you know compounds
like that that are uh that people want
to obtain maybe for like a psychedelic
effect or for no Tropics or whatever um
as long as it's not on like the band
list you know if it's a slightly
different compound that has a different
name then suddenly it's okay or whatever
um so anyways like there's some of that
going on too uh but I I wish I could
make up some like really fantastic story
but I actually never got to see any
despite me being very aware um that it
was there and that's that's it's around
um you know sadly I just didn't have
that um I had I saw some like hemp
products in the past before and um if I
went to like places like
uh hjo which was very
uh um agrarian uh so I think like you
know more people it was interesting to
hear PE older people talk about it a bit
uh they would humor me a little bit um
through my translator I did learn
Chinese but but um uh not enough to to
talk about a kind of a a gray gray topic
I didn't really want to have any
miscommunication fair enough people fa
enough that I mean I feel like
especially when you connect through
something as uh Universal as agriculture
um and then you know being someone who
was there to help prevent the pest
damage to crops it I feel like that's
such a valuable role
um you know you you're you're like a
protector of sustenance at that point it
does feel that way I think that that's
really important and even what you said
before um where you said uh I forget
exactly the words that you used but how
we call them um are enemies right within
the agricultural field and um how like
pest itself as a uh moniker is somewhat
um it has this negative connotation to
it but the you know these these insects
definitely developed over time alongside
of these different crops and we even
have things now where we have uh hemp uh
specific uh pests and cannabis specific
pests that that don't necessarily harm
other crops uh either to the same ex
extent or degree or not at all and so um
when when did you start to then so it
sounds like you were in in China for a
few years uh immediately I'm assuming
following College um or your your
education towards this career path
that's right and so two years two years
okay and and when you came back to the
States um what what sort of drove your
uh your path uh what what what did you
sort of follow in terms of the uh
integrated Pest Management
oh well had I basically um at that point
I had already established uh my personal
professional work um my business
zenthanol Consulting and so at that
point um I was fortunate enough to have
a lot of people I could contact or that
were contacted me about various issues
um so basically just kept going with
clientele that way I have a couple of
long-term uh people that would work with
as well one of them um I'm wearing the
shirt for
dramar um who put poetas on the
map um they're the reason why you think
of poinsetta as like a um sort of a
Christmas plant and there's a funny
story that goes along with it they were
um they had green houses since like the
they were like built in like the
1970s um long story
short said is used to only have a single
stalk and a single flower
but now uh they found one that they
found that one had multi branching and
so they were able to propagate a lot
quicker which allowed it to become more
successful as a plant but um is that the
same cultivar that they use
today yes but well here's the thing okay
sorry I didn't yes no here's the here's
the here's the interesting twist they
thought it was genetic right okay U
because the trait was vertically
transmitted not a lot of things do that
that one thing does though they found
that it was actually this it is genetic
but it's not endogenous it was a microbe
that was inside their uh body
phytoplasma phytoplasma is a really
interesting bacteria a lot of times they
are um really damaging and they are
often times they have to be vectored by
an insect so like we have a really
destructive one called uh honglong Bing
or Citrus Greening disease um or yellow
dragon disease if you want the Chinese
literal translation and that
um that just messes up Citrus uh in
California in Florida
elsewhere and uh
this uh this phytoplasma is really
detrimental but the one that was in the
poinsettas just had this um hormonal
effect essentially and it caused the
plant to sort of multibranch and because
it was able to even transmit through the
parentage people thought it was genetic
but it's
not that's I mean it makes me think of
something like hops Laten vroid or
something that is uh vertically
transmittable across um uh cuting uh as
well as even potentially uh progyny seed
stock and so but you know I guess it
sounds like you wouldn't have found this
in say a seed stock population from poas
where you were then trying
to uh narrow down this trait that you
were looking for uh but it was then
caused by the the virus or the the
bacteria you said um yeah exactly that's
super fascinating so what did they end
up somehow removing the
um the phytoplasma from the poinsetta
and lose this desirable trait or were
they able to narrow it down to what it
was and somehow stabilize that within
the plant further or or I'm just that's
so
fascinating I'm not sure of the details
but I do know
that um I think they found this out by
accident originally and I think it was
because if I remember right it could be
remembering wrong but I think that the
um part of the part of the reason it was
discovered uh by
accident was because the um
the uh the ability to detect these
phytoplasmas recently became more common
or something and so so like when they
were going through some sort of um
indexing process they discovered
it wow and and but did they is this the
same then uh so it sounds like from what
I asked earlier that this is the same
cultivar that they're still using to
have the multibranch
poas and um it's is it still due to this
this
phytoplasma
um uh
bacteria yeah you know I'm not sure if
they make use of the phytoplasma still
or if they've been able to actually
achieve um a a like a genetic and
perhaps more reliable um mode of action
I'm actually not sure if it's the same
one uh and also um you know if they
breed with other cultivars and they and
some of the bacteria pass down um
perhaps it's still not the same cultivar
technically but um but I do I do not
know it could be that this is no longer
like the case anymore okay well I mean
along the same uh strand of questioning
just considering it has to do with
poinsettias um considering that they're
also a a scoto dependent plant similar
to
cannabis what would you are there any
other similarities that you see with
something that requires uh a specific
longer night cycle um when it comes to
Pest Management that you wouldn't
necessarily see in other uh crop
plants uh could you say that one more
time sorry I might have jumbled my words
a little bit but considering that both
like point setas and cannabis require a
certain amount of uh Darkness period in
order to trigger their flowering have
you seen any similarities within the
pest manag agement approaches between
those two in terms of uh specific pests
that you might find with something that
it has a longer night night
period
H I don't think scoto periodicity is a
big part of it but I think that um you
often like a lot of people who grew
ornamentals like cut flowers like Gerra
um which these people did uh Gerra you
can see there's a lily here
Cy um Ros is uh ornamentals in general I
think people have experienced with them
do it does lend themselves to um aspect
of cannabis biology like having you know
scod period dependent development um
often being annual although not always
um with some
manipulation
um and I would also say that like you
know there's some literature very old
examples of like solitary isolated
literature that used to describe um
cannabis as being like in the con in the
in the capacity as hemp um pretty pest
resistant but um then I've also seen
more recent literature that has like and
the only reason I know about it because
they targeted these statements and are
like I don't know what they're talking
about that's not been our
experience um so but I do think what
what cannabis has going for it and what
I find very beautiful about the plant is
actually that it has a lot of the same
charm as a bamboo or uh for me at least
or like even like a
dandelion um or or similar type of plant
that like Hawk beard that grows really
vigorously or thistle um starts out kind
of herbaceous hardens off and becomes
like Woody and just grows really fast so
I find that trait really uh I don't know
I just think that's really cool that it
can grow so fast and something come if
like a cow or an animal comes in and
munches it down it can still like
outgrow it you
know nominally I agree it is one of the
coolest Parts about like the cannabis
plant where it it grows so rapidly when
given the correct environment and
conditions for growth it it'll you know
outgrow almost anything else in your
garden other than like a a really well
maintained tomato or something during
the summer but even those They Don't
Really necessarily get that Woody stock
they're not like a you can't really turn
them into a tree I guess the best you
can do is maybe a a a very long Vine but
um yeah it it is really fascinating with
cannabis how how quickly it grows and
you can see this entire life cycle in
the course of three months let's say um
right yeah so that is really fascinating
you know and how the traits are passed
from uh like the parent lineage down to
offspring in cannabis compared to things
like tomatoes or potatoes or corn or
things you don't see such huge vast
differences within the the progyny um to
in my experience um but maybe you have a
different experience with that I I I'd
like to actually get back a little bit
into where you then pivoted and
transitioned your focus into um cannabis
uh integrated Pest management
application and then also ask about your
own personal experiences with growing
cannabis um I know that you have in the
past but aren't currently and so maybe
we can talk a little bit about
that well uh I mean cannabis was in the
beginning even like pre- beginning
through two degree okay um but uh with
regards
to like what I was growing myself or
like uh or like the kinds of things that
people were growing or or well let's
let's uh maybe make it a two-parter
let's talk a little bit about your own
personal experience uh just to get a
little bit of a grasp of uh what you've
uh personally experienced with growing
cannabis and then also what you um when
you transitioned into making that more
of your professional path with
integrated Pest
Management oh sure well I would say that
like my favorite example is I have three
I have three big stories for me
personally growing I actually had um you
know despite this is not necessarily
like how I I recommend uh people in a
commercial space or something quasi
commercial whatever you call all of this
um uh you know I wouldn't recommend
necessarily growing this way but I like
when it's just me and I don't really
care too much and I have other avenues
of access and that kind of a thing so
that's the context that I'm bring up
here I actually am a big over grow type
person I'm also a big like I I enjoy
having a plants kind of grow without a
whole lot of um interaction on my
part uh sometimes if I really care about
the produce or that kind of a thing like
like I have a low quat tree that I
planted when I was in my parents um uh
house when I was like a teenager and we
still grow we still take the low quats
out you know today as a big tree and you
know sometimes I've cut it back so that
I can get a certain yield or or whatever
but generally I'm actually kind of like
a uh said and forget it type person and
I also prefer to not like have a bunch
of
rigamarole um uh and like lights and
that kind of a thing myself personally
but I love visiting people who do that
kind of stuff um I would say that my my
my most um
informative uh growing was actually when
I was uh growing with my friends
um who were up in the high desert in
like do you know where Lone Pine
California
is I don't but is that like or Bishop
yeah
yeah yeah so it's by it's around that
area sort of the uh the Ino
um uh
land and um they had a river fortunately
they had access on the land to a river
that went down and they were growing the
the cannabis plants in the sort of high
desert high heat uh you know very high
solar
radiation context with a little bit of
shade from like some um oak trees I
believe they were uh and this like kind
of river that would irrigate it and that
was like a really cool but very
interesting um situation because in some
way when it was night time you get all
kinds of bugs people who've never been
in the desert and especially the high
desert of um California
uh Southwest North America in general is
um full of bugs that love to be
attracted to light some things um but
during during the day it can be really
hot um and some bugs will not be very
active and some bugs uh might actually
actually get there and but you are kind
of insulated because the only things
around you are scrubby
life for sure and so so were they like
growing the plants uh kind of like
directly next to the river and just
allowing the river to irrigate them that
way where they didn't have to water them
that's right it was really cool yeah I
mean it sounds a lot like your style of
set it and forget it you know you got
the shade there to take care of them so
that they don't necessarily get burnt
and they have plenty of access to water
and probably very nutritious water as
well considering all the different silt
and stuff that gets move down the river
and any Biologicals from fish or frogs
or other uh Wildlife that kind of is
near the streams and whatnot so that's
that's super fascinating
um but I I do know about the California
high desert and the bugs that you can
get there you can get lots of um not
necessarily locusts but uh Grasshoppers
and um other things that'll just they'll
chew through a a crop of plants and no
time
flat and then you also have the
people uh you do have to account for
sometimes in uh in in desert locations
there can be some uh Wanderers who
are looking for something interesting to
do with their day fair enough and I mean
uh you know I feel like as human beings
if we see sort of a an outcropping of
trees or some Greenery in a vast
landscape of uh desert you're going to
be drawn to it regardless of what your
intentions are um absolutely it's very
beautiful I'll never forget my favorite
uh memory of that place is when it's
maybe like 10 it's been like 10 years
now
maybe um something like that maybe
longer and there was like this huge snow
event and despite it being like the
desert um you know there was like tons
of snow packed um uh away from the road
so like they had to like divert all the
snow off the road and you know it just
like stayed there for a very long time
it was crazy to see that and I guess it
it's very rare um but like yeah the the
mountains and everything is is very is
very peaceful um I find it really I
think people who have never experienced
it there's a desolate beauty of of the
area and I found that was very um
insightful I I could agree with that I
feel like you always see in uh in movies
and stuff the Trope of people who are
taking psychedelics and go out to the
desert to experience their their
psychedelic uh trip because it it is
like peaceful and there's just less
around you to distract you from whatever
that is that you're trying to
experience um and then so from from that
experience
um when you started to become more
heavily involved in the Cannabis uh
Market as an integrated past Pest
Management specialist what were some uh
what were some experiences you had there
that you'd like to share I mean there's
so many that I could I think that uh for
those who might be like listening and
wondering to get some like IPM
Insight um I think I would say that like
a big takeaway that's actually
surprisingly absent uh in a commercial
space too is actually to
like know what could be a
threat surprising how many people don't
even know some of these basic
um I wish I could say it was like really
I mean it gets complicated at scale and
different regions um and different
seasons can be different too I think not
appreciating that as much as you could
um which is like a really common problem
in all kinds of business right so it's
not unique to cannabis but I feel like
that's a really big aspect um many like
different stories and anecdotes of mine
could maybe be boiled down to this like
maxim of like Step
Zero learn the bugs and also learn what
people do about them and also learn what
you can do about them for your unique
context um and it's hard to account for
like 50 plus possibilities and maybe
like 10 to 15 really common um things
that people will deal with but I think
if you know to be forewarned is to be
forearmed um and that's a message I like
to share for free to very people on my
YouTube channel uh that's why the pest
primer series um is what it is because I
would get all these questions from
people and I firmly believe in the
business statement that like you have to
be better than a Google Search and
that's something I've said many times
but uh up until just this very moment I
realized that it's out moded because
people now use um you know machine
learning and AI now with the search
engine
um uh ruaha that people have been
talking about so but you know
essentially people can find out
information your job is not to be a
knowledge Silo and be like give me money
for the secret technique um because the
ultimate answer is almost always it
depends on what you can or can't do and
it's under it's working under those
experiences and constraints that um
allows uh somebody to be I think
informative um but no one's had every
single experience either right so right
right I mean it's like somewhere in
between education and intuition um that
makes the the human um approach to these
different problems and solutions much
more
um it it just it may it's I feel like
there's a more um I'm missing the word
right now but it it helps when it comes
to trying to figure something out if
rather than it being this rigid like yes
no uh like like deduction versus
induction type reasoning yeah yeah yeah
I agree with you you you have to put on
your think your like Sherlock Holmes cap
for
sure what what are some of the
experiences that you've had then with um
integrated Pest Management that you felt
were um some of the biggest learning
curves uh for yourself maybe that kind
of fit into this idea of needing to um
find a solution that fits the problem in
a specific
scenario I think that like I think that
the biggest one could
be like learning what isn't a threat too
what I just maybe the converse of what I
just said like because I've had people I
mean I've had people bring in um you
know I've had people panic over nothing
and find out they spent a lot of money
time and effort on something that wasn't
an issue like some soul might or
something that was sort of Common Place
um as well uh but it comes from the
right place I think
also um something I've kind a bit of a
white whale for me and you tell me if
this is answering your question or if
you want me to be more um uh precise in
the in the answer but I feel as
though
uh like people will believe something
without
um looking at the data and that could
either be because they're ambivalent
about it um or they're desperate and
they don't have the time or even like
the technical knowledge to like make an
assessment that's what you're for you
know for example or some somebody
they've hired you know an employee or
something like that in the commercial
space and if it's just you growing with
your friends it's still the same
scenario it's just you and your friend
who's helping you out with something if
you both don't know something it's
effectively the same problem
um uh so I feel
like feel like that is a an issue that
that's quite common and the only way you
amarate that is by you know being
open-minded trying to learn this stuff
and when people like give you a
solution you know
um at least try to like look try try to
find out you know just other people also
agree with this you know it's just
surprising to me how often I've come
across people who like I'll give you an
example have you heard people say
something like um py Milo is not a
problem of the pest as much as it's a
problem of like air flow let's
say right I've I've totally heard that
where then people think oh I I I just
need to adjust my airf flow and the
powdery mildew is going to go away or um
MH yeah I've I've totally ran into that
but it it's not I I I feel like I see
where you're going with this where it's
like if you already have powdery mildew
then the air flow isn't the problem
anymore the powdery mdeo is now the
problem
um maybe air flow was the reason why it
uh occurred but even that is kind of a
misnomer because you need to take into
account uh heat and humidity and airf
flow and um other uh either high
humidity events or low humidity events
that could cause a sporulation event and
it just requires all these different
angles to be looked at
um rather than just oh it's airf flow
boom there you go take
that right because humidity is a is
actually like a cumulative factor of
things right right and also having the
pest is a factor of also other things
and those mesh together um so yeah
essentially because whenever I ask
people what do you mean by that they
can't really tell me what they mean by
that it's just an it's like a logical
amulet it's like this is my my you know
this is my anti- snake Mouse you can
tell because there's no snakes here yeah
it works exactly so like that kind of
stuff like violence and ice cream right
um yes exactly the coration yeah the
sale of ice cream goes up because
violence is high and it's like no it's
hot as hell out and people are agitated
and they like ice cream when it's
hot right right exactly right exactly so
like you know and again like you know
Are you seriously Matt you know basic
logical issues are the are the problem
sometimes yeah yeah actually because it
is complex it so the word the the most
um uh interesting might not be the best
word but like the the things where I
feel like I feel the most accomplished
or I feel like something really good
happened here wasc was situations where
people who were doing everything right
and they knew and they're like talented
and they've got an expert panel of
people and they're doing everything's
good but then like something something
that they thought was true is now false
or something I thought that was false is
now true perhaps and then it becomes a
forensics question because the system
worked fine until just now so something
has happened here and it's really um
knowing like a bunch of Niche
esoterica uh is really great in that
scenario um where you have an entire
system of like hundreds of thousands or
millions of dollars grind to a halt
because uh there's a new fungus in town
um and maybe your protocols weren't up
to Snuff or they were but somebody was
doing something wrong because you hired
them new or recently or whatever um all
of these things can come together and
coales yeah absolutely it makes me think
of um like how there's the
uh there's a video of like a petri dish
where it has different layers of um
antibiotics on it that are at different
strengths and then they put the bacteria
at the one end of the petri dish and it
hits these antibiotics takes a while to
break through them but then eventually
breaks through them because of either uh
reproduction uh creating some sort of
resistance to that bacteria or to the
antibiotic like a selection pressure the
ones that survive right you know are 10%
but then those all survive so then it's
100% And you know yeah for sure yeah and
it just keeps going and so sometimes
when you when you do get into like
almost uh cuz growing is monotonous
right it it is the same process over and
over and over again and I feel like a
lot of people don't necessarily take
that into account when trying to enter
into the cultivation field they think
that it's it's fun they're going to be
feno hunting and they're going to be
having all this this cool weed that they
can test or try out and oh look at us
we're growing these awesome flowers
um but in the end like it when you get
you know 20 crops deep in one year and
then you get to the next year and it's
well you're maybe expanded so now it's
30 crops in that year and it's just over
and over and over again things are the
same and if you don't notice where those
different you know like maybe a standard
might falter because it wasn't you
weren't seeing an issue so you stop
paying attention to it then it falters
and then you go oh my my God yeah like
you said everything grinds to a halt and
they don't you don't know what it is so
you do have to be like I always say go
back to basics try to just restart um
and and and make sure that you do have
good plans in place and and Sops
especially when it comes to integrated
Pest Management that if you aren't just
trying to reset if you can't figure it
out then it's going to be something like
a cha tasing event that uh does kind of
hinder the the progress overall the grow
um so when you when you found these uh
or had these experiences where it was
satisfying because it was sort
of you know everything was working then
all of a sudden it were it wasn't um
what are some of those pitfalls that you
see you tend to see um whether it be IPM
or otherwise that you've been able to
help people identify with it their
grows uh I'm tempted to say that a lot
of times it's actually it could be like
a um I think this is true at any scale
actually whether it's like a large scale
commercial situation or it's a
relatively small cottage uh scale or
even just somebody growing for
themselves so it's scale it's scale
agnostic but actually it's like you know
something changed with the Personnel if
it's one person you know then it's like
you are that person but in general like
changes in people in what you might call
like infrastructural wisdom or or like
uh infrastructural knowledge or
institutional knowledge um is really
important it's oftentimes hard to
quantify right uh and a lot of people I
think understand this in like their
heart of hearts uh that like you know
there's like this thing and like now
that that is not there anymore for
whatever reason somebody left or uh
maybe those people people who are
executing uh are having something going
on or maybe they're doing fine but the
equipment that they use you know didn't
get checked a certain way so the you
know the people who are applying
something were fine but unfortunately
the product wasn't mixed or you know
things like this where it's often times
like a sort of a cacophony of different
Small Things um sort of breaking down um
and you don't notice it uh for example
but potentially at least you don't
notice it
because um if you're doing preventative
stuff and there just happens to be no
snakes you know to go back to the amulet
example um then you think everything's
fine but then as soon as it breaks down
uh when I was working with the Gerber
grower people here uh we had uh we had a
really big scare because there was
powdery
mildew
and uh we applied or we didn't I didn't
but they applied um a fungicide for it
and there was no effect and pesticide
companies take this very seriously
there's a lot especially with powdered
mil do but a lot of other pathogens they
have have been known to develop
resistances within the season that a new
product is like introduced or even
beforehand uh because the selection
pressure is already there but we found
out that the product just wasn't
applied
oops oh but they claim that it was
applied well we thought that it was
applied and then they thought they
thought it was applied too like it
wasn't um subterfuge it was like oops it
just didn't like it
didn't job that called in sick that day
or something as simple as that yeah I I
do not remember exactly how it happened
but I think it has to do with um uh who
was mixing versus who was applying and
some kind of a some kind of an honest
mixup because they I think they found
the mixed up product oh well this was
obviously the thing uh cuz if it got
sprayed then it obviously it would be
out there and so else happened like just
with water and so that's what happen got
it but that kind of stuff happens and it
costs like lots of money right and time
and stuff I mean it it you know you do
never think about it until um yeah you
either lose that worker that's been
doing all these little things to you
know putting the gum in between this and
that so they hold together for just long
enough uh you know going and kicking
this one piece of equipment right in the
right spot every day to make sure that
it kicks on um I mean obviously those
are silly examples but I do true though
yeah but very true um I know that CU I I
manage a facility and there are so many
little things that have to be done
regularly and um some of them
irregularly where it's more of a you
have to notice that the water lines are
starting to slow down to think oh I got
to go and clean out the filter for this
one this one line that doesn't really
need cleaning that often but only when
it does start to affect the the flow of
water for instance um stuff like that is
very
uh it's like you very user dependent
almost where you have to have the The
Experience uh or experience dependent I
guess um just to make sure that you are
hitting all those or checking off all
those boxes that need to be checked off
just to make sure that everything is
continuing to move in the direction that
you want it to for the production of the
facility
um so what
uh maybe I'll I'll leave it open just
for a little bit here what are some
other uh stories that you wanted to talk
about perhaps um when it comes to either
IPM or cannabis or
otherwise I think that uh something I've
been on a kick on is Research
into like I think having a respect for
pest I suppose let me back up and say
it's very important I think that like
going back to the original reason why I
even got into all this was having an
affinity for something that a lot of
times uh was a pest or a problem um for
the plant maybe in the forest or in the
ecosystem we don't really care as much
but as a crop pest certainly a problem
um and I think that like it lulls people
into a sort of false sense of
superiority necessarily security
although they can derive that feeling
from there uh but I think it is sort of
like a feeling like you know I've heard
all kinds of weird claims like um you
know a a a plant at some weirdly
Quantified level of Health whatever that
means um you know just cannot get pests
or it's not possible for it to succumb a
lot of times it sounds if it sounds like
U like vitalism if you've heard of this
uh sort of um esoteric concept this like
uh it's like uh like there's
a a Vitality that just can't be um it's
almost like a spiritual argument rather
than like one that's maybe you know I
don't know I'm not a specialist in that
sort of thing but I think that if I had
made that comment to a client they would
laugh at me um and maybe like I don't
know press charges
like I don't think that's accepted um
you know for a lot of people but some
people um make these claims or they make
something um around that and some people
seem to find it convincing and it's and
it's like the snake amulet you know it's
fine until they actually deal with
something where it wasn't fine enough or
they were benefiting from something else
potentially um another in this rut and
so that kind of thing too is problematic
I think and uh is why I try to be so
empirical all the time sure I mean if if
feels like another um confusion of cause
and correlation um just like if you if
you go um oh I have uh the the
healthiest crops the the most productive
crops that I have are from the
healthiest plants and my healthiest
plants don't have pest problems so the
health of my plants is causing the pests
to go away and it uh not necessarily
it's probably more about your either
refined or um adequate integrated Pest
Management applications that are causing
the pest to go away which are causing
your plants to be healthier which is
causing your yields to go up or your
quality to go up or or something along
those lines I I see it all the time uh
especially um you know in facilities
where people were battling pests of some
kind and then they are able to either
reduce them below the economic threshold
or remove them all together and all of a
sudden everything is working so much
better um and it does kind of show how
important it is to have uh a really good
integrated P Pest Management either
specialist like yourself uh on call or a
really good plan in place that can be
applied by the staff already
um what are some of the um the biggest
things that you're seeing currently that
people are battling with in uh in Pest
Management um whether that be like pest
themselves or the application of
specific uh protocols or
methods uh well it's kind of related to
the one before I would say like um crop
scouting like there's various pests that
are really common again I've been on a
kick on that respect for pests and part
of that respect is like um you know like
resistance capabilities like you had
mentioned just now pretty Prett pretty
eloquently um and the importance of like
understanding that like maybe this
season it was okay uh and maybe for many
seasons in your particular area it's
just fine you get passed over like
that's just statistics it happens um
people ask me like like you just said
with the IPM plan like oh what you know
why don't use that why am I okay I don't
know it just you know but maybe like
maybe in if I can't tell you I can't
prove a negative I don't know what to
tell you um no maybe this maybe the
amul's real okay but no um but my but
the thing that I think a lot of people
you know a big thing for me I think is
is having the logistical bandwidth to
evaluate your own crop at a regular
interval uh seems to be like the start
and stop of a lot of issues um again
like people can do things like probably
your experience has been this as well um
you know you had the right plan it just
didn't get executed as timely as maybe
would have been IDE deal um and then you
have knockoff effects on that and so on
the often times being able to sort of
really ship that up the problem is that
it does require investment of time it
does require sometimes that you trust
somebody or you are going to be the
person who does it and then you trust
somebody with something else that you
couldn't trust somebody with before um
so that's kind of like it's I think that
is like the the pre- barrier to even
considering it so that is what do you
think about
that um I I do find that especially when
it comes to the commercial application
of things that having
a um a preventative measure in place
rather than a reactive measure in place
is always going to be your best bet and
by yes putting that responsibility into
someone else's hands you're saying that
I I'm prioritizing this responsibility
to someone other than myself hopefully
that is due to the case that you're
prioritizing higher or or more important
things to your own
responsibilities um but in some cases uh
I found like even even with some of the
more simple tasks within a grow
environment that by taking those on
yourselves and passing on a more complex
um aspect of the grow to someone else it
not only teaches them but it also helps
make sure that you can then rely on them
further with uh even bigger more um
important tasks in the future but it
does mean that you have to trust them
and especially with IPM it's one of
those things that if you don't
uh I guess misplaced trust can be a huge
huge downfall in um in certain aspects
of
cultivation uh one of the things that
I've experienced recently was we had a
few aphids um in in the grow and they
came in off of cuting that we took from
an outdoor population trying to preserve
them from a feno hunt uh those aphids
came inside we tried to isolate them we
then uh had a spreading event of some
kind can't pinpoint it down to exactly
when it happened but it did we were then
able to Target and treat those pests
while continuing to try to stay on top
of the rest of the crop without applying
harsh chemicals or a harsh chemistry and
that eventually led to you know small
populations moving throughout the
facility and eventually ending up in a
flowering room and uh you know making
part of the crop um UNH harvestable
basically uh
which you know you you can't necessarily
say well it's because we brought the
cuting in from outside I mean yes you
could go all the way back to that and
say that's the exact reason why we had
aphids and of course that is the reason
why we had aphids but there were other
potential ways to prevent their spread
that necessarily either weren't
addressed early enough or aggressively
enough and we eventually had a little
bit of crop loss um and you know that is
also
in mind keeping in mind that we we
really did try to stay on top of it and
we
were I think the the biggest downfall
was trying to bring clones in from
outside um which is something that I
don't plan on doing in the future but it
was something that we at least can now
say hey we did a lot to try and prevent
the spread of both pathogens and pests
and it didn't work so we either need to
try something different next time this
happens or we need to say we just don't
have it within our bandwidth to prevent
this from happening so we just should
prevent it by not doing
it I feel like well like for example the
fact that you even were was able to
recount you were able to recount all of
that and maybe part of it supposition
you know like a lot of times you can't
like you can't actually know you have to
like trace and act like a detective and
kind of piece things together even
though you can't like cast a spell and
like know what happened I don't see
their tracks through the grow right I
don't see right exactly right but you
know but like being able to kind of like
forensically analyze yourself even and
being able to have the team and and also
the like you know wherewithal to do that
even is like really important I mean
that that's really commendable because
that's what allows you to make those
informed decisions afterwards and have
and hopefully maybe even have data
ideally you would like uh you know you
would you would
have you know tracked it like during a
quarantine phase you know so like taking
the cuting isn't necessarily the bad
part like you said it's like is it the
fault of you taking cuting I mean in a
way it's the fault that the person
giving you the plants head bugs oh but
you shouldn't trust them well it's not
about trust it's about fault so
sometimes I think people naturally also
I think are a little denigrating there
too when it comes to like whose fault is
it um I mean it was it was all our fault
right like it was all our fault there's
all our fault there's no one else that
there was many layers right there's this
like there's this like survivability
onion and the first layer wrapped away
and the second layer went away and also
the third and the fourth so there were
multiple small failures um but the fact
that you even had checks in the is
better than most people
anyways fair enough yeah we
um I I really like our approach to IPM
uh at the facility I help manage um it
was helped design by uh Suzanne Wayne
Wright Evans and she's also uh you know
really well educated and and um
approachable uh person like yourself
when it comes to cannabis pests um
because there are a lot of people that
don't necessarily have the direct
experience with cannabis crops and pests
or um or they're just applying uh
chemistries that might work in other
crops that have similar pests you know
like they oh it's a soft-bodied insect
we can use this um so I I do really
appreciate it especially considering
from someone like yourself who um as far
as I know were and might still be uh a
user of cannabis products um that you
know applying the wrong chemistries at
the wrong times makes the end product
sometimes uh unusable for people with
either
specific uh conditions or ailments or
sensitivities
um uh what I guess uh to get back though
to some of your experience within the
Cannabis
cultivation uh
industry what what are some of the uh
biggest successes that you've seen where
you went into a facility they had a huge
problem you gave them
a maybe even like a simple plan and they
followed it and boom took care of
it oh uh my favorite example probably is
from dramar again just because of the
scale and one of my one of my earlier
ones earliest ones where I felt like I
was super valuable uh was um actually
one of the major one of the major
reasons I was even contracted with
them was because they had some people
who had been growing they had some
workers who had been there for like 35 5
years um and they didn't want to learn
how to use new technology like an iPad
uh to scout for plants um and if I'm
being
honest uh you know they were extremely
talented people um and and I totally get
not wanting to like learn something some
new fangled thing but unfortunately you
know they were duplicating data a lot um
and so that took a lot of their time uh
but the pest that they dealt with that
we we together developed a system for
was a leaf Miner fly in Gerra daisies
not normally a pest of Gerra but um for
those who don't know what Leaf Miner is
it's a um it's a fly uh usually Lial
Misa um they have a yellow black body
and they're kind of pretty mosa Pinta
the painted fly in Spanish and um what
would happen is that the larv are are
laid in the leaf materials eggs and then
they as they grow together they create
these like patterns in the leaves cuz
they're they're mining through it
creating these tunnels and then they
come out they pupate become a fly and
the cycle continues
now uh their leaves had gotten
skeletonized they were so full of leaf
minor fly um and they got really bad I I
still remember the weeks um the peak
time we would get them is week 29 so
weeks 29 through 32 was like I think if
I'm checking my name my time right
that's like the dead of Summer like June
or July somewhere um and we would see we
would use this iPad uh we would track
the uh numbers of flies that we would
get on the glue traps that we put in
each greenhouse and somebody would come
around collect all of them literally
count all of them input that information
into a data program and then we wouldd
see that data visualize very key not a
lot of people do this but it's really
useful because when we release these
wasps called diglyphus which we've used
um several times in the past uh we would
get some effect but event but we were
able to use the data to see exactly when
the leaf miners would go up I did a
regression analysis to kind of check the
relationship and um basically long story
short we saved uh like
$250,000 of um basically product loss a
combination of a product gain or getting
rid of the loss and uh more efficient
use of the diglyphus which were pretty
expensive at like 50 cents a wasp and
you get like hundreds at a time um that
is
expensive um as a as a you know if
you're releasing a mass population into
a uh what I'm assuming is like a large
Greenhouse area or something like that
with you know active fans and stuff that
are just going to decimate any bugs that
get pulled into those streams and
um but was it just by adjusting the
release date perhaps um in correlation
to the population boom to help make sure
that it kept it under
control yeah so like that that those
like two or three weeks are like the the
place where we get like the most damage
because you're seeing the adults so the
adults the adult population goes up so
the laral population is about to go up
and then you don't see that because
they're not in the sticky card and then
you see the adult population next the
next week or two
so uh being really successful here was
allowed us allowed me to convince um you
know my
collaborators the people who hired me
the admin staff were loved it the people
who had to who had to learn how to use
the iPad were not huge fans uh at the
beginning uh but then you know they just
couldn't look at that and
go whatever uh so they were really that
allowed them to buy into a process that
actually made their lives really simple
once they learned how to use it and then
then they really liked it um and yeah it
was adjustment of the timing for that
but then it also made us not have to buy
so many in the future too so it was kind
of a double whammy and then we continued
to do that for the rest of that season
and then moving into um you know because
like Valentine's Day and Mother's Day
are the biggest flower days so we really
couldn't we couldn't let the dam the
plants get super damaged because they
were we would have them for multiple
years so if they got really damaged in
like
summertime and then autumn and winter we
wouldn't have as much sunlight so if
they come in they get stunted it gets
cold and then they come into spring
really raggedy and so that would have
this like multi-year effect
unfortunately so we were able to kick
that um and it was really uh salubrious
to their
health that's really cool I I do like
that sort of knock on effect of um when
when you can Target the pest early
um you know all of the ramifications of
that and the increase in plant health
over time um even in a short crop like
cannabis is extremely beneficial um you
know catching it early rather that's you
know also why I had said earlier it's so
much more beneficial to be preventive
than reactionary or reactive um so uh
when
when now with that being the the Gerber
a daisies um have you had any sort of
immediate uh successes where you you
know you went and found the problem
analyzed the uh the what was causing the
problem and then were able to implement
a solution all within the course of
perhaps one grow cycle within
cannabis oh yeah oh yeah um uh for one
example like rice through AIDS are
really common uh so like I I usually get
like two schools of thought with people
one is people who have like one person
told me recently it was like I'm going
to paraphrase it but it was like my
experience with aphids is um is like
small and harrowing you know like really
bad so the only experience I had was
terrible but I don't have that much
experience so you know people tell me it
can be dealt with can can we do this and
then we have people who have like kind
of learned what works best for them and
assuming that they like screen for them
and they find them early there's there's
no problem for them too so it's like it
can be very different it can be very
different but um I think my favorite
example probably exists within a rice
root aphid example where um I think my
favorite one is when I was working with
this indoor grow and they had been
dealing with rice through aid for like
two years at that point which I actually
wasn't aware of um at first
um they actually transplant they had to
bring all their plants from a different
location to this location um and they
just kind of brought them with them um
they were already aware of
them uh and the main issue was basically
that I think it was it was really a
matter of uh not getting enough
effectively coverage because they act
well again kind of like other examples
I've mentioned like they knew some of
the products to use um and they
knew um that you had to apply it maybe
more than once like that wasn't a
mystery or anything uh but for whatever
reason it just wasn't enough and so we
had to bump up the um we actually got
very creative uh we had to bump up the
buvia basana produ uh use so for those
who don't know that's a fungus that
attacks various insects um in this case
the rice root Aid and we actually ended
up dunking I think a few times we
actually ended up like dunking the
entire pot in like a huge amount of like
inocula and you could see all these AIDS
get microsized like little furry puff
balls all around the um the the pots and
the and the roots and things when we
would check and it was very significant
it was laborious though um and we we had
to do it more than Thrice but it was
effective did you use any anything else
with the Bavaria basana as a as a
knockdown or anything um within that
that root ball
drenching yeah that's right we
alternated if I remember correctly uh
between a pyin product and an aid
duratin product cool yeah those yeah
which are usually my favorite one one
two punches yeah I I couldn't agree more
those those three uh in conjunction seem
to be the only thing that I've ever been
able to use in order to knock down um
rice rud AIDS cuz they're one of the
most pernicious pests that I've ever
dealt with in terms of that you think
you get rid of them and then all of a
sudden you see a flyer somewhere and
you're just like [__] that means
that there is a population somewhere
that I have not been able to track down
or eradicate and unlike
um uh fungus nuts where you can pretty
much you know scrape away the top layer
of potting mix that you're using uh
apply something like bavia bosana or
um uh is it basilis the andensis that
works well on on um on uh fungus Nets as
well oh yeah be basil is israelensis I
think bti is the fly screen yeah exactly
the mosquito dunks um yeah yeah so you
know you can get rid of those pretty
easily but then with with rice root
aphids they seem to be able to burrow uh
well into the pot and unless you really
get a good drench through the entire
substrate it seems as though they just
aren't
necessarily uh they're just not easy to
get rid of um I recently found a product
botanigard Max where it is pyrin and
Bavaria bosana and I have been really
enjoying that for just uh preventative
um works well on
uh uh fungus nuts as well so
I but yeah finding the right chemistry I
feel like that's and using the right
Amounts is so important um it's uh what
do I always hear the the label is the
law right so you have to make sure that
you're following it correctly and um
it's not just necessarily because they
don't want it to be toxic because like
some of these are are much safer than um
a lot of people are led to believe when
the pesticide uh you know name is added
to to what it is you you feel like a lot
of pesticides I feel like just based on
how media portrays them as being
extremely dangerous even to humans uh
but some of them are just very uh
inocula to humans and uh but work only
within the range that they're given you
know too much of it might eventually
make uh some sort of resistance species
in whatever you're trying to get rid of
or too little just doesn't do a thing um
you know speaking of selection pressure
you know that's that's actually a thing
that I think Cu uh um although people do
appreciate it I think sometimes they
don't appreciate that that also is true
for things like Biologicals too um even
copper I remember I was reading an
article from last year uh there was a
type of aphid uh that was colonizing
pepper plants in the Netherlands and
other parts of Europe and the reason why
copper made a statement was because they
found that actually the aphid was um
resistant to paraso wasp I'm not sure
how they Quantified that or or anything
but uh if they're talking about it then
you know I assume that they're willing
to be for forthright you know because
you'd have no reason to mention that
like kind of perversely incentivized not
to mention that but it's very
responsible thing to say if you feel
like that's true and we know that
there's aphids that have like little uh
viral um symbient of their bacteria in
their body that that create toxins that
kill these wasy
so yeah that's how it works so there's a
bacterio phage normally those kill
bacteria but it's actually lysogenic so
it's actually integrated into the Genome
of the bacteria and then that bacteria
has is in the um hamiltonella defensa is
in the uh is one example at least where
this process happens in a lot of aphids
and um so when the WASP puts it I know
right puts this egg in the body uh the
bacteria produces these um these toxins
and they kill the The larva as it
develops um and then also different
bacteria fages have different mutations
of these toxins that um make them more
or less survivable so it's really uh
really complex and um I think that
although it's not really possible to
check for this sort of thing in the
field um it's the kind of thing where
like like if you know this it Alters
your perspective on on ecology on your
Sops so the more you know the better
right it makes me think of the the
Marvel villain Venom where it's a like a
symbiote that that helps the you know
the wrong doings of this uh of this of
this villain almost like where the the
uh the aphids are the villain in this
but of course just uh me
anthropomorphizing
them no but like no I get what you're
saying no it's true true it's a it's a
deadly dance deadly dance it is it is I
I you know one of the things that I'm
always so very concerned about is the
overuse of specific pesticides like
pyrans where um considering it is just
like a contact kill uh due to the I I
believe it interferes with the nervous
system of the of the pest um that there
can be resiliences that develop in
populations over time and so again
that's also why applying the correct
amount of chemistry is so important
because if you don't kill them
um rapidly uh or at least knock down the
population rapidly then you have that
much more potential for them to gain
these different resiliences um are there
any experiences uh like that that you've
faced where people were applying the
same product over and over and over
again and a pest just eventually worked
its way back into their
settings uh yeah
sometimes it's hard to
confirm um it's hard to be like like
really like epistemologically sure uh
but sometimes it's a little bit
easier uh the example that always comes
to my mind was is a like La grower I
worked with maybe six years ago now and
they had
um they had a rice rud aord
problem but they had they had
ostensively they had gotten rid of it
they had no problems for a long time
they checked everything and then uh I
didn't find out this part until later
but we found that they had recently
uprooted a bunch of like this like like
Virginia creeper vine or some other kind
of Vine I forget now but like Ivy or
something that was all across their
building and that's one of the hosts for
Rice fruit aphid oh no um yeah so so it
seems like and also the reason why I was
so sure was there was also like uh like
like feral barley or Rye or whatever
that you see in cracks and sidewalks and
places you know everywhere and I pulled
out the roots and it's like there's a
rice rud Aid right there you know and
there were a couple of others that were
on like the plants and um you know in in
the in the property space and they had
this
door um going inside and it was like an
inch
like of of like CLE clearance which is
you know spacious for Rice fruit Aid um
and so I think that's what happened I
think maybe even the rice perhaps the
rice AIDS were inevitable at some point
um based on their proximity but you know
you might have had a happier couple of
Seasons um if you if that hadn't
happened so funny things that you don't
think about can become a huge
issue and then the same thing is true on
a macro scale so if you accept that as
true you know we should also consider
that as people grow more whether it's at
their home or commercially or whatever
um you know things like certain budw
worms cannabis aphids rice fruit aphid
other pests that are common other places
too you know maybe for 15 years
everything was fine growing where you
are um and then suddenly this influx
eventually builds up this critical mass
maybe it takes multiple years but then
once that started you know now you get
you know powdery mil d
um every year when you used to only get
it sometimes and you know people have to
consider that that can happen right
things don't St the CH the same
Everything Changes in a dynamic system
right absolutely it's
um yeah it goes back to some of the
earlier examples we were talking about
of um just be like if you stay
complacent within a specific system and
you don't necessarily look for the uh
potential pitfalls then you won't be
prepared when you run into them and um
things especially like um pests and
pathogens that can build up sort of that
threshold before they spill over and
become recognizable you know whether it
be uh through mold like the Spore count
within a facility if you're not
maintaining uh something as simple as
cleaning your floors uh and then you
kick up a bunch of dust and dirt all
those spores get a nice little ride on
the Airways over to whatever plants you
have a nice humid night and boom now you
have more more spores than you had
before because you have fruiting bodies
um and so it it can definitely be a a
knock on event of just a
continued
um you know continued maintenance and
continued um upkeep of the little things
can make a huge difference in the end
um let's see what are what are um so
when you do deal with hom Growers um
considering that you have a a presence
with the cheap hom Grow Show uh with the
growing with my fellow Growers and your
uh Instagram presence I know I
personally have reached out to you for a
quick question here and there about
something that I found within my grow
that I either couldn't find through a
Google search or otherwise um what are
some of the uh issues that you feel like
new growers face that you could give
some advice on
here uh I already gave a couple of good
ones know your know your bugs know your
potential
problems and also keep an open mind as a
corollary uh that new things can happen
too so you're not going to have the
whole picture no one has the whole
picture not even me um we just have I
maybe I have one of the more whole
pictures but um that's not the same
thing uh we're still learning things all
the time with cannabis and that kind of
thing um I think that you also made some
really great points too uh just even
basic hygiene is super invaluable um I
think that having you know finding the
time especially in a hom growth
situation should be easiest in some ways
to be able to actually look over your
plants being very detailed um you know
looking you know don't just look at the
leaves look under the leaves look if you
can at the crown of the plant where it
where it meets the substrate you know if
you can up poot the plant and look at
the roots do so um if that's
tenable um you know be I would say make
a regular habit of looking for also um
typical signs of damage uh I have pest
primer videos on my channel that goes
over what they look like various pests
and their damage and that kind of a
thing too but you know there's a lot of
really brilliant um
academic um uh resources for people as
well so you know it's out there it's
it's very much out there um for free for
people to learn so you just have to take
a little bit of time and kind of learn
some of those things that's super that's
like probably the best investment of
time you could you take like two or
three hours even you know a day for a
few weeks and you like really learn and
commit to memory some of these pests and
their common um treatments and I think
you'll you'll do really well uh
especially if you're newer and that kind
of a thing um and I guess also like the
the importance of um well I think I'll
I'll stay I'll I'll stop there H what do
you think of that I think that's great
um educate yourself absolutely is
probably uh especially when it comes to
pests and pathogens is going to be your
biggest tool um as a new grower uh if
you don't know what to look for uh you
won't spot it when it's there and
sometimes catching Things Early is the
best way to um prevent a a an absolute
loss in your crop as well as then you'll
have that under your tool belt to say
I've seen this I know what it looks like
when it starts I might be able to catch
it earlier next time or if you did find
a good way to get rid of it you can just
say hey I'm just going to incorporate
that in my preventative maintenance
rather than um having to ever deal with
this again but then you also have you
know the ability to deal with it if it
comes up um so I I think that's great
you know new new Growers especially when
it comes to pests and pathogens uh it's
it's not necessarily a taboo subject but
it is something that people don't like
to talk about because um it's
frightening it uh to to think that you
could lose all of this time and effort
that you put into a grow uh just because
you miss the fact that there is some
bugs in there or miss the fact that
there's some some mold in there
um and uh maybe maybe due to your
circumstances if your plant has any mold
on it at all then you need to dispose of
it or turn it into Edibles or something
like that um and that's not what you're
Desiring in your end product um but you
know also considering just how big of
a seems like a it like I don't know if
taboo is the right word but it seems
like it's just something where people
don't want to talk about it they don't
want to deal with it you know pests are
you know it's it's hard to deal with if
you get them and it's um you know even
harder to anticipate sometimes how you
need to prevent certain bugs at certain
times of years in certain environments
you know it's a lot to deal with um and
with all that in consideration do you
feel as though or what do you feel like
maybe um swept under the rug a little
bit within the industry where people try
to ignore perhaps the signs of issue
until it's too late
I think that sorry I think that a lot of
uh I think a lot of it come I think an
overs simple thing to say would be that
it comes down to Ego but it's not really
ego it's not really ego and here's what
I mean by that I think that that's maybe
sometimes part of it but it's not like
it's not like a lot of people in my
experience not like a lot of people are
growing whether it's cannabis or other
crops um you know a lot of times you're
not growing in a supportive environment
so uh you know in a healthy relationship
you're probably not going to get
everything wrong ooh shocker but you're
probably not going to get everything
right I should say ooh shocker um you
will make a mistake at some point um the
question is how big of a mistake and the
question also is you know are you know
does the company even appreciate that
you did every all this other stuff saved
them tons of money did whatever talented
person um or you know I guess it depends
on severity of course but my point is
that a lot of times you're not even
allowed to make mistakes a lot of times
that is going to be a ding to your
credibility or if something bad happens
and it's not even your fault in the
first place a lot of times a
Draconian um sort of overarching uh
perspective is the context and so that
causes and it's very common agriculture
um especially a lot of like super
hierarchy right so if that's the case
then there's not a perverse incentive to
not admit that you either know something
is a problem or that you um did anything
wrong sure and that doesn't create a
healthy system for
flexibility no and and I feel like
especially considering uh and maybe this
might be more a cannabis specific
scenario but there is so much branding
behind the different uh successful
businesses within this industry that if
yeah like no one wants to be associated
with improper practices um you know if
if you say Hey you like the way that
that smokes awesome I've been spraying
it with chemicals all the way up to week
four of uh flour and it still had mold
and some pests on it how do you like it
now um you know some people are going to
you know stare at you blank face because
they have no idea that cannabis was
grown as a plant in a crop you know
scenario and then some people are some
people are going to be disgusted by that
and say
oh well that's because you're growing
non-organically uh that's because you're
you know you know this that and the
other thing that they can start to point
fingers at um but yeah it's a p
perception is huge um when it comes to
uh branding and and the development of
Brands and the ability to maintain uh uh
you know a profitable business model
within what is currently one of probably
the I feel like it has like the the
biggest highs and the biggest lows right
now out of an agricultural industry
within the country uh maybe not outside
of the country but um for sure and
through my experience it it seems like
you know people want cannabis and they
want really good cannabis but they don't
want to keep spending more money on it
if it keeps getting better they don't
want to um learn more about it if
there's more to be learned about it uh
they just want the product which is
unfortunate Ely uh you know we are
within this capitalistic economy that we
live in and it's kind of par for the
course
um you know I keep hearing people say
that oh at some point this is going to
turn around the different the price
points of the different pounds that
people can sell within the commercial
Market um or that you know things are
going to get better uh but I I just
don't really see that happening I you
know as the as the cost of production
continues to go down the the product is
going to need to cost less as well and
as there's more Supply the and the
demand isn't necessarily going up it's
going to also Drive the price down and
so we're in for a reckoning of some kind
uh at you know to say the least um but I
do I do think that you know
uh you know people don't yeah people
don't really like to talk about the pest
aspect of things and they really don't
want to be viewed as someone who has
done something wrong um you know and and
I see how you could say that it is ego
but also how it it may not necessarily
be completely tied to Ego because you
know it is an ego that's selling your
product um it you know that may be I
mean depending on the brand right maybe
your brand is entirely egotistical and
all about yourself but um you know if
you're if you're hurting the brand or if
you're hurting the reputation of a
company then um ego does not help it
become uh you know re-rated to the
community yeah I I mean I think you made
a really Salient Point um and I mean
also from your perspective is one of of
information or of sorry of being
informed because you have this sort of
um you know this cultivation experience
here right to draw from and like yeah
and I guess like I'm I guess I'm very
I'm very hesitant to
blame uh like the individual for
everything um I do believe in in you
know individual like responsibility and
all that kind of stuff uh but you know
it's more like it's more like it comes
from like a game theory perspective
rather than you know like it's like the
buck stops here like if I was taught you
know I there was a pathway we didn't
investigate this in this um talk but
like there was a time in my life where I
wanted to join the US Army um up till
like middle of my teens and I didn't
actually end up doing that of course but
like I was taught I had Army instructors
and things um going to a military school
and stuff like that where uh you know
you were supposed to take that personal
responsibility so I get that I
understand that um but like at the same
time uh you you could be like the most
rational person you know uh and like you
understand that if I if I admit it to it
and I'm in a system that's not rational
then I can't act in the rational normal
way um I feel like I'm going to be
vulnerable and I don't actually think
I'm going to be project like protected
and if you're in an environment like
that like a lot of people then it it's
the system you have to look at the
system you look at the ecosystem look at
the cultivation system um it's all tied
together certainly um I don't think it
takes uh yeah I don't think it takes
like a um you know a member of Mena to
see that so no I mean uh prior to
cultivating I was Chef for around a
decade and uh then just you know working
in hospitalities for a bit longer than
that but um yeah PE people don't you you
have so much of the burden of
responsibility upon your shoulders
within a setting like that um because
you are semi- beholden to the customer
and and their experience with uh what
you're providing them and um considering
that cannabis is also another product
just like uh a nice uh you know a nice
dinner out at a fancy restaurant is
technically a product um and you can
immediately see who is providing you
that product right there uh and then in
cannabis with Through The Branding and
stuff and how people are trying to
connect themselves to these Brands
through social media and otherwise you
are directly connected to that end
product and the experience that the user
has and uh one thing that um my partner
and I have even been talking about
recently is like the set in setting of
different experiences and how those can
change your perspective and your view of
of something that may not even have to
do with uh the product itself if you're
experiencing like a product or the nice
dinner you know you could be in there in
a bad mood and it could be the best meal
in the world and it still would be a
shitty meal um that's so true so yeah we
we we do need to maybe take a little bit
more perspective of um how we are all
experiencing these things and uh
especially being a little bit more
understanding because this is a plant
right and plants do plant things plants
have bugs that are attracted to them and
uh maybe a little bit more humility and
openness uh in terms of telling people
more about the process of cultivation
and um even postprocessing like post
Harvest processing and stuff will
provide people with a
more uh beneficial understanding so that
you know the cultivator is maybe a
little bit more better understood um and
and all the plights that they face
within trying to get this product to the
end
user yeah like the solution
is um you know it's like what you like
what you said about like what the con
with the consumer what the person who's
going to uh receed the product end up
getting is you know they just they don't
really want to know all these details a
lot of times they just want to get the
thing and then have the thing um which I
get uh but then like similar but in like
a very similar way if somebody if like a
cultivator has a problem you know they
don't want to like have to learn they
want the fish given to them they don't
want to have to learn how to fish
especially I don't have any time to
learn how to fish um in this particular
moment right you
know you know give me yeah so so but
like the but you know like a robust
answer is always like Superior and like
you know it's like that saying like
every every problem has an answer that's
uh simple and wrong or whatever and so
so true um and I just think that like
everyone it is really I think an
informed Citizen's responsibility to
know what's going on and and like if you
abscond from that responsibility to like
being forms like I don't know how to
help you uh with that that's beyond you
know that's beyond my Ken but I think
that
like I think that like people like I get
why it's like kind of a self-reinforcing
vicious cycle where you know people
don't want to be open on one end and
other people have had to for a long time
not been open that was the Strat for a
long time in growing cannabis and um
yeah it's very and I think you're also
so I want to say that I feel like your
perspective on the market is is
realistic I also respect that cannabis
is more than a market product and I
think that's also an absolutely valid
perspective is also my perspective too
um but like obviously like the way that
most people acquire it is through a
market
and
uh you know people don't think about
like the bugs that are on their radishes
or their lettuce or or whatever and you
know um I you know it's like being a
client doctor I've said before not a lot
of people are like putting me on their
gram being like hey everyone today we
had hash rice root AIDS and we got Matt
here look at that stuff uh you know and
usually and a lot of times when people
bring me um it's not actually that bad
anyways uh um I'm usually pleasantly
surprised not always but um it it does
happen um um and it's kind of like with
you know digging in on farmers who are
like just trying to feed their families
and other people and are actually pretty
decent people um you know a minority of
people or or or some amount of people
who do maybe things that they shouldn't
and are able to get away with obviously
have made people very skeptical about
many things um but like you know I can't
I just can't knock most Farmers I
actually really enjoy working in in food
production and Agri culture um in
non-cannabis crops uh because I get a
genuine fulfillment like I feel like you
know it's like you know did you eat
today you know think a farmer you know I
just feel like I'm
enabling like yeah like the civilization
fundament practically um and so that
gives me a lot of uh uh it makes me feel
really good I felt best working in food
crops and I felt the least fulfilled
working I'm sad to say in ornamental
crops because that's just going in a
vase
folks not a lot of people buying flowers
of my generation I also heard that a lot
from these people how can we get younger
people into flowers and I'm like I don't
know
man I think it's my capitalistic
conditioning as well but whenever I am
planning out like a a home Garden or
something every I'm like everything
that's in there has to be working you
know nothing's in there for free just to
look pretty I want to make sure that
everything's doing something whether it
be providing um you know some sort of
like Bane properties to a pest or a a
you know whether that be like bug or
rodent or otherwise that is around that
I want to keep away or if it's something
just for the pollinators to make sure
that I have a good population of
pollinators in the area but then
everything else I'm like yeah you're
you're working for me I need to eat you
I need to make sure that you're you're
doing the things that I need you to do
um right and I think that's super valid
though that's like that's like a a a Sim
uh they call it like sin biotic nowadays
that's a new research term people will
sin bio synthetic biology or sin Eco
synthetic
ecosystems uh but it's like I mean it
sounds like it sounds really like
extreme or weird or something but really
it's the same as like having a fish tank
or a greenhouse or a garden it's the
same concept it's biodome exactly uh
it's it's the same concept it's not like
the Terminator coming to kill all life
it's um it's literally what's the most
holistic approach to the ecosystem I can
make and then also factoring the fact
that people use money to make things
happen um and then that's just a
resource in of
itself and then that's it you know it's
normal even plants have to
proportionally react to pest with the
resources that they work for by
quenching phons in their chlorophyll so
it's the same thing all the way down yes
I agree and it does feel a little better
um to know that I am also then trying to
provide this more holistic approach
rather than just saying I'm I am
monocropping corn and I'm going to dry
some and I'm going to eat some fresh but
that's all I'm growing because then I
only have to focus on one thing it you
know that's where we've gone wrong in a
lot of ways in agriculture and uh you
know maybe there is more
opportunity in the future for this uh
sin uh synthesized uh bio uh approach
that would allow for maybe
um maybe even like something as as
Extreme as less ecological collapse for
certain species or other otherwise just
by helping maintain the things that they
need to survive as well as what you use
to survive as a human um yeah like that
a lot um or even like or even like
isolating yourself I know that's a lot
of times that's sort of anathema to how
people like to do those sorts of to have
like an ecosystem approach but maybe in
some ways it is actually better to to be
responsible and like kind of keep things
inside and you can still use like
various microbial consortia and um you
know uh Predator insects and pollen and
Banker plants and all that stuff but
maybe you like sort of internalize some
or all of those components so that
there's less spread
or um that you know I just think that's
really interesting and and I love that
people of My Generation Um have really
pivoted uh at least for those who do
care um I guess it's a lot more than the
past but like people are pivoting
towards sustainability people are
pivoting towards um you know just
general better understanding to be
informed I do feel like there's more ad
more more people who could do that but I
do think that people are raising an
alarm about things that maybe should
have even 50 years ago so it's a it's
endearing to see that and I'm glad to
see that you seem to also be such a
person so that's always good to see for
sure I mean it feels like the communal
approach uh in the long run does create
a a more positive benefit for a greater
population than say an isolated approach
where you're really just focusing on
what you need or what what you can get
the most out of something um that
there's a lot of privilege within
isolation as well that a lot of people
don't have access to and Community is
required in a lot of ways in order to
make sure the uh or ensure the the
health and survival of of uh populations
of people um and you know if if uh the
end goal of this is all to either
potentially make make humans uh you
know more happy more comfortable more
healthy I don't know you know more uh
than look at it through the communal
lens rather than the isolated lens does
feel like a much better approach I agree
with
that um so you've had uh you know not
not so much homow experience but you do
help hom Growers all the time and you
have a lot of commercial experience both
within
um uh commercial agriculture for for
food production for cannabis production
for um um
ornamentals uh maybe and and feel free
to take this in any direction that you
want but as an integrated pest ma
management specialist where would you
like to see changes within the
agricultural Community whether it be in
cannabis um or outside of
cannabis I think that if I
had if I was able to direct that kind of
thing at a huge level top down just be
like King for a Day we do this or these
things I think it would be actually um I
think it would
be like basically data driven basically
make a lot of things are moving this way
uh a 4.0 fog Computing using autonomous
vehicles um being able to not only
aggregate a lot of data with sensor
Imaging and other kinds of sensing
systems
but then taking that massive amount of
data crunching it analyzing it using
systems to make predictions for you and
then merge that with your own decision-
making essentially uh what we see in
research being called a cyber
agricultural system uh I think is really
a good idea I don't I think it's
way uh I mean I think that it solves
certain problems that I've actually find
um really disgusting in agriculture you
know mainly being forced indention
servitude a uh basically Millennia old
tradition since agriculture has existed
I would say more or less whether you did
it to your own people or other people's
people it's a thing and um I don't like
it and I think that that could help with
some of that kind of thing um at least
it makes people use resources a little
bit more efficiently that's always good
the problem is that and historically the
problem with doing things like this is
that the Technologies just aren't
democratized enough which is super
understandable reason why they haven't
been adopted um um really expensive and
also maybe not as like capable as they
were in like 10 years 20 years before
whatever uh you know back when Game Boy
was new right like but nowadays it's I
think a different sort of tune and I
think that specifically the
subsidization of that data like imagine
if I've seen research coming out of
China actually uh that I've been kind of
enamored with um but I understand why uh
they get to do the things they do uh I'm
not an advocate for it but um when you
have a government that's just going to
direct and subsidize tons of money
towards something like that you can get
certain benefits out of it and I think a
similar thing like we've done in the US
and other countries could also adopt
this um uh subsidization of of regional
Data Tracking like for example for
budworm
you know knowing when is it that they
emerge in your area what's the degree
day um intervals this kind of data we
don't have to memorize it as people we
can have systems that kind of figure
this out um a push notification say hey
go go apply this today because these
events just
occurred 100% or did you know that like
it's going to like you know even like
weather prediction that we have now is
like having an Oracle in your pocket
right like so and and they're not
actually getting high off of volcanic
fumes they're actually predicting stuff
so so yeah so I mean that kind of stuff
is what I would say because then also we
wouldn't have to necessarily even rely
on products you have to pay for um if
you subsidize it some way and every
everybody could like log into this data
and get and then that data can talk with
other Ai and that kind of stuff and get
that um those sort of like U uh
magnifying capabilities then I think
that it would do a lot to help people go
if there if their if their level of
capability is one then it brings them up
a level all of the other stuff they have
in their mind and their experience works
synergistically with that and then they
won't get Gob smacked um and blindsided
by something new potentially like that
bio bioresistant aphid that we just
talked about you know so that kind of
stuff is what I'm excited about and um
it seems like it's more and more tenable
more and more capable and so I'm happy
about that but we'll see if it actually
gets implemented and if it's actually as
good as I think it will be for sure I I
couldn't agree more I feel like the the
use of the technologies that we do have
access to in order to gather data record
data track data and help create these uh
predictive Maps um that allow you to
kind of uh control more tightly the
different parameters of a growing
environment and react uh more quickly as
well as more effectively to the
different um aspects of a grow um and
you know I've said it before and I'm
going to keep saying it but it's a plant
and plants do plant things they don't
always react the way that you want them
to um but by
providing uh more data over time you
will have the ability to make more
predictive models of how they should
react to specific stimuli and it is um
especially I could see within the Pest
Management world how that would be
hugely
beneficial considering I think um I
don't know if it was you that said this
or Suzanne way wri Evans that said this
but in poinet is like the you know the
margin of error is a couple of pennies
in order to make sure that that that is
profitable and so if you have to apply
some new chemistry that costs you know a
dollar more to apply and you need to
apply it a 100 days out of the year then
all of a sudden your entire crop is no
longer profitable and you can no longer
sustain that business model um so
something that allows you to then be
even more predictive about your needs as
well as you can
reduce uh applic you know how much of uh
chemical you're applying uh you're going
to be able to save money and all through
the ability to to track this data
analyze it more
effectively than a human sitting there
crop scouting and then thinking ah you
know maybe 20% of these plants show you
a problem that's above the economic
threshold so we should apply this that
that's a it's a lot to just do all that
math in your head and um so I could see
that's a great one I I use data analysis
all the time but it's usually for
environmental factors and substrate
monitoring and things along those lines
but they're hugely beneficial we can
reduce our overall irrigation volume we
can reduce our fertilizer applied we can
uh reduce our CO2 applied which is
another cost we can reduce our lighting
that's applied it's the correct um the
correct timing which is an over like
just an overhead reduction in cost and
all these different things where you can
slowly bring down how much input you're
actually putting in to the same output
um and uh I I don't see how there's
unless you have a massive team of human
brains working to try and figure this
out I don't see many other options other
than turning to these um either
predictive models or uh like AI
generative learning and and trying to
analyze all the data that's inputed and
and create a more holistic view of what
the potentials that that data could
cause within the crop um I I really like
that I really I I'm a huge fan of
Technology but um you know I always
think like sometimes it's it's about
who's using it and how they're applying
it rather than the technology itself you
know sometimes it can be applied poorly
right and and be misinterpreted and
cause even more damage um go watch the
Terminator and and then we'll we'll be
on the same page right um just like you
said earlier so um yeah you know that
that kind of wraps up all the questions
that I had for you um were there any
other topics that we didn't touch on
that you wanted to to bring up in our
conversation
today I think we went over a lot of good
things um I I'll you know you asked when
you asked me to go and talk with you
here um you know you had mentioned like
you know homow situations and things and
plants you grow by yourselves and I had
said that you know maybe I don't have a
whole lot of not as an experience but
like you know cool stuff to talk about
but I will say this I want to I want to
touch in on that point at the very end
here as a bonus for anyone who's watched
the end and that's that um I have a
really cool plant that uh um I'm very
proud of uh having planted which was a
it's called Lizard tail I'm forgetting
the binomial name the scientific name uh
but sometimes called Fishman if you've
heard of this if you type this into
search you'll find it um this is a
Southeast Asian plant it's actually
pretty invasive I'm going to be honest
here um so keep it in a pot but um it's
uh it tastes like fish man the leaves
taste like fish and uh it grows really
well and it loves to be watered and um
you know you can put in your stir fry I
feel like it slept on a little bit so if
you've never heard of this um it's
really easy to take care of and I
recommend it nice I feel like uh
probably be good in like Thai curry or
something yeah exactly or like um egg
fried rice or something yeah sure that
sounds delicious um as a little bit of a
I still like to cook even though I don't
really do it that much uh you know
professionally anymore but um oh sure
finding those little herbs and stuff and
and and you know finding the dish that
they uh pair well with is always really
fun
and new flavor experiences are always
fun as well so yeah check it out fish
Min people go look it up
fish cool well I have a couple of wrapup
questions that I usually like to ask all
of my guests and um considering that you
are a cannabis user I feel like you will
still have some good answers for this so
what is your favorite strain of all
time very strain agnostic because people
you know how it is people say that this
is that and other people say be wrong so
I don't even know if I I don't even know
if what I've had is what I've had or
maybe somebody wants to dispute with me
about whether or not I had what I
actually had or not um but
uh one of my favorite strains I've ever
had one of my favorite Cult of ours is
um a death breath that Brandon rest um
had had bred and um uh Hog's Breath also
which is um Associated I'm told with San
Diego in particular and I got to meet
some of the people who create either
created it or continue its lineage um
here in Southern California so I really
enjoyed them uh both because they were
really gassy um I felt like they were
very they had a lot of the uh sort of
peppery turpis um kind of
like like a dark flavor you know kind of
like not fruity not sweet but kind of
like gassy and um Piney and peppery and
kind of these sorts of like Savory more
so kind of Aromas and flavors and I
think that's really cool when they're
really strong and and I enjoy that
flavor profile I'm not enough of a snob
to say that I'll turn down something
else I don't think I'll I don't think
I've reached that point but uh I I did
quite enjoy that and the history was
kind of nice to to boot for sure I I
feel like if you can have that sort of
uh enhanced experience
of not just necessarily it being oh some
weed in the bag but you're like I know
the guy that grew this that put the time
and effort into continuing the lineage
of this and he chose it for these
purposes and now I'm here having a
little bit of flavor of it it's almost
like going to Wine Country and going on
a a wine tasting experience and having
the the wine maker right there with you
talking about it it's a I know it's
Unique and and I feel like those uh
those experiences can be fairly well
cherished for uh their their uniqueness
and um sort of what what might be
referred to as uh authenticity within
that specific
environment
um so uh you know we didn't get into it
but I know that you are a member of the
is it the rare fruit uh tree Society in
Southern Cali yeah the San Diego chapter
of the rare Fruit Growers Association
okay California yes so considering that
you don't personally grow a lot of
cannabis um do you have and this you
know this could totally be cannabis if
you if you want to go that route but uh
feel free to go outside of the realm of
cannabis for this question but do you
have a favorite plant breeder of all
time uh I do it is outside of cannabis
um uh but you
know kind of forgetting their name
unfortunately when put to the test but
there's two people um that come to my
mind both of which I'm now forgetting
one of them was a really really famous
um agriculturalist in China who passed
away last year or perhaps a year before
um and he was very famous people made a
big uproar about his passing uh I think
he's very famous for bringing
specifically like different types of
rice uh and I think wheat too I want to
say uh making it very like um adapted to
the various regions in the People's
Republic of China and basically
especially if you know their history um
you know not to make light of it but
there are several famines in Chinese
history and so doing the opposite of
that is definitely a boon um and then
another gentleman who I'm also freaking
unfortunately but he's the a he's
actually the person who started up the
uh rare Fruit Growers Association
I think one of the rare fruits that he's
really po he's really famous for is
um um uh there's several apples that I
think he kept around even though they
weren't commercially viable that kind of
dedication I think is just really
amazing and I can't imagine somebody
doing it especially in this day and age
like it it's just who has the time
resources ability know how um and care
to be quite honest the the actually
personal initiative to to do it even
though
how many people are really going to have
this like black cherry cultivar of um
you know Apple that with red flesh or
whatever in a black rind you know uh I
don't know I just think that's and and
the same sort of beauty of that uh
impermanence is also what I find there
was a guy who grew cannabis uh here in
San Diego he made this cultivar he
called orange Tang like Tang the orange
drink and um it's gone now uh no more um
and uh when I smoked it it really tasted
like orange juice and not like other
sorts of um citric flavors but really
did taste like orange um and I thought
that was really novel and cool and I'm
sure other ones are like that but I love
um that I got to meet the guy and it's
kind of interesting that it's no longer
available
anymore yeah I do really think that the
individuals who put the effort into
either uh you know preserving a specific
cultivar or creating novel cultivars for
the market um it makes me think of that
guy uh I don't remember his name either
but he was I believe out of Pasadena
California and he did all the different
stone fruit crosses like the um like the
plum and the apricot cross and the
apricot and the uh you know the um I
think like you got like plats and
apriums and um all the different typ of
peir uh peaches and stuff that were that
were developed in that area and I think
he developed like hundreds of these
different varietals that are even still
grown today but to have that dedication
and creating fun novel food stuffs is
pretty
cool the loquat tree I'd mentioned
earlier is the Big Jim cultivar and Big
Jim I think was one of those people as
well who's like really popular um
basically I think he might have been the
person who started the rear Growers now
I think about it or he was associated
with it at least um and now tons of
people have it in their backyards and I
just think that's parallels really well
with the community that we think of or
at least I think of when it comes to
cannabis so I appreciate you um you know
searching out those Impressions I think
they often don't get spoken by me or
other people so it's nice to get those I
usually have to keep it empirical but it
doesn't mean that I have no heart or
that I don't have a um more whim and
fery approach to
life certainly I mean you're a fan of
Pokemon so that says something yeah
right exactly I don't play the games
anymore I do find that they're a little
bit rigid and Game Freak could probably
stand to be a little bit more Innovative
um but you know what we had together
right I'll never forget I'll never
forget right on right on um well I just
have one last question for you uh what
is your most memorable cannabis related
experience
H or just a good memorable cannabis
related experience doesn't necessarily
me to need to be the Apex of it I think
that if I go back to when I was help
helping my friends in the high deserts
of Lone Pine
California and um so I'm in my early 20s
early to mid 20s
um uh i' gotone back from China and it
was just this sort of beauty that I
talked about before it's like cold but
it's also hot from the Sun so it's like
February winter time kind of um and I'm
smoking a joint and like at that point I
had become more I started smoking joints
more often um you know I just been
really getting into my work and
everything and it was amazing to just
kind of like walk down this like pathway
of like scrub land and and like a Ravine
and there's all these like oak trees
creating some shade and it's just there
was like a a natural beauty uh that I
enjoyed in that moment and I and I and I
remember the sky was quite you know
Azure and blue deep of blue um no clouds
in the sky and also you know snow
everywhere just kind of surprising to be
in a desert with snow and so it was kind
of surreal and I think something about
like the Mind space that I was in um not
only smoking but also um you just
hanging out with my friends um just uh a
really great
memory that does sound really nice I
mean I I I forgot too about the snow
from when you had talked about that
earlier because not only are you in the
desert where it's really dry and kind of
uh vast and expansive so there's not a
lot of things to create noise but then
you also have this covering of snow
which just deafens everything else even
more so I'm you know I'm thinking of
something like that where it would
probably be very quiet if you didn't
move and if everyone else was being very
quiet it would almost be
deafening you get some long some uh fast
moving winds as well during the During
certain Seasons but you're right it's
very it was very quiet uh and then but
you would get sort of wind that would
kick up sometimes too so there's like
yeah it's like it's like very peaceful
and um you know I miss it I hope to go
up to opening trout sometime in the next
year or two where they have this this
event you can go and fish and my friends
often come during that time so maybe
we'll do that this year we'll see nice
that sounds like fun well Matt again
thank you so much for joining me today
and I know that this is a little bit of
an unorthodox episode for our listeners
where we usually have people on that are
um either dedicated homeowers or
commercial cultivators themselves but I
do believe that it uh by providing these
different um perspectives of Canabis
cultivation um yours being through that
of uh someone who loves bugs that it is
it provides a more holistic approach and
people can I believe appreciate the
different aspects of cannabis
cultivation more deeply when we give
them the ability to see it through other
people people's eyes um so thank you I
really really appreciate you being here
today and I really think that people are
going to enjoy
this I appreciate it I look forward to
our mutual success yeah well thank you
again
[Music]