Hello and welcome to another episode of
the Way We Grow podcast, a production of
the Craft Growers Network. I'm your
host, Nick Wolf. Today, our guest is
none other than Dog Doctor. Um, you can
find him and his work at Dog Doctor
Official on Instagram, Grow Diaries, and
on YouTube. Uh, Mr. Dog Doctor, how are
you doing today?
And Nick, first of all, thank you so
much for having me here. It's an honor
and I'm feeling very humbled. Thank you
so much. I'm doing great. Enjoying the
winter and the range that uh we're
waiting for spring to come. Apart from
that, living life in the moment as most
as I can. Thank you. For sure. Yeah, I
feel like uh that's how a lot of us are
feeling. just waiting for spring to get
here so we can start to plan some
outdoor grows or uh you know I know that
for indoor growers you got to start to
think about a little more heat maybe uh
heat mitigation and stuff like that. So
that's definitely it's an important time
of year for growers in general. Um
yeah. What's new in your grow world
though? I feel like uh you know you
you're always doing something new in
your grow and um from every time that
I've listened to you talk about it on
like growing with my fellow growers or
just chatted with you on Instagram, you
know, you're always doing something new.
So what's new for you? At the moment I'm
um searching for that wrench again. I
lost that run that actually the one that
the photo that you took in the few days
ago on
Instagram two summers ago I lost her to
a heatwave and Zamnes started a contest
on grow diaries which they do a lot of
it and the seeds they were providing for
the contest were nonetheless the zamnes
so the runs so I decided to okay we have
the setup from troll master now I did
one run with it let's test the setup now
in a different way I'm changing a few
parameters in there because it's my
second time running under canopy lights
and the spectum tuning. So I like to
learn by mistakes. I see what others do
and try to learn by their mistakes also.
But I truly believe that um making the
mistakes ourselves.
uh we we learn in in a different way
than seeing others making mistakes of of
course I'm not chasing that mistakes to
be made but I know that when growing and
when everybody is growing in trying new
things that mistakes are there to be
made so lessons are there to be learned
and uh right now I'm learning how to
spectrum tuning and how to manage the
inner canopy lights. Last run I flipped
the them into flower and only at week
two more or less I connected the ender
canopy lights. This time instead of that
I connected uh straight away from uh the
moment I did the 48 hours dark. I do 48
hours dark before flipping into flower.
To my understanding, I'm not saying this
is the best way or the way to do it. To
my understanding, this helps triging the
plants into flower mode.
Meaning that instead of waiting one week
and something for that first pre flowers
to start showing that there are
flowering three four days only, I
already start to see the little bulks
and I tr I honestly believe it's that 48
hours dark that um make that happening
faster. I don't know. Yeah, I mean you
definitely see a lot of people using
practices like that. I know it was
really popular for a while and I've even
seen people in the commercial space use
it um because of of their belief that it
does help trigger the flowering process
sooner and uh if the end goal is to get
as many different um harvests as you can
then uh starting the flower cycle sooner
um when you initiate flower as well. You
know, it it should potentially bring
down the um the overall flowering time.
So, I could see how how that could be
beneficial. I've I've never really found
any success with it myself, but you
know, I think sometimes it's just based
on the on the space perhaps. Exactly.
What works here in my space may not work
in your space or in somebody else's
space because all space are conditions
are different. I encourage everybody to
try all methods that they feel that it's
something that they would like, not all
at the same time. Otherwise, if
something doesn't work, you don't know
what it is. But this way you can uh find
the better way for yourself, for your
space, for your grow, for your needs.
Some people have more time to be with
the plants, other don't have time to be
with the plants. So just in here, you
have to find different medium. For
instance, if you want to do cocoa and no
and do hand
water, maybe you shouldn't you need to
be with your plants every day. If you
have a water system, maybe you don't
have to be with your plants every day.
If you're doing soil, it can be more
forgiving because it takes longer to dry
also. So, it retains the water longer.
So, every case is a different case. In
my opinion, home growers, they don't
need to
go hydroponic. Like, if you have a big
facility, I can see why you do that
because of the production and how fast
it is and how easy to it is to correct
everything. Something is wrong. Now I
just flush and start again and in in one
day plants are again thriving. If you
are home growing looking for better
quality for a better connection with the
plant for all of it the soil it's more
forgiving. In my humbled opinion the
flavor in the end is also better from
soil than it is from um rock poolool and
stuff like that. Again this is a
personal opinion.
There's no no test. I did not test.
Let's see this. So this is but no for my
experience and for my easy way of
growing I I am with my plants every day
but still sometimes from time to time I
don't have time to go there one two days
because life happens and something soil
and the auto pot oh my
god they were a bless coming in my life
and one that I really really appreciate
this this auto pot system is it's
amazing it's really amazing how easy it
makes one's life and it works on gravity
or on density or whatever you want to
call it, but the weight of the water
brings it down. Meaning even if there is
no electricity, plants will drink as
they please. And yeah, that's that's
definitely something that I um I've seen
a lot of home growers get a lot of
success with because it's it is easy and
it makes it so that you don't have to
worry too much about certain aspects of
the grow, especially if you are running
like some sort of living soil where you
need to maintain a certain moisture
content for the biological activity to
continue. Um, you know, in in some
cases, like with hydroponics and stuff,
I would say that maybe the auto pot
system isn't the most ideal because you
can't really control a good dryback uh
interval. Yeah.
Sorry. And you can probably build up
salts pretty quickly, too, if you're
feeding too high with something like
that. So, um, yeah, that's I I've seen a
lot of people use it. I haven't
personally tried them out, but I've
always been interested in them. Um, but
you know earlier in the conversation you
started talking about how you are on
your second run of under canopy lighting
and as a commercial grower I've been
using it for a little while now and I I
love them. So, I wanted to find out what
your um experience with them has been
considering it is kind of one of those
things that is
uh it's still fairly new in the cannabis
industry and the home growing space and
a lot of people are still fairly uh
hesitant to jump in to use them because
you do increase the heat, you increase
your overall like nutrient consumption
requirements for the plant. um
especially since it's LED. Uh but yeah,
what are what are some of your
experiences with that off of the first
run that you had with them? Honestly, I
loved it and um the results spoke by
themselves, but yes, once you plug them
in, there's a lot of new factors that
need to tune in. Heat will go up,
meaning that your humidity needs to go
up also because you need to keep your
VPD more or less. And you don't need to
to make the perfect VPD but you need to
keep your numbers close enough otherwise
they will be in balance on the
nutritions and then the plants will not
go and they will sweat more everything
will will be more meaning they will be
needing higher EC. So if you used to
work with lowers EC and you bringing in
canopy lights trust me you will have to
be be make bigger feedings because there
will be more plant mass needing needing
food. Let's let's thinking in basics
before I'm taking all my light from
here. Meaning all my grow is here.
Whatever it's down here, it's not
needing it. That's why we lollipop it
because it would not grow. It become
popcorn and stuff. Right now we have
light coming from here also. Meaning
that they growing here but they are also
growing down here. So that will require
energy that will require nutrients that
will require everything that the tops.
So you it's not doubling everything but
it's checking reading the plants and see
how much they are eating. Checking the
runoffs. I like to do the runoffs in
auto pot is difficult but I have the WCS
sensor that tells me what's in the soil.
So I know more or less that if I'm
feeding 1.5 EC and I'm 1.6 or
1.4, I know that she's eating more or
less what I'm feeding her. And from that
I can give her help more and not less
and see if she's building up and I'm
giving her more but she's not eating
more the numbers are going more are are
accumulating there. They're not they do
not want this is how I control my
runoffs in the auto pots. If I'm not
doing out of pots I just I water. If the
EC that goes in is 1.5 and the one
coming out is one, she needs more food.
If the EC that goes in is 1.5 and the
one coming out it's 2.0, you know, she
needs less food or just water for the
next one or something. And this is how I
balance or I try to balance the best I
can the nutrition into my plants. So you
always try to keep somewhat of a of a
consistent level of uh poor water um EC
um rather than having it you know do any
sort of like generative steering towards
a higher EC at the beginning of flower
and then reducing it towards the bulking
period or anything like that.
more or less I I I increase my I start
increasing my C in veg until flour and
then in flour I again increase it with
the with the peas and the case and all
the extra boosters that we are giving
them. this if I'm doing in an organic
way organic on mineral if I'm just doing
minerals which I I am doing now with the
trail master I'm doing the appto all and
clean program which is just minerals no
organic stuff in there this brings
higher ECS but plants seems to like it
um they started higher before I was
doing 0.8 in veg now I'm doing 1.3 in
veg and I'm doing I start flower with
1.5 and I finish around 2.0 You know,
this last year for me was unthinkable.
Unthinkable. I did not understand how
people would go with EC so high. Now I
understand it's everything else. It's
it's like if you go and train into a gym
full of oxygen and the best conditions
you will need more minerals, more
vitamins, more to keep up your body.
Plants are I believe that they work the
same. And to my opinion, they don't care
if it's organic, mineral, synthetic. The
plant itself needs NPK, macro,
micronutrients and everything else. If
you provide them in YX or whatever form
that you prefer to you, they will
receive it and they will thank you for
that. The end product honestly I also
believe that it's raw talk and it's our
way of thinking that makes us believe
that organic is better than synthetic or
mineral. But in the end, if I give you a
really good flower, synthetic, organic
or mineral, well cured, well proper, and
you will most will not know the
difference. I'm not saying that it's and
this, but
you will not know unless you grow, but
we as growers, we know, and I grow for
myself, so I like the organics and the
minerals. I don't go synthetics myself.
Yeah. I um I've always found that like
the best flower that I could ever grow
at home was um either in a like a really
large living soil pot like a 30-gallon
pot or better um or using
um cocoa quar and uh like a just a
really basic like Jax 321 or uh JR Crop
Tech
or any of these sort of like salt salt
based fertilizers that have all the
macro and micros in one side and then
the nitrogen and calcium in another. Uh,
and you just mix those up either in
equal parts or um depending on the
formula, whatever ratio it is. And then
adding some sort of biology to the
substrate like um
like an earthworm casting tea or um just
any other uh microbiology that you can
get in there to help kind of initiate
those responses in the plant. like
there's the the kiten response pathways
and then there's the oh what else? Um
there's like the salicylic acid pathways
that can be triggered if the plant comes
in contact with them in the root zone.
And from what I've always experienced is
that it tends to produce a more robust
cannibid cannabonoid and tarpine
profile. Um, and I always I really liked
it in the hydroponic setting because
then you get the speed of growth. You
can get the um potential for a greater
yield if you have the correct irrigation
and environmental practices in place.
And in my ca in like in a lot of
instances sometimes I think of all that
micro microbial activity in living soils
and if you do have any sort of
sporilation events where you have um you
know mushrooms that are growing or other
fungus that's growing and you get all
those spores up into the into the plant
matter then a lot of that you know there
there are potential for micotoxins and
stuff like that when you're combusting
cannabis but some of them are also
destroyed by combustion. So, um I always
just w went with the I I want to keep it
a little bit cleaner, but yeah, try to
throw a little bit of some sort
of microbial uh activity in the soil.
Um, but I and I've, you know, I was
always before I had to stop growing at
home, I um I wanted
to do those in auto pots because you do
get that benefit of the constant
moisture. And you can also feed through
it as well, like you're saying, at a at
a lower EC.
I'm feeling higher higher now. Also, uh
I with the whole system, the the pipes
were a little bit too too thin and if
you put too much stuff in there, it
would build up stuff. The organic would
not just not work very nice in there.
With the new lines, the blue lines,
black, whatever color you get, they are
they they are pipes. So, whatever you
put in there, organic or not, it will go
through. Of course, after one, you need
to clean it up. But this is normal
procedurement that you have to do with
any system, hydroponic or not. If you
don't want to, if you want to avoid
problems, you have to keep it all clean
from run to run and keep it cleaning if
needed during the run. And uh this is
one of the things that people don't do
that people don't they think that it's
not important. Oh, it's just one run or
no. So it's very important every run to
set up to zero in my humbled opinion
because you don't want to bring any
issue that it was not present in the
previous run but it was starting to be
present but it was a late present so you
did not see it and now you start this
one but it's there so like mildo mold
and stuff it stay there the spores man I
I eonize this is how you say it I tent I
clean it I bleach it I clean it again
and in the And I have a yonzer. I can
show you. Actually, it's here. One
second. Put this in there. And what this
does is this divides the the oxygen
molecule in two. And this kills
everything inside. Bacteria, non
bacteria, mold, mildos, whatever spore
you have in there, it will be dead. It's
a like an ozone generator. Exactly.
Exactly. It's exactly that. So, you
cannot breathe it. But I close the tent.
I put the lights on so that it's very
hot inside it or the hotter I can. I
leave it there for half an hour and in
for a 4x4 it's more than enough. Cool.
There's
Yeah, there's commercial facilities that
use thermal protocols when they're
cleaning their rooms and they'll like
maintain a certain temperature for a
certain time frame and it will um help
destroy any sort of biology that's still
in there. Yes, sir.
Now we have
UV something UVC that they using to kill
the bugs and stuff and the mold and
mill. I'm not sure if it's UVC. I'm
speaking by
head but uh facilities are using and now
home growers are using it also. Future
of grow which is a brand of from Swiss
just released it and Grandmaster level
also did it. Um, you and it's it's
something that you just run half an hour
on the grow and it's supposed to kill
nets trips and everything. I don't know.
I did not try it, but I'm very curious
about the experiment the predator.
Well, yeah. You know, there are so many
new technologies that are kind of
popping up that are either like a
light-based uh pest prevention and then
you also have that ozone generator which
is nothing new, but I've definitely
start started to see people use it more
often because it is a very effective
tool. It is it is a crazy new tool and
people are using it and I'm curious to
to bring it into the grow actually and
to see because trips and nets it's
something that
um in the beginning I was paranoia when
I was growing in rockwool everything
needs to be sterilized and this and that
and over the years when I moved myself
to soil and completely to soil and in
organics I start to understand that it's
normal for us to have bugs they part of
the nature So I can't to accept them but
we need to control them. And what I do
to control it's um neat it's a bunch of
predators and this and that. It's
something that you keep and you need to
keep buying and getting. If I can get
now a lamp that I place it in the tent
and half an hour a day I run it and this
will do the exact same management. Man,
this is that's intriguing. It's
intriguing. I heard about machines with
lasers on big facilities that goes and
they ident with AI they identify the
trip in the past and they just killed
the that one. Yeah, my dad was just
talking about that to me. That's really
funny. That's uh yeah, it's something
that I've seen as well. You know, I feel
like it's still in the process of being
perfected though because if that was so
uh efficient, you know, drones are
pretty cheap nowadays and lasers aren't
necessarily the most advanced technology
and with the AI learning and stuff, it
doesn't seem like it would be
uh excessively cost prohibitive where
you know almost any commercial facility
if you can just buy something like that
rather than spray stuff and cuz the
sprays you know those are all
consumables so you have to continuously
purchase them. And they're not the
cheapest, especially when you get into
some of the uh different chemistries
that you might be using. So, uh yeah,
something like that. I if it did work, I
I feel like we would see it a lot more.
So, I'm still kind of hesitant to, you
know, does it work or is it something
that's still in the process of being
under like developed and and perfected?
Um
on paper sounds amazing. Yeah, on paper
it does sound amazing. Absolutely. Um
well, I'm I'm glad we kind of had this
little ramble here to start off the
conversation, but I'm going to kind of
uh steer us back into some of the
questions that I have for us today.
Let's go, please. Cool. So, um I always
like to find out where your journey with
plants started and whether it was with
cannabis or, you know, if you grew up in
a household that had a like a vegetable
garden or something along those lines.
Um, but what was your for sure what were
what were your first experiences with
plants and what led you into where you
are today with cannabis? So in my family
the they're the they're the farmers
also. I have farmers in a family but I
was I I was a city boy. I was raised in
the city going to the farm raised into
the city. Um so but I always had
contact. I'm not I was that kid that
when people ask what a tomato is or an
apple or a carrot or where does the meat
came from I knew for me it was normal I
grew I knew that the meat is from the
cow and that they killed a pig and that
the chicken. So this was always
something that was very into my blood
and still is I believe and still is and
um but cannabis came to me with came to
me I started smoking very early about uh
13 something like this and at 15 more or
less one seed came in the traditional I
know this is the cliche story but it is
what it is it cames with seeds we put
the seed in soil and bam it grows
something and oh okay it's this easy
let's try this and we started from there
and then there going up and overs and we
start looking for seeds and things and
time passes and
um about uh let's say so it's still in
the past about a few decades ago I
started growing for myself seriously
like okay I'm sick of everybody's else's
weeds each time I grow a plant mini
plant big plant it's always better than
anything that I buy commercial. At least
to me, it sounds better. I don't know if
it is or not, but I don't care. So, when
I started, one thing led to the other
and
um it's been a few decades now that I
I'm kind of engaged with this. When I'm
when I travel, I have to have somebody
taking care of them. That somebody needs
to be somebody from my family because I
don't talk with nobody else where I am
about this. Nobody really knows. I've
been doing this for decades and um a
handful of people knows because of the
situations that we live in here. Once
it's became like tomatoes or like
anything else, I don't care. But I have
to care for now. Not that I think that
I'm doing anything wrong, but they think
it is wrong. So, we living by their
rules. And one thing led to the other.
And um then in about the 2000s, I start
becoming really serious. I start
investing in whatever and researching
and not just growing trying to
understand what I grow, what are the
genetics, why this genetic does this,
why that does that, what is a
phenotype and one thing led to the
other. This always was a solo journey
for myself. Then co and everybody stays
home. Nobody can goes anywhere
supposedly. Everything is going bananas
and I'm home. And what I do home, I grow
grow plants. you know, so I
get even more deeper into it. I start
researching like like it's like like
studying more or less and I start going
online. Something that for me was no I
never did forums. I never did anything
because man, why would I do that?
There's no point. And I started going
online. I found a few channels on
YouTube. In this case, I found the Let's
Be Buds and I
found uh GMLs. I started um getting
leads at that time was the first time I
get leads before it was all HPS and one
of the days I decided
to GML was saying oh if you guys want to
come in and ask questions and man why
not so I say my first time growing leads
that's where I met Spartan and my lead
online then from there I start following
him and I follow my fellow home grows
and everything else
and this was how I became to to go
online and uh since this this was
happening I decided okay so let's make
an Instagram account even if I don't
share any photos I can follow other
people specific because I cannot do this
with my private account because of of
the paranoas so I created an account on
Instagram and one thing led to the other
time start passing and um about a year
after I had my Instagram account up to
all came to me and ask me why I did not
do any posts. Um because I was tagging
them in history stories and stuff like
that because that was the the nutrient
line that I was using. And he told me,
"Oh, if you start posting some photos or
some content the same way you're doing
on your stories, you don't need to do
anything else. We can sponsor you." And
that's when I realized, okay, this there
there might be something else more here
than just me growing. And the there this
passion can actually turn into something
bigger. I don't know. And I started to
post online. This was about uh 3 years
ago, I think. And then one thing led to
the other. And um honestly, everything
is happening so
fast. And I'm feeling very humbled and
blessed with not blessed because I don't
like the word blessed because it's be
less and I like to be more. And I like I
want everybody to be more not less. But
I feel very very grateful with how
things are coming because there's
podcasts happening. There's the
Instagram account is going up and and I
love to talk about these plants. I love
when people come to me and tell me
something that I did wrong because I
didn't know I did it wrong and I learned
from that. And I love to help people
when I see I know many take this as a
personal thing and oh I'm not
criticizing you. I'm I'm giving you the
way I do things and and and the
community is growing and now with the
YouTube is also growing a new community
that I was not expecting. Videos are
coming out and I'm loving this. This is
bringing me even more closer to the
plants that I was before because now
it's not just being there looking at the
plant, taking care of the plant. Now,
when I'm filming, when I'm looking for
details, I'm I'm seeing things that I
never saw before and I'm noticing things
in the in the way that plants grows, in
the way that everything evolves.
Especially when you make a time lapse,
you see how they move, how they grow,
how they spin, everything a plant does.
It just It's not just this. No, she's
moving all day around and changing forms
and goes and came. It's alive. It's
beautiful. And uh I'm loving this uh
this creating content and uh creating
things. That's awesome. I mean, it's
obvious you have a lot of passion for
the plant. And uh you know, it's there's
like an art form, I feel like, to a lot
of the content that you do show where
it's it's not just a picture of a plant
or some impressive yield or a a bag full
of of of awesome looking flowers or
something. It's it's more of the the
grow itself and how you're growing. Um,
what what are some of the the things
that you like to do in your garden that
you might think are unique to your
situation that other people might not
know about how you grow? Uh, currently
uh depending if I'm growing out of
flowers or if I'm growing uh normal
plant, not normal, they all normal,
sorry. If I'm going feminiz or regular
seeds, I grow different. For arrow
flowers, for instance, I don't top. Most
people like topping or not topping. I
don't top. Not because I don't top. It's
just because I don't like to touch them.
I see the out of flowers as something
that you grow and it's not there to give
you more work. It's just there to assist
you. So, what I do with out of flowers,
I lift bend. I only lift bend them. And
since I start only lift bend them, they
start to grow way more and bigger. And I
and I'm getting big big big auto
flowers. I really like this leaf bending
on the outflower. What What do you mean
by leaf bending? Okay,
so plants they grow and then the leaf a
new leaf came here that is covering the
end. Can you see this? No. Yes. That is
covering the the end. So, what I do, I
grab the leaf and I put it under the the
one that is done. Got it. Like, uh, leaf
tucking is another one that I've heard
people use for that where they'll
they'll tuck the leaves under the nodes.
I get it. Exactly. And this will bring
the nodes off. The leaves are still
there. You're not defoliating. They will
grow under it. And this helps out. From
my experience, that helps out flowers
grow more even canopy without being that
tree that everybody likes. And it's it's
a Christmas tree. It's nice. But then
you have this top up here getting 1,000
PPFD and have this one down here getting
300. This helps plants to grow more or
less all the same size and all the
canopy from one plant is will be
spearing the same PPFD sort of. Cool. Do
you do any like bending of the tip of
the plant where you like uh will bend
the top down? I know you say you don't
top it, but sometimes I've seen people
they'll just kind of like bend it over
lightly. Super cropping. I I do not on
autoflowers. On out of flowers, I think
that I believe that high stress
trainings in autoflowers is it's going
to result in uh less weight, not
quality, but uh in not so many products.
Why? Sure. Because an autoflower, she's
doing what the [__] she want. She's on
her on her roads. Whatever you you do to
her, she's on her own. Y if you stress
her, she will take time as other plants
have to to bounce back. But that time
that she's bouncing back, it's not it's
not on hold. Keeps going. Meanings her
veg time keeps going or her flower time
keeps going. In the end, that stress
it's it's something
that it did not make you more time. If
you're running feminiz or regular seats,
you can't stress her plants. You wait
for her to bounce back. You can't stress
her again. You wait. And when she's
okay, you flip it to flower. Out of
flowers, they will run whatever they
want. when they want to flip to flower
they will. So in my humbled opinion out
of flowers we are there to assist them
on their needs. So by looking at them by
leaf bending whatever techniques you
like to use it you're just there to
exist not to stress her for sure. Do you
do any up potting when you grow
autoflowers? I know some people will
um heavily push back against doing uh up
pots, but I always found that it worked
really well for auto flowers as long as
you didn't damage the roots when you
were trans. I do three three of them.
Yeah. Three ups and I like to put
microisal in the roots. If I don't do
transplants, I cannot do that. I either
use the promix soil which has the
microisal already in it. But I still
like
to gently see the roots and give a
sprinkle of extra of microisal in there
and then put it in the soil. And I
really see the roots bouncing big. And
they say bigger roots, bigger fruits,
which is not always the case. If you're
growing hydroponics, you can have bigger
fruits in small cups.
So, but uh I grow soil, so bigger roots
in soil mix bigger fruits. and the
microisal it's a really amazing fungi
man it the network it creates there the
uptaking of the nutrients it also helps
breaking things in the soil plants get
more more susceptible the get they get
stronger also and then if you complement
this with for instance
monocyica we'll get a structure on the
on on their cells thicker will get them
stronger will create little layers that
yeah everything but and it's like some
people Oh, you don't need this or no.
Everything is just a tiny little thing,
but in the end it's 2% from this
monosyica, 2% from the microisal, 2%. In
the end, it's this much percentage. And
that's on the overall results to my
experience makes a lot of difference for
sure. Definitely in a uh in a living
soil situation, I I can agree with that.
Um, what microisal fungi do you like to
use? I I only use apples for everything.
I I I've converted myself to to actors 5
years ago. Then 3 years ago I get
sponsored. So now and I honestly don't
see myself uh going back to anything
else because I see this as a marriage.
When you find a good woman, I know
there's more goods in the in the world,
but why would I be looking at them? Why
would I be curious about them if I have
my my wife? You know what I mean? It's
it's my wife. So I see the nutrients and
my relation with app was like that also
and honestly and this this is really
this is really my my opinion. I was a
believer before being sponsored and I
keep being a believer. It works amazing.
It's not it's a concentrated product
meaning I'm not buying water. Most of
the bottles that you get in the market
on the labels I'm not saying they are
better or worse but the percentage of
water comparing to the nutrients is much
bigger. meaning you have to buy many
more times after this super concentrated
man you use tiny little bits it's it's
more expensive I was paying more for the
nutrients yes but they were going triple
the time that other levels were doing so
in the end it was not more expensive for
sure and and they have one thing that
for me it's crucial in any grow which is
the regulator which is for you you guys
have there as a facilitator on the apps
and you have something similar which is
power side. Basically it's
monosyilica which is active and ready
for the plant. It's not silica but
because silica goes in the soil needs to
break down takes time to get available
to the plants. It's it's it's different.
It's good but it takes time. The
monosyilica formula it's straight away
available for the plant. Meaning that
she will drink it straight away and
straight away she will feel it. It's
like taking I don't know the steroids.
You'll feel straight away. You look I'm
not saying that it is steroids and uh
it's the first thing that goes in my
reservoir always. Always. And it it
should be the first thing in any
reservoir because uh nutrients they need
to go in an order, right? Oh, you're too
paranoid. No, I'm not. Try and put the
silica after you put the calm and tell
me what you see in the water and then
you're going to get precipitation. Yeah.
The other way around and you get a clean
water. So this means that there's a
chemic reaction. Everything needs to go
in the order. First goes Monostica, then
goes whatever the rest of your line is.
Yeah, definitely. I mean, I've
um I've experienced like uh mixing
something in the wrong order before and
just learned from that experience. And I
think one of them was I was making uh I
was using potassium silicut to make a
solution for a a pH down or an alkalizer
for my um my nutrient water. And I added
a bunch of um sulfuric acid to the um
potassium silicut because we had uh I
think we just had some like acid spill
or something and we needed to clean it
up. And so we used the alkalizer to
counteract it and it turned into a gel
because the silica turned into silicon
and it um and it turned into that actual
like it had that chemical reaction and I
was like wow that's that's a huge
precipitation event and that would cause
such major clogging if anything like
that were to happen through some sort of
irrigation line or something. Obviously,
you you wouldn't be mixing bases and
acids in an irrigation line, but um but
but how important it is and how chemical
everything it is. It's it's it's like
this by itself, it's nothing. This by
itself, it's nothing. This by itself,
it's a bomb. Yep. And also the
concentration of of those different um
constituents when you're mixing them in
solution is also important. Uh like
another example that I've I've had is I
was we I would use uh magnesium sulfate
and calcium chloride when I would flush
the plants at the end of a cycle um for
just a couple days. But I wanted to
maintain the high uh calcium levels as
well as magnesium because it's in a
cocoa substrate. And there's just other
there's other reasons why there.
um to make to make a long story short,
you know, I would mix them in
individually and I was like, well, why
can't I mix these together? And I found
out, well, because it makes calcium
sulfate when you mix magnesium sulfate
with calcium chloride and calcium
sulfate is uh it it just precipitates
out of solution instantly almost and you
get this huge layer of uh like calcium
sulfate dust at the bottom. uh gypsum
basically at the bottom of the um of the
mix that you made. So yeah, different
things like that are really interesting
to to look at. And when you see
something so drastic like one of the two
examples I gave, you do realize that it
is important even in smaller amounts to
make sure that everything's mixed
properly. Um especially when you do
start to play with higher ECs. I don't
know about like 2.0 0 to 2.5. But if you
start to get up to like 3 to 4, then you
can definitely start to see different uh
chemical reactions take place if things
are mixed in um in the wrong order.
Yeah, it's pretty easy. I for me that's
still I don't know. I might I might get
there with under canopy lights with a
with turning in and good with with
perfect conditions, but for now 2.4 4
2.5 was the the highest I went last run
and this was the highest I went ever on
on soil. Do you use uh supplemental CO2?
No, but I have um the heater on the
house is gas. So we are in winter time.
So for the most time that that turning
just having the heater on it's it's it's
it's enough to bring the numbers higher.
And then it's me, my family and the
dogs. And I I I I build this in a way
that the whole circulation from the
house came straight into the grow room.
Meaning that all that we breach doesn't
go out the other ways. The other ways
are to bring air in. So I always get the
minimum 600 700 ppms in there and if the
heater is on it goes up to 15 to2 and
they're happy with that. So oh that's
too high. No it's not too high. They can
take it up to three and four and five
and uh ppm. It's not perfect for them,
but they can handle it. It's like the
Oh, you giving them 1,200 ppfd. Dude, go
and take your measurement outside middle
of the day in the sun and tell me what
you reach. You go up to five, six,
seven, depending on where you are in the
world. Cool. Well, and also if you are
uh having higher than ambient levels of
CO2, then the plants can definitely
photosynthesize at a higher rate where
that's they're not going to really uh be
bothered by a higher
um a higher light level. And then also,
you know, that's that's also where a
higher EC of feed can come into play and
be handy because you will have just a
higher overall assimilation rate of
nutrients into the tissue of the plant.
So, you're going to need a lot more of a
dense nutrient package in the root zone.
Um, and uh, you know, don't if you do
have those parameters, don't be worried
about getting up in your EC, man. I
mean, I've I've been running lately, but
it is with supplemental CO2 at 1500
parts per million throughout all the
light cycles and a high PPFD. We've been
feeding at um, 4.5 EC and it works
really well, but you have to have a
really clean nutrient to be able to run
it like that. And I don't think you
would be able to get away with that in
an auto pot system because you do need
some level of drain to waste where your
your runoff is. Yeah, your runoff is
pushing off that extra salt buildup. Um
yeah, but with the high level of
nutrients that are available in the
correct ratios at that EC, you can see
tremendous bud growth and overall plant
health with a really
um a really well dialed in environment.
Obviously, you can do it because
facilities are doing it and you look at
whatever they're doing and it looks
beautiful. So they're not doing soil,
they're doing rock, wool or cocoa,
whatever. So it makes sense this what
you're saying of the buildups because on
the other pot you don't have the dry
outs. It's myself that I close the pipes
and I let it go for dry outs and if I
want to do top fitting on something but
uh the aqua valve the way that that
thing works is he has it's kind of
like he has one one one rubber here and
one rubber down here. When this rubber
hits down here, it's a this one
releases. And when this comes and hits
here, this one releases. Meaning the
plants get the water, the valves go like
this. Then she drinks the water. This
comes down here. And once it's on it, it
opens. It releases again. It will full
again. But the soil is always wet.
There's there's always
I don't know the exact percentage, but
there's always at least 10 15% moist in
there. So for living soil, it's great.
for soil. It's great. I don't know how
this worked with cocoa because I did not
do cocoa in here, but um yeah, you also
said you're using substrate monitoring,
correct? So, you're seeing the water
content and the electrical conductivity
within the substrate. And you know, when
you have that data available, it really
opens up your eyes to what's going on in
the root zone and you can see more
clearly as to how the plant is
interacting with the nutrients that
you're providing it as well as the water
that you're providing it. And a lot of
people do get scared running higher ECs
because they think it's building up in
the soil. But if you can't see what's in
there, then it the only way you're going
to tell tell if you are building up, you
know, things that you don't want in
there is if you're doing like a
saturated paste test or if you're
sending off your substrate for analysis
or if you're running uh uh runoff checks
where you're gathering runoff data
through EC and uh pH.
Um, and and unless you have all that
information, then it's really hard to
tell what's actually going on in there,
you know, unless you do have this uh
substrate monitoring tool where you can
follow a graph basically and it shows
you the highs and the lows and the
trends over time and you can see if it's
been slowly raising up or slowly going
down or staying steady. And you can make
a lot of educated changes to what your
inputs are based on that information.
And it's unfortunate because so many of
those substrate monitoring tools are
extremely expensive. You know, it's like
uh yeah, to anybody who's just
listening, he's showing us his substrate
monitoring just uh right here. So that's
Yeah, it's it's right there. It's
information that you can look at, but it
is expensive. I don't know if you're
using like a Trollmaster substrate
monitor, like one of their WCS um the
WCS2. Yes, monitor exactly what I'm
using. Those are like really great
pieces of equipment, but in a lot of
cases, you know, they're really
expensive to get even just one of them
to move. You need to have 10X or an
Hydro X or something. So, it's not just
the piece of equipment like the the
single item. I think Blue Labs has one
that is just the item coming out now.
There's Blue Love the the good ones is
the Blue Labs and the Troll Master. But
now Mars Hydro, it's done one. Spider
Farm, it's done one. AC Infinity also
did one. And if you go Amazon and you
look online, there's a lot a lot of lot
of them from China. Of course, I don't
know how good or bad they work, but uh
there's a lot of options. meaning that
sooner or later both draw master and all
the the expensive labels they are not
expensive they are just better
construction so it's normal that it's
more expensive you don't pay the same
for a Maserati that you pay for a
a Renault or for a Ford so things get
different prices so yeah and I I used
for our monitoring at the commercial
facility and they did come out with like
the Aoya go platform but even still
the, you know, the startup price was
like $1,500 or $2,000 US, and you, it
came with like a a two-year subscription
to being able to stay store your data,
but after that, you would have to pay a
monthly fee in order to maintain access
to all the data that they're providing.
and the, you know, the whole
subscription service and not being able
to just have that data based on you
purchasing the equipment right there and
and then just like using it locally, not
even necessarily
um like trying to use any of the other
services that they provide, you still
would have to pay for it. And that can
just become even more cost prohibitive
in a lot of ways for people because like
even with some of the other shows that
you've interacted with in the past like
the cheap homegrow you know growing with
my fellow growers show the whole point
of that show is to help people grow
cheaply because cannabis is really
expensive when you're going and buying
it at a dispensary. um in in the United
States and you know anywhere else that
does have access to either a
recreational or medical market it's
expensive and you can grow it for so
much cheaper at home but you know a lot
of people do struggle early
on in the beginning when you don't know
and you think you need more than you
think that you need it's very easy to to
for a grow to become super expensive
with the things that you buy and that
you get Then with overtime experience,
you're starting to realize that what you
need and what you don't need and it
becomes more cost effective and stuff
like that. But it's still not a cheap
hobby. It's not a cheap hobby,
especially if you passionate about it.
There's always something new coming out
and you want to try this and see that
and that. I don't know. Some people like
cars, they buy cars. other people when
when you like this you will go for the
gadgets here for the controllers for the
the little things that do you need them
no you don't need them to grow but they
will help your journey they will uh
which we're trying to be better than
nature which we will never be but that's
that's our our goal it's to be better
than nature to be better than nature
which is impossible nobody can be better
than god this is just my opinion of
course but we go we best we try the lead
we try the extraction
What are we trying to do? Mimic gods.
We're trying to do what he does on the
perfect way inside here with controls
and with everything. And that takes
money and um it's fun job. It's a fun
not a job. It's a fun hobby, but it's an
an expensive one. Honestly, when you an
adult, any hobby that you have, it's
expensive.
Hobby. This is whatever you like. It's
it's it's not it's going to be
expensive. Yeah. Especially if you have
some sort of passion or u real desire to
want to like learn as much as you can
within that hobby. It's going to it'll
drain your wallet in most cases. Um
so you you've you've been growing for
you said over 20 years now.
More. More. Cool. Yeah. More. Yeah. More
than three decades now or and Yeah. And
with the ideas in mind of what we were
just talking about with new growers and
how it's sometimes difficult for a new
grower when they're starting off, um,
how long did it take you to achieve your
first harvest that you were extremely
proud about?
That that's a hard question and a very
good one. Nobody ever did that. That one
got me thinking. I don't
know honestly when I look back
now I'm really only happy happy happy
with what I'm growing now for the past
decade maybe it's maybe maybe not even
that because before that was a passion
but I love it was amazing it was better
than anything else I could get it
anywhere but now I see what I grow now
man I see what I grew last here and I
see how I grow now and I see difference,
right? I don't know if it's me growing
better, if it's the me tuning in things
better, if it's the everything else in
conjunction that makes it but it looks
better, it tastes better. So, I'm really
proud of what I smoke now. But I was
super proud of what I was smoking 10
years ago.
So I I think that we grow and we evolve
in the same way when we somebody would
come to you with weed and you were just
a teenager and you will grab it ro and
smoke and now when a friend comes to you
with weed
analyzing it and put it almost under the
microscope and there's a law that you
have to talk about that with I thought
it was just weed. So we we ourselves
also evolve into someone different that
is more
um picky more uh existent I don't know
how to express it with with everything
which lead us to grow better to to
search for turppins something that 10
years ago turppins turppins yes tpins
yes what the hell is turppins I knew
what was turppins but I would not
growing for turppins for the past decade
I don't care about potency my friend I
care. Of course, I don't want to be
smoking and not feeling
anything, but I care about the
experience for for all of the experience
from the moment that I open my jar.
Sure. From the moment I open the groove
bag and I take that first aroma that
comes in my nose and then when I grab
it, when I look at it, when I break it
down, when I roll it and I smoke it and
I like to do all of it, I don't like to
do the cones. I like to feel it. And
when when you do your first dry puff and
it tastes the same as the smell. Yeah.
For me that's already okay. Okay. We are
running to something. We are running to
and then you smoke and then you get that
third profile coming into you and then
something else different comes
completely different outside and my mind
keeps blowing and time. Sorry. No, it's
it's all good. I I love the passion
behind what you're saying there because
it makes me think of someone who is an
educated consumer versus an uneducated
consumer, right? So, um with with like
the US market, we have this issue where
everything is based on THC. And I know
that that's uh something that's
widespread just across the the world of
consumers with cannabis now that there
is the ability to test for THC and that
it's the largest constituent of the
cannabonoids typically that that's the
number that people are looking at. And
now that they have access to tarpen
testing, people are interested in that
as well. But now they're saying I want
something with a lot of tarpen and a lot
of THC. And they're not necessarily even
thinking, oh, what have I had in the
past that has worked really well for me?
they're just going for the, you know,
the most. And it's it's really odd. And
so it's almost like uh the term that
comes to mind is the tyranny of numbers
where because we can test for it, people
now use that as the um the qualifier for
what is good
versus experiencing something, you know,
saying, "Wow, I really like this." and
then looking at, you know, what it
what's in it so that you can try to find
that elsewhere. Um, you know, it's it's
not necessarily driven off of an
experience-based thing. It's driven off
of a perception of what they what they
want to experience based on everything
some weird number system uh that
we've it's it's unfortunate, but it's
where we're at. It is. It is. and and
and they also I think in the in the
general weed right now it's way stronger
than it was 20 years ago with the
breedings with
everything which is okay it's good I
probably if I would smoke the same way
that I would smoke 20 years ago right
now it probably wouldn't do anything to
me but on this process they're losing a
lot of like the CBD 10 20 years ago we
has a balance of THC a balance of CBD
and then there was the tarpins and
everything else. Right now there's zero
CBD. There's a big number on THC. And
now the turppins are coming in lower
numbers. It's three, five, 10% or
something like this. It's the highest it
goes on the turppins. I don't know. But
it's really low numbers. And people are
looking for that with the bigger it's
better. Bigger it's better. Bigger it's
it's not bigger it's better. It's the
balance that it makes it better. It can
be really low, maybe 10% THC, but those
5% tarpins in
there will make you experience that by
itself the high will be much more
pleasable and and and last last longing.
And another thing that I noticed from
old wheats I I like to call it like this
and new wheats old wheat like the old
skunk the old super skanks and all of
that they would last
for they would last I don't know for 2
hours 3 hours but uh you would get that
trippy feeling from the medicine for for
a long time right now with the new it
you may get that but it's 10 minutes
peak 15 minutes peak And then you need
to smoke again to keep that going. It's
not I don't know if this is also
because you are
now power tolerance also may may not
help to this but but still I do a break
for a week for on smoking. It's very
rare but it it it happens. And when I
smoke again, I feel it's I feel it
straight away. But it's not that uh two
hours that I don't have to think about
rolling another one. What are you
talking about? After 45 minutes, I'm
already thinking about rolling another
one and another one and and so on. And I
think this was the breeding out of
everything to put in the THC numbers in
it that I don't know. This is just me
thinking. I think that's definitely a I
think that's definitely a part of it.
Um, another thing that I've talked about
before on the show is that there's just
more availability of different genetics,
all of which are going to have different
THC can overall cannabonoid and tarpine
profiles as well as whatever other
volatile organic compounds are in there.
And due to the fact that we all have
unique endockinabonoid systems, if
you're sifting through a million
different strains to try and find the
ones or the twos that work for you, you
know, then that's going to be a lot
harder than sifting through the five or
10 strains available in your local area
at the time, uh, you know, 10, 20 years
ago. So, you know, and I know that there
is a lot more available, but not
necessarily at the level that we have
now due to the more popularization of
cannabis culture worldwide that we've
been able to see through the different
legal and recreational markets that have
come online. It opened up just so much
more access to information, uh, strains,
cultivars, the trading of genetics,
whether it be seed stock or clones. And
now with tissue culture, the ability to
transfer a lot of those different
genetics worldwide with ease and uh not
risk exposure or you know incrimination
due to those different uh aspects of
what we can do now. It's a fascinating
world. You know, it's it it opens up so
much more availability for
different cultivars that you you know,
there's the the benefit of it where if
you find something that really works for
you now, like you might be able to find
something that works so well for you now
that you may not have ever been able to
find before because it just wasn't
available. Whereas the sifting of
getting through all those different
strains now is going to take so much
longer that it almost seems impossible
to actually find that super unique
um you know unicorns are getting more
unicorns every day. Unicorns are
becoming harder to find. Yeah. Yeah.
Absolutely. That's true.
There's there's way more options to look
for it, but there's way less unicorns
and and if you really see all the
options kind of came from the same
parents for sure, you know, then they
crossed and recrossed and Greek this
this and that. But if you go to the
base, there's northern
lights, there's
um uh Durban poison, there's Afghani,
there's this, there's that. And from
this the crosses with those 10 maybe 10,
maybe 20, there are thousands. Yeah.
That were born right now. And um with
legalization hitting all over the world
as you were saying, more people also
it's playing and uh which is great man.
You see this is a beautiful thing
because otherwise the plant would not
evolve and tissue culture you were
talking it's something that really
fascinated me. I don't know exact I
never went too deep of it but the fact
that you can preserve the exact same
thing without any pathogens without
anything and a little thing like this
for decades I mean it's crazy and then
you can grow the same plant it's it's
crazy and now there's AI also involved
in in seeds here I don't know if you
heard about it they can AI can identify
the seed male or
female this is huge because uh I don't
know if this is is something that will
come up or not because there's a big
market for feminized seeds around the
world but supposedly feminized seeds are
weaker seeds than regular seeds. They
say if the regular seeds take out the
male problem which is for the home
grower I buy 10 seeds regular and then I
have eight males. This is a problem for
a home grower. If you're in a facility
that you're searching, okay, this goes,
this keeps going.
Like for now, I'm growing the mentado
from the genetics. It's a mutant plant
and it was 12 12 seeds from the 12. I
have five females. All of the rest was
to kill. I have space. I can do this. I
am playing. I don't mind if I'm losing
time because I I like what I'm doing.
But if I only have a closet like a 4x4
or something and this is my grow, if I
put 10 plants in there, it's because I
want the 10 plants out or if I put five
in there, you know what I mean? So if I
if if with AI we can identify that this
seed is female exactly 100%. This is
huge. I I have to see that to believe it
because there's huge. Yeah, that that
would be huge if it were something that
that an AI software could do, but I am
very skeptical. Yeah, I have to see that
happen with a a proven regular pack of
seeds and make sure they're not slipping
a bunch of feminized seeds into the into
the process to try and trick everyone
into thinking that it works. But that
that's fascinating. I'm glad you brought
it up. I'm going to have to look into
that. Go, go, go. I can send you a few
articles on it after it's with pleasure
and you can look for it when it's a new
thing. It's something that it's been
talking about only for the past few
months I believe. At least I only
realized about it a few months ago. But
if this really is true and if this
really goes forward with it, I don't see
why seed companies would not do this to
them. I know there's a big market for
feminiz, but dude, you're selling
feminizes anyway. No, it's just regular
that you were sure that it's a feminiz.
So, let's see. Let's see what the future
has for us on this one. But I'm
definitely I won't say no. You know,
like if it if it works, it works. But
I'm not, you
know, I'm definitely trepidacious to to
be like, "Oh, for sure. That sounds
awesome."
It's like the laser for the the bugs.
Exactly. I would love to have like a
mini drone like this big going in my
tent killing bugs. Yeah.
just set it off for 5 minutes a day. Um,
what are uh what are some of the biggest
setbacks that you faced as a grower? Um,
you know, considering a lot of people
that listen to this are home growers
themselves and everyone faces different
problems within their grow, but we all
have to learn to kind of bounce back
from them. What are some of those
setbacks that you've had to bounce back
from? Honestly, the biggest one and that
I struggle with still even with decades
of growing I sometimes struggle with it
is patience when we growing. I think
this is the biggest thing on growing
it's you have to be patient for
everything in the beginning with the
water especially if you are new new
grower and there's a lot of things
happening and you want to do everything
because uh it's everything is new. So in
the beginning you overwater them then
then you realize you overwatering then
you will be underwatering them. This is
all the process for you to learn and for
people to learn. But I honestly believe
that the biggest setback that we have
it's ourself with the hurry. We hurry to
water. We we we hurry to trim to trim to
defoliate. We hurry to harvest. And
dudes, if you are months and months and
month, not months and months, but three,
four months surrounding a plants or grow
or whatever and then in the end you
harvested too soon, you're losing
potential and you're losing weight and
in my humble opinion, you're losing
three or four months of work because
this is not the the thing. So honestly,
I don't know if this was the what you
were looking back. I think patience and
uh it's the biggest thing that we as
growers need to learn and to accept and
to embrace that uh planting is believing
in the future. So believe in it because
it will take time. It's the same as a
potato, a strawberry, whatever you're
putting on the ground. It will take time
to grow and you cannot rush nature. You
can you really can't. Now, I think
that's a great uh sentiment to deliver
to other growers is patience is key. Um,
we have one of the fastest growing crops
growing for us uh either in our home
grow or outdoor setting or whatever. Um,
and so, you know, we don't need that
much patience with cannabis because you
can have from seed to the the pipe or
bowl or whatever it is that you're using
to smoke that final product with. Yeah.
four months. Maybe four months you you
can do it. Yeah. There's not not a lot
of other plants that you can say, "Hey,
I'm I'm I'm planting this apple tree and
I'm going to eat an apple in four
months." That doesn't happen. Um so, you
know, I feel like be appreciative for
the fact that it grows so fast. But
learn a little bit of patience is a
definite good thing to uh relay to other
growers. I do see people harvesting
still too soon and um sometimes giving
it those extra few weeks uh it just
makes for such a different product in
the end.
But you know that wasn't necessar that I
guess that wasn't necessarily what I was
thinking about when I asked the question
of biggest setbacks. But maybe a better
way to um to phrase it is one of the
things that I like to ask growers is
what are some of the biggest or what
like what is a lesson that you've
learned from a failure in your garden
and then what is a lesson that you've
learned from a success in your garden?
lesson
from let me see so for
failures over watering is it's really
bad for you because you will stuck your
plants I think it's it's worse to
overwater than to underwater for the
single reason that uh an a dry plant if
it will look almost dead but if you give
it water to heat it will bounce back and
over water plants will have problems on
uptaking nutrients. We'll have problems
on root root raw. We'll have problems in
a lot of things. So overwatering is
definitely um a big big big thing a big
lesson in the in the garden and and it's
something that it takes time takes time
to to
to learn either it by weight on the on
the pots. This is something that when I
was not doing automatic wings with auto
pots, I I was something that I found
myself doing it is I know how much it is
without watering. Now I water on how
much it is and then I will look for that
same weight for me to water again. This
was how I myself fight the overwatering
because in the beginning I was
overwatering especially in the in the in
the first years everything was just
water water water water water water
water we would go in water water and the
same plants they drink a lot and they
don't mind that and if especially if the
water goes away and it doesn't stay in
the soil but most of the them they don't
like over watering they they they will
get stuck on growth they will get stuck
on eating, they will get stuck on
everything. That that I think this is
one of the biggest lessons for me in in
growing is the waterings. And you know
what almost falls in line with patience,
right? Like sometimes when you're when
you first start growing, you're like, I
got to make sure that the plant has
water. And rather than being patient and
allowing for it to use the water that it
already has to a certain level so that
you don't create anorobic or hypoxic
conditions in the root zone and cause
these different root health issues. Um,
you know, having that patience to wait
for that dryback, make sure that it
happens. You know, I I do see a lot of
growers where they're just like, I got
to make sure that I get that water on
there like right now.
I I I stop rushing the waters. I I I
actually prefer to to get into the room
and see them like kind of drippy. Oh
man, I forget to water for two three
days. I need to water because I'm never
that time that longer away from them
than to be to finding them droopy just
because of the overwatering. That's for
sure. For sure. Lessons learned when
mistakes were making. I don't know.
Super crop. I learned myself from
mistakes. I did not learn. I did not
know it. did not know it was super
cropping until later on because
supercropping happen when you're working
and you break it and oh [__] it started
breaking and that suddenly that broken
branch becomes the best fruit in your
garden. This was how I learned myself
about supercropping and I started to
implement this this a few decades ago
without reading or seeing anything and
now day now I know it's super cropping
but this all begin with me breaking
branches and that
branch making the best buds in the whole
tent and then I okay wait this this this
may be or may not be let's see and I
start breaking them for myself now I go
there I gently
like I really I super crop them if they
go too big. But this one was a mistake
that took me to a lesson and one that I
used till today and it's been a few
years now. I know the names and the
techniques for them. But this is how I'm
curious about the new one. This one it's
something that I'm I need to do it. I
need to find time and courage to do
it because it happened to me two times
and on the two times that it happened I
will explain you in a second. I believe
that plants grew better. What was this?
Everybody has this big paranoia that the
little top root from the seed, the first
one, cannot be touched, cannot be
broken, cannot be nothing because it's
very
sensitive. The two times that I broke it
in half and I still put it in the
soil, plants grew amazing
compared to the rest of it. So, what I
want to do, this is this is probably
something that I will be doing maybe on
the next run on a few couple of runs, is
I'm going to do 10 seeds and I'm going
to purposely cut five of them in half,
the the tiny root, and the other five
I'm going to leave it normal. And I'm
going to plant them. And I want to
see if the five that I cut the the root
in half, the the mini top in half, will
all grow better than the other five. If
that happens, then I will know for sure
that uh this was just not a casual thing
that happened because the two times that
this happened and I realized it happened
because when I grabbed the seed, the
half of the roots just stuck there and I
still put it in soil, they grew amazing.
So, I'm curious to do this test. It's
fascinating. It makes me think of root
pruning with bonsai where you um you
know you have the bonsai in a small pot
where the roots are constricted to a
certain amount of substrate and then
periodically you go in and you trim off
the extra roots, add some fresh
substrate, get it back in there and you
get this explosive growth for the next
uh amount of time. Um, I've even helped
other growers where they've h have, you
know, they have limited space and they
have to keep all their moms in like a
onegon pot or something along those
lines. So, they'll every few months
they'll, you know, if they don't have
the ability to clone it, right? then or
if they let it go too long so it's
rootbound and you don't have really good
healthy growth. You go in, you pull the
root ball out of the pot, you shave a
quarter to/ inch off of all the
different sides with like a bread knife
or something and then you just put fresh
substrate in there and put it back in
and you get that new root growth um from
the root pruning and you get uh you know
healthy new uh upper growth and you can
take a clone so that you can reset it.
Um it and that's also what works uh or
why fabric pots uh tend to work fairly
well where you can use a smaller fabric
pot um for a larger plant uh where you
might need a larger plastic or solid pot
for the same size plant. Otherwise, this
is because of the the roots getting into
outside and sending the signal out. And
then instead of going around the pot,
it's it creates a bigger mass of roots
inside of the whole pot, filling up the
the the soil better than obtaining
better nutrients. I believe in plastic
pot, this doesn't happen. The roots once
it hits the hole, it will try to keep
growing because it there's nothing there
signal. There's no hair, there's no
there's nothing signal. So she keeps
searching for the deeper place. And this
is why you get those pots with those big
roots. When you using fabric pots and
you take the roots out, you take a
block. Yep. It's a block of soil and it
looks like it doesn't have any roots,
but there's a lot of roots in there. But
it's like a solid root. No, you get the
big massive root down there, you get the
roots going around and then in the
center of it, there's roots,
but it's not the same. It really is not
the same. Yeah, the overall root mass is
definitely smaller. Um, if you were to
grow the same plant in a fabric versus a
plastic pot and at the, you know, the
same time frame, you'd find a greater
root mass in the fabric pot by like the
end of 30 days.
It's crazy. It's crazy. I don't know the
name of it, but it's because of the
sign. It's the same happens that when
the plant gets to the soil, it's it's
it's his hair and it sing signals the
roots to go down and she keeps growing.
I think it works the same way with the
with the fabric pot. Yep. Absolutely. I
think that for the fabric pots and for
that that would be called air pruning.
And then
and then you can also just physically
prune the roots yourself if you need to
accomplish the same thing in a smaller
pot or if you need to remain in that
smaller pot for a longer period of time
for whatever reason. Um in veg it's no
problem to do that. They will bounce it
back. They will love if it's not enough
flower.
Yes, absolutely. Don't do that with an
autoflower, folks. Don't do that with an
autoflower. You're going to trigger it
to flower. So, you know, that those
being some of the the points where you
found, you know, you learned from
something that went wrong, you know, in
your grow where you didn't intend for
the outcome to be what it was, um, but
you learned from it. What are some of
the things where you went into the
process of being like, I'm going to add
this because I I think that it's going
to increase X Y or Z. Uh so where have
you found a success in your garden like
that where you you added something in
and it did exactly what you wanted it to
do? Microisal.
Okay. Seriously. And
um when I first heard about microisal, I
could not believe it myself that it
would do that. Then I start researching
and I find out that I believe it's in
Japan they use microiser to do the
subway meaning they place it the the
stations and they put the microiser and
the microiser in the beginning make made
the big mess and then it creates the
perfect roads and they did the subway
that way. I'm not sure if it was Japan,
Taiwan, some somebody there did that.
Yeah, they they used like a mcelium
culture to do that and this and I start
researching and researching and I start
realizing man this is the biggest
network that exists on earth. There's
nothing bigger than microisal in the
world. We can think that no it's
connected from elsewhere to everywhere.
I I kind of believe that almost all
plants in the world are underconnected
because of the microisal. not the ones
in the pot because they're by themselves
but uh nature itself and when I first
time I imple I implement the microisal
in this case was appto the microisal in
in in my
plants I did a side by side because I
wanted to make sure that uh it would
make big difference or no difference and
it's crazy the the the big roots the
white roots the channels a root without
microism it grows like this and it has a
little tiny hair, normal roots, a root
with microisal, it grows like that and
it's thousands of hairs going all over
her and all of that things are are
receptors are connectors that will help
the plant improve. So I I really think
that the microisal was definitely the
biggest thing that I saw results and it
was exactly what I was looking for and
uh what I was expecting. All of the rest
it is but it is not. This was beyond my
expectations actually. This and the
ender canopy lights the end canopy but
this is still a new factor. I'm still
it's just my second run so I don't know.
Y but for my first run that really was
crazy man. I was expecting I was not
expecting almost double the harvest and
I get almost double the harvest that I
would do on a 4x4. So that's awesome. It
was crazy. It was crazy. And it was not
double the power because the ICL 300
they
are 150 watts each one I believe. So
it's 300 W more in the tent and on top
it's 700 meaning it's not double. It's
not
1,400. It's not supposed to go double
and it went almost double which was I
know it was first run. So I I don't
know. I still need to experience more to
see if this actually is over expectating
what I was expecting or if this was just
the perfect run and now I'm going to be
it's going to be hard to to do it again
and to to to replicate the the results.
Let's see. Let's see. Y cuz we've
definitely found that we are getting a
lot of or a lot higher of a yield with
the under canopy lights, but it's
definitely not double or anything. But
like you said, we're not adding double
the total uh you know, wattage input to
that space. Um, and even still with the
under canopy lights, you know, like if
we're if we're adding uh an additional
30% to the overall wattage input, we're
not seeing a 30% increase in yield. Um,
but we are still seeing an increase in
yield. And the the biggest thing that I
see is you get an increase in overall
uh uniformity of quality where the the
quality that you typically go for. For
me, uh my favorite flowers are typically
about three or four nodes down from the
topmost bud. And because it's usually
like picture perfect, it isn't grown
into another bud. So when you dry it
down and snap it away from the stem, it
gives you a really good um
representation of the morphology of that
plant and the flower structure and the
tricom density and the brack development
and you know everything about it. you
get a really nice representation of the
plant where the lowers would always, you
know, they'd either be with some
cultivars, they'd be dense still, but
they'd just be small popcorny. They
wouldn't have great color, you know, if
if the plant up top turn nice and
purple. Sometimes the lowers stay a
little greener, or maybe they'll they'll
be more of like a a light version of
whatever color you get at the top. Um,
and they, you know, won't necessarily
always develop fully. So, they'll
sometimes still have white hairs
or, you know, just not not be there, not
mature, right? And but when I added the
under canopy lights, I noticed that
everything across the canopy typically,
as long as I'm keeping that overall
canopy density um within the range of
what my irrigation can provide for it
and what I can do for it based on
environmental factors. Um, I can see
uniformity almost from that third or
fourth bud down from the top cuz those
tops still do what they do and they get
dense and packed together at the very
end. But from about that third or fourth
node down all the way down through the
plant, I see a very similar morphology.
And so I can turn a lot of what would
be, you know, B's or C's uh in my in my
buds. you know, if you're separating
them out where you have A's, B's, and
C's in terms of the quality and the look
and the overall size and everything. I
turn a lot of the B's into A's, and I
turn a lot of the C's into B's or A's
even in some cases, as long as I'm okay
with having smaller flowers in that A's
category. They still hold up when you
look at it as color and tricom density
and uh overall flower density. Um, so
that's where I found like I'm super
happy with that because typically I
would get like 20 to 30% of the overall
harvest wouldn't necessarily be
something that you could in the
recreational market sell as this top
quality flower. You could press it,
sure, but that's a whole different
aspect that you you would need like a
specific license to do that in the
recreational market. And so, um, but if
I can turn all of my flowers into A's
and I can just make more pounds that are
resellable or kilos depending on the
market that you're in, you know, that's
that's well worth it for me. Um, and I
feel like for home growers, if there is
an aspect to the consumption of cannabis
for, you know, any other grower out
there, whether it be home grower or just
a consumer that's going to a
recreational dispensary and picking up
flour, you know, there's an aspect to it
about the flower itself and how it looks
and how it feels and, you know, how it
grinds up and how it breaks apart that
if you can make a little bit more
uniformity across the board that even
for a home grower, you're going to have
more stuff that you're enjoying than
it's going to it's going to last you for
longer also because all of those
popcorns that you use if you press you
would press if you make RSO or if you
make whatever you used to do it for that
now there cease to exist there there
will be a very small amount of it if you
do the good pruning if you do a good
defoliations and if you
clean enough down there but leave enough
steel that that that that enough steel
that you leave. It's bud now. It's it's
it's smokable bud. It's not popcorn like
you were saying or it's not under
development like you were saying. Now
the plant finishes from top to bottom
pretty much at all at the same time.
Well, before this run, I would think on,
okay, maybe I harvest half of the plant,
but I will still leave that harvest half
to finish because I see that there's
potential over here for it to still
mature and
grow. This did not happen with the with
the last run. I end up harvesting um two
top of the plants earlier, but this was
because of bud raw trying to get in. And
this was my way of saving the the
closets. This is a very important thing
for everybody that is growing. It's when
you growing a very dense and pocket room
and that thing was really scrggrogged
and super dense and buds get too dense
air flow is very important and even with
good airflow even with good conditions
but raw can appear and early detections
it's very very important because
otherwise it's all your work going
bananas because it will spread really
fast.
So I found one, I took it out. Then on
the next day, I found another one coming
here. So I decided all the big tops on
top of the ones that were affected, I
took them out. This was the solo reason
why I harvest them before because
honestly the whole room in this case and
or the whole plant was maturing at the
same level, at the same pace, at the
same rhythm. And this was beautiful to
see. This was the first time I ever saw
this. It's it's a mature pop not popcorn
as a mature ball down there at
conjunction with there the whole canopy
to the whole room. This this was
something beautiful and then I'm curious
to see if it will happen here or not.
For sure. Yeah. I always will tell
people also if they're facing any sort
of potential bud rot scenarios or
betritis or you know anything that would
affect the overall flower yield that you
might get out of a a space due to
um you know uh pathogens or or or other
um I'm blinking on the word right now
but uh you know these different micology
uh pathogens that you might face um
molds or mildew right? Uh that by
topping your plants early on and
producing more tops for that one pot,
you have the opportunity to make those
overall top colas a little bit smaller
each. You know, I feel like each plant,
and this is just anecdotal evidence, but
I feel like each plant has a certain
amount of potential for overall
um yield based on the pot size that
you're using. And if you dedicate all
that um that whole plant into producing
one cola, you know, where you don't top
the plant, so you still do have side
branching. So it still does kind of
disperse that energy across a large
canopy. But if you do have that one top
cola where it is going in and it's
getting getting like a higher PPFD,
maybe the environment there is a little
bit more ideal for overall growth and
development, then you're going to get a
lot larger of a cola. But that's going
to create a lot more potential for
pathogens to get into it and to take
hold and ruin some of the yield. So if
you top your plant and you let that
energy spread out across the canopy so
that all the tops are kind of uniform,
then you can reduce that by having
smaller buds. And even in some cultivars
in a commercial space, I' I've found
that you get a more desirable morphology
as well if you spread that energy around
to a lot more upper bud sites rather
than just one large upper bud site and a
bunch of side branches. The only, you
know, the only issue that I've ever
found with that is that I don't like
topping for um any sort
of any sort of growing style typically
because if you look at it as a top- down
sort of planular view of a given canopy
space, if it's completely flat, let's
say in a 4x4 tent, then you of 16 square
ft of canopy that the light is hitting
that you're able to absorb and and
photosynthesize with as the plants. But
if you have peaks and valleys, so um you
know if you keep those upper colas on
but then you so you'll have almost like
one upper canopy where all let's say you
have nine plants in that 4x4 space. You
have nine upper colas, right? And then
you have a lower canopy where all the
side branches kind of came up to. You
have these peaks and valleys. And if you
leave all the leaves on there, then
technically with those peaks and
valleys, you're spreading out that 4x4
space into a larger footprint. And I I
don't have the math in front of me, but
I believe you get about like 1.5 to 1.6
times the overall canopy space. So
rather than being 16 square ft, you
know, you're like over 20 square feet at
that point of overall um like highly
photo
synthetically potential um within that
canopy. So you can increase your overall
yield by doing that by capturing more
photons as they leave the light and
enter the canopy. But like I said
before, it's very case dependent where
if you
have massive colas that are going to get
rot because let's say you can't control
part of your environment or it's just
too big and it just always happens or
there's some genetic potential for
different pathogens to take hold. Yeah.
That's uh that's where you need to then
potentially top your plants or or do
something to manipulate the canopy to
create a more uh desirable flower
structure so that it doesn't have those
potentials for pathogens.
For for this one, I tried it all, my
friend. This this uh this was a a closet
with six different genetics. So it was
normal for them to grow different and
um funny enough the younger one the one
that came later because two of them did
not germinate it. So I decided to bring
the papayas up later on. So she was two
weeks younger than the rest of the room.
Oh I'm making
balloons. She was two weeks younger than
the rest of the room and she was the one
that stretched or that bulk the most and
higher. So I super crop her. I bend her.
I the scrog net on the top. She she was
talked that I use on the top. I did not
use for support. I used the scrog net so
that after making the super crop to hold
her there because I would super crop and
the next day I would super crop again
and the next day. Yeah. So this one this
particular
one despite topping was growing this
this like this much distance from the
the the LED up there. She was I don't
know crazy crazy numbers down there and
despite having hair flow she grew colas
like this all of them. Yeah.
So I don't know if it was and I cannot
sacrifice the whole room just for that
one. So I had to keep the
environment at 60% of humidity in my
case. This is what I like to do in
flower actually. I know it's a risky
thing for pathogens is this and that but
um they like it and if you have no
problems in there I do my whole flowers
at 60% maybe 55 by the end. Yeah. But I
don't do like the most do like 50
45 sorry I I start at
77% relative humidity and then I'll work
it down over time to 60 55 and finish
with the daytime humidity being around
55 and the nighttime humidity being at
45 or so. Um because I I try to increase
that temperature differential too. Um
sorry that's another thing I try to do
the most when I can. It's to keep a a
very similar temperature from day and
night. I try to bounce it the least I
can. I find that uh if I get 20 I will
be talking in Celsius, but I can
actually tell you in Oh, 20 Celsius.
What's that like? Uh 78
65. Yes. If I have it, let's let's go 24
because it's a good a good one for for
cannabis to grow. So if I'm at 70, which
is a good good uh temperature, I try to
keep it I I can only do this in in
summertime. I try to keep it the daytime
and the night time same temperature.
Mhm. So if it's 70 at daytime, I will
try and keep it 70 at night time. And in
summertime, I can do this because I grew
during the night cycle. Sure. meaning
that daytime it's hot where I live. The
temperatures goes up to
uh 90s, hundreds. It's normal to be
outside about 90s and 100s.
So, they are sleeping and they have the
temperatures from the outside hair that
comes into the house that keeps it warm.
So meaning that I c I get to in
summertime I'm able to grow at about 80
70 to 80 both day and night time. And I
find out that uh they like that. They
really like that. That's
the that's why I like to grow in
summertime more than I like to grow in
winter time. It's less humidity first of
all. And um they grow more uh stable.
they grow more
beautiful. It's a little bit more
expensive because of the AC that you
have to run AC still to to keep things
on balance because um temperatures
sometimes go really high and you cannot
do that. But then again, if you're
growing in the night cycle, this means
you have to work at night instead of
working at day. Yeah. the temperatures
from the night with balance but bounce
back with the leads with everything and
we you will create a more stable room
with less bouncing on temperatures and
on everything. I think it's it's and I
think that uh our medicine specifically
if she could grow always at the same
temperature and always at the same
humidity that would be the perfect for
her. I don't know because I could not do
this from seed to harvest ever. Sure.
But this is something that I would
definitely like to test and if if I had
the meanings to do this,
I would I would do I would try this
actually for sure. You know, there's a
lot of um research on temperature
differentials in greenhouse settings
where um with certain flowering plants
and stuff and it it's been proven to
work in cannabis as well, you can run
what's called a negative differential.
Um, so a negative differential being the
nighttime temperatures are greater than
the daytime temperatures. A neutral
differential, which is what you're
talking about, where the daytime and
nighttime temperatures are the same. And
then a positive differential where the
daytime temperatures are greater than
the nighttime temperatures. And so one
thing that has been found with cannabis
is that if you run a negative
differential earlier in the flowering
cycle where the nighttime temperatures
are greater than the daytime
temperatures, you can actually reduce
the overall stretch that the plant in uh
goes through
when you when you go through that
stretching bolting phase of the
flowering period for the plant. Um and
then you know everywhere from that all
the way to a positive differential can
adjust that stretch on the plant to
where in an
extreme positive differential where you
have
10 you have 10 or more in in Fahrenheit
I'm talking uh 10 F then you will
um that's you you'll increase the
ability for the plant to stretch by
increasing that positive differential.
Um, so I've used that before in an
indoor setting because I overveged my
plants, right? And so I had to reduce
the overall stretch because I only had a
certain canopy height that I could um
safely maintain for the the production
of those plants. Um, and it it does
work. It's not a perfect thing. It
doesn't there's there's different
research on it where you can do it for
like the first 15 or or 30 minutes after
the lights are turned off uh or you know
initiating the dark period. And then
there's other research about doing it
right before the lights come on and
doing this negative differential swing
um but then maintaining a neutral or a
positive differential through a later
period of the night cycle. Um, so
there's a lot more research that I feel
like could be done with that as well as
having more people try to apply this
research that is done on other crop
plants to cannabis where it could
actually help us as home growers and
commercial growers um, you know, take
advantage of the different seasons and
different temperatures and different
changes within the environments that
we're facing. um and try to use them to
our advantage based on you know
vegetative timing or um uh reduction in
electricity if you can run the AC less
at night or if you can run the heat less
at the daytime or at night or whatever
it may be situation is yeah there's
there's a lot there that I feel like
could be applied and I always am I feel
like I'm saying on this podcast a lot
that you know this is just another crop
plant, you know, it's just another
agricultural product and we should
definitely be looking at the research
that's done for other agriculture and
how it can apply to us rather than just
trying to separate cannabis out
completely because it is, you know, our
special plant. It's our special plant
indeed. It can take a little bit higher
numbers than most of the plants can
take. And that's why people I think put
it in a special because if most of
plants can take 800
PPFD our plant can go up thousands and
something if they can eat this but their
own plants in the end there seeds that
grows and they'll take care. Take for
instance tomatoes. I grow tomatoes the
same way I grow
wheat. I I plant them and then I clean I
clean the bottoms and I leave the plant
grows up. And once the plant is up, I I
just I just let it grow. So it's pretty
much the same as as we grows better. I
find out that if I let it grow all over
the place that I don't have as many good
tomatoes as I would have y and I find
myself with the problems that the same
problems that I have in here, which is
poor air flow, there is no light
penetration. there's this and that's
bringing me problems later on. But, uh,
our plant is definitely special. She she
can take some pretty damn high numbers
on everything, man. It's it's on food,
on PPFD, on I mean then the amount of
photons that this girl can take, it's
crazy. But then again,
you go outside in the sun in the middle
of the day and you take your PPFD matter
and the numbers are crazy and all the
other plants are growing still, but you
do those numbers for them plants inside
of a greenhouse and you kill them all.
Yeah.
Yeah. Nice. So, it's a unique plant in
in certain ways, but it definitely does
what other plants do. And uh yeah, we
shouldn't just try to limit ourselves to
only what applies to cannabis through a
cannabis lens. We should try to
definitely look at it as as growers
overall. Um because we can grow so many
different things with the same methods
that we use for cannabis. And we can
improve our growing of cannabis by using
the same methods we use for other plants
as well. Um so, you know, I feel like
this is a great place to start wrapping
up the show a little bit. Um, one one of
the questions that I did want to make
sure that I ask you though is, you know,
for anybody that's watching this video
on YouTube, they'll notice that dog
doctor is wearing a mask to protect his
identity.
And you know, we have a lot of listeners
in the US, but we do have listeners in
the different uh countries of Europe as
well as um I I know that I've seen
through some of the analytics we have
some viewers in Australia and South
America and in South Africa.
And you know, there's a lot of different
places in the world where cannabis is
still
um not even just regulated, but fully
illegal. and punishable by some severe
yeah severe laws and legislation.
And um you know coming from your
perspective with with all that in mind,
where would you like to see change in
the cannabis community and the cannabis
industry and um you know just kind of
that that overarching
uh group that is cannabis users,
growers, and uh people that are
involved.
I would love first of all I would love
for this plant to be discriminalized all
over the place because uh it makes no
sense that people go to jail for a
plants in my mind but
uh in its natural state it's not like
okay cocaine comes from no cocaine does
not came from a plant comes from a plant
and from a chemical thing with this that
and that and they make it this is just
something that God gives us it grows you
harvest for it's it's like a tomato it's
like anything else so for the first I
would love to see this happening all
over the world which I will believe that
it will happen eventually but it still
will take time for this to to
happen and I would like to see people to
take up the step of even if it is mask
like I am with a mask I know but people
need to be more open and need to be to
to talk with each other more about this
plant and uh demystify it. Does I don't
know if the word exists. Demystify.
Yeah. Demystified what
uh they did really good
mystifying because if you really think
about it 60 17 years ago this plant was
just a plant. Some people would smoke
it, other would not but it was not a
crime. And then with the hippie
selection and all the story that we all
know came the free vision cames this and
all the propaganda and they make it look
like most of the world right now like my
if you go and talk with the generation
of my parents and my grandma they think
of this as something really bad and
something because they painted in the
really dark. This is the getaway drug to
this. This is the start for that and
this is nothing of that. This is
something that we all have inside of us.
We have an endocanabinoid system. We
don't have a cocaine or metaphamino or
whatever system. No, this is something
bad or whatever. Everybody can do
whatever they want. But I believe it's
bad. This plant is not bad. It's here.
It can be used in a bad way. Like
everything, anything can be used in a
bad way. But this is not here to make us
bad. It's here to help us. And I would
love to see people be more open and
going online. The mask came from the GML
show. And uh I was going and covering
the camera each time I go and I think I
need to find a solution so that I can
speak more openly but still show and if
my face not coming. So I found at the
time uh sat mas mask from a dog because
my name was dog doctor and I start
wearing that and after a while I
realized that I needed something more
not so I don't know something better
looking to my mind and and I get this
which which allows me to come like with
you on a podcast for instance and be
talking and sharing my experience and I
I really think that people
should lose the scare because the most
people that do things like we do, the
more normal it becames and the the the
faster we will have this available for
everybody. I don't I by all means I
don't believe that cannabis is for
everybody. Not at
all. But I I do believe that not having
an
option, it's not a good thing. So yeah,
there's nobody died with from from from
weeds. I mean, now with the extractions
and all the abuses under foot, I'm
pretty sure that pretty soon we will
have somebody died from not directly
from the weed because you need like 5
kilos of THC or something to for your
body to
collapse. But uh the same way alcohol
you can drink and drive and have an
accident, they will blame wheat somehow
on the aspects on this. But she's not
really the problem. The problem is we
make it the problem. We should be
talking more openly about it and be more
receptive about it. And I believe that
this will happen when people not came
out of the closet. It is maybe not a
good word for it. Uh but when people
start to be open to at least understand
it and this is happening now with the
legalization happening all over the
place. You have uh people that okay
there's little children's actually
taking this there's this that if they're
giving this to a children with epilepsy
and it's actually helping this cannot be
that bad of a thing and things are
opening but I I definitely encourage if
people are not shy to a point that they
don't mind talking they should
definitely go out and uh check out the
forums because we have a huge online
community right now out and there's one
one thing that I love about this
community. It's a very open community.
Yeah. So once you start talking, people
will talk back to you. It's not it's not
like it's not like if you go for a
kitchen for instance for if you're
working in the kitchens chefs they talk
but they don't share secrets.
You know what I mean? It's it's my my
secret, my family secret. It's my p I'm
not telling you because after a while
you will open your restaurant and I will
lose my sort
of and there is of course there is in if
you work in big facilities probably
there's the secret for the facility this
and that but in general speaking we are
very open mind on sharing our knowledge
or on sharing uh our mistakes our
lessons our our learnings and this makes
this community a very special one in
terms of possibilities on of growing and
of becoming a wider thing than it is
right now. So, I definitely encourage
people to
to don't be afraid of being themselves.
I don't want them to be lying or to be
somebody else because I I think there's
too many people so for us to be
them. But this is if this is something
that you like, talk about it with your
friends, with your family. don't uh
dismify it and uh help us all to get
this plant available to who may or may
not need because by all means I I have
friends of mine that cannot smoke weed.
They get the paranoia, they get this,
they get that. And I actually think it's
the
genetics. If you get the paranoia,
there's probably some different genetic
for you that will work for your
endocanabonoid system. But again, it's
not for also this this is a different
tip. I agree. I like my mom gets anxiety
from smoking anything with a high THC
content in it. But if she has a CBD
gummy or an edible, then she's extremely
happy with the, you know, the results of
of that. And um I've I've met plenty of
other people that, you know, cannabis
just isn't for them. But, you know,
that's no reason to maintain a stigma
towards people who use cannabis. Uh just
as you wouldn't necessarily judge
someone for having a glass of wine or a
beer after you know, at the end of a day
while they're eating dinner or
something, you shouldn't uh be judging
or or retaining that stigma towards
people who are using cannabis in the
same in the same way. But like you said,
it can be abused just like anything
else. You know, food can be abused,
right? We have uh um all sorts of
different ways that people abuse things
in life. So, you know, moderation, I
guess, would be a good thing to to put
in there, but also understanding your
limitations and and using, you know, uh
a cultivar or a strain of cannabis that
works for you with the correct um
cannabonoid and tarpine profile. all
these different things they you know
they they require so much more uh
research on on the part of those who are
producing these products as well as um
understanding and research on the
consumer's end of things where they they
can try to find what works best for
them. Um, yeah, I think that that that's
a great sentiment to have that, you
know, allowing for
more access in different parts of the
world and and giving people an
opportunity to learn more about this
plant. Um yeah, you know, like that's
why the show is called The Way We Grow
because I want to make sure that people
um hear these different stories of
growers so that the community itself can
grow and become more knowledgeable and
have the ability to share that knowledge
with people and show that there are just
a lot of different,
you know, unique and and normal people
that use cannabis and that grow cannabis
and that are part of this world. Um, so
I think I think that's a great answer.
So, thank you so much. And we do just
have a couple of quick wrap-up questions
that I always like to add in. So, what's
your favorite strain of all time?
And I feel that that one has a no right
answer because I'm in a constant looking
for that run that I talked to you about.
It's something that it's still here in
my mind. So, it's definitely something
that I'm I'm looking for that unicorn
again. And maybe I find it, maybe I not.
There was something special on the the
passion fruit turppins in the in in that
plant that uh I still think about it
today. So, it's probably among my
favorites,
but I don't like to say I have a
favorite for a single reason. I like to
have different jars with different
varieties, different effects, different
flavors. And I see this as as food. If
I'm eating bread every day, I'm gonna
get nauseous of eating bread. If I'm
eating sausage, it's it's going to be
the same with that. It's so and I like
to eat in the same way I like to smoke.
So, I will need different effects. I
will need different paladars. I will
need different everything. So, variety
spice of life. Exactly. Depending on my
mood, on my day, I may need something
that it's couch locking or I may need
something that inspire me for me to grow
and work and do whatever.
So I don't have a favorite. I have I
like it's not even more sativas because
this is bro talk because but for the
general people they call it sativa or
indicate effect which is which is not
true because there's sativas super heavy
and there's indicas super super in
spirals. So I like sativas for the day
sort of speaking the the the high
lifting and for working and I like uh
the
hindicas not indicas again but the the
the couch lock for the night time and
for relaxation. Absolutely. That that's
that's a great answer. I'm, you know,
I'm also in the same mindset of it's
hard to pick one strain that's your
favorite because there's, you know,
there's I'm I'm always trying new ones
and so it's hard to say that one was my
favorite. I do, you know, look back in
the past and think of things that I
really enjoyed that I kind of reminisce
upon and wish that I had again. But I
think that that's just me uh you know,
looking through looking at the past
three rosecolored glasses. Yeah. Um so,
you know, the next question of course is
going to be probably just as difficult,
but who is your favorite breeder of all
time?
Damn.
Damn. That's a hard one. I mean, I like
uh I like humbled the humble seed
companies, they have a real, but this is
because they look for turppins more than
they look for poty in their genetics.
So, every seed that I pop from them, it
was always almost like a keeper. I
cannot keep them, but uh they're all
good. Cool. So, if I have to go for one,
I actually would go for that one because
it was the one from the the the
everything that I tried from them. I
never had a bad uh a bad seed in there.
All of the rest, most of them, I didn't
like this or I didn't like that or
something. There's always something
happening there. And they were the more
stable ones. in autoflower. I I have to
go to fast buds. Honestly, they are by
far but by far the best autoflowers I
grew and I tried a bunch of different
seed banks and I'm not supposeding for
them or anything. I'm this is just my
personal
opinion and they are very therapy
plants. They're doing something there.
The breeding they're doing it's it's
they're doing and they are very stable.
you grow like the blackberry. It's one
of my favorites from them. It's very
peculiar one. It's it's almost like a
syrup mixed with fruits, but at the same
time has like this backstage of a on it.
I cannot really explain. It's really
unique. And each time I grow, the plant
grows exactly the same. So, I have a
feeling that if I grew 100 of them in a
room, there will be like three or four
that would be different, which is
normal. And
um others don't do that. I grow now I
grow a banana in six months. I grow the
banana but it's taking like tangerine.
It's no longer the banana. Yeah. And
fast buds in in that terms they are they
are really amazing. Cut to that for
sure. I I don't grow a lot of
autoflowers but I have grown fast buds
before
and they weren't bad. Um I just I never
liked auto flowers personally because if
I find something that's really good it
it's just so hard to find it again.
Yeah. And you can't keep it around. Um
but you know if if you find a company or
a breeder that is
doing you know good work and and
creating stable genetics where you can
at least you know sift through maybe a
few different phenotypes for your your
setting. Um then you know maybe it is
worth it for whatever it is that you
might need it for. out of flowers. If
you're running for instance a perpetual
and you have
always 24 or 18 hours place to place
lights, why not put another flower there
and you have a harvest in between. Sure.
Before they didn't have the turpps. Now
they are getting the turppies. They they
getting good. So then it's in a taste.
But this not being able to keep a clone.
It's one of the things that in the
beginning on the other flowers was crazy
because I always clone and now I cannot
clone. Okay. So, I like this and the
next season will not be this. That's
that's a unicorn. I feel you on that one
completely. True unicorn cuz you can't
find it again. Yeah. Um All right. Well,
last question. What's your most
memorable cannabis related experience?
you when you mean most memorable is the
one that when I think about something
that happens that that memory comes it
was the one of the first times I ever
smoke super skunk okay it was not even
skunk was super skunk and it was the
first time I realized in my life I was
about 17 maybe I don't know the age but
it
was around there and it was the I smoke
it and other weeds and other things that
I would smoke. You finished the the
joints and you would feel it. And I
smoke and I didn't feel nothing. Oh,
[__] I made another one. Nothing. I
grabbed the rest of it and I make the
big fat one. And about half an hour
after that last one, I found
myself tripping like on acid, man. But
but really on acid. And at the times, I
would from time to time take some acid.
And I I really it's it's people would
come, are you okay, dog? Dog, are you
okay? No, no, man. I'm okay. I'm okay.
But just leave me here. And this was the
most intensive and it was the first time
ever that I realize that this is a
sacred plant. This is not here for us to
it is here for us to play and for us to
please us, but it's also here to teach
us and to it's a serious plant. It's
it's and this was when I real and in
from that moment on I believe that was
when I start respecting the plant as a
plant as a being has being part of us.
Until then it was just something for
fun. It was just there. It was
recreational. It was this. And from that
point on I realized it's not just that
because it can take me places. It can
make me see things. It can make me
realize things.
So, it's got to be sacred.
Are you sure? No, I mean that's a that's
a pretty powerful experience to have
where you know the sort of those um time
delayed responses that some strains can
have and then if you do end up over
consuming you can have a very profound
experience that is going to leave a
lasting impression. So, I can totally
understand how that kind of changed your
perspective of the plant at the time.
That's really cool.
Yeah. Well, this has been an awesome
conversation, Dog Doctor. I really
appreciate you joining me on the podcast
today and telling more of your story so
that more people can get out there uh
and grow their own plants or, you know,
participate in this community in their
own way. Um, but you know, telling
stories like yours where you are still
in a state or a state, a country that is
uh prohibitive on the use as well as the
growing of this plant. And being able to
come on here and tell your story is
extremely uh it's brave, but also so
necessary for us to be able to continue
to grow this community. And um like I
always say, that's the way we grow. So
again, thank you so much. I really
appreciate it. No, I'm the one that
appreciate love you having me here and
everybody. And if you in Europe, uh, let
me just bring up. I don't know when this
will go on air, but I'm doing a mini
cup. So if
you just want to grow some European
seeds, I will be sending some nutrients
and some seeds and some groove bags to
give everybody the same chance. I want
to be I want to to to make this not the
traditional cup where you find the final
product is what it matters for me. This
will be the journey the the evaluation
will be on the journey because I'm
giving everybody the same chance the
same genetics the same nutrients and the
same curing. So the whole journey is
where I'm going to evaluate sort of
speaking people and um I don't know if
I'm going to have 10 entries of 100
entries but I feel that this is
something that uh if you in the
prohibition lands we'll be sending them
everywhere of course at at your own
risk. Please be be whatever you are be
safe but um it would be an honor and a
pleasure to to have anybody that wants
to join us on on this journey. Yeah.
Well, anybody that's interested in that,
reach out to Dog Doctor Official on
Instagram and uh learn more from him and
and we'll have uh maybe some of the
viewers and the different people that
have been on the show join you for that
uh for that grow challenge. It would be
awesome. Thank you. Cool. Well, awesome.
Thank you again, Doc Doctor. And we will
talk soon.
Thank you. Growers love everybody. Thank
you for having me. Seriously. Growers
love for sure. Groers love.
[Music]