hello and welcome to another episode of
The Way We Grow podcast I am your host
Nick wolf my co-hosts today are Gabby
Staten Island and Cosmic Our Guest today
is Jesse with Mothership Labs where they
specialize in tissue culture breeding
compliant Sops and training their
mission is to support the Cannabis
industry through science technology
while still aiming to preserve the
culture and genetics that started it all
uh so Jesse welcome to the show how are
you doing
today I doing great thank you for having
me on today this is uh checking out the
show it's excited about what you guys
are doing and uh glad to be a part of it
for sure well we were uh talking a
little bit before the show and you were
kind of explaining a few of the
different things that you have going on
currently so you know I think one of the
first thing our viewers are going to
notice and uh to any of the listeners
out there check us out on YouTube but uh
you have a huge amount of plants sitting
behind you so why don't you talk a
little bit about um like what what
you're doing today and what's uh new in
your grow world yeah so I'm uh down in
Florida right now um working with the
company they do a lot of ornamentals and
all kinds of different plants so this is
their TC lab they produce a crazy amount
um and what we're trying to do is help
you know build a system to where you
could benefit breeders
cultivators have stock of just
disease-free plants um and kind of build
a new model essentially so hope we'll be
able to tell you more about that as it
develops but um a lot of good people
fantastic Growers um and kind of
shifting into being able to help
preserve and provide at a a much larger
scale so uh definitely been traveling a
lot I was just in Michigan too and uh
thankfully I'm in Florida so I'm humid
again but um yeah it's pretty cool to
see like so many so many plants and the
management and everything the operations
behind it it is a ton of tissue culture
here so for sure it definitely looks
like it and I think you were saying that
this facility alone produces over 5
million unique xplants per
year I I believe so and they do I mean
have like 200 Acres huge
facilities um a lot of different plants
nursery and that's kind of what I see
you know in the future that at least in
some areas um starting with genetic
stock and professional breeding um kind
of evolving into that area so yeah lots
of lots of plants here um so it's
exciting to see things at a a large
scale and what it what it could be um
big part of our goal is like how does
that apply to the industry and um how
can we kind of shape that so it benefits
Growers and breeders that that kind of
started this and have been you know
doing this for a long time you
know yeah I feel like that's really
important it seems like there are a lot
of breeders um from yester year uh to
use a term that still don't have access
to tissue culture or different lab
testings that would help them make
either more educated breeding um
practices or decisions as well as also
just being able to preserve a bunch more
genetics at a lower cost considering um
costs aren't going down when it comes to
overhead in the Cannabis industry uh
where tissue culture though as an
investment could definitely lower your
overhead when it comes to even even just
something as simple as maintaining a
large stock
population absolutely yep uh and why we
came out as tissue culture and try to at
least educate and help support that side
is
um i' I've been growing in around
cannabis since I was like 10 years old I
think growing up in
Kentucky I started there and then went
to commercial operations and then to
biotech and then back to cannabis so I
had had that mentality like I I'm not
sending my breeding lines to somebody
else in a lab you know sure um so that's
kind of how it started is like teach
people how to do it and make it easier
better more affordable um and then we
can start trading and do a lot more
business that way like I can send stuff
to your lab we can you know trade
phenotypes for breeding and and compound
that kind of success um absolutely
collaboration for the win collaboration
man yeah yeah so front facing it's
tissue culture that we see huge need in
the market for that we do a lot of uh
you know molecular breeding and
operation stuff and um just trying to
support where we saw the needs um for
cultivators in the market you know and
just build off that you know for sure um
well you know you kind of already
touched on it a little bit but let's
take it back a little bit and talk about
your first experience with growing
plants in general what got you into
wanting to pursue a career or a life
path in Plants um I mean it sounded like
you did cannabis pretty darn early but
where was there anything that kind of
piqu your interests earlier than
that uh I feel it's always somebody's
older brother you
know that uh makes the introduction I
think that's what it was and just being
young I was like this seems cool and uh
being a part of that group know and I
wasn't like smoking a bunch of weed that
that young I I tried it that just being
around the plants is what interested me
so um Kentucky there the culture there
for cannabis has been going on for a
long time I mean there's people in the
mountains that have been just
generations of Growers there like that's
that's what they do that's what they
have been doing um so it's definitely
been around for a long time there and as
I got older I think I was looking more
in the scientific side of things that I
wanted to I was just did like how does
the world work and how does this plant
work um at the time it was like a cool
plant that I could attach science to you
know in school it's like corn and wheat
I was like I don't care about corn and
wheat other than eating it um so I think
that's what did I was like this is I
could be cool and learn science behind
weed I got started it out um you know
growing up as I got older my father
ended up getting neurological disease
and things like that at the same time
that you started getting indications
that cannabis can help you know
Alzheimer's and all these other Theses
so that stuck with me early on and where
I wanted to continue pursuing the uh the
plant and the research side so um a lot
of stuff in between there you know
getting older and and going through you
know high school and everything else but
um then friends started getting cancer
or disease that it could potentially
help help cure or alleviate you know so
um outside of you know growing around
the country and doing you know doing
everything on tour we'll say um I was
like I have to learn how to grow it I
have to learn how to manage operations I
have to learn how to breed and then
after learn the science and that's kind
of where I started so I started learning
how to grow from um you know older
brothers and everyone else uh in those
communities um and then moved out to
Colorado that's where I wanted to you
know be like okay this is a professional
environment now um and started there as
a trimmer actually how old were you when
you moved out to
Colorado uh do seen that long ago it was
2014 so I think I was like
28 I want to say
wow that's crazy to think about um and
at the time because I was I was like you
know hustling doing everything else and
just being in that that side of the
industry to get an apartment I had to
get a job and show everything on paper
and I was like oh man so I I moved here
and was delivering pizzas uh to start
out and I was like whatever it takes um
so I was highly motivated like I got to
make change in my life to to pursue this
stuff right um a lot of good people in
my life supported me down that road and
so deliver you know going from that
world to you know dropping a a large
pepperoni off for like a $2 tip was just
crazy I like whatever I'll do it then um
like I'll take it man like this is what
we got to do so uh how long had you been
growing before you moved to
Colorado you know when it starting 10
you know I did grow here and there and
play around with it um I think getting
serious with it I was closer to 16 17
where I was like I'm going to grow weed
um and there's lot of different ways out
there by then indoor you know was taken
off we were just used to outdoor uh
Kentucky soil is
incredible um so it's really easy to
grow like You' flick a seed out there
and come back and there's just some
amazing weed um
but getting the indoor game we had you
know HPS lights and all that um took it
was like a different learning curve
right like nutrients and all these other
factors that I was like you can't just
throw it out there and it grows so
started getting on forums and learning
from uh other Growers that I knew and um
so yeah I've been growing for a long
time bunch of different methods you know
we had some Hydro guys in town they're
like that's awesome weed I like this one
so huge Community out there um that I
got to get experience in genetics and um
start breeding early on and and learn
some of those things before research and
a lot of the science behind it started
coming out too so um well talk a little
bit about some of those early growing
experiences and kind of where where you
found success and where you might have
had some uh trepidations that might have
led you away from a specific styal into
another
one yeah so Kentucky high humidity right
uh very high that end of the season um I
remember one it was those think is
Alaskan Thunder we had like under a
highway like we just let him go that one
lasted into December just no problem at
all so it was like the easy way of
growing that like I
knew um and I love outdoor the Kentucky
soil grown too was just phenomenal uh we
had some stuff up in the hills there
that was like Perfect all year round and
I got into the um indoor stuff and
that's where I was like I don't know if
I like this at all just way too much
management and measuring nut you know
chemical fertilizers and all that stuff
just produce a different product I was
unfamiliar with so I didn't know how to
do it that you know starting out um but
really when I started talking to like
older Growers that had been doing it a
long time and learned that I could grow
some like really really good weed just
follow what they're doing uh that's when
I started enjoying it a lot more you
know because you're growing bad weed
it's just it's not fun so yeah getting
over that hump I guess um and there's
you know few different people there wer
hu huge grows um I was growing up around
Lexington so you have outskirts of town
and some of those areas that were um
easy to set up you know some basement or
and then we had Farmland away from the
city that we could go out to um grow a
lot more so I think the genetics there
was the most exciting part at least
looking back um a lot of old school
stuff I haven't seen in forever but the
stuff the the uh generational Farmers
had didn't really have names for it was
the best um you're thinking selecting
over years and years of this they you
know some of these have resistances to
that high humidity you know buritis and
stuff like that um that grow just
incredibly well in those
areas and that's how they fed their
families you know and that's how I was
taught like this is part of our family's
Heritage and how we're going to survive
um so that was kind of beating into my
head early on it's like just don't mess
with people's genetics don't mess with
them
you know everybody had their their main
cash crop that was you know a Northern
Lights cross over here or and product
was just traded like I want some of that
I'll give you some of my Northern Lights
and you know afghanis came in um and
then hybrids and I think that's what got
me on breeding and um trying to learn
more about it because it's hard to
identify new genetics when you didn't
know that world existed like everything
is weed uh at some point and then
somebody brings you something special
like what is this like where did it come
from yeah um when you first found that
super special weed since you were kind
of already plugged into the growing
community in the area did you
immediately kind of go oh man how are
they growing it I want to learn how to
do that uh because this stuff is the
best and what was what were some of
those uh like methods that you saw that
people were doing that in your opinion
produced the best bud when you were
first finding some of that stuff that
you thought were you know levels above
the other
stuff um it was this soil grown um at
the time it wasn't like all these inputs
and knowledge behind what they do is
like those little tricks that these old
guys had they're like yeah just let it
sit there for a while um I think the one
method that was actually discussed see
remember subcool mixing in the uh the uh
little mini pools and stuff cook your
own soil started doing some of those
recipes and modifications to it and
that's why I was like oh man this is
like crazy weed um before you see a lot
of that like called Flat weed back then
like it's green tastes phenomenal
everyone loves it but in comparison like
it's is flatweed like gets the job done
um and you had these new mixes coming
out from you know some of these known
breeders and and people started catching
on I was like what is this it doesn't
even look like weed to me The Taste the
just everything uh was just incredible
so I think that's when the organic like
it was all organic at that point um the
weed that I was smoking and getting
older brothers and their friends
bringing stuff in from C it was like
this is insane but I kind of gravitated
towards um just those organic mixes and
um how they're keeping that soil alive
and they didn't know the microbial thing
Le everything behind it they're
fallowing a recipe too you know um so
learning that way was it was awesome was
familiar to me from growing outdoor I'm
like yes nature takes care of most of
that right um so it's definitely stuck
with me nowadays I want to go back and
grow more outdoor but I just got to I'm
grow throwing them in in tubes and stuff
right now so yeah so so then like yeah
what what translated you out of um where
you were focused on growing and then you
said I want to actually go more into
biotechnologies and find out more it
sounded like you were really interested
in how these plants were growing and
what was causing them to do their
different things and and and processes
so what kind of LED you into that
path uh it started because I just I was
growing just some flat weed right I was
like I got to make my weed
better uh so you know you start reading
and get into soil science and then uh
down that radit hole was I would say the
first step and then my weed started
competing they're like man this is
really good I was like science is
science is the way right and just kept
reinforcing those uh those pieces for me
and like my my dad was a researcher too
so we were um I had this scientific mind
from what I was told
and um I was in that that world of
research right I sure beat other
researchers when I was little and so I
had a lot of that kind of pushing me in
that direction too and I think weed
being you know in my life at the time
like I I could attach it to that like
I'm cool because I grow weed but I also
love science you know it was I think it
was important to me when I was in that
early stages of my life too um
acceptance and all the things humans go
through right right um and just continue
to follow it you know just figuring out
how things
work it sort of adds a legitimacy to
something that was seen as something so
um Infamous uh in terms of what a what a
career path could take if you wanted to
follow something where you were growing
cannabis but then you started to talk
about it in this very uh
more higher education scientific uh
terminologies some people would take you
a little bit more serious and you're not
the first person that I've heard say
that yeah that that's it and the I think
the communication it brought to you
where like you're equal right it's like
this guy grows the best weed but I know
some of these things and it starts
bridging that
communication and building those
relationships I guess um so give a
different perspective to where like I
can do all these things that still cool
and you know Associated and accepted I
guess um and we meet you know every once
in a while and share our experiences and
our weed and um learn more things and
start learning together you know as a
community so definitely a big influence
just learning so I come back and be like
check this out like look what I found
out how to do or uh and and started
becoming a lot more fun when I the more
I knew the more fun I had meeting up
with some of my friends and stuff so
definitely a huge
influence and if I if I did my math
correctly you said you've been doing
tissue culture for 12 years but you
moved out to pursue cannabis cultivation
in Colorado in 2014 so you were already
dabbling in tissue culture before you
moved out to Colorado is that
correct yeah so I did uh started with
mushrooms much like a lot of a lot of
other guys right um that was fun as well
and I wasn't doing like tissue culture
every day or going you know hard down
that rabbit hole um I came out because I
was still learning about weed I was like
I figure out how to grow this at a
commercial scale um so it kind of on the
back burner for a little while and
reintroduced um by somebody else that
just passing more knowledge you know and
uh motivating me to start learning more
about that just another Avenue that we
could develop tools with um learning
like first when I started getting into
it I was like this is just unfamiliar
it's very different from U mushroom work
you know and but I was pointed in the
right direction so I could start
building the knowledge base and playing
around I had my own equipment I've had
for a long time and starting to get into
the Cannabis side it was very difficult
like this is not working at
all but is getting used to the tools and
figuring out um what's possible and
knowing that some of these things exist
in in the world of science and
cultivation uh maybe a better grower and
more motivated to learn I
guess but yeah it's been definitely been
around a long
time for sure I mean I I know that uh in
general in agriculture it's been used
for different fruiting trees and stuff
since around the 70s in high production
but was even dabbled in in the 30s and
40s um so it's got a long history almost
almost a century of use within
agriculture which is super impressive
for something that is still almost uh
viewed as The Cutting Edge of new
technology um in a in a blossoming
market like the Cannabis industry um oh
yeah yeah it's for hard to propagate
species right I think so with orchids
and um yeah you know coming out and
everyone's like have you heard of tissue
culture it's been around for a long time
it it's hasn't been perfected I feel for
cannabis specifically and the
applications and um long-term storage
and all the other other stuff you can do
with tissue culture so that's I think
part of the reason for that is that
cannabis is not a difficult to propagate
plant and if it was if it was difficult
to propagate then we probably would have
gone to tissue culture much sooner but
because it's pretty easy to take clones
you know we uh we haven't done that I
have a quick question and a comment for
you first the question is are you
familiar with the grow Stores um new
Earth in Kentucky they were in New Earth
they were in mexic now they're in
Louisville
yeah yeah okay yeah so there's some they
go ahead I think so yeah yeah so they
had grow stores in the80s during green
Merchant and they still have one today
in
Louisville and um we're actually
interviewing them tomorrow on the your
weed stories oh that's so I was
wondering if you knew those guys we
might know some of the same people so
these they kind of like grow the hydro
shops and stuff there obviously that's
where people went to get like Fox Farm
and right you know all the supplies but
some of them and I haven't kept up with
I know some of them kind of Chang names
or locations because it was starting to
uh you know get watched a little more
and like all right what what's going on
here and I know one of them moved to
Louisville so I'm wondering if about
that same crew yeah man now they're
called one CRA
yeah that would be crazy yeah we're
interviewing them tomorrow and the the
comment that I wanted to make is is that
most people don't realize that
Kentucky and um Florida were hot beds
for growing Canabis you know people
people when they think about cannabis
they think about California and but you
know um yesterday I think Nick and I or
me and someone else were talking about
the Gainesville green famous weed from
Florida and you know so much cannabis
was grown in Kentucky as well um it was
number one export I think yeah for a
while oh and you know the the weed I was
used to and California had great weed
too but like some of these Kentucky boys
are crazy like how how good some of that
flower is man you it's
unbelievable um I could imag yeah
definitely they it's been around a long
time and there's places out there like
you you just don't go you know you don't
want to go out there at all um that's
and that's kind of how I grew up like
just for respecting the plant and the
people like don't mess with it you know
let them do their thing let them keep
their genetics and everything school
because it was a way of light like
they're feeding families and um trade
and all that for long long time um I
think I was lucky to get brought up in
that that side of the community too just
to teach me respect for for all these
things so yeah andan high quality weed
has grown in Kentucky for
sure nice yeah tell us tell us some of
the exciting things in your in your grow
world right right now about tissue
culture like what's what have you been
developing what have you been working on
where have you found some successes and
some some failures that uh might be able
to help teach the community that's
looking into either starting a small
home tissue culture lab or even
commercial cultivators that may be
listening or watching this that are
looking into potentially uh sourcing uh
good tissue culture um what are some of
these different things that you feel
like uh you could shed a little bit more
light
on oh there's a lot there's a lot there
um so tissue culture is a extremely
powerful tool
right if used properly um the main
pieces of that that I hear or discussed
about right now is like genetic storage
uh pathogen remediation right
uh micro
propagation so what what I set out to do
was I you know I've run all the you know
Ms media dkw everything in between and
um I can you explain what dkw is and
what Ms media are for those that don't
oh y yep so um migi and skoo uh that is
basically these names are are the
scientists who created them for the most
part right um they discovered that they
have all the the components to sustain
plant life in vitro in vitro meaning I
think it's Italian in glass uh so
sustaining life in glass um essentially
so all the what that means is there's a
uh you have your nutrients hormones
vitamins just all these things that your
cells and tissue needs to survive and
and grow right in combination with light
and your your environment temperatures
uh so if you look at the different forms
of that dkw just another form is driver
kuaki uh Walnut
media um there's specific ones that are
formulated for tobacco and different
plants across the board uh that
scientists work on and develop and
validate like this is for best for this
plant right um so starting out you know
the a lot of the Woody culture media and
protocols and everything was just used
for cannabis
um dkw seems to work better S of growth
but it's it's made for
walnuts um so if you think of it in that
that lens we're giving the wrong I was
like we're giving the wrong food to
these cannabis plants right they want
completely different profile of uh
nutrients and vitamins and everything
else um and that's what I was used to
using it was like Ms dkw and some
modifications so when I started getting
into to it um we actually started doing
research at a research
laboratory uh molecular
genetics uh we installed tissue culture
lab we had gcms hplc so we could look at
all the turpins and just everything for
breeding um I might have been one of the
first out in Colorado that we had whole
laboratory set up Grow rooms on rotation
planting seed and we were trying to
identify uh qtl work so quantitative
trait Loi so basically like where these
genes are and what are they responsible
for the example I use like The Color
Purple it's like okay where do these
jeans that are responsible for the color
purple
live um when we identify them we can
test for them pop a bunch of seed this
big and tell you if it's going to be
purple or not it's like kind of the
short version of that which we can get
more into that too um in order to do
that we had to sustain life and use
tissue culture and develop these things
so there's kind of the background there
but starting with those available media
um and public research and everything we
could gather um it starts at Woody
culture protocols and everything else
right so you quickly see like all right
we could get these to live we get them
to root and but they're just not healthy
they're not healthy enough to manipulate
and that's what I try to teach is it's
not like
micropropagation it's you want to learn
how to manipulate this tissue within
this environment and setup so I think
the exciting things that I've been
working on just this past year is
fine-tuning what that is like the exact
uh components to tissue culture media
for cannabis and hemp um the exact
hormones and you know just the entire
Pro program to support that so went I
think this the entire year 12-hour days
just going through it um that's been the
most exciting for me as far as you know
what we we developed and what we're
working on now uh because it makes such
a huge difference like perfect health
all the way through rooting no problem
subcultures zero loss uh in health
throughout the problem process because
we want to get sustainable storage right
we're just taking clone the different
genetics if it was seed that'd be
different right that's um the best way
to sore genetics I say but since we want
to hold on to all these clones um we
want to start there first because we're
breeders we're cultivators everything
else so we want it to sort long term
without mutations or loss of uh the
Fidelity of the genetics themselves
adding on other
stress factors that cause epigenetic
changes uh and things long term that
could affect how these genes are
expressing um a lot of people say
genetic drift and which don't get me
started on
that but uh that's for a that's for a
population group it's not for a single
plant ah so happy to hear you say that
y this wolf guy is pretty smart yeah oh
no we started talking was like all right
I'll be on your podcast sir it's
great but you look at all the the issues
right you're cloning off mother so we
want to develop the tools that actually
work right um I've been doing that with
MS and dkw media and everything else for
a while which like it's just hard to use
they're not healthy you can see
deficiencies in the plant you can see
things are just harder to root when you
pull them out
what were some of the major changes that
you made from using Ms or dkw media to
your current setup I feel like that's
going to be something that a lot of
people uh should hear because I have a
feeling I might know a couple of them
but from someone that has as much
experience as you I feel like it would
be really good to hear that sure yeah I
hate to say it but there more cow mag
man it start was start there oh man yeah
after all this time I was like are you
kidding me is it calcium nitrate so that
you're also increasing the nitrogen
load uh so lowering the amount of
ammonia nitrate right so that definitely
contributes a ton to hyper hydrosity
meaning you know you get that
translucent look and they they kind of
shrivel um so yeah there's there's a lot
of factors there right um so you start
at ammonia nitrate so you definitely
lower that like immediately available
nitrogen that they can they can use
quickly also as way too much ammonia
right um so the other one is Cal Mag
calcium magnesium need to be raised up
um I just started using calcium nitrate
so uh what else man there's a lot yeah
there's some things that you I just
stripped out
altogether um one of them I think cobalt
chloride dkw has nickel don't need
nickel has way too much sulfur it's got
the balance
sulfur um and then if you look at the
how nutrients are absorbed by the tissue
right it's through diffusion so if you
can manipulate the density of your agar
you can start controlling how much of
that those nutrients it's it's getting
or the the rate of that absorption right
um so all those components together are
made a huge difference but then you look
at the vitamin complex right um lot of
people there's gamborg B5 V
vitamins
um thomine hydrochloride in that there's
way way way too much because all these
things if they're not Balan it's going
to change how these nutrients are
absorbed by the plant it's going to
change how the sugar is process so
specifically thomine hydrochloride it
will um kind of catalyze how that's
processed and and pulled in um and if
anything's out of balance it's just like
um just picture of deficiency right all
this has to be be kind of balanced and
and done uh and then proper uh
ventilation for your vessels is is huge
for
cannabis um so you know dkw does a great
job at least I use Ms sometimes if I'm
out of my my mix um it has a lot higher
nitrogen con content so if you're doing
a marim dissection you can start getting
that process moving a little quicker I
found um than
dkw and get getting into more tissue and
growth dkw seems to to work better the
vitamins had a huge impact though uh
more than I'd expect them to do I guess
um so if you look at there's I guess a
reference called L's Barrel or Le's law
of the minimum right missing one of
those planks yeah yeah um and I can send
links or pictures whatever to help share
with your viewers too but it's the same
kind of concept and then there's molders
nutrient interactions right all that
stuff applies in vitro it's still a
plant it still needs this balanced uh
nutrition and um we're just promoting it
with hormones and supplementing sugars
uh because it can't photosynthesis size
and everything else right so if you kind
of break it down like that it's like
cannabis wants cannabis food tons of
references we can look at like you know
all the nutrients that we use to just
grow weed with right so if you start
there with that balance you can build
and make something effective um the
there's other amino acids and some
things that I started working with that
are helping to control that that rate
and make it more bioavailable and and
process that we found extremely
effective um and I think that's what
started
making um cutting time off of growth
like we can get rapid crazy growth uh
from some of these final
formulas but in order to understand that
and compare we run every single trial
you know public research every formula
that's available just to understand and
start manipulating those those factors
right um
deionized water huge or Ro I know some
people use coconut water and um all that
is going to relate to absorption of
these nutrients and being able to speed
up slow down and control that metabolism
right the light intensity the light
spectrum everything so every time I
discuss tissue culture people are like
give me the
formula that's not it I can give you the
formula and you can just fail miserably
still right you have to have the
internal components and the external and
the techniques and um that's what makes
it successful well that's what that's
what a formula is right it's not just
one little thing it's the entire thing
that you know you have to put it
together correctly I have a question
based on something that you just said
about light and so first you said that
these plants can't
photosynthesize and but then you said
said that um the light is important and
this is something that Nick and I were
discussing and also um you know I have a
little hobby tissue culture lab you know
with a friend of mine and he was telling
me so my friend was saying that we don't
need very much light and you know Nick
said that you know in his research that
you need like 150 to 200 of ppfd and I'm
looking at your jars over there and
they're stacked one on top of it another
with what appears to be fairly low light
so if you could answer the question
about like what are the light
requirements generally I know it's you
know absolutely yeah well picture of
being able to control all this right so
you're looking at um and there's it's a
two-part kind of trick question right
the photos photosynthesis part so I I'll
start there photosynthesis they're
creating uh sugars essentially energy to
grow the plant um we supplement sugars
to help you know provide and boost that
especially at the cellular level they're
not going to be making their own a lot
of species they will stop
photosynthesizing and their um stomatos
kind of get stuck flows and they just
you become in stasis right if you have
the ventilated caps and you know CO2
still present that's something I haven't
measured you know I need I would love to
and you know do a some deeper research
on that but that's kind of like textbook
they slow and then stop
photosynthesizing is it true I
mean I'm gonna look into it we'll see
hope we get some answers right but from
from what I've heard it's uh it they do
stop photosynthesizing but they don't
stop their Risco cycle but they just
supplement the photosynthates that they
would produce through photosynthesis
uh with the provided carbohydrate load
within the media so they no longer need
to provide their own carbohydrates to
still continue this rabisco cycle of
nutrient processing and continuing to
build cellular uh growth and cellular
multiplication absolutely yep so we
looking at developing sugarless media
right and so think about that the hybrid
systems we need CO2 you need
kind of these like traditional things
plants you know how we grow plants um
that' be huge just way less
contamination or issues and you know
sterile work and stuff like that um but
I think getting down to measuring it and
being like okay this is true at maybe at
these points and what does that kind of
process or curve look like right just to
get a deeper understanding so you get
into light intensity um these uh if
you're able to like slow that metabolism
and process down right cooler
temperatures lower intensity and you're
just slowing all that process maybe
higher density media so slowing that
diffusion process as well um and these
are all different species behind me here
um when you get it scale you don't want
everything just growing rapidly you know
you need to control that production
cycle um and you can use a combination
of these things to to slip you know make
that that happened um for cannabis I
think I had one in vro the same vessel
for about a year and you know pulled it
out and it was just fine but it's it
didn't have a vented cap it had really
dense um agar and higher concentration
of the of uh nutrients in there so it
could last you know it's just kind of
slowly pulling that up that gets you an
idea how you can manipulate and CH some
of these factors but my main production
uh rack will say it's like 50 micr moles
per square meter that's it so that's
that's very
low very it's low right it's but
Spectrum so it's almost Balan
Spectrum um of veg and flowering right
blue and red that's almost even on there
so and I've done you know veg lights or
you know that heavier blue spum and you
can get a little more stretchier you
know elongated growth but I get to the
rooting phase and it just I wasn't
seeing the results that I wanted so um
keeping under the Spectrum and that
intensity I think the highest all goes
up to 80 micr moles per square meter um
you're not stressing the the plants out
you don't want to force them to grow
using higher light and hormone
specifically you want to be very
judicious using your hormones to promote
that type of growth uh so finding that
zone where you're not just like forcing
all that on there you know control
within a margin that's when you start
seeing health and and it gets easier
because the plants will they'll react
faster their tissue is just healthier
they root faster everything else um and
I've done it under I think 100 uh 100
micromoles per square meter different
lights that I had at the time we saw
excellent
growth but it's just not nearly the same
as you know what I've developed now um
because you can
get more stress that you're adding on to
the you know on the epigenetic level and
things that we're we're setting up to
start digging through that could affect
the genetics because in the end we want
you know the same or even better coming
out than what what's going in uh to the
tissue filter process right right and a
lot of people don't understand like how
these things can accumulate and change
uh epigenetic stressors and methylation
can be passed on to the next Generation
too could you uh briefly describe what
methylation is I I haven't uh heard that
term used before as it pertains to like
the degradation of genetics or or um
changes in the tics yeah yeah that's a I
guess an easier example there's
different forms of this that can happen
so
um your DNA is not going to change but
through stress and and this happens in
humans as well which is just terrifying
um you can accumulate these methyl
groups um I won't go too much into
histone protein stuff but it starts
limiting its ability to transcribe right
or its ability to
express so over time uh and again it's
heritable to the Next Generation uh over
time you can you know accumulate these
things like again it doesn't change your
DNA but it starts limiting those genes
to uh ability to express right so when
people discuss like man this plant just
isn't the same or it's you know dutting
out or whatever it's like you've been
cloning off this for 20 years you know
this thing is just stressed out and uh
it's not happy right um so that's one
form of this and you can look in you
know going deeper there's specific
locations that this can happen on um
that starts binding it in onto histone
proteins right that's where all this
stuff is W like uh wrapped up so where
it can fit into the
chromosome um otherwise it would just be
stretched out crazy L um but more of
those that happen picture like a magnet
it's just binding that to the sights and
it starts restricting its ability to
transcribe and therefore expressing I
explain
that I think I understand that it's kind
of like a um they're almost like uh
suppressors of expression where uh as
they accumulate over time you can lose
more and more of the genetic expression
that may have made that uh specific cult
ofar desirable initially um and and one
of the examples that I feel like is very
fascinating within this uh discussion as
well is I've even heard people have a
specific cut and they just loved how it
was performing and they're like I just
want to get this onto culture so that I
can preserve it for the long run they
get it into culture they've been assured
that it's uh safe and backed up so they
kill off their mother populations they
then get this tissue culture back and it
has all the coas to ensure that it there
was no mishandling where it could have
been
accidentally exchanged with another
genetic but they get this genetic back
so it's for sure what they gave them and
all of a sudden it is completely
different undesirable and not what they
wanted to grow anymore and it's because
these these different
um uh sort of genetic Inhibitors that
build up over time can actually create a
more desirable product when it comes to
the Cannabis that we like to smoke and
consume as well as you know maybe
there's a picturesque quality to it
where something removes the ability for
the bra to structure in a certain way so
that but the triome density Remains the
Same so all of a sudden it's just this
more Frosty um uh resin dense flower
that then when removed the flower
structure becomes larger which
technically is a healthier plant because
it can support greater uh embryo life
for more seeds because that's the entire
purpose of the plant in in the in nature
is to produce seeds so that it can
preserve its genetic lineage um so I've
heard this you know be viewed as oh man
it it's ruined this cultivar that I love
versus almost now we have to say listen
we want to get the cultivar that we love
on tissue culture as soon as possible
because we will be able to go back to
that same
expression time and time again without
viral loads pathogen loads other sort of
genetic stressors that sort of are
sitting there like you said and they
attach themselves to the plant's genetic
structure over time where it it's only
then removed through either like a
meristematic tissue culture where you're
removing it from the vascular structure
and all these different things
um I find that really fascinating that
that you brought that up thank you yeah
if you think about oh do you have a
question Gab oh what I was going to say
is is you know this is something that
has been experienced with I think most
pronounced is with the sour diesel and
so oh yes the sour diesel I have a clone
that me and my friends have had for
decades but it's just not the same you
know it's gone through those epigenetic
changes and you know
like it's just it's it's what it is you
know I think in another podcast what we
talk about is you know if you have a
clone of let's say wolf for
example and one clone one of the Clone
you have two clones right and one of
them eats a healthy diet every day and
then the other one eats Burger King and
Taco Bell by the time that they're you
know 30 years down the line they're
going to be significantly different and
then if we take the clone of the Taco
Bell wolf you know it's not going to be
the same as the clone of the wolf that
ate a healthy diet all of his life so
absolutely so the lessons are number one
always eat a healthy D diet stay away
from Taco Bell eat some eat some fruit
but also like yeah like Nick said is we
want to tissue culture these genetics
early on you know and if we would have
tissue culture the sour you know 10 or
20 years ago we wouldn't have this
problem that we do now
so that's and you know I hear using
tissue culture specifically marim
culture right it resets the genetics
just like it was from seed again and
that's that's not true right um it does
a lot of these Health you know benefits
Reviving getting rid of all of these
pathogens and everything else even
without going make you young again it's
not going to make I'm working on it
trust me yeah and it's not going to take
away all the bad things that she
did right but it could or I think it
could right so a lot of this has to
do um so just a if you go down really
really small or let's say Maris
dissection right the majority of these
issues you have endites you know fungus
bacteria that you have no idea are even
in there right over accumulating even
viruses that people just don't test for
right that's a huge factor that could
limit Vigor yield performance all those
things we can get rid of all of that and
that's the mechanical action of just
taking the you know new cells right
there's no tissue for those to live in
um but if you get to and same with
viruses or most viruses if you get to
these changes or these modifications I
guess on the DNA itself then how does
that be removed
uh there's some indications to the the
NAD Pathways right so niin nicotinic
acid can promote removing those um
there's
some it's kind of a different mode of
action I would say or describe it as uh
that some of these sites are filled up
before you know methylation can kind of
stick on there so it is possible and I
think some of that does get removed
um if you're using some of the you know
the right formula or additives or um
combinations right and we're at the
point now where we can measure these
things and Technology didn't have all
this uh before so we have new sequencing
methods um Next Generation sequencing
came out right and now we have nanopore
sequencing where I can do a I could
sequence You Know Field applications on
piece of equipment probably this big
come out to the grow sequence it and
then run it right so we have the
technology and now we can we can
accurately measure um and monitor the
epig genome right so now we can verify
these things have been removed or
accumulating what we don't know yet is
the ecosystem that all of these things
create amongst
themselves that's where I start just
going crazy so you get methyl groups and
then you know Ubiquiti and all these
other other long words and what kind of
pressures do the interactions between
those cause like we keep going down that
rabbit hole but um the more we
understand that the more we can uh
create and figure out to truly
clean genetics down to the DNA level
right removing these methylation methyl
groups so it it sounds like um if I'm
understanding correctly you're providing
almost like a uh a growth hormone or a
regulator to the plant to help promote
its um Expediting growth away from
contaminated genetic material um which
makes me think a lot about how resetting
genetics uh if you are using clonal
propagation is extremely important to do
it regularly to maintain um vigorous
growth because vigorous growth will
help uh not necessarily remove pathogens
but prevent the uh buildup within the
tissue and create a lower um uh
threshold or a lower economic threshold
that you need to meet in order to make
sure that it's still maintaining at a
specific output as a crop um but it
sounds like what you're able to do is
use that to then even completely remove
some of these epigenetic changes over
time
by
successively outgrowing the different
aspects that are preventing um a genetic
expression that was desirable that is no
longer
found yeah well everything's always more
complex right there's way more you know
deeper stuff you can get into that is my
hope and that is what we we're building
towards um I will never say I can do
that until I have the data in front of
me and I've proven that you know but if
you think these things are possible and
this is how it functions it's like I
mean that's possible it's like okay well
we have a path forward to where we could
potentially you know truly reset these
genetics and maybe get the reg the sour
diesel back to where it was right even
in the you know in the grow room it's a
the result is genotype by Environmental
interaction right um You can get these
things to express more or less and we
can measure that we can do RNA
sequencing and all these you know bunch
of highle science stuff and we can
measure gene expression um we can now
see you know epigenetic pressures and
things that are are
restricting uh their ability to express
we know the exact you know sites of Gene
regulation and um that controls those
things you know it's like H
H3 on H3 K1 or something like a very
specific point so that's how far
Sciences come and how do we manipulate
it rights make a very targeted approach
um rather than having to sort of uh use
like a shotgun blast to try and get
everything uh all it once or hope that
you hit a few things while you're while
you're trying this specific remediation
method you almost now take the plant
tissue run it through the analysis uh it
spits out the data for you of course I'm
simplifying this but it it gets you the
data you take that data you you go
through oh uh this data fits in here on
the chart I can now take this
application uh or this methodology apply
it to that plant tissue and we should
have a 10% success rate of removing the
um the issue that we found retest all
the data or retest all the tissue after
that next successive generation take
that plant that shows that it was
removed and boom you have the next the
next line within your your um uh your
steps that to remove everything that you
want to remove from the the epigenetic
uh changes since I'm yeah and yeah go go
ahead I was G say since I'm the simple
simpleton here and not as smart as you
and and wolf um to simplify it and use
the same analogy we using before you
know if we have wolf who's been eating
Taco Bell and you know Burger King for
30 years there are things that he can do
to improve his health you know like if
he has high cholesterol maybe he takes
cholesterol medication and stuff like
that and he can lower it so there's
certain things that we can do you know
with tissue culture and other means to
improve the health of our plants and our
genetics but we don't know how
to turn back the clock and fix every all
the damage that we've done yet maybe
someday we will you know but but
currently like we know what we know and
and we're learning more every day and
it's it's
exciting exactly yeah like we have
because there's so many fields of
research that like I want to learn
everything is a problem I'm like oh go
learn this though but if you look at how
fast technology and research is is
rapidly developing right now we have
ai um integrating those fields of
research with AI with genetics with um
then it I think we'll we'll find
Solutions really fast um but it's a
combination right keep your genetics uh
you know if I'm reading I'll pop a bunch
of seed put a coffee in vro if you're
keeping it in tissue culture and it's
not healthy
you're just adding more problems to it
right so just don't keep it in tissue
culture keep a healthy mom until you you
can you can figure it out because those
types of uh you can run into mutations
epigenetic pressures everything else
rapidly if you're you know putting them
in vitro and um uh doing it that way
stress something that's already
stressed exactly it's just like h kill
me please right and you can always
reculture it and you know keep it
rolling but you're just adding more of
that onto it right I'll always refer to
the first part of tissue culture as the
proofing phase because you got to make
sure that everything that's going into
culture is healthy enough to sustain
growth um so I think that was uh you
know we we had Cosmic on earlier but he
had to jump out but one of the things
that he was talking about is the uh
potential for contam ination when using
uh a single uh culture vessel for
multiple xplants or multiple
meristematic uh tissue cultures um just
based on either the uh use of improper
aseptic techniques improper cleaning
practices prior to uh putting into
culture um so what are some of the steps
that you take to help uh reduce the um
or to increase the viability of your
initial xplants when going directly from
a mother population or a stock plant
population at a
facility yeah that's a so refer to a
stage zero right um there's a lot of
preparation you can just do with your
mother plant to start uh if you think
endites that are in the tissue you can
remove a lot of those you know use a a
product with um like biosafe zero tall
something like that it's pulling it into
the tissue and it can kill a lot of
these uh you know Anor robic things and
um knock those down quite a bit right uh
stuff you know pythium when you get
pythium goes all the way up and it
starts getting limp on top if you add
those then it starts straightening it up
because it's killing uh that in the
tissue itself so if you're having
trouble with contamination I would
definitely start there um getting it you
know just knocking as much down as you
can when you take your samples um I've
haven't seen a huge difference with with
the right formulations you always keep
that in mind in health or subculture or
everything where I'm taking that tissue
uh the best is obviously going to be
lower parts of the plant and if you
think
endogenous hormones
um enolation or the this
photomorphogenic response right if it's
in low light conditions it's going to
try and stretch towards that light
there's hormones in there that are
already in the tissue so those always
have a faster response as far as growth
um but you're also Getting
Thinner uh little stock to to cut so we
can Surface sterilize as much as we want
but if it has a really thick stock that
you're trying to put um into the agar
you're not going to penetrate and kill
uh everything inside right that's a
really so I go down this my like
initiations are probably this big I say
tiny um remove all the tissue that's not
going to contribute to Healthy Growth
you don't need it right um because if
you leave it on there there's it could
be harboring harboring contaminants that
you might not see for months like it'll
just build and then a leaf touches the
side of a vessel and then it's
contaminated right so the purpose of
this is like get rid of all that stuff
we know that it will grow and just be
really really healthy in in uh culture
with the the formulas things we've
developed so you just start there get
rid of the chances that there's
contamination in deeper thicker tissue
um it makes a huge difference can I stop
you and ask a quick question
yeah so I mean you're you're kind of
blowing my mind right now by saying that
you should use the lower tissue on the
plant because what I've always been
taught even from the people that taught
me tissue culture was that you want to
use the top newest
growth um so are you saying that that's
not true that you know uh something on
the bottom that may have been there for
longer and is thinner and you know
stretched out is actually better parent
material than like the apic you know the
top of the
plant uh yeah that's what I that's what
I use and there's different sides to it
right if you're taking a mar stem um you
get that apex of the tissue those are
going to be bigger up top remember
you're cutting all that tissue off right
doesn't matter they're way easier to
dissect and and isolate they're bigger
and you have more aggressive kind of new
cell growth cell division and growth
right um but if you're putting in um you
know node node culture or just a shoot
tip um I always take it from the bottom
uh I think University of weth came out
with a paper that's saying you know sub
subcultures they have a lower decline in
health from the basil stock if you're
taking from that which really like those
low shoots that are um just coming off
the stock on the bottom right for sure
makes me think of like UV radiation and
how that can also damage um genetics
within uh any plant and or any living
creature uh so anything that has a
little bit of a more shade response
where it is trying to push a hormonal
growth rather than using the the light
directly on it to to promote and drive
the growth um you're going to have a
little bit of a a greater potential for
healthiest genetic tissue um and this is
something that I feel like uh just for a
little clarification you know like if
you are doing clonal propagation using a
lower uh Branch may not produce the most
vigorous clone so using upper growth for
clonal propagation is usually the most
advantageous simply because it does have
a lot more available photosynthates
directly on site ready to be used
because of the photosynthetic process
that's happening that close to the light
but when you're not relying on
photosynthesis to provide the plant with
the carbohydrates it needs for growth
than something with a higher hormonal
load and it does sound like it would do
a lot better in
vro yeah yep and you're not having to
add these extra hormones and you know uh
say it makes a big difference right so
the thin little little shoots that are
popping up EAS way easier easier to
sterilize like thoroughly sterilize so
you're confident it's not going to start
growing in you know couple months down
the line right and I see just a fash
response but that also has to do with
formulations and and things like that
you're going to see dramatic difference
um so if you just stick to just thin
tissue that hasn't been because there a
lot of those top pieces that you want to
take regular clones or cuting right you
want those big thick
stems um kind of go the opposite it
doesn't it doesn't feel like it makes
sense but that's where I see the very
most success uh as far as sterilizing
and preventing contamination you know
that's that's an awesome trick for
people that are trying to get into this
and and find success early on because
it's such a long process to go from even
nodal culture to uh a a an xplant that
you can then put back into rotation as
either a mother or a um a production
plant uh that it's really hard for some
people to then lose all that progress
and and want to continue um we even see
that even just with hom Growers popping
a seed and and getting some you know uh
thrips or some some disease or just
powdery Milo or something that hinders
their their overall grow and they just
don't want to do it again so limiting
those little potentials for issue is so
huge um and I would like you to touch
on the uh the difference between noal
and marem tissue culture and what you
prefer to do first if you're going in to
do genetic
preservation um would you would you
start with nodal to tissue culture or
would you uh start with marem um and
just to preface this a little bit I've
always thought that you go from
or noal 2 meristem while it's all in
vitro uh so that you can have
um you you you do that uh zero um
generation to really make sure that it's
uh the healthiest tissue possible yeah
so it' just be great to kind of hear
your opinion on whether you like to
start with Nole or um marem uh tissue
culture and
why sure so when somebody's learning I
just I always suggest start with noal
culture get the process and everything
down right um when I am saving something
you for long-term storage or keeping a
clean copy um I always do uh bare stem
right if I pop it from seed usually I'll
just do you know a node um because it
hasn't been exposed to all these other
things and collecting end of fights and
fungus and everything else um I try to
do it early though so you're not having
that full xylem and you know things that
can get in there I'll just take one
sterilize it keep a clean copy in any
other genetic that I bring in meristem
100% but do you start with
meristem I do yeah so once you have a
clean copy right from Mar stem that you
can multiply everything coming out of is
clean right and that's that's the the
idea I have a huge collection of
genetics um I don't know where a lot of
these came from or I do but you know the
facility they came from what they have
whether you know sometimes I know it has
a virus um and I'll take the same
precautions if it I know it doesn't have
a virus you just you know be safe and
follow best practice and protocols and
um you'll prevent the spread right
because you could take something out of
culture you did from meristem and just
give it a virus like pretty quick right
um but new genetics you know I got some
of my old stuff back the other day I
just want some of the the classics Super
Lemon Haze Golden Goat things like that
right um whether to study or breed with
doesn't matter marasim dissection that
way I'm confident that it's clean and
done properly and once I have tissue in
there I can pull as many of those out as
I want um the difficult part uh with
bear stem is the the length of time
maintenance checking them making sure
it's growing and um that's something
we've cut down dramatically like rule of
thumb people say about nine months um I
don't want to speak too soon so I still
got to go home and make sure make sure
it's alive but we you know we could
easily cut that in half or um we're
looking about three four months
um
potentially from from Mar stem to
a like um fully hardened off plant ready
to go into production yep uh but that
rate of growth and these are this new
formula just for this I still want to
make sure that's healthy rate of growth
right right um I'm still not using tons
of hormones or anything like same you
know kind of uh approach that I use but
um you can have rapid growth and have
mutations and and other problems that
you definitely can't see right
especially if you're breeding with it so
we're going to look further into that at
a deeper level but if you start with Mar
stem and you know it's clean and and you
can feel confident in that
then everything else you do from there
um is going to be better than what you
had right because even a tiny little
node that you can sterilized you're
still going to it still could Harbor is
you know like a tiny tiny Spore or
something you're not going to see the
effect of it but over time the plant
grows and those spores or contaminates
grow inside as well right um and that's
the biggest piece because the the stuff
I've pulled out of tissue culture from
marem it is explosive growth like and
it's not too many hormones it's because
nothing else except the plant's tissue
is utilizing the nutrients and
everything else um you know you push it
in and grow it'll get a collection of
these endef fights and you know other
things in there but um that's where you
know part of our name is the mothership
Labs we get new sets of mother stock
from the system every quarter or however
however long you want um and you just
don't have to worry you get extremely
vigorous healthy plants high yields all
the stuff that people think of when when
you talk about tissue culture but you
turn around you're like we're not seeing
that like why right so um definitely
start with
marem uh to practice and kind of dial
things in getting familiar with
everything node culture is just a great
way to burn through tissue you can get
plenty of it um because once you're
comfortable and you can manipulate these
things and you you know what to look for
then meristem is uh a lot easier to like
monitor once you get it past that first
stage it's it's just the same stuff like
transfers clean them up a little bit
make sure they're they're healthy um and
becomes much easier but if you start
with marem and you haven't done this
before it's um I won't say it's
overwhelming it's just like a difficult
First Step you're like I don't know if I
can do this the learning curve again is
just practice like if you just get used
to the motions and what you're looking
for
and proper technique then the rest is
easy you know U well it's pretty easy
you know some troubleshooting here and
there but um I want the stock that I
grow and especially stock that I breed
with to be as clean as I can and as
healthy as I can um because talking
about epigenetic pressures earlier on
right those are heritable to the Next
Generation Um so you definitely start
with uh as clean as you can in until we
get um you know more easier Solutions
right I guess to kind of reset these
things but which I think will come I
mean the the technolog is there which is
crazy so for
sure Gabby did you have a question I did
so you know
I like I said I have a hobby tissue
culture lab and um I've only done nodal
tissue culture in the past and I want to
learn how to do meristem
and so when I went to the lab you know
the other day it took so much time to
prep that I didn't have time to do
meristem and I had already taken all
these clones so I wanted to stick some
in Nole if you have a clone that's in
Nole and you want to do meristem off of
it would you suggest doing this
sanitization procedure
again
um I that's something that I was
thinking you don't think you have to
well I mean I think thinking the right
way that's that's what want because you
had mentioned that it's possible that
it's not clean when you when you do a
nodal tissue culture and I was thinking
you know normally when you do nodal
culture at least the first time you
stick it in you got to sterilize it
after that if it hasn't grown anything
you just pull it out divide it and put
it in New Media but if I'm going from
noal to Mar stem do you think it's
important that I didn't again do that
sanitization process
I don't think so I mean you could
technically right you could let's you
got a thick piece of stem and during
that process you cut through a stem it
gets something on there and gets onto
the the uh the cell tissue or the mar
stem you want to remove um or the tip of
your tool when you're placing it onto
the medium then you could get it but
really if you if your confident clean
you're removing anything that those can
live in anyway right it's not going to
live in the the clump of cells that
you're removing so I think you'll be
fine doing that um the way I do I
usually sterilize from tissue so it's
healthy rapid growth that hasn't gone in
in vitro yet and I'll sterilize those to
put in um but you can do it both ways
yeah if you you know I have some I'm
going to dissect when I get home that
are just in vessels they're fil huge
filling them out but um I don't have a
copy that's acclimated and ready to go I
don't I want to start the process and
get you know get the rest of my
collection done right so you can easily
pull that out um under the microscope
and it's again just feeling comfortable
uh we have some methods that are fast
easy and overall accurate is what you
want um and biggest suggestion if you
get some if you go to the dentist ask
them for
uh some of their tools most of the time
they'll recycle them or send them back
somewhere but they are the best for
marison dissection you can kind of just
peel those primordial primordial
structures off to expose that and just
take it right off what type of tools are
we talking about so those dental picks
oh they're like the handles and they
have like H different shape yeah to
everyone hat oh my God best thing for
dissecting ever like wow um all right
that's a when you get in there with Like
a Knife oh yeah it's it's huge there's
some other ones we'll talk about um you
get in there with a blade like scalpel
blade even number 11 which is like
thinner it's still hard to kind of sort
through that um that little structure
and it's okay you're not like ripping it
things off like you do is you wantel it
off these are the leaves I'll kind of
like push them to the side right and on
both sides so kind of like opens up then
you can visually like see the structure
and where you're you're going into
because after a little bit you're like I
don't even know what I'm cutting here
I'm just like mashing things up right um
especially if it's on you know a
dissection plate so I I hold mine
straight up in the air like this and
I'll get
forceps and so it's sticking up in the
air and I'll peel you know the
primordial leaf and any structures to
the side so you kind of see it it's way
way easier it's just another thing that
takes practice right you do that 10
million times right you're you're
cruising I can do one in like five
minutes and just knock them out um it's
all in the prep work and like I have all
my tools everything's good okay um
because then you know it's you're you
get taught certain things and you like
humans just you're like we have to have
these tools and this it's whatever works
best for you I have a different hand
shape or a different you know my elbow I
got a bum elbow and you know you find a
tool that's really effective that that
works for you um and just use it you
know so I got I got a set of dental
tools I get them for five bucks from the
dentist if you buy them new they're like
50 bucks you can autoclave them uh some
have little tiny blades on the tip you
know makes it much much easier um and
another one is go talk to my dentist oh
every time I I go there she's like I got
like five more for you I'll give them to
my clients and stuff and I'm like all
right by your clients um I'm sorry to
interrupt but something that I'm super
interested in
is what does Mothership Labs do like I I
know that you're a tissue culture lab
but are you are you selling tissue
culture clones are you teaching people
how to do tissue culture um are you
doing um what uh what is it called like
when you just hold all genetics like a
repository like a bank yeah so um we I
build Labs so I design build Labs pretty
much any scale you know we can do uh
fully automated robotic tissue culture
Labs if you want if you want to spend
the money um they exist um and we
started off because you know I've been
running big programs and breeding and
research and um
there's just a lot of bad experiences
and bad business we went through in the
this industry right and I ended up
working with uh my current partner Jay
he's he's awesome and a couple of those
experiences we we went through and we
were like we work really well together
he Bal he keeps me in the lab he says um
and you know Business Development sales
he does he's just amazing man the other
the stuff that I don't want to do right
I'm not good at right um and we started
this because we wanted to choose people
to work with that had the same values
and um you know Vision that we do so we
kind of organically shaped to where we
can do a ton of different things but
this is the way we can help people the
most like in the immediate term um so
coming out building labs and showing
people like Advanced Techniques and you
know developing formulas like here you
go like we do all the hard work just
just go and seeing them be
successful um when they're off when
they're on their own now we have an
affiliate lab we can just like form of
communication right we can send each
other clean genetics whenever and build
each other's catalogues and make crosses
and uh it it's been awesome so the
long-term vision is breeding research
more you know more of the stuff that
that we love to do and uh collaborate
with other people that that do that we
have powerful tools and so we use all of
our uh capabilities to create powerful
tools that are easy to use and that you
can apply um to make your help sustain
the the industry because there's been a
lot of collapse uh across the board
right so like let's save these genetics
like preserve them now we can do it so
they're healthy and we're not having
long-term issues we can have the real
genetics sword um and I'll do sometimes
I'll just do it for um because you you
run into the trust thing too right like
sem your genetics and I'll hold them um
that's why I started like building
people Labs right I the first version I
just had like a mobile kit that I pieced
together I'd show up and be like I'll
show you tis tissue culture is not hard
like and you show somebody the process
that's not that hard like you can do it
man like I got your back like let's go
it's funny to say that I mean I I want
to if you guys will humor me for a
second I want to tell a little story
yeah yeah do you know who Bill Graham is
the guy who sells the the home tissue
culture kit yeah I've heard yeah I've
heard Bill Graham for sure so you know
he gave me a kit and I kept it for over
a year sealed in the Box never used it
because I was intimidated and I just
felt like I had to get ready you know I
had to build this sterile space and I I
like I said it was intimidating and so
one day he comes over to my shop cuz I
own the hydro store and he comes to the
shop and he says that's it we're just
going to do this and he already had
media prepared but he broke out the
pressure cooker so we could make media
and then y um it wasn't cannabis because
it was my grow store but we had scented
geraniums and redwood trees and we
divided them up we used a rubber made
tough box turned on its side with the
front door of my store opening so like
it was in my retail space the door was
opening and we put the plants in there
and everything grew and we got it's very
little of any contamination and then
after that I was so inspired I did
tissue culture every day like if you
came into my store it smelt like alcohol
and bleach cuz I'm constantly spraying
the stuff doing the tissue
culture but now
I've ended up kind of in that same
situation for many years
where I'm scared to do
Marist you know like I got you cover man
I'm just trying to like break that seal
and do it the because I know once I do
it then I'll repeat and you know but
doing it that first time it's like it's
intim it seems it seems so like and
honestly it's kind of like passing it
forward right cuz where I came from is
like nobody helped me for a long time I
had to like fight and
scratch uh you got into the industry
nobody was going to share information
with you like that's my recipe or I was
like all right how am I supposed to do
my job then right
so and we're trying to just fight
against that be like I'll tell you
exactly how to do this and what I'm
doing I have sweets of Sops like if
you're successful then and I believe we
will will be successful together you
know but it's somebody showing me that
it's I was like holy [__] like I can do
this like it's it isn't that hard it's
like someone teaching you how to grow
weed the first time too it's like it's
like such like how you know and then you
see it and you're like it's not that
hard yeah and it it started my entire
career PAAD like learning like you need
to learn in this area I'm like okay cool
and
just surrounding myself with um people
that are way smarter than myself and
learning to ask the right questions
because you you find if you got good
people around you they that are educated
in you know whatever subject if you talk
to them they love to share that right
and I've been to Laboratories where like
like I've been to you know phds like
I've dedicated my entire life to this
and some of those people end up just tur
turning out samples or having to run
more business than science you know and
their dream when their little kid was to
be a scientist so you start like can you
show me this or what about that I go
home and do my homework and come back be
like all right I ran into some more
questions like their their eyes light up
they're like I know all about like he's
asking about this and that's what
inspired me uh a long time ago to go
down biotech and all this and
um otherwise it kind of dies right you
you hear tissue culture lab and the
first thing is like way too expensive
you got a whole sterile room and all
this stuff and I mean if you're doing it
this scale you know you you want some
preventatives in place and um but you
don't need to do this if you're at your
house I buil one at my house that's
pretty crazy but maybe another I ended
up just building a lab in my house so I
could do all this we should do a lab
tour sometime of your of your home lab
um just over video we just invited
ourselves to your house dude we just
I'll just live stream you guys just pop
in whenever you want uh got these I got
these AI cameras too so we could do a
lab tour and a marm EX too if you want
that would be be great that would be
awesome I've been recently looking at
videos on YouTube trying to like figure
out how to do it one thing I wanted to
add is you know until recently you and
and maybe you know and even Bill Graham
and some other people um we had the guy
from kenic come on educating people
about tissue culture and cannabis the
guys that were doing it didn't want to
do it you know like they want to keep
their secrets and make you think that
it's really hard to do because that's
their business plan to like make money
selling everybody the stuff so for me I
appreciate people like you that are
willing to share the knowledge and
educate people um like I said it's the
same about growing weed like if we kept
all the info back about how how to grow
weed it just holds the entire like
Universe back so I I just want to say
thank you for being willing to share all
this information and it's abut I've been
very inspired already you know from from
this and again like you might find
something you're like dude I just
figured this out we go over together and
I could start using it you know like it
to me and and my partner Jay it's less
about like um sometimes I'll just show
up at people's like all I'm Gonna Knock
these out for you to free because I love
it but um it's less about gatekeeping
the knowledge so I can make money and
there's the money will come man if I'm
teaching people to do this properly we
all advance in this money to be made
teaching people how to do it too and
building up labs and yeah I get we build
a network and and exchange information
it's less about me like providing mine
it's like let's exchange information and
knowledge uh and continue to grow you
know yeah and and some of those earlier
companies that did have these very
proprietary tissue culture recipes for
cannabis they were evaluated at an
extremely high um at an extremely high
valuation
due to their recipes and methodologies
and so they were beholden to contracts
to not release that information out to
anybody even if it was friends family
somebody that was just looking to get
into tissue culture because they would
um they would void their contractual
obligations and their fiduciary
responsibilities to these investors
where I think one of the recipes was
valuated at $10 million just for the
tissue culture recipe and
that was you know 5 to 10 years ago and
that company is now out of business
because they realized that you can have
this awesome recipe but if you're not
then sharing it with the community and
helping the community understand the
value behind tissue culture there is no
reason to do it in the first place um ex
exactly Y and you know I've heard so
much bad information or misinformation
right some of the information is like
that's what they learned and were told
and which is okay like I I understand
that too but the work we did and like
the focus work I'm I'm so tired did this
entire year it's like it works and all
these things that you heard tissue
culture can do is possible and let's
let's touch on one of those actually
really quickly sorry to cut you off but
I feel like one of the biggest
controverses in um through the views of
cannabis cultivators when it comes to
tissue culture right now is the removal
of hops lat and vroid through martic
tissue culture and you and I were
actually put in contact with each other
through our mutual uh connection at Tumi
genomics because that's right yeah
because I had reached out to find out
more about Hops and vroid Remediation
because it is something where some
people will say there's no guarantee it
can't happen and they've been doing
tissue culture for years or decades but
they're caught I believe in a mindset of
limitations where they don't think that
something's possible because they just
haven't been able to do it yet and what
I always like to tell people you know
this is also for people that have been
growing for 30 years 40 years cannabis
and are stuck in a specific set of ways
where they say this is how I've always
done it this is how it works and I'm not
going to listen to new methodologies
I've already been doing this for 30
years how could something be better and
so I feel like there people pigeonhole
themselves in a lot of these mentalities
unfortunately but I was put in direct
contact with you because of your ability
that you've shown to remove hop lat and
thyroid and so I'd like to pick your
brain a little bit about that where you
found success and how that success has
sort of been able to been proven out
over time sir yeah I mean it's it's a
Hot Topic right uh and yeah when you
first out I thought like a a potential
client and I was like he's asking he's
asking a lot of questions there what's
going on right but I was it was great to
connect you're asking the right
questions right which was um it's it's
refreshing in a lot of ways
so as everything is right the world is
it's more complex than can you remove it
can you not right it's different with
different genetics um there is the the
mechanical removal part right removing
the the the cells at the the apical uh
Dome um not connected the vascular
system which a lot of these things can
be moved through the tissue right um
that is one part of it but they I
believe there's been some instance where
they have transferred through other
avenues right you know through these
cellular mechanisms and I group that in
like more research needs to be needs to
be done to
understood um but there's some genetics
that are knocking out in the first try
and be like I'm the best there ever was
at TC some genetics extremely just a
pain to to do that with it's not all the
same right so there like the variety of
how these things evolved in the tissue
down to the uh the cellular mechanisms
right they're not all the same cannabis
has a
um very different uh plant in some ways
right so starting there the methodology
and treatments and there's a variety of
those available right you can use broad
antivirals you can do I there's a ton of
things you can apply um to help prevent
frost contamination and and have that be
more
successful uh rule of thumb is I think I
told you too is like 50% of the sample
right is what you want to expect but
there's also those you know those
outliers where like none of those came
out clean um or all of them so going
down to the techniques um so I'm sure
you guys told like cold treatments and
you know a lot of different ways to
approach it the cell actually don't know
about cold treatment can you briefly
touch on that oh sure so you can um
basically take your you know I'll take a
sample this big right uh just your your
tissue and protect it so I got a kind of
step process to you know protect it
store it in a
refrigerator um and I know some people
that have gone way colder than that but
it's basically really really cold for a
short amount of time or refrigerator for
we do like two months or so um I've
adapted that into using some synthetic
seed um techniques as well to protect
those uh protect those organs and make
sure we're going to get functionality of
out of the cells to grow um but
essentially you're you're just slowing
everything down uh it always starts with
the sample that you take right so
remember uh the photomorphogenic
responses you can get a plant to stretch
out pretty quick using far red light
right so why not stretch that out it's
growing really fast then take your
xplant so already you've either limited
or diluted as much as you can right from
the the bottom of that plant um because
template viral you're you're talking
links to this metabolism and growth uh
so if you can just stretch it out and if
you know far red light you can get that
to happen pretty quick right and start
there you're already ahead um so at
least a viral load and everything else
you're working with uh cold storage does
kind of same thing and I've heard heat
cold it's all I think needs to be
evaluated further to get like real truth
behind some of these things but because
we're looking at just the mechanical
separation if it's not able to get into
those cells why does it matter right
which could it could get into those
cells so a lot of that I think is just
an attempt to kind of slow everything
down so it's not spreading into the
tissue you're going to just dissect
anyway um So currently I just use that
far red light which you can get isolated
spectrums of that take your your xplant
and do a proper dissection and that uh
there's techniques which I'll go when
when we're in the lab I'll go over with
all that stuff for you guys so makes a
huge difference right because if I'm
sitting there smearing you know hlbb all
over the samples I'm plating up and so
on so forth um got to prevent that and
that's I think the hardest part where
you can isolate that efficiently um I
use ocular scissors and you know for eye
surgeries things like that you find the
right tool or the best tool for the job
so you go to the eye doctor and get
their used tools too see this is a
you're catching on right we just got to
schedule appointments pick up pick up
tissue culture supplies we're good man
all righty just make a list of all the
doctors that we got to grab their uh
recyclables from or go search in that
dumpster behind the building to see like
oh man we got some ocular scalples we
need well uh funny enough the last tool
is like a hyperemic or hypmic needle
that you can just because it has the
sharp end that you can pull that off
without touching any other tissue on
there right so then you have a in the oh
I got a clean pull then you're able to
just remove it and just kind of plate it
like that a sharpen spoon I'm a rookie
but it's funny that you say that because
I watched a video and it literally
looked like he didn't cut the marem out
he popped it out it's like he just went
in then he went like this like you know
first he peeled it open a little bit and
then he just popped it out I was like
man he made that look too simple we need
to do that in slow motion or it needs to
be slow motion and and even zoomed in
more than yeah the microscope was
showing because yeah technique right and
if you think about just tissue in
general if it's water logged and been
sitting in you know you just sterilize
it and you went took a break that tissue
is going to be different than um you
know you uh you picture like asparagus
and an ice ba ice bath right it's still
crispy and you can kind of snap it right
so if it's sitting in there in your
sterilization solution and it's just
it's absorbing liquid it's going to be a
little more gummy and hard to kind of
pop off right so a lot of those things
is where you fine-tune those skill sets
and don't you start I'm sorry but don't
you isn't that part of the process like
you put it in water and you and you soak
it and clean it then you put it in
bleach and whatever and then you soak it
in water again aren't they always going
to be water logged by that
point um no no not if you're just
efficient with with that process right
so I do a and I can run I think the most
I did in one day was like
22 I would never recommend that it was
it was painful um but I dialed this in
because it has to be efficient for
people to use it right it goes back to
that concept um 50 mil tubes I have a
flat I just pull it up fill it to that
line add the tissue cap it orbital
Shaker for five minutes uh and that's
just with water washing particulate and
residues off for water in T20 or
polysorbate right empty them out and
then I add bleach water that's five
minutes uh on the orbital Shaker another
five minutes for me to set up and
prepare to start pulling tissue right so
that way it's not getting over
sterilized or
oversaturated I'm just like empty them
out rinse and I'm already starting to
pull tissue off so you get in a rhythm
like start with enough samples to where
you get through it um and you start
making it more efficient with like 50
mil tubes or like whatever you have
right you're not sanitizing too much at
a time because then it's just sitting
there in water or exactly yeah so I
stick to like made that mistake the
other day it makes huge difference right
I mean I I mean I was only doing Nole
but still I'm assuming yeah get all
flimsy and yeah so I I usually cap it at
like six different genetics at a time
now just because I'm I got lots of other
things I'm doing um and I can knock
those out get them in culture be good
you know um but start with one you can
do um I use 50 mil tubes just e and
you're not wasting too too much liquid
or having to manage too much liquid
right that's even worse you're juggling
like big jars and space yeah um so you
can just get a 50 mil tube rack and
Shake It you don't have an orbital
Shaker and um but by the time I get to
that six sample or six pavar um it's
still good to go if I start pushing it
do like 12 at once the last one I'm
starting to do is like getting flimsy
and um it'll still grow but we want just
the healthiest high quality tissue going
in right right um so you know as you I
do a lot of like lean 5S training and
process procedure optimization stuff for
Laboratories and operations and that's
why I broke it down because it's easier
to train people pick that up easier
there's like less steps the steps make
sense like I'm not having to do
unnecessary things we we've tested them
and you can get to the final step of
dissection faster and and start moving
so then you don't have a guy in having
to spend all day in a lab to get five
clean samples and throwing out
everything else right I haven't I'm like
I haven't seen contamination a long time
uh which is awesome just be just solid
best practice and just follow the steps
and you're good you can just Mass
produce initiations I guess that's
awesome and just get fast just the
mechanics so going back to the
hlvd a lot of those things are are still
valid right best practice ractice
efficiency because if you're smearing
viruses all over stuff that's not going
to do so well right um those first two
steps are are very important and have
done really well as far as success
getting that stretched out piece
hopefully that's outgrowing or diluting
uh some of that to some extent um and
I've heard people say that like outgrows
hlvd in culture right and that's I
wouldn't be be confident in that I
haven't tested it but I wouldn't be
confident um and the mechanical removal
you can always put broadspectrum
antibiotics stuff like that in your your
media plate um ribavarin or there's a
bunch of them you can do but as soon as
you get that growth it's I don't you're
looking at surface contact right so you
got have antibiotics put it on there and
maybe it'll kill some when it's
contacting that but it's going to start
growing unless that is getting pulled
into the tissue like I don't see that
being effective either right um
so yeah I mean it's really caseby casee
basis I would say and when people ask me
to do it I'm like I mean this is the
truth this is what I've seen and I'm
trying to study this more at a deeper
level so I can give you the you know a
better answer but the the reality is
like there's there needs to be more
research um I see on average about 50
50% success rate so I do twice as many
samples depending on how many I want 50%
success rate is great yeah some people
that's their entire tissue culture
success rate so if you're getting that
with hops and vroid that's crazy that's
extremely successful um I got you you
know I wanted to um to give a analogy
again and so kind of what we're talking
about is it reminds me of cancer so for
instance with cancer you know they cut
it out right but there's still a chance
that they didn't get it all out and that
it hasn't you know and then you got to
go and and do it again you know and so
it's the same thing with tissue cult and
actually with tissue culture I don't
know what they have a better chance of
removing cancer or hop late in vroid but
the bottom line is you have to do the
tissue culture and then you have to test
and then you have to do it again and
even if you test you might have to test
it again down the line or because it's
just hard to know if it's gone you know
so like people think they people think
they're cured of cancer and then years
later it comes back because it was still
inside of them somewhere speaking on
testing and and the length of time from
your um your zero generation in tissue
culture from marem where you're aiming
where the aim is to remove Hops and
thyroid what is the furthest out you've
then tested say a um plant that has
fully come out of tissue culture is a
mother plant or a stock plant at a
facility that was cleaned up you know
they removed all their hops slate and
thyroid plants but they sent it out to
be tissue culture they then uh int took
those genetics again and started
following better practices to help
reduce the potential for Hops and
thyroid um so what's the longest then
that you've been able to go back and
test something that test tested positive
for Hopson before tissue culture and
then tested negative out of tissue
culture was was there ever something
that you found you know that after like
15 months like there shouldn't have been
a contamination problem but it did test
for hops lant again or have you seen
that if you don't have potential for
contamination if it's not being
contaminated that it's been able to just
sustain health and uh uh zero viral
pressure after yeah what's what's that
time span you've been able to see
absolutely that's a great question
because a lot of people assume like
here's your plant for marem
culture it tested negative you're good
to go and that's that's not the case
right because of the nature of the virus
itself um the plant as it gets older and
you know metabolism starts moving your
root system it's pushing all these
things around the viral load increases
um testing in itself the LOD so level of
detection it's only so low that we can
identify it has the virus right it might
not be in the piece of tissue that we
took and might and that's why you see
testing requirements like take some of
this and a lot of it's in the root root
system that we can test for it right um
but when they're that little you might
not notice it or detect anything at all
okay um I might and I'll never tell you
like put this in your clean grow you're
you're good right um because six months
down the road all of your plants could
have it and it's it'll be my fault and
I'm I'm not gonna I'm not that guy so I
would say six months and there's people
that are far more qualified to to speak
on this than than I am that are studying
these fire like Tumi and you know um but
from my knowledge and my um you know ask
asking people and things like that I
would say like six months eight months
down the road I would still test it it's
because I'm paranoid and I don't want it
spreading right um but when it's this
big I would say you know like a teens
siiz plant when it has the a fully
developed root system and it's in that
um final environment uh I would say
where you know hotter temperature
humidity like you're going to you're
going to flower that out I would say
that's when you can feel more confident
you're like okay this thing it's good to
go um by then I would already have
subcultures in there or uh new copies to
where like all right we're clean then
like release all those subcultures that
way you have the numbers coming back
into your garden instead of just waiting
for test to come back and then you have
one plant to start cloning right sure um
so that's the there strategy behind that
U not like here's your plant it's you
know test it in six months get back to
me it's like here's your plant I got 50
of these coming so if we pass that test
you got 50 new moms coming or how many
you want sure how far out have you been
able to test like from clonal progyny uh
and have negative uh test results or
negative in the sense of that it it no
longer shows Hops and vroid after
removing it from that spe specific
cultivar how long have you been able to
see it test negatively for I think the
opposite question is more important
right that yeah I can test it myself
right I have qpcr gel electropheresis
everything so I use that to just
validate my process like uh this isn't
working we got we got to change um and
that's what we want right the the
biggest issue is here's you know people
give me their favorite genetic for their
brand it was like happy to clean it up
putting it right back into a facility
that's just filled with viruses right
right um and I see that all the time
they're like oh so I'm get Vigor and all
this like you bite those first couple
Cycles it's going to perform way better
um but you're not solving solving the
issue so they don't have proper cleaning
uh proper Sops in their Garden yeah and
and you know you should always assume
that you have
viroid and prac practices to not spread
it you know just kind of like safe sex
with random people you don't know like
yeah I mean you're not seeing her piece
but that doesn't mean she doesn't have
it you know or other STDs so you got to
be
careful a place like this right and this
um you see the logo they gave in the new
hat uh lab roots
why we are working with companies like
this we can flush your entire facility
out right now it's a much different
picture you're like wait hold on okay
start harvesting those rooms at like
we'll schedule as these uh clean plants
come up we'll have a whole room ready
you harvest a room and rotate clean it
sterilize it here's your first clean set
just don't don't touch it like clean
room style like don't go in there new
scissors and as they roast out you're
just flushing your entire facility out
with your own genetics you know we can
do do that um and that that's what I see
the next phase of of getting some of
these things restored right it's almost
like a restoration project for for the
industry man um because there's so many
good genetics that I definitely don't
want to lose or because they could be
studied or they could be used for
breeding or and and have these kind of
varieties that um that are just
phenomenal man um but tools like this is
like we flush your whole facility out
you're way more successful and you have
it's almost like another chance just
test anything you know have a quarantine
Proto protocol before bringing something
in your facility right or just hit me up
we got we got some Awesome Genetics too
sure um so there's always the the
functional tools of tissue culture but
then there's the strategy on how to to
apply it so it's effective and you're
getting you're like getting the results
right and that's a big piece I see um a
lot of these places missing is like if
if I install a lab you could flush out
your entire facility you can you know
start generating enough stock um to have
just run I don't recommend propagation
micro propagation
um unless you know exactly what you're
doing and you know how to measure it
right um and that I always take the a
chunk from lean 5S is like deic Define
analyze and proove on Define measure
analyze improve control right and you
stick to that I apply it just everything
I'm like doing dishes saying it just
haunts me in my dreams but there's a lot
I see Jay poking out here you do one
thing man the way you do
everything yeah so the the practical
applic
like we have um some of our other
partners say like group of just amazing
scientists we're going to protoplast
Fusion labs and we create perfect
hybrids by fusing cells together cross
species hybrids we can do so we're going
to have another episode we're going to
try and reel it back in a little bit
here because it sounds like we're going
to need to do another episode um
somebody here you yeah yeah oh good yeah
I'll introduce you to Rael good she's
from uh this is her lab here you want to
say hi hello hi very
impressive yeah they're building some
some awesome stuff out here but um yeah
we love to connect with you again we'll
get you some aim you know dissection
training whatever man we'll get you in
the lab remotely that's awesome or if
you guys come to Colorado you're you're
always welcome so I appreciate that like
I said I I have to go Jess I can help
with man nice meeting you
and thank you for joining us Gabby oh
thank you Nick thanks for inviting me
what a what a great
talk cool um so yeah I mean so far we've
really touched on I feel like some
aspects of the tissue culture side of
cannabis that a lot of
people do find very hard to wrap their
brain around and to there's there's not
an entry level uh tissue culture you
know like it you kind of have to jump
in uh you can't just get your feet wet
you got to go all the way in um Y and
you've you've touched on a lot of those
different aspects that really do help
support uh like you've like in your um
in your mission statement you're you're
wanting to support what's already here
within the Cannabis industry and use
this tool and this technology to
continue that support so that people can
be more successful or you know find
their own Niche within the market that
helps them succeed um like for instance
for my the farm that I help manage we
have a huge outdoor plot and we grow uh
over a 100 different cultivars in that
outdoor plot each year we also have an
indoor space and the indoor space only
can get up to 22 21 to 22 harvests per
year and we're typically running only
between 1 and six cultivars there per
year so we can't even get through our
full genetic library in a year and the
maintenance of mother plants and stock
plants is expensive it's expensive it's
tedious that's the thing that I find to
be one of the hardest aspects of
maintaining a large um stock plant
population is the constant need for
organization the constant need for
um uh proper techniques with within the
cloning process that if something if you
get a hiccup it throws your schedule off
you need to then retake clones it throws
off if you only have a certain amount of
space with like we're a small farm we
have limited space so it's it's hard to
maintain these different populations
also with a small labor force um but
with tissue
culture it does seem as though there is
a lot of opportunity in a lot of
different aspects of cultivation that
can kind of help
bring cannabis cultivation overall a few
steps forward um yeah definitely so with
your experience and like I said before
we're going to have to come back to do
another episode especially when you're
back home in your lab because I want to
go over your your different breeding
practices and some of those projects
that you've done I'd love little I love
breeding stuff so it's one of the like
real fun hobby aspects of cannabis
cultivation I feel like that anybody can
get into and they can really create
something that's really unique to them
it's almost like having a having that
awesome family recipe that you share
with people and they're like oh my God
that's the best food in the world how
did you make this like we've just been
doing this forever um Keeps Us attached
to the the plant you know
absolutely so like I was saying though
we need to do another episode talk about
your breeding talk about your actual hom
growing practices current ly where
you're keeping these genetics alive
outside of culture because the inv vitro
culture you know that's one aspect of it
but you still then need to have the
ability to have those plants in a actual
um growing environment uh yeah X vitro
and uh the different techniques and
stuff that you use there in order to
maintain a certain health I feel like
when you're looking at it through a
scientific lens of these are either
going to be for tissue culture they're
coming out of tissue culture and I need
to maintain a specific amount of Health
that ends up leading to really refined
cultivation practices really refined
Environmental Lighting um irrigation
practices
that are almost they're so essential for
actual cultivation of cannabis for
flower production that I feel like we'd
be able to teach a lot of people more
when we dive back into that but
considering you've had a lot of
experience in the illicit Market uh back
in the day you were able to translate
that into what sounded like helping with
different uh medical and uh earlier uh
programs within say Colorado and around
those areas and then you also continue
with your home growing and your breeding
and all these different practices and
aspects of the industry that you're in
um I feel like you would be a great
person to ask ask where do you want to
see the Cannabis industry change or
develop in the next 5 to 10 years that
you feel as though we're missing
currently
um there's a last there's a lot there
you know
because I I started at least
professional cultivation and management
and you know um
coo restructuring other people's
programs all that stuff so I've seen a
lot
and I was able to ask a lot of these
questions and get different perspectives
right um I would like to see really you
know best practice stuff that um a lot
of that's coming out too especially with
the virus and me like if you just follow
this it's you keep contamination out you
keep pests and things like that to
create a clean product right so that's
one testing um testing is all over the
place we had you know whole Lab we'd
send our stuff out for compliance we'd
run the same samples on our equipment
and another lab they're all different
right so standardizing that because if
it does become medicine we need to know
that those results are reliable and we
can use it as such right um that goes
also also into um what genetics are
truly you know everyone's renaming the
find a good cut and then rename it how
do we build around that to where it is
um oh thank you um how do we how are we
sure that if I go to this dispensary or
the you know wherever that evolves to
and I need
medicine how do I know it's the same
plant that is helping me right right um
I think there's be application of uh so
pharmacogenomics right we have the
Cannabis genome we can do that we have
the human genome
um some of the groups I'm working with
is to connect those pieces to see like
we could both smoke the same joint and
I'm freaking out and you're like I feel
great I love this our body just like all
these plants are different our receptors
our brains are formed differently our
experience has shaped the development of
those right we know about the
methylation and how that is an aspect of
just how life um evolves and continues
to grow so how do we unravel that to
where we understand application for
medicinal purposes and standardize those
pieces um and I would also like to help
like because we've had to create hybrid
breeding programs right classical
methodology I couldn't use I couldn't
grow fields for statistical analysis and
because of Regulation and compliance or
it was just not cost effective um how do
we get
better access for research and
development I know some of those are are
starting to evolve as well um but if
we're not able to grow these plants to
study them and improve without breaking
the bank um then that side is not going
to continue to evolve either right yeah
um so we we're all part of a groups
different groups to push these things
forward and uh contribute
so I think if you have your own breeding
program you have unique genetics for
your brand that we can fingerprint ID
those to at the genetic level um so we
know that's yours and that adds more
power to the brand and builds their
customer base and so breeding programs
and Ed more education behind um how you
can do this effectively in in a
controlled way um I keep going but a a
lot of this into more the the molecular
marker assisted selection and being able
to truly pinpoint some of these things
um using te
biotechnology I you know it feel it
sounds like we can wrap up a lot of what
you'd like to see in the better
application of the information we have
available and putting those practices
into
use and not not falling back to these
old you know quote unquote Bro Science
ways of growing cannabis and producing
cannabis um like it's still the illicit
Market you know like taking this and
trying to truly quantify and qualify the
different aspects of the cannabis plant
how it interacts with the human endoc
canono system and trying to use proper
studies and and test samples and test
groups and different populations of
users to help understand how things
affect certain people
how we can then take that data and give
it to other people so that they don't
have to be a guinea pig for their own
medicinal needs um yeah exactly and you
know I talked to groups that are um you
one has a daughter one has a a brother I
have lots of friends I've seen some that
like they've cured their cancer like my
best friend he had severe um lung cancer
and it's completely gone wow why do that
happen
you know how do we change some of these
people's lives and have a positive
impact from what we're all of us are
just really good at I know some
cultivators that are far better than I
am I have a bad neck and back now
because I've been growing weed for so
long but how can we just organize
together and um share more information
because I I feel like that's a a huge
start right there just being able to
freely talk about what's working and how
we can work together um and as a company
you know my my partner and I were like
if we can pay the bills and just keep
moving it'll happen right yeah we're
working on powerful tools for breeding
and biotechnology and connecting these
other networks so um we can at least
contribute you know to that but it's
can't just be you know we um so I love
to see it people just kind of like it
used to be man like Growers Growers
unite K yeah um and be able to make
positive change because it it is
evolving it is going to continue to to
evolve and change um and it shouldn't be
just the people that have a ton of money
that um is allowed you know so anything
we can do to help um for you know your
viewers or you your your Crews anything
um these guys here are are in the same
mindset this company uh lab Roots too
like we're we're hoping to use a lot of
their experience to scale and and have
some some power behind this too but it's
still going to take work to create a
model that we can keep within the the
community and the people you know right
so I mean that's why I call this show
The Way We Grow because it has two
meanings right I want to teach people
how to grow commercially homeg growing
hobby tissue culture anything in between
I want to make sure that people have the
tools at their disposal and the
resources they need to access knowledge
that has been withheld or gate kept for
decades not only do I want to help
people learn how to grow I want to grow
the community as a whole and I want to
grow the collaborative effort between
different Growers and people that are in
cannabis and cannabis adjacent
businesses
because just like any other industry
that has really taken off it required
immense amounts of collaboration between
those who were working to really
progress the field in a way that they
thought help the most people
possible and Y people like yourself who
are out there trying to help Implement
best practices and um remove different
stigmas from practices that have been
controversial or argued about ad nauseum
you you're so valuable for the community
and for making sure that we do continue
to grow as a whole that that's why I
have this podcast that's why I want to
get people on here like yourself and get
these stories told and get this
information out there because now people
can reach out to you knowing that you
have this background and you know I keep
saying it we got to get back into
another episode to talk more about your
homeg growing because some of the things
that I do like to impart the information
of is you know pitfalls for hom Growers
what you can teach new Growers um where
you found success in your home grow and
failures in your home grow and how you
learned from that and those are all
typically things that I touch on but
we're already kind of budding up on
where I feel like this would be a good
ending place so I'm going to actually
just kind of reain it in really quick
and wrap it up with a a few rapid fire
questions that are always really fun to
hear from someone like yourself you're
you know you're a professional operating
at a high level within the Cannabis
industry but you still love cannabis so
what's your favorite Str of all time oh
man that's I knew that was coming too I
knew
it if if I got the and this my older
brother's friend long long time I
haven't seen it since man The Afghani
and Northern life set he was bringing me
it was just insane was that the afgh the
Afghan and um and he had he brought
Afghan and Northern Lights and those
were just grown to
Perfection um other than that there's
that I've been working on that um
they're just phenomenal because I'm
breeding them kind of for me but also as
a parental line for you know large
flowers and some of these things but
it's uh masar blueberry that I worked
for a while wow DJ shorts blueberry and
then a chem 91 a bunch of chem 91 lines
and Crosses uh chem 91 Skywalker OG I've
grew for a while and then cross those to
get hybrid Vigor and um some of those
are just unbelievable man um wow we
actually short on in a in a week or two
what dude I got some F5 blueberry oh
that's awesome man
Legend yeah it's such a tight-knit
community that it's really interesting
to see how quickly uh things can happen
when you connect with one person and how
closely they might be tied to someone
else that you've connected with and
you're like like it's amazing 5 degrees
of separation is almost it's only like
two or three in the Cannabis industry
it's really it's really fascinating I
usually hide in behind the scenes I go
about lowkey high-tech CU I just stay in
the shadows just doing you know whatever
but um after talking to you I was like
man this like I want to be a part of
this because that like we discussed on
the phone it's just like um I want to
use my my abilities in exchange
knowledge and help support and because
it changed my life you know and
hopefully I can at least Inspire and um
could just change the direction of uh
somebody's path or build into something
much bigger which um that's that's
fantastic so that's awesome well so
favorite strain sounds like you got a
few uh one from back in the day after
light your buddy grew you got some ones
that you're working on now um and so the
next question of course is who's your
favorite breeder of all
time uh
that
is well I have favorite breeders for
different reasons like some of these
Kentucky guys they'll just kind of like
smell the wind you know and they're like
it's going to be a good crap like those
guys because they have some stuff that's
like doesn't even have a name they're
like it's just weed like man this is the
best weed I've ever seen and I just love
the I love that style they pick what's
they select what's best to them and
their family and there's so much meaning
behind that um then other breeders I
don't know man it's because I have I've
had such a huge collection for so long
that I've just I have my own breeding
lines and stuff
but you I would say like some of the old
subcool
stuff was really exciting just like the
tur the profile like Vortex and some of
these that I used to get back in the
day um and I had some of his collection
left too that I need to pop you're the
second person to say his his Vortex oh
vort the the baby poop smells oh
man other than that I mean there's a lot
of talented breeders that are breeding
for you know the way like with the I
just picture them as isolated
populations almost and I feel like a lot
of that is just bottlenecked and
being changed you know and that's
something I have some really crazy like
different genetics that maybe we could
collab and start you know expanding the
gene pool to get more unique things and
stuff like that but there's just a ton
of I can't even keep up with them these
days I'm just in the lab just focusing
on what I'm doing most of the time I
feel that and I you know the guys are
just making their own crosses because
they're passionate I I would say that's
well because that's where I started you
know like it's special to them and when
I'm able to smoke or grow that I think
that has the most meaning to me you know
it's not like a name or I don't care
about any of that I care about the
connection and the experience with the
people and the plants that that uh ties
it together you know it sounds like
you're a fan of anybody breeding uh with
passion and and an intent in mind rather
than a quick
Buck yeah let let's put some some
biotechnology and you know high level
stuff behind it and then like I said all
of a sudden like I'll you extract DNA
once you're like that's not that's not
that hard yeah and maybe they can have
uh some of the opportunities that I was
gifted you know just um but that's what
that's what I got into this that's why
what excited me and what I wanted to
pursue and it just evolved and I kept
going and learning and um I was only be
able able to do that because I was just
open and um
willing to learn you know and continue
learning so I wish that upon everybody
for sure all right well last question
what's your most memorable cannabis
related
experience oh
man there's uh I've lived a long life
canis
um the guy that brought over the Afghan
nor the lights right and my friend's GNA
hear this and just start rolling right
um do when you know we had the flat weed
like the you know just move this and so
he brought her this stuff I was like
that's not weed like that's just fake
like looks crazy um and loaded up a bong
I ripped it and then stood up I'm like
62 63 blood just rushed my head and I
like passed out almost broke a glass
table in
half that's like the the one that I will
never forget it was embarrassing but um
so that had to be cool back then I was
like younger I was like I'm fine yep I
mean there's so many memories along the
way though that I I'm sure I'll think of
man oh and I got I've totally passed out
from a gravity bong hit before just
going from the bucket standing up
hitting it and then just standing there
and being like I held this for too long
Boop oh man I was like all right well I
guess the the other one that sticks out
which is hilarious I mean we're in
Kentucky right we some
wild boys out there sure I went to pick
up weed from my uh my buddy and he's
still in my phone his aligator Mike so
go to you know open the door he had some
like lizards and stuff and we were like
walking back to his living room he's
like don't worry about Elvis man he's
chill I was like American alligator just
walking down the
hallway it's like what is going like 5et
long like what is going on here the fu
he's chill you running stuff like that
like all the time out there like this is
crazy this good it's still just another
Stoner experience right you're just
there to either pick up some weed or
smoke with a buddy or something that's
that's too funny yeah we're like
alligator Mike it was crazy man but yeah
so you know it brings people together
man it has um it's done a lot of good
things in my life and um I I'm just
sciencemed and I I went that direction
so that's how I try to get back you know
awesome dude there's some hilarious
stories along the way we can get into
some more on the next episode we can
even do like another little Roundup
anything else you want to touch on too
but uh yeah yeah we do a lot of breeding
stuff Advan thing like I um I love to
talk about it um just keep me keep me
wrangled in so I don't go too deep for
your listeners maybe I can just send
some pictures or just references
information to help people out too I
love love to do that
well Jesse it's been a pleasure thank
you so much for joining us today and
telling your story of how you got into
tissue culture some of your background
in the Cannabis industry and sort of
where you want to see things go from
here um you're an inspiration for a lot
of people that want to get into tissue
culture and are scientifically minded
but want to get into the Cannabis
industry and have seen some barriers to
entry due to the the stigma and
stipulations of what is required in the
Cannabis industry so again thank you so
much this has been awesome and I really
appreciate your time anytime yeah we
we'll do it again it's uh it's been a
been a pleasure I'm glad to be a part of
this so keep keep doing what you're
doing I think it'll help a lot of people
and and bring us bring us back together
so for sure hey that's the way we grow
that's that we'll talk soon