hello and welcome to another episode of
The Way We Grow podcast uh today our
guest is Jack or at Jack Greenock on
Instagram he is an author a hom grower a
breeder um he's also the host of the
growing with my fellow Growers podcast
um I am your host Nick wolf or mrwolf
grows on Instagram in Reddit and so Jack
how have you been lately it's it's been
kind of a while since we actually talked
in the DMS thoroughly it seems like
we've both been pretty busy in our in
our own world so like what's new with
you what's new in your grow World well
next up is uh Spartan gron project V
it's a Vortex F2 project that he made
from subcool's original Vortex f1s he
took two males and two females and he
kind of quote unquote open pollinated he
had a five pack and those were I think
the four that popped and so I got the F2
which he's calling project V and a lot
of people have been having a lot of
success with that I actually popped a
few of them in a batch of a bunch of
different genetics and then with travel
and stuff ended up having to not go
through with that grow but they were the
strongest in veg so my next run is going
to be purely just the project V and that
alone so I'm going to the regular seed
so hunt through some males and females
pick out the best females and grow those
out flower them out and see other go
nice Yeah we actually um just had
Spartan on a couple episodes Ago by the
time that years are yours is out he his
will have been out for like two weeks or
so um and uh we talked about his project
V and uh all the the effort that he's
put into that to to try and preserve
some of subcool's genetics because well
they're not being made anymore so um
having people like him do open
pollinations and stuff is so vital for
the community to be able to see some of
this work that's going to eventually go
away um but that's awesome to hear that
you're popping some of his uh uh project
v um it it sounds like from what he was
describing it that it has like a a
really like uh citrusy side and then a
really kind of nasty funky side to the
um to the different turpine profiles and
since it sounds like subcool mango and
baby diaper are some of the description
that's what he said like rotten mango
yeah I mean honestly that sounds really
good um I like mango I'm not sure so
much about the baby diaper but if it's
strong like some of the stronger stuff
out there chems and um even some of the
like skunks are ogs Afghans they might
not taste the best but they get you a
really strong high and so if you're
looking for the effect sometimes you
know a spoonful of sugar will make the
medicine go down you can take a nice
tasty dab or something after or eat
something tasty or drink something tasty
but uh sometimes the medicine I I look
at it first as a medical user and even
if somebody doesn't die in the case of
like the breeding work that I started
off with was vegan DOA or Dojo DNA he
every year never kept clones for 10
years so he would take his that's crazy
he'd get clones from like his buddies
like he got like a thin mint but then he
crossed it to some stuff that he Po from
seed and had kept over the years and
then each year cuz he was a sungrown
outdoor it was one season
just one no he had green houses but he
didn't dep and so it just be one thing
per season he always crossed his best
stuff together so you could look back at
like the crosses and you're like oh this
has all of that in it plus one other
thing and then this has all of that plus
one other thing and he never would take
it to like F2 or F3 so I was like just
to have more seeds of one of his uh
projects the buet punch I took it to F2
yeah ended up finding a bunch of really
cool stuff in there it's kind of a
grapey gassy there's some watermelon
subtle fenos in there if you hunt them
out T was actually the first one who
found the watermelon in the f2s but um
it's his stuff was always really good he
hooked me up with some other stuff
called spiked punch that I grew and I've
told the story but I got 13 males and
two females so like thank goodness I did
Sex testing uh yeah shout out to Farmer
Freeman that's my preferred sex testing
person but um I did Sex testing and that
run I also had funny enough from subcool
Chernobyl so I had two of the spiked
punch and one Chernobyl and the
Chernobyl was really really fire I love
that I wish I would have kept cuts of
all three of those but uh life goes on
and you either either still have se you
all have those stories yeah I think um
that being said there's so many seeds
getting back to like Spartan and what
I'm popping next after the project fees
I was thinking about doing some Brandon
Rus gear because his stuff's really fire
but I gotten it recently and I've got
some stuff that's from years ago and I
was just talking about how some of the
best stuff I've ever gotten is from the
community and usually that's cuz it's
fresh it's like made this year maybe a
few months ago maybe six three however
brand new you know as soon as it's dry
and packaged but I found vigorousness
and germination rates tend to be much
higher un fresher newer seed so I like
to at least do one seed run every year
myself like making more seed of
something that I enjoy and like sour 76
is one that I've had for a handful of
years and it's not getting any younger
so it's uh one of my great white buffalo
strains like one that I feel like got
away and um so I'm going to be growing
those out and f twoing that to look
through what is sour 76 I actually
haven't heard of that it was an
unreleased genetic from humbl seed
organization it was a tester and um it
was a c sour o so it was like a Calio
Sour Diesel cross
to Afghan 76 they call it Island Afghani
somebody got some seed sourced from 1976
in Afghanistan up in the mountain areas
cuz people he Afghani and they think or
Afghan and they think that's one strain
like it's a broad Lea no short squat no
there's like 11 16 I don't know how many
different regions in Afghanistan that
have long histories of cannabis bulk um
you know there's a bunch uh but there's
a great page Baba like is one of them
but a few Afghan selection I think is uh
probably the best place that has a
breakdown of a bunch of different uh
phenotypes and things like that for the
different Afghani regions but yeah I
just no I'm I'm done with my S but
they're not all just one train yeah um
like in the early 2000s I had ear always
heard of um people describing that there
were like three main varietals of
cannabis and I I don't even hear that
much anymore where people would describe
Indica sativa and afghanica and um I
feel like it is
like I I do feel as though like sativa
and Inda are a little bit misleading
because like sativa just means
cultivated Inda just means of India and
then of course like afghanica would just
mean of Afghanistan and to say you know
that there's only one sativa or one
Indica everyone would know that that's
you know not what they're talking about
so it seems um almost counterintuitive
for people to think that uh if somebody
says I have an Afghan strain that it's
just one thing um so yeah that
I go back and for the Paradigm of Indica
sativa because I understand like sativa
or sa ofam uh if people haven't seen
that sat satam or s a t i Vu M I might
be mispronouncing it but it's uh another
one of the ways that it's spelled it's
just the Latin uh way of saying like
you're saying cultivated and IND indicia
of India and afghanica um
so there I've even seen like people that
are like talking about like America
American like Str or whatever like
they're they've started sub because we
have got such a rich history now at this
point of cannabis breing in the US that
they subdivided it to that but some I
just pulled up the Afghan selection and
they have I'm probably going to
mispronounce these but uh Chim tall is
the bulk region baharak uh bakan which
is the Hindu Kush because they have the
Hindu Kush mountain range that goes
through Afghanistan if a few of those
other countries Chim tall which is Hash
State
daima um Kos
and col these are all different regions
of Afghanistan
Kos kushkak mesar the mazari Sharif is
pretty famous historically yeah um
pisher is another Hindu Kush
quar south or maybe kahar South and
rustam Kush and we've got schar and
sheon so sorry for my brutal
mispronunciations I've never been to
Afghanistan I had
was offered one opportunity my dad's
like oh do you want to go to Afghanistan
for this volleyball tournament I was
like yeah I want to go and he's like no
no you're not going it's not safe it's
kind of during the time where um like
now things are not the friendliest
unfortunately between the US and
Afghanistan relations so um you bring up
such a great point that there's so many
different varieties uh even in within
one country that uh it almost feels as
though as United States consumers we
sort of exotify it to try and make it
seem as though there's something more
special to it where it's just another
region of cannabis growing kind of like
we don't we don't overly hype grapes
grown in different regions of the world
now we like look at the wine and the
final product and say this is really
nice and I feel like with cannabis we're
we're looking at it and trying to
exotify these different cultures that it
it's a little uh UNC almost it feels
like to effect where it where it is
deserved cuz like if you look at like
Morocco Afghanistan India these places
have been and not to say that we haven't
in the US there's Native American tribes
I've mentioned the Hope mound builders
in the US there's cannabis THC resin in
their clay pipes so they were not only
growing it and cultivating it they're
smoking it in pipes just like stuff
you'd see today like little glass spoon
uh spoon piece or thing like that but
it's all over it's it's in Asia Africa
literally everywhere throughout the yeah
you know but like you're saying I think
sometimes we maybe get this even the
idea the term exotic or Zaza you know
call exotic got short Z and then zah
became Zaza but silly terminology aside
maybe we're just getting older or
whatever but the um reality is like
Afghani hash was popular for a reason
they made a lot of hash and it was
really good and it got exported same
with Morocco Moroccan hash is really
good uh the rift mountains are known and
like just like humble is in the Emerald
Triangle Menino um that whole area vegan
doas from up a little bit further north
uh I should say DOA DNA is his actual
like breeder account cu the vegan do is
more of his personal page but Doo DNA my
buddy Dan the guy that I work with uh in
making seeds he's up from delort
California Crescent City area he had a
train called Crescent City Kush it was
really fire his thing was um in the
early 2000s gas was just not available
you couldn't really get a good like
clone of like OG for cheap
or easily without paying 5 10 15 $20,000
or something crazy for like a cut or
like a flat of cuts and people held that
[ __ ] really tightly so when a little bit
of it got out there he was able to start
Crossing that into some of his stuff and
then made the gas available to like any
of his patients friends family whoever
wanted it and so um I try to you know
keep in that vein and make the stuff
available and I've given out plenty of
free seats the whole F2 you know I never
sold f2s I just s out as testers and had
for sure over 100 people grown so got a
lot of feedback interpretations on what
the different environments would produce
uh what different nutrient regimes will
produce what types of
stressors uh can and won't cause
problems so um seeing indoor outdoor
Greenhouse was really cool and all the
different concentrates people make with
it outside of the wheel things that I
normally would for sure I um you know
after hearing you talk for years about
the different breeding projects that
you've done and how you've been able to
get these seeds out to the community and
see all these different phenotypic
Expressions based on the different
environmental factors of each different
grow and each different uh Personal
Touch that every cultivator has it's
really cool you can really build like a
vast library of knowledge that you can
then boil down and distill into
something very useful for when you're
sending out uh seeds to people in terms
of what to expect and and how to um uh
kind of uh give give the best
information available uh for newer grow
newer Growers as well um and you know I
thought it was really a great point that
you brought up that like all of the all
of these different regions that we do
sort of try to exemplify into this
exotic uh terminology where a lot of it
is just like a a cultural tradition of
the area that has been something passed
from generation to generation and
usually when we uh encounter it we're
enjoying uh sort of this
um like the product of these different
cultures that have been developed over
um in some cases hundreds if not close
to a thousand or more years um you know
for sure I mean with the families in
like those regions we were talking about
it's definitely hundreds like they know
their great grandpa was doing it who
taught their grandpa who taught their
dad and their dad taught them and in a
lot of the cases they haven't changed
like their still using you know the same
coat manure or whatever it is to
fertilize with some of them are using
modern stuff from pesticides to
fertilizers which I do think uh changes
flavors and things like that and uh but
a lot of them have if you like see any
of the 24 regions that we went through
and listed from the Afghan uh selection
or Afghan selection or even like looking
at like India India is all not just one
strain like um I finally learned the
pronunciation after one of my listeners
on our podcast corrected me I was
calling it carala but it's k e r a l a
and it's carala carala somebody from
carala India messaged me and said hey
it's actually pronounced carala and I
looked into it and turn out they right
so we have listeners in Kerala India but
Kyle breeder the reason that we know
this is because Kyle was growing uh
seeds from carala and maybe he got them
from that listener I don't know that was
maybe something separate from my
interaction but he grew this and it was
like a crazy long plan I think it was
like 10 ft tall like he grit on the side
and like it went like around a 4x4 and
like up the walls and just it was just
like the most bananas thing it was like
super tall and linky and just never kept
turning the pot over to make sure like
drill a hole in the side theight
water that's crazy I mean I've heard
yeah plenty of stories like that where
you just get a uh something that's uh
not you're not used to Growing because
it just is um it's used to a different
environment based on the years of its uh
sort of bottlenecking and genetic
selection whether it be through like
local Horticultural practices that have
kind of uh curated this land race
species um or if it's even like a wild
population that has no human interaction
with it I feel like it you can just get
these crazy Expressions that if you put
it into a controlled environment setting
you're going to I mean it's it's just
like a new learning experience every
single time time right they can get like
30t tall in the wild with no help out
there and so crazy to uh give it
nutrients and and lighting and try and
contain it into a confined space is like
I I don't think he realized the fire he
was fighting and um I think a lot of
people say I want land race I want land
race because like you said there has
been a bottle necking of genetics
especially in like certain pools but
there are people out there that are
still traveling the world and hand
collecting the stuff and some some of
it's maybe tainted quote unquote because
people have traveled and given them
modern genetics and it's interlaced into
the pool so it's harder and harder to
find the truer land races but they still
are out there and eventually everything
reverts back to what is in the Natural
Area they only have so many other seats
and even if they Brad something into it
a lot of them don't necessarily love the
new stuff as much as they think they
might when they get it from some person
they see photos and smell it and smoke
it one time and they get a little strain
tolerant after they grow it themselves
and they're like this isn't actually as
good as the stuff we've grown here for
hundreds of years we just going to go
back to stuff we've been grown for
hundreds of years and we've got our
grandma's stash of it over here you know
and yeah I think there is a sort of Rose
Colored Glasses of thinking the old
stuff is always better but then
remembering that there's a reason that
people like DJ schw went through the
process of taking like his best land
races that he grew struggled to find
like any good ones in the bag seeds that
were being imported and then from the
fire that he found in there would make
it more manageable by Crossing it into
one another and then ultimately started
finding stuff like blueberry and flow
and kind of cool unique Expressions that
he could like you were standing with the
Velvet punch um him growing it out and
having sobody different people grow it
out or growing it out a larger scale you
get this feedback that shows you a lot
about the plant and how it expresses
especially when you're making your own
seeds and you're not worried like oh
should I pop 1 two 3 five and he's like
popping hundreds or thousands and things
like that at that scale you get to learn
a lot fast and you can see things that
maybe you would have never seen just you
would have ultimately just by the
numbers if you pop 10 at a time over and
over and over and over eventually you're
going to get to the hundreds and
thousands and you'll see those rare
things that maybe are one in 100 or more
but I think often there's stuff that's
like one in 16 and people only pop like
two or three and um if you just pop a
big enough that's what I learned when I
started making the Velvet punch 2 I had
a 1 in6 phenotype um that's a physical
morphological thing that I called the
Sawtooth you know had like a double
zigzag on the leaf those are so cool I
didn't realize it was exactly like 1 and
16 for a while but then like I
remembered back to my old science
learning and the little charts um little
punet squares punet squares yeah and I
was like oh wait that kind of makes I
thought it was one and 15 cuz I usually
popped 15 of a thing just for whatever
reason you know and um I think it was
because I had 15 cups to be honest with
you for sure and uh 15 cups like fit
into my little tray so I was like that's
how many seeds I can reasonably pop in
this little tiny veg space that I'm
using
and so um 15 was what ended up working
out for me or maybe I did 16 initially
and like one of them broke or got lost
or whatever and haven't been replac but
whatever the reason is um with larger
numbers I sent out 100 people at least
10 seeds usually you know 10 or more and
of that 100 people or it was over 100
people I sent seeds probably like 150
and like 100 grew them you know so and
of that 100 they grew like between some
grew all 10 some grew five some grew
three but like that puts up into the
thousands of seeds that were grown mhm
and I could just go through and kind of
map how many people got this expression
and it was like almost exactly 1 in 16
like within like 1% so wow it was pretty
fascinating honestly science is a
something that should be appreciated
real science that's done with rigor that
has testing and replicates um cuz
there's a lot of criticism and cynicism
for a good reason a lot of science does
replicate the gold standard of what
makes science good has no longer become
the gold standard it's like a wishful
thinking almost for some but um from the
world of and I'm from like a science
that's not necessarily even looked at as
like a hard science but I still consider
we need those gold standards we need to
have you're talking about psychology
right yeah yeah I mean even with that
it's almost more important because of
how um subjective all of the different
uh um approaches are and you have
with everything and you have to try and
uh account for every single variable so
that you can make it uh uh reproducible
um yeah it's it's it's one of the
reasons why like whenever I would um
make seeds and and test out my seeds
that I've made I would always hunt a
full pack because um that's I I try to
think like that's a representation of
what a customer would get um and if I
can't find something in a pack then I
didn't do do my job and if there's
problems within that pack then I didn't
do my job and I shouldn't be releasing
it and so like I've only ever released
like a couple packs of seeds because I
was I was never satisfied personally
after growing out plenty of other seeds
from other reputable breeders and
especially um in the cultivation space
that I'm in having access to all these
different um kind of elite Cuts or or
different genetics that are um the ones
that are desired within the market and a
lot of those are very stable and and
they you can push extremely high
electrical conductivity in your
irrigation and crazy dryb backs and
extremely high uh ppfd and extremely
high CO2 and uh Heats and colds and all
these different aspects of a grow that
in some cases if your genetics are just
a little bit finicky and they might want
to um throw an intersex trait here and
there if they if they run into a
stressor event um yeah you you just
can't really have that in a commercial
space and I was always kind of in my
breeding efforts thinking oh this will
like I would love to see this in a
commercial setting I would love to see
it get out to more than just one or two
Growers um you know and have it
available because I always personally
have considered cannabis like a medicine
and back in the 215 days when I was in
California um having access to like some
really nice strains and stuff and from
people that were really carrying like it
makes me think of like mad farmer up in
Humbolt and his lavender and stuff and
whenever you'd see that at a dispensary
in the Bay Area or something it was like
oh my God I need to get that it's going
to put me to sleep it's going to cure my
headaches it's going to make me hungry
it's going to do all these things that I
needed to do um and the consistency
behind it was so key due to just the
years and years and years of effort put
into something like that um it is a
major effort it's a labor of love really
is I kept the cherry pie for many years
because it was the one thing that was
helping me sleep and then when I found
that high CBN RSO was equally if not
more effective um that made me not so
diligent about holding that cut so
tightly and I gave it back to the person
who gave it to me thinking that they
would be able to keep it alive and they
ended up not keeping it alive for very
long so the Cherry Pie that I was
running for so long and love so much is
no longer um so a good reminder I guess
to if you really do love stuff to keep
it around there's like a couple that got
away from me and um some that's funny
that you were talking about is the idea
of kind of like and you didn't say it
this way but I think some people think
that there's like bulletproof genetics
or like Rock Solid stable and some stuff
is clearly more stable than others for
sure like anything with cookies in it is
going to be or chams or ogs stuff that
comes like be gets like right so if it
comes from her literally everything on
the market there's Herms in it right but
that being said you see stuff like
jealousy or whatever is run pretty hard
in the markets and wedding cakes and
things like that they're run and people
figure out in their system how to do it
and it feels Rock Solid and stable
because you'll see people run it for
years and years and years and not have
problems in their system indoors in a
hydroponic system under a certain type
of lighting in a certain type of
environment and then they get uh Canada
legalizes and then they get all these
Greenhouse Grows Right massive ass
unlimited square footage and they take
all these same cuts that are bulletproof
and they put them into those green
houses and they start herming they start
not yielding like they they don't even
look the same they don't smell the same
they are susceptible to molds and Mild
that maybe they didn't even know were
problems until they took it outdoors and
so sometimes there's what we think to be
a stable a rock solid genetic that gets
exposed when you put it in the hands of
hundreds or thousands or different of
environments I personally think
absolutely you can make any any cannabis
strain no matter how bulletproof Herm
one person I've heard vehemently defend
their strain is uh Rick from uh Mr soul
c99 of Brothers Grim he says L
Cinderella 99 will not Herm and subcool
notoriously said he would never release
stuff if it had Herm stuff in the DNA
but I could tell you if you go look
around on the forums enough under both
of those people you'll find Herms under
both of them and I think a lot of it
does come down to Growers have to be a
little bit accountable of what their
environment if you're growing outdoor
obviously you don't have as much control
but you have to like realize that there
are factors that can make a plant go
intersect I think outdoor is actually
more rare I think greenhouse and indoor
is where you're going to see the most
terms and for sure that's when we have
the most control and when we have the
most control we're most likely to
underestimate certain factors little
things light leaks um ambient lights
like uh red light or green light or even
a green headlamp people think that you
can wear a green headlamp in flower into
your flower room no you can't I'm sorry
I'm here to tell you don't do it no so
I'm going to push back on that just a
little bit just from my own personal
experience cuz we run green lights in
all of our rooms uh whenever we're
applying sprays or anything like that
and we don't have any any um interex uh
issues or anything that uh throws uh
late flower nanners or any po
pollination uh events um and I'll just
ask a followup question on that cuz um
to be specific like I know people that
have green lights in the room and
they're like older like CFL Wes or
softer lights they're hung up in a
certain way that they're not like
blasting the plant with these green
lights it's sort of a but do you have
like a modern LED green headlamp like
something that's uh you're wearing on
your head we we use um LED t5s um green
t5s that are at at an array across the
ceiling basically to provide light for
for movement through the through the
room in the dark um so what I would
avoid is the specifically these head
mounted lamps the old like a really old
one if it's like so soft that you can
barely even see that might be okay but
like I I got a newer one LEDs now I mean
your phone and I granted I used to do
this and I never had intersect but like
look at how much that's blowing out my
camera yeah I mean I usually go in there
with my my camera my phone on as well
it's it's blowing it up so much it's
like uh removing you from the uh the
rendering I got washed out of a frame
there and that's just like one single
Sam
LM 301 on the back of a galaxy whatever
yeah and a lot of these headlamps have
more than that and um even like another
single source of light I have right here
it's another single uh chip that one
completely wases me out it's just a
little flashlight that's uh handheld can
fit you know it's a little bit thick but
takes a doublea AAA or cr123 and
something like that would definitely
definitely make your plants break their
uh Scotto period and for sure that dark
cycle I think bug's research has been
showing that something like
z.0 like like less than one par is able
to be detected by the plants and not to
say that's one to her the plant
necessarily but they're noticing those
changes and Pitch Black is ideal for
sure and um absolutely the one thing the
exception is with fure spray is cuz like
certain stuff you don't want to spray
under intense light so if you're GR R
lights are intense which they should be
you don't want to burn your plants and
so if you're not like in a place where
outdoor you can kind of do it early
morning or late evening and get away
with it but middle of the day you're
going to fry your plant just like you
would if you did it under your grow
light and so there are those
considerations and a lot of plants maybe
they've been exposed to green light over
the years and I don't know why that
green would be less because if you look
at a spectral graph of the par chart
Green is right smack daab in the [ __ ]
middle it's not like green doesn't
photosynthesize like it I I get that it
reflects some green cuz that's what our
eyes see and that means that essentially
that's going to be the least taken up
color but there's been studies that show
like green penetrates deeper and things
like that so it
has I think I personally believe that it
has a usage in the growth process and so
that makes me a little bit concerned in
terms of and this is just to new Growers
out there trying to eliminate as many
possible things not to say like there
are aren't bulletproof strains that
can't get away with it cuz I know people
that have had light leaks in their tent
with a a grow light in the next tent cuz
they like leave one flap open and
normally they'd have a situation where
that when the lights come on they Clos
the one and but they went out of town
and then the person didn't take care of
the situation type thing and like half
the strains in the room hered but then
half of them didn't so it shows that
some stuff is more bulletproof than
others in terms of light leaks during
the dark period but in terms of trying
to whenever I see a intersect trait I I
haven't actually in micro which I'm
fortunate because I try to to the most
of my ability eliminate any possible
cause overwatering underwatering root
binding um high heat really low humidity
really high humidity um interrupting the
dark cycle consistently during flower
and just too much stress like if you
break the plant like apart completely
like not just like supercropping like
some people really or like a windstorm
and things like that might come that
might be a time you could see herming
Outdoors but uh generally if you avoid
quote unquote the common stressors the
things that will make a plant Herm which
sometimes new Growers don't even know to
avoid some of these pitfalls right they
their plant gets root bound because they
just kept it in that pot and didn't
realize because they watch a bunch of
Instagram posts where people pull their
thing out and it's just Roots wrapped
all the way around and they're like that
looks cool like I want my PL to do that
so they wait until that happens to
transplant and maybe they're male
pollinates in in a veg that's another
thing people want to talk about male
plants can start throwing pollen while
they're basically seedlinks a few in
tall if you keep them you get the the
bra at the inner nodes pollinated that
way I've seen that I've seen yeah people
are like my plants already seed I'm not
even in
flour it happens seeds off of there good
to go the funny thing is if you put it
into flour like it won't the rest of the
plant won't be seated unless it
continues to receive pollen but um I
know some people that actually they use
that as like a strategy they vge their
stuff super long until it shows sex
they'll pollinate it to get like 5 six
10 however many seeds and then they'll
bring it into flour and they kind of get
a little bit of both I personally don't
think seated bud is as bad as people
make it out to be we all remember it
being bad because it was like Mexican
brick weed that was imported and garbage
and lost El stirping and was probably
sprayed with who knows what and grown
with not the best methodologies and uh
you know it's not the same as hom grown
if you grow your own seed it even like
indoor outdoor Greenhouse doesn't matter
um it's going to be it's an
inconvenience to break up the buds it's
great for dry sift though I mean you got
to break all the you got to shuck all
those seeds anyway so if you're just
making dry sift out of that and your
little trim bin or whatever you got sit
there with a couple of shows on and you
won't even know that it's that you're
doing anything and then after a while
you got grams and grams of uh of ke
either to press just top your bowls and
yeah beautiful golden ke and it it
smokes great you can even like press if
you get clean it up with static deck
that stuff is like dabbable you can
press out the flags but um I've I've
seen like
um uh some people talk about how like
they'll get different tarpine profiles
on the seed plant versus the unseated
plant just you know the plants yeah it's
immune response or whatever to protect
itself even more and I I always find
that super fascinating like one thing I
always notice is if it's a citrusy
leaning mom then it just gets really
really pungent when when it's uh when
it's seated and I'm like well there you
go you got great hash makings there
right right away I almost wondered that
with the Velvet punch that's what made
me grow out multiple runs a stress test
and then like non-seed runs where I just
grew it for
flour because I wanted to make sure uh
I'd have accurate descriptions of what
people are going to get when they're
going to grow it out themselves because
most people aren't making seed and I was
actually so blown away by the seed run
that like some of the elements in there
um I wanted to ensure that they were
still within the phenotypes in f2s and
f3s and sure enough those were what I
was selecting for um but and it was
there to start like to give credit like
the mother of that is a purple punch
which a lot of people say purple punch
list blah blah blah grow it yourself and
take it to n or 10 weeks and it it's
definitely got a strong high if you take
it 10 weeks most people aren't willing
to take a plant 70 days um and I'm not
saying that you have to 63 I think is
solid but 70 I think a lot of strains
are just better it's like cherry pie was
another one if you take it um the guy
who gave it to me also named Jack he was
uh you know I'm not going to say where
he's from actually he was polish so I'll
[ __ ] say I don't give a [ __ ] polish
Jack uh for the story sake he gave me
the Cherry Pie initially and um he's
like it's good at 9 weeks but it's
really good at 10 weeks so sure enough
first time I grew it I took it 10 weeks
and godamn if he wasn't right it was
[ __ ] fire I actually never ended up
growing it N9 weeks because it was so
good at the 10 that I was just like I'm
always going to take it a 10 so I think
sometimes it's worth the extra sometimes
you don't have the you know Le and the
other thing is there's personal
preference I think um velvet punch if
you take it at 10 weeks it's going to be
Daner and gassier then if you take it at
8 weeks or nine weeks it's going to be
fruer you won't get as stoned but it'll
taste better and it might even look a
little bit um it depends on like what
your grow is like sometimes people in
the later stages of flower their plants
start to look a little bit rough um
they're fading them out with nutrient
and that can lead to necrosis and other
things that are unintended that aren't
just the actual fall fade um it's more
of a you know they're they're flushing
it and it doesn't have access to
nutrients and it's it's starving so some
people starve the plant and I actually
personally do think starving it is a
there's going to be a benefit in the
Smoke it'll smoke smoother in my opinion
I know a lot of people argue that the
flush doesn't work and yada yada and the
um fade will happen without a flush and
like a organic soil whatever it's going
to happen um I'm blanking on the name
right now so I got a little stoned off
my Bon sence sence there we go that's
the term yeah where you start to see the
antoin and uh carotenoids start to show
you get those purples and reds and pinks
and even the yellows and things like
that um can be part of the inessence
process so every strain is a little
different I had like a rosta flag one
one time it was like I had like you know
the red yellow and green just as it was
fading it was uh interesting just to see
like the different but um I will say
that purples can go into black but a lot
of people don't realize uh greens can go
to Black some of the talking about
Afghan earlier some of that stuff will
get black but it never goes purple it's
just green green green and then it like
that like vibrant purple it it just yeah
goes straight to almost like Lack of
Color um yeah I've definitely seen that
as well especially Outdoors um when you
get those like uh late October harvests
uh early September harvests you can
really start to see those colors come
out depending on where you are in the um
in the world if you're a little bit
higher up on the latitude then yeah I've
seen it happen pretty quickly um like
within a week almost it goes from green
to completely black um you know and so
I'm going to steer the conversation a
little bit back to a few of these
questions that I have cuz we've just
been riffing here and I love it and it's
been great flow so far um but I I do
want to find out what was your first
experience growing and it doesn't even
have to be with cannabis like what is
your first memory of uh growing a plant
and uh starting your journey as a as a
grower
overall my first one is going to be kind
of comical because uh I wasn't the
grower and that was the case with the
first several Growers right cuz I was a
kid um and this wasn't cannabis it was
uh Tomatoes my nextdoor neighbor uh
venzo he was a cool dude but they grew
their own tomatoes for their pasta sauce
and uh his wife would hom make pasta
sauce and pasta and things like that
when I was a kid he gave me a BB gun to
sit on the back porch and they had a
little fence around their tomato garden
and he hung a soda can or pop can that's
what we would call it in the midwest at
the time um just like a little aluminum
can on the top of a stick and squirrels
were a big problem in our area the
squirrels would come and eat his
tomatoes and he didn't want to eat the
squirrel cuz it's not necessarily some
people like it he didn't like it
necessarily but I'm not saying it's bad
eating or good eating but neither here
that were there this was my first lesson
in IPM we integrated Petman so I'm going
to go way back to the start hire a
5-year-old hire a young boy with a BB
gun who's highly motivated to go out
there and he said I'll give you a nickel
for every you know this this wasn't like
that long ago so nickel wasn't much but
I was just young and dumbb and having
fun more with the B gun I didn't care
about the Nickels you know but uh
squirrel would come up and try to eat
his uh tomatoes and I'd shoot that can
and make a loud ping and the squirrel
would
[ __ ] go crazy and jump off the fence
or jump to the next tree and just run
away and so that was my first experience
with growing as far as I can actually
remember um my parents and family were
not gardeners we had like a tree in my
front yard just like random [ __ ] um but
other than maybe like some berries that
were on a city Planet Tree on the
sidewalk like nothing actually grew in
where I was at we were into sports and
didn't necessarily have the time that
was dedicated to the garden and so for
me the first thing that I actually
participated in the growth of was
Cannabis and that was when I was a
teenager started smoking in Middle
School my Brother started dealing he was
a couple years older than me and uh
eventually I figured out where it was
coming from through the chain I just
went up the source and uh there was
actually a couple local grows just like
happens now um in random neighborhoods
they'd have people with grow setups and
uh I ended up kind of asking like can I
help like in some way just to like get a
joint to here and there like I didn't
even want payment I just wanted to smoke
cuz I was smoking so much of my
brother's stuff and uh I was like I just
want to not have to pester him for
something he's selling and making money
off of so I ended up thankfully it was a
friend through football um so I don't
think I would have ever gotten into the
grow situation because there was at the
time cannabis was selling for like six
or 77,000 a pound we're talking early
2000s and in the Cleveland area so yeah
it was yeah definitely I forgot that
you're from Ohio uh yeah it was born and
raised definitely was pricey pricey
stuff there at that time so considering
that the crew that I was working with
all they cared about was getting six a
pound and two a light we had 600 watt
lights they're HPS we ran a reverse dwc
system it was a DIY System Home Depot
buckets with uh reverse or recirculating
it was like uh recirculating yeah but
like they they would go from like one to
the next to the next to the next uh
already done recirculating whatever but
this and like I said I was just a water
boy at the time and uh basically my job
was to sweep up the leaves that were
pruned off and then to take the little
blue lab trench in stick it in to the
buckets and make sure that they were all
the right EC and uh pH so I go through
to verify that the reservoir was
matching up to each plant and make sure
that the reservoirs had water because
sometimes they're with DIY systems weird
[ __ ] would happen like it would leak or
crack or whatever so you'd have to
replace a bucket here and there or you
know uh figure it out what was making oh
there's a tube that's clogged you know
and figure out why is it clogged how do
we get it unclogged but in that process
sort of just being around the plants
learning like uh oh well the EC is low
and they start to look like this or the
EC's high and they start to look like
this as here constantly so even though I
was just a water boy I got a lot of
experience in just seeing what a healthy
plant's supposed to look like and you
know how to kind of be around a grow uh
unfortunately you know bad things
happened there and uh the person who ran
the operation got taken out by
competition and I won't get too much
into the details but there was like
crime scene tape when I showed up one
day and just uh unfortunately was never
able to go back to that operation and a
couple years later I was able to go to
California for college and when I was in
California I met well my freshman
roommate actually I was randomly
assigned to live with he started growing
weed in the window sill of our dorm and
uh he just had a literally he was
selling weed and it's funny because like
there's a history of this in my family
apparently cuz my mom when she was in
college her roommate she told me this
like long before like one of the reasons
she's like oh I I don't smoke weed it
makes me paranoid my roommate in college
grew it on my window sale blah blah blah
and I was like that seemed like such a
you know hokey hook story and then sure
enough got college and uh you know same
thing happened to me but I didn't mind
we I loved cannabis at that time I've
been smoking since I was you know young
teen and played football had lots of
injuries and didn't didn't even realize
I was self-medicating for head injuries
and bodily injuries and things like that
even psychological stuff but getting
back to the grow side of things um when
I moved out here my roommate who grew he
he sold and he had found a seed in one
of the better bags he's like well this
[ __ ] was fire so I want to try and grow
this out and so he got a Starbucks paper
cup and filled it with soil from our
little flower beds in the dormatory and
put it in there watered it sure enough
it germinated and it was like the last
month we were living there so it stayed
in that cup for less than a month we
moved out to a little apartment and we
were the very last one thankfully and uh
maybe we even chose it because of this
but it was like all the way at the end
of the parking row and like we were the
last two spots so nobody else would
really even get too close to where we
were at and and then it went around
there was like a fenced in area and a
little grass patch and so we just had
like a nice sunny grassy patch there
that was kind of private and so he just
threw it in a pot got some soil and this
thing ended up grown like 6 and 1 half 7
ft didn't know what it was we called it
sweet skunk cuz it was sweet and skunky
and uh man it was it kind of got us off
on Off to the Races looked into the
medical U licensing got our medical
cards and one of his friends cuz he was
from this area I'm not um his dad had
property and so we set up a grow at his
property and we dug like trenches next
to the fence because we're like these
things are going to get tall man they're
going to be as tall as your fence or
higher cuz we're going to do it right
and we did we set him up and killed it
there and ended up finding even more
local spot and got into doing to be
honest while we were doing this my buddy
who was selling was more into it than me
so he was learning all the stuff I was
just like along for the ride you know
labor sure and um he got into like
Organics and Korean natural farming and
things like that so I was learning about
like m your CHS techniques and things
like that and so I got into Organics
Organics is cool like [ __ ] it tastes
good easy to do in terms of uh once you
get it set up and rolling uh it seems
simple basically water only at a certain
point and you can have certain inputs
here and there to you know supplement so
he got me into that side of things but
um we went through college graduated and
unfortunately like we had a home Breakin
and so a couple of my roommates and and
myself admittedly like got SC like some
guy broke into our house with a gun and
uh so thankfully we all survived um
pulled a fake gun on that my roommate
had a BB gun and uh thankfully it was
like painted black and Y get the [ __ ]
out of my house type thing and the dude
did but we didn't realize like he jumped
out the window that he came in and so we
thought he was still in the house they
like come to my door and I'm like locked
in my room whatever I was actually
studying and they're like somebody's in
the house with a gun like call 911 we
can't find our phone it's like is all
right I'm [ __ ] call 911 they hand me
this fake gun and I'm like pretending
I'm the phone with 911 like I have a gun
if somebody comes up these stairs I'm
going to shoot him so like if the
person's in the house that they're
hopefully not incentivized to come up
the stairs and uh it was all Bluff but
definitely I won't get into the gun side
of things but learned from that
situation to not have fake guns to be
prepared for uh home invasions and I'll
leave it at that but uh never be caught
with my pants down like that ever again
literally I was Stark ass naked I was
going to bed at the time I slept naked
and my roommate's girlfriend was one
pounded on the door and like and it was
such a weird night like the cops came
over I think our house got cased because
like the cops came over like 2 hours
before it happened and said that they
were looking for a missing person and
like there was no missing person at the
house it was like a madeup person so I
think the person who broke into our
house made it look like we were like the
boy who cried wolf kind of thing cuz
they the cops were just out there we
don't want to come back out there but it
was like for an armed robbery so they
end up coming like 15 minutes later
nobody was there but thank to their
credit uh s or whoever it was uh they
cleared the area and and no one was in
the house and no one was outside the
house so and a few weeks later that
person got busted breaking into somebody
else's house who held him up with a
shotgun and wait till the cops got there
so damn yeah doing the same [ __ ] they
got arrested
so but that ultimately it leads back to
the grow I'm [ __ ] feel a little but
like somebody doing the weave over here
but
the ultimate point of that story was the
guy that I was growing with outdoor um
my other two roommates to turn their
back they weren't weak guys and they're
like we can't live with this guy it's
too dangerous blah BL blah blah and I
was like okay I just graduated I got my
first professional job in uh you know
the space that I'm working in I you know
provide services to special needs
individuals autism through py and I was
like okay well I just graduated college
maybe I can move out of my college house
like move into like they're like we're
going to go tour this apartment complex
and it was more professional blah blah
but I go and tour it and it was only
like a three-person place and like there
wasn't a spot for this fourth guy and
and um I just thought oh I'm going to
tour the place and then when I got there
they're like this is the last one we've
got like three more people touring if
you don't sign right now like you're not
going to get a spot and where we're at
admittedly it's hard to find places to
live that are decent and um so I made
the mistake of kind of getting pressure
tactic into signing my lease and
unfortunately didn't realize I kind of
signed the death note of that
relationship with a guy that I really am
sad that I'm not still connected with so
it's my homie Zach zigzac I don't know
if he'll ever hear this but I need to
[ __ ] reach out to him it's uh and
that that was the guy that you had like
uh started growing with your your
roommate in college and stuff yeah yeah
genuinely like it it hurts man like I've
been there actually like emotional like
thinking about it I'm like man he was a
cool ass dude and um he married the girl
[ __ ] I introduced him to our freshman
here so and I told him because of sit I
was like you better like if you're going
to cuz she was a really good person I
was like if you're going to do what
you're going to do like you better
[ __ ] marry this person cuz she's
great person and so I'm happy for both
of them and they're little child they
just had so I'm happy that we're friends
on Facebook or whatever so I see them
from afar and uh I'm just happy to see
that he's doing well and that being said
like
I'm really like close friends with other
people that I didn't have falling outs
with like that that I haven't kept in
touch just because so busy with work and
life and things like that it's just how
things go you know it's uh hard enough
to uh just you know get everything uh
taken care of you know so I've always
heard growing up means growing apart in
a lot of ways um you know it's just you
move or you you change your your
schedules and you know what was a a 420
hangout sesh before becomes like hey man
I might have 30 minutes at 9:30 at night
and everyone's like I'm going to be
tucked in a bed I'm up at 4:00 a.m. for
work so I know man I learned that young
thankfully cuz like my one buddy he
moved to uh just one town over and like
we had just gotten our licenses like we
loved to drive 15-minute Drive was
nothing and like I was in Ohio and I was
like we're going to hang out all the
time and like he got new friends like
they they' hang out with the new friends
and like this was my best friend from
like you know kindergarten through
however long and um it's and we were
still friendly you know from afar but
it's just like the effort it takes to
even my like my family like my dad when
he moved an hour south for work and
stuff like that like we'd only see his
family on holidays like Thanksgiving and
Christmas type thing and it's just um I
moved obviously far away from my family
I 5 hour flight at the minimum and um
it's funny cuz like I could see him just
as much as I would if I moved 1 hour
south in Ohio you know so it's it's
really uh we get busy and that's one of
the things that makes growing so
difficult but the I guess ultimate point
of what I wanted to focus the most on
the show which is what I haven't even
gotten to yet which is uh the girls that
I'm most proud of I guess are the ones
that I did myself and a lot of people
yeah let's [ __ ] on them let's go that
homeow cuz like so far you've been
talking kind of about how you've like
were introduced to seeing cannabis
growing and um you know your your very
first introduction into being the water
boy and the leaf boy and and going
through and kind of just uh kind of
being the Gopher of just of getting
getting what needs to be got done
without being given sort of the formal
education of what uh or why you do
certain things so when did you start to
dive into um like either as a homeg
grower uh like kind of being more intent
on uh your processes or uh did you end
up finding more of a um commercial or uh
or another like working with people that
were producing for the medical or wreck
market so when I like I had like I said
I had the falling out so going from
there I guess later on I personally
moved away for grad school to Florida
and then I moved back here so kind of
even lost more touch with a lot of
people um and when I moved back here
there happened to be a Hydra store right
down my street and I was working at a
delivery service for a little while I
saw the guy at the delivery service
growing in his own like in his closet
just like or like on a balcony like a
couple plants here and there just from
seeds that he got from uh bags that we
were selling and he was doing it organic
but um he didn't really he was doing
some of the techniques my other bu had
done before KF type stuff but he wasn't
having as much success just red little
plants and it was good smoke but it was
like you know 1ot tall plant by one foot
wide type thing and um nothing as quite
as impressive as what I was used to
seeing in High Times growing up and all
that stuff so I wanted to like figure
out a system that I could grow like a
pretty good looking healthy plant in a
small space and I found like these space
bucket type things where you could do
like Home Depot buckets or like totes
like stacked up like do lighting all
around it but my wife uh graciously
offered one of the closets in our very
small space we don't have a whole bunch
of square footage 400 square feet out
here we're very very very close to the
ocean so like don't feel sorry for me
living in a tiny house I'm very happy
iose chose this lifestyle so SoCal near
the ocean 400 squ ft is not that bad I
was I was 400 square ft in Portland
Oregon for a little while and um you
know in the dead of winter that just
gets to
be I'm bundled up here so you know I
totally I can I can relate cuz being
from Ohio cold is cold and uh it's not
fun being cold and she sacrificed this
one closet cuz like it was kind of a you
know borderline of being necessary for
her it was lightly being used and I told
her about my experience growing with
like my buddies and stuff like that and
medical licenses are like a diamond
dozen out here you can really easily get
your in the 215 days you you know just
grow and so I was like well I'll go talk
to the doctor again get my license
updated I did got my license and I was
like all right let's Get Growing got a
tent that literally fit the exact
dimensions of the closet like it is I
had to take out the inner moldings of
the closet like there's like a crown
molding on the door panel that shuts
into it and I had to like pull those off
so that like the frames could fit and
even then like the top frame didn't
quite fit so I built a wooden structure
and uh is it like a one of those
dimensions that's not an actual foot by
foot Dimension it's like 20 in by 18 in
or something weird like that it's 3T by
1 and 1/2 ft yeah it's like the weirdest
it's not exactly 1 and half it's like
one and like it's definitely a is it
exactly 36 in across or is it like 32 or
something it's 36 wide I think okay and
then it's
um it's like just over one and a half so
12 okay I could look up the thing on my
Amazon purchase from wherever no it's
fine I I feel like there's a standard
closet size for like small closets like
that because I got a tent from a buddy
when I was first getting into this and I
was like this is the weirdest dimensions
for a tent when everything else that you
see online is like within like you know
TW like multiples of 12 Ines on on
either you know depth width height all
these different things um and I was just
like why would anybody want a tent this
size and then I I moved and I I saw in a
in like one of my moves that this frame
fit perfectly into a closet and I was
like what is what is going on how did
they even figure this out so there yeah
there must be a standard closet size I
love it man it's a 36 by 20 in x 62 in
so it's like 5 ft tall 3 ft wide and
like 2 and 1/2 ft deep it's like if you
reached your arm into like a a coat
closet it it's going to like hit the
back you know like your arm is probably
going to be longer than the tent so it's
nice cuz I can reach all the way across
and get to the back of the plants and
it's enough space like I've had as many
as six plants in there I work out with
uh two in there now in an earth box but
I was when I got started doing Coco
because there was a Hydra store I could
hit it with a base like if I threw a
baseball from my house I could hit it it
was so close and um so I ended up going
in there and just getting some basic
stuff to get set up and what they were
put at the time and like many hydro
stores and many places rightfully do I
think Coco Co is a good media and it's
simple enough to get
started I met some of the guys who
worked there and one of them's like a
real old OG and uh he kind of took me
under his wing a little bit and I was
just like what do you use like how do
you do it and I kind of got all the same
stuff that he did and just kind of do
exactly what he did to try and have
success I bought way too much light for
my space it was a 3X3 light I got had a
3X 1 and a half right so I was over lit
to start with a a ceramic metal highight
315 C I had like a little super sprouter
bulb and a you know a dome or whatever
so I germinate with that get him going
for a little bit and then I'd put them
under the CM and push it all the way to
the top of the tent and then gradually
they'd grow up towards it and like lower
it down fairly quickly switched to an
LED that was appropriately spaced uh or
sized for my space there was a local
company called Timber grow lights
they're now called High Grove LEDs um
they don't make a LED that's small
enough for my space anymore but they now
do like bar LEDs and stuff like that but
I can't speak to the quality of those I
will say that the cob style that I got
from them is still running strong like
years later so it's how many years do
you think you've been running it it's
like I think five or six years now I
think I got it in 2019 and dude it still
pulls two grams a watt so like that's
great for new Growers to know I mean cuz
cobs are one of those things also that
run pretty hot and you can see that uh
some people have failures on those but
if it's built well and it's running for
Years it'll run another 10 dude the the
um it's like aircraft aluminum but the
the heat sinks are like it looks like
giant hedgehogs off the back like
they're these thick metal rods coming up
and my exhaust fan is right next to
where the light is hung so a lot of that
heat from the driver from the uh cobs it
just drifts right from the top of the
light out of the tent where with the
ceramic metal H the way that it was
cased that metal casing and then that
light it was a reflector right it throw
throws all that light but also heat down
so it would throw it down onto the
plants and then get pushed up and then
cycled out where the he you can barely
even feel it when you put your hand
under the LEDs even a cob that's pretty
intense a few inches away if you went by
that metric you'd burn the crap out of
your plants cuz there's way too much
light getting to where it feels hot and
so I found a migro has a little uh video
where he found this doggo uh apps is
what it's called a lux light meter and
he did a side-by-side comparison with
like a $300 light meter and then and he
did a graph like all right so you
basically just do like times 10 and it
gives you your exact par from the Lux or
whatever or divide by 10 or whatever it
is and um so I never ended up buying a
light meter and I've used that and it's
worked fantastically in terms of knowing
how much light I'm giving to the plants
and uh so that's kind of where I'm at in
terms of like gear and growing but I
started like I mentioned in Coco and um
that kind of OG took me under his wing
and I learned a lot I started in like
three gallon pots and uh I vegged two
blue dreams for way too long they showed
sex because that's how we used to do it
when I was growing Afghani under HPS and
like I just was I reverted back to like
what did I do when I was indoor it's
like okay we vegged them as big as they
could get right they started showing sex
and they were clones right CU that was a
different system I was averting sort of
my old ways set me up for not success in
a little bit of a metric because with
the HPS you could grow clones they show
pistols relatively quick they're they're
old clones they've been around for a
long time they're sexually mature yeah
they'll show pistols and veg almost
always uh especially the one that we
were running this afghan that was so old
and tired we've been running for years
but um it was an AK-47 they called it
but it wasn't the AK-47 from Syria seeds
it was an Afghan Kush that flowered in
47 days from like Afghanistan like the
Kush mountains but um and it had like
little baseball bat colas and it was
just like a super narcotic eye but um
going back to like my girl I was like I
loved blue dreams I was like well if I'm
going to start my own home grow might as
well give myself my favorite strain like
one of my favorite strains blue dream
and so I got some blue dream and uh it
was seeds but the seeds were from Humble
seed organization and admittedly they
are honest about what it was it was a
feminized Cross of DJ shorts blueberry
to Shanti Baba from Mr Nice Seed
company's Super Silver Haze and for
those who don't know Blue Dream is a
Santa Cruz Haze cross to DJ Schwarz
blueberry Santa Cruz Haze is pretty
similar to Super Silver Haz and there's
even some that speculate it might just
be a super silver um I can't verify I do
think Santa Cruz Haze might be its own
thing I do think the Blue Dream cut the
Santa Cruz Blue Dream cut is like
special and it is my favorite one of my
favorites if not my favorite like that's
what people made their fortunes off of
oh yeah it was a yeah I mean 10 12
pounder Outdoors for a lot of people so
it was a huge yielder um it was kind of
like purple punch because like once
something gets super popular it also
becomes super unpopular because a lot of
people get their hands on it or say that
they have their hands on it they grow it
out grow up poorly and harvest it early
and then sell it to the market and
people are like oh Blue Dream sucks I
can't even get high out and it doesn't
even taste good it's like well you you
got it from the guy who was doing it for
cash not the guy who did it because he
loved it and because he wants the dankus
weed and happens to make some money on
it um but that point aside getting back
to the grow the blue dream that I vegged
I think 60 days in Coco got them in like
three gallon pots by the flower and uh
like I said I'm in a 5ot tall tent so uh
those things I put like Tris netting up
thank y because it bursted through that
first the first trtic didn't do anything
second trtic didn't do anything third I
set up a third layer and I like cut out
the first layer set up a fourth layer
and like I just kept trellising it and
kept bending it over because the plant
just got so out of control it filled
every square inch it was a crazy harvest
the bud didn't look great at all it
tasted amazing so like I made a ton of
hash I still have hash from that [ __ ]
run in my freezer oh my God yeah this is
7-year-old Blue Dream hash and it I like
it cuz I have arthritis my hands shake
and if I smoke two or three hits of that
specific Blue Dream my hands just go
Stone Cold still so if I ever need to do
fine work like for whatever reason with
my hands then I'll pull some of that out
of the freezer and take a couple hits
and I realized if I take less than two
or three it doesn't work and if I take
more than two or three I start to shake
even more again so it's kind of a weird
just H getting into the medical set of
things realize people there is a a
magical dose out there that can be the
ideal dose sometimes it's too much and
sometimes it's too little so experiment
I mean when it when it comes to shaking
specifically my father has essential
tremor which is um it's like similar to
Parkinson's but it's not lethal
um it but it does cause like a shaking
of like everything like his face will
shake his hands and arms will shake and
um some of the relief that he found
early on was using cannabis and it would
lower all of his shaking syndromes down
to a manageable amount you know like
where sometimes in the morning he would
pick up his coffee and like he'd get it
to here and then all of a sudden like
the coffee is everywhere whereas if he
had a little smoke in the morning he
could have his coffee kind of sit there
he'd be a little bit more relaxed and it
was really amazing to see the difference
between with and without cannabis in a
lot of cases especially when it comes to
something that is like a nerve related
um you know disorder of some kind or
just some some in general mine mine came
from arthritis I thought I had
Parkinson's I thought I had early onset
Parkinson's because when I moved to
Florida and didn't have access to the
same quality of I moved to California
and had a better access
to Medicinal cannabis selection that
I've ever had my entire life prior and
didn't realize I had arthritis in both
hands from basketball and football I
broke every finger and I'd also used to
Punch walls in Anger with you know
Brothers growing up the youngest of
three getting beat up on like take your
frustrations I my hands are beat to [ __ ]
so they Shake cuz I have osteoarthritis
I found later in life but I was
undiagnosed until like my late 20s and
when I tried the arthritis stuff it just
none of it worked well and it made me
feel sick so when I realized oh certain
cannabis like really helps forarm cut
girl cout cookie smoking that stuff
takes my pain away it doesn't reduce the
shaking as much it reduces inflammation
and it just helps my it's like one of
the best strains for my particular
osteoarthritis and um I think that yeah
just always love highlighting the
medical I side because whether
thankfully it turned out I didn't have
Parkinson I just wasn't um I I think
that the endoc canabo system is so
integrally connected to the human
experience at least for me I have a lot
of head injuries and a lot of hand
injuries in the past so I think that it
really helped me even like people think
that it hurts your memory when I stopped
using it or had worse access to it in
Florida my memory was worse than it had
been in the last 10 years so so
fascinating I couldn't remember where I
parked my car I couldn't remember stuff
that I studied hours for on a test and
it was like yeah there's some stress and
other factors and things like that but I
had stress and other factors during my
undergrad as well and I was able to pull
it off because I had access to Medicinal
cannabis that made my particular system
function and so I loved like like I said
going back to that blue dream I love
that strain so much it was the first one
I had to grow and I loved it even though
people online and oh this looks like
[ __ ] you should kill it and you don't
know what the [ __ ] you're doing I'm like
I've been around can of gr for a long
time like I kind of do know what I'm
doing but I just I messed up and I'm
going to see it through I'm going to
learn from these mistakes cuz uh my
brother and I were just talking about
this
but there's you could read a dozen books
about how to make a table you know if
you want to build a table constructed by
your hand you could write a dozen books
and you're going to pick up tips tricks
helpful tools that will will make
building a table easier but the first
time you build that table you're going
to find out there's a tool that you
don't have and you're going to find out
oh man I even though it said measure
twice cut once I read that but I didn't
feel the experience of not doing it so
when you just said okay it's 24 in and
you cut four 24 in legs and you didn't
measure twice and cut once you know like
you just cut once and measured once well
one of those 24in legs is actually 24.25
in and now you've got a wobbly ass table
so you just learned something from that
experience and until you actually do it
anything any hobby your experience in
life the experience is going to teach
you as much as any podcast will as any
book will or any YouTube video will and
that's just the unfortunate reality is
like I had experience but it was
different when I grew indoor It was a
commercial [ __ ] house that got
renovated specifically to grow cannabis
and they are making what I realized this
millions of dollars a year I was getting
[ __ ] basically paid nothing or trim
like gas money oh man just looking back
just like I can't even believe how much
money they I I knew what it was selling
for and I knew how many pounds we were
breaking down I just never actually did
the math on like sure you know five six
crops a year at this many pounds like
wow wow they were making a lot of
[ __ ] money but uh yeah it's uh I
never was in it that was the thing I was
always in it for the passion I always
just loved smoking cannabis I loved good
cannabis and whether it was my you know
one of my girlfriends I dated in Middle
School her older brother would drive to
California in a bus or van and he'd get
10 pounds at a time and we would always
pick up from him right when he got back
because it was actually from California
and like we knew the guy who did it and
like yeah it was almost like I I was
just on the end because I dated that
girl and I didn't date her because of
that I just happened to find that out
after the fact and it was like an
awesome benefactor to like get access to
some of this [ __ ] that was better than
what we had around stuff that came in
from Michigan just being exposed to good
like even if I only had 20 bucks I'd
rather get like a gram of good stuff
than like a quarter of uh you know Brown
pack Mexican which was like the option
for me at the time my buddy's like I got
a quarter for a quarter I was like what
does that mean quarter ounce for $25 I
was like I don't know if I want that I
know I don't want that actually showed
it to me I was like no I don't but you
can make this into five six blunts I was
like I'm not smoking blunts I'm smoking
bong balls you know and so it's a a
difference in in a thought process there
I guess and some people do just enjoy
the smoking process want to Smoke Joint
after joint blunt after blunt and like
there's a place I think for lower
potency cannabis maybe but um I think
that's like the Bud Lights right and
then there's the craft beers yeah
absolutely I I agree with that
wholeheartedly um it it does seem like
uh for for it it and I think it depends
on like where you are mentally like with
what you're trying to um accomplish with
your smoking whether it be something
something that's like a social thing
where you are sharing amongst people but
you then kind of want to either keep a
little bit of a more uh Lucid mindset
about you so that you can converse and
talk and uh you know be social um
whereas like cuz sometimes if I smoke
something that's heavy I am not wanting
to be social I kind of want to just go
curl up in a corner uh or go like play
some video games or something because
it's just like I just need to check out
right now and um like enjoy my own mind
mental set um so I yeah it's like a
almost like a time and place for
everything and
cannabis you know even as you had said
earlier in the podcast there's so many
different available varieties now that
all have extremely unique effects and
because everybody's endoc canabo system
is going to be unique to them as well
and um you know the mindset going into
smoking I feel has a heavy effect on the
results that you have like it's almost
like every single smoking experience is
going to be different for every person
with every strain that they smoke and
like you said with form cut cookies
finding something that works really well
for a specific uh remedy uh pain relief
mental relief um arthritis you know all
these different like you know getting to
have a a more freedom of movement with
different parts of your body even like
you said though set and setting just
like yeah set and setting they can
consider that and all these other from
mushrooms to acid and things like that
they'll always talk about set and
setting because with a more power quote
unquote more powerful substance some
people think um they'll have maybe a
higher respect for it but I think
cannabis is a substance that alters your
mind a bit um I've seen it categorized
as a mild hallucinogen I've seen it
categorized as a stimulant uh I don't
think it's actually a depressant but it
does make people relax I don't know if
it's been documented to actually drop
your heart rate cuz it typically I think
it's more of a techy card
or yeah most people's heart rate gets
increase so even if you feel tired or
like pass out like your heart rate is
probably slightly increased so um it's
anes caffeine that I feel like set and
setting on caffeine is even important
like um and intention like you said like
what you want out of it like I drank a
espresso at dinner one night and I'm not
a caffeine person but um I got away with
like a single shot of espresso knowing
like I'm going to just this is I was
tired I would be crabby and like not as
uh enjoyable of a conversation with like
my friends that I hadn't seen in a while
and my wife so I'm like I want to be
able to be like alert and Lucid during
this conversation so had the espresso
was able to enjoy my dinner drive home
and by the time like all that was said
and done I had burnt off whatever energy
it had given me you know and like I was
able to sleep just fine where um
sometimes like if I'm like oh I need to
get a project like when I was in college
take a 5our energy or drink a Red Bull
or energy drink or something and I'd get
the paper done but then I'd be up all
night and it's like my intention was to
get something done I didn't have like
the kind of followup of like am I going
to be able to sleep tonight after this
because I was like I just all I cared
about was a deadline and so having more
thoughtfulness to it mindfulness in the
use is uh important because I think uh a
lot of people and myself as well like
can take for granted this is a a
powerful tool you know it's um the stuff
that I'll use like daily just in the
morning to like limit pain and to help
me relax and things like that
um there's certain things that will be
too strong and like I Could lack like
you're saying like if I wanted to go to
a social setting not be able to converse
as well and like I know a lot of people
even like within a circle like we'll all
be talking passing around the joint and
like certain people get to a certain
spot and they're high where they just
clam up they don't say anything they're
like silent you know and like I don't
think it's they're not trying to it's
just like there's so much going on in
their own head whether they're like
paranoid about not saying something to
you know embarrass thems or whether
they're just thinking about other stuff
that's not even happening there in the
moment or they're just analyzing you
know sitting chilling and enjoying like
I'm a BL mouth sometimes I'll chitchat
but there's times where certain strains
will shut me up I'm just like yeah very
contemplative and almost meditating like
within there's more than just closing
our eyes and um crossing our fingers and
our feet and uh a lot of people think
meditation is just one thing there's so
many different types there's movement
meditations and things like that so I
think using cannabis even like the
breathing that's why I think a lot of
people enjoy the bong like deep breaths
in deep breaths out I think that's a
almost a meditation in
itself absolutely I um yeah I agree
wholeheartedly with everything that you
said that's that's a great way to put it
um so uh you know back back to the
growing though so you were growing these
giant blue dreams that completely
outgrew your space uh and um
you know by no fault of your own you
wanted to grow your favorite strain and
uh and and just do that at home so you
had access to the medicine and if i' if
I'm correct me if I'm wrong but I
believe I heard uh from you in other
shows that the nutrients you were using
were like heavy 16 at the time um and so
you know like mixing up all those
different uh bottles together uh as a
liquid form um like what what got you to
like how how did you like the results of
that um kind of what was your mindset
around it and then when did you
transition from that into a more
um uh amended soiless uh
media so I was using heavy 16 and
initially from the start I think I just
used like the ab cuz uh I was a cheap
home grower I got the tent got the light
slowly built out like got a fan and then
realized I needed two then three then
four then however many and um built out
of edge space eventually and um um I
kind of did one thing at a time and it
was like I had the ab and then like I
was like oh what's the next talking to
my and granted he worked for the hydro
stop and he was probably getting a
little cut on these sailes but I I'd go
over to his place and like check out his
grow and he had all these bottles at his
place like what does this one do on it
smell it like a lot of their stuff is
like unlicensed organic like they're the
ab is like a regular hydro line but like
all of the side additives are like
organic kind of inputs like you could
really smell it with like the I think it
was like the prime or the fire one of
them was really humiy kind of a but all
the additives I always felt like were
worth it because um I noticed when I
would run out of a bottle or whatever
didn't use it like the plants didn't
smell or taste as good or didn't grow as
well and um so I'd always kind of cough
up it was a little expensive admittedly
it was like a premier line but I do
think they did a good job and um I still
actually have cocoa and the whole
nutrient line so if I ever wanted to
like for whatever reason do a side by
side I could and um the very next grow I
actually found more success by instead
of going in three gallon pots to finish
I did a bunch of uh one gallon pots
that's actually when I had the Great
White Buffalo grow when I grew the sour
76 and I also grew a tester called
Platinum Yeti um it was like a platinum
headband cross but um it like F3 which
also got me into like oh what's this
whole F2 F3 kind of generational thing
all about and um that grow went really
well I had five plants three sour 76s
and two Platinum Yeti when I just had
two plants in the same space and I got a
shot at my buddy Dave from Ohio C Crazy
Dave and um he was like why don't you do
like a sea of green and I actually
hadn't necessarily seen that in my
experience at this point I wasn't like
cruising forums and [ __ ] regularly like
I didn't even realize because where I
was at in Ohio it was so secretive like
don't tell anybody you're doing this
don't talk about it blah blah blah don't
take photos um so finding out that there
was like a space online where like
people are just like posting their grows
asking for advice giving advice getting
advice was kind of new to me and I I
looked up Steve Green cuz I didn't know
it was he kind of had more of a s green
setup but it wasn't quite like tiny tiny
pots like he was doing a bunch of
smaller plants I was like damn dude
you're like having a ton of success like
I'm going to try that style so I did it
worked and um they're all between like
one and 2 feet tall and got between like
1 and 2 ounces or whatever so it wasn't
like a crazy huge Harvest I kind of went
like heavy on like a schwaz technique
that I saw and I was trying to emulate
um this grow buckets guy or whatever the
main lining method where you get like
eight or like 16 colas and you basically
take off everything except for like the
main uh colas or whatever and um
admittedly the bud turned out great I
just didn't get a whole lot of it and uh
I learned you know you don't necessarily
have to go that extreme with it but um
that was another successful grow in the
Coco and what I realized was it was
taking a lot of time to pipet out the
nutrients mix them up pH do this and
that and make sure that I was using uh
even like we have pretty clean water
where I'm at and not on wood because you
never know that you can change um but
but even then I go and get my own
personal water for my wife and I had a
drink so I don't mind lugging 5 gallon
jugs like I carry two of them all the
time and I fill them up and I bring them
home well there's my cat but uh the
water that I was using was just like you
know you go to the store and you put it
under the thing and whatever you get the
clean water with as close to zero PPM as
possible and it's filtered a whole bunch
of different ways so I was using that
and feeling like I needed to use that
for um the heavy 16 because when I
didn't I felt like again like you could
kind of see like maybe the plants didn't
uptake the nutrients as well or like the
I didn't even know at the time because I
hadn't met Dr MJ and like I didn't even
use a PPM meter I was just like feed
feed water feed feed water feed water
feed or like give it a compos here and
there so I knew that PPM meters and EC
meters existed and I had like that blue
lab trench on but when I looked up like
the hom grower scale of it it was like
so expensive and I didn't trust the ones
on Amazon I was like if I'm going to get
one it's going to be like a blue lab I'm
like man that's like 100 bucks or
something and I was like [ __ ] that's
like as much as like my tent you know
like I don't want to spend that kind of
money uh I was just starting my business
at the time I just moved back here and
like I it's tough to you know make a
living here most businesses shutter in
like a year so uh it's it's tough to
make it happen and on top of that to be
grow on your own but ultimately I
realized if you do produce your own
successfully it's cheaper cost per gram
by a lot and especially because like my
wife and I were going through at least 2
ounces a week and or 2 ounces every two
weeks I think it was so like an ounce a
week um and I was like if I could grow
this and electrical cost even what it is
I could probably save a bunch of money
and I went through and documented
everything and those first few grows and
realized like holy [ __ ] like I'm growing
it for like x amount of dollars per gram
like versus if it's 10 a gram to buy it
I was growing it for like1 two or $3 at
the very worst and like that was only
going down cuz like a lot of one time
purchasers bought the light bought the
tent had all the stuff and nutrients
were a recurring cost or whatever but
like that was only once every several
months or year depending on how much you
buy and so I did notice that was one of
my bigger costs and I did not like as
you see I do have a cat over here behind
me and I have a little green screen kind
of situation going on but just so you
don't see all the random [ __ ] occurring
behind me but um what I realized is like
I didn't like the process of like what
felt like I'm not a chemist I don't work
in that kind of space I'm not in the lab
I don't work with
chemicals I don't know which one of them
are dangerous to me and which one of
them isn't dangerous to me if I spill it
I know like you're supposed to I could
read the directions it's all tiny little
print in an emergency situation I'll
admit I didn't read every single little
warning on the side of those things I
just was excited to grow i' squirt it
all out
and I I would worry if I ever spilled it
or got it on my hands I'd wash real
diligently and like I know some of that
stuff can actually cause harm so I
didn't want it on or around me
necessarily not say it's like the end of
the world people work with it all the
time right but um I figured if there was
a safer and easier solution out there
and I'd already done it kind of in the
past with Organics why not try it inside
and so I had heard about subcool looked
more into his stuff I'd been smoking his
stuff even before I started growing um
so I was like oh this dude has like an
Instagram and a YouTube and he just like
shows his grow and he has a super soil
and so I didn't actually start off with
the super soil um I ended up seeming
simpler to me than doing like the
Lasagna Tech was I found a bunch of
people in the Michigan Community doing
the M3 and there was also a breeder who
I thought at the time was cool and found
out later he's a real dag so I'm not
going to even name them but they were
claiming really good results with this
M3 Michigan made mix and so I ordered a
bag and I was like you know what [ __ ] it
it's not local at least it's from
America and uh so like they shipped me a
bag of soil or whatever and I tried it
out and sure enough it worked damn well
and it was simple I just water only ran
it through and I was like I did some
experimenting like um I start in Solo
solo cup and I transplanted up to a 1
gon and then I went up to a 3 gallon or
5 gallon and I realized like 5 gallon
probably did a little bit better but it
was so much bigger and managing the
water situation in my small space like
three gallons was as big as I wanted to
go so I think I ended up with like three
three gallon pots of soil and I had them
all side by side for the flower tent
area ultimately with that situation and
um it worked and I liked it and
ultimately um realized that people were
having a lot of success with these Earth
boxes I was seeing build a soil using
the earth box and I saw Spartan grown
using City Pickers and um Cheddar Bob
and others using Earth boxes and I was
like man like these pots are all laid
right next to each other like one next
to the other next to the other I'm like
I could basically just use an earth box
and that would be a little bit more
volume of soil and like I see people use
beds so you can c-plant like at least
two plants in there and so I got the
earth box and kind of have never looked
back that's what I've been rocking for
the last several years now and uh I just
got shout out to Resurrection profit he
just sent me a couple fresh bags of M3
so I'm going to reset cuz my stuff I
don't do soil testing and after a few
years it's finally gotten to the point
where it still produces it yields well
it just doesn't taste as good as it did
when I first started so there's
something off in there that I can't
quite figure out and I think it probably
over amended over the each Crow just
gave a little too much a little too much
a little too much and at this point it's
probably just like toxically high and so
I'm gonna scrap that mix it with some um
like potting soil and and garden soil
and use that for outdoor plants and
stuff and maybe even turn it into like a
compost slw worm bin depending on my
situation but my wife is not fond of the
worm bin idea so happy wife happy life
it'll probably just be a outdoor plant
situation grow some like sunflowers and
uh Holly Hawks and other cool stuff
outside nice yeah I um I love the idea
of being able to use like an amended
substrate where you're just re amending
it and getting multiple rounds of
harvests out of it I did that for a
while in like a 30 gallon Grassroots
fabric pot I think I was able to pull
like seven harvests out of it with just
minimal amendments over time but then um
unfortunately I I ran into rud aphids
and um I just scrapped the soil because
uh well I I composted it so that it the
thermophilic um uh process just
annihilated the root AIDS and anything
else that was problematic in there but I
I that and that's like usually my big
biggest warning for anybody venturing
into something that's going to be an
amended substrate used round after round
after round is um fungus knuts rud AIDS
thrips uh anything that is going to be
soil born um in terms of a pest you want
to make sure that you're at least having
some level of security in place to make
sure that those populations either don't
blow up or don't happen or um anywhere
in between um but also you you know you
you even mentioned that you have the
very easy opportunity of just resetting
with a fresh bag of of a reputable um
amended soilless media and going from
there and you know I've even heard of
people who will use like the kiss
Organics mix where um they just uh you
know they'll only run it three or four
times and then they'll reset it because
they're just like by the time the fifth
or sixth gets around I'm I'm losing my
tpine profiles of the same cultivars I'm
running I'm losing the resin production
the yield is significantly less um even
if everything else is met uh and even if
I've seen some people do the saturated
past Pace test and see that they're at
the same level as they were with the
initial substrate but something's
happened there's some uh biology or uh
it's hard to know there's so much going
on in there that like my stuff still
yielding great it just doesn't tastes as
good as it should and I know that I'm
honest enough to tell myself like we're
smoking some of the my other Buddies
stuff that they grow or even stuff that
like from my wife's work that I'd rather
have over home grow and that was just
never the case before it was always i'
rather have my home grow over any
commercial stuff and when that's not the
case anymore it's like well I got to
admit my stuff is not as good as it once
was and there's something wrong with my
process and at least be humble enough to
admit you know that it probably is the
soil like there's I'm doing everything
else the same for the most part and um
not too much has changed I could of
strain here and there but like sometimes
it's stuff that I like you said you've
grown it in the past and it was just
fine and it tasted how it's supposed to
taste and now it's like when it's not
that way anymore well time to you know
reset and I think admittedly I think if
you even get two runs out of a soil
you've probably more than uh gotten your
value out of it because you know even
with cannabis down at like 1,000 a pound
I think is what the average is in
California roughly it'ser even lower
depending on in in the legal Market I
should say um but the um
the trim you can get for like 20 50 I
don't know it's crazy low but um it's
fascinating depending on like the
quality and and like indoor outdoor
Greenhouse type thing um but even if
just a th000 a pound being like the
reference metric I guess is um it's
probably lower than that it will
continue to get lower um even if it cost
you more to grow it yourself than it did
to um you know buy it I think it's still
worth it it's just like the home Brewers
Market the craft you know Beer Market
whatever it is they're going to be a
little bit more expensive and obviously
smaller batch and with that comes higher
cost of production but it's worth it
because we have that passion and the
main thing is there's just no way to
produce what we're able to produce at
scale I've never seen it done at even
the best of the bests um and like when
I'm saying scale I'm talking like
hectars like several C scale I'm not
talking like an indoor production or 100
lights or you know even a, lights like
that's you could do semi craft level or
high quality cannabis and those 1,000
lights and under depending on how big
your team is and how good your team is
but when you start getting into acres
and Acres of so much that's hard area
underglass to have the quality that I
can produce in my little and going back
to like the it's funny because in my
head I saw like when I started like what
I thought was the best it was like the
whole if if you could dream as a
cannabis carer like you dedicate a whole
house to it right and just spare no cost
on expense and things like that but um I
just saw a report and this don't come at
me for racial stuff people but this was
documented in California 99% of indoor
cannabis cultivation is done by Chinese
individuals so like we were doing it
just how they do it like as you see all
these grow houses rated and it's like
basically like an indentured servitude
like these people owe people money and
they get sent over here and they have to
grow weed to pay off their debts type
thing and they're like sleeping in a
sleeping bag and like the rest of the
house is plants so um you would think
maybe in your head like oh that's the
ideal setup you got the most room for
the plants you got all the equipment all
the setup it's impossible for that
grower to tend to each one of those
plants as well as he needs to there's
too many plants even if you double
triped quadrupled the grower
like even at a commercial scale like
when there's thousands of plants or
hundreds of plants the individual
attention to each plant is dropped and
on top of that your personal choice is
less like when you go out to the market
there might be 50 100 200 trains
available thousand strains who who knows
you could go to every single dispenser
in California and find a thousand or
whatever there's 10,000 or more strains
on the seed Market right now y you could
go and find whatever strain you want
cross to whatever strain you want and if
you can't you can probably find the cuts
and make it yourself and like if you
can't you can probably find somebody
else who did something close to that
maybe like one of the parents is
different but even like if you can get a
50% something in a cross if you fenal
hunt through that you're going to find
something like that clone or cut or bag
that you smoked that you liked if you
that was how I did it and I've had tons
of tons of success finding exactly what
I'm looking for and like you said
popping a pack and if I don't move on to
the next breeder do your research
obviously because a lot of them are con
artists and fly by night they're going
to be gone tomorrow and they're doing
knockoff work a lot of the time but uh
even if they're still around like some
of the big ones are some of the worsts
so uh be aware of that but do research
on like who did the original um like
part of the reason I did 50 strains of
green was to basically highlight good
old school breeders who did a lot of
that work to make things like we talked
about at the top of show kind of close
to bulletproof or like really stable
where you're not going to see a Herm
just because it got a little hot or a
little dry or a little overwat a little
underwater like one or two times isn't
going to cause it to just go you know
where some stuff the first issue it's
just bananas everywhere or Chuck and
pollen if it's a early male and so as a
quick sidebar do you mind just briefly
touching on your um your work as an
author and and Publishing your own book
yeah it's been an interesting process
for sure um I recently read or I'm
reading a book from a self-published
author that goes back to the 1970s uh
Tom Kelly 's uh 10th Legion and uh it's
a really interesting book but reading
the back it it said I was a
self-published author because that meant
like I don't know if he said like stupid
enough or crazy enough I should it's in
my car right now actively reading it but
um he said all that basically meant was
like you found a publishing house that
was willing to charge you to like print
your own stuff essentially like and
that's kind of what happened with my
situation is uh I wanted to make a book
I had heard about like the can of Bible
and I've I've seen and own you know a
couple of these books um subcools the
Dank is one that I really like and the
Dank 2.0 where he documents the strs
with photos a description and you know
the story kind of about it and I love
those books so much but like there's
only so many of them and they're not
really making a whole bunch of new ones
and a lot of them were
like the canab for example just like a
bunch of you know maybe like the top
strains of that time um but didn't have
like a real specific focus and like I
grew up in liking like dog breeds and
there was so much if you look into the
American Kennel Club if you want to
learn about any one of those dog breeds
there's so much you can learn about it
like how long the tail is how long the
ears are the temperament all that stuff
and I'm like this is so cool like if you
are into the hobby you have not endless
but like tons and tons maybe it is
endless cuz they keep making Fast
library though yeah and and there's a
lot of deep details and descriptions and
like with cannabis I feel like
seedfinder EU is probably like one of
the closest things we had to that like
you can go and find and it's like a
Wikipedia more than it is the American
Kennel Club because anybody can put
anything on there and they say oh I made
this trrain oh I did that and so you
have to become you know Inspector Gadget
over here and try and figure out 53
entries for OG Kush and yeah like which
one for Blue Dream yeah and like who
actually made it and like so I was like
this is so ridiculous like I get a 100
questions a day asking me not actually
100 but like for a while like we I'd get
hundreds per week of people asking me
certain questions and a lot of the
recurring ones are what is this strain
who like where did this come from who
made this and a lot of times I'd be
listening to shows and I still do like
I'll be in the chat like they'll be like
what is the strain I'll just be like
it's xross to Y you know like I'll tell
them it's OG Kush cross to you know
cookies or something like that and then
I start sort of like Matthew Gates
Whenever there would be somebody post a
image of a plant with bugs on it
everyone would just tag at s angel on
Instagram and then you'd see like a few
hours later s Angel would come in and be
like that's uh tetron ear Decay or
spider mites or whatever you know like
he'd give like the Latin name the real
name and he's like here's what you use
to treat it and here's my you know
there's a link on my website if you want
to go watch my pest primer on YouTube
and like it'll show you all the ways
that you can fight it and like
everything about like how they live and
the reproductive cycles and this and
that so I came to know him by seeing
him basically demonstrating his
professionalism by helping people for
free online and so I was like you know
what I can kind of be that person in a a
little bit of way CU I'm just a nerd for
cannabis strains I tried a bunch of them
myself and I'm always wanting to learn
more about new ones so why don't I get
into that space a little bit more and
make something concrete my Instagram can
be deleted my stuff can be Shadow fanned
but a paperback book that sits on your
desk or on your countertop where you
smoke nobody can censor that nobody can
delete that he might be burnt up in a
fire or something but um I I'll send you
another copy if anything like that
happened and um by making something
concrete forums get deleted or lost and
one gets popular and then it fades out
of you know popularity and then the next
one gets popular and Fades out of
popularity and we lose so much of our
history um in a sense I felt almost in
retrospect like an ethnobotanist in a
way because sure I'm covering ing people
and culture as much as I'm covering the
plant because that's a major part of
what this industry is and what this
plant took to survive you know through
thousands of years like there was
cultural reasons and you know business
even business reasons I'm sure back
times before we even had documentation
I'm sure people were selling it or
exchanging it for other Goods foods and
services and things like that so it's um
a very
historically you know significant plant
and and so little modern research has
been done it's getting better in the
recent years but so much of it for a
long time was just like how is this
addictive or how is it problematic and
bad and how does it cause crime or what
crimes are related to it and now we're
like What does it do medically like how
does it do it how is it helping all
these people with sleep pain anxiety um
you know mental illness so many other a
like it's considered quote dirty drug
because it treats more than one thing
like a clean drug is like oh this is a
pain reliever it does pain relief and
that's it this is a boner pill it gives
you boners like it does one thing it was
initially supposed to be a heart drug
and I found out it became an erection in
right but um it's got a very specific
Target now and there's a bunch of
different knockoffs of that now or or
different styles from gels to Mists to
tabs and things like that so with uh
cannabis it's kind of interesting
because it treats so many different
things and all the different strains
like certain ones are better for
different things and so I wanted with 50
of green to as much as I could document
my own personal experiences with what I
felt were 50 of the best strains That
Grew green and finish green because I'd
seen in
California a lot of like OG's talked
about when the purple came in a lot of
the OG's just threw all their old cuts
out and took the purple cuz that's all
people were buying and so we lost a lot
of history there when purple got popular
and I was like well I need to go I like
a lot of these green strains like in my
personal experience some of the best
effects came from the green strains and
I know it's not just California
California often leads the market but a
lot of other markets kind of feel the
same way like purple is cool it looks
cool I'm my first strain that I put out
V bunch is a purple strain and I wanted
it to be purple because so many people
have never experienced that I get that
like some people still haven't had
access to good purple bud so or any
purple bud to be able to grow that
yourself like seeing it go from Green
and veg to purple it's like a [ __ ]
magic trick so there's a satisfaction
it's it's it's like nothing else I love
that even if it turned pink or red like
it it Chang in colors when it's been
green its whole life other than turning
like yellow or something or brown like
would be uh it's such a beautiful
experience but with as much as purple is
cool and I get that it's cool we lost
some of the passion for green and so I
was like what are my top 50 and I've
tried over a thousand at this point and
I documented hundreds of them and I have
a little Journal how did it smell how
did it make me feel when did I use it
why did I use it uh set and setting like
I got this a couple of them had they're
like cannabis specific journals that
have like pre cutout things for you to
fill in like 1 through 10 or you know
uplifting sedating like smells flavors
uh did it linger did it like hit you
immediately and like all these different
little subtle notes and so I was able to
back reference those as I wrote the book
but then I realized at the same time
like you mentioned earlier in the show
my experience isn't everyone's
experience so I cross reference my
friends I cross reference my family I
cross reference the internet Leafly and
all these other websites and see how
does my experience stack up and I try to
include a little bit of both often times
my experience is the common eight out of
10 nine out of 10 times if it's an
uplifting strain I get that uplifting
effect sometimes I'm the one out of 10
outlier I'm like that Mac one that
everybody loves I [ __ ] hate it I've
tried it 100 times I've tried it from
him I've tried capulator Mac one didn't
like it from the horse's mouth like I
got it directly from the hand and uh it
just so unfortunate doesn't it's it's
profile does not work with my endocan
abinoid system sure a lot of people love
it a lot of people like how it smells
how it tastes how it makes some I'm not
a fan it's like it's very best it's ever
been to me was a seven out of 10 and I
think I'm being generous like probably
more like a 6.5 for me for me like so
like how you talk about the form cut um
Mac 1 was the first thing that I
experienced where I I had um like what I
would call like a true medicinal
reaction to it where like pain that I
was feeling went away almost
instantaneously and um it it was it was
astonishing for me how well it worked so
I mean even that alone right there shows
any of the listeners how unique an
endocannabinoid system can be and how
unique a tarpine and uh cannaboid
profile of a flower or a concentrate can
be and not just that but like you said
you got it from the guy who bred it and
grows it now in the commercial Market I
got it from someone who was not that
person in a completely different state
and so who even knows if the growing
styles were similar and well I only say
that cuz I tried it 15 times before that
wasn't his so I was like oh I just had a
good representation or I haven't grown
it myself yet cuz if I haven't grown it
myself yet I don't necessarily think
I've given it a fair shake so I haven't
grown mac one to say um for myself but I
haven't grown it because I didn't like
any of it when I got it from him and I
didn't like it that was really sealed
the deal I got it from a guy who said
they got it from him and then I got it
from him myself so I was like um but it
is cool that I will say this I don't
want people to get tribal about it I
think Cap's cool I like a lot of his
other crosses I think he runs a good
forum I think that he maybe sells good
product I haven't tried it but um I've
heard good things about some of his
microbes and maybe even IPM products and
stuff like that think capulator schol I
met him shook his hand he was super nice
to me but flower and you know we had a
good good experience good exchange I
didn't um you know I literally only got
the Mac one just to say that I some from
him to try it from him but um I'm happy
that it works for you some people are
like oh like Jack doesn't like the Mac
one so he thinks that Mac one sucks and
no one should use it like no that's not
what I'm trying to say I'm actually
trying to say like the opposite like
just cuz I like something that's why I
cross reference cuz if I would have just
said 50 strains of Jack's favorite then
I think it's a limited book right cuz
like maybe I'd just like more sativa
than you maybe like my wife didn't start
smoking SAA until like a year or two ago
like and I use SAA very more uplift in
uh he highs well I like those you know
especially daytime and midday she didn't
like him for a long long long time until
she started working with certain brands
that had maybe more what I would call
like a closer to the heirloom or or even
um some land race type varieties and
funny enough she actually enjoyed those
more so I think there's something of a
balance in there and some of the more
modern what we call sativa uplifting
crosses and I wonder how much of it
could have also just been with um you
know like with most other systems within
the body nervous circulatory endoc
canabo they develop and change over time
and The receptors can become blocked or
open up or um even yeah through set and
setting as you get older and as as your
uh you know your hormonal structure
changes and the rest of your body
changes over time and your mental state
changes all those things could provide
just a different experience of the same
product from one year to the next I
totally agree and I know some people
will get paranoid now that can't even
use it anymore where they used to love
taking big bong hits and like they can't
even smoke a little bit anymore and um I
do think that's a major factor to how
people are going to experience it so uh
you know I want to rein us back in just
a little bit actually and uh get back to
a little bit more of the growing
questions since we are coming up on the
2hour Mark here I want to just make sure
that I get as much of this in even if we
run over just a little bit sounds good
um but throughout all of your experience
growing uh you know from all the way
back to your first experience where you
were helping uh to now where you have
multiple years of homow experience uh
changing from Hydroponics to uh Organics
or amended substrates um what uh and and
I'm going to pose this as a two-part
question so what have been some of your
biggest learning experiences and a um
from a setback something that really
made you feel like uh like you could
call it a failure in the garden or um
something that you didn't want to have
occur again and then on the other side
of the coin um what have you learned the
most from a success that you found in
your garden where uh you then took that
practice and either uh continued to
perfect it or just took it as it was and
made sure that you were implementing
that every time moving forward so I'll
start with the success first and then
finish with the failure because uh we
recently did episode where we talked a
lot about learning for failures and uh
growing with my fellow Growers so I do
encourage people to check it out uh
growing with my fellow Growers I do host
on Sundays on the YouTube and uh we did
a whole uh I think it was just two weeks
ago about New Year just learning from
failures and a whole bunch of stuff came
up but with the success one thing that
you brought up in just how you asked the
question made me think specifically of
um using the drought stress to benefit
your tarpine expression to benefit the
resin production I listened to Hash
church for a long time and Bubble Man
and others mentioned that lavender grown
in France had the highest tpine profile
it sold for the highest dollar per pound
it had the most linol production which
is a tpine found in cannabis so I
figured well if line is increased by
being grown in this Mediterranean region
and they are known for getting a drought
late season then maybe we can give our
plants a late season drought just like
late and flower couple weeks before we
Harvest them let them get real dry dry
the pots all the way back until they get
droopy and did it once accidentally just
cuz my pots were a little bit smaller
and this is what really made me start
believing it and and push and doing it
every single Harvest because it was
actually that sour 76 and platinum Yeti
grow um they were in one gallon cocoa
pots which if you know about growing in
one gallon cocoa pots especially in like
Southern California where it can get dry
and you have good air flow um those pots
can dry out within like a day so late in
flower you got big you know 2ft tall
plant and next to like a 1 and a2t Tall
plant that foot tall plant might drink a
little bit quicker and so I had two
Platinum yetis one of them they were
both really sandy I just de leafed the
resin was really Sandy and it felt like
grainy almost literally like grains of
sand on the on top of the leaf the one
that got drought stressed the next day
felt like super glue it was so sticky
and it was pungent it was so much louder
and and just the smell was screaming off
that plant I could like when you'd stick
your fingers together they would like
there's like the glue Trace after you
just touched one leaf and it was so
significantly different than the day
before that I just let the one next to
it drought as well to see like is it
maybe just the stage of growth like
they're at the same day a flower this
one's so much stickier than that one and
it just routed and the the one next to
it was still Sandy so I just let it go
dry dry dry dry dry soon as it dried
down watered it again came back it was
super glue sticky so I did that to the
whole room every other plant the sour 76
CU they all got it and from that point
forward I was like all right week seven
drought stress you know cuz I think
that's what it was and um I mentioned
this on the podcast a few times and then
it turns out there was a university of
GF in Canada study uh G is gu l p um
it's a Canadian pronunciation again we
have Canadian listeners out there who
product I used to call it gelf it's gu
um so shout out to the Canadians who
listen I appreciate all the it it's
humbling honestly to like I just I'm
sitting here in my room on a podcast or
whatever and there's people all over the
world actually listening so it is
honestly mind-blowing just like a
Midwestern dude like talking about weed
but that was the biggest success that I
learned from the GU study ended up
showing a week eight drought stress
increased the tarpine canabo production
and the yield the yield was even higher
than like their well-watered condition
which doesn't mean the water came from a
well it was watered well or properly
which meant they did a bunch of studies
figured out how to water as good as they
could did the good as they could method
and then tried that against the drought
stress method the drought stress method
outperformed and if anybody wants I
could send them that link or you could
just look up uh root Zone management GTH
drought cannabis study and it'll pop up
on Google free I would also suggest
anybody that wants to look up drought
stressing and the benefits in a
hydroponic setting as well as even in
organic settings to look up how
commercial tomatoes are cultivated
especially Vining Tomatoes where they go
through
um uh in in like crop steering you would
call it generative versus vegetative
steering events and generative being
that drought stress or other stress
events and vegetative being reduced
stress um events and you can have these
cycles of uh stress low stress stress
low stress where you can produce rapid
onset of uh the the fruit sets for
tomatoes and have it produce um and
ripen and create new Tomatoes all at
once so that you're having this constant
cycle of harvesting every I think it's
nine days or something like that
typically within a Vining tomato um and
so taking those same practices and
applying them to cannabis has shown in a
lot of cases that it's very much a
benefit to the to the plant overall
you're not the first person that says
that they um you
know cuz they saw cannabis as their baby
right they didn't want to hurt it they
wanted to make sure it was happy they
wanted to make sure that they did
everything they could for it and then
they missed something or they caused
some stress event and it opened up their
mind to being like holy crap this plant
responds in a positive way to these
stressors how can I replicate this
consistently without it being something
that is a true detriment to the plant
and so a lot of the times I'll refer to
it as a perceived stress because it's
not like a true stress event where it's
going to cause uh degradation in the
plant tissue or in its growth processes
or otherwise it's it's something where
it's like oh it thinks it doesn't have
water but it actually still does and
you're going to get it water in you know
really soon here anyway so uh just let
it let it go do the thing and then boom
you got tpin that are louder than you
thought they could be resin production
that's off the charts yeah it's distress
versus ESS cuz distress is bad and UST
stress is positive in this case it was
statistically shown the it was a ESS
that late flower drought stress and I'll
also add I personally feel that there's
not a negative side effect and there
could also be a positive side effect I
believe in a week seven or week eight
depending on how long you're I two weeks
before you harvest ideally but week
seven or eight one drought stress
throughout your whole flower cycle but
the second one I would add on top of
that that I don't have data to support
this but I like a drought stress up
through Harvest so right before you
harvest letting your media dry out and
even letting the plants kind of suffer a
little bit on the low water end I can't
verify 100% but I do think just like
that week seven and eight pushes out a
little bit more TPS I would do that and
then even somebody just asked me this
today in the DM what do I feel about the
darkness before Harvest some people will
let the you know say Harvest right
before the lights come on 12 hours of
Darkness I agree with that at the bare
minimum I do like to do at least 24
hours myself so I'll double that dark
cycle so if they're used to being 12 on
12 off or 1113 whatever it is I'll give
them their last light cycle and then
I'll go dark for 24 hours from at least
um I don't push I used to do 72 hours
sometimes I'll do 24 to 48 usually just
on the convenience of my life like when
I can get to it to be honest after 24
though I I like 24 up to 48 I think
after 48 being in the darkness that long
uh sometimes moisture can creep up and
you don't want to like Risk any molds
and things like that um if you can
mitigate it really well with climate
control then you can maybe get away with
a little bit more I don't think that
there's a major benefit from 48 versus
72 I think as long as you get that full
24 Darkness the pl like what the hell
the lights were supposed to come back on
like what the [ __ ] happening and I'm
dry like I'm us all my metabolites man
yeah so it's just like maybe I can put
out something to attract something to
whatever but they tend to uh in my
experience seem to really perform at
their best if you give them just that
little extra nods and um for sure in
terms of mistakes that I learned from
definitely going into the jar too wet I
got moisture meters now so I don't do
that and even then I'll still find a bud
here and there if uh you know I do like
it sticky so I tend to air on the side
of um a little bit damper than some if I
if I wanted to I could get my stuff into
jars bone dry but um I think that
there's a window between like bone dried
powder which like a lot of stuff you get
the dispensary turns out to be and like
that nice sticky sponginess I prefer to
get it in that sticky spongy range but
even a little bit under that is
probably I don't know if it was um PM or
Bud Rod or whatever it was but just like
a spider Webby nasty bortus I think
maybe um within the jars after I
harvested some of the biggest letdowns
and like like I said it was like one nug
but it was always the fattest Cola so
like I lost a s gr Cola on one and 11 gr
Cola on another one and um since then
probably like three or four gram coals
were like the most recent the last few
years that I lost but um I ended up not
typically keeping the jar or I'll just
turn that jar into concentrate even like
the stuff that that didn't have mold on
it just uh if I don't straight up toss
it all I'll turn into like a oil or
something that I end up using to cook
and at that point I feel like it's
fairly safe but have any issues with
that but um some the that Spartan gave
actually about the going into the jar to
wet being his biggest setback that he
learned from um I you know I feel like I
I could say that that was definitely one
point where I tried to get into jars too
wet um because I wanted to to allow for
the enzymatic processes to continue in
the curing and um I think I just was
looking about it as as though these
enzymes really needed a lot more
moisture than they do um and there's
more moisture than you can feel without
a meter like my stuff feels crispy bone
dry on the outside and I stick that
meter in there and it's still like 8 10
12 15% so like when you look at it 12
hours or 24 hours after it goes in the
jar a lot often times it off gases that
stuff on the inside that you can't even
see the crispy little leaves on the
outside are really deceptive
because there like you could flake them
off with a little tap but the inside of
the butt is still really um pretty damp
still yep absolutely I always tell
people um that they know that they dried
and cured it well when you grind it up
and you pour it out and it looks like
kinetic sand where it keeps moving after
you've poured it out onto your rolling
tray or whatever I love that texture I
mean it it rolls up so nicely you can
like I feel like you can take someone
who's had trouble rolling joints and
give them flower that looks like that
and all of a sudden they'll be like man
I'm really good at rolling joints um it
basically pack like once you roll it one
time it keeps its shape and then uh
tends to burn even in like a bowl I have
like a little scooper and like if it's
at the texture I actually like it it
won't fall into the bowl properly it'll
make like a lump and I have to like
scrape it over and off and tap it
because it otherwise it's just like it
sticks to itself too much or like I'll
have to take my finger and kind of like
feather it in off of this little it's a
little bent piece of cardboard or
whatever just like a a scoop and dump
and uh yeah it's covered in resin or
whatever but it's just an easier way to
not necessarily I don't have long
fingernails I always keep mine trimmed
low so it's hard to pick stuff off the
rolling tray and get it into the bowl um
but I know they make little tools and
things like that but this is simple and
it works so nice well those are great
answers for um setbacks and successes
that have helped you kind of shape your
grow and and uh um practices that you
more follow today setback is just
overwatering since Spartan had the same
answer as me um in in terms of seedlings
especially I killed off a couple
seedlings in my early growing by giving
them a little too much water and even
now like mature plants I'd rather air on
the side of underwatering than over
watering because like as we I talked
about in the successes a drought stress
especially like in late flower can
actually have a benefit but that said
the one caveat I do want to give is um
the gal university did the same study
with like multiple drought stresses
throughout earlier like weeks 2 3 4 5
six and if they had more than one before
week seven or week eight then it
actually decreased y decreased terine
production decrease cannaboids so if
you're just like oh Jack said that you
can get away with like all these
stresses and like he loves trout
stressing SPS I'm just going to do it
all the time like no you got to be
careful with it do it when it's supposed
to happen late in the season like it
would in nature in that area where the
best stuff comes from or in a controlled
environment like we're trying to do with
uh horiculture we can control that kind
of stuff stuff and and get the desired
results but if you're just doing it
every time that's like airing into the
side of being more of a lazy lazy
Gardener but more people are more on
gardeners where we just want to give
more more more water and I was that
person and tend to still lean on that
side so I try to like say like is it
ready for water and I'll like lift the
pot I'm like can it wait another day is
it starting to droop like like sometimes
I'll push them a little bit too much in
the the veg side of things and I'll slow
things down so like it's always a
process to kind of Tinker with and dial
in and take time and put it on your
calendar figure out like this V was 30
days this V was 36 this was 40 what did
I do on the 30-day V to make it 30 days
and try and replicate that and try and
cut it down to 25 20 21 however fast you
can get it to get a big healthy plant
ready flower yeah and I I I just like to
always add the caveat as well to you
know anybody that is um attempting to do
like a drought stress or something that
it it matters what substrate you're
using and it matters um the frequency
between your Dbacks because of the the
substrate sizing so all of these
different things need to be taken into
account and for a lot of cases it's
going to take multiple rounds for you to
figure out what is working what doesn't
work and the best practices involved in
there so you know just kind of adding on
uh don't just start drought stressing
your plants all over the place
throughout all of flower cuz more is
better um not necessarily um but so yeah
great great caveat that you added there
as well I appreciate that that does it's
very important especially I feel like we
do have a lot of new Growers um that
listen to the show and especially with
the um the cheap home grow uh show it it
it really has a lot of new Growers that
are looking to glean some information I
know I learned a lot from you guys early
on when I was getting back into growing
um you know after the the covid shutdown
and when being in restaurants was no
longer very tenable for at least you
know two or three years there um the
Dark Ages the dark
ages the recent Dark Ages yes right um
so you know you had your setback your
success um is is there anything that you
feel that when when new Growers or
growers in general are looking at
cultivating um is there something that
you ever like to put your finger on and
say this is probably the most important
thing you need to pay attention to uh as
you're getting into this you know CU
there's there's so many different styles
of growing whether it be
uh salt-based
fertilizers or an amended substrate
whether you're using U high-intensity
discharge lighting LED lighting sunlight
you know there's so many different
parameters that can be unique to the
grower and I feel like we've repeated
this over and over again in this podcast
so far but if you had to put your finger
on one is there any that you could and
if it's not just one like maybe just a
couple it's easy for me because I think
all the things that you just mentioned I
hate to say it doesn't matter it matters
it'll change how the plant expresses
itself and some things work better for
other people and some things are better
suited for certain environments um hid
for example if you're in the great white
North and it's freezing cold all the
time in Canada where you're at and you
want a little bit of uh extra heat like
some people get away with running HIDs
and Noah the growa is up in Washington I
think and he grows with HIDs and still
kills it and there's people with the
most modern LEDs Spartan growing out
there with you know Grand Master
whatever and like you could get the
brand newest and coolest and you can get
the oldest and most classic and they
still work but what I think ultimately
makes the biggest difference above all
is the genetics and that might be you
know a little bit generic thing to say
but you could take a great grower and
give them terrible genetics and say pick
whatever equipment you want and they're
going to have a hard time growing some
dank but you could take a brand new
grower with entry level whatever kit you
know not even all the stuff that they
need
give them a good cut or a good pack of
seeds they're going to grow some fire so
genetics is like you can dial in the
environment slowly over time and good
genetics will do okay to good even in
bad environments so I think having good
genetics is one of the most under
researched things because it's hard to
research like I talked about why I got
into writing 50 strands of green is like
Google good cannabis genetics I want
good cannabis seeds well then I'm going
to get sent to you know some giant
generic white labeling seed bank that
says that they have all these strands
that we just talked about they've got
gg4 they've got OG Kush they've got Girl
Scout cookies they've got Mac one and
it's labeled that so you would think
well they're selling it as that just
like anything else in in life I can go
online and I buy something I should have
some sort of belief that what they're
selling is real and I'll get seeds in
the mail and I can grow them out and
maybe they'll be good maybe they won't
be but if you take the time even just
like 15 minutes of research to try and
go and
like say who was the original creator of
whatever strain and you're going to get
like 20 different articles and you start
reading through the first 10 and eight
out of 10 of them say the same person
that's usually a good sign that is the
one person who actually did it sometimes
it's not sometimes there's a bunch of
people trying to like claim that they're
the original and they might be dead or
they might not be selling that seed
anymore or that seed might not be
available in a pure form because it's
like their closely held cut and a
special thing to them so it's easy to be
like well if I can't just get the purple
punch then like why even grow any seeds
that are not the pure thing uh I just
want something called purple punch cuz I
want purple punch cuz purple punch
sounds good so I go and buy purple punch
from Barney's Farm Barney's Farm didn't
make purple punch and so they're going
to get some seeds that who knows if they
even have purple punch in them and um
some stuff from Barney's Farm is good
but um like their Tangerine Dream It's
good they have a Vanilla Kush that like
the men dope boys use they were featured
in 50 strains of Green for their tangan
Kush because because it's so high in a
few different T beIN and I'm pretty
confident that that is one that is from
them I couldn't find anywhere else the
Tangerine Dream came from so and same
with the Vanilla Kush like the Vanilla
Kush definitely came from Barney for uh
meno dopes crosses that they use any
vanilla stuff or for the most part and
so even though I don't like that breeder
because they have poor ethics I think
and they pushed like breeder Steve one
of the ogs out of the space bur a long
time thankfully he's back stars and
strip Seed Company shout out to Breer
Steve but um I actually made a Instagram
account because I got so many people
asking me you know who should I follow
like who should I get seeds from because
there's so many out there like I said
there's 10,000 strains and um so I was
like I could figure this out I made an
account called aromatic do Ain which is
a c h
NES yeah so aen is just like a seed and
Tao had uh something I think he's the
American one with ke with yeah I think
that's what it is so um I figured I
Googled what that was and I was like
okay cool seeds aromatic Ain and so I
was figured if I ever like got into
breeding or whatever I could maybe make
that my breeder name or something my my
brand but I ended up more so using it to
just follow breeders that I believe that
are good I'll read off a couple of them
ak ak Bean brains the real Crockett 420
lemon hoko genetics uh American one with
the KE we've got stayfly Farms who's
also known as original dster o original
uh Lone Star lar is on there uh iy
genetics Rost to Jeff I think shout out
I don't know if Lawrence larf actually
breeds I might have just accidentally
followed him because he's a homie uh
meno Dope Boys is on there they breed
Jinx Proof alien genetics humbl seed
organization hso uh we've got green
Source Gardens we've got LL seeds which
I think is TOS like how I have this
aromatic a kein I don't know if he ever
turned L low seeds into his actual thing
or not but I'm pretty sure he didn't uh
real Cali Connection I know some people
like to hate on Cali Connection but
they've grown some bred some really fire
stuff including the Deadhead OG featured
in 50 strains of green love that string
skunk house genetics creator of the
Donnie Burger one of my favorites second
generation genetics that's DJ Short's
son humble SE company Nat Pennington
he's cool I got to meet him and his
daughter at one of the conventions here
in California uh spy Ridge Farms they're
a smaller Boutique one we used to carry
some of their stuff in my uh delivery
Sin City Seeds Relentless genetics Bloom
Seed Co JBC seed bank that's a seed bank
not a breeder but Freeborn selections
mean that's mean jeene from Menino old
world genetics is um DJ Short Mr Nice
Seedbank is Shanti Baba green B and then
Mr Soul c99 Brothers Grim uh DNA
genetics they've got some pretty fire
stuff I know that like some people don't
like them in Crockett uh Supernova
Gardens exotic genetics symbiotic
genetics and subcool seeds and then
skunk Master Flex one which is the
creator of the Donny Burger but he also
goes by Skunk atic so that's the whole
list of the 40 people and you can go and
check out any of their Instagrams find
them on different seed banks if you grow
seeds from them and you don't like them
I'd be very surprised because all those
people that I listed are they've been
doing it for a long time and they work
with some of the best if not the best
stuff and I'm I'm picky I'll tell people
straight up like this your stuff's not
good like I don't or I don't like it not
to say that it's not good but like I do
think that I have a fairly um I try to
be a little bit objective in terms of
like there are certain qualities if it
smells if there's a certain amount of
smell even if it's not a smell that I
like I'm not a big fan of how GMO smells
but I know what it's supposed to smell
like and if it's present or not present
that'll dictate like how good the grade
is like a lot of commercial GMOs cut way
too early and you know may be harvested
for hash and tpin are added back in and
things like that so there's a difference
between that and like a flower that's
supposed to be grown 77 78 80 days that
gets taken at 60 or 62 or
50 yeah I agree I think genetics is one
of those things that people really need
to pay attention to because there are so
many other variables within the grow
that um but good genetics are are kind
of a constant where if you have
something that um is stable and grows
well and works for your um your
environment or for your endoc canabo
system whether you know kind of
depending on how you're going about uh
why you want to grow um yeah I feel like
genetics need to be at the top of your
list in terms of what you're looking for
uh to make sure sure that the grow goes
off without too many hitches I would say
and even your list of 40 you know there
I feel like there's just so many more
that could be added to that list um and
and there's those are just the ones that
I've vetted personally and can guarantee
cuz like I know that there's there's
people that I would like to add to that
list because I see the stuff that
they're doing and it looks really good
but then I also see like that person
hearded out six people's Gardens and now
all six of those five five out of six of
those people are no longer even growing
cannabis because it shuts them down and
so I'm like yeah I guess it it depends
on the application right like if you're
if you have the ability to to pheno hunt
then you know like maybe going through
someone like uh Caleb at CSI humble
where you get to just pop a whole bunch
of s1's of literally whatever strain you
can think of he probably has an S1 of it
if I didn't list him he should be on
that list because um either his account
got deleted or he is's definitely one
that I should have on there that maybe
isn't on there cuz I I grow CS I love
his stuff and I think he does great work
so I would definitely agree
wholeheartedly with that
and then in terms of like for hash and
stuff I always uh like if people can
find it I always tell them to look for
Oni seeds because like so much of his
work is so stable and so prolific in
other people's breeding projects I mean
shoot I use a military chocolate for
breeding when I do um and then there's
people you know that have made their
entire careers off of a cut of uh about
on Bloom like on and Bloom Seed Co
because I know I think Bloom Seed Co is
one of On's original like I think they
used to be partners and maybe that's why
no idea I know that Oni stopped selling
seeds for a while because he wanted to
just put all of his seed stock into
production at a recreational facility
that he helped open in San Diego um so I
know more into that [ __ ] I'm in San
Diego so I need to I need to look into
the whole Oni thing cuz um when I
initially looked into it I thought Bloom
was kind of the direction that they went
with the more modern and I think it was
either a friend or uh you know C-
breeder or something like that and I
know Masonic is another one who works
with a lot of like On's uh like his
Wilson I think came from the Wilson
zero yeah so it's it's um that's you
know I definitely am a fan of what I've
seen come out of Oni but uh like I said
I think I just generically included
Bloom because that's where I saw like a
lot of the hash makers even now still
today will say like same thing about
Bloom if you're going to make any hash
like Bloom seedco is uh y they're
specifically breeding stuff and I should
probably add another one Farmhouse but I
haven't grown any other stuff but um
Farmhouse PDX like they do schwall yeah
they're photography is insane and the
stuff that they're breeding looks
incredible I just haven't gotten around
to trying it and don't knowbody anybody
who has yet and so that's got me
reticent to include it because it's like
a lot of stuff looks really really good
and then I try some of it and it's like
not as good as I was expecting or um but
if I hear enough good opinions I think
that might be more open into it I just
don't know like I like to know somebody
personally like that I've talked to a
lot that has been like I grew this and
it was top 10 top five like I mean
you're basically giving it your stamp of
approval you have to be pretty uh
assured that you're not giving that to
someone that either doesn't deserve it
or that may fall short of the
expectations that people that want to
listen to you are looking for um so I I
get it vetting is very important and um
you know it's great to have people like
you out there that are putting in time
and effort into reviewing these
different strains and putting in as as
accurate and holistic of information out
there as possible for people to use when
they're starting up their new grow
that's um it's a valiant effort and I'm
sure it takes a lot of time and effort I
mean you know it it may not be the most
uh you may not suffer while doing it
though if you get to try all these
different strains it's a fun it's a fun
process you know uh the discovery is is
good there's a lot of listening to
podcasts involved there's a lot of
trying different stuff out uh myself and
talking to people who've tried the same
stuff or or you know similar things from
those breeders and kind of
conglomerating it all into one massive
thing like 50 strands of green came
together a lot faster than purple I you
know and like I gave less than 50
breeders in my little list or whatever
there's probably about 50 but I think
like a to be in a top 50 of anything in
the world like you're doing pretty dang
good top 10 or whatever is like
unbelievable and like to be the best
like you really have to dedicate your
whole entire life I think in most cases
to something uh you might get dumb luck
sometimes but a lot of people are really
working really hard and those people I
can guarantee are going to provide solid
product customer service Etc and um yeah
yeah it's 50 strands of purple is
finished actually now and I'm just
getting with my formatter who's getting
a new computer or something in uh
February so the pre-order will be going
live for that soon but that's been like
exciting two three years in the making
like it's yeah I was able to get more
strains initially like than I did for
green like I got my top 50 pretty quick
like I was able to like narrow it down
to that 50 and like it almost never
changed Maybe added one or subtracted
one but like 50 strands of purple I
started with like 60 or 75 and have
narrowed that down to 50 and then like
when I got to 50 I dropped a couple
because I was like this isn't as good as
that this is better than that like you
know and I was a little worried cuz like
I have a couple related like a few
different runs and I'm like well should
I just put this all under like one runs
should like that's how I took the gelato
approach is all just one gelato and it
described the different cuts of G in
there but the um runs Cuts were so
different from one another that I
describe a few different ones because
their taste or their impact like U
medically were so much different from
the next runs that I was like this is
like a whole different strain so I'm not
just going to include it in the same
thing because it has the same name or
some similar shared genetic it would be
like trying to describe alls as one
thing you know it there there's such
vast differences from like uh like an OG
cush to a Tahoe OG or a white Tahoe
cookies even where it is like an OG
leaning cookies asphal yeah exactly and
then you have yeah within runs I feel
like it was like the dawn of the candy
gas era and within that you know I feel
like candy gas is a spectrum you have
stuff that's more leaning towards that
gassy fuy burn your nose even rubbery at
times all the way to this like pungent
sickly sweet candy that like you're
standing in the middle of a candy store
on a hot day um like and and anywhere in
between and so it it would be really
hard to describe those all is one um
especially considering the different
cannaboid profiles that you're going to
find across that Spectrum as well so I'm
I'm glad that you're taking so much
effort and and painstaking time into
making sure that this accurately
represents um what is kind of the
current wave of uh of cannabis
throughout not only you know the
recreational and legal Market but the
world everyone wants purple every wants
everyone wants candy and everyone wants
gas even the origins of those purples
it's like a lot of people don't agree on
where it came from a lot of people don't
agree on what it is and um I would say
maybe even before runs the dawn of the
candy gas was that purple punch purple
punch is super candy gas like if you get
a good it's straight up grape uh Jolly
Rancher with gasoline like it it's super
like you said it can be candy store it I
found out it was methyl anthranilate
just because I was like what is
artificial grape smell because I was
like this is exactly that like there's
no way my nose is like I I've had enough
of those Jolly Ranchers to tell you like
that grape Jolly Rancher has a certain
chemical in there and it's the same
chemical that is in the purple punch and
sure enough I found studies and stuff
that showed cannabis does produce methyl
anthranol and that is what was making it
smell like that it's like sometimes if
it smells the same it actually is the
same like grapes can make Lang Langs can
make it like a few other different
things in nature produce it so it's a
speaking of Oni we had we have a cross
of his that we um run commercially
that's a beach grapes but we call it the
um like one pheno we called conquered
Crush because it smelled so much like
conquered grapes and and you find methyl
anthranilate and conquered grapes as
well and um and it's but it's pungent
and and heavy and Stony and so it's like
a a purple punch without the same Bea
beauty that purple punch has but with
all the flavor and all the potency and
and you know on level 10 I'll trade the
frost for you know potency and and other
things to be honest like I'm realizing
more now I want to move away from Frosty
strains because for sure we've all
picked towards Frosty for so long and
like granted some of them do have
potency um but I'm like 50 strains of
green I I feel like a lot of the strains
in there some even like some of the old
school chem 91 uh OG Kush like '90s
strains are still some of the strongest
smokers today and it's not just me
saying that like I worked at a delivery
service my wife has worked at a
dispensary as delivery services people
are still saying I want gas I want OG I
want Kush you know I want this classic
and these are people that have been
smoken 10 20 30 40 50 years and they
want just OG like I I had one guy if I
if it wasn't gassy enough or cushy
enough he just wouldn't even accept it
get to his place and be like fair enough
not gassy enough sorry like I he knows
himself well that's awesome yep and I
was the same way with like a I ordered a
a jack her or herrer um here when I was
you know just moving out and I was still
getting stuff from delivery services and
um they came with like an XJ 13 or
something they're like well it's a jack
her cross and I was like yeah but it's
not Jack Herr like I'm looking for Jack
her not you know xj13 like yeah there's
Jack in that and it smells Jack is but
like I've smoked xj13 and it's different
like it's different high it's like Jack
with Gummy Bears yeah and there's like
there's more like it's it's messed up
the genetic profile like that it's
already a messy genetic profile it's
it's a whole bunch of whole bunch of
different things and uh it makes a
really beautiful result I love its
result I think it's again like with blue
dream one of my favorite daytime smokes
and I think it's underappreciated
because some people don't grow it that
well and a lot of people have uh taken
that name and and thrown it on a bunch
of different genetics but like the real
stuff that's like terpinolene heavy uh
it's like creative nice Focus nice
uplifter I'm a huge fan of where where
it puts me at least mentally
nice I remember smoking that back in
like 2009 when I was going to Sacramento
State and I was like oh my I I never
knew that cannabis could taste like a
fruit basket and it was like the
fruitiest strain that I've ever had in
my life at that point with like you know
mainly leaning towards Citrus and I was
just so impressed by it and I think that
was like one of the first things where
it was not just either purple or OG cuz
that was kind of what was popular in the
Bay Area at the time um so I you know I
I really like how this conversation has
gone so far and and your dedication to
the Cannabis Community is up there
amongst you know so many people that I
have respect for um and one of the
questions that I do like to ask people
when they're on here especially when you
do have so much experience um running a
weekly podcast interacting with hom
Growers uh breeding homeg growing
yourself um seeing different commercial
spots and their uh in in their operation
um what would you like to see change in
the Cannabis space whether it be uh from
a hom Grower's perspective or a
commercial perspective or anywhere in
between really to me it'd be more and
larger hom grows lessen up the
regulations lessen up the restrictions
allow everyone in California to grow
outside immediately we have 67% of our
state that has bandn outdoor or
Greenhouse cultivation which is a shame
because we have some of the best
sunlight in the world and we grow some
of the best egg products in the world
and I don't think anyone's going to be
harmed byy a little bit of cannabis
growing outside as is evidenced by the
33% of the state that's already doing it
and having any issues so I think we need
to grow up and be adults about it and
say this is an agricultural crop this is
a Horticultural crop as well and it can
be grown at field scale uh you know for
bulk and for lots of reasons you can
make flower out of that stuff you can
make concentrate out of it you can do
whatever you want with it it can be
turned to rope or seed whatever um but I
think we need to allow a hom grower to
grow 100 PL in their backyard if they
want to in a hoop house and if they need
to make that into RSO then so be it and
if they want to use all that RSO
themselves so be it if they want to give
it to their friend or family member who
got cancer then so be it we need to
lessen up the regulations and allow more
just open free cultivation for home
Growers because that's where we get so
much more diversity like there's this
guy who famously saved like 150
different types of apples and he would
carry around all the different apples
and show them to people and sell seeds
and keep them alive and I think we need
to sort of be that person who's doing it
because otherwise as we see with the
commercial Apple Market there's like
four five six big varieties that get
grown and then everything else is just
lost and sort of like with 50 strains of
green or 50 strains of Purple like I
don't want genetic diversity to be lost
to history um yeah there's a reason some
stuff's more popular some stuff tastes
better and some stuff's easier to grow
and uh this and that but like just
because
something even with like ugly looking
bud and like going away from the frosty
stuff like just because something is not
the prettiest um in like the Apple
Market maybe it's not a eating apple but
it becomes a cider apple right so you
can use it for different things like
there's certain stuff that is better for
washing like GMO is not the prettiest
flower it gets kind of fox taish looking
and if you grow it as long as it should
and you get it in the right environments
where I think it likes to be it's not
real appealing for flower but it make
some of the best concentrate in the
world and we need to be able to say hey
some strains need to be taken even if
you're taking it for concentrate 70 80
days and let that happen and even
allowing like the home Growers to have
larger numbers so that they can grow
those 16 22 week however long uh long
flowering plants because right now if
you only can have six plants it's sort
of limiting you to not growing that
strain that takes two three four times
as long to finish as some of the other
ones so I think that would allow people
to have access to what the plant is
really for ultimately which is to serve
us
and uh help us I think at least how we
use it uh to live our best life if it's
to you know have a a medicine that
treats one of your ailments or if it's
just for the pure enjoyment that adults
are able to have adult use I think that
all use is medicinal even if there is
the adult use kind of mentality but the
more we have the better we have the
better the world is going to get I've
seen it like although there's a lot of
setbacks like there there's currently
big wildfires and some of them have
stretched on to San Diego and I am okay
thankfully the San Diego fire
department's been doing an amazing job
with the Ramona fire and with the pal of
fire here uh recently but they are doing
incredible but you know it's just um the
more and better herb that we have the
better I think Society is going to get
like we at least in my own personal
experience I feel myself I'm more
thoughtful more levelheaded more
centered uh more peaceful happy person
when I'm able able to use it and I think
if we have more people in society it's
like when you're hungry if you're hangry
then your life's going to be worse like
if you're perpetually hungry like some
people are 20% of the US kids are uh
food insecure they don't know where the
next meal is coming from some of them
are literally starving or underfed uh
don't have enough nutrients per day so
like it's harder for them to focus in
school and things like that so um if you
can fill those voids if you can give
those kids food they tend to perform
better well I think if you can fill the
void in the endoc canabo system we'll
see a big lessoning and endoc canabo
system deficiency syndromes like I think
I work in the autism space everyone in
my families are either on CBD or um
ratio of CBD to THC or both and it's
benefit almost 80 to 90% of the clients
that I I work with and that was no
pushing on my own they kind of found it
got into it and I just advocated on top
of like hey you know maybe try this or
that or maybe this might help but
they've all found benefit in their own
ways and I think it's going to expand
out to other maybe ailments Parkinson's
and uh things like that like your dad's
with the you know Tremors and things
like that there's so many different
places places that it can help and the
more we allow home Growers to grow wide
volumes and varieties of cannabis the
more we're going to find those blue
dream hashes that make me stop shaking
for my hash you know uh you know for my
arthritis and you will be able to find
those things and everyone will be able
to find those things maybe not just to
help themselves but to help their father
to help their grandfather to help a
friend to help anybody a stranger in the
community like we should be able to help
I have an 80 two 80 plus year old
neighbors that we've got you know a
little bit of cannabis in their systems
and it's helping them out and you know I
think that we're technically not doing
things all like how you're supposed to
we don't have licenses and this and that
we just like give them stuff you we're
not selling them anything so it's uh
more of just a passion to try and help
people and help ourselves and in so
doing I think we all it's not 100% just
uh altruistic there's a good feeling we
get from seeing people uh heal and
seeing people get better and um they
become our Advocates as well cuz like we
love Canabis helping somebody else with
it they become your Advocates and and
advocates for everybody because they
love it so much and they see how
valuable it is I mean we are such
community-based creatures human beings
that to see a community succeed um
through the efforts that you put into
it there's there's just yeah there's
this huge positive feeling that is
associated with that and I feel like
advocating for Access is such a huge
part of what needs to continue to to
happen um because with that advocacy for
Access I feel like help it helps break
down the stigma um and um you know even
through the organizations like normal
where it's to normalize um cannabis you
know everybody's used to seeing a
relative or even themselves or you know
anybody that they know have a have a
glass of wine at the end of the day or a
few beers or even some cocktails or not
or whatnot um and and to add cannabis to
that list it almost seems like a
no-brainer um especially considering
like no
one I I feel like no one does like the
the crazy stuff that you can do when you
get hammered drunk uh when you're the
same level of stoned it's it's just not
necessarily the same in that aspect it's
not the same category it's safer yeah
talk to any canab or to any bouncer or
to any police officer would you rather
deal with a room full of people that are
so high they you know just stoned off
their butt or would you rather deal with
a group of people that is intoxicated on
alcohol meth Coke any one of those other
drugs you want to name like it's so much
easier for an officer to deal with
people that are on like weed or maybe
even like shrooms or something like that
like people they're just a lot less uh I
like a peaceful Society you know like I
I had my home broken into I know what
it's like to not have peace I know what
it's like to feel at at risk it's a lot
more fun to be you know relaxed and and
chilling out and just not worried about
uh the things that we've evolved to not
have to worry about like our basic
survival our basic needs of like am I
safe do I have food do I have shelter
and uh you know enjoying the Lesser and
ler time like we talked about it the
earli part in the show with you know
even the friends that I'm close with you
only get so much time with them so
getting to you know some of us have
anxiety whether it's social anxiety or
whatever like even hanging out with
friends or family can be difficult so if
you can lessen that down so you can
enjoy that time a little bit more it's
just like uh and you know some people
might say oh you're an addict or that's
a crutch or this and that but I think
when it's looked at like a medicine you
wouldn't say that to a diabetic about
using insulin or to anybody else about
using their medicine so I think it's uh
sort of an old forgotten Trope at this
point in some places and some places
still do have the stigma and stereotypes
I'm glad normal keeps pushing because um
I am seeing it become more normalized
like more and more it's like you ask
like somebody if they smoke and more
often than not they're
like yes and then there's not even the
discussion of like is it cigarettes or
cannabis it's like just cannabis in
certain circles in certain places and
it's getting to be more and more of that
or like they'll be like oh smoke what
question mark dot dot dot and like it
opens up that conversation because
they'll be like oh well I can actually
legally talk about this because maybe I
won't lose my job now maybe I won't lose
my kids or maybe I won't have my house
rated or whatever it is so it's like the
freedoms that we gain by having
regulation move the right direction
allow us to l and some of those
stressors that are related to or not
related to even the use of the plant
just the absolutely living with the laws
around
it absolutely I couldn't agree more with
what you said that uh and uh honestly I
feel like that's that's a great note to
start wrapping up the show here I do
like to always ask a few um sort of
ubiquitous cannabis podcast questions uh
towards the end of the show because I
find them to be just a fun way to wrap
up and uh get the same same questions
out to everyone um so uh what what would
be your favorite strain of all time like
your desert island
strain right now I'd have to say Donnie
Burger nice uh is it for effects uh
flavor um it's the effect it's so strong
it's so strong and it's just like
um I really do like a a potent just like
fully even though I might use it during
the daytime for the most part it's going
to be a night time like hang out on the
couch watch something with the wife
maybe eat a little dinner um it relieves
pain very very strong it's so sedating
and like I said I'm kind of a chatty guy
it's one of the ones the rare ones that
can kind of allow me to just like Zen
out and not feel like I have to talk or
think about something to say or uh you
know whatever it is it's just more of a
I almost joke that it feels like you got
whopped over the head with like a Nerf
bat and uh maybe it's because my Spanish
teacher used to like literally do that
to people and she didn't wouldn't do it
hard
but she had like a a little it was like
a plastic bat and it had like a a foam
cover around it and she would like whack
people over the head with it if they
like one kid fell asleep and she whopped
him with it popped him oh that's funny
yeah old days man but uh she never even
got in any any amount of trouble for
that but uh it's just funny to but some
strains like when I take a hit of it
like it almost feels like a tingle the
reason I say that is it almost like hits
me like right here on the front of the
forehead and then like that tingly
feeling almost like like have you ever
ever been punched like that's not a
great feeling but like the U sensation
of something the pain or like the
reaction of like you know it it travels
from like you got hit in your jaw and it
travels up to your brain your body is
processing what happened and with a
punch obviously it sucks but with like
the bong hit it's like a nice tingly
like oh I almost got like a like a
pretty like my wife walked by or
something like oh I got some tingly like
a happy tingle going on not just like in
like the nether regions but like in your
face and like your shoulders and down
your spine and like in your legs and
like it can extend to all parts of your
body but not even just the tinglin but
sort of the um decrease inflammation
which I think helps with the pain um cuz
I have I work out a fair amount and I'm
my job is just very active but um yeah
that that's the main reason pain relief
relaxation and just Ultra potency like
it's probably as close to a 10 out of 10
without being like a fi fickle chem 91
as I can come across in terms of like
that sedating side of things and the
uplifting side of things like Jack the
Ripper would be like the super super
high like crazy uplifting Rippy sativa
that's like I'm so paranoid my heart's
like like what's going on it's just weed
man take a breath you're going to be
fine for sure awesome those are great
answers um and then uh so as a followup
to that one who would be your favorite
breeder of all time I'd have to give it
to subcool even though he's not selling
seeds anymore um if it we're talking
about some could get seeds from right
now it be skunk house genetics because
the Burger work Donnie burger and
otherwise I think all of the burgers are
good double burger triple Burger uh Han
Solo Burger they're basically a really
good representation of what happens when
you cross together um a good OG with a
basically mix of cookies and cams like
the GMO is a garlic cookies from mamiko
seeds and the guy skunk Master Flex
bought that found the feno that became
GMO
which is you know just the garlic
cookies from them which is a GMO to chem
4 or chem D I can't remember which chem
it was and then you cross that into a
Larry OG f8 male and that Larry OG f8
just brings like power and Frost and
Funk and the combination of the GMO and
that Laro gf8 made that Han Solo and
then he crossed it back to the GMO which
made the Donnie burger and any of the
burgers they're just combinations of
basically all that genetic and um it
just Works in my endoc cannaboid system
and I tend to find a lot of people it's
like it might put them to sleep in half
an hour but it's a a strong potency
almost across the board and yeah that
that guy breeds nothing but fire and I
don't know anybody else really that BR
anything to f8 that used that male to
such solid effect like his work really
seemed to pay off and in
Spades absolutely I I feel like burgers
are one of one of my favorites when it
comes to like a gassy or a funky strain
um and yeah Donnie is the one that I
haven't tried unfortunately but I've
always heard good things about it um
yeah that's that's awesome to hear
that's when I got F2 I've got like five
seeds of it left so girl's out and make
some f and send them out yeah share them
with their Community absolutely I don't
think he sells it anymore I wouldn't
want to like step on his toes if he is
selling no I don't I think I even looked
like I think it hasn't been available
for many years at this point
unfortunately
um all right so just one last question
then uh what has been your most uh
memorable smoking or cannabis related
experience that had to be growing out
some of subcool strains and then meeting
Tommy Chong my wife won a Instagram
contest and uh we got to go meet Tommy
Chong at L Cafe which is like the first
Cannabis Cafe in Hollywood that was
legally allowed to smoke in like in
public and it's like going to a bar like
I brought my own weed so I had to pay an
unbottle fee like how you pay an
uncorking fee if you bring your own wine
so I did that cuz I didn't want to buy
their [ __ ] and I had pre-rolled like a
box full of joints and I had a
strawberry daquiri and I had Chernobyl
so like a really strawberry flavored and
then like a kind of almost like a
margarita like lemon lime slurpie
flavored and they're both more uplifting
it was the daytime so I was like you
know good smell good flavor and really
potent on both of them and they both
just the flavors rang true and like my
wife was the one who won so there was 10
people at the table there's like five
seats on each side or whatever and like
Tommy Chong like one of the other
promoters or whatever and there was no
seats at the end of the table and so
like I wasn't supposed to I was just
sitting there like watching like them
all smoke or whatever and like within
like half an hour my wife comes over and
she grabs a few of my joints and she's
smoking them and they're like whose
joints are these like blah blah blah oh
that's my husband like he grew it blah
blah blah and so they invite me over to
the table and they pull up a t a chair
at the end so I got to sit and smoke
joints with Tommy Chong for like the
next three hours and uh he was like the
exact guy you expect from the movies and
TV shows interviews he's actually come
on and podcast I bet you if you ask him
he'd come on potentially he's done the
uh we should probably ask him to come on
he's so cool he's getting older so got
to get him on at some point but he did
um some of the European or european
buddies I can't remember if it was
Percy's grow room or one of the other
guys over there um but he's been on
their show a couple times actually and
yeah he was super cool like they say
don't meet your heroes or whatever um
because often times you get let down
like their personality is not as maybe
they're busy maybe they're hungry maybe
they're tired maybe they just have met
way too many people then get swarmed
with hey can I get a picture can I get
an autograph this and that I get it I
would never ever want to actually be
famous like give me all the riches sure
but I would never want to be famous it
seemed almost like a curse at this point
in many cases it ruins a lot of lives so
I get them not wanting to have that
interaction but Tommy Jong was the
opposite of that and in the Cannabis
space I think he's on Mount Rushmore for
me it'd be like him Willie Nelson Snoop
and uh I don't know some others but yeah
he's definitely way up there and the
fact that I even met him that wouldn't
even have been on my bucket list like I
grew up watching his movies and stuff
and never thought I could meet him and
let alone smoke with him for like hours
and have that kind of real human
connection especially with stuff that I
grew myself that like he was blown away
by and like I got a they caught him on
video like smelling the jar and like he
had a really big smile I's like what woo
like he's impressed by I was just like
damn this dude has been smoking for a
long time he thinks my shit's good I I
thought it was good right like I'm like
oh I grow good stuff right but like to
see somebody like that give a good
reaction it was almost like a big pat on
the back for me for sure I mean to me
good homeg grow is going to be good
commercial 10 out of 10 and that's what
the commercial guy who was there with
him who had like a 10 lighter and 100
lighter he's like dude I miss the days
when I could grow craft like this he's
go look how white your Ash is look how
good this stuff smells he's like you're
doing it even better than we can do it
and I was like you know what that took
all those shitty hating Instagram
comments and and people on the internet
that are like oh you're just a tent
grower you're just a closet grower
you're just a small home grower blah
blah blah what do you know your stuff's
this and that it's like you haven't
smoked it you don't know if it's good or
not like it could be garbage you might
be right maybe it doesn't look the best
maybe it's not but at the same time I'll
take the hom grower side 99 out of 100
times like I think they're gonna ABS out
the commercial competition unless they
are just doing it for the first time and
really didn't get their feet underneath
them yeah absolutely I couldn't agree
more um well Jack this has been an
awesome conversation thank you so much
for joining me today um I'm sure that
people are going to love hearing a
little bit more about your journey with
cultivation and uh your humble
beginnings as a as a leaf pickup boy all
the way up through creating strains that
you've seen hundreds of people grow out
now it's a an inspiring Journey that you
know mostly we want to get more people
out there and more people growing at
home so again thank you so much I really
really appreciate your time and um I
hope you have just a wonderful rest of
your week thank you so much for having
me have a good one yeah absolutely
[Music]
oh