[Music]
Hello and welcome to another episode of
the Way We Grow podcast, a production of
the Craft Growers Network. I am your
host, Nick Wolf. Today our guest is
Jared Richie of Next Big Crop. Jared,
welcome to the show. Thank you for
having me. Appreciate it, Nick. Yeah,
for sure. It's uh it's great to have you
here. you came highly recommended by one
of our former um our former guests,
Jesse of Mothership Labs. So, it's great
to have someone else on here who's uh as
professional as he is and um you know,
but from a different angle of of uh sort
of what you're applying that cannabis uh
knowledge to in your professional life.
Um so, why don't you tell the audience a
little bit about your background and
what Next Big Crop is and what you do
there? Sure. Thank you. Um, so I guess,
uh, you know, in a former life, I was a
secondary social studies teacher. Um,
and you know, I bartended for years and
stuff like that before that. Um, but you
know, sort of graduated college and
then, uh, moved out to Denver, you know,
I guess it's almost 18ish or so years
ago. Um, so I moved out here and then I
got a job at this really cool bar. Um,
like in, you know, just neighborhood
spot that had live music three, five
nights a week. Um, and sort of didn't
really, you know, you know, like those
small sort of things that like really
change your life forever kind of thing,
you know? So that bar Highland Pacific,
um, we used to joke it was almost like
Highland Pacific Wellness Center at
night. Um, so there's a whole lot of
talented gardeners and just music people
and just, you know, sort of all walks of
life there. Um, so you know, I got that
job and I went back to school to finish
my, you had a social studies degree and
I went back to get my education sort of
degree as well to be a teacher. So I was
bartending and going to school and then
one of the owners was like, "Do you want
to come trim for us?" So he kind of
drugged me up the hill to Netherland
where they had some houses going and
started trimming for him and then real
quick after that I was like, "Well, I
want my own lights and I want to do this
on my own." Um, yeah. So started doing
that while I finished my teaching
degree. So I would like bartend at night
and go to school during the day and
somehow started growing a bunch of weed
in between, you know, all of that and
like I think I hid it from my friends
for about a year what I was doing. Um,
you know, before somebody kind of
finally figured it out. Um, sure. You
know, that kind of thing. So, um, when I
finished my teaching degree and I, you
know, started teaching and I realized
that I didn't really want to sort of
continue with that. Um, I, uh, called a
buddy at one of the local hydro shops,
uh, way to grow. And I was like, coach,
will you hire me? You know, I want a
job. I don't want to be a teacher. And
he was like, cool. You start Monday.
We're going on a fish tour. Um, so then
pretty much, yeah, it was one of the
like they had a happy hour for all the
all the teachers and they were like
trying to on like a Friday trying to get
me to like commit to taking this job and
I skipped that happy hour and I went and
I hung up eight lights in a friend's
garage. Um, nice, you know, kind of
thing. And then that Monday, I started
working at Way to Grow. Um so then uh
you know we talk about way to grow and
that sort of education as we continue
but like you know that was like a it was
like way to grow university. It really
kind of a whole lot of like like-minded
people doing a lot of work working at
the same stores doing everything. So I
worked there for a good four or five
years. Um you know and had lots of
projects going on here kind of um like
passion projects if you will. And then
uh um you know, you sort of hit that
point where you're like just getting
tired of sitting behind the counter at
Way to Grow and solving everybody else's
problems. Um you know, and you sort of
develop this like process of deduction
sort of procedure, instinct, you know,
kind of thing. People just come up and
sort of dump their problems on you. You
try to help them solve it. So I applied
for a job at a local uh local grow here
in town. Um and wait or next big crop
was actually managing it. So, they were
kind of like, you're a little
overqualified for the position we're
looking for. Um, and then maybe two,
three months later, I got a job
interview with Next Big Crop. Um, the
group, yeah, the consulting group that
was managing it. And then I got a job
with Next Crop. So, sort of managed that
spot and then we had a spot up in
Glenwood Springs, this like beautiful
greenhouse. And then um it turned into a
big like 50,000 square foot spot in
Maryland that was uh like a super
educational experience with a really
good crew. Um like next big crop wrote
all the applications for this group
green leaf uh green leaf which is in
like Maryland and then Pennsylvania,
Virginia, Ohio, maybe New Jersey. So
sort of designed all their spots um you
know filled it up, taught them how to
operate. Um they sold to Columbia Care
for like couple hundred million dollars
kind of thing after a few years. Yeah,
it was a big one. Like definitely
feather in the hat like you know I think
we designed and started operating with
them like I don't know just shy probably
200,000 square foot kind of thing. Um
you know they really turned it on. Um
and then since then you know did
Oklahoma and next big crop was part of a
publicly traded company uh called
General Cannabis. Um, so when some of
the laws changed about publicly traded
companies actually owning uh sort of
cannabis businesses, they were about to
sell us to one of the competitors
because they wanted to go into a
different direction. So myself and now
my two partners, Rich and Christian, um,
sort of decided to buy Next Big Crop
away and went private from general
cannabis. So that was I think August
will be four years or maybe five years
at this point that we've been private
and away from the publicly traded group.
So like in that time you know I've done
all kinds of all kinds of stuff you know
pretty much every you know just it
really depends like where we meet a
client in in their journey you know some
application writing some financial
models and all that kind of stuff um
then we would design facilities for them
you know we have engineers and like you
know depending on you know building from
the ground up or you know sort of a
retrofit to something else that was
already existing um you know and then
from all the way to grow years sort of
had all those contacts with every sort
of supplier and rep and nutrient company
and lighting manufacturer. So pretty
much have every wholesale account um you
can you know you can imagine. Um so then
we sort of will outfit those facilities
with all the equipment spec all the
stuff you know do like P and like you
know irrigation designs fertigation
stuff um like all the building
management systems um and then in lots
of these spots with like competitive new
markets uh it's not like Colorado or
California, Oregon, Washington um where
there's sort of that legacy work that
had been done. So then I started getting
on planes and flying out there and
teaching people how to run their
facilities kind of thing. Um, for sure.
You know, so did that for a handful of
people. Um, and I guess sort of still do
that till today. You know, now we're
just a little bit more selective of who
we work with and, uh, kind of like the
projects, you know, you have to make
sure everybody's like same values, equal
vision, like that kind of thing. So,
right. Um, really kind of whatever
somebody needs, we have done and we'll
continue to assist. For sure. Yeah. It's
really hard to take on a project when
the, you know, the vision doesn't align
with uh what you can provide because
sometimes people want to like do
something that's so esoteric or like
very unique and it's like they want that
uniqueness to be their their sort of
brand and their their stamp that they're
putting on the the product that's coming
out of it. But in a lot of aspects,
these legacy practices are not
sustainable in the current market. And
uh it's really hard to find people that
are willing to change and understanding
that there is ways to improve and that
maybe their secret sauce isn't that
secret. Yeah. Well, and also just like
you know
um we don't need to reinvent the wheel
here either kind of thing. Like there
really is sort of like that, you know,
every situation is different, like every
every single one is different, but there
really has to like sort of be this like
sort of uh optimal like execution of
this plan, you know, like so sometimes
people think that I'm going to come in
and do this. So, I'm going to, you know,
and like sure on paper maybe that not
even on paper, maybe just like in
fantasy that sounds great, but on paper
it makes whatever as much sense, you
know, in reality like um it doesn't when
it comes to some of these more like
commercial competitive situations. Um,
you know, like I don't know, like don't
get me wrong, it's fun to fantasize
about all this. I'm going to do this,
I'm going to do that, but like you're
like, yeah, it's expensive. It's costly
to make mistakes or to not have that
right vision. So, like really is a lot
of thinking and planning. Do do you have
the ability to talk about any um
uh people that were looking to become
your clients that you had to turn down?
I mean, you don't even need to
necessarily name them, but perhaps some
of the things that they were trying to
achieve that were untenable and just not
necessarily um feasible with either what
they had available to them for resources
or in general, you know, if it was
something where it was just like this is
poor agriculture and you shouldn't be
doing this and if that's your sticking
point, then we're out. Sure. you know, I
guess one some of the, you know, maybe
10 and 15 years ago, um, when it was
more of a competitive market, and when I
say competitive, I mean like limited
licenses going out, people would throw
money at you sort of without thinking,
um, you know, so people could raise one,
two, 10, whatever, however many millions
of dollars to sort of build these
spaceships, if you will, um, to operate.
Um, and I guess it's not quite the same
as, you know, today as it is then, you
know, so lots of people sort of have
these grand visions, but they really
don't have the capital to back it up or
they don't really have the experience to
back it up. Um, you know, so again, it's
like, sure, dude, you could throw up 10
lights in a garage with your buddies
over a weekend. Um, but you can't do
that with 500 lights when the city's
inspecting you, the fire marshal
inspecting you, and like there's all of
that sort of compliance that has to go
with it. So I'd say like the biggest
hang-up is people really you know sure
it you know the dream of what they want
it to be kind of thing and also like
people don't realize how much it really
costs to operate and you know lots of
people you know now you have lawyers you
have CPAs you have all of this stuff
that kind of goes along with it um in
like that professional world that you
don't have with like a passion project
at your house and so I feel like that's
probably the biggest you know are people
trying to show you know one of those
things like you can fit this much light
because you have this much power. So,
your HVAC, you know, everything's got to
fit numbers wise, right? Um, you know,
for these facilities to work or you
could be like the best grower in the
world, but you don't have enough, you
know, dehumidification to have control
or, you know, so trying to sort of
balance like the fantasy verse reality
verse like true expectations like you're
never going to
hit three and four pounds every time.
there's going to be hiccups, you know.
So, just people having the realistic uh
understanding of sort of how hard it is
to, you know, to sort of hit repeat
repeat repeat
um right um is probably the biggest, you
know, and I guess some of the new stuff
is, you know, I'm going to do autos from
C, you know, and which I love, whatever,
you know, but again, yeah, there's just
like I guess the new the new I'm going
to do this, it's going to re, you know,
I'm going to reinvent the game and all
this kind of stuff. If you're like, "No,
man. Like, don't get me wrong, some of
those ideas are totally real. They work.
People are executing them." Um, but
you've never done this before. So, just
to sort of gamble on something so big.
Uh, sure. You know, that kind of thing.
Yeah. It almost like helps to set up
people's expectations uh within reason
so that they know that, you know, and we
see this all the time, too. whenever um
we'll I'll go and look at another
facility or something and people are
asking for help that they'll you know
they'll be like this is my goal and
sometimes the goal does not match what
you have available to achieve that goal
and setting up more reasonable
expectations for what you already have
available is so crucial because you can
create you know I I haven't seen a
facility that doesn't have the ability
to create awesome product the thing is
is that They have to be okay with either
a quantity uh of awesome product that
you know may not be what they were
originally hoping for which kind of can
temper some expectations down a little
bit where they're going oh man I really
wanted to you know 10x my investment
within the first 2 years and you're
going that's going to be uh maybe 5 to
10 years from now uh if you're lucky and
you don't have crop loss after crop loss
due to you you know, your lack of HVAC
or your uh your use of your reuse of
soil if you're in some sort of like
living soil facility or, you know, your
input costs are, you know, you you
initially bought this giant pallet of
inputs, you know, 5 years ago and it's
been sitting there and working great,
but when you start to look into buying
it again, it's going to be, you know, 10
times the cost that it was 5 years ago.
Um,
and also one of the biggest ones is I
feel like right along the lines what
you're saying is like when when markets
open the price per pound is however high
you know as more facilities open um you
know I don't even know where we want to
start with that number you know kind of
thing but like right you know if you
can't basically sell your pounds at
$1,000 a pound and still be profitable
with that you know like you can still
run a profitable business at that um but
if it cost you 800 bucks to pro a pound
and the market's really only offering
$600 to $800 a pound for that, you know,
that that sort of model that you gave
all your investors a year or two years
prior um is just like irrelevant. So
that's probably one of the hardest
things
to get everybody on the same page with
is kind of like um sort of understanding
the cost of that operation verse what
when the pound, you know, when a market
gets flooded and it comes down like you
know where's that balance point?
I mean, Oklahoma is a great example uh
and case study for anybody that wants to
look into where it started and where it
is. Um, and it happened so quickly, you
know, like I feel like Oregon and
California, while they did have, you
know, massive booms in production when
everything went legal and recreational,
uh, the price never plummeted as fast in
such a short amount of time. you know,
we we we're all still now around the
same price across the country,
unfortunately, but um it took us a
decade to get there versus 18 months.
Yeah. You know, did a lot of work in
Oklahoma when that sort of went off. Um
and just like you sort of say like, you
know, everybody's got their own thoughts
about this that whatever, but like in
Oklahoma there was like two agents or so
something like that for the whole state
and they gave out 13,000 some licenses,
you know. So there was no inspections,
there was no whatever, you know, like
basically, you know, um, you know, we
built a really beautiful greenhouse for
a client that we operated and like the
only rules were basically like you could
do whatever you wanted outside as long
as it was behind a fence, you know. So I
filled up an acre and did what I could,
you know, and you know, next summer,
yeah, at the end of the summer, we had
4,000 some pounds on the one acre, you
know, and that was just one acre. And I
knew of farms that had 50 and you know
there was the stories of the guys with
500 and you know so at that point there
was more product there than you know in
a short time than anywhere else. Yeah.
And it it's still not even recreational
is it? No. They shot that down. Yeah.
That's a medical market. That's insane.
Yeah. without interstate commerce. It's
just like I mean of course there's
illicit interstate commerce going on and
and backing and all this other stuff
that that like how could it not there's
not you don't see giant you know
thousand pound bonfires of cannabis
going off all the time. Um, yeah,
Oklahoma is a huge state and like, you
know, I'm sure the Oklahoma people would
like say it themselves, like almost
everybody we worked with, they'd be
like, "I own my property. You know, tell
them come out here and tell me I can't
do it." You know, like in Oklahoma,
nobody wanted to pull permits. Nobody
wanted to do it. Yeah. Their buddies
down the street. We're going to help
them build whatever, you know. So, um,
for all the licensed stuff, who knows
how much unlicensed work was also done
that fed those markets. For sure. Yeah.
That's it's pretty crazy to think about.
And uh with more states coming online
all the time, you know, there there
could be other potentials for something
like that to happen where you have, you
know, a set cost of entry, right?
Regardless of the size of the facility
you want to build. So you can basically
go in there with you know like you're
saying like $10 million in capital spend
a tiny amount on the lensure and just
blow up a space you know and it would
and then you know sure you might have
this spaceship to operate
but man in a saturated market like that
it feels like you know your your talent
pool is going to be diluted your um your
overhead costs are going to going to
skyrocket after the, you know, the short
interval of time in which people realize
that there's this tremendous demand for
certain perishables and consumables that
all of a sudden is going to
be, you know, they're they're going to
deplete their stocks. They're going to
have to restock all those things and
they're going to go, "Well, I'm going to
up my price. Why not?" like that. Well,
even along those same lines, I feel like
um I had a handful of friends from
Colorado all run out to Oklahoma because
they couldn't legally work in the
industry here because they had felonies.
So, in Oklahoma, there was no regulatory
whatever to who could run and operate
these gardens. So, I feel like there's
probably cultivators from all over Cal,
you know, sort of like our legacy stuff
like we were saying out west that were
like, "Yo, here's my chance to get back
in legally and went there." there. So,
there were probably a bunch of talented
guys running these gardens, you know,
that had that experience and were like
able to pull off what they, you know,
they could walk the walk. Um, and then
sort of again quickly their dreams or
what they were promised didn't work out.
Um, so then things turned to that gray
area for a lot of those projects.
Yeah. when you it's and it's really
fascinating because the people that I do
see operating in Oklahoma still and uh
like maintaining a certain amount of
success are extremely small farms like
you know 20 lighters, right? Like
something where they're just pulling off
five really good harvests a year, you
know, maybe pulling 50 60 lbs out of it
and then offering other sort of classes
and educational material. And with the
cost of living in Oklahoma being what it
is, you know, you can survive pretty
comfortably off of, you know, sub 100k
uh income per year. And if you already
own the property or land, you're pretty
comfortable. Some of our um some really
good friends, I guess, sort of uh you
know, guys from here from Denver that
went to Oklahoma. Um it's it's one of
the larger I guess maybe sort of groups
in Oklahoma. They're called Evo
Cannabis. Um they put out I know Evoke.
Yeah. Yeah. You know. Yeah. like the
Amid and Wes. I don't know. Omid's a
real good homie. Um, they put out really
a friend. Good. Cool. Um, you know, they
put out really good work. Um, and
they've sort of been able to expand and
you know, again, they started out more
of like trying to do like an extraction
sort of facil extraction lab for like
their facility and then partnership
didn't work out and then we designed
them their 20 their first 20,000 foot
spot. Um, then they just took it and
ran, you know, did what they do. Um,
yeah. You know, then they've expanded.
Um, and I feel like they're I don't
know. I guess you sort of proud of your
certain friends. You're like, "Y'all did
it." Like kind of thing putting out that
type of work at that scale and stuff.
So, like there are probably those other
big examples similar to them. But, you
know, I don't know. If I was in
Oklahoma, that's what I'm going for.
Well, they're they're they were such
nice people when I met them. I met them
over in uh in San Jose, California at a
craft farmer meetup for talking about
craft was there. Yeah. Yeah. And I think
it was Amid and his lead grower were
there and it was uh it was awesome to
talk to them and hear what they were
doing and and how they like developed in
Colorado and then took that to Oklahoma
and were one of the more popular brands
already on the shelves of the different
dispensaries and you know that sort of
level of understanding all the different
aspects of like compliance and um like
the buildout and everything. They were
just, it seemed like they were able to
go execute and get it into the market in
such a good way that they, it's cool to
see something like that that it's still
around cuz a lot of the brands kind of
came and went like flashes in the pan.
Yeah, totally. Yeah. So, like we
designed their spot with them um kind of
thing. They actually built it's pretty
cool like you know like when it comes to
all your dosatron and uh like all the
plumbing like we did all that plumbing
design work for them. they actually
built it themselves kind of thing like
you know getting pictures of them
covered in the purple glue and stuff
like that you know um whatever you know
but again like they built it themselves
so that's like a built not brought built
bought not bought brand um
you know so like just I don't know super
proud of them kind of thing you're like
sort of celebrate what they pulled off
um you know I guess we still share a
whole bunch of genetics with them um you
know kind of thing I saw that actually I
was just talking to Amid the other day
about the 8 in bagel and he was saying
that he got it from his buddy in
Colorado. And then I saw it on your uh
on your list of uh genetics that you
offer. And you know, this is actually a
great segue into the next thing that I
wanted to kind of touch base with you
about and learn more about is the I
Party with Jarrett collection, your uh
your genetics list that you curate. Um
so tell us more about that and sort of
what uh what got that going and uh where
your inspiration comes from. I sort of
always been
a call it a collector kind of thing. Um
yeah I think I started growing cannabis
in like 2007208
um when I first moved here. Um you
probably touch plants every day since
unless you like leave the country or
something. Um and I feel like sort of
yeah sort of when I first started there
was like sort of like two camps that I
was like working with kind of thing if
you will. Um, you know, one uh was a
bunch of southern dudes from Arkansas
like John and Chuck and GMAC and Jason,
you know, they gave me my first plants
and lights and stuff. And the other was,
uh, you know, one of the bar owners and
sort of his sensei, Master Q. Um, so I
basically I was going to
school and doing work for everybody sort
of like apprenticing under them, you
know, learning and um, the guys from the
south just always had better genetics
and grew better weed than anybody else
in town. Um, so like kind of like
started to really get into it there and
I got a picture somewhere. I could find
it and send it to you, you know, but
like out of all the, you know, packages
you would get from people, I would
always pull a gram out and put it in a
little nouging jar and label it, you
know. So at one point there was like a
hundred some different jars of different
genetics that I'd bought and you know
shared with friends and stuff like that
and have them like all stacked up like a
Jenga you know pile kind of thing. Uh so
I sort of always love genetics kind of
thing. Um and then as you know you sort
of do it a little bit longer and you
start like keeping your own mothers
instead of getting clones from friends
and um then you sort of start getting
into like popping seeds for yourself.
Um, so I feel like I was always a
collector. Um, just cuz like I don't
know, I thought it was the fun, you
know, it's part of the fun part. And as
you start doing it more, you realize
that that kind of is like one of the
things that separates you and makes your
product more memorable, you know, and I
guess sort of in some of the older days
when you would have a couple passion
projects yourself kind of thing, you
know, and everything's going and getting
labeled, you know, like um when your
work gets selected first, you know, part
of it because the quality of the
product, part of it was because like
diversity of genetics and like, you
know, sort of always had stuff that none
of my friends had. um you know because I
would go hunt stuff out. Um you know and
that's going back 16 17 years ago. Um so
fast forward you know sort of became
friends with another dude you know chef
in town Johnny like the knife is what we
call him. Um and that's when really
started yeah that's when we really
started popping lots of seeds kind of
thing. Um I still have this one strain
called Cookie Wreck that I've had now
since I think I popped that seed in
2011. Maybe shared it three times. I
think it's like as special as something
as I've ever worked with. Um but yeah,
even back then kind of started popping
seeds and holding genetics and sort of I
would end up feeding all my friends
gardens clones kind of thing. Um yeah,
far back then. So like yeah, I guess you
know going back to a little bit what
Next Crop does, we outfit these
facilities and then I would show up on
site and sort of we'd have numbers that
we'd have to hit right out of the gate
to make everybody profitable. Um, so
started bringing my genetics with me so
that I knew what I was doing like right
out of the gate. Sure. Um, so sort of
like those genetics were sort of just
supplied to sort of clients or more of a
private situation. Um, and at this point
as things have loosened up a little bit,
like you know, and like sort of holding,
you know, 50, 60, 80, 100 moms kind of
thing to hold your whole library is a
ton of work, you know, kind of thing
when it just comes to all of it. People
don't realize how hard 120 right now the
facility I'm at. And it's, oh, it's a
process. Yes. You know, sort of
repopulation, making sure you have
enough stuff at the right time, all
that. Um, so the whole I party with
Jerry, you know, I guess when we got all
these trade shows, you know, for all the
cannabis trade shows, people are like,
"Oh, what do we do at night?" We're
like, I'm like, "Oh, we're going to go
party with these guys, you know, we're
going to go party with the Canada team.
We're going to go party with whoever."
Um, so then somebody inside the company,
uh, actually dude named John, he's one
of the Croan reps now. You should meet
John as well. He's like, "Well, we're a
party with Jared Joe." So then, uh,
that's where that sort of name starts
came from. and then uh sort of started
joking about how I sponsor artists and
athletes. Um just you know people that
are really cool, you're like they're
part of the team. Um but basically back
to it, you know, so N sort of trying to
do like here's my 18 strains kind of
thing for the fall season, winter
season, spring season. Um so you kind of
like here's this menu. This is what's
available now. Um you know we'll have a
spring, we'll have a summer. So like
every basically three four months that
list changes to like the next set of 20
kind of thing. Um we sort of tried to
set up a subscription program now kind
of thing just so we could be a little
more prepared as well as like our their
clients can be prepared you know. So if
somebody wants one strain every 90 days
they can sign up for that. Somebody
wants two strains every 60 days you know
we have one person that wants four
strains a month. Um, you know, sort of
just like you almost have like your
sushi menu and you sort of like, you
know, you're signed up for x amount on
whatever cadence and frequency. Um, so
you just sort of this is what you're
going to get every 60 days. You know,
you kind of get your cuts. Um, so that
like, you know, the garden staff,
cultivation team can plan that they
have, you know, two new things coming
in. The sales team can also then be
prepared, the marketing team. So, just
to kind of try to get everybody like
aligned in that uh here's the new this
is what we're going to focus on. Um not
have to go pop all the seeds and hunt
for themselves and all the work and
question marks that comes with that. So,
like these are proven genetics that run
in commercial facilities. You know,
here's your COA, here's your pictures,
here's your cheat sheet, like you know,
they sort of try to become friends with
all the guys at all the gardens, you
know, feel like you are or like I am,
you So, it's like, yo, here's my number.
Call me. I'll tell you however I can
sort of help with like a little bit of
growers notes um as well, right? So,
it's sort of something we just sort of
launched in January. Um sort of seems
like it's going pretty well so far. Um
but, you know, it's just a way for
sort, you know, sort of all these
cultivation teams to just be like, cool,
I got two two new strains coming in
every 60 days. And then they can sort of
make their garden fresh with that. So, I
really like that. I mean it's it's also
really beneficial to see from a a
commercial standpoint that it is
commercially viable because you know
there are a lot of popular strains that
you get in uh nowadays like that you may
be sourcing from someone who is some
sort of uh popular curator of flavors
and their style of growing might be you
know kind of what we touched on earlier.
or it might be this esoteric unique
um you know maybe maybe they don't use
like any sort of uh substrate monitoring
or anything and they're using these
massive pots and running their plants
vegetative the entire cycle and so
that's how you get the morphology of the
flower that they're sending you but then
you're putting it into a facility that's
running small like onegon cocoa pots
using substrate monitoring high EC feed
and you're trying to match all of these
other parameters that you're used to
following
and it turns out into this, you know,
big old boof stick or something along
those lines where it just doesn't work
out in your parameters. But by having
someone like yourself who's also then
connected to multiple facilities that
are running different styles of growing
that you've seen similar or the same
cultivar run in already, you can provide
super accurate data to people to say,
"Listen, if you are running it in a
small substrate, then you need to really
drive your P2s for bulking or you really
need to um you really need to make sure
that you're running a super generative
environment all the way from start to
finish because it does not do well in
high humidity midflower or you know just
different things like that where you can
you can really help people hone it in
and not misstep when they intake new
genetics because for me one of the
biggest things is when running new
genetics I'll just throw like nine
plants in right like one light worth of
of this genetics because I'm like I'll
test light it but at the same time
sometimes when I see you know you're
you're by day 40 and you're like this is
[__] this is not working out. And
but you've already dedicated, you know,
two months to this plant and you got to
ride it all the way out because at this
point you're not going to lose all the
yield potential from all of that input
and overhead that you've put into even
that one light because that's still in
today's market a significant portion of
a yield in some cases. It's a real
estate on the table, you know, and so
it's, oh man, it's frustrating to take
in genetics that then don't work out the
way you want or that you run them, let's
say, outdoor, right? And then you're
like, man, this yielded great for me
outdoor. The returns on the hash were
great. The tarpine profile, the color,
the structure, all did really well in an
outdoor setting. you throw it indoors
and it, you know, throws
in, you know, people have something that
works great inside and then they go
outside with it and fill up hoop houses
or fill up fields and then all of a
sudden it doesn't do what they thought,
you know, like for sure. Um, I mean,
both both ways, right? It it cuts both
ways. You can't really necessarily
uh take an outdoor and run it indoor and
you can't take an indoor and run it
outdoor and expect the same things. Like
sometimes they do work out and there are
strains that definitely do great like u
super boof right indoor outdoor it does
the same thing pretty much and it's
going to yield significantly for you but
you know something like uh what's one
like uh like some of the different grape
strains
you'll run it outdoor and it'll yield
great won't throw interex traits have
you know phenomenal tarpen and and
overall structure throw it indoors
you're seeding out your whole room and
uh it's it's frustrating. Yeah, that's
sort of scary or whatever, you know, and
like I've dealt with it. Anybody's
anybody's like hasn't dealt with this
yet. Question how much plants you plant
work you really do, but like all the
viruses at this point um that come with
genetics and all the skeletons that come
with them. Um we test regular with tumi
genomics out of Fort Collins, Dr. Tasa
like you know I they're just as kind of
kind and great people. Um they're sort
of on the cutting edge too of all like
SOPs for HLBD testing and all of your
other you know full panel whatever else
you want to do you know they'll take
care of you. So we test stuff regularly
with them. Um I guess sort of our mutual
friend uh Jesse Leech and Mothership
Labs like done full mar dissections
across the whole library. So it's like
these plants have this vigor to them
that's like sure really exciting. Um,
even cutting branches, cutting clones
off this these plants that have come out
of
dissection, like take your scissors and
you go right through it and you're like,
"This feels different," you know, kind
of thing. So, um, I don't know. Try to
just have like, like I said,
everything's tested, everything's been
through marathon dissection.
I don't know. Just one of those things
you're kind of like done everything we
can to provide the people with something
good, right? No. And I feel like all
those different steps that you're taking
to provide um like clean genetics that
are well tested that have been proven in
multiple uh environments. Uh so you can
kind of see how the phenotype changes
over those different environments and
the different uh operators and how they
have their own unique uh kind of ways of
dealing with things in the grow that
produce different structures and
morphologies. It's it's really helpful.
Um and so that's back to what you said
earlier a little bit like sometimes
people like I run
insert whatever gen or whatever
nutrients this size container under
these kinds of lights and you're like
huh we have a client that does the exact
same thing like kind of here's pictures
from their facility you so you really
can kind of offer
uh that sort of specifics to go along
with them um yeah to people so it's I
don't know that's sort of the new fun
thing that we've been working on did
some breeding work really excited to
start popping a bunch of new seeds to
sort of refill that list, you know, with
stuff that's going to be like one of one
we've made in house. Um, you know, just
like you, I'm guessing got a full fridge
of
seeds, more seeds than you should have
kind of thing. You know, you're really
excited to get to kind of thing as well.
Um, so I don't know, like you know, like
I said, the list cycles about every four
months. Um, so that way that like, you
know, the people that have subscribed
kind of thing. you know, again,
depending on the cadence that they want
stuff. Um, you know, realistically that
next list is going to have turned over
and they get to pick off that menu again
and sort of just try to keep everybody
like fresh and excited about what's
coming and uh, but at the same time
bring back like some of the older
nostalgic stuff like, you know, got a
like a pre98 bubba that's, you know, in
dissection and a Durban poison and
dissection, some of the old chem stuff,
you know. sort
of yes, there's the new hype and
whatever, but also like the building
blocks of that nostalgic work, you know,
that sort of love and you know, like I
I'm sure you're thinking the same thing
too, like if I could have this back, you
know, especially going back, you know,
near a couple decades of work, you know,
there's certain things that have been
lost for a while that, you know, you
would do just about anything to have
back at this point. So hopefully at this
point never losing anything again. um
you know because we'll be able to store
it on the shelf in a vessel, right?
Yeah. It's uh the huge benefit of tissue
culture. I I um I'm a huge advocate of
it. It's come up so many times now on
the show that you know we have we've had
Jesse on and we've had uh one of our
he's a wizard by you know you know he's
great and he's super helpful. And then
one of our co-hosts Cosmic, he also does
tissue culture at home so that he can uh
maintain a a large library for his
breeding purposes. and um I do tissue
culture at work and uh it's you know
it's just one of those things that it is
going to be a part a huge part of the
industry and for anybody that's still
trying to push back against it I'm going
to say well that your time's coming and
it's going to you're going to you're
going to learn one of the things I feel
like at this point too like I don't know
I don't say it's like more inspiring
than running the big gardens or whatever
but like there is something really cool
about how specific and concentrated your
work is like every knife stroke and M
it's just so concentrated that like it
really shows the quality of your work
and how much attention to detail you pay
to it because it's not like you're like
oh that that plant's going to veg for
three weeks or whatever you know you get
to be a little bit sloppy and sort of
make up for it. Um you know you're under
a microscope doing like surgical work
almost. So, I just think it's really
cool that it's like so specific and
clean and like, you know, you put on
your headphones and get under the hood
and just like go to work and I don't
know, you get in that tunnel and trance
of it and sort of just love it. So, it's
it's a I mean, it is all propagation,
right? But cloning for me is the same
thing. I love doing clones and and you
know, making those that perfect tray of
clones is really satisfying. similar to
like filling up a bunch of way I judge
people like if I was going you know if
I'm going to hire somebody um one of the
I feel like easiest ways to sort of see
how good they are and like how
consistent their work is and like you're
like you know cut a tray of 50 for me
you know kind of thing and like sort of
their their clone work will really show
how detailed or how sort of consistent
or how much control they'll have of the
entire garden you know so if you like
call me you know fill a tray and that'll
that'll tell you just about everything
you need to know about how talented
somebody is in your garden. For sure. I
always look at the cutting board that
they bust out and if they have two lines
on the cutting board that I'm super
happy. Yeah. Just even like just
consistent. Well, even just going back
to like, you know, getting into like the
garden a little bit. You're like, yeah,
like your mothers and the clones set the
pace for the rest, you know, you have
such like sort of specific timelines and
deadline, you know, kind of thing to
everything in your garden that if your
clones are slow out of the gate, it's an
uphill battle. Like you always sort of
joke like, you know, you start at 100%.
You know, kind of thing. And every
little mistake, you know, you go down to
from 100 to 98 to 94 to whatever and you
never get to go back up. So it's like
how few mistakes can you make and how
can you hit like all those apex turns
that you're chasing you throughout this
round. So it's just you know how far
forward are you always plan and look and
thinking and it really starts with how
good are your clones. That's like
absolutely. Yeah. Yep. And uh yeah, I
feel like that's a great way to break it
down for people, even for home growers,
too, where if you're looking at, you
know, the potential for your garden. You
need to definitely start with 100%. And
you know, if your clones aren't that
great, then you already need to say,
"Well, I'm not going to have the best
harvest I possibly can." And if you
accept that, then you can still work
within the parameters that you're using,
right? you know, let's say your genetics
just aren't that great or you don't have
a veg space that's able to be dialed in
well, so you're always, you know,
through some environmental parameter
having some sort of nutrient deficiency
or other health issue with the plants.
Well, that's what you get to work with,
so let's just go from there. Um, and I
feel like a lot of times when people are
trying to optimize their
space, they they they miss that point
where it's you have to work with what
you have, but sometimes what you have
isn't ideal and you can still do really
well with it, but knowing how to then
kind of pivot around those issues is
something that does take a lot of time
and practice and patience. Yeah. you
like to your point here like you know
sort of I guess this is like a two-part
answer to this in my like teacher days
you know like you know there was
something at the one school I was
teaching at you know they would call it
like two kisses in a wish and I feel
like this is like my biggest takeaway
from being a teacher you know after
you'd sort of finish these projects or
assignments you know the whole class
would go around and like you know every
student would like you know one student
would sort of essentially not be in the
center of the circle but like their work
would be on on on center stage and the
whole class would go around and sort of
you give them two kisses and a wish like
two things that they did well and one
thing that they could improve on. So I
feel like that was like one of the
biggest takeaways for me because it's
like hard to sort of accept criticism in
that way from peers at times or but you
know like in the garden you really need
to like as far forward planning as you
can be you know to put out fires three
months down the road. Um, and you don't
want to dwell on mistakes and stuff from
the past. But you need to connect those
dots and reflect back to really
understand where that hiccup came from
and how I can, you know, like, okay,
that happened this time because of,
let's say, your environmental conditions
or, you know, you don't have the proper
irrigation setup, you know, so how do I
now connect that dot backwards to plan
forwards? Um, that it's all going to
kind of come together. Um so I don't
know like reflection is really you can't
dwell on stuff and let it bring you too
far down when you like have these
hiccups or mistakes but you do need to
reflect um and sort of how do I improve
and connect those dots so then that your
plan going forward um you know is
improved and more optimal than it was
before.
Absolutely. And you know, looking back
at where those hiccups may have started
is kind of a puzzler's dream. If you
like to puzzle and if you like to do
anything sort of uh like mentally uh
like a mental gymnastic sort of practice
or a mental exercise, then by looking
back and trying to puzzle this together
and figure out where you had an issue,
you're going to be able to learn so much
more than just by trying to prevent
everything from ever happening. And by
having, you know, it's a it's a great
trait in the garden to be able
to problem solve, right? Because
problems arise all the time. We're
dealing with living plants. It it's
inevitable. There's bugs, there's
pathogens, there's environmental
conditions, there's electrical failures,
there's other equipment failures. All of
this can go wrong. And rather than
freaking out and saying that piece, you
know, that one little piece of the
puzzle fell away. How do I I can't do
anything about it? because I needed that
piece to finish the puzzle. You have to
say, well, this is kind of going back to
what we've talked about before. You're
now operating at 95%. So, you need to
bring everything down to match that.
Otherwise, you're going to hurt the
plants by, you know, oh, oh, so you're
you can't have the room cooled down far
enough when you're putting that much
wattage in the room. Well, guess what?
You can't run your lights at 100%
anymore. you you got to make sure that
you're cycling your dehu properly so
you're not dumping all that extra BTU
into the room as well. U you know all
these different things that you can then
sort of dial those down to match your
new baseline because of something that
isn't working properly or because you
just don't have the ability to have it
work properly. And so yeah,
it's with so much of like gardening in
general, you have to be able to pivot on
the spot and be able to adapt to what
changes in the garden. And so yeah, you
know, now too these days with all the
data like every sensor in the world that
we run and all this data, you know, it's
kind of like, you know, I guess in the
old days like, you know, used to have
like the big desktop calendars
everywhere, you know, and you would, you
know, you know, back, you know, like you
click your little thermometer for high
and low and for temperature, humidity,
you know, this was my pH, this was the
EC, like you know, you would write all
of those inputs in daily for everything
you did. Um, you know, and then like I
don't know, mine too would have like
what concerts I was going to or what,
you know, so like it really told the
story of uh, you know, that round kind
of thing. So you could look back and
you're like, "Oh, well, you went on tour
for a week or two." You like, you know,
so you could see like the fluctuations
of certain things to connect those dots.
But now we have sensors and stuff like
that and alerts on your phone or your
computer, you know? So like kind of like
turn it into I don't want to say muscle
memory but like you know like we're
saying like this
reactionary my dehuses can't handle this
like well what are you going to do to
now sort of make it so your dew can like
whether it's adjusting temperature and
raising your temps or trying to spread
the irrigation out in a certain way or
less plant you know again what good
decision you know what good decisions
can I make for what's in front of me and
this kind of thing like y you know sort
of have to like just be comfortable
to like call that audible, but you still
have to follow the plan, you know,
cuz you know the whole point is have a
plan that works kind of thing. So, you
know, but again, one of my buddies is
another consultant. He's like, "Dude,
anybody could buy SOPs and they work."
You know, sometimes like people like us
are real important when it becomes like
those emergency procedures. You're like,
"That's what you sort of are buying um
is us to help you solve on the fly."
Like I don't know. It's one of my
favorite parts. You're like how creative
as creative as you can be to solve is
sort of how much you get out of it. So I
like love that creative problem solving.
For sure. Yeah. I was a chef for like 10
years and part of you know being a chef
is problem solving because you have to
make sure that your budget works or your
menu server didn't bring this in and you
need it on the flya like you know like
that's the fun
part. Yeah. Yep. Constantly. And so that
shows a lot in the garden. Yeah, you
know, add another pan or cook this what,
you know, like I don't know that shows
how good you are is like cool, I have
all this normal stuff in front of me,
but now I have to add this and this and
this and do it as fast as I can. I don't
know. I think that's cool to show how
much in control are you that you can do
it, right? And one of the biggest
lessons that you learn um is redundancy
because you need to be able to um you
know, if if something fails, you need to
be able to continue to execute.
Sorry, I have a little foster puppy over
here. Not little. All good. Yeah, no
worries. No, but yeah, like you said,
the redundancy, man. Like it's one of
those things with like you all your me
and paws in a like, you know, like be
prepared like kind of thing like and
then when stuff does go a little
sideways, like hang, you know, hang in
there with it and solve,
right? Exactly.
Hey, Phil. Sorry UPS guys out front. No
worries. There you go. Tell
um well, you know, I think we've had a a
great little intro into uh what you do
with uh Next Big Crop and um sort of
your the I Party with Jared collection
and everything that you're doing there
in your sort of uh professional life.
And you know, correct me if I'm wrong,
but it sounds like your partnership with
Next Big Crop is kind of leading up a
lot of the cultivation aspects of the of
the the group that you're with because
of your experience with growing and and
cultivating and um you know, helping
other growers out when you were working
at the gardening store. Um is that
pretty accurate? Yeah, you know, myself,
like, yeah, like you sort of joked about
earlier, like nobody's ever gonna buy a
computer from me. Um, you know,
Christian, my one partner comes from
like the finance world kind of thing.
So, if uh like Excel spreadsheets where,
you know, you could compete in them, you
know, he would do really well. Um, kind
of thing. like he's a numbers and
organized as can be and just like
extremely good at like the project
management aspect and keeping everybody
accountable and in row and you know if
this gets backed up you know we didn't
order these you know whatever you know
air conditioning unit or we didn't order
this at time so that moves everything
back on like the you know the project
management and the buildout charts you
know everything's moved back three weeks
now because of this and yeah so
Christian doesn't like you know I
couldn't do what he does when it comes
to sort of that project management and
like financial stuff. Um then my other
partner Rich um he actually founded Next
Big Crop in like 2012 or 14 or you know
what feels like forever ago. Um he sort
of has a construction and landscaping
background and he built one of the first
green houses in Boulder as like a
construction worker and then next thing
you knew he was running it. So he sort
of has a construction and uh cultivation
background as well. He ran a bunch of
spots as well. Um and then that's when
he started doing the application writing
and that's sort of where next big crop
came from um as a whole. So you know I
couldn't do what either of them do um
for sure kind of thing. Um I would also
dare them to try and come play with
plants and do you know kind of one of
those things like you know sort of at
this point like all these projects are
just honestly like too big for any one
person. Like there's no unicorn out
there that can do it all. Um, so sort of
to like have that complimentary team
where everybody's sort of a subject
matter expert in their lane. Don't get
me wrong, we all wear lots of hats, you
know, and solve and whatever, but like
um to sort of have that, you know, that
comfort spot of like, you know, where
you hang out, you know, this is your
world. You got to own it and you got to
be just on all of it, you know. So sort
of next to crap like you said, you know,
we have lots of clients pretty much
almost every state that, you know, legal
markets working in, you know, design
facilities, sort of sold gear, sold
genetics to, helped with operational
plans or financial models and all that
kind of stuff. Um, so I don't know, I
feel like sort of the network we've
built, um, you know, between vendors and
clients is like something to be proud
of. Just kind of like you can walk in
any room with your head high, you know,
done everybody right kind of thing over
the years.
For sure. Well, I mean, considering your
uh vast background in dealing with the
cannabis plant, um we I do like to find
out sort of where you started your
journey with, uh plants in general. So,
you know, whether that be when you were
younger, uh, growing up, if there was a
garden in the backyard or, um, you know,
some people say that cannabis is the
gateway plant to gardening and, uh,
sometimes it's the other way around for
people. So, where did your journey with
plants begin? Sure. So, my mother is
like as talented of as an artist as like
you can be kind of thing. Like, she ran
she was an art teacher. um you know when
she was younger she ran a clothing
company and sort of designed clothes and
all kinds of stuff there. Um you know
sort of quilting like drawing, painting,
all of it, photography. Um but I guess
she always had like a vegetable garden
at her house growing up. Um you know so
she literally would walk across a creek
to the other side of the field to
garden, you know, pick all of whatever
and that was dinner for her. You know,
she just ate salads constantly. Um, you
know, and I'll send you some pictures of
it. You know, like they just moved to
Asheville, North Carolina a couple years
ago. You lived in Philly my whole life.
Um, but she has a couple bird of
paradises that are probably like I think
one's like 43 years old. The other's 30
something. Um, she has a few other
plants that are 50 plus years old that,
you know, she's been carrying around.
Like at this point, she has to hide
stuff from my dad when she brings home
new plants kind of thing. Um, you know,
she's probably got 500 plus like cact
cactuses, succulents, cacti, succulent.
That's so cool kind of thing. And I'll
send you pictures. It's like pretty
stunning work kind of like like how do
you know the Latin names for all this
stuff? So, I feel like I didn't really
realize it, you know, like how you know,
when you're younger, you don't realize
certain things of it, but like they said
she had plants that, you know, the house
I grew up in, like one of the rooms like
big glass windows, it was two stories
tall without a second floor above it,
you know. So she had 20 some foot tall
plants my whole life kind of thing. Um,
you grew up around plants. Yes. But I
didn't really I guess to be honest I
used to mow lawns like from the time I
was like I don't know maybe 11 I was
mowing lawns to make money to buy dirt
bikes. So like didn't really realize it
you know kind of thing. But like you
know back when I was a kid I could tell
you all kinds of stuff about sky
whatever insert whatever lawn you know
we had Kabota tractors whatever you know
kind of like whatever. just didn't
really maybe realize it till older that
maybe that's where it all started. Um
and then like I said when I got this job
and I guess sort of always sort of
self-medicated my whole life pretty
regularly kind of thing. Um so then like
you know I started bartending at that
one bar and they sort of drugg me up the
hill to get trim for them. Um you know
and then you're like I want my own
plant. So I lived in this little
carriage house um you know tiny little
carriage house like in the city and I
was teaching whatever. I literally moved
my mattress to the staircase. So, I was
like up against staircase and then I
hung a tarp and I hung 20,000 watts on
one side and then I had a little bedroom
with some just T5s. So, I moved all my
clothes down into my living room and
kitchen and I literally slept on a
mattress next to 2000 watts and did that
for a while I guess until I got robbed,
you know, and then that's like a whole
new learning experience kind of thing.
Um, and then I got robbed and sort of
freaked out. you're like ah you know um
it's sort of one of the you know Q like
the one sort of sensei master mentor
that is you know we could talk about him
you know he's a sensei kind of thing he
is so far ahead of his time he was part
of a project up in Netherland that he
wanted out of um and he was kind of just
like why don't you you know he told the
guys his partners why don't you bring
Curly up you know and they used to just
call me Curly and uh so then I started
going up the hill
Um, like sir said, like I never really
grew any plants until I started growing
cannabis. And then, yeah, I went from
two lights, you know, with my mattress
next to that tarp here in those white
shoe boxes home all night to uh 10 to 14
to three house, you know, you know, next
thing you know, kind of,
you know, as sort of many houses you,
you know, and I guess like I was
finishing my teaching degree, like I
said, it was, you know, the first time I
went through college was like BNC
student. and I bartended and partied and
had a real good time. Um, but when I was
get my teaching degree and started, you
know, growing. Um, I got a 4.0 kind of
thing, you know, like all of a sudden it
was like the first time you ever had a,
you know, with those big desktop
calendars, it was the first time I ever
had a schedule that I guess I followed,
you know. So, like all of a sudden, you
know, school clicked, I got a 4.0,
graduated with whatever high honors
from, you know, like that kind of stuff.
Um, and like I said, you know, kind of
just, you know, I think like a lot of
people, it almost gets addictive kind of
thing to have these gardens and trying
to make something so pretty and, you
know, just uh it's like a very creative
outlet, you know, where you get to take
something from being like, you know,
small little plant to this final
finished flower, you know. I feel like
probably like lots of other people, you
know, in our world, great at starting
stuff and not finishing stuff projects.
Um, and this was like the first thing
that ever clicked. Yeah. you know, this
was the first thing that ever clicked
that like I followed through and in that
way and like finished hard and um you
know, and just got super proud of your
work and um nice you know, like you
said, that's now 17 years later, you
know, kind of thing. But um how was that
first grow setup though? Like so you
said you had just like a tarp kind of
separating the room out, but uh yeah,
what was like your inputs? What were you
feeding these plants? How how did you uh
Yeah, was it a successful first grow?
We'll call it medium. um medium, you
know, kind of like so it was like a
little carriage house with like, you
know, your sort of sloped roof and a
little tiny staircase that went
upstairs. It was a tiny little bathroom
with like a sliding curtain kind of
thing. Um so I had a mattress up against
the stairs and I used to have to fill up
five gallon buckets, you know, in the
shower and like walk across my mattress
to get to the PL, you know, kind of
thing. like like literally it was like
you know and there was like a a little
fire place or there was a chimney in the
middle of this space. So took a hammer
and you know beat a hole in that chimney
to try to exhaust everything out of you.
So I literally had to T5 you know sort
of tarps down on floors and hung and
like uh you know I guess at that point
we were using like the Dutch bleach
trays like the little you know 6 in
slabs um okay you know kind of thing. So
I think in the beginning we you know it
was on ionic which I think it's
Australian or but ionic was a one part
you know recipe you know you veg near
bloom and like a little PK booster and
so just basically had little
recirculating pumps you know with those
leech trays and the slabs. Um so like I
said I slept next to these plants with
you know the lights going at night and
you know the upstairs in a little tiny
carriage house with no insulation in the
middle of the city. Um, you know, so
were you doing like eb and flow? Uh,
were you doing like an eb and flow
system or just like we had like a little
like your cement mixing bins you get at
Home Depot or Lowe's kind of thing. I
think they were 11 gallons a piece and
just like a little pump with some drip
stakes, you know, drip line going up to
each slab kind of thing. And it was I
guess because these guys, you know, used
to do, you know, big houses up in the
mountain. So it' be two plants of light
just to keep the counts under 99 and,
you know, so I just basically mimic that
of my house kind of thing. Um, oh, so
you do you did four plants under 2,000
watts? Yeah, kind of. You know, and I
like So, yeah, dude, it was, you know,
and again, the guys I was getting
genetics from like Chuck and John and
them, like it was as good of like we'll
get into this, but like if I could have
that cut of sour diesel back, you know,
from back then, I would do anything for,
you know, it is the
best sort of cut that I've ever touched
that I've lost, you know. Do do you
remember what specific cut of sour
diesel it was again? is this is going
back like the 14 to 17 year mark here in
Denver kind of thing. Um so I don't you
know they just always just referred to
as the D you know and they're from the
south with big old beards and yeah big
dudes like oh the D what you know like
kind of thing. So I wish I knew what cut
you know it has been long gone kind of
thing and I have been searching ever
since to I'll have to connect you with
uh one of the uh well with my co-founder
with the um the craft growers network
Gabby because I got my eyes all over
that. I can't wait to get to meet him
and go mess with that kind of thing.
Yeah, cuz he's got a few different sour
cuts that uh one of them might be the
one that you're looking for
cuz like 18, 19 years old. Yeah, his
list is impressive. Um you know, kind of
thing. So, I can't wait
to trade, collaborate, do whatever kind
of thing with him to get my hands on it.
So, cool. Um, these guys also used to
have this Hawaiian that was like just
like like I said, I would only smoke the
like during like midterms or finals, I
would only smoke the Hawaiian cuz I
joke, you know, instead of smoking like
instead of smoking dope, I would smoke
smart with that Hawaiian,
you know, kind of thing. So like I don't
know but yeah it's going back a while
and then you so like it was ionic for a
while and then um you know that was sort
of the one team's recipe and then the
southern guys were all in GH and it was
you know like said they have a bunch of
southern boys like you know shot we
talking shot glasses of green purple
pink you know like your general
hydroponics three part so like yeah like
those recipes were written in certain
ways from them you know and then I guess
the good you know they introduced me to
the guys at chlorophyll here in town,
which is no longer around, but like Bow
and Lee definitely like educated me too.
And so I feel like
super righteously like thankful that I
sort of had like the teachers and
mentors I did because they were kind of
like as good as you, you know, sort of
came up on like teams where these guys
really, you know, and I guess even back
then like I started joking like, well,
in the name of science and like, you
know, you would run have trash cans with
reservoir, you know, kind of thing. One
of the next setups after that one that I
loved, we had built out a warehouse in
Boulder and it was a 10,000 square foot
warehouse and it was all eight inch PVC
pipe and they cut the tops out of it and
had little handles like kind of thing in
them. So they'd be like 40 foot runs to
mimic the Dutch leech trays kind of
thing with 8 in PVC on just saw horses
big horse troughs as reservoirs at the
end of it kind of thing. So like three
of us could run this 10,000 foot
warehouse. It was so basic and simple
like that. So then like after that one
got broken down, I stole a bunch of the
8 inch pipe for my house kind of thing.
But I would even run like, you know, the
exact same strains, you know, you had
4,000 watts in the basement. So like,
you know, two two eight inch pipes on
one side, two PVC pipes on the other
side with different reservoirs, but the
exact same genetics but different, you
know, nutrients and stuff like that. So
Okay. Even back started running some
side by sides and stuff to see the
difference. Yeah. Just I don't I guess
like I love cars and motorcycles, so I
feel like, you know, sort of I don't
always look at as like race car [__]
you know, and like Sure. Yeah. You're
racing like, you know, this verse that
and like, you know, you were writing
down the recipes and all this stuff and
everything was comparable. So, it was
just like, you know, you sort of
competing with yourself to just see
where you could take it. But when you
were running those 8 in pipes, were you
still uh using like a drip system and
just letting that be sort of your trough
to drain to waste? Yeah, basically you
you put your little coverver like half
inch or 3/4 inch like sort of PVC down
it so it hold your slabs up, you know,
like off the ground kind of thing and
just put the slabs right all the way up.
It's like, you know, if you could
imagine big warehouses full just saw
horses and 8 inch PVC like so simple,
you know, kind of thing. Um, and again
like I don't know like the simplicity of
it, you know, it's like race car stuff
like like I was and I love like sleeper
cars like you know you don't want to
advertise anything but you want to be
real fast. Um, so I always look at like
you know the same kind of thing as like
8 inch PVC was designed to hold water
and move water. That's what we were
doing in it, you know, and you sort of
cut it, design it, make it work in that
space. and uh you know
like I don't know it was so simple but
yet it worked so well kind of thing. Oh
that sounds awesome. I mean sometimes
the the best systems are those that are
the simplest to use because you don't
have to there's there's no guesswork and
then if anything fails it's as simple as
you know busting out the uh the sawzall
and and cutting the pipe off and
throwing in a new piece. you know, it's
it's easy. It's all form and function.
Nothing to look cool. Like just, you
know, it is truly like performance
designed kind of mentality, you know,
don't get me wrong, like could we get
bored over the years and you be like,
I'm going to do organic, I'm going to
switch to this, whatever, you know. So
like have done it, you know, working a
way to grow like you know, you work
there at the store, you put your, you
know, eight or 10 hour shifts in and you
just read every bottle on the shelf kind
of thing and like make up fantasy
recipes or you get to like essentially
watch all your customers buying all this
stuff and who does really good work and
cherrypick these ideas from them and
stuff. So like you know I've run like
every nutrient you know you could
imagine all the different substrates the
different size containers what you know
like like I said in the name of science
it was just like fun to like practice
and put it all together. Well let's do
like a little uh fun mental exercise
then since you have this experience with
all the different nutrients and all
these different setups. if you were to
help a home grower set up a 4x4 tent,
right? Yep. With um and let's talk
hydroponics because organics and stuff
is more of a religion to a lot of the
people that grow that way rather than a
practice. And um I feel like if that's
the route of growing that someone wants
to go, I wholeheartedly support it. But
it's really hard to um to say that this
is, you
know, you know, from from someone who
sold the different inputs and the
different aspects of growing, it's hard
to be like this is exactly what you need
to do to be successful. But with
hydroponics, in a lot of cases, there's,
you know, there's different recipes.
There's different um there's different
forms and functions of the different
hydroponic systems that you can use that
kind of required either a tweak here or
a change there. So, if you were to help
someone set up a 4x4 tent, what
nutrients are you going for? What style
of hydroponics are you helping them set
up? And what are some of the things that
you think you might be able to help
alleviate in terms of the struggles of
hydroponics, whether it be like runoff
capture or nutrient delivering or uh
tank mixing or anything like that? Just
kind of run through uh if you had to
design your own 4x4 tent at home right
now. Um I guess what so we'll sort of
start you know kind of obviously LED
light at this point just
because you know temperature control
electric you know all of this stuff kind
of thing for you know that such a small
space I don't know like love fluence
lights you know love lights ran DLI
lights for a while like those are my top
three kind of where lights like any of
those you know you have like as good a
fixture as you could get um I don't know
I guess starting to mess with some BIOS
lights as well um I haven't run them
yet, but like about to start playing
with their under canopy stuff. Um, so,
you know, get your sort of your standard
bar style LED. I guess when it comes to
nutrients, I feel like it's a pretty
no-brainer for me. Um, I'm on team Cana,
you know, kind of thing. Like,
um, there's an A and a B kind of thing
to it. It's always equal parts of A and
B. So, it's like you could kind of do it
with your eyes closed or, you know, like
the answer is more or less, you know,
kind of thing. And they both go up and
down at the same time. sort of when you
look at your plants and you're like do
you know color or this or whatever you
know the answer is more or less so like
and they have an AB veg and an AB flour
right yes but also for their cocoa line
yeah the cocoa specific nutrient line
it's the same for veg and flour kind of
thing so for a home grower you literally
could get your cocoa A and your cocoa B
and it's the same nutrient for veg and
flour which would be super convenient um
you know like I love like said I kind of
love these compressed cocoa blocks at
this Right. Um they're so just
consistent and easy and no mess and no
pots to wash at the end. Just you know,
you get all like, you know, the
commercial part like is there a virus in
there? Oh, you didn't wash your pot good
enough. Now you just spread it to your
next plants. What? Yeah. So these
compressed cocoa blocks sort of
eliminate all that and the labor and
stuff. So like in your little 4x4 tent,
like I guess I always like to sort of
think of it as like pattern on a dice.
you know, when it comes to your plant
arrangement, you know, you could do
four, you could do five, you could do
nine, you know, kind of thing. But like
the pattern on a dice kind of is like
how we'll set those plants up to sort of
have just like that sort of even space
management so that all of our plants
ideally you could take any one plant and
put it to another spot and they're all
the same shape and you could switch them
and nobody would ever know. Yeah.
Because that sort of shows your control.
So like four plants, five plants or nine
plants in that. I guess you could do
eight too, but um you know in that 4x4 I
know again I can of cocoa they have
their like cocoa flex pots now and have
like a one gallon and a three gallon. So
I don't know I love the smaller ones. So
I would stay in that one gallon pot. Um
and I would build myself you know
outside your tent you know get yourself
like that 55gallon drum or 20 gallon
trash can whatever you know kind of
thing. um and sort of the correct pump.
You know, you got to do a little bit of
math when it comes to pumps um just to
make sure the pressure is right. But,
you know, get your pressure compensating
like netin drippers so that you know
every plant's getting the exact same
amount of feed. So, I can't and I guess
the other thing is like um I picked and
it's been this way for years and years
too, but like you know uh there's
certain bottles that I used to love that
I don't use anymore just for like
cleanliness purposes, but sort of like a
synthetic liquid nutrient like can of
cocoa. The reservoir is always clean,
the drip lines are always clean, like
you know, so like you always sort of you
don't have to worry about that certain
maintenance kind of thing. So like you
know A and B you know you have your PK
booster you could run a little
hypocchloric acid or whatever you know
but you really don't you know don't get
me wrong years ago it used to have 15
part recipes and stuff like that I'm
sure you know but now it's kind of like
yo a b maybe some cow mag depending on
where you live and well water city water
whatever you know RO stuff but like the
hardest thing I think to teach somebody
especially for a home grower um what is
wet and what is dry if you don't have
the sensors kind of thing you you know,
like so as long as your environment is
in that sort of window of VPD that's
going to be happy, you know, kind of
thing. Like you don't need too many
parts of nutrients to really put out
stellar product. You know, the answer is
like what is wet and what is dry and
kind of like, you know, again, just keep
it between the lines. You don't have to
be perfect, you know, just but like, you
know, so I go like, you know, pick your
LED light, some can of cocoa nutrients
of the same veg and flour nudes in a
onegon pot with a drip, you know, and
then you go to Home Depot or Lowe's or
whatever and get your little six gallon
waste runoff, you know, kind of like
cement mixing bin and that can catch
your waste water and you could, you
know, go water your house plants or
whatever outside with it kind of thing.
Um, if you wanted to reuse it, you
certainly could, but like I would keep
it simple like that, you know? And then
I'd also focus on make sure you have
genetics that you're stoked and excited
about. They're going to give you the
product in the end that you want, but
like it's that simple kind of for sure.
So, a few questions then in your
opinion, seed or clone for a first
grower?
Clone. I guess like hopefully I show you
hopefully you have, you know, a friend
that can kind of coach you along and
help you out and they'll give you those
first couple clones that they've grown
it then they could tell you the little
bit of the cheat sheet with it. If you
kill it or mess it up, who cares?
They're going to give you a new one, you
know, kind of thing. Um, so I would say,
you know, get clones from a buddy. Um,
so you know, you got a friend, you got a
mentor, they're going to like coach you
along. It's fun, you know, that kind of
thing. Right on. Yeah, I agree. Clones
are kind of uh always what I would
suggest to people when they're starting
off because you can look and see where
it's what it's produced in other
settings and have a a goal that you can
have as your target. Um whereas seeds
are just a lot more hit and miss no
matter how good the breeder is. It's one
of those things where there is no
uniformity in cannabis breeding right
now that you you can't plant a field of
cannabis seeds at this point and expect
for there to be a um a true uniformity
across that entire crop. So plus
say that again. Plus you know if you
love it you're like cool let's do it
again. Same strain. Yeah exactly. How do
I do it better this time? You know what
improvements am I? You know so it gives
you that ability to baseline and
continue to make good decisions.
Absolutely. Absolutely. I agree with
that. Um and then uh so like I always
suggest for people that are starting off
with hydroponics to just run a um a
single set of irrigations per day where
they always where they reach field
capacity, achieve some runoff, and then
allow for a dryback over the the
remainder of the day and through the
night time. And with that in mind, um,
is that something that you would suggest
for new growers as well, or would you
suggest something slightly different?
I don't know. I guess it's one of those
things of like, you know, there's no
like one correct answer here. Obviously,
it's kind of like I would almost say
like pick that philosophy you're going
to follow, that methodology from the
start and follow it all the way through.
You know, if you want to get cute and
play with like your sort of irrigations
and like push it that way, you start
that way from day one and you follow
that plan. If you want to push that one
big uh, you know, sort of scheduled feed
or you know, kind of as the plant needs
it and then you're not going to water
again until the plant is ready to
accept, follow that the whole way
through, you know, kind of thing. But I
would say I don't think there's a right
answer here. It's kind of what do you
sure what do you want to learn from? And
then you have to stick with that the
whole way through to like, you know,
prove it to yourself what you learned.
So, um, for sure, you know, we could,
yeah, you know, we could get cute and
start talking like, you know, kind of
where do you live? Like what's the
humidity? Like Colorado's dry. This is,
you know, so certain certain other
factors might lead one of those
decisions to being a better decision
than another. Um, but again, I would
just say you pick one and learn from
that and follow the plan. Absolutely. I
I really like that it consistency is key
in a lot of aspects and your plants,
especially when they're on drip
irrigation, they're going
to I if they're getting consistent
irrigations daily or at a specific um uh
volutric water content, let's say like
where it it dries back to a specific
number and then boom, it triggers an
irrigation event. um as long as you're
triggering it consistently at whatever
set point that is, the plants are going
to tend to respond positively to that.
And um so yeah, I I suggest doing the
the the one set of irrigations event of
events per day and doing that all the
way through because then they'll see
this extremely generative and I I think
the morphology of the plant tends to be
very uh desirable in that aspect and
then people can start to mess with how
they want to manipulate their yields.
But um or you know if it's at a specific
dryback point making sure that you just
hit it with the irrigation then all
those things I think work really well.
Um what what EC and what pH would you
suggest for people if they're running
the uh the can of nutrients? I don't
know. You could probably just always
stay safe and just be like six point you
know kind of thing plus or minus
whatever but like you know your six is
just like will hang out right there in
the middle kind of thing. Um, and I
guess in all honesty, yeah, P, sorry,
6.0 PS. Um, and when it comes to like
sort of EC at this point, you
know, what we used to do 5 years ago, 10
years ago, whatever, 15 years ago, you
know, kind of thing is very different
than sort of um what people are
currently doing. Um, you know, again,
all the sort of different nutrient
manufacturers, you know, like, you know,
Canon, Athena, Front Row, GH, whatever,
you know, like all of them have their
recommendations kind of thing, you know,
but again, I think it's going to go back
a little bit to like how many watts is
your light, you know, do you have a PAR
meter and what's, you know, what is your
reading at canopy, you know, kind of
thing, you know, do you have CO2? sort
of some of these other factors are going
to swing that, but just to play it safe
and sort of straddle a fence, like you
could probably hang out at like a 2.0 EC
the whole time and be pretty
comfortable. You're not leaving
something on the table kind of thing.
Um, but you are pushing hard enough to
get that desired result, you know. Um,
and again like sort of different
nutrients sort of concentrations and um,
you
know, all situations are different, but
basically if you sat at a 6.0 pH and a
2.0 EC, you could probably go hang out
and be super comfortable throughout a
whole run. For sure. I think that's a
great answer, especially for new growers
and especially if they're not uh
providing any supplemental CO2. And you
know, within that same uh line of
thought, keeping all the other
environmental and lighting factors at an
acceptable level rather than trying to
push them to the nth degree. Um because
at that point, there are going to be
different nutrient packages that need to
be increased in order to make sure that
the metabolism of the plant is uh
operating at its full potential with the
photosynthetic potential of the light
that you're providing to it. And so all
of those factors, you know, it's like uh
the the Liebig's law, you know, you have
your limiting factors within like the
staves of a of a barrel. So if as long
as you're raising them all up together
and going little bits at a time on all
of them to make sure that nothing spills
over, you should be able to achieve a
pretty optimal result for your
situation. Yeah, totally. Cool. Well, I
think that that was fun uh to tell
people a little bit about how they would
might uh how someone with your
experience might set up a new home grow.
And um yeah, one of the random other
things if possible. Yeah. You know,
doing this little homegrow, if you could
set yourself up, like this is one thing
I feel like you I've pushed on a couple
of friends over the like if you could
set yourself up a 4x8 tent, but really
only have one blade in it so that you
can contain everything inside
there. You know, you don't have to worry
about stuff spilling. You know, you
could fit if you had to fit a little
portable air conditioner or humidifiers
or whatever kind of other factors. You
know, if you had the space to put a 4x8
tent, but truly only put one light in
it, but put all of your other
environmental controls in there, like
that's the sty way to like absolutely do
some killer work in a small space like
that. For sure. It's like um the the
step up from a lung room, but right
before you actually meet a fully uh
sealed environment. So you can, you
know, you can still do passive intake or
exhaust or even active intake or exhaust
and something like that if you need to
because like yeah, you could have maybe
an AC inside the tent, but you need to
exhaust the AC still at that point if
it's like a standing one or you know,
you cut a hole in it and you stick it up
against a wall where you already have a
wall-mounted AC or something like that.
Then you're still having some sort of
air exchange. And you know, I've seen
all sorts of different styles of that,
but I do really like the idea of having
a 4x8 or a 5x10 with just one light. You
have a lot of room to work around your
plants. You can even center that light
in the tent so you have an extra like 3
feet and 2 feet on either side and you
can get to all different sides of your
plant really easy that way. Um, it's a
great way to learn. I think that's it.
Also containing smell, containing
spillage of water, sort of all of those
things. Plus, like while you're working
in there, you could watch this
humidifier kick on or you hear an
exhaust, you know, kind of it's like it
it's one of those things. It's just it
turns the same thing that we do in these
big big buildings now just to a smaller
scale kind of thing. So, you get to like
see how this turns on, this turns off,
you know, like just all the moving parts
pulling levers and how it all works. So,
absolutely. I think that that's a a
great advice for new growers, especially
if they have the ability to and the
space, right? because there's, you know,
a little bit of overhead cost that you
got to con deal with there. And then the
space of a 4x8 tent is significant if
you're in like a small apartment or
something. So all these different
factors need to be taken into account.
But, you know, if for an ideal, you
know, one light setup, that sounds
awesome. like a lot of people I think
would be able to hit the ground running
and ex and succeed, you know, on their
first however many harvests that they
get out of something like that if
they're and you could do quite a bit of
work out of that little space. Like, you
know, Oh, yeah. I mean, you're not
really Yeah. Yeah. You're probably if
you're doing everything correctly,
you're you're easily pulling 12 to 15
pounds out of that space per year. And
if that's just for your own consumption
at home and you're going through more
than a pound a month, then you might
need to slow down a little bit. I don't
know. I'd be impressed. But yeah,
whatever. You know, that kind of thing.
For sure.
Um well, uh let's see. So, we kind of
we've touched base on your background,
what you do at Next Big Crop.
Um, let's talk about some of the current
things and current projects that you're
working on and uh maybe some of the
things that you've seen within the
cannabis industry that you either might
want to see change or see move in a
certain direction. Um, like what are
some of the trends that you're seeing
and things that you're currently
experiencing through your consultation
services? Um, sure. So I guess like one
of the you know like I said we kind of
have projects um every you know lots of
markets kind of thing even at this point
like internationally kind of thing. So
that's like something shiny you know and
fun to talk about and dream about and
stuff like that you know hoping it gets
closer. Yeah. You know been working on
one project in Costa Rica for almost
three years now. Um so that's real close
to getting across the finish line and
can't wait. Um
um but I guess sort of like sort of
certain things see in the market these
days one of the things I guess like the
hardest thing as a consultant sometimes
is to like come in and sort of try to
prove to you know like the team that
you're coming in to work with you're
like yo dude I don't want your job like
I'm not here for your job kind of thing
like I'm here to help you solve stuff
and sort of get in and get out kind of
thing. Um, you know, so like it is a
it's a dance and like trying to figure,
you know, you got to become friends with
the cultivation team. You got to sort of
put your time in the trenches a little
bit and show that like, yo, I've done
this. I'm going to work right alongside
with you to help solve this, you know,
kind of thing. Like I win when you solve
problems and get better kind of thing.
So like that's like, you know, one of
the biggest and like most immediate
obstacles like everywhere you go. Um,
you know, sort of like I don't know. I'm
gonna sort of probably maybe upset some
people is like saying, you know, but
there's just like certain things that
are just unrealistic. Like when it comes
to like sales teams and accounting stuff
and whatever spreadsheets, you're like,
you know, bro, like your spreadsheets's
not real. Like, you know, so sort of
again bringing those expectations back
to reality and, you know, kind of thing.
It's like, you know, people
want something that tests this high that
finishes this fast and, you know, and
like it sort of just puts like
unrealistic goals or like, you know,
objectives in front of everybody, which
then causes like teams to clash, you
know, the garden's like, I need more
time or I need more money or I need
whatever, you know, to make this happen
and so it's sort of like it's sort of
hard to, you know, and then certain
people have like certain egos that are
like you know, sort of hard to work
around kind of thing. And like um you
know, and again like lots of it's
opinion based like this is flowers
impressive, this could be better, what
you know. So like I don't know. It's
just I wish there was a little bit
more. I don't know. I guess like said
sort of I feel very lucky to have sort
of become friends with the people like
I'm friends with and the network and all
that kind of thing. And like you know
your people really take care of you like
you know I like to think I take care of
you know kind of thing. Um, you know, so
like protecting yourself by like
building this killer team around you,
uh, vendors, friends, clients, you know,
kind of thing.
Um, you know, so I don't know. I guess I
wish people would treat you. I guess I
wish people would treat you the way you
treat them kind of thing. Um, you know,
kind of thing, which is like I guess
it's a you know, in the old days like
etiquette was everything and you know,
people sort of stepped out of line like
you know, people got blacklisted or like
you know, kicked off the what, you know,
kind of thing differently than now.
Um, you know, you know, it almost seems
like a bunch of what you're saying boils
down to education. Um, where, um, as
producers, you need to educate the, uh,
your marketing team. They need to
educate the buyers and the buyers need
to educate the consumers. And that needs
to be there needs to be some continuity
there in education so that you aren't
facing people that have um like as a as
a consultant you're not going into a
situation where you're facing these
undesirable expectations where it's not
necessarily unrealistic in certain
aspects but it's
not it's not feasible within what they
have available to them to work with
which is something that keeps coming up
in this conversation. Right? Like how
often it is that you see people
expecting something that they can't uh
they can't execute on or they don't have
the team or the resources to execute on.
But then working with that expectation
as though it's going to happen and you
know watching the sort of bricks crumble
around those expectations as it doesn't
come to fruition and the frustration and
the anger and the blaming and the ego
clashing and all these different things
that come up from just miscommunication
or an uneducated person. Um, and not
necessar I'm I'm using uneducated simply
because like there's parts of this
community and this and the culture
around cannabis that I feel like when
you're growing the plant, you have this
connection to it. When you're consuming
the plant, you have this connection to
it. And everything in between is kind of
not it's not necessary in a lot of
aspects. And so when there's whole
industries built around that unnecessary
part, you lose a lot to this
capitalistic uh suck hole, right? Where
it's it's it's unfortunate because it's
how we are able to get the product to
the consumers because of all the
different regulations and you know the
actual uh logistics of it. Um, but there
is this huge disconnect then between
what people are saying, I want this in
my joint versus what the grower is going
like, I can't grow a 14-week sativa and
get it to you in a $10 joint. There's no
way I can do that. No one in their right
mind is going to grow that. And so when
the sales team is saying, "We need
sativas. I need I need a 14week sativa."
That's what people ask. Bro, I've had
that conversation three times in the
last two weeks kind of thing. You know,
it's it's it's unfortunate, but like
it's almost hilarious how uneducated it
is because it's something as simple as
the disconnect of you're saying you want
a 14week sativa. Do you you're doubling
our input cost and our overhead to
produce that single gram. Let's just
talk about it as a gram, right? 100%
correct what you're saying. How are we
going to do that? Tell me how we're
going to do that and tell me how it's
going to maintain profitability because
you're getting enough ask for it, right?
But yeah, so
Oh, it's it's frustrating. I've been
there and I've, you know, you know, like
plants. We've done like grower events,
you know, you go to the dispensaries so
you could customers can come ask you
questions and, you know, and you sort of
put out like blogs and newsletters and
stuff like that, you know, and again,
it's I just feel like it's one of those
things of and I'm we're not the only
ones that talk about it obviously like
everybody talks about like sort of that
consumer education plans and all that
kind of stuff. And it's just one of the
harder parts and like you know sometimes
deal with like you know sort of I don't
know like was at a grow the other day
and like you know sort of they had their
wish lists and thoughts and like you
know we're trying to push stuff on you
and you're kind of like like bro I've
had bigger bedrooms than your whole
facility like you know kind of thing
like you've never worked in a garden
like what you're telling me we need to
do or asking us to try to help you do is
just not real kind of thing. and like
like I said, I've had bigger bedrooms
than the whole facility kind of thing.
And just like
the stubbornness or whatever, you know,
kind of thing to to try to like achieve
these, you know, goals at the end is
really hard. And again, like the other
thing again, like I feel like, you know,
we were we mentioned earlier some of
these smaller more craft growers, like I
love those craft licenses. like if I
could have my own that's what I would do
you know like absolutely you know um
because then it's like authentic it's
real like it's owner operated you know
kind of thing um I think some of these
facilities get in trouble you know maybe
this is a part people don't want to talk
about but you're like how much of these
big big facilities staffs um don't
really make the company money they're
there to fulfill roles because they're
such a big company and it needs it all
those salaries drain
you know kind of and make it really
difficult for them to be profitable
which then lead to cutting all the
corners and you know that kind of stuff.
So again like I don't know I just give
me an opportunity for like you know
those crafts size facilities where it's
a team of you know four 10 maybe what
you know but those small crews together
and like some of the best uh product
I've seen here in Colorado you know from
like smaller grows you know their
stuff's pre-sold at a pound and it's
like two growers and two trimmers and
that's it. These guys are about seven,
you know, but they've all been there
seven guys in this facility, but they've
been together for four or five years and
their work is killer. Like, I'd be
excited to go buy it, you know, kind of
thing. It's in the flow guys in Boulder.
Um, you know, kind of thing. Like, I
don't know, but like that's what a team,
you know, they pay their guys well.
Their team is super loyal to them. They
go perform and execute in the garden.
like their product is killer, you know,
like that's the success successful like
facilities and teams. I think um I
agree.
I see that all the time like you got to
have a happy staff in order to have a a
good product and uh unfortunately so
many people are just trying to go for
um like uneducated and uh and unskilled
labor and then just trying to like bring
them up in a certain way which can help.
But also there's so many opportunities
there for there to be
um a mis a mist transfer of information
where you can't then apply that
knowledge elsewhere. And so you're like
training them to do this specific task
and when you ask them to try and then
apply that knowledge in a different way,
it doesn't always work. And
um it's it's tough because it is an
agricultural product and so I don't see
the price ever going back up. And a lot
of people for a while there were saying,
"Oh, we're waiting for the market to
rebound. It's not going to happen.
There's there's no there's no reason for
it to happen. There's only a reason for
the price to continue to go down." I
feel like, you know, my only back little
push back to that is I do think that
like people will be brand loyal to
somebody that has treat, you know, kind
of thing. like some with some of these
smaller ones like you know you'll always
be able to get you'll always be able to
be profitable with your work. you're
good enough to hit, you know, grams per
square foot kind of thing. Um, and and
dot dot dot, you know, all that stuff
down the line. You know, maybe you're
not printing money like the old days
kind of thing, but like it is
profitable. You know, you can pay your
people,
right? You know, all of the correct
inputs that you want without like
skipping something. Um, so I don't know.
I think that that's just kind of why
it's like that balance point of that
sort of craftsiz garden
um is a very happy medium for um for
sure. you know, to go hang out in kind
of thing. It's safe. Yeah, absolutely.
I'm I'm sorry. I was kind of more
referring to this uh constant race to
the bottom that you see a lot of
different operators. Yeah. And and so
like by by racing to the bottom and and
by uh you know by showing that the value
of the product can be reduced, you're
not going to then trick anybody by
trying to raise the price of something
uh at the same quality point and saying
this is worth more now when they were
already paying, you know, yeah, a lower
price for it. And when it comes to those
larger facilities and those larger
producers that are still producing
quality at scale, th that's where I feel
like it's it's a problem for the
overarching market because when you do
have small craft farms like you're
talking about that are able to achieve
uh $1,600 price point per pound or even
some people that are breaking it up into
eighs or quarter ounces or ounces even
and selling those at a high price point
so that their overall pound price is,
you know, significantly
more if there's there's only room for
like extremely small boutique and highly
sought after with limited supply
cannabis to be able to achieve those
high price points. It's never going to
be for anything that's mass-produced.
Um, at least in my mind, that's what
that's where I make that
differentiation. even working at like
way to grow like you know people would
come in with receipts from three other
grow stores and be like they said they
would sell it to me at that you know
like so like every you know it's one of
those things I feel like across the
board everybody's getting beat up with
that race to the bottom idea you know
and right
um yeah it's one of those things of like
it just it beats everybody up like
across the board and it's hard to deal
with but it does but yeah I'm with you I
don't think it's certain things will
never come back up you know certain
things will be good because they're
they've earned it. Yep. Those guys with
eight lights that are still operating in
the gray market, they they're the ones
that are making a killing right now. And
uh hats off to them. Let them keep doing
it. I know. I miss those days,
right? It I'm envious. I'm envious, but
I I have uh other obligations. So,
that's it's Yeah. Now we're all grown up
and Yeah. kind of like Yeah. I'm not
about to be running midnight runs with
uh you know 20 pounds in the in the
trunk. Yeah, it's one of those things of
like sometimes you joke about you know
you're like waited for all these years.
You're like is my door getting kicked in
tonight? Am I getting robbed or
arrested? You know kind of thing. And um
so I guess glad to sort of have moved on
from some of that. But I guess at the
same time some of the romance and the
sparkle of that was a whole lot of fun.
Oh for sure. I mean aren't the the
greatest like the greatest novels are
like tragedies? I feel like, you know,
and so we don't want to live that
tragedy though anymore.
Um, let's see. What's um what are some
of the successes that you've uh
encountered when helping out a facility
that are uh a highlight for you? And
then also um if you don't mind sharing
what might be a couple of or a failure
point in when trying to help implement
these different things at facilities
where um through both the success and
the failure you learn something
tremendous from it. Sure. So I guess
we'll start with the failure part kind
of thing you know. Um I feel like
sometime again it gets just back to like
communication education kind of stuff.
Um, and like Sarah said, like teaching
teacher, um, you know, if you could just
imagine the class behaves differently
when you have a substitute teacher than
like the regular teacher, you know, so
when it comes to some of this stuff, um,
if you're not tight with the cultivation
team that's on the ground there, you
know, like sometimes you fly in for a
week and then you're back in Colorado
for a week or to a different site for
that week, you know, you sort of stagger
back and forth and you still have your
sort of cultivation meetings and uh, you
know, like that kind of stuff, but like
you know when you're away if the staff
isn't like backing you and sort of
performing to
um you know what they were supposed to
do that day you or even almost like a
little malicious or like oh we're not
going to do that cuz he's not here this
week you know then it really turns into
a battle of like us verse them you know
and they have a whole staff on there
they all live there you know and I'm
just a guy getting on a plane flying
back and forth you know that's coming to
tattle on them or whatever you know kind
of thing so like that's like the hardest
thing. Um, you know, and some of them
have really hurt cuz like you get really
close with cultivation team, you know,
kind of thing. But then the owner
doesn't want to pay for something
anymore. Well, you know, kind of it just
turns into a little bit of a battle of
like us versus them. So that's kind of
just why at this point, you know,
uh now that we're like private and it's
just like sort of myself, Rich and
Christian versus like this whole big
publicly traded company, it's easier for
us to like sort of insert ourselves in
as being like an owner's rep and being
with them kind of thing versus, you
know, sort of the bosses over here
trying to push revenue for whatever
board in New York and stuff like that,
you know, kind of thing. So, you know,
it's like you get to, you know, one
sometimes I'll joke or complain like why
do I care about your garden more than
you do, you know? Um,
you know, like that's a tough
conversation to have. Yes. you know, so
I feel like that's like that I don't say
failure part, but it's like the uglier
part kind of thing, you know, because
like as a consultant, you know, there's
lots of, you know, high fives, hugs, and
partying, you know, when things are
working, but you know, things, you know,
there's the hiccups, lots of
fingerpointing kind of thing, you know,
sort of. So, like, you know, when things
work, there's like almost say no praise,
but like, you know, everybody expects it
to be that way, you know, and then stuff
gets a little sideways and, you know,
fireworks kind of thing. So, Oh, for
sure. Oh, I mean, no one brings it up
when it's working, right? No one takes a
a lawn mower into the the shop to get it
fixed because it's working. They they go
in because it's broken and it's not
working. And when you're the one in
charge of the fixes, right? Like you're
you're the repair man for their grow. Um
they're looking at you for all the
failure points, especially if any of it
happens after you've already come on to
the team to help them execute on what
they're doing. A lot of it though, like
you're saying, especially with larger
teams, and if that team doesn't feel
connected to this style of growing and
the direction that they're being given,
then you start to run into um little
clashes that might not even be uh like
you might not even see it as what it is
that's uh generating this issue, but the
outcome of that issue is still then
affecting the grow in one way or the
other.
And sometimes it's like you need to get
on board or hop the [__] off because
this train is going and uh we're here to
make sure that it's going to continue to
go. And when Yeah. When you give
someone, you know, something simple like
let's say it's a IPM SOP and there's two
people that are ex Oh, it is. Oh, it is.
And when you have people that are you
you say, "This is what you do these days
of the week. You do it every single week
and you do not fail to do it." And then
you come in and they say, "I've been
doing it." And you go in and you're
like, "There's [__] russet
mites on these plants." If you were
doing it, you know, like these right
here. Yeah. Sulfur and oil and sulfur
and oil don't mix. And so you're like,
you're like, you come in and they're
like, "Well, I sprayed, you know,
they're like, I don't know what
happened." And you're like, bro, that
phototoxicity from that, you know,
application, every le leaf in this room
is burned up. Like there's nothing left.
Sprayed suffoil on Monday and and sulfur
on Tuesday. Oh,
I wonder why it looks like, you know,
like so there's that. Um, you know, kind
of thing. Um, I guess along those same
lines though, like the sort of the most
like rewarding part, you know, like I
feel like I've been asked this question
a handful of times and like the answer
has evolved a little bit, but like you
know, when you're working in a garden
where like everything's jamming, like
all the plants look good, people are in
a good mood, like music's bumping in
every growroom kind of thing, like that
vibe is like intoxicating kind of thing.
So like that's contagious. Totally. you
know, so like there's that, but like
along the lines of that, like some I
feel like my like greatest success
story, you know, home girls, you got
your first harvest at a new spot. And
they're like, "Does anybody have any
friends that can come in and help
harvest or whatever, you know?" So the
one girl uh brought her boyfriend in,
like no job, no whatever, never touched
a cannabis plant before, you know. But
on day one of harvesting, like, you
know, his hands were moving faster than
anybody else's. So like hired him on and
then he was working just in the you know
the harvest and like the trim team and
then so I moved him up to like the sort
of processing space. Um, and then next
thing you know, I brought him outside
with me to run the outdoor. And you know
within a year he went from being some
you know one of the girls boyfriends
that came in for like temp work to
running the whole facility you know and
it was like you know kind of thing where
like when you get to like sort of like
said maybe what I run a you know
teaching background but like you know
you find like the younger version of you
know yourself or just somebody super
like in it for the plant kind of thing
and you get to like sort of bring them
up like that's [__] rad you know kind
of thing cuz like I don't know This this
analogy might be distasteful, but
sometimes you need them to drink the
Kool-Aid. Like you need them to be like
on board with the process and not um
hey, you know, I read somewhere over
here that this might work. Do you think
we should try? It's like, yeah, maybe in
a couple years when you have everything
that's already here down and it's
operating properly and then we can start
to play and have fun. But even with that
though, they're reading on their own.
They're doing what you know, kind of
thing. You're like, it does. Yeah. You
know, kind of thing. You're like, I'll
give you the books. Here's the websites.
Listen. Yeah. So, it's like when
somebody does like go to do homework
after, you know, you just worked eight
or 10 hours or however long in the
fields 100 degrees in Oklahoma, you're
still going home and reading about
cultivation methodologies to come in and
ask me more questions. Like, yep. I'll
take you to lunch every day. Like, let's
do it, you know, kind of thing. Yeah,
absolutely. You know, so like when you
find those, you know, at the same time,
like I said, the rewarding part is like
when you find those, you know, you can
sort of build those relationships and
those teams and like you see somebody's
life change because of the plant and
learn in the same way as you did, like
it's [__] cool, you know, and like
Oh, absolutely. You know, one thing that
I like to Oh, sorry. One thing that I
like to do with people is is um you know
if they have an idea for something that
they want to implement in the grow I'll
say listen I want you to tell me why we
do the things that we are doing now and
when you can tell me why we're doing
those things then I want you to tell me
why we should implement this other thing
and if it works and if it makes sense
and you understand how it's going to
interface with these other processes
then let's give it a try. let's let's go
cuz it you know if it's something I
didn't think of I never be the smartest
person in the room right you don't want
to be there and try to be like I know
everything and I am the allseeing eye
you know it's it doesn't work yeah say
so like I encourage it's one of those
things you're like you sort of present
the idea discuss it whatever you know
like is it can we do this in a
controlled setting where we're going to
get to actually see a result like so I
don't know like it is really fun and
super rewarding to and I guess like one
of my other favorite parts of it I guess
is like, you know, you've done this
forever long and like lots of people
that have done it like we have. You
know, you can walk in somewhere and
you're like, takes five minutes to put
together that like lowhanging fruit list
of ways that we could improve this.
You're like, ding, ding, ding. You know,
like you're already, all right, we're
already done. Like, we just stepped this
up. Yeah. In whatever sort of I guess
grading scale that we are, but like I
don't know. Like I love the creative
problem solving part of it, you know,
and then when like the light bulbs go
off with them and you actually get to
see those improvements like quickly. Um
I don't know like for sure again it's
like you know at this
point there's no secret sauce, there's
no whatever. It's basically how
controlled of like an understanding do
you have across like all of the aspects
to balance it out?
Yeah. Yeah. I feel like one of the
things I've seen someone that I've
worked with do that I was just like,
"You get it? You're starting to get it
is uh when they uh started to understand
why the EC would increase in the
substrate, I I tried to have them
problem solve it by giving them the idea
of saying, "Make a salt solution in
water. Keep one in a cup, like a full
cup, and then keep one in a half a cup.
How much salt's going to be left when
that water evaporates?" and watch them
problem solve that out and then go the
the substrate's the cup and what we're
putting into it is the salt solution and
what's coming out is when you're uh
you're adding more water to that salt
solution but still maintaining the
volume and I I'll go through this like
process with them to try and have them
just relate it to table salt in water
and in a cup and it um it usually works
pretty well to get them to go oh my gosh
I see that if I'm I'm allowing it to dry
back too much and I'm not pushing that
extra salt off it's just going to keep
building and I don't want it to go too
high. But you say I do want it to go a
little high and you start to go, "Yep,
just just keep an eye on it. Keep
monitoring it." And it you see some
tremendous results. I have I have a
buddy right now who is he swapped over
from, you know, this uh
multi-part um uh semi-organic,
semi-organic
uh large pot system to where I'm like
just I want you to do one gallon cocoa.
I want you to do drain to waste and
we're going to up your EC slowly. And
he's
um amazed by how fast the plants are
growing. And I'm like this is it's fun
to watch, isn't it? That's what like
said like give me can of cocoa flex
pots, the one gallons, your cocoa A and
B nutrient with a little bit of a
drip and like you know put somebody on
with that and you're like yo if you can
do this then you can get it creative and
do whatever you want later kind of
thing. But like it really is that
simple.
to knock it out of the park kind of
thing. And uh definitely I don't know.
But yeah, like you like explain it like
you're talking to a second grader. You
if everybody can understand that kind of
level then like that's true
comprehension and we can move forward.
No. Don't need to absolutely ever try to
be too smart. Yeah. And and you know
such a huge part of education is uh the
continual education of the people who
are teaching, right? And so by teaching
other people, I feel like it's always
been the best way for me to hone my own
knowledge of a of a subject because if I
can teach it, then I have a better grasp
on it. And if I can teach it to people
across a multitude of, um, learning
preferences, then I can know it even
better, right? And so, um, that's why I
love doing this podcast and talking to
all different people and and, you know,
honing my own skill through these
conversations. Um, and with like even
trading stories though, you know, like
this worked for me, you know, and like
along those same lines like I don't know
sometimes I really wish I had my my
garden that's my like showpiece,
masterpiece, whatever, you know, kind of
thing. Um, you know, sometimes I
certainly really wish I had that right
now. it kind of but other times like I'm
talking to a different you know half
dozen to a dozen different gardens
that you know you're sort of like
invested and involved in all at the same
time. So like if you're trying to sort
of make whatever one correction here and
there and whatever I'm waiting six days
or 10 days before I imp implement
certain things you know versus waiting
two months. So you're able to like with
that process of deduction and like hone
in on whatever like you're trying to
achieve and uh you know sort of get to
that result so much faster
by having your hands in you know so many
friends gardens or whatever you know
that kind of stuff. So it's just like
for sure I don't know again simple
control like reflect on it but like you
know one of the other things I feel like
you know along the same lines we're
talking about you know when it comes to
success and failure stuff sometimes it's
like fail faster like this person
doesn't fit this
role move on to the next deserving
person or like you know this application
of whatever you know we're trying to
manipulate the plant with like doesn't
fit like don't keep forcing it. It's
not. Yeah, it didn't work three times
already. You know, you hoping it's going
to work the fourth time like isn't going
to make it happen. Like move on. That is
the definition of insanity, sir. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. So, like just that idea is
like fail faster, you know, again,
reflect and get back at it. Absolutely.
I you know and I feel like with both of
our
um I feel like we we both have sort of
this uh passion and and uh focal point
of education in a lot of what we're
doing like me with the podcast you with
what you're doing through your
consulting services with next big crop
and even in your past with you know
helping educate people and even learning
from your interactions with people at
the grow shop and and um at all the
different aspects of the grow world that
you've uh encountered through your
career.
So, I feel like you'll be a great person
to ask this question to. Um, and I want
to break it up into two parts. So, the
question is, what uh advice would you
give to new growers? What's that one
piece of golden advice you'd give to new
growers? And I want it to be for someone
who is homegrowing for their medicine as
part one. And for someone who is trying
to enter the cannabis industry as part
two. Sure. So part one
um for home grower for like medicine and
passion projects and just like the craft
and like the love of it you know like
these days like I guess it's people like
you with these podcasts you know that
are such an open book of information um
all the YouTube channels all just the
reading that is out there kind of things
like do your homework um and sort of uh
you know again you know also at this
point you probably have a friend
somewhere whether it's in your state or
town or across the country somewhere um
that is like totally invested in like
this is their life and like lifestyle
and career. It's to sort of like pick
pick a team essentially that you want to
sort of join like a philosophy a
methodology and sort of like follow that
you know do your research so that you
like pick the correct team kind of thing
but then really follow that plan that
those people give you or that you like
you know put together yourself kind of
thing until it's sort of a little bit
exhausted or like you're ready for the
next one you know and again like you
don't need all the fanciest everything,
you know, like you don't need that much
space, but like you do need a plan kind
of thing. So, like really do your
homework and put together a
plan and then go execute it kind of
thing. Um, don't shoot from the hip, you
know? So, it's like that's what I would
say for the home grower is the most
and just like de make a plan and then
follow it and your next round is going
to be different than your first one. Um,
but like you sort of need to make those
mistakes. Push it too hard underwater.
What you know, it got too hot, it got
too cold, what, you know, like the only
way to sort of find that
uh sort of happy medium across the board
is to push it too hard to go under, you
know, one of my buddies and I talk about
you're like, "How long does it take you
to figure out a strain?" You know, and
the answer is maybe four runs, maybe
five runs. You know, first one's sort of
shooting in the dark. The second one,
you probably push it too hard. The third
one, you probably back it down too much.
Fourth one, ideally, you know, you're
right in that butter zone and like
really hit it. But if not, the fifth
one, you should totally be able to. Um,
yeah. So, maybe a home grower should
almost think of it like that way kind of
thing. Like it'll take you four rounds
to
hopefully be comfortable and happy with
what you did, you know, because you're
going to learn a whole lot in those
first four.
And I feel like that's uh that's
applicable to not only a a specific
genetic, but any sort of style of
growing and then any adjustment to that
style of growing. And um you know once
you start to learn about the different
aspects of growing more, you definitely
have the ability to make those
adjustments on the fly as well as make
more adjustments at once rather than
only tweak one or two things in order to
make sure that you're tracking what
those changes do to your grow. Um, so I
I think that that's great advice for
people and it it falls in line with a
lot of what other people have said to
that answer or to answer that question,
which is patience. You know, have
patience with yourself, have patience
with the growth style, trust the process
that you put um in place and if it
doesn't work, that's where you get to
start to be your puzzler and you start
to get to try and figure out why it
didn't work and make an adjustment from
there. Um, so I think that's great. One
of the things just yeah you I guess it's
the other one too but like I think one
thing that I realized you know through
gardening um you know I don't think I
was ever very patient before of a person
but like through gardening you realize
that like you can't fake time like it
takes twoish weeks to clone a plant. It
t you know like like you know you can't
fake time kind of thing. And you also
can't fake how much time you invest into
your project. you know, the guy that or
the person that puts in 20 minutes a day
versus the person that's put in an hour
in a day or whatever, you know, but you
can't fake time kind of thing. Like the
more you put in, the more you get out
and just like, you know, again, even if
that first harvest or second harvest
isn't, you know, these big nugs like
you're seeing all, you know, like kind
of thing, you're still learning. So,
just like you really can't fake that
time that you invest. Um, so for sure
that's great. I guess along the second
line for somebody wanting into the
industry,
um, man, I feel like this is a loaded
one kind of thing.
Um, um, I guess we have don't. Yeah.
Well, not going to say that, but maybe.
No, I know. I know kind of thing. uh you
know kind of you really have to want it
is maybe the first thing like you have
to want this to be your lifestyle. It's
not just a job. It's not a career like
this is a lifestyle that uh you know and
again I going back to some of my
beginning feel like very lucky that I
started you know cultivating like sort
of when it was still a little bit outlaw
in Colorado like you know they started
having medical cards. And I remember
going and getting my medical card at a
dispensary and then you know you meet
the doctor and you pay your tab and then
like you walk out of the back of the
doctor's office into a dispensary
there's somebody's grandma packing bowls
for you you know while he could wait and
pay with a credit card or you know debit
card to get a gram or what you know and
you're like what is you know kind of
thing you know what is going on. Yeah.
You know kind of so like but again like
I don't know looking back you're like
that was cool. Um, but you really have
to want it to be like it is a lifestyle.
It's
exhausting. It's a commitment kind of
thing. There's a whole lot of sacrifice
that goes along with it. Um, you know,
kind of thing, especially in the
cultivation side of it. Um, you know, so
um I don't know, some people want to
work in the retail side of it. Some
people want to be say, you know, again,
like, you know, you really got to want
it to do it. Um, and again, I would say
at this point, a lot of places are
established enough where you could find
out the reputation of how a company
treats their people. Um, and I would
just make sure that you're joining a
team with values and sort of like you
feel like is like a like-minded facility
or group of people. Um, because
otherwise some of them are pretty toxic
and it's just not like a positive part
of life or what you should be doing, you
know, kind of thing. The whole point of
like cannabis and self-medicating and
like the plant and all that is to make
people better, happier, like things
better, brighter, shinier. Um, so make
sure you're joining a team that that
like is their purpose kind of thing. Um,
and if a place isn't that, maybe you got
to pull a rip cord faster than you want.
Um, so that you don't like tarnish, you
know, something that is so sparkly. Oh,
for sure. I've um I have definitely
bailed on um different grows, not
necessarily like just like cut cord and
run, but I've I've had to exit different
companies just for the simple fact that
their values while uh were, you know,
purported to be one thing ended up being
something completely different or you
know, you go into some place thinking
that you're going to learn and all of a
sudden you're hearing stuff that you're
like, I I know that this is wrong. like
I've been this has already been
disproven. I've heard a multitude of
other people say that this is wrong and
so why are they saying this? Or you know
on on the worst end of things, you run
into people that are
doing a bunch of coke, drinking a bunch
of booze, you know, smoking on the job
and not paying attention to what they're
doing. Um yeah, like cleanliness, dude.
like people in like this is similar to I
don't want to say food production or
what you know but like we've done all
that food production stuff we've done
classes and what you know like like
needs to be clean
kind of thing like that's one of the
first things like sometimes you walk in
places and you're like oh wow I could
eat off this floor like [__] yeah this
is going to you know kind of thing or
you walk in and you're just like
disgusted from the you're like yo I need
to burn these clothes kind of thing. So
if you don't walk in and immediately
say, "Wow, this place is clean."
I don't, you know, that's one of my, you
know, kind of I'd say, "Oh, I agree."
And and clean is sort of a a spectrum,
right? Like depending on each facility,
the the level of cleanliness that can be
achieved is is on a spectrum. And so you
have to have, you know, temper
expectations, but then also, yeah, if if
the end goal is to create a product that
you are putting into your body, whether
it be through smoke, vapor, an edible, a
consumable, a topical, anything like
this, like it's going into your body.
You you don't want to go into a place
where you don't want your body to be in
the room where it's being produced.
And don't get me wrong, like point some
of the best cannabis like ever grown's
probably been grown in some old basement
somewhere or whatever, you know, doesn't
mean it's not clean. Like doesn't mean
they don't follow plans, whatever. Like,
so it doesn't have to be this spaceship.
It doesn't have to be so cutting edge
and robots and, you know, but like you
walk in and tables are dirty or floors
are dirty or whatever. Like that's a
flag. Yep. Absolutely. I agree. I I
think the dirty floors thing is one of
the big ones that uh Oh, man. You walk
in and there's just like muddy
footprints everywhere and you go, "Oh,
fuck." Yeah. Like, you've never
downhill.
Yeah, absolutely. Well, Jared, this has
been a wonderful conversation and I
think that this is a great point for us
to start wrapping up and uh going into a
couple of these last little questions
that I like to ask. Um, was there
anything else uh about Next Big Crop or
what you do or about uh cannabis
cultivation in general that you wanted
to touch base on before we get into this
these last few wrap-up questions? Um, I
don't know. I guess maybe
just like I said going back I've said it
how many times now but like sort of feel
really lucky to have gotten to sort of
come up with certain people like you
know in an ideal world like give me some
dosatrons like Wall-E and
Chris you know I feel like I remember
the first time I installed a dosatron
you know I you know I was running a spot
out in Maryland that came home to a
whole bunch of dead plants in my
basement kind of thing and you're
like Chris, I think it's time. So, he
like whipped me up one and then Wally
helped whatever, you know, kind of
thing. And then all of a sudden, it
removes so much time and mental, you
know, that mental exercise of filling a
res and whatever, you know. So, it's
kind of
like I don't know like like I said, I
love race cars and building race cars
and stuff like that. And so, like look
at this like so, you know, you have like
that part of it, you know. Um, and then
like there's like the other part about
like we were just talking about being
clean like Zach Homie over at Biosafe is
a wizard again, you know, when it comes
to like the clean chemistry behind this
stuff, you know, like I could keep going
on sort of about the certain groups of
people, you know, like the Canada guys
that work real close with, the Fluence
guys and the Dvita guy what, you know,
so like make friends with people and
like learn from the subject. subject
matter experts and I feel like I guess
I've done a pretty good job at that and
like sort of always take care of them
for them taking care of like educating
you. Um and like I don't know like for
have a network to solve you know any
garden in this country I feel like we're
one degree away from you know solving
any major problem next to crop is one
degree away from like I'm not going to
pretend I have all the answers cuz I
absolutely don't but I know who does you
know and all it takes is just like a
phone call to get these answers.
Absolutely. Um so go hang out in a
network like that and like it's a real
good spot to be for sure. I mean, along
the lines of what you're saying, there's
there's so many different things that,
you know, someone can introduce you to
that will change your life as a grower.
And one of those things kind of with
what you're saying is, uh, you know,
give me any grow that doesn't have a
dosing system and give me three
dosatrons, an open sprinkler, and a
liter pump, and I will change your life.
Yeah. Uh, in a heartbeat. And you will,
you know, you'll think that
it's it's it's crazy what you can do
with something just as simp with as
simple as that. And uh and people will,
you know, it'll change their life. They
they or when it comes to time in the
garden. Yeah. when it comes to IPM stuff
or when it comes to insert whatever sort
of subject matter expert you're pulling
in for
this using people that are that
expertise and have done it and like
actually walk the walk and do it like
nationwide or even internationally at
this point like problem solve with those
people and learn from them and you're
like whoa things work you know kind of
thing like
you know so they're going to look at
problems in a whole new way Yeah, you're
like, not that it's a problem at this
point. You're like, cool, I got it. I've
done it, you know, kind of thing. Like,
yeah. Um, there's other fires to put out
besides the sort of mechanical aspects
to this stuff like that. So, yeah,
without any problems, growing cannabis
starts to become pretty boring,
actually. Uh, that's the point. It
should be it should go to plan. It
should be boring. Yeah, it it like at
the end of the day if if
uh if you if everything's going off
right, you can probably run a 100 light
facility with two or three people um in
the garden and each one of them should
not be spending more than 40 hours there
a week. So yeah. Yeah, I think your
numbers are pretty right on. Yep. And uh
for anybody that's a home grower, think
about it. You can take knowledge that
you're learning either from these
podcasts or from other shows or other
educational resources and you can put
yourself in that position if it is
something like Jarrett said that you are
driven to do because it does require a
lot of dedication but it can be really
rewarding and in the end if it's working
well it's not that hard of work and it's
really re like it like I said it's
rewarding and it's it's not bad and you
got to find the right people though with
the right uh mindsets to work with and
work for in this community though
because there are still a lot of
um let's just say what it is. There's a
lot of [__] and it's not just in
this community and industry. It's across
every industry and it's you know a life
lesson to take to find people that you
like working with and that you can align
your philosophies with to make sure that
you are not there struggling to get
through to the end of your shift or the
end of the day. Yeah. Like honestly like
that's like me and Jesse like met up at
a spot that you know he's you know had
to walk away from and what you know that
it's one of those things but like you
know you meet somebody you get to talk
to him for 20 minutes and you're like
huh you're pretty cool you know kind of
thing and like you know like next thing
you know you're like how many years
later how much do I talk to you every
you know kind of um you know across the
board like we'll probably start talking
a lot after this too you know one of
those things of like you know like I
don't know I literally almost every
facility we've ever worked at. I like
still talk to people at those spots like
regularly. Yeah. Whether it's
like talking genetics or whatever, plant
stuff or even cars, sneakers, food,
whatever, you know, kind of like, you
know, you become friends with these
people in the garden because you shared
something with them and uh it's real and
it like carries on. Yeah, it's a
tight-knit community when it comes down
to it. Um, you know, there's a there's a
lot of uh issues with communities that
are that tight-knit. you get a lot of
incestuous uh
reciprocal, you know, [__] that is
not necessarily the best in some cases,
but then you can build these long-term
friendships and and bonds with other
people that are within this industry.
And in a lot of ways that's you know
those are the people that will be in the
future the giants whose shoulders other
people are standing on whereas we're
standing on the shoulders of so many
giants before us and all of the [__]
that they went through in the
prohibition era and are you know even
still there's a lot of issues with that
now but there's so much of the
information that we're drawing from to
be able to help all these different
growers perfect what they're doing in
their own style. We didn't start it.
We're not even the people that are
continuing to discover it because that's
happening in other agricultural
industries. And we're just trying to
make it the best that we can with the
information and the circumstances that
were given given the legality and
history and everything. Fun stories of
it. Like one of my homies went to
college with in Ohio 20ome years ago.
Yeah. When he moved out here too. And
yeah, he's a raft guide and ski bum and
all that kind of stuff. um and he used
to trim all my um product for me with
me, you know, then he went and got his
MBA and so we would listen to his like
textbooks while he's getting his MBA and
trim circles and stuff, you know, and
like now his company's hired my company,
I've hired it like whatever. So like
nice, you know, like and like even just
going back to other stuff like I don't
know who doesn't love traveling, you
know, kind of thing, but like can't tell
you how many trips to Mexico, Costa
Rica, you know, Europe, like Croatia,
Italy, like, you know,
like different sort of groups of
cultivation people that have traveled
the world and done really cool [__]
together, you know, and it all is
because of this plant, you know, you're,
you know, on some sailboat in Croatia
doing whatever you know kind of just you
know rafting the Grand Canyon like with
a whole bunch of wild [__] that
you know like so it's just one of those
things like you know there's like I said
it's a lifestyle and you know like sort
of you stay you know I'm from Philly so
like Alan Iverson has a tattoo CT on his
neck like crew thick you know it stands
for and I feel like that's one of those
things of uh you I don't know I sort of
subscribe to it like you take care of
your people and like Yeah, definitely.
So,
yeah, I feel that. I feel like yeah,
finding finding the real ones in this
industry, you you latch on and you try
to just build that group up even
further. Um, and so, yeah, I think
that's a a great place to kind of end
our main conversation on. So, uh, let's,
uh, let's go into a couple of these fun
little wrap-up questions and, uh, we'll
wrap up from there. So, uh, favorite
strain of all time. Loaded question, but
of course. Yeah. Maybe when I was
younger and I guess like we talking
about still chasing it. I talk about it
too often. You know, I feel like the
first time like you're
like I don't know, like a like a a sour
diesel or just a diesel that like when
you would walk in the bar 15 years ago,
you know, with a ziplockc baggie and you
could have a gram in your pocket,
everybody in the bar would point at you
and go, "You have sour diesel in your
pocket." Like I miss that diesel. Um, so
I love some diesel
first. Then nowadays we're talking older
stuff. also like really love like a good
Indiana bubble gum is like I don't know
love it kind of thing. Um so like for
some of the older stuff like your diesel
your bubble gum I don't know like some
headband like same kind of family in our
circle of friends like Chuck and John
had this cut of Hong Kong that um I've
bought a bunch of different cuts of Hong
Kong over the years. None of them have
been anything like it so I don't know
what this really was. But this Hong Kong
was stellar. You know, a buddy got
arrested one time and they walked him
into the police office with it and um
you know, he had smoked a couple grams
out of the ounce kind of thing. But
every cop in the police office, I guess,
kind of congratulated him on the way out
because it made the whole office smell
kind of thing. And that Hong Kong was
like anytime used to that would come
around like I would load up for myself
just because it was like nothing I'd
ever seen. Like that was probably the
first like exotic cannabis I'd ever like
latched on to. Um so yeah, diesel,
bubblegum, Hong Kong in the old days. Um
heard of Hong Kong. Oh, again I have
not. This one might have been something
else and mislabeled or whatever because
all these Hong Kongs I've had since have
been not like you would not, you know,
it's just not the same. Um so hunting
for it kind of thing. If anybody has a
Hong Kong, I'd love to trade for it. Um,
then the cookie wreck, you know, those
seeds that I popped like 2011. I think
it's just smell, taste, whatever. Like
it's performance-enhancing, like, you
know, it like makes you like creative
and tunnel vision of, you know, like
every broomstroke would be the same if
you're sweeping a floor, you know, like
I swear you leave the house and you're
like uncomfortable and then the same
spot on the highway, you're like windows
down, turn music up, like I got this,
you know, it's like artistic and
creative weed, like
performance-enhancing. And then I guess
some some of the more recent stuff like
I don't know like now I'm older and
don't want to be so sped up. So like I
love some Koshmet like proper kosher. So
I know like like people might say
whatever like smell, taste, whatever. I
love how it makes me feel you know at
this point I want herb that like yeah we
all sit like this too much. Yeah. So
like something that opens your chest up
and gives you better posture is like one
of the ways I like sort of judge
cannabis. So like I don't know one stuff
that makes me feel better. Yeah. I love
some like archive had that pie face that
came out a couple years. Yeah. H long
time ago at this point without a bunch
of THCV in it. So it was like a diet
weed. So my girlfriend had me go hunt
that out and we found a really killer
winner of that. I guess most recent
thing that's my new favorite skunk tech
and mean jeans piec. That's like that's
like the best tasting herb. I [__]
love that piec.
I've heard nothing but good things about
the pie scream. It is so, you know, it's
stunning, attractive. It's like as
advertised. It's as attractive as you
could hope something is. And it's not
purple. It's like your seaf green, like
almost sweet like gum green color.
Stunning. Test 35 plus at a bunch of
different spots for us that, you know,
handful of spots we've shared it with.
Um, it's like you're
like as advertised like it smells. It
tastes as good as it smells, which is as
good as it looks. like, you know, ding
ding ding, like down that line. And it's
just a very unique flavor. You know,
it's fruity without being runish, you
know, like it's just it's very unique in
its own way. And um I don't know. That's
like my new favorite. It's unfortunate
because I have this thing where like I
really don't want to grow ugly weed even
though I know sometimes like a good
diesel or something is just going to
look like [__] when you're growing
it. um compared to what you might be
used to if you are growing these purples
and the different runts and you know
candy gases and all these different
things that are you know popular within
the market those are pretty and fun to
grow the you know the scinessence in
them the color change everything that
happens to that plant as it grows you're
just like oh this is fun and enjoyable
visually um olofactory you know all
these different things that you're just
like oh I love I love this um and I
think that's one of my pitfalls where
I'm just like I don't want to grow any
green weed. I I know that it might be
good, but I'm I'm sorry. I don't really
want to grow it. I have this new like
Mercy, you know, not really new, but
it's from Gage Green, you know, out of
Michigan. It's like TK by Glue by High
School Sweetheart, and it's like green
and sort of rubber nostalgic cush. I
don't know. It's one of those things
you're like, I haven't tasted anything
like that in a while. So, that's sort of
like a new favorite on the list as well.
But grow it and love it either way.
Yeah, it's green again though. You know,
it's really shiny. It's got the sparkle,
whatever. But again, it's like green. It
is nowhere near purple. And whatever.
We've been growing a cut of sherb
cocktail lately and it is green with
just, you know, tinges of purple as as
it like in the last couple days. But it
is so loud and it's such a yielder that
I'm just like, "Oh, I guess I'm growing
green weed right now." Yeah. There you
go. Yep. Cool. Well, uh, so that you
know, you have a a of course with
someone with your experience, it's going
to be really hard to pick out one strain
that you like. And so I I'm totally fine
with it just being a bunch of different
ones that are kind of developed over the
time. Nobody at this point's just got
one jar on their table, man. You know,
that kind of thing. You're like, "What
time of the day is it? What are we
doing?" Like, you know, that's there. We
all have, I guess, options in front of
us kind of thing. So, but I guess I'm
trying to pick one. I know.
Yeah. So, and I just kind of got to cut
a Durban poison back and put that
through dissection. I can't wait to run
that because that used to be a favorite,
too. And hadn't really seen something
that was like that textbook Durban
poison, you know, where it is 100% like
recognizable, whatever. So, um, that's
just coming out of dissection like as we
speak pretty much kind of thing. So, I
can't wait to get that back on a table.
Um,
nice question. Yes, cool. uh favorite
breeder of all time.
I don't know if I can even pick one in
all honesty. I guess sort of I go
through phases, you know, like went
through an archive phase for a while.
Um you know, yeah, I guess did a whole
lot of archive work for a long time and
just sort of like kept finding winners,
you know, out of everything. That cookie
wreck came from
Canadenture I guess during COVID went on
a total like 808 genetics at a Hawaii
run. Um I don't know Bloom does killer
work too.
Um you know let's let's kind of curtail
this question for specific set of uh
interests and skill sets. So, if you had
to choose one breeder that you were to
curate your next
quarterly cut menu from and hunt all of
the seeds yourself, you have, you know,
you have unlimited time to hunt the
seeds and unlimited space to hunt all
the seeds that you want to hunt, but you
have to curate your 18 cultivars or
however many cultivars for your clone
list. What breeder would you go for to
start hunting through a bunch of
different packs? first. Great job
narrowing that question down. You nailed
that.
Um, that was a really good sort of
parameters to put it in.
It makes it harder but easier at the
same time. Yeah. So, I'm just trying to
think like who's got 18 different things
that's going to cross my menu that I
want kind of thing.
Maybe Bloom at this point
like kind of diverse enough where it's
like gonna touch your soury going to
touch like fruit in the like different
fruit categories kind of thing. Going to
touch some nostalgic with also being
relevant and new.
Um I don't know. That's probably my
answer for lack of for sure with your
parameters just kind of like who would I
go holler at? Like that's who I'd go
holler at to go try to pick 20 different
things to to go chase cuz like I don't
know like you know you need the
diversity who like you know cuz like or
you know I don't know like Alex from
Clear Water has done a whole bunch of
killer work over the years and I've lot
of his seeds because he's really diverse
too. So, I'd probably call Alex to be
honest or whatever between the two of
them. Either Clear Water or Bloom just
because I want a menu that's not so
focused on one trait or, you know, I
need a diversity. My mind immediately
goes to CSI Humboldt.
Great answer. Classic answer.
Especially if you're trying to curate
with a bunch of different flavors. I
just pick up S1's of everything that I
wanted to run and hunt 120 seeds of
them. Yeah. you nailed it on like being
able to diversify a menu out of the gate
that way. Um, and it's also your
nostalgic classic plus new, you know,
kind of thing. Like, all right, your
answer's better than mine.
Oh, it's not about better or worse. I
feel like it's um because, you know, a
fully curated Clearwater uh menu or a
Bloom menu, oh my god, you're going to
kill it. like you're going to have
you're going to have uh commercial
viability out of you know you'll
probably only need to pop two or three
packs of each genetic to find a true
unicorn and and and run it and run it
across facilities across the entire
country whereas you know my methodology
I need to pop like a couple hundred of
each one. Well, like I don't know. Like
both those guys too I feel like are very
like they touch older work but they're
also very current, you know? So like
you're making everybody happy with their
menus kind of thing. I don't know. I
guess I've run lots of Alex's seeds over
the years and like always found winner.
Like I don't think I ever walked away
without something from packs of that we
popped. Um for sure. So I'll stick with
Bloomer Alex and Clear Water. Cool. I'd
be happy. Awesome. All right. Well, last
question. What is a uh most memorable
cannabis related experience that you've
had and want to
share?
Um, whoa, tough question. Um, kind of
thing
like I don't know. I feel like there's
some I'm going to do this in like a
three-part answer kind of thing. Like
first one, you know, you remember the
first time you hit two pounds of light,
then you remember the first time you hit
three pounds of light, then you hit
four. Like, you know, kind of like So,
like, yeah, have like those like
specific memories of like
self-accomplishment, you know, kind of
thing like where you're like, "Oh, wow.
I didn't know I could do that. I did
that." You know, and you pulled
something off. Um, I guess maybe also
like this cookie wreck strain like never
shared it really in like you know the 13
or 14 years or whatever, you know, kind
of been running around with that and
finally started a whole breeding project
with it. Um, I feel like there's just
sort of like
nothing the way it makes you feel. Like
out of all the genetics like Evergrown,
nothing is like this. Like if there is a
certain medicine in it, you know, to to
do the studies and the research with,
like this is the specimen I would pick.
Um, so like excited to have finally
started breeding with it. Um, you know,
and that kind of thing.
But Canada specific memory. I don't
know. Like also going just back to sort
of like the friends like you know what
it's like showing up somewhere Costa
Rica, Mexico, wherever. even like when
like went say on through Croatia for a
couple weeks and you show up with like
your work, you know, and these guys are
like, you know, and you're with a group
of friends that have supported you and
helped you like manage and get through
all the, you know, but you you're on the
sailboat in the middle of Croatia, you
know, running around island hopping and
the captain of your boat is like, you
know, calling ahead to the restaurant.
So all the chefs come out to your table
and serve you. all you got to do is give
them a little bit of, you know, taste of
your work kind of thing. So, it's like
just like these rad opportunities and
like
friendships that like it really, you
know, and again, it's probably a cop out
of an answer, but like you know, like
been through the was the gateway into
it, right? Like cannabis was the
connecting tie for for that experience
to occur. And then I guess all right
just to wrap that up you sort of become
friends with you know I guess like I've
always seen lots of music you know I
think there was a good fiveyear run you
know when I was younger where I saw like
200 plus nights of live music a year
kind of thing. Wow. Um yeah, quite a you
know um um you know so made lots of
friends in the music industry and like
at this point sort of you know have one
friend that photographer so like I'll
trade him um you know some product and
he'll give me prints from the shows and
stuff like that but like you know sort
of I guess at this point sort of like
you get to sort of share your work with
the band you know that's playing at Red
Rocks you know so like you're getting
the band high that's got 10,000 people
in the crowd
getting high off this music and stuff
like that. So, like sort of goes back to
like I guess it's sort of a joke, but
I'm trying to be serious about and like
really want to put together this whole
team of like sponsored artists and
athletes, but like I'll sponsor any
artist. Like I'd give out herb to all
lots of local musicians and stuff like
that just because it's like I don't know
like go get the musician high that then
plays the music that makes all the
people happy, right? You know, kind of
thing or whatever. So, it's like I don't
know that sort of whatever. That's
probably the highlight for me. Like I
said, go [__] get the people high
that make the other people happy and
like sort of get to stand there in the
crowd with nobody knowing that you gave
the band all that weed that they smoked
and now they're playing for the whole
Red Rocks venue or whatever. Like that's
the highlight. Like that's the coolest
part. That's cool. Yeah, that's really
cool. I think that's a a perfect thing
to a perfect way to answer that question
and a great way to end the show. Um
Jared, thank you so much. I really
appreciate you taking the time to talk
and share your story. Yeah, it really
has been and I I um you know, I've made
so many friendships through doing this
podcast and Oh, there's my dog. Mine's
asleep on the cat.
But I've made so many friends doing this
podcast and um made like connections
that I feel like will definitely last a
long time or last a lifetime. And uh I
feel that with you here. So I really
appreciate your time and joining me
today. Um I well hopefully we get to go
do it in real life and go make some of
these memories soon, you know, kind of
thing. We'll have some good stories, but
I also, you know, very much appreciate
you inviting me on and getting to share
the story and kind of talk and all this
stuff. For sure. Well, like I like to
say, sharing these stories helps the
community grow and overall that's the
way we grow. So again, thank you and uh
we'll talk soon. Till next time. Thank
you.
[Music]