[Music]
hello and welcome to another episode of
The Way We Grow podcast a production of
The Craft Growers Network I'm your host
Nick wolf today our guest is Genevie
also known as Miss nudy grow on
Instagram uh Genevie how are you doing
today welcome to the show Hello thank
you for having me I'm excited to be here
I'm doing really well it's a beautiful
sunny day here in uh Eastern
Canada and the snow is
melting nice yeah I'm out in uh Western
us and Oregon and it is a a dreary
Oregon day out there so okay I'm jealous
of the sun actually but it's probably a
little colder it is a little colder but
we do get a bit more sun in the winter
time I think than you folks out there
just based on my experience in BC but oh
definitely yeah I mean if it's anything
like uh like Seattle then it's yeah
dreary and gray all the time yeah a fun
fun fact is when I turned 40 which was
uh almost seven years ago now my treat
to myself it was 2018 and California had
just become recreationally legal so I
went down there for 420 to San Francisco
with my jeep that I currently have now
rented pod through on the back drove up
to Victoria from Edmonton CU that's
where I was living and then down the
coast so Oregon became one of my
favorite places and I definitely want to
go back there because it was just like
driving down that um that Highway that
Coastal Highway through Oregon like man
gorgeous the driveth through Oregon is a
lot nicer in my opinion than the drive
through California on I think it's
Highway One or um I think it's sometimes
101 I'm yeah I get them confused but
that's why I didn't say it because I've
only been down it once I don't ask I've
lived here my whole life and I don't
know but it's um the the parts in
California can be kind of treacherous
along some of those
extremely like hairpin turn backs
through the like the the hilly mountain
side there it's it's like all sheer
Cliffs and stuff and I always get like a
almost like a panic attack driving
through there it's a that's a lot like
BC and you're right I it was a lot like
that like just uh we went through at
night to like those big
redwoods uh just like all of a sudden
you come up right up to one and you
could literally if you're not paying
attention go right into it which I'm
sure happens all the time but yeah yeah
all right so what's new in your grow
World um I know that uh for a while
there I I'm not sure if you're still
working with the same commercial
facility but um you kind of went went
from a home grower to a commercial
grower in somewhat rapid succession very
close to around the same time that I did
personally so it was really fascinating
to watch but um yeah what's new in your
grow world thank you uh for watching it
has it's been exciting um from what I
here to watch but also to experience so
um the quickest recap would be like pre
2018 I was a social worker working in
the city of Edmonton in Alberta which is
on the western side of Canada um kind of
hobby growing and like blasting into the
space um so much that I moved into
corporate Canabis so jumped around in
Alberta at a few spots and then was
transplanted out here for a really good
opportunity and did that thing for a few
years um it was like a crash course in
in corpor cannabis really like I was
managing B2B um sales uh not just
domestically but
internationally um I helped basically
mold and bring that team from we were
just little weaklings to like all the
way up into all the best provinces in
Canada as far as recreational so BC and
Ontario with a craft grower designation
um I chose that pheno that was winning
Awards around Canada um The Daily grape
and um pretty much made the cultivation
Department what it is that day da grave
awesome so so much so that we had other
partners so is managing other micro
cultivation sites across Canada so as
far as BC so Western to Eastern allies
and then throughout Atlantic Canada so
when I moved out here I got to travel
everywhere in Atlantic Canada so it's
been a really cool experience um I did
resign from that position at the end of
last year because it was really burnt
out and that
um I just needed to recognize that I'm
an older lady going to be 47 soon um and
so I know and recognize those those um
signs and symptoms and I pushed through
it for a good year um and honestly like
built out that cultivation and post
Harvest Department it was very
successful a Grower's success really is
like when you can't grow enough of the
product that the people want right like
that's a problem in it myself um but
that was the biggest problem so at that
point
I down to the young man that I was
mentoring and he does amazing and and
it's it's awesome so that's kind of what
I what I'd like to do continually is
just find another spot where I can learn
things for myself so I had do have a
specific list of things that I'd like to
experience in in at scale um and make a
little bit of money this time I haven't
done that yet I've been working strictly
for passion and honestly the
industries the best word I can use is
raped it out of me like my creativity
like you know like just a lot of things
where uh intellectual property just like
you really learn lessons as you come up
and in through any probably fast-paced
um Ever Changing industry with so many
transient people like the companies I
worked for don't even exist in Alberta
you know like so it's so and that was
only a few years ago so I mean it sounds
a lot like the restaurant industry yeah
a lot of people compare it to that for
sure I used to work um in hospitality
and restaurants in the city of Edmonton
which is a huge over million people city
um funny enough at Atlantic or east
coast bars and I'm I wasn't even from
the East Coast but now this this is me
um and yeah it is it's a lot like that
it's like money is the number one thing
and it's ever changing and over
regulated you know I was working in the
bar industry and serving industry when
the rules were still a little bit more
laxed and it was a little bit more fun
and there was culture to it and this and
that and then it started getting over
regulated and I dipped out and so coming
back into that corporate scene has been
a little bit trying at times but you
have to learn what you do is you learn
to work with that type of mindset and
those types of
people definitely yeah I um I was a chef
for like 10 years and worked on the west
coast and the east coast and it is uh I
feel like there's a lot of similarities
because there's a lot of passion within
the people that want to get into those
Industries um you know there's a lot of
like glamour as well uh in the
restaurant industry bar industry
exactly like industry events like you
probably know that would get put out Red
Carpet
Events yeah yeah you're right yeah it
they're they're very glamorous and um I
feel like a lot of people think that you
know by working hard or working with the
right people that they're going to be
the next you know sensation or uh um
have some sort of like big payout for
from from just being raked over the
coals consistently for years but usually
I mean for the masses that those
accolades sorry for cutting you off but
if you this some real steaming about it
if you work towards those accolades for
example and win Top grower 2023 in
Canada people don't give a [ __ ] in
Canada they're either telling you you're
paying to play which I didn't cuz I'm
poor as F and so was the
company or or you don't deserve it right
so it's like well what do I need to show
you to prove that I deserve this award
you know it's not based on just growing
good weed it's based on like leadership
and other skills right so right maybe I
don't know if it's just cuz I'm a female
but these accolades just get pushed
aside you know I've won awards for my
strains and my feno hunting you know
Canada wide and in New Brunswick and in
Alberta when it was Elite legal I was
winning homeg grow Awards but people
just don't care you know so I don't
usually mention them except on podcast
to validate myself for sure well I think
it is important to bring up what you
what you were saying there is you know
accolades there's like so much more to
it at this point now where you have to
be like marketing yourself and and doing
it in a very specific way to follow
whatever people are like in out of that
but that kind of reduces the you know
like the essence of why you're doing it
in the first place almost to like to
meet these demands of the the consumer
and the public and it's not necessarily
sustainable for like a mental state or a
you know even just like doing what you
want to do or doing it because you have
like the passion for it or something
like that it's it can be muddied very
quickly that way and I yeah it's it's
hard
to you know if you're chasing Awards and
stuff it doesn't sorry it's hard to stay
authentic that's what I'm hearing um
because there's no payoff for it you
know that's what the people say they
want and I've provided it but there
hasn't been much reward whether
it's the reward is likes or engagement
or
um pay money would be nice you know like
it just hasn't been rewarding so you
scale back on that naturally as a
Creator because you want to get paid or
you want some sort of win-win I think
most people probably and so it's
happening really fast too where it's
like almost and I don't want to be
Associated as an influencer either right
like that's a Dangerous Ground too with
all these different documentaries coming
about not even cannabis related but you
know um sure like I I don't want to
influence other people I I'm just trying
to portray or show um authentic
um life you know just like these are the
struggles of trying to get through this
corporate
world right and this is what we do at at
the job that I'm at wherever that job is
so before this job I was dancing in
rooms with plants in a vertical spec you
know like um it I'm looking for the I
guess the next place to go dancing and I
um do I've started to get some interest
so I have been looking at um outdoor
opportunities and so relocation will
probably be in my near future in the
next couple years I've turned down a
couple things already that just don't
align and when you've been in the
industry even though it's only been six
years it's a small
short um I guess what am I trying to say
it's not a small industry but it's a
it's a baby still it hasn't been around
that long so the industry is still
really young that's the word I'm looking
for um but a lot has happened right and
so I I guess I I want to make sure that
yes I'm jumping back into corporate
cannabis but I want to make sure that
it's going to be something that I can
also put some passion into as well right
for sure absolutely I mean if that's I
feel like everyone has their own sort of
drive for what they're Desiring in a in
a position if it's for um you know the
unfortunate capitalistic means that we
all are currently surviving off of um I
I think that if there's like part of it
where you know if if you love what you
do you won't work a day in your life is
what I've heard time and time again and
there is some truth to that but then
also you know like we've talked about
earlier there is a lot of potential for
people being taken advantage of if they
are are like highly passionate for a
position and will sometimes you know do
anything it takes to get into an
industry or a position because they feel
like they need to get their foot in the
doors so what you said there where
you're still you're turning down
positions because you want to make sure
it's the right fit a lot of people
should take note on that because that's
a very important thing to know your
worth as a grower yeah especially in an
industry that's going to take advantage
of you if the possibility if the
opportunity AR
and so guarding yourself against that is
extremely important oh absolutely there
what I'm noticing the shift and it's
good for me the shift that's happening
in in corporate canis cannabis is good
for me they're starting to look for
leaders and managers and head Growers
that actually know how to manage teams
right and so that's been probably my
biggest success is that I had a
background previous to this industry
where I was managing you know sometimes
hundreds of thousands of case loads of
people right so managing is is something
that I'm really good at and so before
though there's so many loudmouth you
know men and women but mostly men that
were like promising the world to people
been growing for 30 years like yada yada
classic you know and didn't follow
through and haven't follow through like
the last place I was at I was coming in
like the sixth person after five men
that just didn't want to get on the
floor with the plan
and 3 to four years later that's still
what CEOs are you coming to me for
seeing like Hey we're looking for that
manager that's wanting to get on the
floor with the plants and and manage the
people right like we that's what's wrong
with this industry I know you're an
American podcast but it might be similar
we we usually are following right behind
the trends there and the the culture in
in all these facilities is that it's
profit over people and so that's no
longer craft right as my mentor Kevin
JRE would say it's um Quality over
profit that's craft cannabis but um
that's what you're seeing and so people
if you go on indeed and see the reviews
for a lot of these places it's terrible
so they're taking note of that and they
need to switch that around so they need
more people and there's lots of leaders
like me and a lot of them are female
that know what to do have more empathy I
guess can work with the young people
it's like a very young industry but it's
young people that are in it right like
I'm going to be like I said 47 but I'm
more rare like there's I'm working with
19 to 30y olds generally so it's a
different
generation yeah I um I completely agree
with that it is it's really interesting
to see an an emerging industry that has
this Legacy market and uh groups of leg
Legacy Growers who um you know like to
use the term Master grower or um expert
Gardener or you know some of these terms
that kind of are there to almost inflate
the ego rather than to provide an
explanation of what their capabilities
are and we're seeing that a lot of those
people that are trying to
maintain standards in this industry as
the price continues to drop as labor
prices continue to go up as the overhead
cost and the the cost per Goods you know
all everything is going in the wrong
direction for profits to go up right and
so yeah to have people who care about
the plant as well as make wanting to be
there to make sure that the people that
are taking care of the plant are also
taken care of is extremely important
because most Industries fail if the if
they don't take care of the workforce
especially when there is so much labor
required within agriculture in general
right and it's agriculture that's right
there what you said some of these places
are 100 acres how is that not
agriculture right and even in even in
small like Boutique uh farms for you
know Farmers Market uh style um Farms
where they're small enough to keep
things uh you know maybe they do one
style of crop or they only do a small
amount per year that's still fairly
craft and when you look at cannabis as
comparable to the agricultural Market in
general then you start to see that these
um these differences in scale do end up
prioritizing difference uh they they
prioritize things differently where you
can be small and you can prioritize the
workers because that means that the
workers are going to prioritize the
quality of the product because they feel
like they're being taken care of and you
know there's this reciprocity there
where as if you're in a very large you
know 100 Acre or you know giant
Greenhouse facility or or some of these
massive you know multi Light Room indoor
facilities and you have these um these
teams of workers that are trying to
accomplish all these different tasks but
are constantly being marginalized
because the you know the overhead keeps
going up like I was saying the price per
pound keeps dropping and all of a sudden
everyone wants a raise each year right
and so it's really hard to keep up with
that and so sometimes I've seen a lot of
places have the policy of like either up
or out right like you either need to
continue to rise up and provide a better
um like a better worker for the company
or you should go find work elsewhere
because because we need to hire new
people that are cheap enough to maintain
the just the amount of bodies that need
to be thrown at a task yeah um you know
like de leafing or transplanting a lot
of these things are fairly simple to
understand and to get really good at but
you can't have someone doing that who is
making a whole lot of of money I mean
you you can but that's where I feel like
you have like Craft Farms versus is
these massive facilities there's there's
just a different requirement into labor
and having someone with your
understanding of how you know humans
work right where you're going in there
to make sure that they feel heard and
understood and cared for and then also
understanding how the plants work
sometimes you can have that sort of
like uh per it's almost like a a
parental nature it feels like where you
have to be like like guiding but firm
you still have to make sure that the
stuff gets done right but you have to
make sure that they understand that
listen I know like we're all tired today
but we got to get through this right and
then you know tomorrow we'll have a more
chill day and we can go over some more
fun practices and learn some new things
um yeah right it's a balance and not
everybody has the patience I think for
that kind of
balance
um and so that's fine that'll just bump
right that'll bump us right up to the
top we'll be floating right yeah I mean
it does remind me a lot of kitchens
that's the thing that if you if you have
a good reputation for doing certain
things then you're still going to be
relevant so like when I quit I've been
off for six 6 months and so when I left
I was like oh [ __ ] like I can't be off
for too long because I need to stay
relevant coming off of like a big win
and stuff
um so the last 6 months I have been
doing a lot of back to my roots homeg
growing so um still like having some
genetics that I've had for a long time
and just like really dialing them back
in and like maybe as you know you might
neglect your plants at home because
you're giving all your love and passion
to the plants at work and so um I
noticed that when I had the time off my
plants outside were just getting ready
to pop off was August the best the best
outdoor I've ever had was last year I
built a bunch of hugle bed boxes um I've
been doing that since I started you know
in the city I was growing in the city of
Edmonton when it was legal in the
backyard so just not that long really
since
2016 um but each year outdoor growing is
like fabulous out east fabulous out east
compared to sort of where it was before
so that was awesome but um even the tent
growing right like um I popped a few new
seeds and I have been trying to grow
sacred tobacco for offerings uh the last
6 months my partner in crime Katrina
Jackson we sort of developed a
Consulting business like we're not
incorporated or anything yet but um you
know it's hard to kind of delve into
Consulting and I I don't feel honestly
ready for it either like I have more
experience gain and I'm ready to go get
that you know a few more years out in
the field but in the
meantime um Katrina's got a whole side
that complements my cultivation skills
and experience so she's doing um product
development and some of the products
she's developed for the Canadian Market
have and are still top selling products
uh topicals 2.0 products stuff like that
so um we were working in some indigenous
communities out here in New Brunswick
trying
to um I guess get some Workforce going
on out in those communities so bringing
the youth back onto the reserves by
offering them like a cool place to work
like a weed facility right so um based
on the fact that there is some funding
money out there for indigenous
communities and things like harm
prevention or like what I just said
bringing the youth back um and so we
thought wouldn't it be a cool idea to um
help the community build their own
production facility so they can
manufacture their own sacred products um
for Sovereign ground or jump into the
legal industry really like um you know
this it's two separate ones out here so
it's awesome yeah so that that would be
something that I'd love to keep doing
unfortunately it's like relying on
government grants and funding and that's
just so um
not stable so right it's it's fairly
sporadic and when when the money does
come it's you almost have to be there at
the the front of the line snapping it up
as quick as you can exactly we uh we did
get lucky enough to sort of collaborate
with the doctor Dr Shelley Turner who's
like an addiction specialist physician
out here in Canada she's been working
with um people trying to get or has
successfully gotten people off opiate um
therapies like Toxin and and things like
that to cannabis treatment so can
cannaboid therapy so we're we're still
going to work on that and try to pursue
that and that's why I'm bringing that up
um but at the same time you know it's
time to get back to work and get a real
job and like put that stuff to the side
for
now for sure well I I feel like we've
had a a really nice um sort of like
catch up to where uh you are right now
in terms of what you're looking to do
next and make some moves but um I do
like to find out sort of where the
passion started and where the interest
in Plants started and so um like all the
way back what were some of the first
experiences with plants that you had
whether it be cannabis or otherwise and
then if uh if it was Cannabis that was
kind of your first um interest in Plants
then how did that potentially evolve
into vegetable gardening or otherwise or
if it was perhaps some like vegetable
gardening with Mom and Dad or grandma or
Grandpa and then if it went from there
um into cannabis let's hear the story
ooh yeah you nailed it it was my grandpa
so my
grandpa uh we used to spend like parts
of the summer with him and he had always
had this big Garden in the backyard and
so we were always uh my sister and I
were always helping him back there so
just like early on really had a good
connection with with plants and um just
like a basic
understanding my dad was an avid
Gardener also growing up and um but I
was kind of too cool for gardening like
my dad was always trying to get me into
it but it was just like [ __ ] Garden's a
lot of work like it's weeding and you
know I wasn't grasping the connection
piece or you know anything like that um
and so I I really just like didn't do
anything until I I owned my own home in
Edmonton I did the domestic thing for a
long time and so when I I own my own
home I was like I should have a garden
cuz that's just what people do like so
um I called it like hate gardening at
first because it was hard it was way
harder than I expected it to be um so I
actually had to like learn about the
vegetables that I was planting and learn
about what they shouldn't be next to and
you know just things like that and uh
once I started learning more about each
thing I really started getting into
trees and I had just had a lot of fruit
trees in my backyard for being in a city
so I was learning about pruning and um
probably did like 10 years of just sort
of practicing in the back and like every
year I'd grow new flowers cuz flowers
are hard to grow I don't know if
anyone's tried to grow like you know
flowers that you just get in the in the
uh Greenhouse place just like you grow
vegetables flowers longer to germinate
like I mean it depends but they can be
tougher
um and so I just looked at weed as
another flower it was just another
chemically um complicated flower but it
was still a flower um and I hadn't
really just decided to grow weed the
reason I started to grow weed was
because um I started to need it in
abundance I got really sick um um back
in like 2015 2016 and it ended up being
a kidus and like just some ulcer stuff
and I lost a lot of weight and I was
going through a lot at the time um I had
been sober from drugs and alcohol for
four years at that time 3 four years
like abstaining from everything I went
to treatment for cocaine and booze and
um my buddies were telling me to like
yeah smoke cannabis you know it's going
to help you with your stomach and I was
just like no like back then like even
2016 I mention it to the my sponsor or
whatever and they're like whoa like no
way like that's crazy I had a
psychiatrist at the time because like I
was really well wrapped in treatment and
you know maintaining and doing really
well cuz it's hard to stay sober I'm
sure people know addictions everywhere
um but my psychiatrist who is really
helping me along with like uh I also
have ADD ADHD um so I was like you know
en enjoying to keep going with her but
she cut me right off when I um admitted
to admitted to um using cannabis to
treat my stomach problems but the thing
is is that the doctor the gastro people
were trying to give me like
um chemo meds and things like that and
things that I was more scared of getting
addicted to I guess and like they just
make you really Dopey and out of it um
so I was still just abstaining and then
I I believe it was Christmas time or I
know it was Christmas time and uh I was
just desperate and my buddy was like
here smoke this like enough's enough so
I did and um it changed my life forever
um that night even I felt a little bit
of hunger like appetite like to not have
an appetite and be chronically nauseous
for a year is I was suicidal like it was
terrible it was terrible so um
that was the start of when I started to
heal my body so I went into the system
um to try and get a legal
prescription um and that was really hard
to navigate as somebody who didn't
wasn't Legacy or didn't know anything
like I had a drug dealer of course but
it was like a nice guy that I trusted in
the social work Biz you know I did it on
the side sure I didn't know any like
black market people
um so
I did eventually get my 2 GS a day or
something like that and I remember
taking almost a year to convince this
freaking Doctor to let me grow my own
because it was costing so much money and
it was like yeah 2016 2017 at the time
um so it was pre- legalization here in
Canada but there's still a long medical
history here since the 9s and so I was
just trying to navigate sort of the end
of that and it was difficult at the time
I didn't know that the Cannabis Clinic
that I was attached to that I was
referred to from my doctor was actually
owned by
Aurora like as a consumer you don't know
that these clinics are owned by these
big huge corporations and so then
they're put they're pushing you in that
way to you can only buy these products
so at the time you have to get a
prescription for one one licensed
producer so you'd kind of go through the
roles of that So eventually I navigated
that system for about a year and um it
was so expensive like $700 a month just
just to to get what I needed and at the
time I was infusing so fun fact is I
started educating the community on
YouTube
in maybe 2017 18 I'd have to look back
it's a long time they're embarrassing so
I barely go there but uh um infusing
that was my thing trial and error back
in 2016 which is only eight and a bit
years ago you couldn't get any
information from anybody's grandma or
anybody about how to get weed butter you
had to figure it out yourself or know
somebody that knew what they were doing
so I did the whole butter with water
with like oh I went through so many
gross things that I made my friends eat
cuz it would get you high but it tasted
really bad or didn't get you high like
so that was sort of my Jam then and so I
was going through a lot of weed infusing
um I started like dwelling into the
unregulated market a little bit selling
my Edibles and my infusions cuz I did
eventually get really good at it and um
kind of dwelled into cvd because at the
time my dog um had been diagnosed with
epilepsy a really severe type of
epilepsy cluster cures and um someone
had recommend CBD CBD was so expensive
plus you didn't even know what you were
buying back then um unregulated and so I
decided to grow it so um the very first
CBD that I ever grew was called Candida
um it was popular at the time it's a
very good uh CBD the highest CBD on it
was something like 190% and it was
considered a hemp variety because the
THC was under.
3% um I actually won an award with that
candida it was the highest CBD in the
homeg grower competition that I was
enrolled in at the time through Hempfest
but CBD is something that I still
continue to keep um I'm doing a
deadlights now which is subcool it's a
really awesome um strain of CBD as well
it's the closest thing I found since I
had the candida that I had that I lost a
long time ago but um yeah just uh I
guess just really getting
into pop popping off is the word I use
for for educating so whether that was
teaching people how to infuse I just
really want to give back I guess uh I
wanted to help what I found hard to find
for myself so um some of those videos
got you know some pretty good traction
at first I couldn't monetize on anything
now because like it's way it's like 10K
that's nothing now but also because I
was smoking weed so they're all age
restricted and
like it's just old news the old days
right yep I mean we still will even put
like that our content that we make isn't
isn't made for kids because there's so
many different laws and you know
depending on if it's Canada where you
have to be 18 or the US where you have
to be 21 and there's you know there's
still a huge stigma so we just try to
protect ourselves as best we can um so
yeah that makes sense yeah yeah you you
brought up a lot of memories with uh
making Canabis butter and stuff I uh oh
yeah me and my partner would always make
it using a crock pot water and butter
and and the you know all the extra trim
or um we we use like a vaporizer so like
all the preved weed just goes right into
it yeah yep oh gosh like I have not
found one way that someone's mentioned
that I haven't tried to either decarb or
Infuse like I've done milk I've done
honey I've done like ke like I can put
ke in anything like and then it's good
it's good recipes because it wasn't
anything that I was told by that magic
butter machine or anything like that
just using them as an example they're a
great machine but um by trial and air so
just knowing and feeling what works best
for me really like I still have
unregulated clients that want my CBD oil
and my gummies because they are most
effective for them just based on
probably the way I Infuse it who
knows yeah I mean we I we make fudge
with the butter because you can just
stick fudge in the fridge and it lasts
forever and uh a good idea you know like
we're having like little tiny pieces
like
quarter quarter of an inch yeah uh
they're just so small and cuz it's it's
so potent but I don't you can't really
find that on the market everywhere has
like regulations on the
THC um like the gr of THC or the
milligrams of THC that can be in the
edible and it's like well you're making
me eat a whole bunch more sugar than I
want to to get the same results and
because of my colitis I have a sugar cap
like literally will send me into a
puking fit if I go above say like 18 gam
in one serving which is not hard to hit
cuz a pop has like 50 I could never have
a pop or I'd start vomiting so those
those Edibles are not for me like I
couldn't even have them the other thing
I don't like is a lot of regulated and
unregulated Edibles on the market are
distillate so I'm not a super big fan of
distillate it gives me a headache I
don't I like a full flower effect um so
it's harder to find so my stuff is
always just like it's the guts it's
everything you know for sure and also I
I like will always make the butter now
with stuff that's like been sitting for
a year or to so it's always you know
fully oxidized like extremely old
cannaboids that have mostly converted
into whatever their final form is going
to be already so I'll I'll decarb it
maybe a little bit but sometimes I just
will let the crockpot go for like 24
hours and I'm like yeah that's that's
enough heat to decarb it all the way
yeah for sure that's that's the kind of
that's how I make my death
brownies yes that I mean that's why F
such a small amount yeah it's not what I
want but it's happened before because
yeah that exactly the old stuff that's
been sitting there you don't even really
need to decarb it cuz it's already
oxidized and degraded into CBN and then
yeah it just hits you so good yep a
funny story like uh maybe like 10 or 15
years ago I I had done just that you
know used a bunch of old weed and made
butter and then I made um rainbow Rice
Krispie treats with it
and I cut the squares into what I would
think people would want to eat for a
Rice Krispy treat not thinking about how
much THC and uh cannaboid were going to
be in there and I gave my dad one and he
ate it and got so high that he like
passed out on the couch and then crawled
to the bathroom because he had to throw
up it was just so intense of a of a high
and ever since then I've been like
extremely careful with my portioning cuz
I think that was when I was like you
know 17 or 18 and I was just like no you
can take it man just just eat the whole
thing you'll be fine I had one earlier I
I feel great yeah I know I know I've
death sentenced My Friends by accident
before yep oh that's funny though um so
with uh with some of your earlier grows
when you were just doing the homow thing
what were some of the methods that you
use what sort of style of growing were
you doing um I like to dabble a lot my
main style would be quar and um sort of
any any of those pre-made bottles so
I've used Advanced
Nutrients um that's what I started with
there was Emerald
Harvest um just like all the fancy stuff
and then um I started buying just like
General hydroponic because I wanted to
learn like um at the time I was a big
fan and still am I don't follow much but
uh Dr Coco so I learned earned like by
watching his tutorials like even if you
go back into some of my old tutorials
they're like I love Dr cooko like how
embarrassing like shout out um I ended
up on a podcast with with all those guys
which is like something cool that you
know um I used to be on growing with my
fellow Growers I I was with the guys at
the beginning for a year I was with the
Shane and the guys so that's where I
think I first encountered you um was
with the growing with my fellow Growers
podcast cuz that was one of the those
are
my yeah you know it was one of those
podcasts that um I feel like I my
podcast also kind of Falls within the
same category of trying to be
educational where we're trying to like
not only allow people to tell stories
but to get information out there that
they feel would benefit the community uh
of both Growers and consumers alike
right yeah um and they were definitely
some of the the earlier uh shows that
you could listen to and really pick up a
lot of great information
that you could then apply to your own um
either homeg growing situation or if you
were taking notes of all these different
things that you were learning and you
could cross reference it based on you
know this panel of people that were
providing their insight into like
specific topics you know I think one of
the first ones I ever listened to was
their indoor versus outdoor um grow talk
which to me was just such great
information to help um teach any new
grower about like life light cycles and
um substrate needs and requirements and
electrical needs and requirements and uh
if you are trying to remain um on the
cheap homow side of things then how you
can accomplish that without needing to
invest all this money into tents and
lights and nutrients and all the
expensive gizmos and gadgets right like
it was it was refreshing to hear that
cuz so many other places were like you
have to buy
air conditioner and you need to seal
your room and get Co2 yeah with all tape
and [ __ ] yeah and yeah to this day like
giant zip ties to hold up my fans in
there like things are ghetto at to make
it as cheap as possible but I learned so
much from those guys and I continue to
learn from those guys like they are some
of the top OG's like still [ __ ]
committed
and every single week you know like holy
no matter what's going on in their lives
like especially shout out to like Jack
and um Russ and like the ones that are
there like every single week like wow
good J they both done an episode with me
and uh I've also sung their praise
because they um they've taught a lot of
people community yep I wish I could do
that for a living and make money like
that's what that's the dream right like
that's what I came out hopping to do was
like I have posts on LinkedIn that are
like [ __ ] government weed like let's hom
grow together and I'll teach you how
right but nobody wants to pay me so it's
like I got to go back into into the old
money bags but it's what the dream would
be right the passion is is aligned with
the hom grower that is the heart of
cannabis I will always say that so it's
such a battle for me ethically to work
at scale and Export and live behind
these regulations and stand behind these
companies and know that that's not the
heart of
cannabis right cuz the companies aren't
smoking the the weed none of them nope
none of them tell you they are they're
not smoking weed you go you get that guy
in a room and you smoke him under the
table that's what you do they'll never
let you put you doing that they're
drinking alcohol and snort and cocaine
it's very similar all over I'm sure
yep I'm I'm lucky to be in a in a
position with the company that I'm at
where we are um you know I'm proud to uh
consume the Cannabis that we produce
because it is it's small it's a little
four room facility 12 lights per room
couple of large veg spaces cuz we also
do two acres of outdoor where we take a
lot of good care on our outdoor plants
and um use non-toxic and um you know
regulated it uh Reg ulation approved
sprays for Pest and pathogen prevention
and then we turn it all into fresh
frozen it all gets processed so it's
nice and clean and it's some of the like
the better DS and stuff on the market
that I like to do that actually that's
like you're leading me into the outdoor
I have interviewed for a couple places
that basically grow biomass in a good
way for inputs or um to make uh yeah
inputs yeah and we use a lot of General
agricultural practices um because we do
row cropping basically and it's it's
very satisfying to be able to accomplish
so much with such a small team because
sometimes I feel like the outdoor places
they think I need to just get a bunch of
Labor to throw at this cuz I'm going to
dry it all and trim it all up and sell
this flower and I'm that's just not
necessarily the move for outdoor
cannabis right now um it I feel like
concentrates and uh EXT TR s are the way
to go I agree same with out here too
there's outdoor Greenhouse there's the
green belt going on in Ontario there's
some really good climates to grow even
here in New Bruns look like I said if I
had the money to get something started
on this land there's 60 Acres here I
could grow
um
but it's tough um so with your um it so
it sounds like you've mostly done
salt-based uh growing to I it's totally
fine Simply Organic or like solely
organic basically the last like three
and a half years so indoor and outdoor
always outdoor has been organic um I've
always been interested in learning about
soil I mean I hang around with the guys
that have taught me how to build my own
soil um like I've always been interested
in it but I never understood it like as
a salt grower I was always trying to
control everything and add everything up
by math and so itd be like you know like
I just didn't understand how the plant
was just picking up the nutrients when
it wanted you know like or when it
needed you just had to keep the you know
the plant happy in the root Zone and how
simple it is to do organic and so I just
really started diving into that more
indoor um as I was able to at the
facility that I was at plus doing it at
home on a smaller scale in my tent so
seeing the variation too some of the
same genetics even um between salt
indoor facility grown with like some of
the best equipment and then also just in
my tent right you can see like different
variations but so organic is new um it's
where I align
now as far as the best quality cannabis
is organic living soil grown cannabis in
my opinion based on doing my own
experimenting with the same genetics in
Organics in salts using different
fertilizers even organic
synthetic fertilizers okay so there's
those too um the best quality in my
opinion is always going to be the living
C and even more so like the hu culture
stuff that I grow outside as long as
it's a genetic that's for outside
because it's been bred outside so
something from California or even the
East Coast over here that is going to be
the best
cannabis for sure I've heard a lot of
people um sort of say the same thing
and but I you know I I always like to
ask though when was the last time that
you took uh you know the same care for a
small number of plants and grew them
with salts at home cuz it sounds like
you've been doing Organics for like 3
years now I was going to just say well
right now so I switched back to salts uh
at the end of this outdoor season I
decided I I was unpracticed and so I
wanted to get back into it so it's
harder to find the inputs that I need
just living rly where I live and so
that's kind of been that I'll just you
know make my own [ __ ] here cuz I can get
it here but so um I I've always used can
of Coco so I just stuck with my can of
cocoa and then um I'm using like a local
fertilizer company called rise nutrients
and it's working really good but um just
like what I'm trying to say is that
these part A and Part B nutrient
companies like I I'm using rise
nutrients right now and it's working
really well
um previous to that I was using Remo
nutrients and they work really well with
the same can of cocoa I don't
necessarily see different results I find
them to be all very similar and I like
ease of use so right that's going to
always usually be my go-to I like rise
because it's local and I can get it here
Remo I can also get here but you know
there's a chance it could it you know
the shipment could not make it I could
drive to the rise guys house probably be
like hook me up you know yeah um so
that's I'm kind of want to choose
local yeah I can agree with that I um
I've been a huge fan of uh Jr crop Tech
okay uh for salt-based nutrients but I
don't believe that they're available in
Canada yet or they might have just
recently um but it they have like one
bag for flour one bag for veg and you
can you know either use the salts um
directly into your Reservoir and mix
them up or you can make a stock solution
and dose them in um and they they don't
sell their own calcium nitrate which is
really nice because brand name calcium
nitrate when it's under a hydroponic
nutrients label is always more expensive
but you can get really highgrade calcium
nitrate for extremely cheap so they they
like promote that you do that which is
really nice because it really reduces
the overall cost per gallon mixed even
at high strengths like um at the
facility that I uh help manage right now
we're running between 4.0 and 4.5 EC
input which is you know it's it's really
high and a lot of people get like whoa
that's crazy and it's like well yeah but
we have really high ppfd CO2 yeah sorry
I've worked at a place that also ran
really high like that or like where it
doesn't read it's like five plus or
something like
oh my gosh that's crazy um yeah I mean
we we try to keep it within there and
then by using substrate monitoring we
can detect that you know that the poor
water EC is staying right around there
which is really ideal for like a bulking
phase and then you can raise it up
really quickly for um a fin like a a
ripening phase or a stretching phase you
can get those generative and vegetative
cues and uh you can kind of turn on a
dime a lot quicker with that high EC
yeah because it's easier to reduce and
uh increase based on your substrate
management but I've seen people also
Crash and Burn really quickly when they
don't have the correct monitoring um uh
like the different like substrate meters
and whatnot to be able to tell when
their plants are getting out of a safe
range yeah that's what worries me right
away in big facilities is just like they
don't prepare as well for the dry out I
guess like especially in Rockell and
then you're using High EC like
that yeah I I always suggest Coco cuz
Rock will yeah if you get too dry then
you're never going to really recover
from that I've seen some things in some
big facilities uh out out west or
whatever I worked in a 500,000 ft
facility so just pods upon pods upon
pods just weed fields of weed inside and
walking into a room where the staff the
day before forgot to like switch the
irrigation to on after transplant or
whatever and like the whole one side of
the crop is just like laying on the
ground basically but I've also seen it
where they've quickly like burst the the
juice in and it come back in two hours
and they're like they're okay but
they're like you know they're it's like
amazing how resilient these plants are
when you think a plant's dead some of
watching some of those like what not
toos has been like very beneficial and
helpful for me to like be like okay so
that's the extreme of that definitely
yeah I feel like you learn a lot from
the different failures that you witness
and uh sometimes the successes go under
the radar because things are just
working as they should so you didn't
necessarily catch that that one thing
you did really helped set it off right
yeah
um so uh throughout your Growing
Experience both um indoors at you know
with your your home grow outdoors with
your home grow at the different
facilities that you've helped uh run
manage and work at what were some of the
successes that you found in your growing
experiences there that helped you learn
something and then on the flip side of
that coin what are some of the failures
that you witnessed that help you learn
something kind of within the same vein
of thought that we were just talking
about okay so
um probably one of the most like kept me
up at night but was the most exciting
and best learning experience was at the
last facility I was at I came there to
basically develop the the
um cultivation department and so first
thing we started with was a pheno hunt
and the reason I came out here part of
it was that that genetic library that he
had and so most of the genetics and I'm
just choosing not to say the names of
places that I
work um so the genetics people can
figure it out the genetics that were at
there 20,000
seeds 500 different
strains um and literal cuts too that
were shipped over here like somehow some
way all from Kevin jodrey California
like huge genetic seed banks like just
stuff that I was like holy [ __ ] like
this guy doesn't even know what he has
you know he probably does cuz he got
most of them he went on a big thing
anyways um so it's that was like 300
over 300 seeds it was a small feno hunt
when you talk about like what people do
out at scale or whatever but like you
know 30 seeds
each 14 different
strains um all researched by me and my
team
picked out of 500 which is really hard
when you have like it's an overwhelming
amount of like research and okay guys
like we're just at the table like what's
on this one what's on this one like you
got to figure out what your CEO wants
right so it's like not what I want but
what he wants so he gives me this like I
want fruits give me all the fruits right
so that that's the first hunt so we're
getting apples we're getting bananas
we're getting grapes but you want
there's all these different strains of
all those different fruits so it was you
know trying to narrow it
down and so just from the very day one I
was
never that was my first big task where I
was responsible for that much genetic
material like it kept me up at night
like what if these seeds don't pop like
I I've always been really good at it you
know but I've never been able to do this
cuz facilities out here aren't popping
seeds like you're just going in you're
working you're doing your 9 to5 and
you're out right like so it was like
unbelievably that he was trusting me
with this but um we did it we had a 98%
success rate so that was
exhilarating exhilarating cuz these
seeds were all different ages like I
didn't know some of them we didn't even
have history on they were just like sure
Ken J's Bank you know like
cool um so yeah that that whole process
um from
eliminating like so we we
like it was over 300 seeds that survived
all these little seedlings I still have
pictures it's the coolest thing to go in
every day and be like you know they're
all still alive and then you know
getting them past that first transplant
and then you start setting them in for
DNA right that all that whole process is
so cool so that was very successful that
whole year just amazing and ended up
getting um really like 20 solid genetics
to add to his library and only they've
used one really and that was the top one
just for what was trending at that time
and that was the grape because it right
we picked that I picked that because all
through the grow it was the only one
that smelted like real grape so I knew
it wasn't turfing and I knew it was
different and then when it dried it
smelt like grape candy and then when you
smoked it you got so high it was high
THC so it was like a really it was easy
to grow low Leaf like it was just
obviously a good choice and so that was
probably my biggest success so that that
one Awards um there was the very first
legal Cannabis Cup at 1/3 so for me
that's a success I don't need to win
first every time and then also in New
Brunswick um it
was runner up for top sativa I think
last year or the year before they do a
babis cup out here and so that was
really cool just that genetic um first
like a first time gal just you know no
30 years of genetic hunting or growing
hair but you know having obviously Kevin
at the time to help out here and there
he's a busy guy so whenever I really
truly needed it um but that was probably
the biggest success so the biggest
failure before you get into the biggest
failure um I I love the conversation of
pheno hunting because I feel like it's
one of those things that are um it's
like one of the last real sort of like
passionate um things that people can get
into with cannabis is like breeding and
pheno hunting because you can have such
unique tastes that are very subjective
to yourself and if you're kind of
following
that you know call it passion or call it
whatever you want of I like this so I'm
going to follow it to try and find the
best iteration that I like um so many
times you can find something that is
just exceptional um but a lot of people
will do pheno hunting in different ways
and so I was curious what were some of
the practices during your pheno hunt
that you took that um other people might
be able to learn from for sure I love
talking about feto hunting and I don't
pretend to be a master or an expert at
it I most of my experience literally
comes from my own homeg growing outdoor
indoor um and then that that experience
as well and just all the different
genetics that I've grown in the last six
years to scale right so there's
something to that but basically the the
thing that is the most simple that made
me understand it the most especially
when you're doing it for someone else
right so you kind of have to be good at
it and like yeah I'm going to use my
intuition and what I like as a very a
daily smoker right that's in this
like I am a consumer too um but I'm am
like a I'm an elite
different like small make no like I
don't buy weed from I'm not the consumer
that they're after so you have to like
um figure out what your project is first
so this advice comes from Kevin so who
is like a world renowned Breer breeder
teacher feno Hunter Mentor he says that
simple as like you feno hunt based on
whatever your goal is so you make a goal
so whether that's your goal so that
that's going to be for I'm going to uh
be feno hunting for a medical strain for
a effect or I'm going to be feno hunting
because I want it to look visually great
or I'm going to be feno hunting because
I want it to be 30% THC I'm feno hunting
because I want all those things you know
and I want it to smell like a fruit my
boss so um yeah so it almost became
easier at that time I figured out my own
rating charts just based on um um the
directive that I was getting from
different mentors so like all my mentors
I was like asking and pulling
information uh the guys I was just
speaking of um they let me stay in the
group chat so even though I'm not on
there every week with them I can still
read and learn what they're popping in
there or I've gone in there with
questions stuff like that so based on
all that knowledge and just like my own
research I created uh rating sheets
which I find is really help to to write
things down as homeg Growers we don't do
it enough I think or people just maybe
don't think of it as as important as it
is and for me I always started with like
journaling and writing it all down
because I was working on a forum so I
was posting this stuff and then
eventually it turned into notebooks that
were just like records of what I did so
basically keeping records however that
looks for me it was a checklist like who
doesn't love a check like a checkboard
where you're checklist is
looking authoritative to the plants like
hello yeah I'm the boss like I got the I
got the clipboard today um but like
based on what you're looking for right
so visually you're looking through them
all the way from seedling development to
to flow which is the most important
obviously but you're looking for Vigor
so in Ved you're looking for Vigor
that's the main thing that you're
looking for and you can you can see that
by how fast the plant's growing how how
dry it's getting more quickly how much
more you have to upot it like that's
bigger when a plant's just like let's
get going like I'm going to grow into a
tree that's a good plant right there so
but you don't know if you have a male or
female maybe so um it depends on what
your project is again right so maybe you
are looking for a male cuz people are
pheno hunting males I've done that here
I have Royal cush pollen because I did a
male pheno hunt so um probably the
biggest thing for people that they can
take home and use is record keeping and
then following that along and not doing
too much so you want to keep your plants
as healthy as possible um you don't want
to be Survivor hunting not in the first
run you want you want to be looking for
for fabulous and you can't look for
fabulous when they're on death's door
right or if you're like oh yeah I'm
going to starve these things like no not
on the first run not on the first you
know so I always tell people they need
to create a baseline that they need to
follow in all of their practices when
pheno hunting and they can't baby any of
the plants they can't treat any of them
special they have to just perform on
their own and you have to choose them
from that performance document it yep
and document it and then you know one
thing that I always like to ask because
I have my own very specific practices
for this but what do you like to flower
out in a feno hunt do you like to flower
out the seed plant like the plant that
was produced from the seedling or or do
you like to clone it and flower out the
Clone
both so again for me it would depend on
what I'm looking for if you're wanting
something that is going to perform well
in a facility then you can clone and see
how it's going to go um and then just
keep repeating it basically but I'd say
if you're looking for a unicorn and
you're you're able to
really follow that seed right through
the flower that's
your
mother like your first
mother sure so are you um when you do
that when you flower out a seed plant
are you usually taking cuting and saving
the cuting as your mothers yeah so
that's the first mother that you're
flowering out I guess and then her
babies are waiting in L to either be
called or move on to the next um flower
so you're getting to see I guess it's
valuable so what I'm saying is it's
valuable to see that seed product turn
into a flower um in my experience that
seed plant is a stronger that's the most
vigorous the plant will be that's just
how I've seen it it just like the stocks
are huge like it's just like it's an
amazing thing to see so I think if
anyone can do it uh most facilities
can't because they're it's a schedule
you have you know four or five rooms
then one one of them is probably for
moms and veg and so you're on a tight
schedule and so a lot of times you're
not even you're not going to be able to
see any of those seed mom seed seed
plants become the flower goddesses that
they deserve to be for sure I um it's
it's for that exact reason that I always
suggest people uh flower out clones
because sometimes when you have a seed
plant right and you grow it out and it's
super healthy super vigorous and you you
flower it out and you get this awesome
expression and structure and you saved
the clone of it and then you go back and
you flower that clone out you might be
disappointed yeah sometimes the the
Vigor changes sometimes the flower
morphology especially will change and
I've noticed sometimes that the tpine
profile will change from a seed plant to
mother and it it could just be due
to you know whether it be the tap rot or
um the the overall root structure and
vigor of the plant y yeah but I I see
the value it especially for hom Growers
because it might be the best iteration
and if they just are going to be popping
seeds every run then why not but
definitely in like a commercial setting
it it almost makes more sense to flower
out the Clone because yeah you want to
make sure that's what you're act right
right that's that's what your successive
or yeah successive crops are going to be
um how they're going to be best
represented is is from the Clones yeah
um if if your goal is a factory setting
and and sometimes even a small place is
like you know everything is a certain
way that's still sort of mini factory
setting I don't know what else to call
it but you got to make sure that they're
going to perform like their sisters like
it's all going to be very um
homogenized definitely and it it's
almost like for for people that are
growing for medicine too it's one of the
reasons why I never suggest autof
flowers for people that are growing
specifically for medicine because if
they find an Autoflower that produces
this awesome cannaboid and turine
profile and they say oh this is the best
medicine I've had well here's some tough
news my friend it's going to be
extremely hard to find that again
because you can't clone the autoflow and
unless you're working with a really
refined company like misto genetics or
something you're not going to be able to
necessarily find the same phenotype
within that same pack of seeds or even
in 10 different pack of the same seeds
and so that's where I always am telling
people you know like run your clone
because if that's the Unicorn for you
then you know that you have it and that
you can reproduce it yeah it's a faster
way to get to that goal too like that's
what I'm hearing from you and that's why
they do it like that in in regulated
cannabis or in facilities is because
exactly you want to make sure that it's
going to perform and if you're using
your your like I have the same we I have
some new stuff but I have the same stuff
that I know works for me for the last
few years in there just keep doing its
thing
for you know
and the point of getting that
is the uniformity is what you want like
the consistent medicine exactly what
you're saying so even as a homeg grer if
you're medically minded you might want
you know this is my strain for daytime
and this is my strain for night time and
these are the two I like to mix together
and this is the one I make for oil so
right yes absolutely and um yeah there's
there's so many different avenues that
we could go into in terms of maintaining
that genetic stock right where people
need to uh keep the Mothers Healthy keep
them happy um they need to you know if
if they are keeping moms around for a
long time they need to know the risks
that they're um possibly going to have
have to face through that through you
know different pressures building up
within the plants whether it be viral or
uh fungal or um pathogenic uh pests you
know all these different things that
keeping a plant around for a long time
which was a very common practice in the
traditional Market Days of I need to
keep this mom around because she's the
one that produces the Clones that I like
to run versus successful successively
cloning them at a regular uh interval to
make sure that you have fresh vigorous
genetic material to make your production
clones from and you know this is super
Rel relevant for hom Growers who are
growing for medicine as well as then you
know anybody that's wanting to take
those practices like you took your
practices like I took my practices and
translate that into a commercial space
learning some of these things is
extremely crucial and um I've seen some
definite like uh missteps where people
will try to enter into the commercial
space and take their you know I baby
this one or two plants and make them my
everything for this 3 or 4 months that
I'm growing them and then go into a
facility and get really disappointed by
the fact that they can't baby every
single plant because they're responsible
for
hundreds I know it's a real shock as a
person that's been
there it it was a huge shock for me as
well I just uh even the first yeah even
the first facility I worked at
everything was handw watered and uh and
I was like oh this is nice you get to
spend time with with each plant and then
I look back and I'm like how how did we
even afford that sort of labor for the
amount of product we were producing it's
ridiculous irrigation has been the one
thing that's trended in all my positions
like I was an irrigation lead actually
at this one
spot who I was hired on to help get the
automation going it was a vertical
grow
um and we were hand watering okay so I
trying to remember how many plants are
in there three tiers dude three tiers uh
so we were using a um zoom
boom to water the plants with buckets
and ladders and there was one time where
I was in the mother room and I swear to
God I wish I had this footage but I was
on this rickety old ladder with my 5
gallon bucket dragging it up to the
second level they didn't even have a
hose and a
pump not that no no because of the weird
concoctions of things that were going on
I won't even get into that but up on a
big
ladder with my uh lab Beaker plastic
Beaker like watering these three gallon
375 milliliters in each one five times
yes no human there I'm sure right and
then you got to go log it all but
anyways that's not even my story I fell
off the ladder everything went down and
I was like hanging from the second
year we handw watered like 900 plant
rooms like three tier 900 plant rooms
like that for six months every day and I
wonder that's brutal how did I do that
yeah yeah that was crazy it just made me
think of it I must have blocked it out
but it's like a fun experience when I
think of actually like setting up the
automation we were using nlex and it was
my first time it was during Co and so
they got the nlex machine into the
facility but because of Co they couldn't
send out uh it was because it's from
Texas so there was nobody coming over
from America at that time so they
couldn't bring out any textt to like
train the staff on it and that had all
sort of happened before I got hired so
we got hired and they're like here's
this kid he'll teach you stuff and then
set this up you know so there was lots
of experiences where you send the water
out and it goes up and you're like oh my
God I hope that went into the right room
and then you're running down the hallway
to the facility and people are yelling
cuz it's like oh my God the water's
paring into the storage and there's star
like it was like so many crazy
irrigation experiences uh that's crazy
floods floods floods like 500 like how
these were 2,000 gallon tanks for
R and we how does it how is it not
automated to shut off when it hits the
top you know like
you later and go back and be like [ __ ]
and the whole place would be like so
flooded that's crazy boys did that with
acid once like for
um um
phosphorus acid it like exploded out of
the nlex machine and the whole place was
flooded with acid like 8 months later
still cleaning up like pieces from the
ground that were like chewed away yeah
crazy [ __ ] man crazy that's crazy the
the nlex is the um like the fertigation
skid right where it has a few different
input channels that you can put the
different like acid or the your
different mpks and whatnot into it and
then send it out we we use one of those
for our field irrigation okay um and the
craziest part to me is that the software
that the thing runs off of is from like
the late 90s oh my God it's similar then
yeah I I bet you looks like an old
computer when you're on there it's like
the yep and and you have to like the the
screen is like that green with like
black block letters probably have
pictures on here if I can find some I'll
send them to you yep I I use the same
machine every summer and it works great
when it's correctly functioning yeah
like but it took us a while like my boss
had you know a manual this thick that he
read through to make sure that he
understood it and then only taught me
the things that I needed to know and
like distilled it down to okay these are
the only functions you ever have to mess
with cuz there's so much back it was
overwhelming you get the little piece in
there that you
need y easy and I remember it for the
summer and then like right now cuz we're
going to get ramping back up to get our
crop going for the summer I'm thinking
about it and I'm like oh I don't I would
have to go and stand in front of the
machine again for an hour or two just
back and forth oh yeah the memories came
right back to me for sure yeah I always
wondered why is this machine seems so
old but it's like new technology so
strange it is it is really strange and
it's because it's been used for so long
and in Greenhouse uh irrigation and
applications um where you know and the
thing with it is is you need electricity
to run it and that's why I always
suggest people if they are setting up
like a commercial facility or even like
a an advanced home grow where they have
you know a few lights in a in a room
built out that they could just go with
something simple like a dosatron where
it's all hydraulic and it all just doses
your system through the water pressure
itself so you can just if you have clean
water on your main yeah then you can run
it from your main and you don't you
won't ever lose water pressure unless
the entire like District you live in
loses water pressure and if that happens
you have a whole bunch more stuff to
worry about than your
grow yeah there's been some crazy
learning curves out here for weather
[ __ ] like hurricanes throwing [ __ ] down
so for sure or freezes as well I'm sure
because you probably have to keep your
lines like your your fill lines if
anything's running Outdoors you got to
keep them wrapped in some sort of
heating cord or um have a we we we've
had some like crazy uh ice storms out
here in Oregon where we had to set up
like a a a drip um setting in our
different irrigation systems where we
would have it burst little amounts of uh
water through the system every couple
minutes it won't freeze very small
amounts yeah and just stuff like that
that you start to learn the uh you know
how the facility operates based on all
these other things and you start to
become that like Universal key where
you're I can fix that really quick or I
know how to do this um but it does come
with time and with a lot of uh failures
right because you don't know that your
lines are going to freeze until one of
them explodes on you totally
yeah um so you know we kind of got a
little bit off track there but I think
it was great you know with the feno
hunting and irrigation stuff that's a
lot of stuff that people should know is
you know it takes a lot to figure out
and to experience-based for sure I'm not
a learning by the book like that manual
did nothing for me it was scary because
I didn't have someone visually showing
me how to do it so right it's a
different Lear um with with that being
you know we were at uh where your
successes were and then we were going to
go into what one of uh your setbacks
were that you learned a lot from so go
ahead and uh share that story yeah so
probably my big my first big setback or
um where I was
disappointed was also in the first year
of the place when I came out here um it
was the first spot where I was like
fully in charge
and so any crop failures would be me um
facing the consequences and so we had
some challenging in input issues and and
like I had alluded to earlier um it was
a big shock to come from western Canada
to Eastern Canada east coast
specifically where um the biggest city
from me is an hour and a half away and
it's not even that big of a City
compared to what I'm used to um and just
not being able to get the things that I
need especially at a a scale size so um
was working with different soil
companies cuz it was a living soil it
was aquaponics as well and so trying to
find a living soil that's also going to
be complemented by our fish
poop um and so the
first or second I can't remember it was
the first or second um flower grow where
it was like um monocrop it was dosy cake
we were growing um and the
soil the soil that we were using ended
up
being um like the batch that they had
made was extra hot so the plants were
just getting fried they were getting
ammonia burned and like so it was like
hard to watch I called it brown Town cuz
it was like a section of the the crop
that was just turning brown and we had
to to get rid of some of those plants
early it didn't all die but um it wasn't
it wasn't a good crop and compared to
what I'm used to Growing or what we had
grown right so that was a big learning
curve and you just got to take your
dumps with your successes right like
it's not all going to be roses and and
sunshine and sometimes it is going to be
disappointing and you know at that point
we were just trying to do our best to
like get the crop to the finish line and
um the other thing because from that
crop we didn't use most of it honestly
most of it went to garbage but that the
other big fail that I could think of was
um managing the grow where I have full
control because I'm there every single
day versus managing the same strain at a
different facility that's two provinces
away and they're not listening to me or
updating me or keeping in touch or you
know like it's just like hard to work
with this man who just won't work with
me um and so we had just gotten into BC
here which is hard to get into for all
the way from the East Coast this little
but I had sent the buyers uh the Dosey
cake and I had sent them like the weed
and they were just like yeah this is
fire we want
it so when the batch went over there it
was um mixed with a crop that was like
it was our crop and another crop um so
the quality was different and like maybe
not to to everybody it looked very
similar like my boss would look at it
and go it's exactly the same but to
somebody like me or you we'd be like no
like I don't want to sell this mid but
I'll sell this good quality like some
people can see the difference smell it
whatever so that's what went out I had
to literally face to face that buyer
because he's like I went out and bought
a doy cake and he's like it was not what
you sent me so that was hard to talk to
you know like to just like be the grower
and be responsible but not throw people
under the bus cuz it's not that cuz I
did I let it go out right like it was in
my control or I thought it was um and so
it's stuff like that that's that makes
the job harder but like I said you take
your dumps with your success and it's
not as often so I find that the job is
more rewarding than it is not
rewarding for sure yeah that's a really
great point that you bring up that just
because two people are growing the same
strain with the same Sops and you know
attempting to mimic the Styles as exact
as possible the end product can turn out
vastly different you know maybe it's an
environmental Factor that's slightly
different or maybe there's an input
Factor that's slightly different you
know especially if that was what I
noticed was the biggest thing was the
different irrigation style so a lazy
version versus consistent irrigation
like TP just you know people
just it's a labor of love right hand
watering one the the irrigation
practices as well especially if you are
in a living soil situation then the
nutrient availability is going to be
highly dependent upon how that
irrigation is applied and so you know
not only is it just irrigation at that
point it's the overall nutrient density
within the root Zone and the the you
know percentage of different
constituents that are making up that
nutrient package for the plant they're
they're all going to be um adjusted
because irrigation can affect especially
in living soil right it can affect the
pH of the soil it can you got to let it
ride it out in living soil like it's not
like that's what I missed about salt you
know just being able to flush and
control verus you can flush it and reset
it yeah like watching Brown town just
slowly die before my eyes like that was
so hard
yeah that's be coming from like strictly
going automated salt places you know
Rocko cocoa to like this is living soil
like right well then also this was with
uh like a dual root Zone aquaponic
system we hand watering in the um fish
poop but okay um so yeah yeah we were
doing a bunch of actually rearch
research research studies
with the government of Canada so we were
maximizing on funding through uh certain
tax benefits that you get for doing R&amp;D
and so instead of it costing a lot of
money we ended up you know it paid for
itself and that was through doing a uh
affluence uh studies so we had
scientists I was working with a
scientist um we were using actually the
doy cake um to replicate you know is
this making a difference basically by
adding this effent what's in this poop
what's you know we had send it away for
microbial analysis which is really
difficult to get um because you can go
to your basic cannabis lab or any lab
really and get a microbial analysis
that'll tell you like your cfu or
exactly how much microbials are on
something but it can't tell you what
microbes those are so are they good are
they bad like you just don't know so it
was um through a university in uh
Halifax I think um dalh Housey it's a
good popular one that we got our
affluent in our soil and like the
scientist LED that whole research
project and then we were actually um on
a couple of the the world aquaponic the
virtual um conference too so the
scientists was on there talking about
what they found and what we
found is that there wasn't really any
rare or like unique microbe in fish
effent that was doing anything to create
like higher yield higher quality
basically any microbial input will help
break down the what you need and will
work the same whether it's fish poop
Worm poop um teas that people Brew based
on those things compost that kind of
thing you know so it was it was pretty
cool that is really cool I um I always
listen to or I used to listen to a lot
the um growing with fishes podcast with
Steve raisner and um I always wanted to
try out like the Dual root Zone planting
where you have your little your fish
tank and you just run almost like a a
thin nutrient film technique with the
plant sitting above it with the yeah I
can visualize that diagram right now
dude yep for sure me too I the a home
when they got rid of the fish farm I was
like can I have like they're three lb
fish right they're huge and my fish guy
Gary was like I'll tell you a sad story
man he's like you don't want one of
those in your living room cuz you need a
big pool and you'll find it on the
ground Dead one day which I did always
find lots of dead fish so cuz they'll
just hop out of the tanks yeah as soon
as they lose oxygen those suckers are
jumping out they're and it's aggressive
jumping like you you have to have
netting on them our our genetics anyway
is the tilapia so they're they like a
warmer a warmer a warmer
water yeah that's um I I feel like
anybody that hasn't really heard much
about
um uh aquaponics should go and listen to
the growing with fishes podcast yes they
are the experts I had very basic
knowledge of it honestly people want me
on their they have asked to be like a
speaker and stuff and I decline because
like it's not my forte like yeah I did
that but it was very ghetto and it was
yeah probably
not you know but it was a good
experience I love the fish
actually I still have a picture of them
up I
see um well I have a couple more
questions to go
through um so I'll ask them and then um
we'll just go from there so you know
with all of the um experience that you
have had um especially it sounds like
you've seen some of the practices within
the industry that a lot of people might
be like ooh that's something that I want
to avoid um as well as some of the
things that you've seen that are fairly
successful within the industry and and
you know running teams that are highly
productive and and really helping hone
in those different aspects of the grow
um what are some of the things that you
would like to see change within the
cultivation industry
um honestly uh the most important thing
I think that needs to change is just
what we were talking about earlier and
that's in regards to um positive
leadership and so there just needs to be
a bigger shift in um management and
Leadership and that needs to trickle
down into
productivity um and so I feel like any
any facility or any industry or any
workplace is going to need to
incorporate that um type of you know
newer style
leadership um to get anywhere and to get
people to stay you want we're seeing
more transition and less um like staff
retention because they're just not being
treated properly and the generation of
today is like [ __ ] you you know like
they do not give one [ __ ] about paying
for rent or like they'll go live in an
RV by the river like it's just unreal
like people just won't put up with [ __ ]
and so that managers need to follow that
Trend you know because it's just like
it's such a waste of um a per a
company's money and time to be replacing
these people constantly so it's like you
need to get the right people in and do
the right things you need to pay them
properly um no
[ __ ] communicate
more more transparency honestly like but
I don't really see those things changing
quickly so it's just going to be like
that's how I see um changes happening
but it doesn't necessarily mean that
that's where anything's going I hope so
slowly but
surely sure uh you know in the same line
of thought uh what are some of the
pitfalls that you might be seeing in the
industry or perhaps things that are
being swept under the rug um are there
any other other things there that you're
seeing other than what you've talked
about pitfalls I guess for me would be
like regulations and so um the tight
regulations and the amount of tax that
um that is being taken from Cannabis is
insane and I you know I know at the
basic level from being in it so here in
Canada you're having to feed all the
different provinces separately like
separate um buyers they all have
different rules and regulations you need
to know them um you can't mess up at all
and then they're they're taking all your
money so things are are starting to get
known and so you're seeing like leaders
in this industry shouting out about it
and wanting excise reform and you know
that's going to stop a lot of these
smaller businesses from being taken out
honestly and
and and so the pitfall is the changes
are are coming too slowly and and so
companies are just expiring because they
can't wait they can't wait for the
changes so if they people are getting
taken out and it's just not fair so it's
like going to be a monopoly just like
every other industry where there's all
these corporations that own everything
and everything's being exported because
they don't want to pay the excise tax so
if you like good weed and you you want
it from this guy well you can't get it
from this guy cuz he needs to make money
so he's exporting it to Germany so any
good weed you're making more money and I
know this for sure you're making $2 a gr
for dank ass weed in Canada domestically
versus four plus dollars internationally
at their like American or Australian or
you know Euros right so it's even more
money so yeah no
excis makes
sense that does I feel like supporting
the local cons consumers and community
over your
um trying to get the highest dollar is
something that a lot of people should
think about because that's that's very
important it
is um so having been a new grower uh and
trying to you know and then successfully
entering into the commercial space um
what are some what is some advice that
you would give to new Growers whether it
be um in homow sense or in a commercial
sense new
Growers so much so much
um the best advice I can give to new
Growers is to start with good reputable
genetics and so
um invest in
yourself so figure out res
search um find out come to me even come
to you I'm sure ask where people are
buying um their genetics and how cuz
sometimes It's Tricky so I don't mind
having those conversations but I think
that's the most important thing because
you can get so turned away by having
just someone's St someone's you know
basement unstable genetics like I would
I would give a new grower those and let
them know that's what they are and that
you know this is a good learning too
right like let's watch for everything
you know like so
there's benefits but I wouldn't if
you're just doing this on your own and
you're like you want to make your own
medicine and you want to learn and get
on as quickly as possible you got to
start with good quality stuff and That's
genetics first for sure I agree with
that I think that you know genetics
always tend to be at the Forefront of
what's important for a new grower to pay
attention to uh one thing that I do like
to add to that is that I think it's
beneficial for a lot of new Growers if
they have it available to grow a clone
rather than a seed because yeah that's
clones that are tested and proven you
can have certain expectations on exactly
what it should look like whereas with
seeds sometimes even if they're really
refined and from a really reputable
breeder there can be different
morphologies that the the you know that
the phenotype can can take that might
throw you off from thinking that it is
what you were looking for but if you
grow a clone and you see it grow out and
you do it a few times and you can kind
of see this is what something that is
supposed to produce really well does in
my setting and environment then you can
then start to look through seeds and
find things that are you know comparable
so you can go this is where my Baseline
was it's this clone I know how it grows
here I'm going to start looking through
seeds because I do want to try something
that's like a grape flavor or maybe find
something that's an OG or a GMO or you
know just something that you maybe if
it's flavor forward that you're
searching for or a specific cannaboid
profile that you're searching for you
can at least still know what you can do
with the um the setup that you have yeah
I
agree cool well you know this has been a
wonderful conversation Genevie I really
appreciate you joining me today
um I do like to wrap up the show with a
couple of questions that I ask all of my
fellow Growers um so what is your
favorite strain of all time White
Widow I love white right off the bat
yeah right off the bat I'm not growing
White Widow though I know I need a good
one though um so I just need to invest
in my favorite white widow that I've
ever grown is from Amsterdam Amsterdam
marijuana seeds um out in the
Netherlands that's actually my favorite
genetic seed bank they do their own
thing um and they have the best white
widow I like their white widow extreme
it's called it's just the
effect um that one I I grew so long ago
that I was be pre before I was like
getting a lab to test anything so I
don't know what the tpin are on it but I
can guess that lemoning is up there
because of the euphoria that you
experience with it it's like a haven't
felt a lot of strains that give me that
and so I miss it so I I definitely need
to invest in getting some
seeds nice yeah I haven't had White
Widow in probably a decade or more it's
skunk right like I love a good
skunk for sure you know every time I
hear skunk I I I just can't ever I can't
remember ever having something that did
taste like skunk the closest thing that
I can yeah the closest thing I can think
of is like a good GMO or um
like one of the different Burger strains
from from skunk Master Flex and okay
I've never tried one of those but GMO
for
sure yep um but yeah th those are always
like I think that that's what skunk
tastes like yeah yeah I encourage you to
get out there and buy some White Widow
extreme it's got a really unique like
I'd say like a burnt rubber I still
remember like but almost like lemon
burnt rubber hazy
smell that does sound good yeah well
along the same uh line of questioning
what is your favorite breeder of all
time or who is your favorite breeder of
all time I should
say hard hard hard it probably be what
I've grown the most of so I'm trying to
think like collectively like what where
do I go
like I've grown a lot of Barney's Farm
I've grown a lot of dinm
Kevin jodrey is also a favorite breeder
I do have some of his um genetics not
just from you know where I worked but
also seeds he's
given
um I'm trying to think of a Canadian
person that I want to
plug
uh yeah I'll stick with that well that's
so fine I feel like sometimes inetics
black cherry punch boom boom boom Oh
Canadian you know what I was just
talking about this I'm going to do a
shout out this is only because they
didn't come to my mind like jeez Lise
I've already grown T like in commercial
setting there is a breed here mother
Labs so I've grown black cherry punch it
they got from in-house genetics I
believe I don't know the whole story of
it but I've grown it in different
facilities cuz these facilities have
bought it from them so they're located
in Saskatchewan which is where I grew up
and was born which is cool um yeah if I
could ever get a job working under Brian
who is the CEO and founder or like on
their science team as like someone's
assistant I would love that job just how
much learning the tissue culture like
banking um uh like breeding pheno
hunting it's just like imagine going to
work and that's what you do every day I
know there's probably paperwork involved
but prob yeah definitely a lot of
tracking um yeah so I'm going they're my
favorite because I have experience
they're Canadian let's go with that
mother Labs nice yeah we have tissue
culture come up a lot on the podcast
because um so many people are getting
into it and I think it's really
important experience it is it's really
fun actually there's like a lot of calm
that you have to maintain in order to do
uh tissue culture very well because so
much of is very fine motor skills and uh
patience yeah maybe your facility needs
me
ni um we we are so small but
uh International here I come there you
go maybe not USA actually never mind no
probably not
I not not currently um C cut cut
yeah um so last question then on sort of
these these uh wrap-up questions is what
is your most memorable cannabis or
smoking related
experience oh
wow
most H you know some people it'll be
their first time smoking other
people embarrassing like that first like
joint that I my buddy forced out my
throat when I was like I'm going to kill
myself like um that's pretty out there I
guess like that joint saved my life so
in like a really hopeful but like
desperate that you know that's it I
guess but in a fun way I was trying to
think of a fun
one I guess it would be that trip so
taking I called it um like the grand
weed tour
2018 and that was literally driving down
the coast through Washington Oregon
Northern California stopped in Weed
California to look for weed and they're
like sorry we don't have any weed and
it's dangerous for you to be asking that
you know so why you know like probably
should have been killed a few times on
that trip but God's with me Creator
thank you protecting me but some of
those experiences I was on hippie Hills
smoking a joint we missed 420 so like we
got there way too late rolled into town
but we were like so what you know a
little bit later rolled in and still was
like very solo but smoked my own joint
that's probably one of the most
memorable like that's history that's
where history has been you know so
that's cool maybe it's different for
people who live closer but like I just
thought that was cool yeah yeah I I grew
up in the Bay Area and um it was uh
cannabis is a huge part of the culture
there yeah it's so neat it is and yeah
smoking up on hippie Hill is definitely
something people should experience if
they have I felt I feel grateful for
having experienced the little that I've
experienced in the last eight or nine
years I am not a an OG or a legacy
grower I am a noob at this I just happen
to like whip in and like work my way up
and win some stuff but honestly like I
am so grateful to have gotten and had
the blessings that have had in such a
short amount of time so it's cool well I
feel like your experience uh speaks
volume for your own capabilities as a
grower and you know a lot of people can
learn a lot from yourself if they do
want to enter into the Cannabis industry
and you know I just want to thank you so
much for your time today telling your
story and getting this information out
there to people because like I like to
say getting this information out there
to the Community helps us all grow
together and that's the way we grow uh
just like uh the title of the podcast so
again thank you so much I really
appreciate your time thanks Nick
[Music]