[Music]
Hello and welcome to another episode of
the Way We Grow podcast, a production of
the Craft Growers Network. Today our
guest is Drew Madison. Now Drew was
suggested for the podcast by our last
guest, Jared Richie. and um you know he
was introduced to me as Jared's teacher
when Jarrett enter entered the cannabis
space and sort of his sensei and uh the
the grow guru that he got all of his
information from. And so after hearing
that introduction and enjoying my
conversation with Jared so much, I knew
that I had to get Drew on the show. So,
um, Drew, welcome. And, uh, tell us a
little bit about your cannabis journey
and, you know, where it all sort of
started for you. Thanks, Nick. It's a
pleasure to meet you. Um, yeah, Jared's
a good friend. Uh, we've known each
other for a couple decades now. Um, met
in Denver long time ago through a mutual
friend uh, in the restaurant business.
Uh, I think a lot of us in this industry
have had some time in the restaurant
business at one time or another uh, due
to its flexibility and such. Um, but
yeah, I um I I grew up in Florida
originally, East Coast, and uh where the
laws and uh the the mindset on cannabis
is is very different um than than in the
West where I ended up meeting Jared and
so forth and really beginning my
cannabis uh career. Um but you know
started in Florida growing up and then
uh went to college at University of
South Florida and uh graduated there and
I couldn't get out of Florida quick
enough and um so back in uh 90 1993 I
bolted to Denver uh met a friend who had
escaped Florida a couple of years
earlier and um and just hit the ground
running. Absolutely fell in love with
Colorado. the people uh were probably my
favorite part. Even though, you know,
the mountains and the the snow and the
snowboarding, I I grew up surfing, so
snowboarding was a natural segue. Um but
I absolutely fell in love with Colorado
and but as I was saying, the people and
the mindset of just the kind of live and
let live um kind of mentality really
struck me and uh I took a liking to
right away. And um and about a year
after I moved to Colorado, I had a
friend, my roommate had a friend visit
him from University of Florida. And down
in Florida University, there were two
hot spots for cannabis back in the day.
Long time ago, uh really when Kind Bud
when that name really didn't even exist
in Florida, it was called Crippy back in
the day. That was the name. And it was
it came from Miami and it quickly came
and went to uh uh Gainesville, Florida,
which is where the University of Florida
is, the Gators. And those two places
seem to be the epicenter of of
high-grade quality homegrown cannabis in
Florida for quite a while. And uh I was
lucky enough, as I said, uh when I moved
to Colorado to have a friend come out
from UF who had a little bit of cannabis
cultivation experience. and he had some
amazing genetics for back then. Um it
was it was very hard to come come about
or come by uh kind bud crippy um just
really good dank seedless you know sense
of media back then and this is one of
the few cats one of the few guys that
had it and I was very impressed um by
what he had and um and I was I was
intrigued and I asked I picked his brain
and uh unfortunately he was and I'm sure
a lot of people have experienced this in
this uh industry is that u some people
are very forthcoming with information
and some people hold it tight to their
chest and uh I don't know if it's pride
or ego or just their own hard work and
they don't want to give it away and
that's that's understandable and uh but
he was one of those that kept it close
and so um I began my cannabis journey
kind of figuring things out on my own
and learning the hard way making many
many many many mistakes as a matter of
fact almost all the things I have taught
people over the years have been because
of I've screwed them up learn the hard
way and will never forget those lessons
So sometimes those are the best things.
And so um yeah, so I I started growing
in Colorado in about
1994 just about a year after moving out
there. And it all began in a little
closet in a apartment complex off of 6th
Avenue um west right by Red Rocks
Amphitheater, which is where I lived for
a while. So it all started there in a
little apartment with a 400 watt metal
halli, a hydroarm eb and flow, one of
those orange plastic ones they used to
make a long time ago. all a kit ready to
go right in the box. You just take it
out of the box, get it set up and and we
had some seeds from a couple of uh you
know bags that we got uh on the black
market. Of course, everything was black
market back in the mid '90s. And I just
had a couple of seeds that we were lucky
enough to find and uh popped them and
they they germinated and got a few
ounces of incredibly good incredibly
good cannabis my first uh time around. I
was quite lucky. Nice. So it started
there and uh you know I didn't and I
then I went from one project to the next
uh all personal projects. Um I didn't
really get into commercial growing for
maybe about 5 years after that just I've
been a connoisseur
um and uh and so it's just been more of
a personal project taking care of my own
health. Um, I do have chronic back
issues and so that's been a very good
thing for me to get into it producing it
for myself so that I can uh take care of
my back and help me sleep a little
better because that's that's my main
thing is I don't sleep very well. So
cannabis helps me significantly at night
especially the heavier indicica dominant
strains high high mine u tarpine strains
uh help me significantly when it comes
to sleep. So that's how I got my start
in Colorado in the mid 90s and then
graduated from place to place. I' I'd
rent a house uh talk with the landlord,
examine the basement, determine if it
was worthy or not, and uh put some time
and money into it and uh usually have it
for one hopefully two years instead of
having to bounce from year to year. It
gets uh costly and it's kind of a pain
in the butt after all the setup to uh
have to bounce. So So base was my thing
for quite a while. I feel like basements
were uh the thing for a lot of people
for quite a while because you know I I
always see the old pictures of people
trying to do it in their u attic and if
you're in a place like Colorado that
becomes a problem in the winter when
you're the only house on the block
without snow on the roof and so um yeah
I've seen like a lot of people kind of
trend towards the basement in that time
and especially in colder areas you know
you have a a more um your your
temperatures can won't fluctuate weight
as much, you'll have a little bit better
control, especially considering the
different controls you had access to in
the '90s are far different than what we
have access to today. And, you know, you
were having to maggyver a lot of things
to make sure that it worked properly.
Um, what were some of those first
experiences? Indeed. Yeah. What were
some of those first experiences like
when you were growing? Well, you know,
it's interesting you bring up the the
climate issue and that that that's one
of the biggest things we deal with and
that's why we're so blessed for the
growers luckily enough lucky enough to
grow in Colorado. Uh we have some very
nice uh weather uh and it's very
conducive of growing and cultivation.
You know, in in a in a grow your
parameters are very important. Humidity
and temperature being two of the most
important. And Colorado were blessed
with incredibly low humidity. And you
know plants do you know with vapor
pressure etc. They do enjoy a certain
amount of humidity for maximum growth
etc etc. However can you go too far and
create too much humidity and all of a
sudden you're dealing with major issues
mold bud rot um all sorts of other
issues that you have to you know whether
it's spring um to mitigate and it's just
opens up a whole can of worms. And so
Colorado is a beautiful place to grow
because of that lack of humidity um
squashes that potential for the mold and
mildeo. Now, of course, things can still
grow and fester, but it's just a great
head start we have in Colorado. Um also,
the uh just the climate being cool,
almost every night, I didn't I my first
probably my first 15 years of growing, I
didn't use air conditioning once. I
didn't need air conditioning one time. I
I I I specialized in growing up in the
mountains up in the foothills. Evergreen
um was was an area that I I enjoyed
growing very much. You know, we have
about a elevation of 7 to 8,000 ft above
sea level. So, every night of the year,
even when it's 95째, even 100째 in Denver,
it'll be 68째 at night in Evergreen. Even
Denver will be in the low 70s on a very,
very hot day. And when you're pumping
dry air at 72째 into a grow, that's even,
you know, and that's the warmest it
gets. Um, in those summer months at
night, it's it's very conducive of
healthy healthy plant vigor. And so I
was very lucky to have that.
Were you running your plants uh the
lights at night then so that you could
kind of offset those day temperatures?
Um, all right. Yeah, indeed. It's still
something that's super suggested to a
bunch of growers. It's it's something
that I feel like a lot of people miss
that that one key point of it. It it
works good in the summer and in the
winter because you have that ability to
heat or cool more efficiently.
Absolutely. And another thing to
consider too is the electrical uh the
the tiered uh service of electrical uh
service provided uh XL Energy whomever
it happens to be always charge less
money at night for uh those less in
demand hours. And so that's also another
uh benefit of being able to grow or
using your 12 and 12 cycle to be on at
night. Um it's it's it's it's cheaper as
well. So but yeah, between the
temperature and the and the price, it's
a no-brainer to pretty much put that 12
hours on at night every night. And so
yeah, Colorado just did me did me so
right early on. Like I said, I was able
to skip the charge of the air
conditioning and then of course the
costly maintenance and then the
purchases of the air conditioning and
installation and all that and getting
the HVAC guy down in your basement and
all those things we've had to deal with
um you know having people in our grows
or in our areas and our or in our
sensitive areas. So it's been very very
nice uh just pumping pumping air in
pumping air out. I had things on you
know temp stats and uh you know so the
temperature would get at a certain
degree get maybe above let's say 84
degrees boom fan cuts on. I've got some
massive, you know, 7 800 900 CFM fans
pumping air in and pumping air out at
the same time. Obviously with carbon
filters back in the day when things were
on the on the uh DL and underground, I
had some ozone inline ozone generators
that were also used in conjunction with
the carbon filters that seem to scrub
the air even uh you know getting what
the carbon filters missed. So it was
quite an effective uh scrubbing process
because of all that air I had to pump
out of my house in lie of the air
conditioners. So for sure but it was
quite effective. That's awesome. Um I
mean it sounds like you were already
thinking early on about you know the uh
environmental needs of the plants and
making sure that you were also targeting
a low cost. So budget, you were very
budget-minded, which I feel like is
something that is so important. And you
can't just look at, you know,
necessarily buying the perfect equipment
to make everything run as smoothly as
possible. And sometimes you really need
to
uh you need to look at it as like a
costbenefit benefit analysis and see how
much you actually can spend feasibly and
what you can get with that price. And
you know, air exchange in a room while
not necessarily ideal for you know some
of the things that you mentioned you
were uh you know controlling for with
like the ozone and the carbon filters
for molds and pests and pathogens. You
were already you have those in mind and
you have that as part of like your SOP
already which is such an important thing
to do. Um, and since you were like kind
of already geared towards really tuning
in to what you had the capability of
achieving, what were some of those
initial harvests like? Did you kind of
hit the ground running and start to see
success right off the bat or did you
have a few large failures? I know you
kind of mentioned earlier that you learn
from failures as we all do, but um, what
were some of those early on successes
and some of those early on failures that
taught you some lessons? Absolutely. Um
well, luckily I I hit the ground running
with a successful little three ounce or
so harvest with my first harvest in the
closet um in the one apartment complex
where I started on my adventure. Um I
was so pleased and so amazed and you
know I grew up gardening first of all.
So I grew up in in the southeast as I
said in Florida. I was also in Atlanta
for a handful of years which is where my
father stayed. And I would go visit him
and he always had a wicked garden in the
backyard. I was always, you know,
helping him pick, helping him plant,
helping him weed, all those good things.
And and I love just, you know, just like
and I wouldn't see it every day. So
every 3 4 days I'd go out in the garden.
I'm like, "Oh my god, that pepper is
twice as it was." It just blew me away.
Just nature blew me away. So extending
this over into the cannabis realm was
just a natural geeky thing for me to do
and just enjoy watching it grow. And
cannabis explodes. like just every day
you see a difference with cannabis and
and how it how it's affected by your
stimuli and the environment that you
create and so um so some of the so I was
quite successful at the very beginning
um had as I said because I didn't read
it in a book we didn't have the freaking
internet back then um I wasn't able to
just you know press a key and see how
somebody else is doing it down the road
or on the other side of the country or
whatever and so you know my cloning for
instance my first cloning
Um, and I f my first fora was with seeds
as I said and they they popped and
germinated and they worked quite well.
Got rid of the the males. The females
worked. I got the 3 ounces from it. But
soon thereafter I tried some cloning and
I didn't have any direction and I was I
took clones. I took leaves as clones.
Like I would take I took, you know, did
the 40 the 45 degree angle dipped it
into the solution and they wouldn't root
because they were leaves. They weren't
branches. And so I you know I just
didn't know anything back then. So the
leaves failed and then I tried bigger
pieces and that happened to have
branches and hey those worked and I just
figured that out on my my own and and
you know back then I'm using some cheap
powderized hormone that you got from the
garden store. They didn't have clonex.
They didn't have you know grow tech or
any of these better brands of gels. And
so um so quite a bit of failure back
then. So once the cloning thing started
working I had some more and more
success. But, you know, I would my f one
of my first grows was in Evergreen,
Colorado, and it gets cold at night, as
you alluded to earlier in your comment,
and even in the garage. I was growing in
a garage uh above. I had a kind of like
a mother-in-law suite of a big master
house up the driveway. And so, I was in
this guest house, and there's a garage
on the bottom and the and the habitation
up above, and I'm growing downstairs,
and it's not insulated. And I had to
get, you know, and I didn't realize the
space heater thing and what the minimum
temperature could be without screwing up
the plants and what that would even look
like. You know, how do you even
recognize if you're screwing up the
plants if they're too cold? Well, I
learned quickly that they will continue
to grow. Let's and let's say they're in
the, you know, clearly in the 30s,
they're going to wilt and die. But let's
say they're in the low 40s or mid-40s or
or higher, they're going to still grow.
They're going to still look very green
and lush, but what's going to happen is
that the inner nodal space is going to
stay. They're not going to fill in the
gaps on the colas. So your little nodes
are going to be spread out like they are
at the very beginning of growth, maybe
around the third, fourth week when they
start to really flower, but what they do
is they just don't end up filling in.
You don't end up getting colas. So you
have these beautiful plants with hella
crystals, hella tricoms everywhere
because the cold actually brings out the
tricoms as we know the cold temperatures
at night. But you have these little nugs
everywhere and they don't add up and
they don't look that great and they end
up being covered in trikes but just
little popcorn buds. So, I've had
multiple sessions with temperatures too
cold, not realizing that until I figured
that out. And bringing the temperature
up. In my opinion, I like the
temperatures not to get down below 60. I
like the low 60s, maybe 63. Get that
really frosty look going, but not hurt
the plant and not ruin that potential of
those big fat colas growing. So, I like
to keep my temperatures between about 63
64 at the very very coldest and right
around maybe the mid 80s to low 80s.
Some people talk about the high 70s and
the very low 80s. I personally like the
metabolic absorption of the water, the
nutrient in that mid80s, mid to low 80s.
I don't like higher 80s cuz funk starts
forming in the reservoirs, etc. But I
really do like those low 80s. It seems
like the plants ve uh are very vigorous
and they grow quite well in that that
kind of range. And so so yes, and then
and then on the opposite side,
temperatures getting too hot. Back in
the day, we're growing with thousand
watt metal halli lights. Hordalux was
the cream of the crop bulb. Those things
have like the most hot centers ever.
Like if you see them on a on a a thermal
scan, it's just like molten lava in the
center by the bulb and then going out
from there, it's exponentially cooler.
And so you have these crazy hot spots.
And so, you know, the the the the
tricoms are much less around the hot
spot. The the the hairs, the actual
pistols of the flower of the of the buds
are much smaller, too. And those are
thwarted as well. And so it so getting
too hot is a big deal. And then I
started adding fans right under the
lights to push cooler air between the
light and the top of the bud. And that's
that helped a lot. And that's before air
cooled lights. And that was a that was a
big deal when air cooled lights came in
because then we didn't have to have
those fans. But then we fig figured out
the glass was cutting around cutting out
some of that energy that the plants
wanted. So we soon got rid of the air
cooled lights and and moved toward just
heavy air conditioning and and uh and so
forth in these larger grows that we've
been doing. So lots lots of failure with
just temperature. Um humidity has been
huge failures as well, frankly. Um you
know, as I said earlier, plants love a a
decent humidity up until a certain point
where they start growing mold and then
bud rot. And so, but I don't like
spraying a bunch of stuff. Even organic
stuff. I' I'd rather not spray it. So,
the best thing to do is just keep those
parameters, keep the humidity, in my
opinion, in the low 50s is perfect cuz
then you get that vapor pressure. You
get the maximum um the the maximum
absorption of nutrient, maximum growth
without the chance of uh mold and mildew
uh happening all over your bud. So, just
keeping those parameters in check seems
to minimize those problems. And so
temperature and humidity were big
problems with my my early grows.
Sure. And you have such a different uh
like nutrient assimilation rate uh rate
of assimilation when you're under these
um highintensity discharge lights
because they do push off so much like
heat down right onto the canopy that
adjusting for that heat and the leaf
surface temperature can be a little
harder than what growers are
experiencing now with LED lights where
they actually need to maintain a much
higher temperature and much higher
humidity for maximum transpiration rates
within and the same grow spaces that you
know had maybe a one:1 fixture uh
replacement where they had HIDs and now
they're on to LEDs and boom they have to
completely change their environmental
parameters to to still achieve the same
highquality product. Um so when when you
were when you were growing all these
different methods what were some of the
biggest innovations that you saw? I
mean, you mentioned air cooled ballasts,
which was huge for HID growers. Um, and
I know that Jarrett mentioned to me that
you owned a grow shop at one point. So,
you must have encountered numerous uh
innovations throughout your career and
both growing as well as retailing these
different products. What were some of
the ones that you look back at now with
like a really fond memory of being just
the most cutting edge thing that you had
seen at that time? and maybe give give
me like the top three things that you
you witnessed. Yeah, that's a great
question. Um, you know, I have to say,
you know, one of the one of the first
things I saw, you know, I saw a lot of
different technologies come out as far
as the type of hydroponics cuz
hydroponics is fun. It's uh it's
engineering. So much of the hydroponic
industry is engineering from the
lighting to the to the actual plumbing
um and pressurized water systems, spray
systems, aeroponics, aquaponics. Um, so
one of the most interesting things I saw
early on was uh I went to there was a
guy named Gordon Creaser and he's his
he's a really popular Australian
hydroponic um grower that is uh an
innovator from probably almost 50 years
ago at this point. He was early
hydroponics, but he did aquaponics with
fish and it was incredible. And I got to
go to his house in Orlando probably
about 30 years ago right during my first
couple of years of of growing. And uh he
had his whole garage with an aquarium
and an entire self- sustained fish
aquaponic setup and it blew my mind. Um
and you know back then I was just doing
top drip with rockwool and top drip is
still my favorite even today. Um but I
was just just getting started and it's
going to this guy's garage and seeing no
nutrient, no anything and not even pH,
just the fish keeping everything in a
homeostasis
uh situation was just blew my mind. And
so to me that was the first thing that
like was revolutionary and different and
I know that's still being done today.
Aquaponics all across the world uh for
sustainability etc. Um the next thing
that really blew my mind was probably uh
the lighting thing. Um you know the LED
thing was is absolutely revolutionary.
um going from just the same old same old
for really a couple few decades with the
HID lighting whether it was metal halli
for the veg cycle and you know high
pressure sodium for the the bloom cycle
but just to have this LED and
essentially kind of the same LED can be
used for veg and bloom which kind of
blew us away as well. Um you know we do
have some specific spectrums that go
back and forth between grow and bloom
but in general a lot of people use the
same light for veg and bloom and do
quite well. Um but the l you know that
literally the half the you know double
the amount of lumens, double the amount
of par watts um going out with half the
amount of energy being consumed and and
less than half the amount of heat was
absolutely revolutionary especially for
home growers. You know commercial
systems are different. You can get away
with with mass air conditioning units,
etc. And and um yes, it costs money to
run, but you can get it done. But with
some home systems, you can't even do it.
It's it's it's it's a it's a non-starter
for a lot of guys in whether in their in
the bedroom or a basement or whatever or
in a closet like where I started. And so
having access to LEDs just opened the
door for so many more people to be able
to tap in, use their facil, use their
home to be able to grow, maximize, grow
their own medicine. Um, and so this and
and then just better quality product,
you know, um, less airy bud buds that
didn't get the the burn like I was
saying, uh, with those hot spots that
were created so often with the HID
lighting. Um, and so the quality went
up, the cost went down, and I think more
more and more people just entered the
market and started growing for
themselves because it was uh, it was
just it was just easier to do and uh,
and less money to to do it. And so I
think the lighting was a huge huge part
of it as well. Um and thirdly, I think
uh these climate control systems are are
badass, man. Um I remember 20 years ago
dreaming and wishing that I had engineer
friends that could have developed a um a
rockwool or a media sensing hydro um
hydrometer with a probe that could sense
if your rockwool didn't if the pump
broke your rock, you know, your plant.
And because in rockwool you don't have
much of a buffer. If your system goes
down 24 hours, you're going to be dead.
Your plants are going to be dead. And so
if you had some sort of sensor, and of
course we have smartphones now, and we
have all of this present today, which is
a beautiful thing, but I would have died
for this 20 years ago. You know, I I get
a little message on my phone saying,
"Hey, I'm low. I'm sensing 10% humidity
in your rock cube, whereas it should be
20% or more. You have clearly have a
problem." I'd race home, fix my my uh my
my pump or my dripper got, you know,
clogged or something, and problem
solved. Um, I can't tell you how many
times I walked into a room and even
before looking, I could smell I could
smell rot. I could smell the rot. And
so, if anything is different, every time
you're walking down the stairs and going
into your grow room, if anything is
different from the smell, the sound is
different, you know something is wrong
and you're and you're bracing yourself.
And so, the smell of a little rot or
something different even for 24 hours. I
go down, it's like, okay, my plants are
are are dying because they got too much
water. They didn't get enough water.
Something's going on. All of these
automated systems are just absolutely
amazing today that can let you know on
your phone. You can on your app, you can
turn on an exhaust fan, you can turn off
an exhaust fan, you can you can turn on
water, you can adjust pH with these
doser systems. It's so to me these
automated systems that aren't just for
these big commercial box places, but for
you know Joe in his basement um are just
really badass and and fun to use, fun to
dial in. And as I kind of alluded to
earlier, you know, we're kind of we're
hobbyists, but we're also little
engineers ourselves. There are not many
people that are growing that don't know
how to use their brains and their hands
to fix things because things happen and
the growth store is not always open down
the road and you need to make something
happen right now at 11:00 at night when
you discovered it and you need to fix
the problem right then and there. So, I
think every grower has a little bit of
uh engineering inside them whether they
admit it or not. For sure. I I agree
with that wholeheartedly. And you know
it there is so much more peace of mind
when you do have the ability to monitor
your grow from a distance. But it also
then it it's almost a double-edged sword
sometime because you know maybe there
was a little bit of ignorance is bliss
at times. You know it it it always sucks
walking into a room when you start to
smell that that rot smell where you know
leaves have wilted and are not coming
back and it's just that it's a very
obvious smell. you said it and it I like
had a [__] reaction to that to that
thought because I'm like, "Oh, I [__]
smell it right now." Um, but you know,
if you have the ability to monitor it,
then when you do see a problem and if
you're the only person that can go and
fix
it, you're almost obligated to because
if you don't, then you can't blame
anything else besides yourself or your
own lazy ass, you know? Um whereas
before you might have just been like
well I just I check on it twice a day.
If it's not within my checks I don't
know what else to do. I can't I can't go
out there every 15 minutes. Um so yeah I
I do love monitoring though because it
also helps with a lot of these newer
technologies or techniques I should say
such as like crop steering which isn't
new. It's just new for cannabis, but you
know, people in tomato and cucumber
industries have been using crop steering
techniques for decades successfully as
well and and you know, being able to
produce that much more uh produce off of
each plant. So, um let's see. So, you
know, you said that uh your father was
sort of your start into gardening in
general. Um, what what were some of the
first plants that you remember growing
that you were like really excited about
that maybe sort of
uh uh excited your um your senses to
where you really wanted to follow this
plant, this path that you've taken with
plants. And then you said you also went
to university and I was wondering does
that happen does your degree happen to
um play into your love with of plants?
Good questions. Um yeah, my dad started
me off. He was always a gardener. He's
actually a landscape architect. So he
was um worked for the US Fish and
Wildlife Service and he would design
wildlife refugees across the southeast
of the country. Um US wildlife refugees
like you know 100 acre 200 acre refugees
where the visitor center would be where
the you know uh like in a swamp the Oki
Finoi swamp in in North Florida, South
Georgia area. He uh you know designed
that whole refuge and you know where
everything went, the bathrooms and the
where where the swamp you know would go
and the the boat launches would be and
just everything and where the plants he
he know knew every plant what every
plant was every tree was he could
identify. So, I had a little bit of that
in me and we, like I said, in Atlanta,
we always had the garden. And honestly,
my favorite plants were tomatoes and
beans. And I think because I because I I
got the satisfaction. I'm not a very
patient person, and I wasn't a very
patient kid. And so, being able to see
something every day grow and change blew
me away and and it kept me going. If it
took weeks for things to happen, it it's
a little harder for me to stay involved
and stay chomping at the bit. But
watching a tomato grow every day, coming
from a little flower to a little ball of
fruit and just grow literally every day
and see that. And the same thing with a
bean. And beans were really cool to me
as a little kid cuz they would follow a
string up or a pole up and just and
every day it's like another 6 in. And
I'm like, "Oh my god." You know, and
then and then eating eating the the you
know, our our our fruits of our labor
literally. Um that was awesome. you
know, we would cook and eat the the
vegetables in our garden, you know, on a
on a weekly basis. We'd harvest, then
cook them the next week. Sometimes we'd
can and preserve them as well. And so,
just all of that all the way from farm
to in my belly uh was neat seeing that
whole cycle and then expanding on that
in in cannabis later in my life and
being able to grow my own medicine. And
as I said, I've had a, you know, it
started recreationally with me with
cannabis because of just absolutely
loving the plant, loving the effect on
me, you know, in college, etc. in late
high school, which is pretty much where
I started. But it it soon happened after
I hurt my back in my mid to late 20s to
where cannabis was a lifesaver as far as
a medicine for me. And so the the
ability to produce my own chemical-free
organic medicine that I know has zero
anything bad on it. Uh and then consume
that cannabis both eating it and mostly
smoking it. The edibles don't aren't
quite as effective for me. They're very
effective for others. They don't work
quite as well for me. So consuming it,
smoking it or vaping is best for me for
sure. But being able to follow that all
the way from where I germinate the seed
or take the cutting from a host plant,
growing it, curing it, smoking it, and
feeling better from it. It's a pretty
neat, it's pretty cathartic, you know,
it's a pretty neat circle of of life
right there. And so that was a real
treat learning that as a child through
eating the the benefits of our of our
labor to smoking and consuming and
having a medicine that is a benefit of
my own labor as well was it was a huge
treat throughout my life. Yeah, it's
it's no wonder that uh you know farming
popped up in multiple different cultures
around the world. It makes a lot of
sense. So uh going on to then did you uh
kind of pursue any path in horiculture
or botany or anything like that when you
went into college or um what was your
path there?
So in college I was you know I was one
of those lost kids frankly in in school
um most of my friends knew what they
wanted to be when they grew up knew
where they were heading. You know, I
liked gardening, loved it, but I wasn't
hyper passionate about anything in
particular. And so I I've been searching
most of my life for that thing to just
jump into that just was just a green
light and everything pointed me in that
direction. And frankly, nothing nothing
did that for me. I ended up just kind of
falling into a few places and then just
very much enjoying and feeling
incredibly lucky and blessed where I
fell. Um, and so in school, I was a
liberal arts major. I I was a very
rounded uh major. I I got a bachelor's
of arts in liberal arts and uh
specializing in philosophy and so you
know I will talk to you all day and
argue with you all day. Um but yeah, but
nothing specific about the horiculture
back in school. And uh and like I said,
when I I just kind of fit into it when I
came out to Colorado and then had that
friend visit the friend of the friend
and showed me this amazing bud that he
grew and that just started the started
it in my own mind of hey, if this guy
can do it, I think I could do it. You
know, it was nothing against the guy. He
was a great kid, but but I but I felt
like I could do it at least as good as
he did. And I'm glad, you know, that
introduction happened because without
that, I may have never tried to
cultivate. I may have never understood
how amazing this medicine even was in
the first place. Um, and so yes, even
though educationally I didn't get
anything directly from it, I I ended up
working and finding my my way through
uh, you know, my mid mid to late 20s and
just falling in love with the plant,
realizing how much it does for me
mentally and physically and then just no
matter where I'm at in life, finding a
place in my home to grow my own
medicine. And I've I've been lucky to
where I've only bought a very little
amount of the cannabis over the years in
my entire life. And I'm 53y old man
right now and I've only bought, you
know, a handful of bags of cannabis in
my whole life because of my ability to
produce for myself in Colorado. And one
more thing I want to say about Colorado
cuz I can't give Colorado enough props.
Um, in California, I have to say as well
for that, even though I didn't live
there, um, Colorado was a sanctuary for
pe for like-minded people like myself
when it comes to cannabis and cannabis
rights. um Colorado, even though people
would get caught and people would get in
trouble for cultivating in Colorado
because it was federally illegal and
state ille illegal statewide as well up
until uh you know the the early mid
2000s. Um it it it the the penalties
were much much less than most of the
other states and it was a known thing
and in even different jurisdictions like
Boulder County, I lived in Boulder
County, Colorado in in the city of
Boulder. Much less repercussions if and
when you you were to get caught with
such a thing. And so that was that was
taken to mind and considered as well.
And so I can't thank Colorado enough for
giving me the opportunity to take some
risks, but also know that I wouldn't get
uh you know, the the the repercussions
weren't nearly as bad as in many other
places. So I I just I can't thank
Colorado enough for giving me such a
safe haven. And so many people from
across the country seem to come to
Colorado to grow. You know, it was
California and Colorado seem to be the
big the big hubs. you know, of course
Washington and Oregon as well, but um I
can't give enough props to my my home
state of Colorado, man, for giving me
the opportunity.
Nice. Yeah, I I I mean, I feel like it
was uh Cal California first with 215,
but then Colorado went recreational
first, I believe, and um kind of blazed
the path there. And you know there were
a lot of issues with that early
legalization and there still are so many
issues with legalization in terms of the
um restraints still put on homegrow even
in certain cases or um you know how much
uh like how they regulate it. you know,
if it's a plant count or something like
that, that's so silly and arbitrary
because, you know, if it if you can only
grow four plants, then fine, give me
four 5x5 tents and uh I'll show you how
much wheat I can grow. And it it's just
silly things like that that don't
actually make sense. It just makes sense
in the mind of someone who's building
these different laws, who's never
actually grown a plant themsself. And so
I I do appreciate like certain uh states
that have a heavy um you know a heavy
number of active individuals towards
trying to uh adjust some of those laws
and stuff like Michigan I know is a big
one. California as well, I feel like
does kind of help push towards different
laws being either um relooked at or
reviewed just to make sure that they
aren't necessarily causing any sort of
uh issues with just like like I said
like Homegrow. Homegrow is one of the
big ones for me. But
um when when you were So when was the
first year that you started growing?
Remind me of that. Was it 94? Yes, it
was 1994. Yep. Okay. And um do you still
grow today? I I totally understand if
you don't feel comfortable talking about
it. Um but um maybe talk about one of
your more recent grows. Uh that that was
kind of using whatever you felt as
though was like your your most uh
advanced setup. I should say advanced
only meaning like the timeline in which
it was was grown in.
Nice. Well, yes. Um, I recently moved to
Costa Rica. So, right now I'm talking to
you from Costa Rica. I live in a little
town um right south of a town called
Hakaco in central on the central Pacific
coast. So, I can surf uh as much as I
can and uh live a good life. I I'm I'm
very very very lucky. And uh cannabis
has some some to do with that as well
through my journey um helping me get
here. Um, so I'm not growing currently
because in Costa Rica right now you can
you can technically grow if you apply
through the ministry of salude which is
the health ministry and you apply and
it's a pretty extensive process uh using
a doctor um much more stringent than
what we have back home in the US and in
Colorado but you can technically grow up
to six plants if you go through this
process. Um but it's not a process that
I want to deal with right now. I do have
some local friends that can help me out
with some medicine and then have been
able to at this point and so it's not
one of those things I just really want
to jump through those hoops at this
point just like I did back in the states
though years ago I'm keeping an eye on
it and um seeing where it goes and the
easier it gets um and closer to
recreational because they are heading in
that direction as well which is
beautiful and as soon as they do that
I'll I'm sure I'll jump in with a little
homegrow of myself is once it's 100%
legal but right now they don't mess
around with they right now they kind of
lump it in with other drugs It's just
very unfair. Um, you getting caught,
that being said, you getting caught with
a little bit of marijuana, even being a
gringo like myself, an American, no big
deal at all. They just don't want you
selling, don't want you growing,
providing, uh, you know, transporting,
anything like that. Um, so the last grow
I set up was a friend's grow in a
basement in a in a very beautiful
concrete unfinished basement, which is
my favorite place to grow um, as far as
uh, home grow. and um 9- foot ceilings,
unfinished. Um I had uh had him install
uh a mini split, a three-tonon minit
system, which is a very nice robust
system producing a [__] ton of cooling.
And uh also had a commercial
dehumidification system set up all on um
stats so that uh humidity gets too high,
the dehumidifier turns on. Um same thing
with the temperature gets too high, the
AC turns on, turns off when needed. So
it was complete climate control. I had a
uh tankbased CO2 system installed as
well. I had minimum exhaust. I had a
negative pressure installed so that at
the front door of the house, you didn't
smell any smell coming out, any weed
smell. Even though it's technically
legal with the plant count that they
have going, um they still want to be
incognito because of the neighborhood
they live in, which is understandable.
So I always usually like recommend
between 300 and 600 CFM going out of the
house through a filter at all times so
that you have that negative pressure at
the front door and at windows and
throughout the house. And so climate
control was completely dialed. It was a
top drip uh rock wall slab system. Um I
worked with cocoa for quite a while. I
switched from back maybe about 10 years
ago from Rockwell slab top trip to a
cocoa system in a 10gon cocoa uh mixed
with 7030 cocoa to perlite uh mix and I
switched to the uh cocoa about 10 to 12
years ago when the russet might
infestation happened in Colorado and
everybody who's grown in Colorado can
remember the tragedy that was the russet
mites coming and taking over Colorado
for a couple of years. Worst part about
it is no one really knew what it was.
And so a lot of us were festering around
just freaking out seeing these uh
effects on our plants and not having any
idea what it was. And only some elite
people from California knew what it was
cuz they had been dealing with it for
quite a while. So all the interstate
commerce, which was a great thing when
it came to spreading love and spreading
genetics, unfortunately also spread some
really hardcore bad bad pathogens,
including those russet mites, which to
me to this day are the worst pathogen I
have ever dealt with in this u in the
cannabis world. Um I've been able to
take care of them and I know how to
essentially get rid of them now and to
control them now. And I use sulfur
mainly um sprayed sulfur as opposed to
the sulfur vapor because the vapor I
have killed uh plants too many times
with it just getting a little too
costic, a little too dense as far as the
vapor. And the sprayable sulfur seems to
be work very very good at about 1.5
teaspoons per gallon of water used. And
uh it works quite well uh for the russet
mites and honestly for the you know
potential fungus, mold, anything like
that at the same time. uh kind of kills
a few birds with one stone. So, but the
russet mites were were a huge issue um
back in the day. I think I just lost my
train of thought where I was going with
that with uh no worries at all. You
know, I feel like that's such an
important thing to bring up is the
simplicity of using wedible sulfur to
take care of russet mites because russet
mites still are a huge problem and um
I've had to deal with them a few times.
Wetable sulfur always seems to be the
best way to go about it. I always like
to remind people though that if they're
using oils or mineral oils or essential
oils and any of their other sprays or
IPM practices to make sure that you
either give the plants a really really
good wash with some sort of surfactant
like um like even just dish soap or
something like um capsill uh like an
adjuvant where you can really get all of
that extra oil residue off the plant
before you hit them with sulfur because
you will melt your plants if you combine
oils and sulfur is too close together.
And it goes the opposite way, too. If
you need to apply oils afterwards, make
sure that you are rinsing the sulfur off
of your plant if you just sprayed them
for russet mites or other mites or
especially molds or mildews work. Uh um
you know, sulfur works really well for
those as well. But I also agree, I do
not like the like sulfur burners or
anything like that that atomizes the
sulfur. it it just does seem to cause
some issues and it doesn't go away after
like the rooms just end up starting to
smell like sulfur after a while and that
it doesn't go away. Um but you know I
think we so you brought that point up by
the way Nick about the the oils. Yeah,
that that's a very very good point to
bring up for people listening. Um sulfur
is incredibly effective. However, with
the oil it's like a toxic solution and
and let me tell you another toxic
solution. If you have humidity going, if
you are running a humidifier, you never
ever ever want to to run sulfur. Spray
sulfur or use a sulfur burner because
the sulfur will turn into an acid rain,
literally an acid rain and melt your
plants even worse than spraying. So, so,
so mixing sulfur and oils is a horrible
thing and mixing sulfur in a humidifier
is also a horrible thing. And then
thirdly, putting applying just like when
you're applying anything to plants,
whether it's a a good oil, beneficial
oil, or it is sulfur itself, you want to
spray when those lights are off because
when you the the stomatas are closed,
you you you can burn the [__] out of
your plants when the sulfur night. Now,
you can spray even a half an hour before
the lights turn on. As long as they're
dry, as long as the plants are dry by
the time the lights turn on. So, that's
another thing I'd like to point out so
people don't fry their plants as well.
just uh pop on a little green light or
something and spray the [__] out of your
plants in the while they're dark. Let
them dry before those lights come on.
Come on. Yes, absolutely. And um you
know, so what we were talking about
before was the last grow that you had
set up and um I think we just got a
little bit uh onto a russet might
tangent because it's a good tangent to
get onto. Um you know, it's one of those
pests. You say it's the worst that
you've ever dealt with and I agree. It
is up there. It's probably my number
two. My number one being rude aphids.
Um, but russet mites are definitely root
aphids.
And I for anybody out there that is
wondering if they're dealing with root
aphids, uh, my best advice is to know
the difference between winged root
aphids and fungusnats is fungusnats
wings lay flat on their back. Roote
aphids stand up like the wings are
preying on their back. So those are easy
easy things to to look out for. So if
you are dealing with something like
that, good differentiator, Nick. That's
that's a really good point. One one
other thing I would point out, winged
root aphids fly into light.
Fungusnats fly indiscriminately. And
that to me, that was my easiest way. And
and they're a little bigger, too. The
winged root aphids are a little bigger.
You can see their wing structure better,
like you just said. That was a brilliant
point. But if you just watch for a
second, the wing root aphids will find
their way and make their way and die.
And that and that's another way you can
tell you have them. You have dead bugs
on the top of your top leaves of your
plants. Why? Cuz the wingroot aphrons
are searching out that light. They hit
your light. Well, not an LED. Excuse me.
Let me back up. Back when I was growing
with a metal a high pressure sodium, the
wingroot aphid would go up, hit the
light, die, fall onto the top of the
plant. And now on the top of the plant I
have tens if not dozens of dead what are
these bugs? They're wing root aphits
because they're flying to the light.
Fungus nats will never fly to the light.
They're just flying all over the place
just looking for a place to breed. So
that was another way of being able to
differentiate the two for sure. But yes,
I hate those things man. Let me ask you,
Nick, what what what was your were you
know because clearly you need like a a
drench to deal with wing grews because
they they they're they're feeding off of
your roots. Um what's the best way that
you use to clear those things? Uh
pythans and Bavaria
Bosiana. And and now Botanagard actually
has the product Batanagard Max which is
Pythans and Bavaria Bosiana mixed
together uh in an aquous solution. So,
it's super easy to mix up in a spray
applicator if you're going to do like a
sprinch where you're actually using like
a sprayer like you would for your uh
folure applications, but you're just
kind of hitting the top of the pots. And
uh it's also why I suggest always using
solid plastic pots because if you're
using a fabric pot, root aphids are they
are usually permeable enough where root
aphids can enter and exit um the that uh
that mesh bag or that that fabric pot.
Um but yeah, uh py pyth and and bavaria
bossiana work for me. Very nice. You
know what also I I want to throw in
there when it comes to the root aphids
thing or the um excuse me the uh russet
mites thing. I had incredibly good
results with beneficial insects as well.
And some people don't like spraying
anything on their plants and I had
incredible results with from Arbico
Organics and there was another one
that's like a little cheaper. They're
online, you know, the top three hits on
Google for beneficial insects though.
Predatory mites. Predatory mites.
Californicus, swerki, and Andersoni.
Those are the three Latin names of the
beneficial mites that kick ass on uh
russet mites. Um curcumin mites, all the
most evil mites that you can get, the
beneficial mites were incredibly
effective. And the the best way was a
two two-part treatment. What I would do
is I would spray a little bit of water
as a kind of a surfectant so that the
the things that the the bugs that I
would sprinkle on them would stick to
the leaves that are. So I would spray
with a little backpack spray or some pH
balance water. Then the first thing I'd
do is I would shake the ready to use
bugs that were just like ready just
chomping at the bit to eat. Shake those
immediately on my garden. And then at
the same time they have these little
they're called sachets which are like
these little packets of of bugs that
have bugs of all stages inside of them.
So they continue to breed inside the bag
and to go out the little holes that they
have in the little sachets and they'll
go out on their own, search out the
bugs, come back to their little nests
inside the sachets and have a little
environment for two, three, even four
weeks. They'll stay alive. And so I
would have the ready to use that would
knock them down immediately within the
first day or two and I literally 24
hours later see my plants look healthier
24 hours later it was incredible. And
then throughout the next week as those
sachets are starting to do their thing
have better and better and better
benefits or or better uh
uh better recovery of these plants that
were damaged from the the the russet
mites every single day from those
sachets. So I really recommend it's a
little money. you're going to drop a
little money on these, but but 100%
organic. Um, they don't hurt any
anything else in your garden, and they
just really go and attack what they need
to attack, which is those russet mites.
And I can't speak highly enough of those
beneficial uh predator mites.
Nice. Yeah, I I've used predator mites
before for things like fungusnats. Um,
but I I and we've used them as well for
like two spot spider mites and and
whatnot. Um, I've never used them for
russet mites, but I'm glad to hear that
they've worked for other people in that,
especially for those people out there,
giving them an option if they are trying
to avoid spraying. Um, especially, you
know, after you get past week, you know,
three, maybe four at the latest. Uh, you
you really don't want to be spraying too
much at all anymore. Um, and and you
know, there's some things you just don't
want to spray in flour at all. Like, you
don't want to spray sulfur at all in
flour. you're if you're in a commercial
setting, you're going to pop for sulfur
on your plants. So, it's uh it's
important to know your limitations there
for sure. Um Yeah. Have you ever tried
nematodes for the fungus nats? Oh, yeah.
Destroys them. I had the best results
with the nematodes. Yep. Absolutely. We
we've been using these new one from uh I
think it's called like Sierra Naturals
is the company that makes the uh the
nematodes that we've been getting and
they've been coming in on these little
tiny sponges rather than in the cake
form and they work great. You just pop
them into your into your mixing tank
with your airrating stone and your your
circulating pump and you're off to the
races. If you are using nematodes
though, just remember to apply them
through a um a diaphragm pump. Don't
apply them through any sort of uh siphon
pump or anything like that because the
pressure that builds up in the system as
well as the like chopping action of the
actual motor can cause the uh nematodes
to be destroyed cuz they are little tiny
living they look like little worms. Uh
if if you need to have a reference look
look back to that episode of Spongebob
Squarepants that has the nematodes
eating everything in the ocean. They
look just like that but they're they're
tiny. Um yeah. So, you know what I did,
Nick, to get around that though because
of the pump thing and and it seems like
they're even more effective because they
don't want to live underwater. They like
they need a little bit of air. And so,
so what I would do is I would mix them
up in a 5gallon bucket like heavy
concentration, you know, like 10 million
or whatever the count was. It was a
heavy. And I would just hand water the
top of every one of my plants that had
the nematode or excuse me, that had the
fungusnat um infestation. And so, I just
hand top that. And so, I would never
even add them to my reservoir. or I
would just add this mega high
concentration of nematodeses to the top
of every one of my plants. And you know,
being in Colorado, my plant count was
always, you know, in the tens as opposed
to hundreds. So, it was it was feasible
to do, you know, 20 plants, you know,
top dress like that. And that was
incredibly effective for sure. And you
do only need to soak the top inch or two
of any pot size because that's the the
depth at which which um the neat or the
fungusnat larvae are actually living.
they're not going to be much deeper into
the pot. Um, so I think those are all
great tips for people that are battling
a few different uh pests. You know, we
don't we don't actually get into pest
control too often here, but I feel like
it is really important and so I'm really
glad that you brought it up uh you know,
just with the the Russet might threat of
thought. I thought that was great.
Um, can you talk a little bit about uh
transitioning from being a home grower
into your time spent in the retail space
for different grow equipment and stuff?
Absolutely. Um, you know, I did my my
transition was kind of twofold. It was
from the home grow underground cannabis
cultivation to the to number one
commercial cultivation because I got
into commercial cultivation. Um, I set
up a grow in in a set in a part of
Boulder. Um, it's called Gun Barrel.
It's kind of a little it's it's still in
Boulder City, but it's on the outskirts
of Boulder, and it's where a little mini
warehouse zone is. And so, this was one
of the first places Boulder City allowed
and zoned for back when the laws passed,
zoned for commercial cultivation of
cannabis. And in Gunboro, I was the was
the first warehouse that opened up
there, my little warehouse with a
friend. And it was back in the day where
you had a notebook of caregivers uh or I
was a caregiver for a notebook of
patients and of people that needed care
and needed medicine and uh were able to
legally buy it from me and I was able to
legally sell it to them, but I had to
have a notebook filled with their kind
of license paperwork and stuff showing
the state. And uh that was my first
commercial grow there. And it was about
a 50 light uh operation with uh like 18t
high ceilings. Um, I brought in a
10-tonon HVAC unit, which blew me away
because, you know, my house at the time
had a three-tonon. So, this was like,
wow, this is so big and cool and um and
it was just it was just so
groundbreaking. You know, we didn't have
electricians that were used to hooking
up lights like this yet and running this
much conduit and we didn't we didn't
have plumbers that were, you know,
willing to do the jobs needed for the
water. And uh it was just really
groundbreaking and it was hard finding
subs and finding uh engineers honestly
as well to figure out uh um BTUs of heat
created from each light and depending on
what light technology it was etc etc. So
my first fora was into the growing
commercial side of it. Um which which I
absolutely loved and I ended up working
for uh myself like I said at the
beginning and then a commercial
dispensary called Sweet Leaf Compassion
Center. And I was the head grower for
that for a year until it was found out
through uh the local jurisdiction that
it was about 25 ft too close to a school
and had to be shut down. Oh no. You
know, just some of those ridiculous
laws. But so that that gave me a bad
taste for the commercial side of the
growing. So I got out of that um at the
time and um a little actually before
that though I got into the um into the
side of retail hydroponics and opened a
store with a friend in Asheville, North
Carolina. And that was that was quite a
while back. That was actually
um in 19 let's see that was right around
19 99. Yeah. So so maybe about 5 years
or so after I started growing I opened
this little grow store in Asheville. And
Asheville was kind of like a boulder of
the East Coast. It was an epicenter
where growers and like-minded people
came to help each other out, to be a
community, to know they're safe, know
that the laws for getting caught
wouldn't put you in jail for 20 years.
You still get in trouble. It is North
Carolina, but it's a different kind of
feel in North Carolina being Asheville.
So, my store was called Asheville
Agricultural Systems, and it opened up
in 1999, right around 2000. And just
last uh about two years ago, we sold it
in in addition with uh four other stores
that we had opened subsequently. So we
had five stores in total throughout
North Carolina and one in West one in
Virginia as well in Charlottesville. And
we sold those and made uh some good
money and I was able to buy this house
in Costa Rica with my proceeds from the
sale of that. And so that was pretty
awesome. um taking my you know getting
into that and learning retail and and I
have a little retail experience. My mom
owned a little perfume store when I was
young and on the main street in my town.
So I learned how to do inventory and
ordering and customer service and how to
greet people and how to restock shelves
when you know par levels got low etc.
And so I took that little bit of that
knowledge with my mama and uh took it
into the hydro store in Asheville and
were very successful with that store and
ended up opening as I said four more
with the help of my brother-in-law and
my sister who did an amazing amazing
job, Ashley and Richard um and just kind
of took it took it over cuz you know I I
didn't live in North Carolina. I
couldn't run the thing. And so they they
basically helped uh launch it into the
stratosphere and to a place where we
could eventually sell it and uh all make
good money. And they're both now retired
from it as well from their hard work.
And I'm uh semi-retired, but not exactly
retired. I uh I still run a uh a uh
legal marijuana cannabis business in
Denver called Luminescence Labs going by
Denver Dabco, which is a cannabis
extraction lab uh based out of
Evergreen, Colorado right now. Very
cool. Uh is that the kind of the the
entire business is they just make
concentrates at this point? Exactly. So
that's my current cannabis business is
uh Denver DAB and we we basically are a
hydrocarbon extraction lab and we use
butane and propane mainly butane at
different concentrations depending on
what uh consistency we're trying to get
at the end. But we do live resins, live
batters, we do sugar wax, we do regular
wax. Um we've done cartridges in the
past and we'll uh probably have some
live resin cartridges in the future
again. But um yeah, we're just a
concentrate lab and we sell wholesale to
dispensaries across the state of
Colorado. And um and yeah, we uh love
what we do and uh I'm it's kind of
crazy. I I produce we produce
concentrates all day long, but I still
have to say flowers. flower is still my
favorite personally even though I I love
and give major props to concentrates and
connoisseurs of such but uh my personal
favorite still uh some very good flour
and you know the whole tactile part of
breaking it up and smelling it and
experiencing the bud and the plant and
the packing it into the bowl or loading
a cone or twisting a joint. I just I
very much still enjoy consuming cannabis
on a regular basis for sure. Yeah, I I
do as well. I um I prefer flour over
concentrates. Although I do love
concentrates. Um but like uh you know I
always it was really it was a a weird
experience the first time I used a
blowtorrch to heat up glass to smoke
some some concentrates and uh and so now
I just use like one of those puff codes
that's like the electric uh dab rigs
basically. Um, but other than that, I
just I enjoy vaporizing my flour because
I smoked too many cigarettes when I was
younger and smoking joints now just ends
up making me a little bit wheezy. Um,
but yeah, flour all the way. Yes, I I
very much enjoy it. Uh, I I do enjoy
concentrates from a pen like you're
suggesting as well. It's it's very nice.
Uh, especially, you know, when you're on
a lift going skiing, snowboarding, you
know, you're driving in the car, well,
you know, sitting at a park in the car
or something. It's just more handy to
have an apparatus like that as opposed
to dealing with the flower. So, there's
a time and a place for for all of these
methodologies. For sure. For sure. For
sure.
Um, let's see. So, so with uh it sounds
like you were a fan of hydroponics uh
throughout your entire growing career.
Did you ever uh dabble into any sort of
like living soil organics or anything
like that? Okay. So, I Yeah, that's a
good question. Um I have dabbled but I
have to you know I have to admit failure
when there's failure. So I was not able
to be a good I I tried to do the organic
soil growing route. Now or living soil
hadn't really caught on yet. This is
about 10 years ago and um clearly plenty
of people were doing living soil. Um but
in the cannabis world it hadn't really
taken hold yet and uh there wasn't that
much information about it. So I hadn't
really been turned on to it. didn't
really know of the incredible benefits
of the sustainability of it. It's
incredible how sustainable it is. I know
people currently that are using the same
pots 10, 15 cycles in just top dressing.
It's incredible what they're able to do
with this living soil. However, I was
not able to figure it out um at the
time. And like I said, it was 10 years
ago when I tried it. And I did more more
on the just standard organic soil route.
And my harvests were decent, but they
didn't touch the quality and the
quantity cuz frankly, I was into the
quantity as well back in the day. I was
making some money and and so I wasn't
able to really get the bang that I that
other people that I knew were able to
do. And I gave it a few tries. I gave it
four or five cycles worth. And I was
happy with the the quality and such. I I
was happy with the the cannabis I was
consuming from it, but it just didn't
make sense in the space I had. I could
literally grow about twice as much with
my hydro techniques that I had dialed
over the years. And so that being the
case, I went back to hydro and stayed
that way and have modified with organic
top dressings, even with hydro and uh
played around with a lot of different
methodologies within hydro. the organic
thing I I let go because of my inability
to be a very good organic grower. So my
specialty was in hydro and I just kind
of locked in with that. And when I do I
do uh enjoy organic bud here and there
and I get it from a couple of friends
that are masters at that living soil and
so I do get to indulge as well for sure.
you know, and it I think we are a little
bit uh lucky nowadays to have all these
different companies that have these um
built, you know, uh amended soilless
substrates that are geared exactly
towards a full cannabis cycle. You know,
you you you use this many gallons of the
soil, you water it, you never let it run
off, and you take it all the way from a
seedling to harvest in that soil and
you're good to go. Um whereas trying to
figure it out before you know like there
were very few products available 10
years ago like what maybe Fox Farm
forest or something like that that you
were able to try an organic grow in but
even that it had different salts in it.
It wasn't geared specifically towards
cannabis even though there was a little
bit of like a Fox Farm is kind of a
cannabis brand. uh it I can understand
how it would have been difficult and
even for myself I've grown organically a
few times but I always come back to
synthetic or not synthetic but
salt-based fertilizers because it is uh
you can you can change everything on a
dime. You can adjust on the fly. You
don't need to do any sort of soil
testing analysis that you know you you
might need like a degree in organic
chemistry to truly understand break down
and make uh a smart educated decision on
what your next inputs are going to be.
um and and inputs alone, you know,
there's the standardization of certain
salt-based nutrients, you know, like
mono potassium phosphate, calcium
nitrate, calcium chloride, uh all the
different sulfates that you can use, you
know, malibdum sulfate, uh manganese
sulfate, all these different things are
so standardized, they're so they're so
uniform that you can source them from
different areas and they're predictable,
right? Uh even if some of them have a
higher quality than another uh with less
impurities, less heavy metals, things
like that. Um but that all usually is
available through testing that that
information is there. But you know,
every batch of
uh fish hydraulicate might be slightly
different. Every batch of uh bat guano
or seabird guano, depending on where it
comes from, is going to be slightly
different. So it um there there's a
consistency with salts that I really
like as well. Um indeed. When you were
growing, did you think or did you see
that any of your techniques were
something that you didn't see other
people using but that you felt were uh
key to your success in the garden?
That's a good question. Um sure. There,
you know, some um one of the things I
use, you know those plant yo-yos? Have
you ever seen those things that are on a
spring? I probably got a few behind me.
Those were out a long time before. Right
on. So, those were out quite They're
come The original ones come from Holland
and they were brilliant. Um, when I
first saw them like 30 years ago, I was
like, "Wow, this is ingenious." And, you
know, they were sold for tomatoes, but
they weren't taunt enough to hold the
tomatoes. So, we knew what they were
really meant for. They're made for
cannabis for sure and being from
Holland. Um, but I never really saw
these in many grows. I saw them at the
grow store and I brought a few in and
then started bringing hundreds of them
in because they worked so very well. And
so that is the one thing that out of all
the grows I've had and set people up
with it. My grows look a little
different because instead of stakes and
many people or trellis, those are the
two main, you know, a trellis net or
people staking their plants up and their
coal is up. Um, this yo-yo system was a
system that seemed to differentiate my
grows from others. So, what I would do
is I would take, let's say you had a 4x8
tent and you've got the posts, the
vertical post of the 4x8 tent, you know,
going up. I would take a 10 gauge wire
um that was coated with rubber like a
wire you'd get on a spool at a hardware
store and run that wire around the
diameter perimeter of the of the tent.
Okay. On the outside of the poles. So
it's like a perimeter of wire like a
fence of wire wire fence. So I would do
one at about two feet two two feet off
the ground and then one at about 5t off
the ground and then one right in the
center under where the lights are like
right in the center. Okay. And so
basically it is a grid a the perimeter
of wire around the 4x8 would be where
all of those yo-yos would be attached.
And so the whole perimeter of the tent
on the inside would have hundreds of
these yo-yos just strung around up high
and down below. And so as you know in
cultivation
um to maximize your harvest, every place
in your tent that has light, you want to
have green there. You want to have a
leaf, a cola, part of the plant. You
don't want any light hitting the floor
essentially to have a maximized garden.
So these yo-yos I was able to basically
take from a early, you know, from early
on in my growing. I was able to
absolutely maximize every square inch of
light that I had in a grow by taking
these yo-yos and taking not cuz you know
yo-yos and and and stakes and trellis
are used for two reasons. They're used
for support so the plants just don't
drop down and fall to the floor. And
they're also used for straight up
manipulation. So, you're putting that
cola or what have you exactly where you
want it to be to maximize its light um
or its ability to get light. And so, the
yo-yos are the same thing. So, I'm able
to like hook the hook around the cola
and then look look at the the canopy and
go, "Okay, that's a perfect spot. That's
a spot where light was hitting the
floor. Now, it's the cola's right
there." And then I would clip the yo-yo
right there onto the wire and it's set.
And it's on a spring. And so, as it
grows, it doesn't have to be reattached.
I don't have to weave it under a trellis
again. I don't have to, you know, fix
something. One, it's kind of one and
done. I hook it on and since it's on a
spring and it grows, it just keeps
growing in that direction and it's set.
So, that that right there is probably
the way I maximize my my harvest
throughout my career is because of that
manipulation technique. Um, and another
thing that's very important that we kind
of talking about the legalization of it
or the illegality of it back in the day
is is Colorado was one of those states
that plant count mattered. It still
matters in in in in many in many ways.
You know, six plants you're able to grow
as, you know, recreational user, etc.
But count matters. And to what you were
saying earlier, you could grow six
massive plants and that technically
that's totally legal. It's six plants.
Um, and so I did that as just a person
that, you know, I'm not a big fan of
jail and getting into trouble. And so I
never wanted to even test those waters.
And so I always grew the fewest possible
plants in a given space as possible. So
in, you know, some people would have
like a sea of green and have like 50
plants in a 4x8. In a 4x8, I would have
no more than eight plants. No more than
eight plants. And so it's very important
that through that yoing yo-yo technique
or what have you that I maximize every
square inch of production space because
I only have eight plants to deal with.
And so it's very important to maximize
that. So CO2 is important. The yo-yos
and plant manipulation was very
important. Clipping leaves every two
weeks is very very very important. Um
keeping things clean um was very
important. I was just very anal because
every plant I had was so important to
produce because I only had a select
amount of plants trying to minimize my
plant count throughout my career. For
sure. When you say clipping leaves, do
you mean like removing the extra fan
leaves that are shading out flowering
sites or are you actually going through
and cutting off some of those extra
sugar leaves or the leaves that are more
uh close to the
flowers? I've seen both. Good question.
Um, primarily primarily fans and mids
and so I would I never clip sweet
leaves. Um, to me those are too
important. Um, and I don't want to shock
the plant. I have shocked plants before.
Different strains react differently to
leaf clippings and you have to just know
that as a grower. Um, or just test it
out yourself and figure it out. I grew
uh, in my career AK-47 was the was the
strain that I grew and made most of my
money and had most of my success from.
And I had the best AK uh AK-47 feno that
I had ever seen. I was lucky enough. And
I, you know, some of its skill, some of
it luck. I had a lot of luck, Nick, that
a getting that AK feno from Netherland,
Colorado, which was a little grow town
outside of Boulder, um changed the
course of my uh growing uh career. It
totally set me up. And so different
strains react differently to that leaf
pulling. Um and the AK didn't like it
very much. So the most I could do with
the AK was just a moderate major fan
leaf only the giant fans whereas a lot
of the strains today you can go in and
like you look at the jungle boys you
look at some of these guys these three
per guys two per guys they they are
stripping you know and it's part of
their protocol every two to 3 weeks they
go in like when they kick into bloom
they strip it completely two 3 weeks
later they strip it completely two to
three lers one more time and then it's
done um I I have done some of that Um
I'm just leerary because of my
experience with my AK. But but
absolutely um I don't mess with the
sweet leaf, but stripping those at very
very least stripping the fans
significantly helps the end product. The
tricom production, you know, that direct
sunlight seems to produce more tricoms.
Um and obviously bigger and better uh
swollen colas as well when you got that
direct light. For sure. Yeah, I I agree.
I you know I I use the uh leaf stripping
and as well as like a a day 21 prune uh
at the facility that I manage and we are
able to push numbers up really high. I
think um one of our most recent harvests
was my personal best and it should be
just over 3 lb um per 4x4 area. So we
were we were really pushing it as hard
as we could and a leaf strip was
definitely required you know not only
just for the light access to all the
flowers and the flowering sites but also
for environmental maintenance and air
circulation and all these things that
really help promote ripening and bud
development.
Um, so I mean you've seen a lot of
different aspects of the cultivation
space, you know, from home grower to
commercial grower to uh retail shop uh
owner and not only just doing it in one
space and in one community, but seeing
uh the trends across multiple
communities uh especially coming from
that retail sort of um that viewpoint.
And so, you know, with everything that
you have seen change in the industry
over the past, gosh, 30 plus years, what
are um some of the things that you would
that you think might be changing
continuously? Like where do you see the
market or the industry going? As well as
what are some of the things that you
would like to see change within the
industry?
Interesting. Well, you know,
trends-wise, some of the things I'm
seeing are just a continuing in
furthering automation. Um, like I I I
briefly mentioned before, the sensors
that can pick up the humidity in a
media, whether it's in your cocoa pot or
in your rock wall, and be able to send
you an alert on your phone, no matter
where you are, and let you know that
things are going to die soon because
they don't have enough water. That's
just brilliant. And I, you know, I was
screaming for that 20 years ago, but we
just didn't have the technology back
then to produce something like that. But
I think that um, you know, the margins,
the commercial market, which is really
pushing most of this, is the commercial
market is is it's capitalism and
capitalism means we, you know, the
people who own the owners want more and
more and more. Um, and that's just the
way capitalism is. And so, you know, a
harvest can be a great harvest, but the
next harvest, the capitalist is going to
want a little more. And that's just
unfortunately the world we live in. And
so, that being the case, we're we're in
this industry, we're striving for a
little more harvest every time, whether
it's so the technology is going to
increase in advance, all in the hopes of
getting better quality bud, better
quality medicine, but getting more of it
per square foot, per watt, per per
dollar spent by the owners of the
businesses. And so these technologies
from humidity sensing to environmental
controls that I said earlier that can be
you know drawn up on your on your
smartphone and you can turn a fan on off
uh manually. Of course there are going
to be on automated settings to to to
turn on and off themselves. But these I
think these things that are helping
people put less actual physical time
into it and take that burden off of us
and do it automatically I think are
going to continue to be pushed forward
in this industry. Um, so a lot more
automation. I think honestly computers
and robots frankly are going to continue
to push as well and cut people out of
the workforce unfortunately. Um, but you
know whether it's harvesting, you know,
I saw some apples being harvested by
drones the other day on online and it's
only a matter of time before this is
automated as well. as as anyone who's
worked in a commercial grow like
yourself, Nick. Golly, dude, the the
trimming. I mean, that's it's so
laborious, but we still don't have
badass trimmers yet. You know, they're
they're getting there and they're
getting better, but um that kind of
automation, I think, is going to save a
ridiculous amount of money, increase
margins significantly for the for these
companies. And so I see automation
because of in a capitalist society and
in in us wanting more and more uh that
that's where the demand is going to be
as far as just you know maximizing every
crop that much more and I think
automation is the only way to do that.
So I see that as being a huge thing and
and and conversely it takes it takes
away a lot of what we love about the
industry. You know we love the hands-on
part of this. That's what got you I'm
sure into it. That's what got me into
it. It's the hands-on, the watching it
every day and not just looking at my
phone and looking at data or looking at
a spreadsheet, but getting in there and
being part of the garden and part of and
watching it grow every day. And so
that's that makes me a little sad is
that with this amazing automation that
we have, we're taking a little bit of
the personal aspect out of it. Um, and
and as you know, the best way to keep a
plant healthy is to look at it every
day. You know, like we said, smelling
it. You can smell if something's wrong.
You can certainly see if something's
wrong. um you can see a bean popping out
or a or a male flower popping out. Um
you know because you're in there every
day and you're looking at it. If you're
if everything's automated, you're not
looking as
diligently, [__] falls through the
cracks, man. You know that powdery
mildew pops up and you don't see it
until it's 4 days too late and then
everything's got it. And so I, as much
as automation is badass, we still need
good master growers and and helpers to
be in those grows every day, getting
down on their knees, clipping those
lower leaves, looking at the stalks,
looking at the top of the rockal cubes
for the for the winged root aphids,
looking for the the the fungus mats. Um,
that that's how we find trouble. that's
how we prevent trouble and that's how we
modify and pivot to continually have
good gardens is because of the hands-on
aspect and being very involved. And so
that I'm a little afraid of the
automation side taking away of that. Um
but it's it's it's tricky because it
brings so much goodness to it, but we
don't want too much of it because we
still need to be involved every day to
avoid the other pitfalls. Yeah,
absolutely. It is definitely like two
sides of the same coin. And um you know
we we use a lot of automation at the
facility that I work at, but we uh we
always say that automation is not a
replacement for observation. And so you
really do need to make sure that you are
getting into the grow and confirming
with your own eyes what the data is
telling you. Um don't let the data lead
you, let it confirm what you're seeing.
Um so that is a huge point. I think that
that is very important. Um you know kind
of speaking along those same lines of
you know it's it's a huge pitfall to
allow yourself to only look at the data
and you know in some cases now to be
able to keep up with the market trends
it's almost a similar pitfall to not use
any data whatsoever. So uh you know in
the same sort of line of thought of
pitfalls in the industry what are some
of the ones that you are seeing new and
old growers face nowadays just different
pitfalls? Yeah, you know, um, a lot of
the same old ones I'm seeing, um, you
know, whether it's the bugs, you know,
the the bugs, the disease, you know, the
automation is helping these to thwart
these things, but they're still there.
You know, there's still humidity issues
and and it's hard to keep that in check,
especially in humid environments. Like I
I I can't imagine growing in Costa Rica
like like the amount of equipment I
would want to install day one before
even getting started. the hardcore
dehumidification that I never had to
really deal with in Colorado. Um the air
conditioning, um the, you know, the the
scopes that I would look at because the
million kind of bugs that live down
here. And so, so, you know, it seems to
be a lot of the same pitfalls. It's just
we have different tools to work with
them now, thankfully. Um you know,
spidermitites,
uh russet mites, and winged root aphids
are still three, in my opinion, biggest
pitfalls in the bug side. and then
powdery mildew and then uh betritis uh
bud rot are the two big things on the on
the pathogen side. Um, and then some,
you know, funk in the water. But we've
got cleanse now, you know, by Athena.
And that that that that uh chemical that
what is the name of that, Nick? I'm I'm
drawing a blank. Acid. It's uh it's HO.
Exactly. Exactly. One hydrogen, one
oxygen, one chlorine atom. And that
seems to have revolutionized many people
that I know's gardens right now because
they just added because, you know, a lot
of people went to feed to waste because
they couldn't deal with that
recirculating water and just
contaminating their whole garden cuz
everything was fe was recirculating up
until, you know, maybe 10 years ago and
then people started getting smart and
doing the feed to waste to eliminate
that potential. Well, with the cleanse,
with this hyperstatic acid, uh, you can
go for a month without changing a
reservoir. I know people who have 30-day
reservoirs that are as clean as ever.
Their tubes don't get clogged as much.
Um, and so there there's definitely some
products that I would have died for 20
years ago that are coming out now that
are helping with these uh minor
pitfalls, but it's just keeping things
clean. You know, like you said earlier,
clean, you know, cleaning up the bottom
leaves. It helps the airflow. It takes
out humidity and tent humidity is an
issue. It can get too high very quickly.
you take out some leaves, do a minor
leaf pool, even on the bottoms, your
humidity is going to jump up or excuse
me, jump down 5 percentage points
overnight. It's beautiful. So, keeping
the leaves off the bottom, don't give
the the bugs a place to to fester, to
grow. Um, be in your room every day,
every night. Look around. Your eyes are
your best friend. Your senses are your
best friend, your nose, your ears. Um,
but
cleanliness really from day one,
cleanliness is your number one friend
when it comes to a garden, even in a
organic soil garden. You know, just keep
it clean, keep, you know, just keep it
running right. Um, take notes when you
apply things, take notes of those days
when you, you know, notes are so good to
reference. I keep calendars on the wall.
I have calendars like with month after
month straight down so I can very easily
calculate things out whether it's
cloning dates or harvest dates. I write
notes. I, you know, I'm spraying sulfur
this day. I know to follow up 3 days
later with another hit. Um it's just I
just data is good. I love data. And so
you can't keep enough data. You can't
keep enough notes. And just keeping the
cleanest garden to me is is the most
important thing. Yeah, I agree. I you
know I think that it's really
interesting that we are um almost
rediscovering certain things and that
they're being implemented into
cultivation now. So like for in instance
with that hypocchlorous acid right it is
uh you know it it it goes through just a
process of electrolysis where you're
just adding something to plain water
like potassium chloride or sodium
chloride and then you're just applying
electricity to that water and through
that electricity you're stripping apart
the two different constituents and
recombining them into this now uh clean
non-toxic thick uh chlorine
uh liquid basically that you can apply
to your plants and it's not sodium
hypocchlorite like what you would find
in bleach where it's going to actually
cause issues with the plant by adding
these sodium atoms especially if you're
using uh potassium chloride as your base
and it's something that we had the
ability to do for you know over a
hundred years but we just never thought
to apply it in this manner and so when
you know I'm I really love the fact that
you are an old school grower but that
you are excited about these new products
because you see the usefulness in their
application where I I do feel as though
there are a lot of older growers who
tend to be stuck in their ways and
sometimes that you know there if it if
it's not broke don't fix it and I get
that but also always being open to these
new ideas new concepts and new
methodologies I feel like is it's how we
as humans continue to learn and grow and
and better ourselves. So, I really like
that you brought that up as Exactly. I I
really like that you brought that up as
something that you were excited about
seeing it come into use and seeing the
efficacy of it. It's a perfect example
of that.
Um, with all of this information that
you have as well, all this knowledge,
what would be some advice that you would
give to new growers? Well, new growers
have have so many wonderful resources.
Um, YouTube YouTube is so awesome. Um,
just just dive in. Give it a try. Um,
it's so safe now. You don't have to
worry about the legality of it. I mean,
depending on what state you're in, I
think there are what, 15 states still
that have draconian laws, but but it's
getting there. Every year, we're pushing
closer to total legalization in the
whole country. So, there's just so many
less worries. I'd say absolutely go for
it.
Um, I I would definitely use YouTube for
for for resources. There are just so
many videos, you know, from guys like me
that just have just love to help and
share information. There's there used to
be a lot of stuck up growers out there.
There really were a lot of jerks that
that didn't want to spread the love and
they were holding on to their little
secret. And the one thing good
about things going on in society now and
this cannabis movement and being so out
there is it's very open source now. And
I love that. I I want I don't want to
hold on to my I want to spread the love
and teach everyone that that needs or
wants to know it what I know and then
they can come back and teach me
something because I I I am I am only so
smart as I know how much I don't know.
Okay, I know I know a lot about
horiculture and about cannabis in
general, but I know there's a [__] ton I
don't know and I want to know more. And
so I have am open-minded enough to know
that there are not only new products
that can give me uh better results than
I've had before if I have an open mind
to try them, but there's also people
that maybe have been growing for only a
few years, but have had a different path
that can show me something that I
haven't experienced before. And so I
have a very open mind and I just want to
produce the best, tastiest, most
effective cannabis I can produce. Um and
and I know I'm not the best at it. No
one is the best at it. there's always
someone that knows more and so I have a
very open mind about that and so I think
that a beginning grower has so a
beginner grower has so many wonderful
resources but just to go ahead and just
do it don't put it off just give it a
try even one little plant um if you have
a friend with cutings I would suggest
maybe starting there cuz it's just so
easy to know you have a genetic and for
for those that don't know you know
clones are a genetic duplicate of the
host plant so if the person is having
good results with this one plant if you
take a clone from them or they give you
a rooted clone, preferably a rooted
clone you would get and put it in your
system, then the chances of success are
astronomically high. Um, as opposed to
starting with a seed and you have other
things, you know, sexing the seed and
even though it's probably a female, that
still could be a male and then yada yada
is the right fenos and writing the
different phenos and keeping a mom of
all those phenos in case which one is
the best. And just don't even deal with
that. Get a good cutting from a friend.
And if you're in a state that it's
legal, go to a store and even buy a
cutting if you need to. if you don't
have a friend that has one and start
that way and start with a little a
little system whether it's, you know,
soil, cocoa or hydroponic. All three are
great to start. Um, if you really want
it easiest, pop it in a thing of ocean
forest, fox farm soil, um, and just
watch it grow and just give it water.
You don't need to do anything else and
just watch it. That could be your first
fora into it because it really requires
nothing but water and a little sunlight
in your window sill. Um, but you know,
there's so many ways to take it and
advance it from there. Just like I said,
the the YouTube videos and the resources
out there are
I'm envious of those resources
considering what I had when I started.
So, I say just reach out there and and
but don't don't put it off. Dive in.
It's it's an amazing amazing venture. I
I agree wholeheartedly with that. Don't
don't put it off anymore. Just if you if
you have seeds, get that seed wet. If
you have a ability to get a clone, I
definitely agree. I suggest clones all
the way for a firsttime grower. They
make your life really easy right off the
bat. Um, well, Drew, that was this was
an amazing conversation and I think that
about wraps it up for some of the main
questions there, but I do always like to
ask a couple little wrap-up questions
just to kind of round out the whole
show. Sure, man. And, um, you've smoked
for a long time, so you probably have
experienced a lot of different strains
and cultivars. So, uh, since you are a
grower with this much experience, I'm
going to break this question up into two
parts. What was your favorite strain to
grow of all time? I I feel like I might
have uh a little inkling of of an idea
of what you might say considering what
you said earlier about the AK-47 being
sort of your bread and butter, but uh if
that's not it, I I am all for hearing
it. Um, and then what was your favorite
to smoke? Okay, very good questions. Um,
okay. Yes, you were right. The
AK-47 was so special. And let me just
say why. Um, for a grower it was, um,
giant armsized colas and as fat as my
forearm. And I'm a skinny dude, but I,
you know, still that's a huge cola. Um,
and this is back in the day where people
were very much into showing off the size
of their colas. And so having a cola
that big was a cool thing. Nowadays, no
was like, oh, all that stick weight and
stem weight. Nobody wants a cola that
big now. But back in the day, you know,
10, 20, even 30 years ago, that was like
people like were like when they saw a
cola like that. And it wasn't me. I I
have to give credit where credit's due.
It was a strain. I I was blessed with
the best one of the best genetics still
to this day I've ever gotten. But the
smell of that AK nick was what really
set it apart. It was one of those buds
that when you were at a party or at a
get together and you were in the corner
of the room and you whipped out your AK
nug, everybody did this and looked at
your corner like within seconds. It was
known. It was one of a kind. No other
plant smelled like it. Yes, Chronic
smelled like skunk, but AK had its own
such a unique smell that everybody knew
it and everybody wanted it cuz it was
the the nastiest, gassiest with a little
bit of fruit as well. Everybody loved
the AK. And so it it was it was props
being able to have that and and uh
getting that kind of recognition. And so
it was very weighty. I was growing back
in the day off
of 1000 watt lights. I was growing 2 lb
plus 2 1/2 lb of light all day long.
This is 20 years ago. Yeah. All day long
on that. Um, it cloned in 7 days, 8
days. Wow. Both in clone machines and in
1in rockwool with domes. Um, very uh uh
um mold resistant. It was bug resistant.
It was just it fired on all cylinders.
What can I say? And then finally, the
smoke of it was delightful. It was a
high It was a true hybrid. Mine I
guessed at around 50/50 based on my
effects or the effects on me. Um I could
sleep on it. It was good pain reliever.
Um it was incredibly tasty and so it was
just the best allaround for me. Um now
since then, you know, with all of these
boutique bougie strains coming out,
especially in Colorado, and I've got
some, you know, friends that that work
at Clone, which have amazing genetics
over at Clone Colorado. Um also at Free
World Genetics. Uh Sam and Austin who
run that are two amazing savants.
They're badass at what they do. Um love
their genetics as well. Um one of my
favorites was called Orange Cookie Chem
which was a free world genetic that was
absolutely delightful in white with
tricoms. Super tasty with that orangey
tangy kind of back tone. Absolutely
delicious. Medium yielder. So this is
strictly for flavor and effect. I
absolutely love that strain. And
um and let's see. I I think right now I
would have to say this this strain
called Fremac, which is actually another
one of the free world genetic strains.
Um that was it was kind of fired on all
cylinders, but it was very very stony,
big buds, dense buds, got a little rot
here and there if you didn't really
watch your humidity. You want to keep it
under 50 if you can. Um but just fired
on all cylinders. Easy. two, you know,
two pounds per light. If you were under
a thouie, um, or if you're with LED, you
know, you could get a pound off of a
600, you know, a pound and a half off a
600 watt, uh, maybe even 2 lb off a 630
W 4x4 LED light. Um, so an incredible
plant, but very, very stony, a little on
the indica side. I prefer a little on
the indica side because I'm looking for
a lot of pain relief. I have a a chronic
back, low back pain, and I've had
indicas usually help me a little more on
the back. So, I'd say the Freemac and
the AK were my two favorites. Um,
overall, I do like the diesels as well.
New York City and some Sour D. I'm still
a fan of those. Um, as well, but I love
trying new Bud. Someone has another
strain, I'd love to try it, especially
when I'm sober because I like to give a
a very good opinion on, you know, the
the taste, how it tickles my throat, how
it tickles my nose with the tarpine
effect, and then of course the the
effect 10 or 15 minutes later. I'd love
to check it out for sure. Is the is the
free mac sort of their version of the
the miracle alien cookies? Yes. Yes,
it's I believe it's the miracle alien
cookies mixed with their free world chem
I believe. Oh,
cool. Really solid base chem as well.
Yeah, that sounds awesome. And the and
the colas were very different. The much
bigger colas because as you know the uh
miracle alien cookies has very small
little nectar buds but they're small.
Um, but the free mac is is like three,
four, five times the size of colas than
the the Miracle alien cookies.
Delicious. Nice. Everything those guys
do, honestly, Nick, is great. If anybody
has a chance to hook up with Free World
Genetics, I highly recommend it. For
sure. Well, um, if, uh, if you know them
personally and you want to help me get
them on the show, I'd love to have them
and hear more about their story, too.
Um, dude, absolutely. I I guarantee it.
Yeah, we'll do it. Cool. Well, um I mean
the next question uh may have already
been answered, but uh feel free to just
run with it. Who is your favorite
breeder of all time? Man, you know, old
school DJ Short. Um I hate to keep
coming back to my boys, man. But Sam and
Austin, Free World Genetics are my
favorite. Um for sure. They've been
taking care of me for like 5 years, six
years now. Um and they're just really
cutting edge. Um they work with you
personally.
Um, I just really like their personal
touch to it. Like I, like I say, I'm
friends with both of them and so it's
not like on big some corporate big
corporate um thing, you know, like some
online company. I can really talk to
them on a personal level and tell them
what I'm looking for and they will sit
me down and say, "Hold on, let me put
some thought into that. Drew, let me
call you back in 30 minutes. Let me call
Austin and let you know see what he has
to say about it." So, honestly, I think
it's free world. Um, you know, I like
some of the old school. Like I say, DJ
Short did some amazing amazing things
for for a long time and was really an
innovator in the industry and so but I'd
like to say Sam and Austin with Free
World are my favorite guys just because
of what they're doing currently. Nice.
Yeah, we actually we did a show with DJ
Short and it was a great episode talking
about his blueberry and his flow and uh
um yeah, it would be great to get more
breeders on here to talk about their
strength. Uh yeah, so um I need to watch
that episode. Nick, you should. It was a
really good one. That was with our our
co-host, uh, Gabby Bronstein. He's, uh,
also known as Gabby Staten Island. He's
the guy that brought the, uh, the Sour
Diesel out from the the East Coast to
the West Coast. And, uh, it was a really
fun episode. Sick. And so, let's see,
last question then, just to wrap it up.
What is your most memorable cannabis
related experience?
Hm. Cambers related
[Music]
experience. You know, probably my first
time to Red Rocks Amphitheater and going
to see a show. Um, I think it was Blues
Traveler back maybe 20 years ago. They
used to come to Red Rocks every 4th of
July. And I don't know if everybody
knows what Red Rocks is, but it's like
the most badass amphitheater in the
world maybe, but in the country for
sure. It's set between these two massive
red sandstone rocks shooting out of the
earth overlooking the city of Denver
with this mountain range in front of it
as well. Um, and you're rocking with
like 8,000 like-minded amazing people.
And the the moon July 4th every year
rises out of the horizon. And you know
the moon when it's coming up is always
bigger looking. It's insane. And you see
this glow and everybody in the stand
start to kind of scream while they're
watching the glow before the movie even
comes up. And I got goosebumps even
talking about this right now. And we've
got some, you know, killer flower. I'm
sure it was AK back in the day. It was
20 years ago. I had a fat bowl of AK if
not a few joints going around and
spreading the love with everybody around
us. And everybody's starting to scream
as this the moon is rising and it's full
and uh and the music's playing and Blues
Traveler was just popping back then too.
They're at the top, you know, everybody
was grooving to them and it was just and
everybody's like hugging everybody and
passing around joints and like I say, I
got goosebumps right now thinking about
it. But that was quite possibly the best
cannabis related experience sharing the
cannabis with that I grew with people
around me, complimenting me, you know,
always a little pat on the back. You
know, I don't like to be too egoistic
about this, but it it was it was
beautiful and the sharing and everybody
hugging and the moon rising and the
music and the red rocks and me being
like my first few years living in
Colorado after moving from Florida. It
was a moment of zen and cannabis only
helped that become that. You know,
without the cannabis, it would have been
good, but it was just it brought
everything together. Amazing. That
sounds like an epic experience. Um, I'm
sure a lot of people have similar
experiences, whether it be with music or
um, some sort of event or gathering
where they're passing around some flower
that they've grown and the the vibe is
already nice and high and and positive
and uplifting and then you're just
sharing that extra experience. You know,
I don't it is a little bit egotistic,
but it's always so great to get a pat on
your back for the flower that you that
you grew that everyone else is enjoying.
It's a really great experience. So, I
wholeheartedly can understand how that
feels. Um, well, man, Drew, this has
been a great conversation. Thank you so
much for joining me today. I'm going to
have to reach out to Jared and thank him
for pointing you in my direction or me
in your direction. Um, I think that, you
know, we've touched on some really great
subjects today, just like general grow
knowledge, IPM knowledge, your
experience and your journey through this
this uh this world uh as a as a cannabis
person, right? Uh it it's a fun this was
a really fun conversation. So, thank you
so much. Um, I I really always like to
end these episodes by reminding people
that the reason why we have these
conversations is because it's so
important to get this information out
there to people. Uh, just to have a real
conversation, to talk about cannabis and
how we all experience it as both growers
and consumers. And getting that
information out there to people is the
way we grow. And that's uh, you know,
for the names sake of the podcast. So
again, thank you so much for joining me
here today. I really appreciate your
time and your knowledge. Nick, it was a
pleasure. I love the name of your
podcast. I think it's beautiful. Um it's
it's touching. It means a lot. And that
is how how we progress and move forward
is to talk about the way we grow and uh
everybody has a little bit different
take and and us sharing our stories is
how we progress this movement and how we
push it forward. So, it was a pleasure
and an honor to be on your show and I'm
so glad Jared introduced us and uh and
uh I'm going to be diving into all your
other episodes and checking them out
right away. So, look forward to Well,
thank you. Thanks everybody.
[Music]