[Music]
hello and welcome to another episode of
The Way We Grow podcast today our guest
is at westore peace on Instagram he is
an outdoor organic hom grower I am your
host Nick
wolf so Weston how's it going um it's
going it's going good awesome excited to
be on here yeah I mean you're one of the
uh the most prolific outdoor home
Growers that I know of on the subreddit
that we are both moderators of the uh
rcraft marijuana subreddit and uh I feel
like you always take a lot of time and
effort to put into your outdoor crop
each year um but you know how's life
going in the offseason in the offseason
it's um me arguing myself about tripping
and uh starting to think about what
changes I want to make next year and how
I got a couple months and if I do want
to make changes you know what I'm going
to do and how I'm going to implement it
but normally it's um just trimming and
kind
of brainstorming about what's going to
happen next year for sure yeah I feel
that I feel like it's like this time of
year is always the time of year that at
like a commercial level we are looking
at genetic acquisition and um starting
to plot out
where we're going to plant the different
genetics based on their flowering time
sometimes we have the ability to map it
out based on their flower initiation
because we'll have some that'll start
you know two to up to four or five weeks
before the rest um and they still only
need 65 to 70 days of flow so that makes
sense too because you don't want to be
running uh all around the garden that
like all the stuff that's going finish
early is here the next and the next so
you don't have people scrambling around
them makes sense yep absolutely um so uh
what in in your garden this year
upcoming what what do you have planned
is there anything that you've already
started to look into I have been as you
know on the craft group hitting up all
of the grommies on there trying to start
doing genetics from the craft group
solely would be is is my main goal
that's cool cuz normally I buy clones
and I have a reputable source and I do
appreciate them and like them but it
would be cool to start putting up for of
growing you know things from giant
breeders start hitting up all the homies
and started growing you know within the
group I think that's going to that's a
good idea and I I'm kind of soak about
doing it uh how many how many times have
you ran from seed outside versus from
clone it do you feel as though it's like
a pretty even split or no not even I
would rather do
clones just because you know what you're
getting and every plant's going to be
the same so season got it my garden now
I'm on season I just finished season 4
so season 3 I did all seeds except for
maybe two or three plants and I was
super stoked with some of them and I was
less stoked with some of the other ones
and also the variation and finishing
time I'd rather have two or three that I
know are going to finish all at the same
time rather than having you know 15
different plants that are skewed across
the the finishing lines and like also
you get into where like you notice
certain plants have specific needs well
I'm not here all I'm not here all the
time and I have to have something that I
can kind of get into a routine on if I
can figure out two plants you know
fairly quickly in the season it's easier
than me trying to play it by year on 15
different you know gen you know 15
different splits for sure I mean
especially cuz um for all those
listeners that don't know uh you you use
uh raised pots correct like uh fabric
pots for your for your plants so if you
on Reddit I have a bunch of pictures but
I do I use raised pots I use fabric pots
which is pretty standard I do have a
grapple base under each one of them and
this last year I moved up to 200 gallon
pots but yes I used I used raised pots
off the ground and I have a buffer
between the between the ground soil and
the bottom of the pot I found that in
rainy Seasons that your pot touches the
ground especially if you live somewhere
where water is going to be running down
like the way our property is laid out it
will run off the hill and come down and
run through the garden that they will
just be soaking water up if it rains for
a week you know even lightly the ground
gets wet and then they're constantly
Wicky moisture so that kills your
ability to water very much cuz you got
to keep the top kind of wet but then you
can't feed and you can't like you want
to do something the pot's already
saturated and you got to you can't it
kind of slows your ability to make a
move that makes sense that's a that's a
cool application of using gravel for
like a almost like a raised water table
um where you're getting it outside of
the zone of uh the flooding that's
coming down through your property there
um you know you live and you see it a
couple years and you make you know had
to you know kind of find tun it you see
what you see I didn't know the first
year that that was going to happen and
then you see it and then by then I
wanted to run the life of my last plots
out in soil and then so when I moved up
and switched then I went and did went
ahead and made those changes nice well I
want to come back to your growing style
but I I want to find out first in your
growing Journey um what were some of the
first plants that you ever grew whether
it be cannabis or otherwise um you know
we've had some people on here where
Cactus was their first plant that their
grandma gave them or something and then
some people that never grew even a
vegetable before they started growing
cannabis and then they started venturing
into the world of other gardening and uh
applications of the knowledge that
they've gained from growing cannabis so
uh for you what was what was your first
experience growing any type of plant my
first experienc in growing was in
Missouri I had a buddy who was growing
indoor and needed to move it somewhere
um due to some circumstances that were
out favorable
and so I took them in and started
growing them and then I real I didn't
let me phrase this how I was going to
say it realized how complicated it was
but also how interesting it was at the
same time and that's really really I've
taken what knowledge I have from
Cannabis and moved it outwards because I
really didn't wasn't into like very much
agriculture before that any house plants
or anything oh wow that's pretty cool
you know it's like I said it's kind of a
split 50/50 of people that started you
know oh Grandma had a vegetable garden
and I helped her out with it or I had no
care for vegetables or other gardening
and then cannabis was my gateway drug
into gardening so um it has the power to
do that you know it it definitely does
um well that's really cool to hear uh
what what do you like to garden now
other than cannabis is there anything
else that you have uh in your garden cuz
I know you have a pretty big sort of
garden space I have we have aelas my
wife has all the all the stuff around
the house I don't we have mint and Rose
and lemon balm and the thing that I
appreciate the most is she grows uh
angel wing Bonas and that is one of my
favorite plant those grows and the way
it flowers is there's it's something
special about that one but she does she
grows uh angel wing Bonas and I uh I put
in the compost tea and help uh keep them
going nice nice um well let's let's go
and touch back then on um some of your
first cannabis growing Adventures I
guess uh so it sounds like your first
experience was um almost put like in an
emergency situation where you helping a
friend out by taking plants from a
non-ideal situation putting them in a
situation where you could help them out
um what did you learn from that how did
you go about uh deciding how you how you
were going to continue to grow these
plants and did you get to a successful
Harvest yes I took them when they were
just in flow and I brought them over and
this probably wasn't a very good
experience to is to bring up but it
really got my uh I mean as small as it
was got my feet wet I think it was about
12 plants but I brought them from his
house over to mine and we got them to
flour and we got them to harvest and we
got them Pro you know got them dried and
that was kind of what sparked me into it
and then as far as my first big
adventure was deciding to move out of
Missouri and move to California and just
be like you know here we
go
cool um so once you once you kind of
took that step from Missouri to
California it it sounds like was uh like
cannabis cultivation in your mind was
that something that you were kind of
driven by in any way oh
100% 100% cuz you know I don't know if
you've ever lived in the midwest but I
want to say for like 2012 I mean the
amount of decent weed you could get was
okay but it's kind of perplexing when
you know how things work on the you know
on the West Coast to see like trash run
like to see garbage come in there and
you're like how does like how does this
product make it to the End Market like
there's no you know no reason and then I
kind of got I wanted to move somewhere
and I was picking Colorado or California
and I had came out to trim Camp one year
at a buddy's house and then me and my
wife my girlfriend at the time my wife
now I was like we're moving to
California and she was like well you're
okay with it and I was like you let's do
it and I kind of moved out here didn't
really have anywhere to live when I got
out of here I got in contact with my
friend and then just started working for
him when I got here cool like at a at at
a cannabis farm or something or yeah had
a farm cool how was your experience with
the the Cannabis Farms like uh in terms
of a commercial cultivation um operation
oh there's the good and there's the
really bad there's the well back then
there was the there was the good and
there was the atrocious and it depended
on where you went you could see things
that you didn't want to see or you know
as far as just talking about growing
like people spraying you know Avid and
floride or doing whatever they can to
compensate for their lack of skill to
give a product to the End Market you
know without far any consequences or not
thinking about anything outside of you
know out of profit and then you see
people who cared about it and you really
kind of see the difference in Growers
when you travel around and see the
different Farms cuz it's there's a stark
difference or was a stark difference for
The Growers that are still
around for sure did you only um have
that one commercial experience with your
friend that you worked with or did you
um it sounds like you were looking at
other farms at least by their practices
did you have an opportunity to work with
any of them oh yeah so I came out and I
worked with my buddy the first and the
second year and then I got hired on to a
big farm up in Lake County California
and so it was 70 Acres total 2 35 acre
plots on the side of a mountain so um
old school black market
farm and there were tiered into the side
of this mountain were 5x five by five
poles and so all teered down what do you
want to call it all cut out of the
mountain for these holes and they were
just I don't know like 400 gallons of
dirt in each hole or more and so I
started doing that um and that ended in
a raid which wasn't very fun um but
after that I worked green houses I
worked for another farmer and then in
between getting growing jobs I would go
around and do peace meal work at other
Farms so I mean I'll probably work at
you know 15 16 different places okay um
are there are there any experiences that
you had while working at those places
that stand out that you'd feel
comfortable talking about just to kind
of spread a little bit of the
experiential
knowledge well that's a vast question
like what what kind of experiences good
experiences bad like I experiences or
like inspirational or kind of like what
got me going well let's let's take it
from the route of um through your
experience uh working at all these
different facilities at all these
different Farms what did you pick up
that you carried with you and what were
things that you knew you needed to you
needed to avoid when um having your own
grow um avoiding laziness cuz what a lot
of the farmers well cuz there was so
much money into it back in the day is
that someone would own a proper and they
wouldn't necessarily they would know how
to grow but they would be as hands off
as they could with it and the lack of
atten attentiveness is a huge thing like
trying to automate your outdoor grow is
I don't want to say it's lazy I mean
there's obviously perks to it but if
you're not an attentive grower you need
to be in the if you're not in the garden
you don't know what's going on like I
don't care how many people you hire like
if you're the one in charge of it and
you're not there it's not going to go
well 100% going to fail you know if you
try to subc trct your job to somebody
else who has less experience than you it
always turns out bad and so that's like
kind of what you learn is like if you
want this to go from the start to the
Finish as well as it can like you're you
can't go on vacation you can maybe take
two days three days off at the most like
I mean but you need to be there and you
need to be in the garden every other day
hands down that's like the that's what
you know people who aren't into growing
and start growing outdoor it's not a
hands-off thing by any means I mean
there's lots of watching and sitting and
watching but there's also a purpose to
that too and that's like you need to
know when you might have a bug infection
start or infestation starting or you
need to know hey these things look like
they're getting underwater Because by
the next morning they look you know like
there's a lot of what a lot of what you
are going to need to know about the
plants is just going to be staring at
them if it's it sounds stupid but when
you start doing it you're going to
realize that I mean like go sit out
there for an hour in the morning and at
night and in the mid afternoon and watch
the differences and you know start
tracking how they're
reacting right definitely like picking
up on the trends so that you can apply
the proper approach whether it be
through like an IPM practice or a
nutrient application especially if
you're growing in um some sort of uh
living soil situation or something where
you're using the biology to make the
nutrients readily available you have to
really be almost ahead of the curve on
that where you you can't be like
reactory you have to be proactive about
it and that takes a lot of attention
yeah because I mean 90 5% of what you're
going to use organically is not water
soluble so if you see a problem you
you're already late you're late to the
game by the time you you pick up on it
right and that's where you kind of got
to learn what to do ahead of time
because by the time you figure out you
did something wrong now you've spent a
week trying to correct that but you were
already a week behind yeah absolutely
couldn't agree more it's hard to explain
that to people it's like by the time you
see the problem you you're already late
to the game you're already late to the
party for sure as opposed to like
Hydroponics where you could just just
have like missed a couple of phing for a
day or two and it's going to go
catastrophic you're going to see a lot
of issues pop up from that and
then both of them kind of have their
positives and and negatives and I I
think that you know that is definitely a
conversation for another day but it's so
fascinating to hear
um I I I do love Organics when you like
use the analogy of a battery where the
the bigger the battery the more like run
time you have without having to worry
too much about it um so you know I kind
of want to get back into how you're
growing now and how you developed your
growing style and so you kind of told us
about your negative experience with this
these different cultivation uh jobs that
you had um what were some of the things
that you picked up from these different
jobs that you took with you and either
uh tried to apply
to uh quent cultivation experiences or
what you still keep in your tool belt
that you're using today well and that's
yes I love that question because a lot
of the negative experiences are learning
what not to do working in other peaceful
places and a good thing about that is
you get to see a wide array of people
trying different things and seeing what
works and what doesn't work without
having to experience them yourself
because with outdoor growing you get one
shot a year so the ability to rerun
something over and over and figure out
what's going on what works and what
doesn't work could take a decade you
know like because you can you're not
doing five six runs a year and you're
like okay that works that doesn't work
that doesn't work but what I did pick up
is as far as outdoor growing goes I
really don't like synthetics or
non-organic food sources I don't feel
like they perform as well just from what
I've seen and I like indoors completely
different story but Outdoors you if you
you compost tea any day 100% of the time
my money's on it so as far as what I've
learned that works is
compost teas figuring out your watering
and then as far as food sources going
just using a good multi-purpose food in
the beginning and then kind of playing
it with some top dresses by ear
throughout the year cuz your compost tea
if you have a good compost te is going
to provide a lot of nutrition because
you don't need a you don't need a you're
not pumping them you don't need a lot of
nutrition you just need something
consistent and you need a ability for
the soil to unlock what food is already
in there and that's what a compost te
does absolutely what's uh what's your
typical go-to compost tea um if you're
just applying something throughout the
year I do
about four eight cups four to eight cups
of worm castings four cups of compost
and the worm castings and the type of
compost you get are going to make a
night and day difference if you get some
compost from the grow store it has
sticks and twigs and it looks like it's
meant for you know mulch for someone
like flower bed it's not going to works
so you need a high compost or a high
high quality compost and I mean there's
a couple different you can use like
there's the C compost from organ there's
the Malibu blend which I really don't
like cuz it comes from it's steer manure
and there's like there can be bugs and
stuff in it I've learned that over the
years to avoid that but basically Earth
Thor castings
compost telt meal alphalpha meal maybe a
little bit of humic
acid uh maybe a little bit of azomite
and then just black strap molasses or
just molasses you can get a grow store
and and do you do like uh aeration for
it or do you do like just a quick mix no
do an airra and you're going to run it
about 24 hours and doing outdoor
temperature is a big thing so you never
want to start it in the morning you
start it in the morning and it sits in
the sun all day you can like try to
cover it with light but the temperature
is really going to play into it so you
want to start it at night run it all
night check it in the morning probably
run it the rest of the day and by the
next morning it's going to be it's it's
going to be popping off and you'll see
the foam and you'll see all the uh CO2
coming out of it and that's how you know
you're where you want to be cool that's
pretty cool um so as you've kind as you
were learning all these different sort
of methods and uh finding that you know
compost te's and the applications of
different composts and worm castings and
stuff um are extremely beneficial what
what did you start to uh develop in
terms of your other top dressing
practices or other growing practices
that you're still using
today um thinning out the plants um I
don't you've seen outdoor plants a lot
of people don't know if you have a a
plant that's 10 ft tall I mean you're
going to say from the stock out at least
40% of that needs to be cleaned out
because you're not going to get any
Light breaking through there and so what
you learn is if you leave all of that on
there it's going to low kill the size of
your buds and also create a place for
mold so you really want to worry about
air flow that's another good one
um keeping your plants spread apart not
having them grow into each other is
going to stop bugs from
spreading um I've seen Gardens get
ravished by broad mites I mean but if
you have everything right next to each
other you're never like you're you're
not going to stand a chance because
they're going to spread too
quick for sure yeah I am we we typically
will grow in row but it it is like a
much larger production what what I'm
doing at like the commercial facility
versus what you're doing at at your home
and I I love how you have your different
beds sort of separated out and
um how how you have the ability to kind
of address each plant's needs in a very
holistic approach of of applying a meal
of this or you know
uh this that or the other thing um in an
organic form um what what have been some
of your recent uh like let let's let's
ask this in a two-part question so um in
terms of what has worked really well for
you recently in the garden what would
some of those things be and what would
also be some things that haven't very
worked very well for you in the garden
recently um sort of the the pros and the
yeah okay uh worked very well since I
moved this spot not worrying about the
height or the size of the plant I found
that over the last couple years that the
amount of so you have is going to
correlate with how much bud you're going
to get off the plant regardless of the
size of the plant so trying to plant
early to get larger plants generally
isn't going to yield anything more than
you planning two weeks later and having
a smaller but a fatter plant which is a
good thing to know I don't think a lot
of people realize that cuz if you see it
you know I had one from seed last year
that was 12T tall all it did was create
a headache a lot of plant to work on and
got the same thing that a plant that was
you know 6 to 7t tall would have had on
it sure I guess training and not trying
to shoot for the largest plant
competition is a really you know is a
really good one cuz you with like when
it comes to working on them and not
having a limited amount of time to do
that is you don't want to have to be
trucking a ladder around or you know if
you can't see the tops of the buds you
don't know if a caterpillar got in or
like you create this scenario where
you're not gaining anything but but a
lot more work to get the same end result
and I I don't think a lot of people
realize that too with I mean you can get
oud and noed by a big plant and they are
very cool but when you're the one taking
care of it that is it's not necessarily
very cool no and then also it it it
feels like a lot of the uh especially in
an organic scenario a lot of the uh
productivity potential for each plant is
heavily dependent upon the root space of
that plant and so if you're and yeah
right and so if you're growing in a in a
limited root space say like a raised a
raised pot or a raised bed of some kind
or you're planting them uh in a row or
something else where they are are then
sort of budding up on each other so they
only have a specific square footage per
plant that they have like sole dominance
over versus the other plants then coming
in and The Roots interchanging so they
only have a certain amount that they can
work with and so yeah if you're going to
get a bigger plant then sure you're
going to have a bigger biomass but all
that bigger biomass is taking energy
away from what could be flower sight
production um 100% I mean I even see
this in indoor too like smaller plants
usually produce the Daner buds uh they
can just put a lot more effort into it
especially when you're talking about
similar pot sizes um you know growing up
you were going to have a three
four-footer next to a two-footer and the
same amount of pot with the same amount
of roots you're going to have have an
yes it's going to focus more energy into
production for sure 100% it might not be
the like comparable yields like you
might get more yield out of the three or
four footer next to the two-footer um
but the each individual flower might
have a little little bit more appeal to
it you know it might have a better um
genetic expression or
morphology uh sometimes those bigger
plants when you grow too many Bud sites
on them the flowers seem to lose a
little bit of that luster that would be
on something that is a more manicured
plant that has fewer Bud sites as as it
relates to the root size yeah and I
think that like with outdoor too and
especially with Organic because you're
not able to like you're not able to pump
it like there's only so much you can do
to feed it right you can do a compost
tap which is going to start pre you know
creating a bioavailable nutrient but not
necessarily in a large amount that you
want to really keep an eye on your soil
size to your plant size cuz as above so
below like you don't want your plant
five times bigger than the pot I mean
you want to have it maybe you know your
your flowering plant two to three times
bigger than your like the soil area
width and height wise because you're
going to run into that we're going to
get string air buds like you can have as
many Bud sights on it as you want but if
it doesn't have you know you can have a
Cadillac but if you put a four-cylinder
in there it's not going to be like you
got to keep everything you got to keep
everything balanced you know you can't
have a giant plant with no soil and no
food no ability to feed it uh right so
you got to kind of keep that in mind it
almost seems like oversizing the pot to
the plant size uh tends to provide the
longest runway for what's available and
so the plant can just it can do the the
best that it can do in the environment
without being limited by something like
a the root size or something like that
100% And then I I don't think you know I
don't know that a lot of people think
this but like if you're organic growing
and I don't know how analogy put this
you're like the pit crew at NASCAR
you're not the race car driver like
you're there trying to make sure
everything's ready for when it wants to
use it you're not the one you know
putting the gas on steering the wheel
you're just trying to be there and
you're trying to give the plant
everything it needs so it can do what it
want wants to do but like if you try to
take the range too much that's when
you're going to go off the rails cuz
it's only going to do what it wants to
do you know and like you need to be
there and make sure that has what it
needs but it's like you're not really
steering the car you're just kinding to
making sure it's it's fueled for sure
and even even in that same analogy of
like a race car right you're you're not
trying to run the fuel to empty you're
going to try and fill it up before it
gets too low because you don't want to
throw that race car off balance by
having a a a weight increase and
decrease that's going to
sort of like make that battery of the
root Zone overcharged or undercharged
you want to kind of keep it at this nice
level so that it it it has the buffet to
eat from without ever needing to feel
like it needs to wait for that Buffet to
get refilled oh yeah 100 well that plays
in the pH too because if you if you
don't keep everything as far as being
able to control pH in a pot outdoor you
you can't all you can do is do
everything right so that it has what it
so it doesn't go out of balance because
I mean if you overfeed over compost T
put too much you can go too acidic or if
you want to over amend with like azomite
or you want to use like a a silica Rock
based product you're going to you're
going to keep you got to pick you got to
kind of keep giving it in the middle
ground so it has what it needs or it
will it will go out of pH which is it
happens rarely but when it does like
they're you know you're kind of you shot
your foot there you're done yeah I agree
it it is it is one of those things where
is a boat so like it's hard to over
steer it but if you do over steer it
it's really hard to correct it
um so little little tiny tweaks here and
there always seem to work the best as
opposed to these giant fluctuations in
um additions or subtractions to what's
there and available for the plant um so
I want to ask in your current setup
since you did just restart into larger
did you say 200 gallon pots I went from
150 to 200 yes okay so did you restart
that all from scratch did you do a fresh
uh mix of new potting mix and substrate
or did you use older
substrate no I went with new substrate
um okay what's your ideal mix like if
you know how about you run us through
what you did to prepare those 200-gallon
beds so that anybody that's thinking
about growing some large outdoor plants
has an idea of what it takes to get one
of those
started well it depend so uh your soil
that you're going to want to use is
really going to be kind of dependent on
your growing style and a thing to not
get carried away with if you were
starting from scratch is you don't need
a heavily fed soil you don't need a hot
soil you don't need something with you
know that's loaded up with every single
Amendment on the earth on it you want
something very simple you want perite
heat
moth um
pH balance you want a buffer in there
and maybe a very light food and then you
can that allows you to mend it yourself
because the first year I got soil I got
you know it was basically like a grow
Shop's version of like Fox Farm or
something but they had loaded it out it
had every Amendment like you stick your
hand in the bag and it would burn your
hand like it was hot like there was a
lot going on there and what that kind of
kills your ability to do is do anything
else CU it's already been done like if
you were trying to make a change like
you already everything's under the sun's
already in there you can't do anything
with it which doesn't mean it's bad it
means you're going to want run water
you're going to run a light tea that's
about as far as you're going to go with
it what I like to do now is get a more
basic soil without a lot of food I found
that downto Earth biofish is a very very
good Amendment for the beginning so I'll
amend per bag with biofish and make sure
it's really well mixed in there and then
I will pre-water all the pots and try to
keep them wet for a week or two before
I'm going to plant in there to like
start the biological process in there
get everything alive get everything
working and then you want to check to
make sure your soil's not hot cuz if
your soil's hot you're going to burn
your plants and that's like one thing
that no one ever teaches you like hot
soil is literally Outdoors it's going to
be hot like you're going to put your
hand in there and it's going to be steam
coming out of it you want to kind of
kick off the biological process and let
that work its way through a little bit
before you're going to plant your plants
in there so it's it's like almost making
a fresh uh super soil or a living soil
of sorts where you're taking um your uh
paracity uh um fraction of the media
like your perlite or your pmus or uh
volcanic rock or anything like that then
your substrate Side pet Moss uh um cocoa
quar anything like that and then your um
biological side which is also kind of a
substrate side where it's your uh
compost adding all those together then
adding your sort of nitrogen potassium
phosphorus calcium magnesium all those
different macros and micros mixing those
all together and all of a sudden you
have all this biological activity and
that biological activity is pushing off
a bunch of heat and you want to wait for
that biological activity to kind of slow
down because you're right it it just not
only is it like hot in terms of the
chemical Avail or the nutrient
availability is going to be so high that
the plant's going to be burnt through
the osmotic stress of the electrical
conductivity of everything that falls
into solution while the biology is that
active but also the actual thermophilic
composting that's occurring that's going
to overheat the root Zone and cause uh
hypothermia to the roots and actually
cause uh death and Decay translated that
way better than what I was saying but
yes 100% it's like that's when you hear
hot soil everybody thinks nutrients well
it like out hot soil is literally
temperature hot soil and even if it will
burn it will kill the plant just bace
cuz I mean it could be like we look at
the summer here it's like 70 but if you
stick your hand in there and it's 95
degre you put a plant there it's done
yeah absolutely I mean a 95 degree root
zone is not great especially when you're
going from 60 to 95 degre that's like
maybe you could slowly get up to 95
degrees and hold it for a few days if
you have available water but definitely
not if it's just from one to the n yeah
yeah like I mean it can handle higher
temperatures in the summer like this
summer it was 112 for a week straight
and the plants were definitely they were
not having it but they you know they H
through but if you did that to a plant
it would you know it'd be game over it
it's also one of the reasons why you
have to turn thermophilic compost
because um it'll combust if you have it
at the like perfect level of dryness to
wetness ratio and you have the just the
you know right amount of enzymes in
there the outside temperature and
humidity aren't uh you know
disadvantageous for causing a fire to
start it'll just spontaneously combust
and I have never seen at videos now I my
my dad had compost in our backyard and
it caught on fire one year and he had to
spray it down with a hose um it was
crazy I I didn't know it could happen
either until I saw but now I'm always
very cautious about making thermophilic
compost the power of the microb yeah
that that fact that they can get that
hot all the way up to the point of
combustion and still be active yeah
that's insane you know it it makes me
think of those uh like the extremophiles
that live near the thermal vents in the
bottom of the ocean that you know it's
like oh where the water would boil if it
could but it's under so Lally can be
higher than boiling water temperatures
yeah right yeah two 300 water and these
crabs and Crustaceans and worms and
stuff are living and they're fine with
it it's nature is crazy and you know
it's it it's really cool to know that
there are these extreme differences
between something that does use this
biologically
active substrate versus a
non-biologically active substrate in
like Hydroponics and you can achieve
really great results with both and the
interactions between the rizosphere and
the substrate and the nutrients that are
either being produced biologically or
being introduced through the nutrient
water
package the reaction with the roots is
also super different too like the root
exites that are produced in an organic
media to help attract the specific
biology that's going to help Cate the
specific nutrients to make them
available there's something really cool
about that I mean how long did that
process take to develop nature you know
I mean it's you know that's what kind of
why I don't doubt it either cuz I mean
it for millions of years this has worked
and like it's like the whole thing is
already
organized yep it's like the um uh soil
food web that uh Dr laningham will uh
preach through her different books and
and classes and stuff it it makes a lot
of sense that you have these different
processes that have developed over time
to help cycle and process phosphorus and
nitrogen and potassium
and carbon and all these different
things that you
can like actually now put through that
scientific lens and and explain uh where
it's but it's still all those
interactions together are almost harder
to explain as a whole rather than the
each individual processes oh well you
yeah because you look at one part of it
and it's like okay so the plant is going
to you know put carbohydrates into the
soil to attract something you're like oh
that makes sense well then it also does
20 other things and there's sugar
there's sugar it produces out through
the um stamata to keep plant to keep
bugs away that'll kill like it's like
you start looking at all of it you're
like this is very well orchestrated it
is it is um so back to you building your
your current setup so when you were
building these beds I remember you said
that you had uh a rock layer at the
bottom did you layer the pots in any
other ways and and did you add anything
else like either on top of the substrate
or within the substrate um to kind of
help with a specific style that you were
going for uh yeah so this year which I
normally don't do and I had kind of goes
back in your questions of things that
have mixed results was doing a top a top
dress layer of you know here remember I
have to look at the gra but Clover and
some other grasses and some legum some
type of peas to keep the Sun from
beating down on the soil so a lot of the
problem with outdoor growing is that
you're going to have a large pot and
you're going to have it dry from the
bottom up and the top down at the same
time and leave a section in the center
as it's using the water and as the sun's
evaporating the water you're going to
end up with you know a dry bottom of
your pot and a dry top of your pot and a
wet Center of your pot which is going to
mean you're going to overwater the
center and to get the bottom wet you're
going to have to really overwater the
center to get the water down to the
bottom of the pot from the top and then
you're going to have the top of the pot
drying out and killing all of your your
food web roots on the top of the soil
that run about I don't know maybe they
run a foot deep from the top of the soil
and so I did a cover crop which worked
extremely well but not thinking about it
or never done doing it
before uh it attracts a lot of bugs you
get a lot of pest brought in cuz there's
a whole like five different food sources
you just brought onto the scene like
right in the same vicinity of your plant
which I would do it again if I used
something that didn't grow as high that
wouldn't grow up into the bottom of the
plant and like literally have a ladder
into the into the plant like a climbing
uh pee or something or yeah you threw up
you threw up a ladder right up into the
right up into your bud so that anything
that walks on the ground can make it up
in there not that it couldn't before but
now you know you make it a lot easier
but it don't really layer the soil I
just put the soil in I don't have I me
know a lot of people do super soils
where we want the bottom of the soil to
be one thing and the middle to be
another and the top to be another really
just do one soil make sure it's amended
well and evenly distributed and then
I'll do
I like the idea of straw better on top
of the pots to you know add that buffer
so they're not getting beaten down by
the sun like a like a mulch layer like a
mulch layer or just something you don't
really want mulch you want something to
inert because you don't want to start
you don't want any biological composting
process to start on top of your soil cuz
that's going to be a it's going to be
not be good but yeah like a straw an
inert straw something that will get wet
but won't like start to break down and
decompos in the top just to add a buffer
for the light or buffer for
heat
radiation cool kind of kind of helps
trap in some of the moisture too so
you're not losing too much through
evaporation you're losing some
evaporation and then you're you're
keeping your soil temps down which I
mean keeping your soil temp down is kind
of a lost battle there's only you can
get don't get a black pot and don't let
the sun touch the top of the soil that's
about all you can do so I mean you can
with outdoor there's only so much you
can control and you just got to kind of
figure out what you can it's like the
was the AA prayer control what you can
control don't worry about what you can't
but like figure out what you can do and
then you got to do that very well fair
enough
um were there any other things that you
implemented this year that you had in
years prior that you felt uh was a great
Improvement to your plants or did you
add anything that you kind of felt as
though hindered your ability to tune the
plants the way that you like to I don't
think that I really did anything to
hinder myself this year other than bad
strain choices if you saw my pictures I
had one strain that did phenominally
well and then I had one strain that I
was very disappointed in and because it
couldn't handle heat stress it was
untrainable it just anything that I was
going to do with it it was not it would
not take it and then you know at that
point you just got to let it run you
know if you try to I I don't like to top
plants I like to just bend them over and
get new shoots to come off I feel like
when you top them it it kills your yield
and it kind of it sets the plant back
about a week or so if you're going to
cut on it so if you are going to top it
you want to top it before you planted in
there but strain Choice Outdoors is it's
massive like you can get one like I had
one that just you know and then you have
half your garden set on that and you're
like you're okay with it but I mean it's
certain point you can't do anything
about it yeah I agree
it we we've even just stopped even doing
any training on outdoor plants um I mean
especially cuz they're in rows and you
have you know 30 or 40 plants per row it
it doesn't really make too much sense to
just to try and even the canopy it kind
of becomes a hedge either way have more
surface area too if it's not even right
absolutely you have PE Peaks and valleys
versus a flat plane always has more
surface area that's the same reason why
we we tend to not top indoors either is
because if you have a a completely even
canopy in a 4x4 area then you only have
16 square ft of available surface area
directly down from the light but if you
have Peaks and valleys you can sometimes
uh one and 1/2x to double your total
surface area which just means more
Photon absorption so um that's a it's a
great point for people to think about
when you do have the outdoors though
where the sun as a single point um but
spread across such a large surface area
at a such high ppfd and the fact that it
moves across the sky you have this
ability to really capture light uh on
almost all different sides of the plant
especially when you're down in like
California not too high on the latitudes
um you get a lot of that really nice
light um and so it almost feels like you
could top it you could spread it out you
could do whatever you want with it if
they're not growing directly next to
each other they're going to
capture you know a ton of a ton of
energy from the Sun oh 100% like that's
I've noticed I have a tree that
overhangs one part of my garden and
around high noon so whenever the
brightest of the day between about 12:
and 1:32 p.m it blocks a couple of the
plants off and you notice the quality of
the butt on those plants will be a
little bit higher and the yield is going
be lower but like right when right when
the ppfd is going to be too high is I
want to say too high but you know
extremely high if you can block that off
and that's like a lot of the the
advantage of a greenhouse is that you're
you're taking that and lowering it down
a little bit and your quality is going
up sure you're making like a more even
spread of the light at a lower intensity
rather than that sort of high peak
intensity of the midday and low
intensity of the morning and afternoon
um% yeah so um
out of all the aspects of your gardening
nowadays what do you think is one of the
most important things that you do in
your garden um that you might not have
touched on so far or if you've already
touched on it um maybe dive a little bit
deeper into its importance to your
gardening
um say watering is probably going to be
your biggest factor in anything if
you're not watering correctly that
anything else you do is going to be it
starts with watering everything is to to
be n and void so really keeping an eye
on how much water your plants are using
and how much is evaporating is going to
be a huge Factor because that's
especially I want to say organic because
you're going to your microbes are going
to die if you get it too dry and they're
going to die if it's too wet and you're
going to get mold if it's too wet you're
going to get fungus and root Rod if it's
too wet so that is like if you have a
good soil and you can keep the water in
the pot at the exact level you want the
amount of moisture you're going to have
the best results by far for sure what
what are some of your watering practices
like what are some of the Tells that you
look for and what are some of the other
insights you might be able to to share
with other outdoor Growers that might be
looking into doing something in these
larger um raised pots where you have a
because you have like a like Matrix
potential would be something where
you're actually using soil sand silt and
Clay where the water availability is
dependent upon that Matrix potential
whereas within uh substrate you have uh
osmotic potential and you actually have
um water available within the poe space
of these substrates that are made out of
a it's like a soiless media where you
don't have sand Sil or clay um yeah so
what are some of these practices that
you do with uh your your substrate and
if you could also just really quick
touch on what what substrate did you use
for these 200 gon pots I used vital
Earths blend of soil Co which is um it's
pretty good soil I've never used it
before it is a little bit pricey because
they are uh they're proud of themselves
and not in a negative way but you know
Vital Earth is you know is kind of a poh
brand sure their soil is the only soil
you can find that doesn't have any dairy
manure any dairy anything related to
Dairy farming in it which is a one of
the big things because Dairy farming and
the byproducts of it are not nice at all
when you start looking into that um
but I did that and as far as watering
goes is
that you want to water you want to water
every day you don't want to not water
every day if you're if
you're if you're not watering for four
days at a time there's a problem and if
you're watering every day and it's dry
every day that's also a problem you want
to get to the Fine medium where you're
watering every day to keep it
so I don't use a moisture meter so I
have no way to tell you how to like
verify this but wherever you're water
level wherever your moisture level you
want it to be you wanted to drop down a
little bit every day and bring it back
up a little bit past that every day and
you want to keep it in this range cuz if
you let your soil go all dry if you let
your soil dry out it's going to become
hydrophobic and that's going to make it
really hard to water it and get it wet
in the next day or two without having to
like literally run water through the pot
until it's coming out the bottom and
even then you might have dry Pockets
within there for sure you're going to
get like channeling and stuff as well
you get channeling or you can like you
can think that the pot is full of water
you stick your you can like stick your
hand down in there and you'll find just
dry there'll just be dry areas in there
where it doesn't get wet so once you let
it get past the point of being too dry
it's going to be hard to get it as a
hole back to where you want it to go for
sure it it kind of makes me think of a
Sarcan Rhythm where you really want like
because the plants kind of have this
24-hour cycle just like humans do where
you have the sun coming up and going
down and it it's something that has just
sort of genetically been embedded in our
code um following that with plants does
help it seems with their overall health
rather than having these extremely long
points of of drying and then High
irrigation you know you you can run into
like hypoxia events or stuff at at that
point as well too where you have too
much water in the substrate um but yeah
finding that perfect sort of balance
within the sub sound very lame and on
here but it's hard to explain if you're
not using a moisture meter cu can't say
like it needs to be here it needs to go
there it needs to go there it's kind of
all played by ear and like you I
explaining it would be easier in person
to show you what I mean but another
thing too about that
is if you go out at night and your soil
feels dry and you go out in the morning
and your soil looks wet the amount of
water that the plant is dumping back
into the soil at night can also trick
you too because if the soil is dry at
night and it's wet in the morning it's
not wet all the way through the pot you
still need to water it but the amount of
water that is up in the plant that comes
down when it goes to I don't want to say
goes to sleep but when it goes to sleep
is a there going to be a lot of volume
especially with a large Plant so you got
to be careful not to get tricked by that
because if you go out you know at you
know in the evening before the sun goes
down and you're like oh these need water
you go out in the morning they look like
they don't need water they still need
water for sure yeah you get a lot of um
condensation to on the top of soil just
from the the temperature change from
night to day and uh yeah I've definitely
seen that where it looks like it's fine
and then all of a sudden it's starting
to look drought stressed with some
wilting leaves or perhaps some you know
red pedals or uh you know yellowing
around the fringes or some other sort of
high EC osmotic stress that you might
see you start seeing like the bottom
start to yellow out and yellow from the
you know you'll start yeah 100%
right I feel like another another really
good point to bring up especially when
you are running a a heavily amended
substrate that you're using that
biological activity that by maintaining
a certain moisture
content you're also maintaining the
health of the biology within the pot uh
for those nutrient cycling processes to
continue to occur at a you know a
healthy rate rather than booms and busts
um because that can cause some some
burning or uh nutrient imbalances i'
I've seen as well or you can kill off
part of your roots I mean your roots
will go Brown in different areas of the
poth which you won't see or if you start
yeah another thing too a good way to
gauge it too is is if you have fungus
growth in your pots and you can maintain
fungus growth like Fruity and bodies
that's how you know you kind of hit like
the perfect
Zone that's a really great Point yeah
but if you can have fruy mushrooms in
the pots and you can keep them alive and
they keep fruiting over and over again
you you know you're like right where you
need to be cuz you can use that as a
gauge to to the whole the whole soil
Health as a whole you know that's a
that's a really good way to sort of
explain it for anybody that's grown say
um mushrooms because when you make your
grains for the different mushrooms like
oyster mushrooms or shitake mushrooms or
any edible mushrooms let's say and you
you take those grains and you either
steam them or you cook them you don't
cook them until they're mush and and and
wet and sopping and soaking where you
can take a handful of them and squeeze
them and water comes out you cook them
until they're just cooked enough or
there's enough water content within them
so that the melal colonies can kind of
take hold colonize those different
grains and then you can produce those
fruiting bodies from them because the
fuing bodies yes they do contain a lot
of moisture but they pull a lot of that
moisture from this the substrate block
and um you'll see the whole block kind
of shrivel up a after the mycelium sort
of consumes it and the fruiting bodies
Sprout um so that's a really good point
because yeah you don't want it to be
mush where it's really wet it can't be
dry because then you don't have the
ability for the melal col to take hold
of it it has to be just right it's like
a kind of like a goldilock Zone some
people call it it is kind of like and
then like for a I don't know how you say
it it's like a it's the canary and the
coal Coal Mine so to speak in a
different way but if you have rooing
bodies you know like you hit where you
need to be cuz if they can live and the
melum can expand and they can fruit and
they're not getting overwatered to where
they turn brown and die and you see new
fruiting bodies coming up you know
constantly every couple days now you
know like your whole your soil food web
is you where is the best you're going to
get for sure it's like U some people
will call like the melal structure the
roots of mushrooms where like using it
as an analogy for plants and their roots
and in using that analogy they're not
wrong in some aspects where the moisture
content for uh healthy myal production
is the roughly the same moisture content
required for healthy root production um
and root health so that's a that's a
really good anal ology to to bring up to
people who have either one experience or
the other that they can then apply that
to yeah and it's like and yeah and then
it's easy to like for an obice approach
too because if you can see that like
that's you don't need to know anything
like if you don't know anything that is
like that's your sign like you know that
you're golden there once you've hit that
for sure also then you get into like
what kind of like I think I have Shaggy
parasols that come into the pots and I
don't know if they're necessarily
from spores that are on the property or
from the soil I put in but I had or
something some amendment I use I don't
know exactly where they came from but I
have the same fru in bodies every year
even when I soils same Fring bodies and
you've been able to identify them as to
what they are I'm not I'm no I'm no
micro expert but I have got on some
reddits and that's what I've been told
multiple times that they kind of fit I
haven't tooken a Spore print or gone
into all that but I kind of assume
that's what they are that's kind of what
I've been led to believe for sure you
should you should see if there's like um
I know some uh like mushroom uction
companies like if they make a bunch of
shiitake mushrooms or other things like
that they'll sell their uh fru blocks
afterwards as mushroom compost and I've
seen people take those and put them into
highly active substrates and then get
more fruiting Cycles out of it umw where
you can then you know go through and
harvest a bunch of shitake and stuff or
oyster mushrooms or whatever it is that
they have growing on them well then two
another thing to think about are they
Endo or Ecto micro isal like how are
they going to interact with your too
yeah I you'd have to look into the the
specific type of uh um of mushroom that
it is and and how that's going to
interact with the plant I you know some
of them I know that there are some
mushrooms that are
um I forget the the exact term but
they're basically some of them really
like dung or or manure and some of them
like uh rotted Uh Wood like oh um it's
like Nile seor
yood kind yep so there's like one's for
rotting wood one's for digested organic
matter and
um yeah you would you'd have to wonder
is it going to be beneficial in a root
Zone where like if if it recognizes the
roots
as uh if it is soric I'm listeners
forgive us if we aren't using the
correct terms but if it likes if it
likes wood or lignan and it is going
after the roots is it going to go after
roots that are dead uh is it going to
cause a disease to the roots that are
going to cause them to die or is it
going to leave the live Roots alone and
remove the dead root tissue and
potentially even provide some sort of
um agent taking up whatever whatever is
in the compost or whatever is already in
the soil and turning it into something
that it can use yeah absolutely you so
many of these different interactions I
feel like there's probably studies out
there that have some of this information
in there um so whoever finds that out
please let us know um but this is It's a
fascinating conversation to think and
that's like if you want to get into
compost te's a lot more which is a step
I haven't gone is like getting a
microscope and looking at what you have
and every tea you have Y which is which
is a step further than you know most
most hom Growers or most anybody who's
like I mean if that's your profession I
could see why you how you have the time
and the ability to do these things and
it's kind of nice to know not really
need to know but I mean taking your tea
and testing every te you have and being
like okay well you know when I this is
my ingredients I use and the times I use
and the temperatures it was I'm getting
a higher result out of that than I am if
I do it you know you know you can play
it by year at home but like when you
really get it down and start doing the
science on it like you could probably
find tun a t to be pretty pretty good
probably and and a lot of it would then
have to do with where you're sourcing
your um microbial and biological
consortiums and what you're feeding it
and if those different constituents
change throughout the seasons as well
like if you're using a like let's say
you you make your own Co compost and
you're using compost that you make all
year and it's from your kitchen scrap
well is your kitchen scrap based on
seasonally available produce and if so
does that produce have a higher you know
because it's going to be cores of apple
peels of banana uh shoots of broccoli
kale whatever these things are eggshells
coffee grounds whatever is that you're
having right and you know based on
those like I'm I'm pretty sure potassium
is going to be high in banana peels so
are are you heavier in potassium or are
you heavier in something that's like oh
I had a bunch of dead and
dying blackberries on my bush and I
threw those in there and so you're going
to have a bunch of phosphorus from the
seeds of the of the blackberries and
stuff um like what what's the makeup of
the compost how is this biology going to
affect it and the source of the biology
where is that coming from oh 100%
another thing I think about too which is
I don't really know like so you have all
your different micro risal like that you
can use like obviously you can buy a
million off the store like whatever off
the shelf okay when you colonize your
pot with one and then you want to use
another later in the year can it out
compete the one you've already colonized
your pot with because you have I mean I
see a lot of I don't want to say Kimi
but it's like can't remember the name
they have a product makeup F and it has
a special type of basilis in there or uh
but do you know that that's going to out
compete what you already have in your
pot or are you just throwing you know
like do you already have the a whole
colony in 200 gallons and you're trying
to recolonize it half through the year
isn't even doing anything cuz I mean if
you lab test it and it does process
phosphorus that doesn't mean you're
going to get it colonize and already
colonized pot and that's like a lot of
like what I haven't seen research being
done is like you know if you're going to
colonize your pot one in the beginning
are you ever going to be able to change
the composition of what's living in
there you know and try to recolonize it
with something else for sure the first
thing that comes to mind uh about like
that out compet out competing of one uh
either let's say it's a melal colony um
you you know you may have like an endom
micro isal fungi within your soil that's
helping provide some benefit between the
uh roots and the the rest of the soil um
but then if you introduce trichoderma
you're going to decimate that population
of micro isal fungi and it's going to
way out compete it but it's also then
going to provide its own benefits to the
plant not necessarily in nutrient
exchange but in protection from like
ferium pythium other uh
negative um uh pathogens and uh rootborn
diseases
so what what's the approach that you
need to take I think is really truly uh
subjective in a lot of these different
cases based on what you have available
and what your the pressures are on your
um your system oh 100% yeah that's just
that's just kind of things I think about
going forward is like I trying to get to
the point where I know these where you
can know these differences but it's very
hard it's it's not easy to do no and
like you even said you know you're
especially as an outdoor grower your
knowledge is built up season to season
rather than grow to grow where I mean it
is grow to grow but you have to look at
it as this season to season thing
because you have one opportunity one
yeah it's one opportunity per year
unless you're doing some sort of light
depth setup but then you have a uh a
greenhouse basically and you need to
manage that completely differently than
in your outdoor setup um what for your
outdoor you know one of the things that
you touched on briefly earlier is that
integrated Pest Management is very
important important because you only
have one crop per year that you get to
work with and if you're using this as
medicine or even as a recreational um
thing it the importance of making sure
that you make it through to harvest with
a limited crop per year is dire so it's
dire and it you know and not not too
negatively touch on it is like that's
what that's why I think outdoor gets a
bad WAP is cuz some people will do
whatever they have to do to make it get
to the end instead of doing what's right
and the hard way to get it to the end
but yes uh IPM is figuring out your IPM
is going to be something you need to do
within the first year or two because if
you don't figure it out by then you're
never going to have sub you know good
years after that like that's like a you
got to figure that out and you got to
probably talk if you don't know someone
who's watching that doesn't know talk to
somebody who does know and at least
start with somebody somebody IPM that
they've kind of created cuz if go out
without knowing what you're doing you're
going to have it's going to you're going
to have a bad time for sure what what
are some experiences that you've had
with IPM applications um knowing that we
can't necessarily tell other people how
to apply their own ipms but um in terms
of where you found success with a um
let's say an early detection that you
were able to eradicate and then um
perhaps something that maybe got out of
control that you weren't necessarily
able to fight back within that specific
season where it did then negatively a
affect your yields so when I look at IPM
and doing organic and not using any non
approved sprays like so even spinoid is
not approved in California anymore even
though it is organic so you got to look
at like I'm very very religious on not
using anything that has any sort of
negative effect on human health that has
been proven sure
so and when you're looking at an outdoor
sense it's not I'm never going to get
bugs it's like you are going to get
something and you need to know that it
is going to happen and what you want to
do is get in place an IPM that is going
to slow it's going to reduce the chance
of it happening and if it does happen
slow it down so you have time to react
i' I've heard it referred to as uh
achieving an economic threshold uh yes
there's going to be pressure and pre and
there's going to be pest pressure but
you need to keep it very very low and
keep control of it because you're never
going to have it's out the plant's
outside you're never going to not have
bugs
to say that I never had bugs this year
is that's untruth like did you did you
control it and did you go a good job and
not have any negative effects from it
yes did you not have any bugs on your
plants no because I even use beneficial
insects like we have Green Lace Wing
here that come around naturally on the
plants there's ladybug larva there's
assassin bugs there's stuff that like so
you're going to have bugs on your plants
that aren't bad that you're going to
want there so it's like kind of managing
that and trying to fix pick something
that is going to keep the pressure at
Bay and allow you to make a choice and
that's why I saying earlier so I like to
use my own Bio Innovations they have you
know Grand Evo and venerate which are
two really good sprays that if you're
going to be consistent and use them work
very well but they are not going to save
you by any means like if you if you go
out and you weren't doing anything and
you see that problem like there's only a
few products that you can use that are
going to be organic and safe that are
actually going to help you and they're
going to be contact sprays at best like
you're going to have to go out and do it
religiously to bring the pressure back
down to where you want to to be so I'd
say being on top of that and figuring
out a cycle of three products you want
to use so when I'm in veg I use a
mixture of mineral oil I'll use Grand
Divo and vener and then when I get into
start going into flow I'll pull the oils
out so I won't use any mineral oil
stylid oil if I was going to use neem
oil I won't use that anymore or if you
are going to use neem oil you're going
to back that out and then I found
another product I can't remember the
name of it but it's basically sugars
that they found that plants Prett on
their own and they synthesize them and
they're so like a different type of
sucos guard huh is it on guard Ong guard
or it's called regalia or you said
regalia right no I don't really use
regalia okay I was thinking about using
it but that's more of a that's more to
trigger a plant immune response to like
funguses and stuff but
um I'll think of the name or I'll grab
it in a minute but anyway you're going
to move into keep using your venerate
your grand Evo and then move into a
contact spray that you're going to want
to spray every 3 or 4 days CU you're
just going to at a certain point you're
just going to say I assume that I have
pests and I'm going to spray for them
and you have to be religious about
it right and then you follow that
through and then right about flour like
right when you get into like the last
two weeks you need to as hard as it is
to do you're going to need to spray for
Caterpillar still which is going to be
um
BT as much as I as much as nobody
outdoor wants as much as nobody wants to
spray their butt with anything however
safe it is if you don't I feel like the
consequences of having caterpillars and
having caterpillar excrement and having
mold and all that is way out way more
harmful than having sprayed with BT yeah
personal opion basilis sensus is not uh
a harsh uh biology that would then
negatively affect the end User it's it
doesn't produce MotoX or anything like
that that would affect um someone
whether it be through consumption uh
through combustion vaporization or um
turning it into it like a tincture
edible or otherwise um and that's that's
been proven through its application on
you know numerous crops uh that have the
potential for caterpillars um you know
it makes me think of a lot of like
different brassas uh such as cauliflower
cabbage uh brussels sprouts all those
different things that you need to have
something like that sprayed into them or
else you are going to lose 50% of your
crop each year oh you are and then the
then the the negative for ramifications
of having mold in there like so I don't
know about cauliflower but cannabis you
don't want to take anything into the
drying room that has mold in it cuz now
you have a sealed environment where you
just have where if you don't have
control over your if you get any spikes
and humidity you're just you're
literally creating a culture like a pet
Tre dish in there to spread mold to
everything and so like caterpillars is
like I mean I hate caterpillars and I'm
sure every outdoor grower can say the
exact same thing but like if you think
you're spraying too early for
caterpillars when it comes to flour
you're not just just go ahead and do it
for sure um since you do hang a lot of
your end product outdoor for uh smokable
flour as well as for concentrates um do
you end up doing any sort of washes on
your flow to move remove um dust debris
uh insect droppings carcasses or
otherwise I do not and I've thought
about doing it I haven't tested it yet
I've heard mixed results I just don't
know it it would probably depend on how
dry it is when you're harvesting cuz if
you've already had your plants outside
and 80% humidity every morning for 2
weeks and then you duck them in a bucket
of water and then put them in the drying
room I I haven't tried this but I have a
feeling from past experience that you're
going to have a bad time yeah I don't I
don't see that turning out too good yeah
yeah and I'm not against washing it I
don't think it's a bad idea by any means
but if you're if you're going to destroy
everything and not have anything at the
end then you know people who smoke
outdoor you know what
comes absolutely I feel like there's a
you know there's a little bit of a charm
to outdoor Bud that you know it has so
much more characteristic to it let's say
um and regardless if that's due to the
extra stuff that comes along with it you
know it's been something that people
have used for
centuries thousands of years um and the
fact that we now have
these pampered pallets of indoor
cannabis uh in climate environmentally
controlled sort of uh clean rooms in
some filtered water never sees anything
other than fil yeah I mean I'm not and I
love that and that's awesome that we do
that but also you can't throw everything
that got to that point out and they say
like you know well outdoors in the past
you know I feel like a lot of people do
that and a lot of people newer
Generations especially that haven't been
around a while like I know people that
I've like talked to that don't know what
brick weed is for sure that don't know
like don't like they you've lost this
idea of what weed is came and like now
it's just all indoor and there's nothing
that everything before it doesn't exist
right absolutely I mean and in some
senses it it'll never go back so um well
maybe maybe I shouldn't speak so soon on
that who knows maybe it'll go back to
something that's less than uh quality
uh depending on how things change if
Federal legalization ever goes through
but oh well I don't want to think about
that but yeah I get what you're saying
no we don't want to talk about Philip
Reynolds right now um so with
uh with the fact that you do you know uh
save a lot of your flour for both um
dried flour it is and then you do a lot
of it seems like you do a lot of
concentrates as well um what have been
some of your your U most memorable
harvests uh as both flour and
concentrate most memorable Harvest so at
this property I'd say this year as far
as flow and concentrates go the
governmental Wast I grew did phenomenal
for
both 100% nice um
and as far as like doing concentrates go
I like doing concentrates but another
aspect that a lot of people need to
think about too is that you cut your
your labor down to nothing by doing
concentrates like doing fresh frozen
you're cutting out Harve you're
harvesting and it takes a little bit
longer you're cutting out drying you're
cutting out curing you're cutting out
bucking down you're cutting out big
leafing you're cutting out trimming
you're cutting out you're cutting off
you know like three four months worth of
work by doing that which you do get a
very excellent product depending on who
you find to work with and if someone's
willing to work with you which I've been
lucky enough to find somebody that's you
know pretty proficient at what they do
and very regarded but
um
yeah that's another aspect to think
about is doing fresh Frozen cuts your
labor down cuz growing outdoor is a very
labor intensive job every step of it
every step of the way yep and another
cool thing about fresh frozen is um like
even we touched on before about the
somehow how some people will wash their
buds from outdoor or even indoor if they
so feel like it but um you know I've
heard a majority of people will do it
for health reasons because they just
can't have those uh extra things that
come and take a ride in on that outdoor
Bud um but if you're doing fresh frozen
and you're washing it uh for the for the
Tricom heads you do remove a lot of
those other potential um dusts and bugs
and other things that's why when you do
outdoor fresh Frozen doing rosin the
first wash you're never going to have so
any reputable rosin producer is never
going to have a first wash cuz the first
wash is considered
contaminated so the first wash is going
to be taken set asign for Edibles and
that's like so you're going want so if
you're going to do a wash you're going
to do you know the guy that taught me
does five washes so the first wash is
going to be a very quick wash it's going
to be your best triome heads and it's
also going to be all your contaminants
so it's kind of a double-edged sword
because you're washing off all the
briest you know easiest to break off
Trikes and you're taking all your
contamination and you're setting it the
side for Edibles are they are they not
uh rinsing it oh they do R they you do
their first wash and you rinse it and
you collect all that and you set it the
side it's considered contaminated now I
don't know if they've studied this or
whatever I don't know they don't How
Deep The the research into this goes I'm
sure it's there but that you're doing
your washing your first wash or the
first harvest you get out of whatever
your material washing is set to the side
for Edibles because you're then you're
taking all your contaminants or anything
that could be in there and pushing it
out and you're not you're not pressing
that or freeze drying it or turning into
a smokeable product so you are getting a
cleaner product from that even though
you are taking the best of the best
triome heads and setting them aside sure
that's really fascinating I've never
heard that before but I could see how um
depending on the washing practices that
might be necessary to really make sort
of you know maybe this is like one of
those tricks that people use to get that
that what five star hash six star hash
or whatever the stuff that you can just
straight take the the you know the nice
no contaminant when it's done just yep
and and you can it's dabbable basically
at that point um that's really
fascinating I hadn't I hadn't really
thought about that yeah and that's a way
that so like when you're yeah it cleans
it up a little bit so that is the also
the benefit the benefit from doing you
know if you're going to Fresh Frozen not
for resin but for rosin you are going to
get a cleaner end product that you can
have too too so if you are concerned
about contaminants from outdoor health
issues or you're sensitive or whatever
going on with that that's going to be a
better product choice for sure makes a
lot smoke bud but the older I get I
realize why people stop smoking bud it's
not you know it is a you're still
smoking and combusting something for
sure I I I had to like just completely
stop actually smoking smoking like
combusting and I only do like a volcano
vaporizer now or one of their
um like handheld units because it just
uh
there's no way to kind of avoid what
comes with combustion um it's yeah you
know you're not spoking cigarettes but
that you know over however long you've
been smoking does factor into that at a
certain point yeah well I spent a decade
smoking cigarettes too and that didn't
help me um so you know now I get to face
those
consequences I'm in the same boat are
yeah I mean that and then also growing
up in the Bay Area I think uh blunts
were life at one point and uh yeah I I I
face those consequences now with a
little bit of a cough every once in a
while 100 100% you know you when you're
younger you're like [__] it then you get
older and you're like H you know what
maybe I need to rethink this a little
bit absolutely
um all right so uh you know since you
spent some time doing the cultivation
thing um
at a professional level where you were
helping out at these different Farms
where you were uh learning these
different practices and ins and out and
and got a paycheck basically from it
without having to be the the entire
business owner yourself and then moving
into having your own hom grow where you
were making it for your own medicine and
for your own consumption and uh for
sharing that flower with other people um
where would you like to see the
cultivation space sort of go over the
next 5 to 10 years and and where do you
think as though it could
improve where does it need it needs to
be
more less consuming energy and I know
saying that to an indor grower is a bad
thing but there is a mass amount of
energy consumed to grow Bud for people
to smoke it is when there's ways that
can be done without that and I
think how the market has been trained as
far as since legalization came about and
people that you know would never think
about smoking weed or putting thought in
are now smoking and they the only thing
they learned of what they've been taught
at the
dispensary which is you know indoor
wheed is good outdoor weed is shitty um
and you know that's like that's as far
as the extent goes and I'm not saying
indoor weed well most stuff of the
dispensary let's not lie is not very
good but you know there are good there
is a way to grow weed without being so
you know Carbon heavy us it carbon have
been growing it I think there needs to
be a shift to that because if you look
at how many warehouses have been built
to grow weed or how many warehouses have
been repurposed and there's thousands of
Lights in there just you know run the
meter is kind of like working away from
that and the thing about outdoor that
gets a bad wrap is if you're going to
try to grow 300 plants with five people
you're not going to grow good wheat like
it needs to be brought down to a smaller
scale which I don't ever see happening I
would like to see that but I don't think
that it's going to be there but if you
can grow
outdoor at and you can figure out how
much you can do to grow like that's
where I'm at I have 15 plants probably
can't grow more than 15 plants and still
do what I do because I'm going to
overburden myself with labor yeah you
know and that's just personal
perspective but to see the market go to
more of a niche smaller farmer kind of
thing and making it more accessible to
smaller Growers to get into the market
rather than just saying you know if you
don't have $2 million in backing you're
never going to be a business is kind of
where it's at now I
maybe not so much in Oregon but as far
as Colorado and California go like
you're not getting into the market it's
it's kind of the same in Oregon right
now and um with the the price per pound
going down significantly over the past
three years and and continuing to go
down uh while the cost of production
continues to go up it does seem as
though any point that you can reduce
your costs uh or increase the not only
the quality but the quantity of
production unfortunately is extremely
important to make sure that small
businesses continue to remain viable um
a lot of these larger businesses because
overhead uh costs go down as you scale
up um when it comes to
um like how much it costs to run a
business versus how much income that
business makes your net your your cost
to grow a pound goes down when you grow
more obviously but what yeah what goes
in entails that does the quality go down
nothing no other factors is measured
other than what can I produce for it's
all the bottom line yes and that that is
unfortunate and um you know I I
mentioned RJ Reynolds earlier uh and and
other large uh either tobacco companies
or other uh multic conglomerate
companies that may pivot into the
Cannabis space if it were to become
federally legal uh are going to be able
to produce uh cannabis
uh I you know fortunately and
unfortunately we've been able to
increase how well cannabis can be grown
with less of
a uh like
secretive nature to the processes behind
it a lot of this information is now more
readily available and companies with
lots
of uh Expendable Revenue that they can
put in into re research and development
and creating methodologies that produce
cannabis at a specific level especially
if they're homogenizing an end product
like a pre-roll or something like that
or a
concentrate companies that have the
ability to produce vast amounts of
cannabis and get it to the market for a
very low price but maintain
consistency and a certain level of
quality not necessarily you know top
shelf height quality you know that guy
with four lights in his garage that's
growing everything in a living soil bed
and just crushing it um you know like
not that level of quality but something
where it's it's smokable it's not going
to get you sick because it it has a
specific level of standard that it has
to be held to because you have all these
different regulations you're going to
have something that's going to be
usable but it's going to be hores light
it's going to be yeah you're I was going
to say you're talking Miller Light yeah
it's going to be something that is a
lower quality product but it's going to
be consistent and it's going to Garner
the most use out of your average
consumer because for me like I used to
be a chef but I still love getting a
burger from like In-N-Out or McDonald's
or something where it's
consistent you know I know exactly what
it's going to be you know going to a
Burger House or something where there
it's a fancy restaurant that has a
really nice burger sometimes I'm like
did they did they do too much did they
not do enough am I going to be
overpaying and way under under liking
what it is oh
100% um yeah that's like that's when it
when it when the top comes off and it
fully goes legal there's going to be
it's going to be a race to mediocrity to
say not to be negative about it but it's
going to be a race to the middle not to
the bottom or the top because it has to
like meet some standards for enough
people to be repeat customers cuz that's
the only way that they're going to be
able to maintain any sort of business
model like that but it can't be the best
because that's going to cost too much to
produce and it can't be the worst
because well no one's going to want to
come back to it so it has to be
somewhere in the middle and you know
there's a lot of advanc advancements in
technology within the Cannabis space
like the distillation of different tpin
and the mixing of different tarpine
profiles to match specific cannabis
cultivars and doing that through either
gathered tpin from Cannabis production
or synthetically tpin or uh you know
exogenously sourced tpin from
non-cannabis related still like natural
sources but then the mixing of those and
the application of that
to you know R roll flour or even whole
pounds of what looks like nice cannabis
but may be completely tpless when it's
done drying and curing because they
dried it and cured it in 5 days you know
yeah or whatever race to the end goal
was yeah that that yeah well like what
I've noticed here in California I'm sure
it's the same everywhere is so when I
came out here it was full boom like
Farmers everywhere like nobody liked I
want say nobody liked Farmers there were
so there were farmers everywhere and
they got a bad rap from coming in from
out of you know different states coming
and setting up shop trashing everything
and leaving and being able to survive as
a business while creating a product that
was horrible just because of the lack of
demand and the kind of approach I took
as like leaving leaving the industry so
to say and finding a different career
and then still doing what I'm doing is
like you're watching all these Legacy
farmers fall off left and right and
obviously by quality first like the
lower quality farmers are Dro it off the
mid quality farmers are dropping off
even people that grew pretty decent
flower either change their practices
based on how much money they could get
out of it right so if you're not getting
3,000 a pound anymore you're getting you
know 250 to 500 a pound
well all the practices they use to grow
good weed they are not doing anymore
because they're try they're trying to
survive so all of your high-end flower
on the outdoor scene is starting to fall
off too and you're starting to lose any
good outdoor flower that you can find I
mean it's hard to find good outdoor weed
Y which only furthers furthers the whole
thing that outdoor is not good which is
like it's stigmatizing almost it's like
starting the self- ending cycle of like
it's just going to try to burn itself
out yeah yeah it's like the the snake
that eats its tail the the Ora Boris
it's just uh going around and continuing
to eat itself and it's never going to
stop um yeah I agree with that it is
unfortunate to see sort of some of these
trends that it it
almost it's going to be hard to break
the cycles and these trends that they've
already started
because as the price per pound goes down
yeah you can pivot away from more
expensive puts uh uh less intensive
farming practices um but if it was those
intensive farming practices or the
specific inputs or uh different things
that you did to make your farm work
because as you know these are plants and
they're growing and they're alive and
they need things to make sure that they
stay alive and if you start to remove
those different
things maybe your plants don't survive a
year maybe you have a failed half crop
or something like that and maybe that
crop was what was needed to keep the
lights on or you know oh 100%
so you so because yeah it feels like the
way that things are moving away from
smaller Growers being able to provide
for their local community to larger
scale Growers providing for a more macro
Community um within each
state and and how homeg growing seems to
be sort of one of the last bastions of
ability for people to produce the
medicine that they want or the Cannabis
that they want not necessarily what's
available on the market um what would be
some advice that you would give to new
Growers based
on your successes and failures as a
grower
yourself advice I would give to new
Growers is
don't stop doing what you're doing it's
very very easy to get discouraged to
have a bad year and especially like if
you care about what you do and it's a
passion project and you're doing this
because you believe in it it's really
easy to get disheartened having a bad
year like you can have a bad year and
your bad year can be six like if you're
outdoor it could be six months long that
you are just like and you don't want to
do it next
year you know so like what if you choose
to do if you choose to start growing
outdoor and you want to grow what you
want to grow for you
and then you need to kind of take pride
in that and like there are you're going
to take some hits to the face you're
going to get knocked down and it's like
I mean you're going to get you're not
going to know what you're doing you're
going to get blindsided by pests you're
going to not know you're going to kill a
plant you're going to you know all these
things are going to happen and it's not
something that you need to stop doing it
because of that like you need to like
try to remove the emotion from it and
like logically look at what you're doing
because when you put a bunch of time and
effort into something especially like an
outdoor even what I do is considered
small you know on the scale of Outdoors
like it's easy to like I mean you got to
just keep rolling with it yep it seems
like uh something that it seems like to
be a repeat uh advice for new Growers is
don't let your
failures remain failures let them become
a Learning lesson so that you can take
that
information that you gain within that
failure so that you don't then face
those same failures again in the future
100% And it's like when you first start
growing it's like falling up the
stairs like you're going to you're going
to hit the you're going to just keep
[__] up until you end up to a spot
where you have something that you like
kind of understand what you're doing and
like like like we saw touched on before
you get one shot a year don't let the
first year that you just completely [__]
the whole thing up stop you from trying
to get the next year for sure it's just
like any other skill or practice um
there's plenty of different books or um
ID IDE IES that will say you know you
need
10,000 hours of practice to become a
master at something or you know a
million hours of practice to to become
you proficient at something I I don't
forget the exact or I forget the exact
numbers but repetition and perseverance
through a lot of these different
practices and aspects of cultivation are
what go are what are going to make you a
better cultivator overall and every time
you fail if you pick yourself up dust
yourself off and say that suck I don't
want that to happen again how am I going
to prevent that like I failed and this
is what I did wrong don't don't try to
blame or figure out some reason why it
wasn't what you did which I mean that's
like that's generally in life too if you
can accept the responsibility you can
move on another thing I would offer to
new Growers is don't be afraid to ask
questions because I don't know one of
the Jungle boys browers said that you
can give people the tech and they won't
use it anyway like there's like some
sort of ego about growing and I don't
understand like how it works that no one
wants to listen to the other person and
I'm sure you've experienced this like
you could be like I know what you're
doing wrong change this okay well if
you're not because I said that you're
not going to do it now or whatever it
may be like don't be afraid to ask for
advice and find somebody that does grow
and pick their brain because especially
with outdoor if someone like I've been
growing about a decade if you if it's
your first outdoor and you have access
to somebody who's been doing it for 10
years like that's going to be your key
to getting better quicker yeah like
you're not going to get the actual
experience doing it but like you're
going to like you're going to learn
don't do ab c and d and then that's
going to keep you from fail you know
that's going to bring in like your
success to be like I know I'm not going
to fail this way and I know I'm not
going to screw it up this way like
listen to people around you that have
done it like don't be too egocentric
that you can't take advice from somebody
because if you get one shot a year it's
going to take a long time to get good
and you might as well talk to somebody
who's done it and get some like take
their input y I was just going to say
don't let pride and ego stand in your
way it's this is a it's it's hard to
grow really good cannabis um and not
necessarily because like the processes
are hard but because there's so many
different aspects to it that can fail
and without knowing what those things
are ahead of time or how to react to
them you can have this sort of Snowball
Effect and cause an avalanche to fall
down on the grow around you without
setting up those proper barriers to
prevent it well that too and like then
you talk about the whole atmosphere
online like from Instagram it's like but
it's so egocentric to grow weed like and
I don't like on a mass scale it's like a
personal pride and like everybody's ego
is literally tied to them growing weed
that like even new Growers like even if
you were to stumble upon Instagram like
this is the vibe that the whole industry
gives off and it's like this [__] you
I'm the best kind of vibe which I mean
when you get people with long experience
you people are showing off and there is
a there is ego in there and there is you
know pride in people's work but like
from an outside perspective if you were
just trying to get into it like looking
at all like the way that people think
and act about cannabis online is not
going to help you in reality like it's
all it's going to do is hold you back
and it's kind of gatekeeping in like a
like a brainwash way that everybody want
to acts like they're so good and you're
never going to get to their level which
is not true at all like I mean there's
plenty of people that are open to
discussing and giving advice but like
when you look at the Grand Vibe of
everything online it's telling you the
opposite and don't you don't need to
believe that nope yeah it's it's the
exact that is the exact opposite of
what's the truth to Growing um there are
more people that are going to be willing
to teach you how to grow and help you
along the way um especially when it
comes to trying to help fix something or
trying to help prevent something or
react to something or set up the best
practices ahead of time so that you
don't run into those issues there's so
many people that want to help new
Growers because without new Growers
getting into this it's it could
eventually become something stagnant
that does go to only the people who can
afford it and that's when we do start to
run into issues like we were talking
about earlier of larger companies being
the only source for cannabis and if
that's what can happen we want to try
and prevent that and by trying to
prevent that I think one of the best
ways that we can is by promoting hom
Growers to continue to grow um and to do
it as best as they possibly can
because it's you know it's just as easy
to produce enough for yourself as it is
to produce enough for yourself and a few
other people and other people see that
you can produce it for them maybe they
want to get into it and it can just
spread and spread and spread and
hopefully you know eventually you know
I've heard other people say we want to
over overgrow the nation where there's
just more Growers than people know what
to do with and so larger corporations
don't have an opportunity to enter the
market because there's just no demand um
something like that would be off 100%
And that's
like kind of like I don't want to sound
egocentric like I can go down to
dispensary and buy the most expensive
weed there and the stuff that I grow
like blows it out of the water like and
that's like where what you don't realize
is like or what people don't realize
this the like whoever's advertising you
that they have the best weed at the
dispensary or wherever is full of [__]
in its marketing 90% of the time I don't
want to say it always is like you're
going to find stuff that's really good
there but you're not going to find it
being advertised very heavily and
there's not going to be a lot of it it's
going to be very Niche definitely you
know it's not hard to get I mean I want
say it's not hard it's not impossible to
out compete a lot of the commercial
Growers just from the reason like
yes terms of quality it's not hard to
out compete like from a home grower
aspect and that's what people need to
realize too is that like people talk a
big game about a lot of the weed
especially in like the that commercial
sense and like the legal industry but
it's all hype 100 like not all of it but
it's there's a lot of fluff in there and
there's a lot of people that don't know
what they're doing and a lot of people
that have grew two years and now have a
job growing and like there's a lot of
there's a lot of a lack of Legacy in
that market that like is not it's not
hard to get up to where they're
at it's not it a lot of it like I said
earlier there's so much accessible
information online or through
communities or forums or uh chat groups
discords reddits Instagram Pages it's
everywhere really good Reddit I know a
really good Reddit page yeah we know a
pretty good Reddit page Artcraft
marijuana on Reddit check it out some of
the better Growers that you're going to
find within the Reddit cannabis sphere
um
yeah you know this has been a wonderful
conversation and I really appreciate
your insights into organic hom growing
especially as it pertains to outdoor
practices and maintaining a specific
level of quality and um high
expectations for what you want out of
the Cannabis that you are growing for
yourself um so I just have a few little
wrap-up questions to ask you wrap it up
that I like to ask everyone so um what's
your favorite strain of all time
my favorite strain of all
time oh that's a hard
question favorite strain of all time
turn noal is one of
them Lamb's bread or breath is one of
them and then Cinderella 99 is one of
them and I haven't smoked the new
Cinderella 99 but like it's hard to keep
strains through the decades you know
like so what I might have be saying is
what one of my fav Durban Poison but
Durban Poison when I was in like college
like' 07 not like the Durban I've seen
now but yes so like chernov
Cinderella and yeah those are two of my
favorites awesome those are some really
good ones um so then uh with those being
your favorite strains who would be your
uh favorite breeder of all time my
favorite breeder of all
time oh that's a hard one I have I have
one person that I really like based on
the work that I've grown and it's OB
obsolete is a really good breeder his
stuff I try to collect auctions seed
auctions get everything I can orange
cookies is one of his strains I grow I
don't want to say it's one of my
favorite strains of all time but that is
a very very nice plant and there's some
other stuff like orange Fruity Pebbles
I've grown him from him high octane he
has a lot of good stuff very cool very
cool all right and then just the last
little question here what is your most
memorable cannabis related
experience most memorable in a good or a
bad way I kind I kind of want to tell my
RAID story just so people that uh
haven't weren't around when this was a
thing understand this that sounds like
it could be a memorable story it was
very memorable so I worked at this this
the first job I had where I was running
the farm and it was the one I told you
about Lake County so it was on the side
of a mountain and it was off botle Rock
Road if you want to look it up in Lake
County I think it's Kelseyville
California so it's in the middle of it's
kind of in the middle of nowhere on the
side of this mountain and you had to
drive this really long you know windy
[__] Gravel Road that you could
barely get a car up to get there and I
think it was mid
August late August and I like where I
stayed was in The Shack on the side this
sounds really stupid but there was a
Shack on the mountain on stilts and so
there was a like a a shed basically on
top of these stilts and I remember
sitting there one day and it was
probably noon it was like in the middle
of the day when it was hot so I was
inside and I heard a car I'm like I
don't recognize this car I don't
recognize the sound of this car and so I
open the door up to the shack and I look
out and I have a bunch of guys pointing
AR-15s at me and so the sheriff had
walked up in front of the truck that was
driving so they were already at the door
so you get the full raid experience
they're screaming at you pointing guns
at you telling you to get on the ground
like I get out of there and at the time
I was on the side of mountain so I
didn't wear shoes the whole time Tippy
[__] so I get out of the I go out of the
shack they're screaming at me to get on
the ground freeze they're asking me
where my shoes are at I don't have any
shoes sh and they get up and you know
they're the tough guys you know so they
arrest me and I'm sitting there and I'm
shaking while they're putting me in
handcuffs and the guy looks at me he's
like why are why are you so nervous H
what are you nervous about and I was
like I've never been arrested before and
you see the look in these guys' face
just go from like they're you know
they've got the bad guy too like oh okay
and so they they handcuffed me they put
me up and they set me off to the side
and they sit there with the they take
the side by side and everything that's
on the property and it takes them 6
hours to cut all these plants down cuz
they're cage so they had me sitting
there watching them cut all these plants
down the that I spent all your growing
and dragging them in front of me and
putting on this whole you know
production that you know they like
you're you know like you know shame on
you look at all what we're
doing um it wasn't it wasn't very fun no
that's probably the most memorable one
that was the one that impacted me the
most I want say in a positive way but
kind of seeing how you always hear about
people getting raped and you hear about
like the past you know like the cops and
the helicopters like when you're
involved in that that is like they they
aren't [__] around oh that sounds
quite terrifying actually like it was a
little little traumatizing but it it
definitely made an impact on me for sure
well I mean it seems like you made it
out of there uh sem semi
unscathed I did make yes 100% it was a
whole it was a whole thing that ran on
for about 2 years but yeah for anybody
who's watching that wasn't around in the
in the Black Market Days like getting
rated is definitely a scary not fun
experience that I'm glad we've kind of
gotten past as a as a cannabis community
and law enforcement how well they don't
interact together wow well I mean that
is definitely a memorable cannabis
related experience that you know not a
lot of people are going to have to face
nowadays so um bringing up for them yeah
them that they don't have to experience
that me too well again Weston Peete this
has been a wonderful conversation thank
you so much for joining me today um do
you have any little shout outs or plugs
you wanted to give before we wrap it up
I just want to shout out ourcraft
marijuana uh shout out you thanks for
inviting me Nick and then uh if anybody
feels inclined to check out my Instagram
that'd be sweet I just uh I have a lot
of pictures of my grow and if you want
to get a hold of me on Reddit or
Instagram I'll answer anybody's
questions I have no problem talking
about what I do with anybody it'
probably be easier to get us some good
in-depth explanations when I have time
to think out my you know type out my
questions so if anybody wants to pick my
brain or ever contact me for information
open doors awesome well thank you so
much again and uh I hope you have a good
rest of your day I hope so too night
talking to you dude awesome peace
[Music]
oh