[Music]
Hello and welcome to another episode of
the way we grow podcast, a production of
the craft growers network. I'm your host
Nick Wolf. Today our guest is Liam
Spencer. You can find him at the Flying
Liam on Instagram. He is also the owner
of Series Cultivation where he helps
growers optimize their cultivation
process and facilities. He's also an
accounts executive with aoya.io and also
provides his cultivation expertise
through the Groworld A platform. Uh
Liam, welcome to the show. How are you
today? Thanks, Nick. Appreciate it.
Thanks for the intro. I'm doing well.
I've just been, you know, uh traveling a
lot, trying to keep up and um you know,
just uh really excited to be here and
have a conversation and see what we can
uh get into. For sure. Uh well, you come
highly recommended for having a um an
educated cultivation discussion by a few
different sources. And so I was really
excited to get you on the podcast today.
Um what's new in your grow world? you
you do a lot of different things and uh
kind of wear a few different hats. Uh is
there anything that's kind of been uh at
the tip of your brain lately?
Uh you know you being that that I'm
working with Aoya and I I started in
September of last year uh I've gotten a
lot of exposure to a lot of facilities
around the country and I I kind of cover
from uh Michigan all the way over to
Oregon. So I get to see sort of every
every stretch of the indoor and
greenhouse industry in uh in each state
and and you know just get an idea for
what people are doing, how they're doing
it and uh and kind of understand you
know what's working for people, what's
not working, best practices, what people
are are interested in. So the exposure
to that many facilities has been uh
really invaluable. Um, you know,
obviously I've was working for ScienceL
before and got to see quite a bit of of
facilities there, but uh kind of
expanding outside of Colorado, uh, the
Michigan market, uh, you know, really
highly compressed legacy markets and,
um, you know, really the the whole
breadth of, uh, of, uh, performance
across the board. So nice. That's really
been the most interesting focus for me
lately.
Um if if you can divulge anything uh
along these lines, I would love to hear
what are some of the most innovative
solutions that you've seen people uh
integrating into their cultivation
facilities that maybe you hadn't seen
elsewhere or you know it was just a
really uh ingenious application of
something that normally may not be in
that uh style of application.
Oh man, that's tough. There's a lot uh
there's a there's a lot going on and a
lot to it. And I think you know being
able to walk into a facility and see hey
these guys are really uh you know making
do with what they've got um doing the
best they can with what they have the uh
the sort of maggyvering and and
ingenuity. Uh it's across the board. I
mean you know people between different
methods of collecting runoff to
different ways of dehumidification.
um you know, sort of what what the uh
there's a lot of people running under
canopy lights lately that I've seen
getting great results. Uh there's a lot
of different, you know, people playing
with different spectrums. I see a lot of
mixed mixed indoor lighting, so HPS LED
combo. Um still see a ton of HPS lights
in the in the market. Uh but the guys
that are really performing well seem to
have a really good understanding of
staff and workflow in the facility.
their cost of goods is low. And I think
that, you know, some of these, you know,
to kind of answer your question on
specific applications, there are I've
seen some people really
uh string together their
own sort of solution when they can't
necessarily afford something like Aoya
or, you know, uh like a Agonomic IQ. Uh
there's there's quite a bit of hot gas
reheat going around. I've seen a lot of
people like kind of modifying their HVAC
units to get reheat and getting really
good results with stability in their
humidity in their grow rooms. Um I think
the the combination of HPS and LED does
help a little bit with um mitigating
some of the uh sort of high increase in
transpiration that you get under LEDs uh
alone. I mean, you still see that guys,
you know, putting far red at the end of
the day and and, you know, early in the
morning. Um, but yeah, I mean, it it's
it kind of all blurs together. I mean,
I've seen some pretty creative things,
you know, as far as benching and and
drainage goes. Um, you know, sort of
running
uh pipe drains under the benches or, you
know, stringing together irrigation
zones. But yeah, I mean, you kind of put
me on the spot there. It's kind of hard
to to No, you you kind of touched on all
the hot topics um which is really great
because um of course seeing it in
application in these different um you
know commercial
facilities it it does show that this is
where the market is looking right now.
This is at least on the cultivation
side. Uh you know people are kind of uh
forging a path whether it be through
these uh like far red light applications
or the um reheat applications of their
pre-existing air conditioners so that
they can get that better uh
dehumidification capacity for the
facility. These are all the things that
it you see a lot of people talking about
and have been talking about at least for
the past couple years. Um, so I that's
it's very I mean telling to say that it
is being seen in the market right now.
Um, but you know, I I do like to bring
this podcast a little bit back to your
origins as a cultivator because it
sounds like you have a wealth of
knowledge that you're tapping into when
you're addressing these different
solutions and seeing these different um
uh either problems arise that you're
helping tackle and then finding the
solutions for. And so that all has to
come from somewhere. Um, so all the way
back, what are some of the first
experiences you had with plants in
general, whether it be cannabis or not?
And then did it start with cannabis and
go to perhaps some vegetable gardening
here and there, or did you do any
vegetable gardening with, you know, mom
and dad or an uncle or an aunt or
something like that and then transition
any of that like passion or knowledge
into cannabis?
It's a really interesting question.
there's a lot of uh there's a lot of
cross-pollination across both of those
things. So, I think you know to say like
my journey with cannabis um started in
one area and my journey with gardening
kind of started separately of that.
Although when I was a kid and and in in
high school, you know, first started
consuming cannabis, um you know, we'd
always get bag seeds and try to toss
them out and we had these abandoned lots
in our neighborhood that we try to grow
stuff. Never really turned into
anything. And then when I I I didn't
really grow plants. I wasn't super
interested in growing plants as like a a
business or anything like um you know
professionally until I got into college
and I changed my major to environmental
science and I got into a couple of
classes like ethnobbatney
um and you know kind of led me down
towards horiculture. We had a community
garden uh on campus and you could go
there and just volunteer and work in the
garden. It was a pretty pretty decent
sized uh garden and you could just go
there and first time you volunteer
you're probably spreading mulch around
or you know double digging plots or
whatever uh was needed to be done and
then as you kind of progressed through
and got a little bit more experience
they started assigning showed some level
of proficiency too. They'd start
assigning more complicated tasks like
transplanting or propagation things like
that. And I got really into it. I was I
was like that this is really exciting,
you know, starting to get a closer
understanding of where my food came from
and and how to how to cultivate it in
different environments. And then I got
into uh aeroponic growing cuz we had a
program on campus for the it was through
like the um the wellness uh initiative
uh where we had these aeroponic tower
gardens planted all over campus. And I
helped build them and clean them and
take them down. And I got involved in
this project uh you know as a volunteer
uh where I'd go harvest and then
eventually got to a point where I
started giving these presentations and
kind of sharing how it worked and
teaching people about vertical gardening
and things like that. So that's where I
sort of got really really into the more
uh into the soilless growing and then
did that for a long time. had a lot of
people ask me if I if I grew cannabis or
if I was interested in doing that or did
it in in those aeroponic gardens and I
kind of was very resistant to it. Kind
of pushed back a little bit on it cuz I
had gotten in trouble for cannabis in
college and just kind of you know tried
to move away from from that a little bit
at that time. But then I I ended up
living in a house where I was able to we
had like an area where we could
cultivate in in the house that was
secret. Um, so I started playing around
with with tent growing and then um
translated that into when I graduated
college and I had kind of traveled I I
kind of left Orlando and I went to Costa
Rica, did my permaculture design course,
stayed there to work on the farm for a
couple months after that and then went
down to Ecuador and I did this like
indoor or it was um it was an urban
agriculture course And it was a once a
week class for a couple months. And I
got, you know, learned kind of like what
their strategies were for raised bed
gardening as well. And um yeah, once
once I kind of finished that and came
back to the the states, I was working
with a friend of mine who had a
business. He was starting a business
building garden beds for people in their
backyards and their front yards and
different kind of projects where he was
building vegetable gardens. And I got
really involved, you know, did a lot of
builds, did a lot of plantings, a lot of
workshops, things like that. And uh and
then I moved over to back to Orlando and
kind of helped build another similar
business up there that was a little bit
more high-profile, a little bit more
boutique for, you know, some of the more
uh upscale neighborhoods, community
gardens, things like that, living walls.
So, I got really deeply involved in
plants outside of cannabis for a while.
And eventually one of my friends started
working at Cur Leaf in Mount Dora in
Florida when they were opening kind of
before they brought plants in. And he
continually tried to convince me to to
join over there and I was a bit
resistant to it at first and finally
he's like, "All right, let's see what
this is all about. I'll get in the
commercial cannabis space." And about
what year was that? Uh that was 2018.
So cool. Yeah, it was it was uh it was
when Florida had gone medical. I think
True Leaf had already established a
couple facilities. Cure Leaf had a site
down in Homestead. Um but this was like
sort of their big project. It was about
6 acres of greenhouse and then they had
well by the time I left they had
expanded to building out about 250,000
ft of indoor. So went from a team of
like initially bringing on around 20
people. um ended up with over a hundred
in cultivation alone. Wow. And uh you
know probably even upwards of that. We
had to during co split into two shifts.
So half the cultivation team was on
three to four days a week and the other
half was split. But there were still you
know 100 people on each shift. So that's
crazy. Yeah, it was a massive operation.
Still still is uh really big and they're
still producing quite a lot of cannabis
over there. But that was my foray into
commercial cannabis outside of just tent
growing. And but I had so much
experience growing and gardening outside
of cannabis that I picked up a lot of
the the techniques and and the
procedures and practices quickly. But a
big focus was on operations and
efficiency and problem solving and
distribution of labor and staffing. That
was really where a tremendous amount of
value came because there was all of this
problem solving on a daily basis we had
to do to make the operations work and
keep the gears turning efficiently. Um,
and so kind of having to sequence like
dozens of different processes kind of
all happening at once and making sure
they all happened in a coordinated and
efficient effort was uh probably the
biggest part of the learning process
initially there. But then I got really
into the technology and the greenhouse
management and managing sort of the
climate in the greenhouse and using all
these different controls platforms like
Pa and Ritter. Um you know we had this
other old platform called UCOM which was
I guess micro grow. Um so we and then we
had a internal BAS system that was made
on site in house. Uh so there were all
these different programs I had to learn
and then had to help commission the
climate control system skid. So really
just got deep into uncovering how all
these controls and technologies worked
and figuring out how to optimize them to
get the best environment in that
greenhouse that we could cuz it was
really uh a lot of poor design decisions
went into that. So a lot of maggyvering
and problem solving. Do you mind uh
talking a little bit more about your
time at Curleaf? And um I feel like with
such a large facility, you could
probably see some of the um some of the
best aspects of the commercial
cultivation uh industry as well as some
of the the potentially the worst parts
of the commercial cultivation industry
just you know in terms of efficiencies
or discrepancies. Um you know there's a
lot there to probably unpack and
whatever you feel comfortable with.
Yeah. No, I mean there's definitely a
lot to unpack. I I you know I fully uh
acknowledged that there were there was a
lot of
um poor decisions that were made uh over
there and they they learned a lot the
the company as a whole learned a lot uh
in the process of retrofitting and then
building out on that property. So, you
know, they're they're they spent quite a
lot of money on trying to retrofit the
greenhouse and initially there was some
guidance to retrofit it to make it more
uh representative of an indoor space
within the greenhouse and you know with
the intention being that hey you know
maybe we can use AC to mitigate some of
the external heat coming from Florida
outdoor environment but the execution
was uh there were a lot of challenges
and a lot of um turnover on the dire
ctor side. Uh we had a lot of leaders in
that facility turn over every few months
and I think a lot of that just came down
to like you know playing a blame game or
or trying to
um trying to understand like why certain
decisions that were made that spent a
decent amount of capital weren't
yielding results or turning into
positive outcomes. Um, you know, that
was a big part of what I was trying to
to do there was, hey, we had, when I
came in there, they had taken a lot of
the aspects of the greenhouse that were
functioning and growing orchids
beforehand and sort of shut them off and
and tried to, you know, do what they
could to seal off the environment or
make it an indoor environment. And that
was um probably not the the best
decision in the long run, but I I kind
of understand where they were coming
from. I think they they you know quickly
realized that Florida greenhouse
conditions are not optimal for cannabis
of any variety. Although some like we
had Afghani that usually performed
pretty well um handled the tropical
climate much better than some of the
other cultivars that were brought over
from Colorado. Uh but yeah, I mean, you
know, just with that large of a site and
growing and expanding that quickly,
there's always going to be issues. I
mean, I don't think that there really
had been many facilities across the
country of that size and that scale up
until that point. So, nobody really knew
how to turn that into a um a proper
production site, uh you know, anywhere.
So, I mean, it sounds daunting. Yeah,
it's a huge learning curve and and
there's, you know, everyone's always
going to make bad decisions when, you
know, but as long as you learn from
them. I think building the indoor was a
good decision on their part. Um, just to
produce the volume and quality that they
kind of were anticipating out of the
greenhouse like just wasn't happening.
So um yeah I I I I think uh you know
without trying to look back from an
objective place of like hey you know
what were we trying to accomplish there
the team on site the the team on the
ground we really did well fending for
ourselves a lot and kind of as this
revolving door of of uh direction was
happening we figured out a way to kind
of stabilize and ground ourselves to be
able to manage all the people we had to
manage. I mean, I had over 40 people
that I had to be responsible for at one
point. Um, and then I kind of
transitioned more into just fully taking
on the responsibility of managing the
lights and the curtains and the, you
know, all of the uh mechanical aspects
and really kind of dived into to deeply
into learning the technology that was at
our disposal because they had, you know,
there were thousandgalon batch tanks for
each zone that were hand mixed every day
in that site. There were guys in this
the water room just mixing tanks all day
for a long time. They they didn't have
any sort of dosing system set up or not
until they commissioned the climate
control system skid which was towards
the end of my time there. Wow. I left in
uh end of summer of 2020 when COVID kind
of it was a there was a a big transition
during that
period and I had um I had to report to
somebody who came in very recently who I
had to coach and train and and educate
that um that was basically I I I would
say it it made me feel a little bit um
undervalued. dude on on site there. Um,
you know,
without saying too much, I just didn't
really uh I didn't feel appreciated or
respected for the amount of sacrifices
and time and effort I made. So, I
started looking for other opportunities
and got the chance to move to Colorado
to to to work on indoor craft
cultivation, which was a piece that I
was really interested in that I hadn't
had the chance to do up until that
point. For sure. I I I mean the um the
underappreciated and overworked aspect
is something um I I come from a culinary
background before I got into cultivation
and it was of of course it was like
taking people who were passionate about
something and um abusing that passion
for the gains of the company because
they were willing to put in all that
effort because they were searching for
knowledge themselves, right? And uh when
given an opportunity with, you know,
such a large facility, I would almost
look at that going in and be like, "Oh
my god, this playground that I've been
given, I can learn so much from what
they have to offer here." But then all
that effort and you then you have to
train the person who's taking over the
position that's going to lead you. Uh
that doesn't sound like a good
leadership decision. I can I can
understand that. Um and it does seem
like an underappreciation.
Yeah, I mean there's a lot that goes
into that sort of decision, right? Like
I understand there's a level of uh like
I think I preach this often, but
staffing, leadership, and culture are
really what drive performance in a lot
of ways because when you have a team
that's passionate, that feels
appreciated. um they continue to work
hard to continue to elevate that as
especially when they see upward mobility
or at least being treated well and being
being shown some
appreciation that goes a really long way
especially compounding over larger and
larger teams. Um I think I see the most
successful gardens have the most
cohesive and um cultural teams when I
when I visit facilities. kind of going
back to what I was saying before, but um
you know what I what I learned through
Cure Leaf, which subsequently translated
in into what I did briefly at Begood,
but um just finding just having uh
quality communication between people and
teams and feeling like we're humans
outside of of the garden. Uh you know,
that goes a really long way.
And there's there's often uh not a lot
of resources allocated towards, you
know, team appreciation. And I worked at
Whole Foods before I worked in the
cannabis industry. And they did a lot to
try to keep the culture before Amazon
got involved, but they did a lot to try
to like promote culture within the
company and, you know, team building
things like that. So there's there's a I
think with big companies, it's often
challenging to get that right because
there's so many different variabilities
from sight to sight and the type of
people that are available to work at
each place. It it is very hard and and
you often do have to bring people on
from outside, especially to higher
positions. But promoting from within. I
mean, there's some guys I I have a
friend out in Nevada who's very much a
uh very fond of promoting from within
and training and bringing people up. And
I think your greatest success comes from
having people that work that once worked
under you at a certain point um elevate
to that level of success to be able to
go out, you know, like like it's a it's
a compliment when you hire somebody and
then they get offered a position, you
know, at that director or manager level
outside. it it it feels good to know
that that person's skill set is is
evolved and competent enough to take on
that kind of role. Um, for sure. So, I I
I really think investing in your people
uh makes the big all the difference in
the world, especially in markets that
are really tight and very bleak and
people don't feel like it's nice when
everything's going well and everyone's
making money and you're all bonusing
out, you know, but when you're having
hard time paying the bills and paying
your team and all that, like it's uh
morale is very easily dropped and it's
very infectious when you have low morale
in both ways. is morale is a very
infectious aspect of the garden. So, I
couldn't agree more. I that's like some
of the biggest things that I feel like
the industry faces right now is um in
this downturn that we're all facing is
keeping the morale high enough so that
the there's still a continued strive for
excellence in the product that's being
produced because it can so easily fall
to the wayside if if you're feeling
underappreciated or if you don't feel as
though there is any hope for the future.
Basically, you know, when you look at
this and you go, man, over the past 5
years, we have not been necessarily
trending towards
uh uh you know, this high profit margin
that we were at at one point. Um and so
I I I think that investing in your team
is extremely important uh at all times,
but especially when times are tough. Um
yeah, I mean, if you're really good,
it's easy for you to get taken advantage
of uh as well. Um, you know, there was I
there was a point at in at my journey at
BEG Good that I was solely responsible
for about 150 light 140 light facility
and I didn't have any
full-time team members over on that
site. And, you know, I just had to make
it work and kind of continue to keep the
operation going and turning crops and
turning cycles around. Even though the
facility was horribly inefficient, there
was no capital to be able to invest cuz
there was, you know, uh a previous
contract grower that had uh some
conflicts with the ownership and there
was just a lot of uh mismanagement of
resources and um leading to kind of a
zero sum game where you're driving your
cultivators to do more and more work,
you know, less and less people. Um
that's that seems to happen a lot where
you're you're like running down to a
skeleton crew. So there's a fine line
between operational efficiency with
minimum amount of labor required to get
each task done and there's a whole you
know between that and like just having
the absolute barest bones people on
staff to just keep the building open and
you just expect way too much of those
people. They have to come in on the
weekends all the time. That's just not
really fair and not sustainable long
term. And if somebody's really good and
they can do it, that doesn't necessarily
mean that you should make them uh Mhm.
you know, so especially with no stake in
the business or no and and that's a
tricky game, too, is like equity is not
usually the right move for like a
cultivator, but it can be. It's just a
matter of what is the capacity and what
is the potential future of this
business. I've seen so many cultivations
in Colorado alone just turn over and go
out of business or shut down. Uh it's uh
even some of the the what I thought
would be some of the more quality um
businesses, they just they can't get
their cost of goods down. They can't get
their price their selling price high
enough. They can't pump out enough
consistent crops regularly. I mean,
those are some of the key pain points
that you see a lot with compressing
markets that are built upon a high price
per pound initially. Like Colorado took
a while to compress, so people didn't
realize that $2,000 pounds were not
really reasonable anymore until it was
too late. They just kept holding on to
that. There's so many people using
products like BioBiz and um Mills or all
these different products that are crazy
high price point per gallon mixed. and
um still just you know running that
because they didn't want to accept the
truths as they were coming down the
pipeline of the prices continuously
falling. And then once you have to learn
how to run uh with a lower overhead and
input cost, you start to just see all of
these other problems arise because you
aren't transitioning in a holistic way.
You're kind of slamming the brakes and
pulling a U-turn. So, um, yeah, I mean,
I would say that the gravity of impact
of input costs changes at different
scales. Like, I still see guys that are
running house and garden, but they're
doing well cuz they're getting higher
price per pound and the quality and
flavor of their product is better, but
they're smaller. They're putting out,
you know, very, you know, like somewhere
around 100 to a couple hundred pounds a
month as opposed to large facilities. So
when you're talking to like the gravity
of those those quantifiable changes in
input costs, a couple cents per gallon
maybe makes more of a difference at um
at a facility that's selling commodity
product. So you have to use something
that's going to be way more cost
effective because now you're talking
tens of thousands of dollars a week or a
month as opposed to like a couple
hundred bucks per crop cycle. Um, sure.
You know, I think that's that you you
have to distinguish what what context
you're talking about because not always
is the change in lower fertilizer cost
can reflect in a better business
outcome. Uh, and that's something that I
think often is overlooked where we speak
in absolutes about I just need cheaper
cocoa. I just need cheaper nutrients. I
need what? Cheap lights. Like you know
all these factors are much more
complicated than just speaking from
directly a price point cuz if you're
talking economics you have to build out
the whole proforma on that equipment
almost every time. Otherwise you don't
really understand the the downstream
financial impacts of getting a $300 LED
that may go out in two years or that
degrades or the spectrum shifts over
time or whatever the problem might be.
or you know, you get cheap sensors to
monitor your substrate and then you have
to constantly calibrate them and there's
tons of labor going into that or
whatever the the case may be where
you're actually downstream causing you
know higher uh labor or um you know
costs to like let's say you know you get
I mean I'm not maybe don't need to use
the sensor thing but you get a cheap
piece of equipment and now you're not
trusting that what you're seeing is
accurate or real and you can't make
decisions off of it. Uh, you know,
there's things like that. Like cheap
cocoa has inconsistencies in volume, in
salinity levels. Uh, rockwool, you know,
there's there's so many different
aspects to input cost. I often look
above consumables to just like, you
know, operating cost as a whole of like,
okay, are you renting the building? Are
you um, you know, what is your what are
your licensing fees on a regular basis?
And then how many pounds do you need to
produce to get uh to get to that point
uh to of what is profitable? And the
economies of scale are so market
subjective like Arizona has a lot of
massive facilities. Well, they're
limited license. So those massive
facilities don't have to produce premium
topshelf flower all the time to sell all
their product out, you know. But
Colorado, there's a way more there's a a
way higher
uh volume of producers to consumers. So
it's, you know, it's a bit more diluted
and saturated. So I I would say that you
have to have a high quality product and
check all the boxes in order to have a
good brand with with marketing that's
successful. That's and and that's where
you you maybe know producing a few
hundred pounds a month is probably too
much. Uh you want to have market
scarcity.
Yeah, we I think we only do produce
uh like around 60 pounds a month or so
at at our facility. I'm not 100% sure on
that, so don't quote me, but we
um I mean it it seems to work better to
have a little bit of
uh underprouction or scarcity like you
said so that the market uh is just
continuously eating up whatever it is
that we put out. Um, but even still with
the downturned price, it's it's crazy. I
I uh I I I do hope that at some point
maybe that there is just like more uh
quality recognition for brands and stuff
because sometimes it feels as though the
the branding doesn't necessarily reflect
the quality and uh that can always be a
little bit of a hindrance for the
consumer when they go based off of what
they see through social media or
otherwise. Um
brand brand um transparency and like
having a brand that stands up for a
specific thing and and tries to do its
best to fulfill that is is key. I mean,
there have been brands here in Colorado
that have fallen because their quality
dropped off and they were a quality
brand and they lost all consumer trust
because their their quality started
dropping off and then they just fell off
and fell out of the market. So, you do
have to be consistent and honest and
transparent with your brands. Uh, a and
make sure that you're not overselling
your brands and saying, "Hey, this is a
super premium quality brand at a high
price point, but you look at the the
product quality on the shelf next to
another brand and it's it's there's a
huge difference. So what those quality
metrics are is so uh so variable uh and
and I would I would even venture to say
like subjective
um or sorry objective but the uh the end
of the day like what every consumer
shops for product for a different reason
but when you look at market trends a lot
of people are shopping still on potency.
Um, potency doesn't always directly
correlate to quality, but quality has a
lot of other metrics. I mean, your brand
has to be honest and representative of
the product you're putting into the
market and know what your target
customer base is and satisfy
them. Not everyone's going to be the
best quality producer in the state. You
know, not everybody wants that. So if
you're trying to sell to the top to 10%
of the of the market and there's a you
know 40% of the industry is trying to do
the same thing. I mean there's only so
much
room. Yeah, that makes a lot of sense.
Um it does seem to be this uh this
constant battle between quality and
quantity that you hear a lot but I mean
there are ways to achieve both
especially at the scale um that where
it's feasible for that scale and um yeah
it doesn't seem like it is even possible
to have all of you know if you say 40%
of the brands are trying to v for that
top 10% of the spots um it may just be
better to, you
know, take accept that maybe there's
brands that are better than yours and
just try to find your niche elsewhere
rather than be in that top 10%. That
seems like a very hard
uh uh that that almost seems like a
heavy crown to wear cuz then you have to
maintain it. Mhm. Absolutely. Yeah. And
every brand has changes in quality and
consistency over over the years. You
know, it's it's an unavoidable aspect,
but the tighter you can get your
operations and this goes beyond branding
10, you know, being in that top 10%.
Right.
So, I think uh you know it goes it goes
getting to that point of consistency to
be able to put out that product in that
top 10% goes a lot it goes far beyond
you know just your parameters in your
cultivation and being able to repeat
your processes whether it's irrigation
or environment genetic selection is a
huge piece of that. So like really
making sure that you're driving new
genetic material into the market and
bringing in quality cultivars that are
sort of setting the pace, right? Because
otherwise you're just chasing and you do
have to have a stable of
of you know your sort of staple
cultivars that people like to consume
and know how to maximize those and bring
those to consistency. But yeah, you
know, again, it's it's you I couldn't
tell you like, okay, you need 50% of
your garden to be these cultivars that
are always selling out that everybody
wants and 50% to be new. I think that's
just always going to be a product of
what your feedback is from the retail,
you know, from from your buyers. And and
so many of these markets are like uh
retail plus wholesale. So they're the
strains that the wholesale buyers want
are all often times much different than
what the retail buyers want, but the
retail buyers are only buying small
volumes. So you have to figure out how
to satisfy demand without distributing
resources too
far. Yeah, it is that is a great um
description of what we're facing here in
the Oregon market right now. um the the
wholesaler versus the retailer and and
just kind of what each of them are
looking for. And it's unfortunate
because the retailer is usually looking
for higher quality and are more willing
to pay a higher price for that quality
because they have the you know that
direct knowledge of their uh customers
and who's going to come in and buy you
know 2 ounces a month of that product
for the next month and they so they they
already know that they have that sold
basically. Um whereas wholesalers, you
know, you just go in and they say, "What
do you got for cheap? What's the buy one
uh get one half off?
Uh what's your deals of the week?" Um so
that that always is a a huge difference
in in what they're looking for. Yeah. So
you're probably prioritizing the
retailers, but then the retailers only
can buy so much at a time. And then you
have to have, you know, accounts
receivable for a lot of these guys,
these retailers, because they can't
necessarily pay cash on delivery. And
for you to get into all of these
retailers, you have to agree to some
kind of terms in some cases. Um, so
yeah, they're paying the higher price
point. It may take a little longer for
you to get the money, but you're going
to get more. But then you have to have
somebody fully dedicated to chasing down
new orders and collecting and you know
that that game just becomes high labor.
Uh whereas with wholesalers if you can
you know just work with a few guys that
are purchasing a large volume at a time
and they're they maybe are paying lower
um you know lower price for your product
and are less discretionary on the
quality. uh that that still is a high
portion of your market. So maybe
allocating time and energy to satisfying
those customers if they're still driving
profits because they're much lower uh
labor cost. That's a that's that's
another whole decision. Everybody wants
to be in all the stores and have their
product brand be at the top and get all
that highest price point, but it just
takes so much because you have all the
packaging aspects, all the marketing.
you have to, you know, go to these
dispensaries sometimes, set up a table,
educate the consumers, you know, there
there's a lot that goes into that. And
that's not really my my
um sort of knowledge base. I'm not very
I mean, we had retails when I was
working at BG Good that we were so we
sold directly out of a lot of our
product out of our own retail and uh you
know, a lot of the strains that I was
cultivating either I was bringing in and
they would say, "Hey, this is really
great. We got great feedback. Grow more
of that." or they were like, "Hey, do
you have this? Can you grow this? Can
you do?" And it was like this constant
struggle between because when you're
vertical, you know, you have to balance
satisfying the customer demands with
what is actually production viable in
the facility. Everybody wants, you know,
I don't know what people I mean, a lot
of people
wanted very specific things like these
really old sativas or like a Durban or
something. And we had some stuff that
had it in it that was more production
viable. Um, but it was this constant
battle between like product quality
meeting different shelf demands. So we
were putting certain products on the top
shelf, other strains would go into the
middle shelf. And so we were trying to
cover all the bases with one cultivation
in a couple retails that were hitting
all the tiers in the shelves. And I
don't know that there was a lot there
there was a little bit of a still a
disconnect there. But from the
cultivation, our focus a lot was on like
what is revenue generating? And you
know, I learned a lot and you know, we
made a lot of mistakes in terms of like
chasing flavors and wanting to grow
certain strains cuz we liked them cuz we
thought they were good and we thought
they would sell and people would want to
buy them. Then we put it out and then
they didn't. But then we had all these
genetics and production. So we made a
lot of uh a you know we made some
oversight uh mistakes in terms of you
know the business aspect of of producing
cultivars for the the consumer. But
often times, you know, the the
cultivation would be backed up on
certain flower cuz the retail couldn't
sell at all cuz we didn't have a lot of
customers coming in. And then it was
just back and forth. And then sometimes
they'd clear us out and then we'd be
we'd be running behind and it was just a
very much like a a roller coaster in
some in some capacities. Sometimes we
did better than others. So there was a
bit of a disconnect and I think that you
know having the operations that when you
when you are vertical uh the that can be
really uh insulating and and really
positive for a lot of companies because
you're not subject to wholesale bulk
prices. You know you can if you can move
your product. So you have to scale it
properly. How much are we producing? How
much are we selling out of the stores?
we make sure that we if we overproduce,
can we still get a wholesale price that
makes this product worthwhile and viable
and profitable? Um, and do we want our
product in other people's stores? Like
then maybe we do want to sell out some
of our premium brands. You know, there's
a lot of different things and and that's
just Colorado. I mean, I'm not as
familiar with the retail game in Oregon,
but I know I can imagine from what I've
heard it's challenging as well. Yeah,
definitely. I don't I don't know. Um, I
mean there's a couple vertically
integrated uh cultivation and um retail
spots, but you know, not a bunch of uh
sort of the mom and pop style um
vertically integrated spaces that were
like in Colorado or uh Michigan. Uh you
know, I I believe when Michigan first
went recreational, everything had to be
vertically integrated. Um and so things
like that, it Yeah, I don't I don't see
that much out here in Oregon. Um, but
you know, when you first entered into
the Colorado market after leaving
um, uh, Florida, what were some of the,
uh, facilities that you you were working
with um, other than be good? And then
tell us some more of the like what you
saw and how you developed more of your
um, like the key points in which you
direct your cultivation knowledge. Now,
um, what were some of those things that
you saw?
You know, I I tried to connect with as
many people in the industry when I moved
to Colorado as I could because I had a
lot of guys that I'd worked with at
Curleaf in Mount Dora that came from
Colorado. They came from a bunch of
different companies like Greenman and,
you know, um, Native Roots and things
like that. So, I tried to build my
network out there and made some friends
that were really knowledgeable. That was
where I first really got introduced to
precision irrigation or crop steering or
kind of you know some of these more uh
advanced and I guess more precise uh
strategies. But it gave me the
opportunity to like get out there, see
what other people were doing, make some
friends, and then kind of get some ideas
and bounce feedback off some of my
colleagues where I could really make all
the decision a lot of the decisions.
Financially, not so much, but at least
like cultivation practices like
substrate are we growing in? Uh, you
know, h how are we watering? Um, you
know, what nutrients are we using? uh
you know some of these these less
infrastructural more kind of subjective
arbitrary kind of things that were based
on per grower preference and grower
style. So it was easy to pivot cuz the
first grow that I was running was 125
lights and then we had a ton of
neighbors. It was in a it's in an area
that uh was no was initially and when
Colorado went went legal, a lot of
people started building grows in this
particular zone. And so there were uh
there were tons of of facilities in that
area. So there were tons of growers
there. So it was easy to kind of
connect. But then obviously through co
people stopped hanging out and
connecting. Uh there was a bit of
isolation. Um, but yeah, I mean, you
know, I got I kind of got to meet some
of the bigger players and some people
who were doing doing things well, but a
lot of people and still to this day, but
especially back then, a lot of people
had not adopted drip irrigation even or
um uh you know, LEDs were just everyone
was very resistant to to upgrading
technologies and getting new things and
you know um it was it was it was
definitely uh eye opening to see how
many people were so committed to this
like home grower style growing strategy
and you know being able to like dive
into you know I worked with EST Tech
Lighting that's how I met David um and
he introduced me to a lot of different
technologies you know Aoya obviously was
uh partially through him just as in he
was one of the few people I knew
actually had used at that point and I
had done a demo with them but we we got
priced out a little bit And so there
were these like different
uh different things like LEDs and how to
use them properly cuz a lot of people
struggled to get yield with LEDs in
Colorado. And a lot of it was
infrastructural like people with
drywall. Everyone has mold problems
here. Everybody's dealing with betritis
or some kind of a aspiggillis
contamination where they have to
decontaminate flour and they don't have
the facilities to drive clean
infrastructure. That's one of the things
that's really nice about Michigan is
people built these grows with like DPS
paneling and uh you know a lot of the
right um not all I mean by by no means
is it like overall kind of dialed but uh
people did things a bit better because
they learned from the mistakes of the
Colorado guys and maybe Oregon. you see
a lot of drywall, a lot of exposed wood,
a lot of spray foam, a lot of things
that are like uh potential surface area
contamination risks. And you know, I
think that's a a major thing I learned a
lot about working there was how to
manage uh microbial issues in the garden
and how to manage pest issues as well.
But uh because we had so many grows
nearby, we had so many vectors for
issues and guys working in the grow that
home home grows or whatever. But yeah,
dealing with betritis and mold and that
sort of thing. Like I tried the reactive
oxygen generators, hepoiltration, UV,
PCO, whatever. You know, I tried all
these different ways to passive and
active sanitation, spraying, zero. I
mean, everyone was doing tons of
different things. No one really knew a
good solution. Everyone's rad sourcing
flowers. So,
um, yeah, I mean, you know, to to touch
back on your point of like what did I
learn? What did I see? Being so close to
so many different craft grows and being
able to make a lot of those decisions.
Obviously, I didn't get to choose the
HVAC or the lighting or the racking or
anything. So, we had a huge problem with
runoff where we really weren't able to
drive much runoff cuz we didn't have
floor drains. Um, we had to learn how to
steer our plants with the least amount
of water and fertilizer we could
um to get the the desired outcomes,
which was very limiting and very
challenging to get yield because we were
having hard times bulking obviously uh
and making sure that our pH and runoff
was in balance. But, you know, that was
some of the the stuff that was a little
bit newer to me when I got there that I
think I developed a really high level of
proficiency in was just doing what I
could with what I got. you know, like
having to problem solve and troubleshoot
and figure out a way around it around,
you know, limitations.
I feel like that builds such a great
foundation though for um future
knowledge application, right? So,
because now you have um the
understanding of how the parts work, you
can take those parts and uh reassemble
them in a way that works better for uh
the scenario that you then have at hand
in the future. Um, and I I always like
to think of it as like a big puzzle,
right? And you're you're building that
border of the puzzle. And when you get
that last corner piece in or side piece
in, everything else starts to just kind
of fall into place. Um, but it is a a
puzzle at first trying to figure out
where the different pieces go. Then once
you see it, you get that bigger picture
and you can kind of plug and play with
all those different things that you've
built your knowledge on over years of uh
you know experiencing
uh let's say like a water line fails or
you need a bypass on something or you
need some redundancy in your airflow or
your dehumidification or something
because oh it went down this one time
and the whole room turned into a giant
mold fest. Um so you you you see all
these things over time and you start to
build uh a bigger resilience for issues
as they get thrown at you. Yeah,
absolutely. I mean you know dealing with
the well if this happens then we do this
always as a result of having p you know
real world experience with those things.
It's very hard to solve problems that
you've never dealt with without the
right tools or at least some sort of
reference. And not being afraid to ask
experts for help or people that you know
have a higher level of knowledge or
experience on something. I did that a
lot in the beginning. I relied a lot on
my network and my people to be like,
"Hey, what do I do about this? What this
is going on? What would you do in this
situation? Hey, we had this outbreak or
we had this um or I had this person who
was really challenging to work with." uh
you know all these things like a water
line busted, a pump went down, uh I had
to handwater, you know, there were times
when our fertigation skid. I won't say
you know uh who it was, but yeah, like I
went to go upgrade cuz we had to do this
in order for the skid to function, we
had to upgrade the firmware in the or
the software and I had to replace this
component and it was like over a weekend
and the whole thing failed. So, I had to
come in overnight and hand water
rockwool like in two flower rooms just
spent the whole night watering uh hand
watering rockwool and like that was just
like a really Yeah, it was like there
was no other way to do it. I couldn't,
you know, get my fertilizer to mix. So,
there's little things like that happen
where oh, we had a room flood cuz a
solenoid valve stayed open. Um, how do
you bounce the plants back from getting
flooded like entirely flooded with RO
water all night? you know, what do you
do? You you you don't want to overwater
them, you know, and fortunately at that
time I was playing around with some
dissolved oxygen bubblers and like
little things like, okay, like I know if
this this situation happens based on
this situation that happened to me
before, like this is what I I think
would be the outcome and what I could
see being being the outcome.
Um but uh but I I you know I I even to
this day I still rely a lot on on
feedback and and ideas from my
colleagues and I think that's help
what's helped me just in the
resourcefulness aspect right like
figuring out how to problem solve and
troubleshoot things when like building
my own env you know I worked with one of
the guys at the company to build our own
environmental controls platform because
we didn't have one and we just had
thermostats and it was like how are we
managing our environment with wall
thermostats and wall humidistats. So, we
start we got some Ecobees, we got some
relays, we took the home assistant
program and we put it all up and built
this dashboard, sent protocols and
signals and we could look at our
trending data over time and like, you
know, that that worked like to an
extent. It wasn't great, but it was
better than not having anything, you
know. Um, yeah. So, uh, so little things
like that or like building out a full
irrigation system in a grow that was
handwatered without any resources. Like
I had to figure out where to get tanks
and pumps and solenoids and PVC piping
and just scrap it from different places.
The old grow, whatever it was, put it on
my orders for nutrients. So, it wasn't
like, you know, adding to the cost. Like
little things like that. and and you
know coming into a grow that had three
bedrooms and they're all open to like
whenever you walk into the grow you walk
right into the mom room and there's
spidermite webs and okay how do we fix
this and consolidate the the amount of
the education I got on solving problems
in a highly dysfunctional environment
and grow across many of the facilities
that I've operated in is I think you
know like there's there's an aspect to
it that's like
um you know you learn a lot about what
not to do and and design and build, but
you also learn how to like make do with
what you got and figure out how to get
get to optimal, not ideal, you know, and
that's a conversation I have with people
often is, you know, we chase ideal and I
chased ideal for a long time of like
what is the ideal conditions? What are
the what's the ideal environment? What's
this ideal substrate look like? But if
you don't have ideal conditions, like
ideal like, you know, a setting that is
um sort of and nothing's really truly
ideal, I guess, cuz you could always
take it to the next step. But, you know,
making the best out of the environment
you have, which might mean, hey, at
night time, we can't turn our nighttime
temps down because we don't have enough
dehumidification to pull out to keep
that 1.2 or 3 VPD at 70. So, we can't
go down to 70. Um, but So, what do we do
instead? How do we solve that problem?
You know, we can't run the rooms as
cold, whatever the case may be. We can't
buy more dehumidification. Um, that sort
of thing, like, you know, you're like,
okay, well, what's going to be the best
outcome with what we do have to work
with? For sure. And, you know, if we
can't run our plants off, how do we
stack EC and then also drive EC down in
the substrate later in flower? Um,
right. I feel like it's um it's a common
thread on this podcast that we end up
bringing up Liebig's law and the
different staves of the barrel and how
if you have a limiting factor in one of
those staves, then the water is just
going to overflow before it hits the top
of the barrel. But a lot of people look
at that and they say, "Hey, I want to
bring that stave all the way up so that
you have a full barrel." But sometimes
they need to think maybe I just need to
cut the rest of the barrel off where
that stave is so that I can get optimal
performance at the um you know the you
have your limiting factor bring
everything else down to operate within
the the best possible parameters for
that limiting factor. Sometimes you end
up uh doing much better than you would
think you would be doing when you say oh
I'm operating at 75%. how can I I'm not
going to get 75% of my product.
Sometimes you end up getting 85% or 90%
of what you might have got at 100%
because sometimes you have diminishing
returns on yield um based on you know as
you you can only give it so much before
you start to see diminishing returns.
And so um I that's a very very valid
point. And I'm glad you brought that up
because we tend to bring this up all the
time on the podcast and I feel like
especially for home growers or smaller
commercial cultivators. Um you do get
kind of lost in the sauce of I want the
best. I want to have everything perfect.
I I got to make sure that I I just
optimize optimize. And then eventually
you start to see a I can't really get
past this one point. Ah it's okay. just
bring everything back down there cuz you
were probably producing some fire flour
at that level or just consistent, you
know, like you're not over you're not
frying your plants by just over revving
the engine. Yeah. And and I think
there's some nuance to that too. Uh
the um what I what I have noticed is
like let's just take CO2 for example,
right? like if
you which other levers or which other
staves in that barrel are more impacted
by a limitation on CO2. Um like cuz and
this I I bring this up cuz I've seen
this in facilities recently here in
Colorado there's like sometimes a uh a
shortage and like you have CO2 and then
the next day you don't and so you don't
have it for a certain period of time.
you have to make real-time adjustments
to your light intensity and you know
even your nutrient inputs and uh your
irrigation strategies because you're not
assimilating as much carbon into that
plant. Um so that CO2 uptake can maybe
it has a heavier relationship on uh
water demand but also your your light
intensity has to be uh equally changed.
So, you know, and and this is more
open-ended, too, but to say like, you
know, some of these limitations like how
I can only do three irrigation events a
day on my irrigation controller. Okay.
Well, can we even is it even worth
trying to do P2s if you're only getting
three events? Like, maybe we can't bulk
our plants properly and we don't want
channeling. So, we're like, well, how do
we first of all, the easy like obvious
thing would be, hey, how do we get more
events? Let's put an open sprinkler in
or whatever it is. But maybe there's
sometimes where you just don't have that
option
uh or don't have the capital, you know,
and and maybe that's a bad uh a bad
example, but you're like, well, you
know, maybe it's a good thing we can't
bulk because we actually can't pull that
much moisture out of the room that, you
know, we we don't have enough dehue to
pull as much water that we're putting
into the room out. And that's an
infrastructural thing. Um or we just
have too many strains in one irrigation
zone. We're trying to water too many
different strains all the same way
because we need to have this much
variety, but we don't have that much
control, you know? I mean, and and you
still see cultivations that have like
multiple stages of flower in the same
room. I mean, I've seen it recently, and
it kind of shocks me still, but um to be
able to to say, hey, we have one room,
so we have to keep the environment the
same for all the plants in all stages of
growth. The only things we can change is
irrigation strategy. uh and nutrient
maybe even potentially nutrient inputs,
but if you have one or two batch tanks
for the whole room, you know, there's
little like nuances to this stave, you
know, the the height of each stave in
the barrel at at each time. Uh it would
be really interesting to dive deeper
into the specific dynamics of
relationship between one one stave to
another over leveling the whole
equalizer. like, you know, we're we're
looking at a sound board and we're
trying to equalize everything, right? I
I I like that a lot because yeah, just
cutting it all off at that one stave may
not actually be optimal. Um, and you
know, if it is maybe that only two other
staves need to be lowered in order for
you to continue to operate at an op uh
an option optimal output, then um you
should probably do that rather than
limiting everything. especially if by
limiting everything else, you're also
either reducing quality or quantity or
um potentially uh inviting other issues
like mold or mildew or other things like
that. And um so yeah, that's a very the
nuances are are extremely important and
uh those are also subjective for the
facility that you're looking at or for
the home growth situation that you're
looking at. You know, like one of the
biggest things that I see home growers
struggle with if they're just growing in
a tent is um their exhaust versus intake
and the positioning for those two. If if
the tent needs
to go hotter, then you need to make sure
that you're pulling hot air in and
putting it in at the bottom. And if it
needs to go cooler, you need to pull
cool air in and put it in at the top so
that it can come down over the light.
And it's just like little tiny nuances
that you um you can optimize but
definitely need to know the situation
that you're facing um in order to do so.
Um so after Yeah. And so after uh you
kind of went into the Colorado market uh
have you uh remained in the Colorado
market since you moved there from uh
Cure Leaf? So I moved here in 2020, got
involved in the commercial uh indoor
cultivation then and uh and I left the
last facility that I was operating in in
January of last year. Uh so ever since
so I the two facilities that I operated
in that I ran here um one you know both
in Denver both relatively small um very
different environment between the two
but uh long story short is I left due to
a variety of reasons. One was the
company selling the facility um you know
financial issues within the company um
and then just other opportunities that
presented themselves. I started working
as the sort of uh technical adviser and
and sales uh person at ScienceLED in
September of
2023 I want to say. Yeah. Um, so for
several months I was running the
facility,
uh, and I was working for, um, the
lighting company and we had, you know,
several different iterations of that,
but part of that was I was able to bring
on a couple guys part-time to help do
the day-to-day cultivation operations
until the um, we were able to get kind
of stabilized to an extent,
which led to uh, some complications or
conflicts of interest within in money
flowing in the company, money, you know,
kind of moving and, you know, without
getting into too much detail, there was
a big sort of conflict between the
current employer and, you know, both
employers and so I had to kind of step
away from the garden and focus full-time
on the the lighting company.
So, yeah. So, then that's where I
transitioned out of full-time commercial
growing was about a year ago.
Wow. And um since then uh it sounds like
you worked at ScienceLED and then um
have also now transitioned over to uh
Aoya um the the substrate and
environmental monitoring and uh data
platform. Uh can you talk a little bit
about your time there and um sort of
what your experience has been?
Yeah, I mean um you know I also I
started my consulting business in 2022
uh just due to a variety of things that
were introduced to me as opportunities
to generate more revenue, bring some
more value, step out of the garden and
into the bigger picture of the industry.
And it was all opportunistic, right?
like referrals with certain companies
that were like, "Hey, I know, you know,
maybe you want to work with us in some
capacity, but not, you know, fully, that
sort of thing. genetics opportunities to
to potentially create some genetics
licensing deals or work with certain
providers that I trusted when other
people asked, "Hey, do you have a a
connection to a trusted nursery?" That
once tissue culture started becoming
more mainstream in the preservation and
cleaning of genetics, I was able to
establish some good relationships there.
So, there was all these little pieces
that kind of flew like fell together. uh
and then you know sort of negotiating
hey I have this entity I'm willing to
have an employment contract with you
full-time while I also have this entity
that I'm doing outside you know work in
as long as there's no conflict of
interest. Um you know working at science
was really interesting. I learned a lot
about uh just the mechanics of of LED
lighting and diode manufacturing
uh spectrum drivers, the nuances on
driver technology and and diode
technology and lensing and optics. Uh,
you know, I had been using the um EST
Tech fixtures, but I'd also ran we we
had Fluence at um at Curleaf and I had
gotten some GVAS and uh you know, so I'd
used a variety of different LEDs and I
had science LEDs in the one of the
facilities in one of my rooms cuz we got
a rebate. So, the rebates were really
cool. Colorado was really, you know,
doing well, giving out a lot of rebates
to Excel Energy. So, I saw an
opportunity there to leverage my network
and my connections and say, "Hey, I can
probably get these lights into more
facilities and and uh you know, that
sort of thing." So, I I did that. Um,
you know, got some cool projects in, but
I really focused a lot on learning and
advising and helping them with their
growers because I had replaced the guy
who had previously been doing that uh
there. He'd moved on to another job. Um,
so yeah, there was a lot to learn from.
So, we had a lot of home growers. We had
a lot of uh living soil producers
indoors and greenhouse. We had a lot of
guys that were producing rosin. Um, you
know, a lot of solvent lists that really
like the dynamic spectrum, very small
scale, small batch. And then we also had
like planet 13 and we had um some bigger
facilities and and we were working with
a greenhouse manufacturer with uh one of
the larger um se like breeding research
facilities in commercial agriculture.
Um, so there was a lot of interesting
distribution of uh of resources in that
company towards different markets and uh
and I really actually enjoyed and
appreciated kind of taking a step
outside of cannabis too and going to
some of these research conferences cuz I
got to go to NC 101 which is a
conference which is a state of the
industry conference for controlled
environment agriculture from vendors to
university professors to private
research all that. Wow. And that was
really interesting. Um, and then, you
know, a couple of, uh, non-cannabis
related research conferences and just
general conferences, which was really
fun. Um, cuz I was also really
interested and still am in kind of
branching out outside of cannabis. Same
with the decision to go to Roya. I mean,
Aoya is working uh working with one of
the largest raspberry producers in the
world and using some of our technology
to help grow raspberries and substrate
uh to a much higher yield and and all
that. So, there's a lot there. I'm not
going to go too deep into that, but uh
that was really fascinating to see sort
of the cross-pollination of CA and
cannabis. Cannabis can sometimes be for
the CA guys a black box or like we don't
want to get involved. there's legal
issues with research, but then there's a
lot of innovations and ability to
leverage new technology and cannabis
that isn't accessible to the CA guys as
much. So, it was interesting to watch
those two worlds kind of collide and
walk in between them. For sure. Um I uh
I believe it was uh uh Ramsay Nubani. uh
I think he worked at Aoya for a while
and um he's provided some excellent
information kind of circa the era that
you're talking about where there was
this um this push for controlled
environment agriculture knowledge and
applications to start to be used within
the cannabis industry and um kind of
vice versa by taking you know this high
ticket item uh commodity item like
cannabis and using some of those extra
funds that were um generated by its high
ticket price to be put back into
internal research for some facilities.
And it does seem like um you know like
tomato growers have been growing using
generative and vegetative steering cues
for vining tomatoes for decades and been
using it successfully to produce um you
know extremely highly productive and uh
nutriently um dense produce. Uh so it it
only makes sense that something else
like cannabis with such a high nutrient
demand would benefit from the use of um
different uh steering cues and just
different um different horicultural
practices that are typically kind of
reserved
for food production or otherwise. Um and
it it is really interesting to see these
worlds sort of collide. Um, I always
point people towards plant empowerment
if they want to look into some of the
more refined practices and
understandings of how plants act and
respond to their environment and their
different inputs. Um, because cannabis
is just another plant and it is going to
do a lot of the things that other plants
do and we typically put it up on this
pedestal in the cannabis community as
saying that it's this magical uh special
plant. Um, and it does have some really
unique qualities, but in the end it it
is just a uh a water pump, right? It's
just putting water from the ground out
into the air and uh assimilating
nutrients in the process. So
understanding that a lot of plants are
like that is I feel it it kind of
demystifies but also opens up an avenue
for people to look into different uh
aspects of controlled environment
agriculture or other horicultural or
agricultural research that is um it can
be applied and it can be used for the
benefit of the cannabis community uh
especially as growers. Mhm. Yeah. I
think a large amount of the resources to
that end are being invested in lighting.
uh from what I observed um in terms of
like you know uh research agg obviously
breeding and genetics is a big part of
it too but um but what I was mostly
interested at science was learning a bit
about some of the uh spectrum research
on plant growth and sharing that cuz
that was a very under uh not very well
understood aspect of cannabis production
specifically but just plant production
in general fluence did a good job of
doing a lot of research on far red uh
there's been a lot of studies that have
come out on different impacts of red at
different times of the the day, whether
that's actually effective or not. If
it's, you know, vers 640 nm versus 660
nm. I mean, there's all these specific
nuances that you can get into with
lighting and spectrum and timing and
whether it actually helps or not, what
cultivars, what varieties uh respond
better. Um, so that was one of the
things that I was most interested in,
but I did see that was quite a big topic
of conversation. and irrigation still is
a is a large, you know, nutrient
assimilation. Bugby did a big study on
phosphorus. I mean, there's so many
um different approaches within the CA
space to what they're trying to do. So,
they're trying to do research to figure
out how to get better produce, better
quality produce, better nutrient density
in their produce, um uh more yield, uh
more hearty plants. I mean, you know, as
the climate changes and evolves, a lot
of the CA guys are in green houses. So,
they're figuring out like using tools
like CDROA to manage the greenhouse like
the autonomous um the the grower
challenge that they they usually win.
So, it's like, you know, there's a lot
of different facets to it, but it is
interesting to see, well, hey, AI and
and and machine learning in general um
are making their way into cannabis
production. And there's a bit of uh
gripping that's going on where people
want to hold on to the reinss and and
think that they can outperform the
machine and they probably can in in some
cases and in other cases probably not.
Uh but that's been a huge topic like I
was at Cultivate last year and that was
a huge topic of conversation within
flower producers and whatnot is like
using these you know machine learning
tools or these AI imaging devices like
hyperspectral imaging or RGBs to predict
plant growth and yield and plant health
and pest problems. But there hasn't been
enough of an assimilation of data to be
able to cohesively make those decisions.
So, it's learning on its own as it goes,
which I think is really cool and shows
promise. And you know, Aoya is working
on that. There's some other companies
working on that. Um, but you know,
there's a there's a a huge difference in
culture between CA and cannabis in terms
of growers and who, you know, ego and
value and and a lot of these aspects and
and at least that's from what I've
observed. You know, I could be wrong,
but I've just noticed there's a um
intellectual property is is huge in in
cannabis, even though a lot of it's just
around people chucking pollen, you know.
Um and uh it just things operate
differently. Values are just different.
Um but there's a lot to be learned on
both sides. For sure. You you would say
then that there's a lot more ego-driven
decision-making in cannabis than there
is uh in controlled environment
agriculture. I take it. Uh yeah, I mean
there's definitely still some on in in
the CA space, but there's a there's a
lot of
uh university research that translates
into relationships with farmers and
producers there.
Um a lot of the cannabis research, I
think people there's two sides. There
are people who really appreciate it and
and
and look to uh implement what they're
seeing in the research and there are
people who don't believe it or don't
like you know understand it maybe um and
and don't don't see the value as much.
There's still a huge impact from the uh
legacy culture for lack of a better term
of the sort of covert operations and uh
you know the
the quietness of the innovation and um
proprietary nature to the you know
cannabis growers that is still just
prohibition behavior. But at the same
time like there's a lot of conversation
around hey we used to have much better
chirps we used to have much louder weed
we used to have you know people say all
kinds of things on that end which is
probably true in a lot of cases but we
have to understand like why exactly is
that what do we have to what do we what
um bridge do we have to gap to be able
to get is there fundamentally a conflict
directly correlating between production
uh like
production strategy
uh that is at a sort of a this is like
an open-ended question too but at an
absolute between quality small batch
craft and like volume production. I've
seen some really good quality product
and really really uh really loud flower
coming out of some larger facilities,
you know. So, there's there I think
there's a it's a bit of a gray area, but
I'm I'm I'm curious what you think on
that as well.
For sure. I mean, I think that like with
the like the legacy market and um you
know, there because of the prohibition
era mentality like you talked about and
the you know there's a lot of
unwillingness to share information and a
lot of it I believe is due to um the
penalties that would have been faced to
share that information openly and
potentially be tied to that information.
um you know like people like Tom
Alexander who uh did Senseia tips way
back in the 70s and 80s. He he was a
bold pioneer to be able to put that
information out there and tie his name
to it. That's uh you know it's almost
unheard of in that era. There was only
maybe five or six people that were doing
that and openly admitting that it was
them putting that information out there.
And um so when you get caught up in a
mentality of this works for me and then
you get pushed into a market that um you
know every last little resource counts
because you are starting to see a loss
in price and uh an increase in overall
production. Maybe you want to stay
unique in your ways and you don't really
want to change because um I mean in
general change is scary for a lot of
people and especially if you've been
doing something for a really long time
changing is going to be that much harder
and uh I I feel like that is one of the
pitfalls of some of the legacy growers
is not being willing to adopt uh not
necessarily wholesale change right but
little things that could imple that they
could implement to make their lives that
are, you know, precision irrigation, uh,
environmental monitoring, things like
that that don't necessarily change what
you do or put into your plants or how
you grow them or the environment that
you're giving them. It just gives you
more tools and insights into the um
applications of those tools. Uh so I it
is a it's a very I feel like touchy
subject especially within the
overarching cannabis community because
there are a lot of legacy growers who
were pulled into this market because of
their expertise at the time and then
basically be forced to change with the
market as it's changed. And sometimes
that's through uh you know their own
choice of wanting to stay vibrant and uh
have have their potential grow with the
market and then some people that are
just stubbornly stuck in their ways. You
know, kind of I I know I'm going kind of
on on the extremes of both ends of the
spectrum there, but uh it could fall
anywhere in between that as well. It
just it does seem like it was something
that it was hard for people to adjust
and those who did did great and those
who didn't maybe still did great for a
while but eventually they started to see
the tides kind of turn on them. Yeah.
The attitude of like constantly trying
to learn and get better and innovate.
you know, there's a lot of uh discussion
around people switching back to HPS
lighting because they got better quality
or, you know, better better flower or
whatever the case may be that they're
saying, "Hey, I'm you know, going back
to handwatering and organics and liquids
and HPS lights the way I used to do it
versus like, you know, driving new
genetic material coming out of these new
environments where you're actually
selecting under your selection pressure
comes from the environment that you're
cultivating in that's representative of
your of your high production
environment. Like there's a there's a
there's a give and take there, but I
mean to me I I would I would look to
like innovations that are not like
taking a step back is fine as long as
there's a uh a clear economic outcome
because it's it's a business, right? For
sure.
Like when I was in right when I
graduated high school in 2009, I felt
like there was this peak in the um at
least in California in the 215 as well
as the gray market where the quality of
product that was coming out of like the
Bay Area and SoCal was at such a peak
that I can understand looking back at
that and saying, "Man, this the weed
then was really really good. it was
knock you on your socks good, but also I
was, you know, a much less educated and
knowledgeable individual. And I feel
like um one thing my partner says all
the time is as we learn more, we know so
much less, you know, and it's like by by
gaining all of this knowledge now in the
cannabis industry of the different
styles of growing and we have, you know,
probably a million plus different
cultivars that uh normal amounts of
people are consuming on a weekly basis.
And uh all just all that uh sort of
compounding information provides almost
this dilution effect of well what is
quality and now we know that we have
individual and unique endockinabonoid
systems that respond differently to
different cannabonoids as well as the
different like tarpine esther and other
volatile organic compounds uh as they
coalesce together and we're responding
to them differently. It's not like a an
ibuprofen where you have, you know, one
single ingredient that's affecting your
system. You have a myriad of ingredients
that are affecting your system and, you
know, maybe when there were five popular
strains available to people, you knew
that one of them worked way better for
you. But now when you have 40, 50, 60
different strains available at one
dispensary and 10 to 20 different
dispensaries within driving distance all
holding a different menu, how can you
even tell what's going to work for you?
You can't go through, you know, hundreds
of different strains in the same time
that you could five, right? And you have
constantly changing menus as well
because the production is so much
greater now than it was 20 years ago.
Um, I just it's a it's a completely
different market. And to say that there
was a better, you know, to have
rosecolored glasses and look in the past
and say that weed was better, I I don't
believe it. I just don't, you know, I I
I've smoked some of the tastiest weed in
my life in the past couple years, but I
still remember the stuff from 10 or 15
years ago cuz it made an impression on
me. But I'll remember the stuff from
this year and last year the same because
it's also a lasting impression.
Yeah. Yeah. I feel the same way. I mean,
I've recently, you know, I've done I've
judged some competitions and I've tried
some, you know, interesting unique
flavors and whatnot. And there's a lot
of of similarities in a lot of the
varieties that are out now that are in
commercial production, especially
because the market demands a lot of the
similar flavors. But I guess yeah what
you're getting at is is important to to
point out which is that there and this
is this is partially beneficial to like
in the uh legalization and the in you
know sort of advent of private research
within the industry is we're able to
understand what makes what are the all
the factors that makes a quality
experience or at least like quality
product and its effect on every
individual person. like we it's so
daunting to try to say hey I'm going to
figure out what strain works the best
for me. It's like well we have to
understand why and what those mechanisms
are and it's very complicated. Everyone
every person is different. Everyone just
like your digestive system is different
than mine and certain foods aggravate me
that don't aggravate you. like you know
or vice versa like that's sort of uh I
look at it in in similarly to that which
is it all starts with the base material
and like how that's cultivated like what
are the practices once you remove all of
those factors like contamination risks
and poor storage and poor curing process
or whatever uh it might be there. Then
you get down to like the raw material
input and how that affects you. uh
that's a hard place to get to to try to
evaluate. M um so I think that there's
just this like wide world of of
understanding um so many different
factors of the of the plant um that yeah
the the production piece is is also just
a small portion of it right and and then
also you know one of the things that I
feel like it's a little bit swept under
the rug when people are asking for the
different cultivar that works for them
is the understanding of you Within the
cultivation market
currently, you can't have something that
yields the same grow for 12, 13, 14
weeks and remain um viable uh for a for
a commercial facility where most of them
are u maybe pushing 10 weeks at the very
most for a lot of their cultivars. Um so
anytime that you push past that, you
can't then ask for that much more money.
uh per unit being sold uh typically um
maybe for some really high quality uh
product, but in a lot of cases when
people are saying, I wish that there was
a really good sativa on the market
because I know that that worked really
well for me when I had it back in the
day. Um you know, a like I said, a
14week equatorial or a GMO or something.
It's like yeah, just not commercially
viable. It's it it you don't see a lot
of people growing GMOs like you know on
its own like you'll see garlic cookies
or like you know burgers or whatever
like cuz they they they're shorter but
they still get some of the similar
flavors but they're not just GMO
anymore. No. Um and that's you know
that's a that is a a case of we are um
we have to conform to market viability
which is a it could be potentially a
sacrifice on on on um that specific
cultivar and and the the people who have
had that experience with that cultivar.
Yeah, I I agree with you on on that
completely. I think that like the reason
that's part of the reason I think Sour
Diesel like was so strong uh and so
popular for for a while back in like
2008 2009 um Yep. Yeah. one of the
co-founders of the Craft Growers
Network. Um he goes by Gabby Staten
Island and he was one of the guys that
brought Sour Diesel over from New York
back in the early 2000s and um you know
people are people will still you know
demand it on the shelves but it you know
from a cultivation perspective when uh
you look at it as a cultiv cultivation
to buyer
relationship selling big fluffy green
buds it makes me sick to my stomach as a
cultivator.
trying to see that in a bag and try to
go and shop that around because the
expressions you're going to get from a
lot of people are going to be, "Are you
the dumbest [__] that just
walked through my door today?" Um, and
it's it's really unfortunate because
then when
people see that it's available, they
want it. So I you know there is this
huge disconnect um I feel like with just
across the board when it come you know
at all different levels from cultivator
to purchaser to retailer to consumer and
there needs to be a little bit more of a
holistic approach in bringing more
knowledge there somehow and that's for
someone more intelligent than myself. I
I can see the problem but I have no uh
avenue for rectifying that at this
point. Yeah, I mean social media is a
double-edged sword in that regard
because social media, especially
Instagram, which is where a lot of the
cultivators are, uh, is pictures. You
can't smell, you know, you can't smell
weed on Instagram. It's all bag appeal.
So, you know, we've leaned further into
like, uh, this conflation of quality
with bag appeal, um, that that we never
used to have before this was like a
thing, you know, before. So yeah, I
think there's a big that has a big role
to play too. Uh education and and
teaching people what like teaching
consumers what quality product is. And I
deal with this with my family like
elderly uh family members who are
interested in trying cannabis again.
Um but like my parents even or you know
my cousins or whatever that are like I
just don't know like weed's too strong
for me these days. Like I I can't smoke
it. like I just get way way way to way
way too high and I want to try to find
strains that work for me or I want low
potency weak wheat or whatever. they
have these ideas in their heads around
like what they want and need out of
cannabis, but they just can't figure out
how to get it or how to find it or
there's this like mindset of like I
don't want this high potency, high THC
weed anymore, whereas, you know, that's
still talking about THC where whereas
it's more, you know, I mean, yes, that
number could potentially impact how high
you get, you know, but to a certain
point like there's some
um there's some there's some factors
there where testing fraud or whatever,
you know, I mean, there's so many things
we could talk about there, but I would
just say like for some of those guys
rabbit hole. Yeah, exactly. And I don't
need to go there, but for some of those
guys who are looking for product that's
going to make them feel the way they
want to feel off of smoking, there's so
much out there and there's very little
resources to uh help them figure it out.
You know, you go rely on your bud tender
most of the time.
It's I feel like it's why I am such a
huge advocate for home grower rights
because I feel like that's going to be
one of the best routes that any
individual can take into trying to find
what'll work for them, especially if
they have uh access to clones and uh
readily known cultivars in their area
because then they can, you know, they
can try it out at home, compare it to
what's at the store. If they think that
they like what they do better, then they
can, you know, maybe spend a little bit
more on a pack of seeds or on a really
nice cultivar or something and set up uh
two small spaces even one just to keep
that cultivar around, learn about
cloning and and propagation because
that's also a blast in and of itself and
then also be able to grow that product
that they want and desire uh readily. So
it but it is uh you know when when you
are sifting through all the different
iterations of even you know like let's
just say something like Girl Scout
cookies right you can see Girl Scout
cookies at every dispensary in some
iteration in every state that has a
market for it and they're all going to
be different.
you know, maybe there's going to be a
few degrees of difference in some, but
in others there's going to be, you know,
a hundred different degrees of
separation, and it's going to be vastly
different. Uh, so it it the the
commercial space is um it has a lot of
refinement uh to be done.
I've seen a lot of um I've heard a lot
of people say that Girl Scout cookies in
some way or another killed quality weed
um because it was like it made the
Purple Candy
um you know, purple candy gas or purple
candy kind of uh craze take over
everything and that's all everyone's
growing in LA and that's all like and
it's like oh like it it totally ruined
the creativity and breeding and can and
it's like you know I I see the point
there but at the end of the day like it
it it is what it is for a reason uh it
does well in a lot of conditions and it
performs um and and I think that the
original Girl Scout cookies was not
really a great production strain. No.
Um, but the form cutter, the the thin
men's cut or whatever, like they they're
not great producers and they're they're
not really purple either. Like they're
they're kind of that like uh you know,
speckled green and purple with with nice
orange hairs. It it's a you know, it's a
beautiful cultivar, but um I remember
getting like the packs that were in the
Bay Area in 2009 and it was amazing.
like some of the best smoke that I can
remember to this day. But, you know, no
one wanted it at the time at when it
first came out because it was weird and
different. And people were looking at
these tiny little nugs and they're
going, "Man, I just give me some Sour
Diesel or something or some Super Silver
Haze or some Blue Dream because I want
to see like one big cola in the bottom
of my zip when I'm getting a when I'm
getting an ounce, you know? I don't I
don't want all those different little
popcorn nugs." But it did. I mean, it
has staying power for a reason, just
like lemon cherry gelato or
um I feel like there's just too many to
name off now where there's they're all
considered these elite cuts or, you
know, uh commercially viable cuts that
do well in, you know, a variety of
different markets. But that was the same
that it was, you know, 20, 30 years ago.
It was just those markets were much
smaller and the the cuts were only
passed around to a few people, but those
few people provided for a majority of
those people in the area. So that it was
just the product was better known. Yeah,
I think the breeding world is probably
the final frontier of unadulterated
creativity in the craft growing world.
um being able to select strains
and make new crosses that are new
flavors and just really try to like hone
in what your goals are and what and and
have there's there's not always going to
be, you know, predictable outcomes with
phenotypic variation. So, if you're just
if you're really breeding for a real
purpose, that's one that's one like like
a true economic purpose like, hey, we're
building this cultivar that's going to
have these qualities and these things
for production, whatever. Um, but I also
think genetic preservation and looking
at like creating combinations of flavors
and selecting things that are more out
of more for the the consumer that really
appreciates
uh interesting depth and uniqueness to a
cultivar is about pretty much all we
have left because everybody really is
growing very similarly nowadays. A lot
of people are growing in small substrate
with high EC uh you know precision
irrigation strategies high you know
reasonably high PPFD LEDs like not crazy
but like you know there's a lot of
similar practices that are successful in
the commercial space that can still
produce quality product. So there's not
a lot of creativity left within that
aspect of it. I think a lot of that is
the sacred is left for like, you know,
some of these um more well-known
breeders who have a reputation for
putting out new quality hot strains.
Yeah, I couldn't agree more. It and it
also feels like because some people will
kind of say, well, what about organics,
you know, like what about having some
sort of commercial facility that runs an
organic system? And my retort would be
well all of these organic systems that
have been found to be successful in an
in an indoor setting um are also very
homogeneous across you know if you take
a large enough sample size um that it's
all running you know these these fabric
beds with uh something like a bluemat
drip system or even other irrigation
systems and uh substrate monitoring so
that you're hitting your same target
drybacks and wet dry cycles and making
sure that the electrical conductivity
still isn't getting too out of control.
And it all of these practices kind of
then steer back to this, you know,
controlled environment agriculture
conversation that is already a fairly
refined practice uh and can be applied
through a variety of substrates,
nutrient inputs, uh environmental uh
control abilities. Um it it's just, you
know, I've we keep on circling back to
it, but it's just about making sure that
you're optimizing where you can and and
not
um you're not overdoing it where you
can't uh afford to. Um yeah, simplicity
is oftent times uh much more rewarding I
think uh than getting like lost in the
sauce on I want to need the nanobubbles
and I need to do you know I need to
default on day 21 and day you know just
having these like precise boundaries
that you're sitting within the it's it's
a dynamic environment and I think like
the creativity that comes from exploring
new flavors is all we can have left and
hold on to that we can do ourselves in a
lot
in a lot of ways. Like I can go into my
basement and take a male of this and a
female that cross-pollinate, right? Like
that's not very hard and I can get some
really cool unique new expressions and
flavors based on the genetic potential
of each of those cultivars, right? So I
could still do that and find something
that nobody else has in a way. Um, but I
but I like you know there's these there
are guys out there now doing synthetic
and organic combination where they're
feeding base salts and adding in which
is not really reinventing the wheel or
doing anything new. It's just, hey, I'm
putting this kelp fulvic acid combo
through a separate doser in line after
my batch tank so I can still deliver
these microbes and these bio stimulants
to my plants and get what I think is
creating an increase in flavor profiles
and expression in the plant. uh you know
there is a science to the the
biomechanisms behind adding those
compounds into the plant and the
chilators and the the biological
organisms and enzymes you know there's a
lot of depth to that argument and to
that style um and so I I understand like
okay hey this is a new way of applying
that strategy that we were doing in our
batch tanks and barrels before we were
doing all this stuff and keeping our
lines clean still you know still like
kind
adapting and you know these old school
practices to new school production
methodologies which I even don't even
like using those terms but like you know
the legacy versus the
modern practices. I think that that part
of it is very limited in what we can uh
what we can explore in terms of
dynamics. I mean, veg time, pot size,
planting densities, like very very
myopic decisions that you make that
could have substantial outcomes on
expression. But I recently walked into a
facility where where someone was growing
in onegon pots and vegging for a long
time and he really really felt like root
circling and constraining of of space in
the root zone drove a a a more desirable
outcome on bud structure and um and
density and and what he was looking for
from his buds over years of his trial
and error and experience. That was his
that was where he got to in his
decision. So they were growing in these
large plants in these you know plastic
onegon pots. Um and you know
like if you're not
um you have to do a lot of thing you
have to make a lot of adjustments to
like fulfill the outcome of your your
specific decision on your observation.
There's so many confounding factors but
people have unique things and then they
have to work around that and all the
other aspects. your irrigation strategy
has to change a lot when you're when you
have too small of a you know maybe not
too small but when you have a really
small pot with a big plant you it's hard
to just go full generative
um but some strains respond really well
to that and others don't for sure I yeah
like cuz sometimes we'll categorize like
the different cultivars as being like
generative balanced or vegetative
themselves and you know and and trying
to match those with your environmental
cues and your irrigation cues to try and
optimize it. Yeah, sure. Maybe uh
overvging your plant, providing some
sort of girdling, which is a stressor,
so it's going to provide some sort of
generative response, is doing something
to the morphology of the flower that is
desirable, but um it it seems like a a
long walk, you know, to get to the end
result that you're looking for. Um but
if it works, it works. And it's really
hard to discredit uh the different uh
methods that people will use that
they've developed over time. You know,
like you're saying with this probably
single or mult multicult cultivar uh
growing style that they use for this
because it works and they've found that
it works. So they're not going to change
it. Um but you know like we've also
discussed previously that could
eventually become a hindrance if
some you know new strategy or technology
or uh option becomes available in the
cultivation facility that you then are
either uh too stubborn to change because
of a single method that you must keep to
make it your growing style to keep your
uniqueness. And unfortunately, you know,
that's a little ego-driven at that
point. Um, so I, you know, I it there is
a balance there and especially as a um a
consultant knowing that, you know, some
people are just going to be stuck in
their ways and it's about optimizing
their ways rather than implementing
optimal ways, right? Uh that's uh I I
have faced that issue as well and it
it's a hard one to get used to
especially when you see and have seen so
many different styles that you can kind
of formulate a you know if you have the
education and understanding of how and
why plants react to certain things and
you see a variety of ways that people
implement those different things to
watch how the plant reacts. You can pick
and choose what works the best because
you've seen it and now you have your
anecdotal model set up. So you're boom,
ready to run. And then when other people
are faced with that model that you set
up for them, they say, "Well, this
doesn't work for my setting because I
wanted to do it this way." And when you
put this in place, it ruins everything
else. Um, so I I've I've faced that.
It's a it's one of those things that I
feel like is is a pitfall for um people
who want to enter into consulting where
they're trying to maybe push their own
ideologies too much and not uh hear what
the people need and responding to those
needs better. Yeah, there's so many
flavors of of uh advising or consulting
that a lot of it comes down to like you
know what we're trying to do here is
achieve desired outcomes and then we
work backwards from our desired outcome
towards what we're what our day-to-day
is and get slightly more myopic but at
the in the very beginning you have to
take a holistic just like medicine right
like you have to treat the whole system
you can't just go like yes you have to
stop the bleeding and put a bandage on
it and all that but when you're we're
talking about like holistic health, you
know, like our whole system is flawed
where we're not eating well, we're not
sleeping well, we're not, you know, all
these things, right? Like we're
hijacked. So, in a garden, when you're
looking at the holistic aspect, you're
looking at what are the key dysfunctions
of this operation and then we work
backwards to the specific production
things that are happening. And, you
know, you can look at trends and see
things, but it's not always the best
idea to just go, okay, we're going to
switch to onegon pots at nine plants
under a light at like, you know, 10day
vet. like you can't just go directly to
those things without a true
understanding of revenue generation in
the business and what are the key
factors that move the needle for the
company. Um you have to look at that
first and then go well how do these
things all play into this right at every
step of the you know efficiency is
always really important. Um, but
efficiency isn't the whole picture, you
know? I mean, you got to make sure that
the person feels good. Uh, and that
translates into like desire to make
change. And so from it's easy to look at
like the consulting thing as like a rose
colored glass kind of thing. It's like,
oh, I'm here to try to help you know
what what are you really doing to
support this person? What what your
outcome based uh decisions and and value
based. we're trying to bring value to
the company in a a way that's supportive
that empowers them to drive success in
the business. That's one approach. The
other approach is I'm taking a piece of
this and I'm going to get the
performance out of this. Uh and so
that's where my incentive is is to like
take my SOPs, my strategies, all my uh
you know the way that I do things and
I'm going to place it in this facility
and I'm going to get it to perform the
way that I want it to. and then I get
the uh the upside of that. So, there's
different approaches and it doesn't all
it's not all applicable across the
board. Some people really just need
somebody to bounce ideas off of or to
just tell them when they're doing
something that doesn't make sense. And
some people want you to just step in and
run everything for them and do it all
yourself. Every business has this this
gradient of like involvement and
empowerment and um you know when you're
taking a a holistic systematic approach
you have to look at like what is the
foundation of this company and the
culture and is it owner operator is it
uh you know somebody trying to sell this
are they what what are they trying to do
here uh and how do we change
incrementally change practices and
procedures and whatnot to like back our
way into that and maybe like there's
this potential roll out of capital
expenditure that needs to happen. Like
we deal with a lot of consultants at
Aoya. We have a lot of consultants that
come in and say, "Hey, I need to get a
Roya in this growth so that I can see
what's happening so that I can help make
decisions and make changes and help
them." And that that's a very common
thing in the industry, you know, I mean,
people step in, they implement their
tools that allow them to to do their
job, and then they can, you know,
functionally make a a pull a bigger
lever there without without as much of a
um time or labor investment on their
end. So, you know, I see that there's a
there's such a wide range. Some people
are like, we're taking our brand into
this grow. We're going to put our we're
going to take these two flower rooms.
We're going to run them our way. we're
going to do our do our thing here. We're
going to bring our brand in and we're
going to sell the brand from those two
sell the product in our brand from those
two rooms. So, there's like, you know,
there's such a a wide scope of of
consulting uh type
um uh I guess business. Um, but it's
also very challenging when you have to,
and I've I've had this personal
experience with clients who didn't get
the out the results that they were
looking for because they didn't put in
the time and the effort and the work.
Um, or they didn't pay, you know, or or
like it's like if you don't pay, you
don't listen to someone's advice. if
you're if you don't have any skin in the
game, you know, uh and if it's just ask
getting advice that maybe isn't as
helpful as or writing out someone's SOPs
or writing out a IPM protocol for them,
well, they don't do it or stick to it.
There's two sides of that. It's like
either you need to put somebody in there
who can or you know and and what am I
willing to actually do here? Like how
much involvement am I willing to
actually have and and do I actually see
a potential positive outcome here? like
when I when I'm going to help this
person, am I actually going to like let
me let's be real here. Like let's be
really realistic. Is what I'm offering
and what I can what I have the
capabilities and capacity to do is is
this really going to help this person?
Like is it really going to make a
difference? And you know, to me, I'm I'm
I'm at a point where I I don't
really want to do that much consulting
unless I really like the people and
really have trust and respect and know
like this is a relationship that's
positive, you know? I mean, you really
touched on it when you said trust,
right? Um I I feel like in in a even in
a a non-consulting
uh setting like let's say you're an
employee for a producer um as the
producer you have to trust your
employees and as the employees you have
to trust those uh that are hiring you um
in in the direction that's being given
as well as the effort that's being put
into those directions. And so, you know,
it when then translating that to a
consultant and uh client relationship,
the the trust that needs to be there
needs to be something that uh precedes
the application of these different um
methods and SOPs and strategies, right?
Because if they if they don't trust that
you know what you're talking about, then
they're not going to want to implement
it. And if they don't implement it or if
they partially implement it and you as
the consultant are saying, "Okay, here's
the results that we should be seeing
when you implement my my recipe this
way." Uh, but you're not seeing those
results. And they're going, "Well, we
listened, you know, to what you said."
um then that's where I can see a lot of
um frustrations arise where you know
unless you have these different
abilities to monitor and then
understanding uh of how to interpret the
different data that's being generated by
these different monitoring apparatuses
so that you can be like oh this tank
emptied at this point I see the dryback
here I see that it wasn't handwatered
then when that was the standard because
you saw that the volutric water content
dropped below a specific point. Why
didn't that happen? Oh, well, we didn't
know that the tank ran dry. Artifacts.
That's one thing I I I like that that
David uses that term artifacts in the
data cuz you're like you have to have
enough relevant world experience to know
what to look for and what trends
typically could mean certain uh certain
things. And and you know to me uh
looking at data it can be a double-edged
sword because you don't necessarily know
what to look for always uh if you're not
trained but also if you are you can get
lost in the sauce and the data and just
disappear down a rabbit hole in data
that's not actually helping you. It's
kind of uh myopic too myopic and getting
in the way. um you know when you get
lost in the data all the time like you
may notice things and but the reality is
is you you make observations in the
garden and you validate those
observations with the data that you're
looking at, right? Uh and and so then
there's there's a lot of
uh conflicting potential problems that
you could have that could reflect in the
same outcome in data. um right, you
know, having too heavy of a dryback or
having a VPD swing of like, oh, our dew
went down here or lights went off and we
sprayed here or whatever the case may be
that you're seeing like the decisions
you're making are not always live and
die by by the data, but as more so how
does that how do we like look at the
data objectively look at the facility
and the plants and make correlations
here that drive quicker
solutions and outcomes to improvement in
a more efficient and effective uh way.
Um right, you know, and so that's why I
think it's really helpful for a lot of
consultants to have more data and more
more of that. But um but that's kind of
uh that's kind of the a big challenge
too cuz it can be
potentially limiting for uh for some of
these consultants who aren't always on
site all the time, who aren't always
there. Maybe they have to place somebody
who's got that skill set to be like,
"Hey, you need to go do all these things
and check all, you know, and then I'll
look at this from a third party
perspective and make some uh make some
uh recommendations." For sure. I mean it
feels like there's a little bit of a
misnomer in the industry at this point
right now uh based on what you just said
where you know there there may need to
be less datadriven decisionm and more um
uh data supported decisionm where you're
not just looking at the data and making
a decision based on that but you need to
like you said look at the plants see
what they're saying to you based on you
know their structure their
tur you you know, are the pots actually
drying back? Is there a consistency
across the crop? Um, are there
inconsistencies? Look at those different
things. And then look at the data and
say, "Oh, you know, maybe I could
tighten up this parameter a little bit
more." Or I could change this uh and
tweak this. And I, you know, I can see
that based on the data and these
different trends that it is going this
way or that way. And I've seen that
before. It's caused this. So now I can
make that educated change. Um it because
sometimes you can look at a nice uh
pretty chart and sometimes think oh
everything's fine but then you go into
the room and everything's not fine and
you have to then figure out what it is
that's causing that. Um, so I yeah,
sometimes I do believe that there is
like a tyranny of data where if you
stick to the data and only the data,
then you're not going to, you know, that
like you said, you're lost in the sauce
at that point and you're not really
looking at, you know, are the plants
healthy? Good. Leave it alone. Don't
look at the data anymore because you're
tricking yourself into thinking you need
to do something. you're chasing this
this um nebulous kind of idea that you
have that this one thing you're doing is
making all the difference and you're uh
yeah you like I like I said you get lost
in the sauce easily. Yeah. And that's
the really the value of on-site you know
having somebody on site to really um
help be the eyes. And I think there's
starting to be you starting to see these
like um Google glasses or these like you
know AI assisted technologies that allow
you to look through the eyes of somebody
else in uh in the facility that makes
you be able to you know potentially be
more valuable offsite or again back to
the hyperspectral imaging or RGB cameras
or whatever like it's assisted you know
it's assisted you're still making the
decisions you're still and maybe the AI
will start driving those decisions in a
way that's way superior to what we're
able to do. Um, and then you don't need
those types of people. But like you know
I think that we have to really start to
like define what our value is in this
space of evolving technology and not to
to to let the ego get involved and say
oh I'm better you know or I'm it's like
okay how do we make as humans make
objective decisions to uh to support
people's businesses right like we're
we're not just here to try to be the
best crop steer be the best breeder or
whatever. You know, it's like we we want
to we want to make this industry
sustainable and have longevity and have
still have a degree of craftsmanship and
and care and pride. Uh you know, that
that is that is what we're holding on to
in a lot of cases. That's what allows us
to, you know, love and appreciate what
we do. Um right. You know, I think that
we have to to strike the balance between
production, revenue, and just
stewardship of of our of the the
plant. For sure. I mean, man, you you're
really well spoken in this field.
Obviously, you have a lot of experience
and I feel like your application of
knowledge is up there with a lot of
other people that I've talked to that
are kind of leading big changes in the
industry to try to make this sustainable
future for those of us that are not
necessarily in this for some uh ego
prize, but because there's so many uses
for cannabis, right? like whether it be
a medicinal use, a recreational use, uh
leisurely use, um whether you're using
some topical for grandma's arthritis, or
if you're using, you know, a giant 1oz
joint to set the party off, right?
There's just a huge variety of
applications for cannabis. And as
cultivators, we are almost the first
line in this operation where we are
producing uh what is going to eventually
be turned into this myriad of products.
And um you know with all of your
experience both in home growing and
commercial cultivation and um through
all of these different avenues of
optimization that you've taken
um for yourself, what are some of the
biggest learning experiences that you've
had? And let's take this as a
two-parter. So what would be one of the
biggest learning experiences that you've
had that was due to a setback? And what
was one of the biggest learning
experiences you had that was due to a
success?
Um, yeah, that's a great question. The
the um the setback piece we've encount
you know I've encountered multiple
situations with setbacks that were both
um eyeopening and disheartening at the
same time. um you know dealing with
hopllay and vyroid once we understood
what it actually was. Uh we made an
executive decision to clear house in our
mom and in our mom room and reset our
fix uh because everything was so heavily
infected that uh our production volume
was going down and that was before I
really knew best practices to mitigate
that. you know, we were victims of the
um I guess ignorance of hopllay and
vyroid until it was too late. Um
bringing in genetics from outside
sources that you don't trust fully. Uh
that was a double-edged sword because we
also got russet mites from that um from
that uh that clone order that was some
of the best cultivars that we had, but
we got it from somewhere that was not
necessarily
um I guess uh reputable uh back then
because there were not a lot of
reputable options that had really good
variety and uniqueness and things that
were not out in the market fully. So
that was a naive decision that that I
made that I, you know, wouldn't say that
I necessarily fully regret because I
learned a lot about how to manage hop
and vyroid, how to get rid of russet
mites, but also like when to stop when
you when when it's time to uh to reset
and and like what is the point of
critical mass and no return and then
never letting yourself get back to that
point again moving forward if you can
help it. you know, when you have a
problem that gets so out of hand uh that
you have to make a huge sacrifice,
that's um that was a that was a a low
point, but also a big learning curve for
me where I just I really understood like
incremental checks and balances and and
understanding like crop registration
even down to that like sanitary
practices with shears and it helped me
manage mold issues in the garden too
because it I just took a much more
systematic approach. Uh, you know, I
think that's a big part of it. Um, yeah,
that's kind of how I would answer that
question in terms of
setbacks. The, uh, the other side of
that question is, you know, how do you
how did I triumph from a success?
Um, you know, I think the successes, a
lot of them, there were definitely some
successes in terms of product that we
produced, quality and yield and whatnot.
And like had some really good runs. Um,
but you know, to avoid the like, oh, the
you should have seen the fish that got
away kind of story. Like I think a lot
of it came down to like I felt success
with training people. Um, I I I think
that I've taken a lot of pride in my
ability to break things down and coach
and train and educate people. And
um, you know, when my first job ever was
a martial arts instructor and then I was
an English teacher online and I, you
know, so I've had a lot of jobs and
roles and experiences as a
um, you know, an educator, I should say.
Um but yeah, when I was working at
Curleaf and and bringing up a lot of
people at the same time and just
watching people uh sort of take to
things or how to everyone has a very
different way of learning and uh and I
had a couple guys that moved on up and
ended up in much higher roles and
learned a lot and applied themselves and
um you know, not to necessarily credit
myself for their success at all, but to
be like, hey, you you know, they have uh
acknowledged that they wouldn't be where
they were without me. Um, for sure, you
know, I've had some really challenging
problems with staff, too,
where people who felt undermined when I
came in or who felt like I maybe didn't
have hadn't proved myself or hadn't
hadn't succeeded in a certain way that
allowed them to have respect for me,
which was a projection obviously of
their own personal insecurities. but to
bridge that gap and like build that
trust and build those positive
relationships to be to a point where I
had a successful collaborative effort
with someone who felt very much like I
had stepped on them. Um, and then you
know through the work and the my efforts
and my labor and my knowledge and
everything to like kind of level with
that person and give them opportunities
and then see them successful on their
own. Um, that that's a a success in my
book.
Yeah, I love that. I It's always so
great to see especially when you are
trying to approach it through um you
know not necessarily learning that my
method is best but trying to teach
people um you like in industry
standardized best practices
uh or um even just some basic
understanding so that they can make more
educated uh decisions themselves. And
then you start to see them make those
decisions as you would have hoped for
them to make them. It is a really nice
feeling because you you can start to see
that your uh style of education is not
only effective but it is uh it's working
real time live right there in front of
you. And that that's a huge a huge
feeling. I I can definitely agree with
that. I've I've seen it a few times
where I've taught somebody something and
then seen them implement it successfully
and it feels really good to see that
that education is being uh understood
cuz sometimes I feel like I ramble and I
I feel like my my mind doesn't
necessarily work in the same way that
someone else's mind may work and so my
explanation of something might just be
you know too esoterically me to be
applicable to their their way of
understanding Um, but you know, through
this podcast and even other
conversations that I've had with people,
it is uh it is definitely helping to to
make a lot more of this information
um accessible to people and then to make
people like yourself or myself or any of
our other guests more accessible to the
general community. um where now they'll
see that you have this level of
education and understanding where maybe
they'll reach out to you with a question
because they feel confident in your
ability because they've heard you talk.
They've heard your your cander and your
understanding of these different topics.
Um I I feel like that's just such a huge
value to the community in general as
well. Yeah, I appreciate you hosting
this podcast, too. I think that is
really valuable to have you know there's
a lot of noise and there's a lot of
negativity and there's a lot of uh it's
easy to get caught up in a lot of things
in our industry because it's it's very
turbulent very tumultuous you know um
and I think spreading the word and
education from not from a place of ego
or authority or anything just like hey
we're just here sharing stuff this is my
experience you know nobody's any better
than I I like to uh I often like to use
the term principles like guide uh guide
a lot of things. So you know if you
understand the core principles of
functionality of of a system um or just
a way of thinking then then you can
always revert back to uh to that that
the fundamentals and the foundations of
of uh of problem solving and
troubleshooting and and and learning how
to problem solve. Learning how
to objectively make decisions that are
based on principles is is is like the
teach a man to fish thing in such an
extreme degree, right?
Yeah. Absolutely. Like provide those
foundations so that they can build their
own program, their own house basically
rather than um you know providing all
the pre-fabricated lumber and
everything. You know you you want to
give them something solid to work from
but not necessarily provide them the
whole thing. it because it is there is
such a uniqueness to how each individual
wants to operate not only within the
garden but within life that it's really
hard to give them a cookie cutter and
say just do this. Um
I'm guilty of that. I wanted that for a
long time to be like I just need the
recipe. I just want the you know like I
want the irrigation strategy. I want the
you know whatever it might be. Um, I
wanted the the solution. Like I wanted
the the myopic answer. And it's like
that doesn't really help help you. It
doesn't help anybody. It it just you're
trying to like fit this close this box
on um the specifics. Like we could go
all day into like specific crop steering
strategies, but I don't think that
really helps people that much from my
perspective of like we don't you you
learn the nuances of of these very kind
of um advanced strategies through a lot
of your own trial and error and
experience when you're trying to make
decisions based off of logic and
principles and and that sort of thing.
You know, I I that's why I I try not to
get too deep in the weeds on anything,
you know, specific because I just find
it to be less less helpful than um than
talking about what we've talked about
today. For sure. Well, I mean, we we've
kind of already gone over our uh
predicted runtime here, so I'm going to
start to try and wrap us wrap us up, but
um you know, there there's so many more
questions that I'd want to ask you. you
know, the future of the cannabis
industry, where you see it going, what
do you feel is being like swept under
the rug in the cannabis industry now?
But, you know, I feel like we've touched
on a lot of that stuff kind of uh
without it being direct throughout our
conversation. So, maybe one of the final
wrap-up questions that I can ask
is what advice would you give for new
growers entering the industry? you're
you're not cuz you yourself are not one
of these uh old legacy growers that has
been doing this for 20 years and adapted
with the market. You know, you you kind
of entered it at a you know, late stage
um within the cannabis game almost as it
was going fully recreational across um
majority of the states.
So, you know, maybe you could address
this for people wanting to get into the
cultivation industry or even those who
want to just get into growing cannabis
in general, but what's some what's some
advice you would give for new growers? I
mean, I I going to start with values,
right? like be humble, uh be curious, um
your use your excitement to
uh to learn, um and and kind of keep
your keep yourself uh within the like
it's easy to get lost in the weeds as I
just said. And I think if you're a new
grower coming in, find mentors, find
people who really understand certain
things that you want to learn, uh, and
diversify those things and like really
try to I think what helped me the most
when I first started working in a
commercial facility, um, was that I just
wanted to do everything. I just wanted I
put in all it's work. It was work ethic.
It was like I just I wanted to work in
every department. I wanted to learn how
to do all the things and I wanted to be
knowledgeable and useful and valuable
and I found the thing that I was really
good at, you know, whatever things those
were that I was really good at and I dug
into those and I made a difference and
made it, you know, measurable. And I
think like just picking people to learn
from and picking opportunities that give
you the most the best education and and
being constantly hungry and curious. uh
you know be the first one there and the
last one to leave. You can't that's
something that you can't learn from
somebody is uh is work ethic you know um
and I always found that to be the most
valuable quality within my employees to
to a certain extent was like you could
have all the knowledge you want but if
you can't just get out there and do what
has to be done you're not going to get
anywhere. Um, and I think that your
network and building that network and
meeting people and building
relationships h they have to go, you
can't necessarily do that on top of like
above and beyond learning the skill and
having the core skills and core
competencies. develop those core
competencies as much as you can and also
take opportunities to build your network
and to meet people and to ask questions
and sound stupid and whatever, you know,
like just constantly remove the ego and
be hungry and and try really hard to
diversify and find mentors. I think
that's those are my best best bits. I
like it. Yeah, it's be hungry for
information and open to that information
when it's given to you. And you know,
just if you're going to apply it, apply
it, assess it, and don't necessarily
just take everything for its face value.
Because there's a lot of
um uh what's the what's the term? Snake
juice. You know, there's a lot of
there's a lot of misinformation and a
lot of uh bad information out there. And
so being skeptical also I feel like
would go handinhand with what you're
saying is um you know take that
information and but use some skepticism
and when you're trying to apply it and
and don't just take everything for what
people are saying as being true um even
if they sound good when they say it.
Yeah. I mean definitely don't don't rush
the process. You know, one of the things
I learned from my early days in martial
arts and competing and whatnot was like
something that my instructor and master
always told me, which was like you never
really lose, you know, you may lose a
match or whatever, but at the end of the
day, like you either win or you learn,
you know, or you you do both. Uh, sure.
So that's I think it's easy to get
disheartened and have the um you know
bruising of the ego and whatnot and know
when it's time to walk away when it's
time to move on and move forward and
when you're not no longer being served.
I think I see a lot of people stagnate
in the industry when they're finding
like this job isn't serving me anymore.
This this you know I'm not learning I'm
not getting anywhere and they just fall
into complacency and just stay there. uh
you know, take risks, jump off and do
something else. And and if you fail, you
fail, but like keep trying. You know, I
I'm grateful for my um opportunities
that I was able to move into when I felt
like certain places were no longer
serving me. And I I constantly built my
network to put myself in a situation to
where I had opportunities when they when
I needed them.
Sure. It's like uh um dig the well
before you get thirsty.
Um I've heard that a lot. Well, that's
awesome. And um I think that's a great a
great little wrap- up to our
conversation. Uh of course, because this
is a cannabis podcast, we do have a few
ubiquitous uh cannabis related questions
just to wrap up as a sort of rapidfire
finish to the conversation. Um so, what
is your favorite strain of all time? M.
Oh man, there's just so many for
different reasons, but if I think back
to like my best experiences on cannabis,
it was probably uh some of the old
school
hazes, mango haze,
um you know, some of those really nice
hazy strains that that I had as a kid.
Yeah. And and you you grew up in Florida
is what I take it. Yeah, a lot of our
weed was from California and uh so I'm
probably from New York, but Yeah, for
sure. I think mango haze might have been
from your neck of the woods. We had some
interesting haze. We had like uh we had
a couple Florida haze strains for sure.
Swamp Boy seeds and whatnot. Yeah. Cool.
Well, um you know, the followup to that
question is of course who is your
favorite breeder of all time?
Uh man, that's a that's also a tough
question.
Um, I I used to I used to really like
DNA. Um, but I think I think most of the
stuff that I've had lately that I really
liked has either come from like um you
know, Seed Junkie or like uh
um you know, even uh there's a there's a
breeder here in Colorado uh called
Loving in Her Eyes. Yeah. just some
really really incredible incredible
strains. So something like that or like
you know I always really liked compound
growing compound genetic strains. They
were always some of the more fun ones to
grow. I'm I'm wrapping up a very small
hunt of um the blueberry rose from Love
in Her Eyes. I um I love their products.
I also their their Instagram profile is
always so well curated in terms of the
the flower pictures and the sort of
mystique to the to the profile as well
where they don't even always tell you
the name of the strains that they're
showing. Um, so it it gets you that much
more interested when it's, you know,
these beautiful blues and reds and
purples and uh like deep indigos almost
in some cases. Their their color
spectrum that they can produce out of
their genetics library is astounding.
Um, definitely cool, man. All right,
last question. Oh, sorry. Go ahead. No,
I was going to say there's a new a new
um breeder in town here that is someone
if you're in Colorado to look out for,
which is Eleven's Genetics. They have
some really cool crosses of old school
like headbands and things like that that
have some new new flavors uh kind of
associated. So, there's you get these
old school flavors with some of the uh
qualities of modern production that that
make sense. So, that's one that I I
really like. some of their strawberry
adhesive is a good one. That sounds
good. Strawberry. Yeah, it's really
good. So,
awesome. Well, yeah. So, last question.
Um, what is your most memorable cannabis
related experience?
Um, like as a kid or like is this just
extremely open? It's it's open-ended.
Uh, you know, it could be like your
first time smoking. It could be, you
know, that time you almost got busted by
the cops. You know, we've had a a wide
array of answers for this question. So,
don't pigeon hole yourself. No. Yeah. I
mean, I definitely I I would say in
terms of like best positive memory,
probably would be the first time I ever
smoked. Um, just listening to some music
that touched my soul. And and I and I
did get um I did get busted when I was
in college for smoking in my dorm. So
that was definitely extremely memorable
because they did kick me out of my dorms
for
for smoking it. We uh we I lived in a
suite with two rooms and one of them was
these two guys that came from the same
town and the other one was me and my
buddy from high school and my buddy from
high school didn't really smoke but the
other two guys did and it was a cold
night and I was like hey we should still
we had this window behind the building
that we usually climb out of to smoke
behind and this time they were like no
we don't want to climb out there we
don't want to climb out there. I'm like
all right whatever we'll you know towel
the door we'll get the splof out. We'll
open the window. We'll turn the fan on,
do all the things, but we forgot to
cover the vent and um like the the
shared room vents, the vent that went
into the hallway. And so, oh no, the
return vent pulled a lot of that air in
the room out into the hallway and like
within an hour or so, the TA had called
the cops and they banged on the door and
we were watching like James and the
Giant Peach or something and I was just
so so stoned and I heard banging on the
door and we ignored it. Banging,
banging, bang. And finally I get up,
walk out of I was in the room with my
sweetmates and I walked out. They closed
the door on me and I was in the little
like hallway between the two rooms. Look
at the door and I just see two cops out
there and I just heard one of them say,
"Well, if they don't open up this time,
we're going in." So I opened the door
and uh there was a they were doing the
whole good cop bad cop routine. and they
had like the little canine patches on
their their shirts and they were
threatening to bring the dogs in and
searched my whole room and found this
like tiny little nug. Uh I'm assuming
this was in Florida. It was in Orlando.
Yeah,
I was about to say I I haven't heard
that level of uh militaristic style um
approach to a college kid with weed. Uh
unless it was, you know, Florida across
to Texas or something along the southern
states there. Yeah. No, they they they
were aggressive, man. It was Yeah, it
sucked. But uh I had to do fortunately
um uh I didn't get arrested. I didn't
get anything on my permanent record. But
that's good. I did I was in like
probation on for with the university for
like two years after that. Jeez. Yeah. I
knew in that moment I was like, "All
right, they're kicking me out. Can we
start packing?" Yeah. But uh Wow. Yeah.
Yeah. Well, that is those are both
definitely some memorable experiences.
So, thank you for sharing. And again,
Liam, thank you so much for your time
today and um having this conversation
and kind of going deep on a few topics
that we don't normally get to touch on
with um with other cultivators. you
know, we we do a lot of uh homegrow
discussion and people who have just
entered into the commercial space. Um,
but we rarely have people on with your
level of commercial experience and kind
of understanding uh of where this
industry has been and is going um you
know from the past 5 to 10 years and
moving forward. So, thank you so much. I
really really appreciate you being here.
And these conversations, as I like to
say, are how we spread this knowledge,
which is why the podcast is called The
Way We Grow, because this is how we grow
as a community and as individual
cultivators.
Awesome. I love it, man. Keep doing what
you're doing. I really appreciate you
hosting this podcast. It's awesome to
see that you're getting some knowledge
out to as many people as you can and
bringing on a diverse array of of uh of
speakers and guests. And yeah, it's uh
it's cool to see. It's inspiring. So
keep it up, man. Awesome. Thank you.
[Music]