[Music]
hello and welcome to another episode of
The Way We Grow podcast a production of
The Craft Growers Network I am your host
Nick wolf uh today our guest is Sasha
the Slovenian Hobbit welcome to the show
Hey man nice to have you yeah no it's
great to have you back as a guest um
you've kind of been a great co-host for
Gabby and myself over the course of this
podcast as we've started it up and
providing a different world view than
what we have um you know where can
people find you on uh on Instagram
before we get started uh right now on
Instagram it's uh very complicated for
US citizens to find me actually because
my Instagram name is
Garten by doer betics uh which is
actually gens
is a term in German which means a garden
dwarf the the caregiver of your garden
you know like you know in German culture
there is people who have a lot of people
have these Gardens and they have this
little dwarf hidden inside of the garden
somewhere he's hiding you know I I
actually few years ago I did it
purposely when I open up my own company
that uh I wanted to Target the German
speaking Market actually I was not
interested in us Market at that time or
any other Market uh so I purposely did
it cuz I'm small guy I have a little
beard and I have like ponytail and you
know I'm I'm a I'm a I'm a dwarf you
know I'm a garden dwarf so this Garden
dwarf is Garden but I will open up I
will open up a account now very soon uh
I think before this video goes out it
will be Slovenian Hobbit so this will be
me will be my picture and uh yeah you
know I opened the rock two months ago
with you guys uh for me still I live in
a place that is uh um very much illegal
to flower Canabis uh you can grow it but
you cannot flower it you know right so
um that kind of area and uh it's very
interesting times for for uh
decriminalization and legalization in
Europe now it's it's it's going up and
down man uh it's you know when you to
look to Germany now in this moment is
very very very difficult situation
because we don't know in this moment if
they going to uh make it illegal
again they are talking about it that
they will forbid it again actually I
cannot even uh think about how how can
this you know how people will go on the
street it will be a riots you know this
will be this will be problem because
they allowed people to grow at home
three plants they can possess like 50 g
a month um this is in Germany this is in
Germany yeah yeah uh so now the because
of the government is not there it's it's
like the the there you know building the
government which is not it's not going
well now and now the the parties are are
on the r which is actually against the
legalization so they want to make it uh
illegal again sure uh which is
Impractical I don't know how it's
possible to do that now uh but let's see
okay and I will not talk about it we
have guests who Vincent we was on the on
the on the show a few weeks ago we we'll
do another show with him in soon so he
maybe can tell much more than me but I
hear something you know because I'm in
Austria but I live in Slovenia but uh I
have a business in Austria with clones
so we are quite dependent on the German
Market also so it's like right maybe in
a few months I cannot ship anymore there
again you know that would be crazy that
would be really unfortunate yeah I will
keep you updated about this definitely
so for sure well you know we know that
you know you have this uh awesome clone
business where you're selling uh unique
genetics that are sought after in the
European market uh from some of our
previous talks and so I would definitely
suggest the guests go back and listen to
those uh so that we don't have to
retouch on too much of that here because
I really want to get into your growing
style knowing that you are in a
completely different Market than what
the US uh is and that you know you have
some let's call it past experience with
growing flower out um you know in
different scenarios and settings uh
so what were some of like so I always
like to start this uh show with talking
about some of your first experience with
plants um and I do feel like we talked
about that before but if you don't mind
kind of taking it back just a little bit
for some of the newer listeners and
telling us a little bit about your um
your personal history with plants where
it all started and how it evolved into
cannabis or if it evolved from Cannabis
into you know uh a desire to grow
vegetables or other um other things in
general just to kind of take us a little
bit along your growing story good
question actually that you mentioned uh
if vegetables were my first inspiration
definitely yes uh I grew up in a garden
of my grandmother which uh in that time
in Yugoslavian time it was in the 50s
60s she everybody after the second World
War uh grew food at home because um it
was you know after Wars normally
everything is destroyed all the economy
is gone so you are depending on your own
few meters of garden to have maybe
better food than you know you can do
what you do so I grew up in a very
beautiful beautiful garden which my
grandmother carried so much about and uh
she she gave this knowledge to my mother
and my mother also to me but my
grandmother actually was more of a
because you know I grew up and my
grandmother's still alive and she
actually
uh let me play in her garden all the
time and I had to do work also you know
my first experiences with with plants is
is potato tomato
salad uh you know herbs a lot of herbs
uh I have you know my grandmother even
let me have my own patch when I was like
5 years old that's cool yeah she she
said you do you remember what you grew
yeah uh carrots um it was carrots and
some Sal got one tomato nice but you
have to understand that in these times
you we did not buy seeds all of the
seeds were made by my grandmother for
that you took you take because this is
heirloom varieties you know today we we
know that this is a weom Tom but at that
time we didn't know about anything else
we just take you have one uh uh variety
of tomato or two maybe uh and one
variety of carrots one variety of
cabbage one variety of of of potato or
two maybe sure not a lot but all of
these were very stable and they
performed in uh the you know the teroa
you know the the the it was the um um
the stuff that grew here for 50 years
already before they select they selected
so much it was acclimated to the climate
and to the yeah that's awesome yeah and
this is also the basic knowledge for
cannabis after okay we talking about it
right now because this is the basic
knowledge how you select yeah sure uh
because outdoor growing uh you know you
have to understand until 2003 I never
saw a plant growing indoors okay yeah uh
from my childhood from the end of' 70s
uh until the 2000 three I never saw a
plant grow under light never okay always
under Sun always which with all the
envir environment which means uh very
good soil very good soil means for me I
live on a river very near a river and
the river bed you know when the river
this river is very big and it's not
controlled 100 years ago and it went you
know it how you say it uh flood a lot
yeah like overflowed overflowed yeah so
it is a lot of sediment the river is
Alpine River it has a lot of uh
magnesium calcium a lot of iron a lot of
Tracee Trace elements already in the
water so it's like and the the river is
like few M away from my house here it's
a big big river it's a yeah it's called
mura and uh yeah
so to go to kabes then you know like
growing up in a garden um in Yugoslavia
at my grandmother's place you know we
have also we have animals we have pigs
we have chicken we had rabbits uh we
grew I mean one of very near there was a
Butchery here it's like there is a lot
of you know it's like a farm you know
like we yeah so I saw a lot of reality
in the beginning food production was for
me very very normal uh when I was 10
years old I knew everything you know
about food about food about the plant to
to the ripeness of a of a fruit and
produce that fruit or even if it's not
vegetable it's meat I saw everything you
know traditionally in Slovenia at that
time when I grew up we used to kill two
pigs uh and in the in the winter time
like No And as kids we were all there
you know to see that you know how an
animal was opened and everything was
taken out and all the meat was used and
every part of the animal was used really
every every part not a lot was thrown
away um so um it is like that you know
when you grow up in this kind of
environment that you actually use
everything you produce
yourself and then when the first kabus
came when I was
years old you know and because it was
not was that the first time you smoked
or the first time that you saw it grow I
first time I smoked okay was when I was
12 or 13 years old okay and then because
I saw it is a flower and it has seeds
inside for me was of absolutely the
first thing I did was take out the seeds
and plant it sure I wanted to see it at
once you know absolutely yeah this was
1993 1993 yeah all right yeah so I
planted them so of course something grew
but you know in the beginning was like
you know 1993 and then
1994 I got seeds from my cin um and he
got it from a guy that came from India
okay yeah we have a lot of land races
here so it's like yeah everybody that
grew here we call it domach which means
hom grown you know domma means home
right like doile yeah yeah yeah have
like this is homegrown so homegrown
means you did it yourself on your garden
yeah and domach was really like uh the
average week with was maybe 5 6% THC
only yeah sure uh but it was land rais
but already acclim it you know okay yeah
uh so then in '96 I I got some seeds
from
Amsterdam and those were like you know
we grew all the time from 93 296 so are
you are you are you 16 now yeah okay
yeah yeah born so you were born in uh
1980 uh
1979 okay okay cool yeah but the thing
is you know in the last podcast I told
you about Mongolia I was 19 years old I
was wrong I was 21 when I was in
Mongolia okay yeah like 200 one yeah I
was that moment when you asked me I
didn't count real but I was 21 years old
when I was in Mongolia yeah okay but
when I was 16 you know I left you know
when you went to high school here in
Austria I mean I was born in Slovenia
you know in Yugoslavia and I went to
Primary School in
Yugoslavia and then the war came and we
were after that we were own country
Slovenia with a separate country not
wasl anymore so and then the high school
came and High School uh I could go to
Austria to high school for 4 years I
went over the Border after After High
School you you graduate with matura and
then you can go to study to University
yeah so I went to lublana which is back
to Slovenia you know okay so I was in
Austria and I way back to Slovenia now
I'm back in Austria again for for my
company because they they allow growing
cannabies uh until you flower uh but
let's jump back yeah
um the the before anything came from
Amsterdam uh the things that were grown
here were very uh
phenotypically very different from each
other and all of the stuff was grown
outdoors in compost you know compost
gardening style that we do you know when
you do vegetables when you do everything
else you know how to do anything it's
the same thing with konomis sure it's
the same code that the the the uh plants
speak the same language definitely and
and I'm assuming you're doing this in
some sort of either like raised bed or
uh like hugle culture uh sort of um like
well tilt or well cared for uh plots of
of land or little patches of Earth yeah
so yeah like you're you're applying
compost to replenish all of your organic
matter and making sure that the
microbial colonies there are healthy and
you have good vermac compost activity in
there and um so I mean yeah but then
still you know then still it's uh from
plant to plant it's uh different you
know the same plant in the same bed one
will perform one will not and why
because they have a different background
for feeding you know they have a
different background from parental uh
side and then they have because of that
they have this different demand for the
food mhm an OG from Pakistan uh and know
I say always that the ogs come from
Pakistan Afghanistan region it is
Afghanistan it is not Inda it's not
sativa it's not ruderalis it's the
Afghanistan the the base of of this uh
family of plants it has it does not
demand a lot of nitrogen it it does not
but if you lack calcium magnesium and
iron with this with this OG related
plants you always have problems OG OG
always want to feed on the trace
elements so much and my assumption is
because it's coming from these regions
where there is not a lot of nitrogen at
all in the ground
nitrogen you know there is a lot of
other stuff but nitrogen is not so much
present there's not yeah you know um so
with other strains like sativa related
or more to the equator let me say of
course a lot of uh rich soil yeah
because everybody knows equator is
volcanic activity is high so you have
even the trace elements you all have
this comp composting which is really all
the time there is like layer of compost
there which is unbelievable yeah
microbal microbal life always I say to
people when you know a plant is outdoors
planted in the ground not in the plastic
container but outdoors in the ground it
is like communicating with the with the
base again you know uh and uh there is
like this taale of you know there is
enzymes and they live in these cities
you know the roots go and there is
cities around those roots and some of
these cities are producing for example
there is enzymes there and these enzymes
go to work and the plants one day says
to them today today I need a lot of zinc
and they go to work and they gather the
zinc and and the microle it's
transporting the zinc to the to the
veins and it's going up to the plant
yeah for sure the ne the next day the
same or the other or other uh you know
uh organisms are uh uh trying to get
iron or trying to get mden or trying to
get uh you know uh you know sulfur for
for the plant you know but it's what
what the plant tells those things it
comes right yeah in containers signals
yeah yeah yeah yeah I think that's great
I mean it makes so much sense in
a like in a in a limited Amendment sort
of way where you're you're kind of just
maintaining a a we we've talked about it
before with other guests where if you
look at an organic substrate that's you
know high in organic matter you have
sand silt and Clay as your main
constituents of the soil right and then
you have whatever else is in there
whether it be like Leaf litter more
organic matter if there's any sort of
like pmus or stones in the soil that
allow for drainage you know a higher
sand percentage in your in your soil um
you have this like battery and the the
more that you care for it or the larger
it is then that like battery has like a
a greater potential for the plan so it
the plant can tap that battery and get
all that energy it needs um even though
it's not energy it's the nutrients that
supply for the the energy Cycles from
the Sun but it's uh it's a I feel like
it's a good analogy to look at it where
you are like you care for the substrate
substrate takes care of the plant versus
in like a hydroponic setting you just
need to make sure that your hydroponic
nutrients are correct and that the ph
and the EC are where you want it and
then your irrigation practices are in
place
um not saying that you don't need
irrigation practices in place for
especially if you're in like this uh
like directly in the ground you don't
want to oversaturate and create some
muddy or anerobic condition no exactly
and that is very good point because
people ask me when they come to my
facility and they
see they see the M plants like growing
more than six months like sometimes I
have two plants in a one 11 lit pot it
depends on the strain yeah we have one
Garanimals clone which is also from
finest you know American clone uh we we
put two plants in 11 lit container it
grows
up and it's you can get a lot of clones
like that you know and you have to feed
it a lot and then people ask me how do
you do that you know like in 11 L
because they are looking like trees
really dark green and I mean dark green
green as lime green some strains is not
to be dark too dark because then they
they are too overfit right you have to
you have to know your strains to know
that right uh the dark green are
normally the ogs that I have in my
company and but the the lighter green
are more the sativa is the plank and you
know the big butt and the yeah but but
the thing is um with
feeding which people always forget is
that the roots need a lot of
oxygen if you grow in soil which is
actually a mix of light mix with we have
which is speed based uh a lot of perlite
is inside it's actually very near
Hydroponics already because it's not
this is not living soil what we use to
do because we need for
production and uh if I would grow at
home uh when I do uh I I never do any uh
live uh I do living soil I don't do live
not alive soil you know what I mean but
in but in the company where there is a
schedule and protocol and it's a
different story if you go to to this big
scales it's it's a total different story
it always people are fighting each other
against you know if you're organic or uh
you know ecological grower or if you are
hydr grower and you know but but
actually it's not right to to
actually it depends on your environment
and depends on your demands you know
right it's it's uh it's setting
dependent absolutely you can't just say
that one style needs to work for
everyone that's a little
um Centric I guess I it it just doesn't
really work um cuz yeah people have
different demands in their Gardens and
they have different uh desires for their
outcomes so you can't just say that one
is the only way to get it done
um but let's take it back a little bit
so cuz I want to I want to kind of learn
about your transition from you know it
sounded like you had your one outdoor
crop a year of whatever was growing
there you save seeds from it grow some
more maybe get some seeds in from
Amsterdam or something like that um so
what was your first experience then when
you really went into it with intention
where you were like I want to make sure
that I get really good flower out of
this and was that in an outdoor setting
or um was it in your first indoor
setting uh and then you know kind of
talk about the transition between those
two and what you what you did as a
grower okay uh until I went to study in
lublana for you know to study I studied
German language and literature and
gistic I'm a professor for German
language which I don't do know but uh
the the thing is when you go to study to
University you have you know a time in
your life that you will never have again
you know just doing your studies for me
it was very simple I I I choose this and
I went to live uh for six years for free
you know to be free travel whenever I
want uh it was easy living uh cheap
living uh a lot of friends I made a lot
of friends all around the world um it
was really good time
so in this time I realized that people
grow for example in luo there was this
guy who grew indoor wheat and I saw that
in
2001 I never saw IND IND whe I heard
about it but never saw
it because we grew so much outside but
even before that you know uh it is like
that we were Growers you know because we
come from rural areas we live in very
you know there's a lot of forest and a
lot of patches and and we were Guerilla
like you call it Guerilla growing this
what we were uh and today it's like that
that still these kind of people exist
and are still my friends they provided
clones also for my
facility um these people are still
living this kind of way uh and uh
through this kind of people I saw that
thing what you asked me when did you
realize I realized when we started to
buy seeds from a specific cultivar
and then try to find uh between those
seeds to try to find uh something that
you would like to have again yeah so
those people already uh cloned so
cloning was on the end of the '90s 98 I
think I saw cloning right okay but we
did it for outdoor first we didn't
flower indoors but indoors under high
pressure sodium lights I saw it first
time on 2 one I saw
it what what was your impression of that
when you when you first saw I was I was
blown away it was it was purple wheat
what I saw oh really okay yeah no I
first first thing that I saw on lights
it was really purple Wheat really purple
yeah it was wow it was Shaman by Dutch
Passion The Strain okay which is
actually outdoor strain and we we used
to grow it a lot of outdoor after that
uh but those guys already had the moms
and during the you know in the winter
time when the the month is not there for
those clones they were flowering them
indoors yeah so they already made those
selections and I actually saw that they
they did it like you know from few packs
they popped they have this numbering and
then fewers the winners you know which
they were reproducing reproducing all
the time and you have you know when you
buy wheat from them you have the same
weed for years
which is like you buy wheat and it's the
same and you buy wheat it's the same you
buy another wheat half a year later it's
the same cuz they were doing the clones
and that's how we realized it's it's
standardized and the standardization
standardization of something that is
very much good chosen you know somebody
that choose really good at that times it
was like you could be the master of
ceremony you know people you know the
whole scene you know the whole concert
scene I was in music business man when
whole people everybody knew about the
strain because everybody was smoking it
because it was like so prevalent you
know the when the Amnesia the Shiva
Super Silver Haze cut came it was so
obvious it's like smelling like incense
stick all around you know it's like yeah
you know so when when you first
encountered this um realization of this
of the
standardization um by using clones and
and reproducing in the same environment
and you know reproducing in an indoor
environment rather than in an outdoor
environment where you know if you get
one crop per year maybe you use a bunch
of clones for it but the quality of that
product one month after harvest versus
10 months after harvest is going to be
pretty different and you probably know
that as a consumer as well just having
the different uh progressions of if it
was an outdoor crop versus an indoor
crop where then in the indoor crop you
know F you get five four or five
different harvests a year so you know
you're maybe having stuff that's 3
months old at the most four months old
yeah and and so you have a much uh
higher level of like a standard of what
you're expecting um so when you when you
experienced this where were you at in
your growing career like what were you
doing at that time actually the thing is
what I want to tell you is like a friend
of mine was growing orange bot which is
Californian orange skk uh for a long
time like six years in a row through
from seeds all the time buying seeds and
doing it yeah so in the first two years
he had really good crops and I mean the
the the the weed was the same almost
like really all from seed all from seeds
but then it changed he bought the same
packet
packs somehow the weed was not the same
anymore
uh and it was not depending on the
season of the weather it was weather
weather was the
same but the quality was
lower and he always relied on seeds
always the seed form of it always
because it's stronger plants it has a
better root it has it it's true it it's
stronger plants it has better root
system it's more uh uh uh uh strong in
sense of against pred it's predatory in
the sense of um no no uh issues with how
you call pests yeah uh it's much more
like that if you have a good line but if
the line gets bad and you sell it as a
producer which is Big producer in Europe
actually today very well known
company um that you do that and most of
those companies are like that if you're
not a small breeder anymore you you
don't have that anymore uh because they
all rely on white lab production which
means uh it change uh you cannot have in
your menu 150 strains and tell me that
you are producing them in house that
that is absolutely impossible to the the
HVAC system alone to be able to handle
all those different pollen sources
without there being any potential of
cross-pollination is a little bit
ridiculous you're you're talking about
like multi-million dollar facility alone
just to be able to have the
infrastructure in place to handle that
and sure there might be like lab grade
facilities in different parts of the
world that are seed producers you know
that produce uh like row crops right
like wheat or um corn or uh other things
like that where it needs a high level of
standardization and um uh safety
protocols to make sure there's no
contamination but no one's doing that
with canvas seeds like you can't you
wouldn't be able to find the backers for
the infrastructure for something like
that just due to the legality reasons
yeah cuz you're still producing flour
yeah yeah and you know you asked me when
I did realize you know I realize you
know when my crop got stolen in
2000 and my father called me
I was in lublana start you know with my
guys I was in radio I was a radio
journalist and I was working in radio my
dad called me like you know hey I
remember the day I was crying man he
told me hey your Duran poisons are gone
there were trees at home here I have't
in Gard I was crying man on the phone
was like my my dad called me like he was
crying also yeah that's how we were were
you know like we were depending this
[__] you know and we have a crisis in
you know there were some heroine junkies
in the town here you know they needed it
you know more than us you know so they
were stealing it yeah but all of these
guys are already gone you know you know
because karma comes back and you know
they're not alive anymore these people
but uh you know I realized that time
that people come to my place to steal my
ganja so I have to move to another
strategy to get the ganja on so we moved
indoors and uh me and my dad made a
indoor room and I flowered in this room
from 2003 till
2019 until when I opened my facility in
Austria I stopped FL well I mean let's
keep it as Anonymous as we need to or uh
you know uh so I have a few questions
though so this the first time you grew
indoor was this before or after you saw
the uh High Press sodium setup while you
were in Luana I grew before because we
used to make the cloning uh we go to the
clones and we put them under artificial
you know CFL lights sure you know to
grow them a little bit so that was my
first experience with growing but I you
know it was like just like maybe one two
years just to to prepare the plant a
little bit before you put them outside
to not flow to not flower too too soon
in the season right if I get them in
March I have I can put them out in May
not not in March because it's too cold
and the the flowering time would be too
L too too too short so it would flower
so we knew that yeah already uh because
we we read the books you know like uh
some some guy have this uh Clark book uh
one one other guy had hor cantes book
some other guy had Ed rosental book you
know sure so you just cross referenced
it found out the information yeah we
found out the because it was no internet
yeah so we also had the like these
magazines we have this grow magazine
which we have also but there was no
internet there was no phones man so it's
like from season to season we saw more
than the this this when the the
magazines came and the this internet and
everything we already knew that you know
what I mean you already know that from
experience because you see it all all
the time and then you were like okay I'm
so interested because other people have
the same experience like overgrow you
know I was watching overgrow man it was
like yeah man that was my community was
overgrow you know because at that time
you have nobody to talk to about it sure
and then as soon as you see someone else
write something down that you've already
been experiencing you're like oh it
confirmed it hell yeah I was doing the
right thing and has a picture with it
you know like and they have like a good
explanation versus the the anecdotal
evidence you know I feel like even with
like the photo periodism of the plants
right like you were saying you can't
just throw a clone outside and March
even if you have a good climate you're
lighting depending on where you are in
the world you're going to have uh you
know probably close to 122 lighting and
you're going to initiate flowering and
then you're going to go into a reveta
stage of the plant and then it's going
to flower out again and you know some
people might say oh that works but it
works with some strains right but some
strains I mean it's not it's not the
method to to rely on no yeah no we've
we've even found growing Outdoors that
sometimes we'll just we won't start the
outdoor plants until you know Late July
MH yeah or mid July mean yeah idea you
just throw the Small Clone out there and
it has two three weeks of uh vegetative
growth and then boom F flips the flower
but also has like this robust amount of
root growth at the same time so you get
this kind of
synergistic growth where the roots are
vigorous the upper growth is vigorous
and you get these huge plants from
nothing and the pests have no time to to
to be you know like that's part less
pests have you seen that when you do
this L Late July crop like you say uh
that you put out side vegetative state
clones which really hardening but then
it's like much less
problems Les less pressure overall cuz
if if pressure builds up on a day-by-day
basis and you can only do so much
through spraying or applications of uh
beneficial insects or otherwise you know
before it becomes either cost
prohibitive or too late in flower where
you don't want to affect the final
product then you know if you're adding
on a month or two that's a lot more
pressure to be built up and one thing
we've also found is sometimes your your
yields can almost be the same in certain
cases depending on how uh close you're
planting if you're doing like uh either
a row of of plants with some sort of
drip irrigation or something um you know
if you have them at a 5ft center like a
one one and A2 meter Center between
plants then you have uh you know if you
give them those extra two months of
growth they're going to just grow into
each other in The Roots as well they're
going to sense that they have now
limited space to grow and their yields
aren't going to be like you know if you
if you have three weeks of veg versus
two or three months worth of veg you're
not going to have three times the amount
of yield for that extra veg time and
you're going to have all the extra pest
problems like you're talking about so
that's something that you know as a as a
grower I always thought you know if
you're growing big plants Outdoors you
need more a lot more veget time and in
some cases sure but in other cases it's
almost not advantageous you know it's
very simple to make a giant plant
actually it's not it's not difficult you
know it's like you put it all you sprout
it in February and then grew it in
inside as if you can and then in I saw
that in March they already put putting
them in tunnels and they are prolong the
light of course for six 4 to 6 hours you
have like HPS lights that give a little
bit of uh heat and uh you know then in
may they already have these big plants
which actually then outgrow everything
there but actually man you know how much
waste it is to do that like this is only
for the eye to to to do something like
that is not e economical that is not
economical it was in the time when in
America you had this plant count right
because of that it still do yeah well
and it's also if you look at it from
like an agronomic standpoint as well the
the nutrient assimilation from the
grounds to create this huge plant all
this biomass like the actual yield from
that total biomass the percentage or
like the fraction of the total biomass
is going to be a lot less than if you
have smaller plants with really healthy
robust growth
uh you know the the fraction of of that
total biomass that's going to be your
end product is going to be way greater
in a smaller plant so yeah you're right
it doesn't it doesn't make sense but it
is impressive you know we see these
people like the Mendo Dope Boys or these
different groups that are like we're
going to grow the world's biggest
cannabis plant and flower it out and
it's like all right you know like that's
fun actually it's it's not like a a
production purpose it's not a production
purpose no definitely but you I mean I
appreciate everything some people do
that you know over the stone have you
saw that man they they grow something
over Stones like a bonsai like a bonsai
you know and I've done that it's fun
it's fun I mean that is some cool [__] I
I mean I like that you know but it's not
yeah it's not like monocropping in a in
a setting to produce a bunch of flow no
no you know what is very very much
important what I I wanted also to touch
on a little bit the quality of the water
that you are using
is I think this is something you know
when you say you need light you need
soil and you need water you don't even
need soil you need a medium yeah what
the medium is it can be r w yeah it can
be yeah so uh but the water
quality to bind the nutrients in the way
yeah arated water Living Water you know
drinkable water it's like we have a lot
of luck here in my country where I live
especially I
mean my place is like you drink the
water you know it's not so it's
drinkable but it's not that good as in
the mountain region right they have it
from the tap man yeah it's drink it's
drinkable water everywhere
here it's so good that it's drinkable
from the TB I don't buy bottled water
ever here ever I don't buy it I have to
buy bottled water here it's uh we're on
this well and the electrical
conductivity of our tap water is uh
1.7 so oh my God you know like 950 parts
per million or so I have
0.4 from the top man I always check it
it just blows me away oh my God we only
use it for cooking or stuff uhhuh the
thing is with water and the people don't
realize here how easy it is to grow
actually the water is drinkable water so
if I can drink it the plants will drink
I have always have to put a pH minus
here always because of uh it's it's
seven so I go to 6.3 6.2 for the for the
pit based plants and when I do cloning
on rock wool and
on easy plug which is speed based I for
the PED based I do 60 6 61 and for rock
wool I do 5'7 you know uh when you
actually you have to with rock wool you
have to always do a
preo uh for 12 hours minimum because you
know the rock wool itself has a pH so
when you put it in water it has to
balance out this pH so the water is I
put in 5.0 and I from my t
I have to put 5 fo0 the water to put in
the Rock wol so next day when we come to
work to to do the cloning it's
5.7 5.6 5.8 you know the RO W and you do
this pre soak and it's working fine uh
but I already also saw that you know
it's the medium
only yeah so the water is so much
important water I want to touch on that
the water quality will bind the
nutrients and uh you have a lot of more
playroom to do with this water if you
have a water uh uh EC of 1 point
something from the tab you know you
don't have a lot of room you know right
cuz you you have to know what is in the
water already right so so you don't add
it you know but here here is like I I
like I know that the economist likes a
lot of iron right many don't many people
don't know I mean don't know don't talk
about it they know but they don't talk
about it that iron is as much when they
always say km km km you can add kmak no
problem yeah but the if lack of iron
comes then no no carmar will help you no
NPK will help nothing will help you
right because there is locks you know
she will lock down all of all of these
Trace elements are so much important to
know about them and to be careful what
kind of medium you are working on and to
be U kind of aware that with some
cultivar you need to add them with some
maybe you don't need to but you know
it's it's depending a lot of this uh
because people always then think that
some brands of fertilizers don't don't
work all of them work it's very simple
to do a fertilizer you know you make it
you make it from scratch actually for
told us already how it's you know it's
very easy to do a fertilizer but um to
make to make a good fertilizer and to
balance it right and that's another
story yeah right absolutely well so um
you know speaking of fertilizing and uh
uh kind of the grow style in general so
when when you and your dad first then
started having to grow indoors because
you were worried about losing your crop
either to theft or um I don't know if
you had any sort of crop failure just
due to weather um or otherwise before
that but you know indoor growing kind of
does limit a lot of those issues or
potential issues um and so what was your
first setup like it sounds like you used
some of the CFL bulbs that you were
already using to keep your veg plants
alive that were going into the outdoor
Garden um but when you when you first
set up your indoor garden for flowering
what did that look like what was your
media um how did you decide how to keep
your plants uh fertilized whether that
be through the medium as like a living
soil did you just pull some soil in from
one of the beds outside um tell me about
it okay I mixed my own soil first you
know I knew about the the soil but we
did not buy soil at that time we we
mixed our own and that means I I bought
so pit based stuff uh in back everything
must be sterilized right so we could not
take some good compost from outside and
bring it in that's not possible right so
uh my secret additive was warm compost
warm uh drippings from from red worms uh
yeah and they sold them here for like a
50 lit bags or 20 lit bags uh and we mix
this inside and we mix the guano the the
bird and the B guano inside and you have
to understand that was 2003 you know
2004 2005 and we let it sit for 2 weeks
before we planted and we were not
putting them in pots we were putting
them in beds so you had beds inside we
have beds Inside Man so what were these
beds built out of they were built
from it was plastic bed it was like you
can buy it you know you it was like this
plastic container which can hold on each
side and you can carry it right okay and
you we just drain
whole but it was like we we put two or
three plants in one bed sure and we saw
this technique with s you know s
Amsterdam s seats he he wrote articles
for the German uh magazine and he has
this that has don't use pots use the
beds and so the the plants connect with
the the roots and we had clones already
in the beginning we never put seeds in
indoor in the beginning we we have we
have this access to to these PE people
my friends who having this uh
standardized clones right the the
super in Lana the friends in lublana
which is not actually from lublana but
all of them are from all around Slovenia
but are in lubl because there are
students sure and all of them are living
every from the mountains from the
seaside from the you know all of these
are still my guys you know still Growers
still still doing their [__] still still
really good people I love them my family
you know uh so still it's like uh you
know some Growers uh I will not talk
about them now I will talk about you
asked me what was the the light man at
that time you could only get HPS it was
not or MH yeah metal halight for the
vegetative time and HPS yeah uh and
after they put out the Phillips uh put
out the osam osam put out a light that
is can be used for vegetative state and
the flower stage at once do you need
need to change it anymore yeah we use
that one you know the ostram now T4
Epsilon something you know it was 400
wat lights you know and then we changed
to 600 you know and we use the old tro
you know the magnetic one the really
heavy sheet you know you cannot carry it
it's so heavy we use that one so after
that you know when the first uh ballast
came that are uh digital you know we
were so ah you it's so light man you can
carry two of them in your hands because
otherwise first of all the ballast man
was so heavy and it started to broom
after 2 3 years when you use it it start
to make this sound
like it was like broom sound you know
like and it is not good sign because it
uses more electricity for Less
efficiency yeah you see it was always
and then you know when the the light uh
came to we we saw the uh keramic metal
highlight you know the caramic TM
uh did what we tried this it was good
for vegetation but maybe not for FL I
mean I never went into it so much that I
could tell but I saw it and I worked
with it a little bit uh and now I work
with lead lights you know it's a it's so
cost efficient to to the HPS right I
still have HPS at home somewhere hidden
you know when I use it maybe one you
know because it produced a really really
good flower too U it has it had its own
qualities even if it's 40y old
technology right what were um what were
some of those first harvests like that
you that you and your dad
had um not so good the first one I mean
but it was clones so it was like we
instantly knew something is wrong okay
you know because we saw the product from
my people and we saw it from indoor and
from outdoor and we saw the same plant
like it how we behaves and then we
wanted to reproduce it like them and uh
it was like uh the first round was a
disaster and you know what was the
problem
ventilation I was going to ask yeah we
did not put uh the strong we then on the
second round we have it was like a
revelation even the the second round was
so much better it was so much better
than anything uh and then we tried to
keep this level for some time and then
you add a little bit more and we we
adjust the wing uh the the you know um
the wings were better because before we
had the small ones and sure pool tubes
and and uh [__] [__] you know some
[__] like that uh at the end from round
to round from strain to
strain
uh you get better and it was like we
have five crops indoor crops a year mhm
so we were like you know each year five
so 10 years it's like 50 crops yeah 15
years is like 75 crops right you know
like after 100 crops
you know your you know what you're doing
yeah oh absolutely I um so like when
you when you first noticed that you
needed more ventilation did um what were
you seeing in in some of that in that
first crop where like did you did you
realize that they were like heat
stressed or um was was it a uh a
humidity issue or was it both um it was
it was like a condense was starting to
to to put the walls were condensing you
know dripping dripping oh my gosh yeah
man it's like what the [__] you know cuz
my dad was like I said to him like
ventilation but he got some small 20
watt you know think like small
ventilation but is that is nothing you
know I mean but you have to understand
that time you cannot get just into a
grow shop you know there was no Grow
shops here so
you have to get this [__] you know like
even carb we have no carbo filter the
first two years cuz we living the room
like 90 100% humidity the first yeah
but then on the second man it was
already like 50 60 the uh per of of
humidity and uh temperature wise was
much better we got a heater then you
know and then everything went much
better uh and the ventilation after we
because we were very focused on
ventilation because one time in the
first year I think we get powdery Milo
right and we didn't first time I saw it
I mean I saw it on wine grapes I know
what powder Milo is and you know how we
cure it at that time H with
milk we we we we have uh Farmers here
who have cows so when you put 100% cow
milk on
processed milk you dilute it 10 to one
you spray your plants with it and the
powdery Milo is gone yeah I've heard
that as well but but it's really stinky
it's so stinky man I don't want to
repeat it ever in my life ever no so
this you spread this on your indoor
plants and uh and then it yeah you just
had like rancid milk smell after a while
it was like yeah but the crop was really
good good at the end man really good
yeah I mean really good it was it was I
mean we have just a little bit of powder
mildo we sold it and after that we
really got into what was the reason the
reason was that we got the powder mildo
with a clone that we acquired from GRS
from aan facility it already had that
cuz other stats you know the powder
mildo plant the New York City Diesel
plant was like leaning on the Cy Star
plant which had no powdery mildo but the
the New York City Diesel plant was like
white it was like somebody would put
flour over it you know like so this is
so this is the the true story of how
sour diesel was created then right you
just took New York Diesel and sprayed it
with milk and let it go
sour but but this clone new New York
City Diesel at that time it it was uh
produced by
S but it has nothing to do with your
sour diesel or nothing to do with Kim or
nothing to do with anything like that it
just like their version of what they
were trying to get close to yeah but I
think someone just made up a name you
know for for that specif specific cut he
made s is a great breeder for other
stuff I know but for this cut I mean it
was very specific wheat I mean it was so
smelly that this sheet when it GRE I
mean it was it had so this Aroma was
like I don't know I mean people in
Austria will know about that cut it was
in the '90s and in the early 2000s New
York City Diesel cut it it was I was
puking you know like to to for me strong
yeah the aroma the aroma was like
whether you like it you don't like it I
never liked it I just got one clone one
time and it had powdery Milo it infested
my crop it was like not good relation
with this plant with me in the beginning
you know sure something I don't like
right but doesn't matter I know that
some people liked it because they
produced it and it worked for them but
in my place it was infested with with PM
so I I saw PM then and I from that time
I was
really uh trying to you know fight
against PM all the time but it's like
it's all about the VPD uh the vapor
pressure deficit uh powder milu has no
chance if you create an environment that
is not possible to connect to the plant
absolutely I um I like to explain to
people that uh powdery mildew is a it's
a mushroom basically right it's just a
it's just it's just like other um fungal
uh organisms where you need uh a wet dry
cycle as well as like a hot cold cycle
in order to Spate the the the Milo
spores and so if you think about it like
the the forest floor right where you
would get edible mushrooms or something
from if you were out foraging you you're
going to have all this Leaf litter on
the top of the forest floor so below
that where the melal colony um is is
growing it's going to be cooler it's
going to be wet right and then when it
pushes up its fruiting body above the
leaf litter on the floor it's going to
be a little drier and a little bit
warmer and so if you have cold wet
nights and dry warm days you're going to
have this sporulation event in your grow
area where you're going to allow for cuz
because powdery mildew spores are
everywhere right you're not going to be
able to reduce powdery mil spores unless
you have a completely sterile
environment with like HEPA filters and
uh UV filters and all these different
things right so if you but if you're
creating the environment for it where
it's like wet cold then hot dry then wet
cold then hot dry you're going to have
all these spores just love and life
because they're the melium can grow at
night and then it can Spore it can
produce its fruiting bodies in the day
which produce more spores and then those
sporulate at night and then they produce
more fruiting bodies in the day so it's
just this and Nick you know why actually
because uh there is this SP the this
spora on the leaf the the you know the
when you look at the microscopic way of
the leaf it has this spora and it has St
stomata and it has wax around the
stomata when you have this dry hot
instead of wet cold uh the the wax is
dry out and it's
crumbling and it makes the belief
susceptible for the Spore to connect to
the leaf it can ENT it can enter the
plant through this gate after that
that's a great point cuz you always
notice when you have a really good
steady VPD like um cuz you know you want
a temperature differential day and night
but that means you also need to adjust
your humidity day and night so that the
overall V vapor pressure deficit kind of
remains um uniform day to night without
having too much fluctuation you you can
have some but not a lot but when you
have that limited fluctuation and all
your param are set you get that awesome
waxy cuticle where the the leaves are
shiny almost right and healthy and happy
absolutely you can you can see it on
like tomato plants too right uh like a
really nice healthy tomato plant is
going to look waxy and shiny and then
you know if you uh allow for that tomato
plant to maybe go too long or get
unhealthy then you start to get powdery
Milo on it so um yeah it's very very
similar things where yeah vapor pressure
deficit is huge huge and it sounds like
you had a huge experience early on to
see that ventilation is one of your
friends if you don't have um like air
control or air conditioning uh and air
Handling Systems like that um for
example you know you in my facility when
I uh moved my first facility to the
second one when where I am I always have
this this calculation in my head I have
to uh remove uh the air from the room
eight times an
hour I I can be able to do that eight
times or 10 times an hour if I can
remove the whole air space sure to
change it then the the VPD is okay right
you know what I mean you never have
problems well before we get into too
much of what you're doing currently I
just want to wrap up a few questions
about kind of some of these earlier
experiences with indoor settings um so
did you run this living soil that the
substrate that you would create um and
put into these beds is that what you ran
the entire time that you did your uh
homeg growing or did you ever move into
Hydroponics I never did Hydroponics
instead of Coco I tried Coco okay I
liked it but the other the the stuff was
uh at that time I had no you know it's
always the thing that you have to learn
and you learn by mistakes sure always
always you learn by mistakes and uh
because if you cannot question something
that you did wrong what is the problem
you always have to ask what is the
problem why is this thing and you always
is your fault it you have to get rid of
the of the ego think that somebody give
you a sick plant and that the plant was
in the beginning when you got got it it
was already okay but now it's not good
so the Gen itics must be it wrong wrong
you are the problem you know what I mean
it's always the Grower's fault first of
all 99% right let me say like that yeah
so let when you go through this concept
uh then by mistake uh you make all the
mistakes right you you don't you know
with and then of of course when you C
cultivate clones instead of seeds you
always have the same plant
and with the same plant you can
masterize the process very much quickly
very much better because this plant is
always the same genetic
material uh of course it's depending on
how the mother was cut and how was yeah
the Clone sometimes is better sometimes
is worser but it is the same cut so if
you're good you have a good environment
even from very very bad clones you still
can make really good plants if you put
all the dedication into it and take time
and uh don't rush things you know uh so
actually it is always been a lot of a
lot of empiric work that means grow grow
grow all the time indoor outdoor you
know I was doing indoor but in these
times man we doing outdoor too because
to do to do uh indoor in the summer was
never an option no it would you would
need like all the sorts of air
conditioning and yeah and we don't have
this air conditioning we don't buy this
[__] it's like I mean and you know all
the crops uh that I got from this time
you know from these years I tried many
many many different genetics from
Austrian clone Market you know I buy I
mean there was there was so much
genetics that you know trying did the
Austrian Market open up like when was
that uh
available uh around 2000 it's even even
before yeah it took 25 years yeah yeah
cool Sorry Sidra but yeah yeah but it's
so long you know actually the Clone
Market is there and my guys before that
are were working on it already you know
because they didn't get those clones
from Austria but they made them
themselves but
it's but in the sense of of uh the aan
club Market is so big now and U we don't
want to get too much into it now don't
want to talk about it too much but it's
like I'm a part of it you know gens
production by atics is a part of it
we're quite a big wholesaler now and
people know us and genetics we have to
represent them and this is the story how
I got to those genetic actually because
without all this work when you ask me as
a hom grower to see all the other clones
in the market I could not I could not
even have any um ability the ability to
think about the
genetics it is like for me when you say
to me orange bot orange bot is the same
[__] as Californian orange skunk
Tangerine Dream
Tangi uh everything with orange orange
punch it is all based in the same family
of plants the parent
genome sure or purple you know the we
have a clone which is ice cream runs
actually it's like purple urle it's the
same it's the same thing a little bit
variation of it but it's the same thing
as purple lle it grows the slowest plant
to grow ever produces very dense purple
BS very spicy uh no issue with mold no
issue with paste it outside performer
totally you know that how you know the
plants because uh through the years of
growing as a home grower years and years
uh and trying different cultiv until you
try to make your own crosses of course
you know you end up there yeah you make
your own cres but then you know it all
ended for me when I uh you know I have a
family man I have two k children and I
have to feed them and uh the thing is
that I needed a a a real job you know I
mean I was working a lot of stuff in my
life I we didn't talk about that but I
was involved in the music industry I was
involved into theater but big theater
you know I was translator for a very big
director who was working in German
Market we were doing very big
Productions so I was paid I was paid
very good there so I could actually be a
hom grower
and you know coming from a production
and living for 6 months without a
problem you know from that money yeah
it's like that but after you know uh
then it turned out you know time time
tells so now I started my own company in
Austria and after that I knew that I
have to quit
flowering right this is the story that
how I stopped
flowering I know it's like uh yeah I
started a legal business so I had to
stop the flower yeah let's talk about
that I mean uh as someone who I I think
cloning is one of
the it's such an essential stage of the
Cannabis life cycle if you're growing
for production and the different methods
of cloning all seem you know there's
ones that work really well but then
there's some that might just be uh you
know like a hom grower uh in a couple
plants here and there where you know
they they can be a little L Fair they
don't necessarily need to produce the
nicest clones but with some of the
standards that you've mentioned before
on previous shows uh when dealing with
the European market where you have a uh
different Regulators coming in and
telling you how you have to do certain
things and uh certain precautions and
standards that you have to have in order
to ship clones uh over country borders
which is something that you know I feel
like a lot of American listeners will
kind of be blown away by that that's
just something that's part of your
regular business model um how did you
develop your grow Style and what are
some of the things that you do there
that you um like what are some of the
things that you do there that you feel
are are working really well for your
your cloning operation and where do you
feel as though there might even be some
hindrances due to these different
regulatory bodies that you're beholden
to okay uh good question man it is to
transit to from hom growing to a
facility is a very big thing you you
many Growers who are home Growers now
maybe think that their model of Home
grow could work in a big facility
normally it's not the Sops are so you
know we you go out from homegrown and
you don't have no experience in
industry and actually I did work for
some other people in the industry here
but they have no Sops it was all it was
all Anarchy you know yeah I've seen like
and I saw that and I didn't want to work
for them anymore no and I opened my own
[__] and I created my own system you
know and the system is like that that
you keep mod plants of specific
strains specific
cultivars uh that is actually personal
connected I'm I am uh that is my opinion
is is very high qualiity one from the
beginning already because they were
really selected for years already they
were not a clone from last year what I
got in my company from my people you
know they were like already clones that
are like 8 to 10 years old at that time
and now they are like almost 15 20 year
old you know it's like and the thing is
I did not go to the Australian market
and get clones from other shops and open
my own business with those
clones because normally people do that
it's
like 90% of people did that at that you
curated your own Library I curated my
own Library you know no of course I got
a few strains which I got from from a
library that is in Austria also but this
is a friend of mine you know and it was
it was classical strains which I needed
for my customers at that time Still
Still I need but now I have additions
which I only I have and the people that
they have those strains they got it from
me and I have no problem with it when
they sell it it's not of course it's a
free world man what you want you know
it's like I'm not I'm not having no
problem with that if you resell the
genetics that I got of course it's it is
like that comp let's compete with
quality of the of the Clone then you
know how it's rooted you know how the
mod plant how you shape it how you how
you produce it the thing is that uh I
tried uh in the facility that I was
working before I open my my my own
facility with the business yeah is uh
all they all also used
Hydroponics which I am not really
professional in I'm really more
professional in sense of pit based stuff
and soil cocoa mixes and uh uh you know
mother plants which are grown for like
half a year or 7 months and then I
change them all the time I don't I don't
grow old mother plants I don't want to
have my mother plants to be old and
Woody woodiness woodiness is not a good
thing with clothes so are you saying you
you you still keep mothers around for 6
months or you've lowered that time now I
I still have some strains you can keep
for 6 months others you can't I mean to
have a you can obviously you can keep
them for years you know right some some
shops did like when I started my
business some shops had mod plans for a
year or more they were also bragging
with it you know like like we have this
you you can make do you can make D do
from the stem man like wow yeah what
about you know it's really funny to
think about it too knowing what we do
know now uh about how somaclonal
variation and
um uh like pathogen buildup or other uh
buildup of uh exogenous source es on the
plant that are causing it to express
differently than
its uh unadulterated genetic version
let's say and how those can build up
over time in older plant tissue and how
I I've even worked for some people at
one point that they you know they wanted
to keep mothers around for as long as
possible because the idea behind it was
that that mother the Clones they get off
of it are going to be uniform to the
product that they were using used to
growing and that product changed over
time because that one mother was around
for like a year and a half right so the
Clones you were getting off of it at 30
days out from the transplant versus you
know uh 360 days after the transplant
they're going to just be lacking almost
in a little bit and so they thought that
they were doing it to keep the genetics
at a specific level whereas using
Healthy Growth in recreating new
moms uh successively and uh you know on
a on a regular schedule keeps the plant
in more Health as long as you're
choosing your healthiest clones from
those batches and and making sure that
you're taking care of the the mothers
and the root system of the plants so
that they maintain Health um and so you
know as someone who does have to keep
plants alive and to keep these genetics
um you know in in a sense stable uh
where you have you know very consistent
results with the Clones that you're
shipping out what are some of the
practices that you're using to maintain
those mothers uh at a very healthy um at
a very at very healthy growth as well as
what and then from there talk about some
of your cloning practices that you feel
as they'll create your best clones okay
uh mother plants as I said not to be uh
too old but not cut them too early for
you know you have to cut them for
structure for sure but some of those
clones are like like you saw this these
big steams and you think it's going to
be the you know some of them you can
root very good some of them you can't um
it depends on strains because when you
keep like 35 different
cultiv it depends it depends on
strengths so sure uh but the thing is
normally it is very simple don't do not
overw
your
moms my first rule do not overwater it's
very important that's something that a
machine doesn't know a pump doesn't know
when to stop pumping you know uh that's
why I have uh two gardeners for the moms
two guys that are paid for their jobs to
do that like every third day you know
and even before they have to go through
because regular checking because we have
different size of pots but do not over
over overwater your mothers ever because
if you do
that it's a very big big you know two
two steps back yeah uh the the second
thing is do not keep your moms too old
the third thing is experiment with
different mediums when you clone for
different cultiv okay we just we just
realized that for example very old
cutting from White Widow uh very old
cutting new cutting from uh America the
ice cream runs are uh rooting much
better on rock wool instead of uh easy
PL easy PL is a pit based yeah but rock
wool is rock wool we have
Gro the grodon has it advantages but you
have to keep a lower pH for the grodon
than than for the uh Rock uh then for
the easy PL the two different mediums
different strains react better in
different mediums also maybe not many
producers talk about it a lot but when
you have uh a variety of exotic strains
like me have like you know all the
American strains they work much better
on easy BL now than they do on groon you
know for me
I use yeah and I use now very uh I I
experiment now with different kind of
rooting hormones okay I use I use
powdery rooting hormone which is
phosphorus actually uh which is actually
for I buy it here in Slovenia uh and
it's actually you know for all kind of
cuttings you know for soft for uh half
uh uh hard stems and for Woody stems you
can root everything with this one you
know it's called corx yeah
okay corx oh corx corx yeah and the
producer is in Slovenia so okay cool
yeah and uh we use now a one that is
clone 91 we got this product clone 91 it
smells like ethanol which is like
strange I use it first time last week to
try it yeah it is it is liquid you pull
liquid and you can root you know before
you plug them you have like a hand full
of clones and you put them into soak for
20 seconds okay yeah we try this now so
I I always tell people never be because
I work with different stuff a long time
until you know I try something else and
sometimes never be uh two stop born on
something that okay something works but
don't be stop born that only this is the
the it and over because that that that
goes into a narrow Point uh sometimes
it's not available you know you want to
buy the material that your production
goes on and it's not there it's like
what what oh what should I do now you
know sure you have to have a second
pathway you know to go ah this works too
so all the time you have you have a
solution right yeah you have to I like
to point out to people what some of
these active ingredients are like in uh
rooting Solutions and stuff you'll
usually have uh it'll say IBA or endel
3ic acid or maybe NAA which is
napthalene acetic acid and you can find
those different components in other
products and you can look for the ratio
at which they're put into your favorite
product and either dilute to that Ratio
or find something with a similar Ratio
or maybe just like you're saying try
something else don't be too stubborn to
to not want to try something else
because a lot of these different things
especially when it comes to
Horticultural practices like cloning
right we've been cloning plants for over
a hundred years at production levels in
around the world and there's plenty of
information out there on what to do for
it right so being stubborn in one way is
yeah you can't you can't do that we also
we also did experiment I tell you this
in my facility we did the guys did the
experiment without any rooting hormone
at all to plug it into the the easy
plugs we did it you know 50 of those we
did without hormone 20
rooted without hormone just because the
mom was so healthy also right the plant
itself but with with hormone almost
everything will root right so it's well
and even like like the IBA and the NAA
are just different uh oxin and cyto
right and those are already produced uh
endogenously in cannabis plants for you
know apical growth root growth all these
different things that we're like
applying them to
um that you know it's already uh it's
already there we're just applying extra
to try and promote something and so yeah
it's that's it's important to know that
there's different ways to get to it and
you know the as you asked me before you
know about the agencies come into your
facility to get uh the paperwork done
for you that you have a European planed
passport at the end of the day yeah and
those agencies are actually there to
have an insight and have a control uh
over pests and diseases that can Ure on
the market you know and actually it's a
I have actually very good relation to
them and I work with them closely for
exports which is outside which is
European exports I don't need to to to
extra to talk to them but if I export
outside of Europe I have to organize uh
meeting and they have to come to make
you know always is a different if uh one
country demands something that they need
to step inside they will always you know
sure it is uh they paperwork is done
like if somebody from outside of Europe
wants clones from my facility it's very
simple you give me an import permit and
with this import permit I go to to Aus
to this agency and they come to my
facility and uh go through this import
permit what H what is the demand on the
import
permit from this demand uh they will
check all the
facility uh and even Beyond of that and
you know if the DeMont is checking for
all kind of viruses they it is there I
already did it so it's it's it's a deep
scan uh people call you know you have
this Tumi genomics stuff right you know
have this kind of data it is all valid
valid but it is also uh very unaccurate
also on the same point sure it's not
it's not U this thing the the the
standard for shipment outside of borders
of cont
let me say it's much more different
standard sure absolutely I mean it has
to be right we don't want to spread
pathogens or invasive species or other
things like that that could potentially
harm crops or other uh like native
species of plants or other things like
that that can that can be devastating
and so it's you know there's a part of
like the level of bureaucracy behind
that that much oversight I'm sure can be
a hindrance in some people's eyes but
then the ability to also help
prevent issues like catastrophic sort of
events potentially from occurring
brother um like could you imagine like
let's just say something with hops Laton
vroid right if something like that
entered into a market where there's a
like a CBD manufacturer and it somehow
makes its way into that fac fa due to
mislabeling or something from LAX
standards it could it could ruin you
know destroy let's say it just ruins one
crop but this crop is over a 100,000
acres or something that's that's crazy
amounts of wasted resources and wasted
time and all these different things that
could have you know gone into a
productive crop so yeah that's I think
it's really valid to have stuff like
that especially when you are shipping
over country or continent borders which
is something that again I don't think
that a lot of people in the US market
are thinking about how much
standardization and oversight will be
required if something like that were to
happen it's already it already happens
if we're shipping other production crops
that are through some sort of clonal
tissue like whether it be like apple or
other Orchard crops things like this
oranges you know all these things that
are they're they're single cultivars you
know they're they're uh cloned onto
existing root stocks or you know it it's
a whole Market in and of itself that has
extremely high levels of uh oversight
because it you know you if you ruin
something like the orange market it not
just ruins you know the the capitalistic
sense of it where you have nobody
gaining money from their oranges anymore
but you also lose a lot of that
potential neut source for however many
millions of people that that would
provide it for so it is it's important
but it it requires so many different
angles to look
at yeah man it is um actually you know
the the these agency people who are
officials government
officials that's very helpful people for
my facility for example you know I
always followed
their advice their advice was for
example I was shipping to Israel one
time few years ago and uh they told
me uh that two years ago one Austrian
farmer tried to ship apples into Israel
and just just apples themselves right
apples apples man and all the apples
when they arrive in t
aiv were
destroyed cuz they didn't pass this
standard because they didn't pass the
standard and what was the problem he
told
me because it was like when I contact
them because I have a from Israel the
the inquiry you know and um they give me
the import permit so on the import
permit there was listing of stuff that I
have to check for before I send it
man that was like a list that was like a
list is when you talk about whole plate
and virus you there was not only whole
plate and virus there was stuff written
there I still have this paper it is
stuff written there all all viruses I
know like tobac virus latent something
virus then mosaic virus from some
different mosaic virus again some like
beat curly top virus I don't know man
it's like every [__] fuing thing that is
possible to check for they they wanted
to have it
checked and we did that then you know
and actually he asked he told me that U
the thing is why the apples were
destroyed from this farmer because he
was using uh some stuff for uh
prevention you know some oh you know
like a pesticide or something like a
pesticide or something that was allowed
in Austria but not allowed in Israel
yeah that's a that's a big one yeah yeah
this is like the thing is that wow he
used that you know for you they give you
this checklist what you are allowed to
use and what are not allowed to
everything you get everything these are
these are really documents man this is
like you have to go through and you have
to check what is actually on your Market
because most of that stuff on the list
is not there on your Market but you have
to find stuff that is there on your on
your Market in your country to check for
it because Israel is a different
environment man it's like they have
different it makes me think of in the US
every state that has a a legal like a
recreational or a medical market for
cannabis has different standards for
testing some of them will test for
pesticides some of them won't some of
them will test for mot toxins like from
a mold or something like that that could
have been produced on the flower some of
them don't yeah some of them test for
THC percentage using one protocol some
of them use another protocol all these
different things where it's not
standardized at all but some people are
still wanting to use the
standardizations we have in place and
then open up interstate commerce or
International Commerce and how how can
you do that when the product from your
Market is is going to go to this other
Market if it gets tested it's going to
fail and it's going to get either
trashed or returned but still all that
shipping cost is going to then fall on
the initial Nick it will not get it will
not get returned no way no it's get
itest Destro it's going to get destroyed
onto the black market you know destroyed
right it's going to get destroyed yeah
absolutely destroyed so it's it's not
something where I feel like we're uh
mature enough within the market to be
able to even start to think about that
stuff until we start creating a little
bit more
standardization and less of this sort of
fog that is the Cannabis Market where
you can't necessarily know how it's
going to even be tested within your own
States Market you have different uh
standards of testing for each facility
within a specific state so you can't
even you know like one one company might
might test your your product and come
out at 20% THC another company might
test your product and it'll come out at
35 THC and the only difference is is
that they pulled it from the top of the
bag versus the bottom of the bag yes you
know it's it's stuff like that where
it's uh like how how can we use those
that level of uh discrepancy within our
standards and say well we can apply this
to a larger market it just doesn't make
a lot of sense to me and you're making a
very valid point that you know within a
market like you're operating in where
you have to have all these standards
something as simple as using one
pesticide that's totally fine within
your Market it causes the entire
shipment to get destroyed all that money
gone all that production gone all that
time and effort gone right all because
you didn't read somebody else's
standards two papers you know your you
know what is allowed in your country
what is allowed in those this country
where you try to export you have to have
two papers and then you have to you
measure you like what you know and then
you find this cross like oh [__] we
using this and they're not allowing it
oh [__] you know yeah this is the [__]
you know yeah that's I mean that's a lot
to deal with the thing is that I always
you know I I'm a locky one that I I
really don't use a lot of pesticide in
my facility I right my thing is you know
of course I use some but it's really
soft one uh plant wash also um but the
most important thing most most important
thing clean your [__]
floors yep walk in with the shoes that
you are walking into your facility have
a changing you you change your clothes
change your shoes always do use bath or
anything like a shoe bath we have we
have a mat which is like you step on it
and it's like disinfecting stuff right
but most most of it this will not
prevent uh anything if you don't use
extra your shoes in the company is your
shoes you don't you don't walk with
those shoes anywhere else and when the
floors of the facility has to be so
clean that I can I can lick it boy you
know absolutely that is the thing that
is most uh I think you can M maintain uh
the most past free environment through
this first absolutely yeah because when
the clean clean floor is there then
there is no more uh there is no more
room for these things to to be really
impacted you know like right they're not
they don't have hiding places you know
you can so
um we already talked a little bit about
your mother practices and your uh
cloning practices is so what are some of
the other parts of your facility that
are either unique to your setup or that
you really feel as though you have
dialed in cuz I think you're in a mixed
light setting correct you have a it's a
greenhouse with supplemental
lighting actually it's not a greenhouse
but it's like a it's like a u you know
it's made from panels you know it's
industrial complex but from one side of
this industrial complex it's glass it's
a glass it's a glass wall okay yeah yeah
oh so just the wall is glass not the
ceiling no not the ceiling no just the
wall the ceiling is not glass the
ceiling is sunlight you know it's uh the
light is uh Austrian producer that I
have for lead lights and this this
producer developed these lights that I
have uh this line the Evo line for six
years development on cannabis okay these
lead lights are specific made for conies
what what's the company again sunlight
sunlight okay I've heard of them but not
with un Sun but s n sunlight it's aan
company they will start to sell in
European in American market now they
just announced they're really they're
really really good they're really
expensive also but uh also very quality
I mean this is the top top shelf lamp um
for are they high Bay lights where um
you know you're keeping them still six
seven eight feet above the plants or are
they uh the bar style arrays where
you're dropping them right down you know
18 to 20 in above the can you can do
both with those light actually when you
do the vegetation vegetation like I do I
always keep them very high sure I don't
I don't go but when you do flowering
with these lamps cuz they are full
spectrum lamps uh you go close you can
go close and this facilities in
Switzerland and all I mean this facility
really big facilities they they are
providing facilities with these lights
for years now and uh they are really
like you know you will see now actually
they will come to your market now so um
and they are actually like Steve Jobs
one guy made it you know Martin is his
name yeah he's a guy that made you know
he was a grower and that guy produced
his own lead lead lamps but because he
was not satisfied with the lead lamps
what that was on the market at the time
and he was in a garage you know and from
that garage a million million company uh
came to light now you know and they are
really good producers and we have a good
relation uh I was supporting them in a
time when they were not so known
actually and uh I bought all the B stock
from those lamps yeah they had you know
I bought these lamps U which is perfect
you know the same lamps that they sell
now evoline but thing is that the glass
because the protection is
e65 that means you can spray in this
environment with this lamps yeah that
you can they are waterproof lead lamps
and you can spray sulfur sulfur also
they have like Co coating for because
lead lamps you can destroy with sulfur
so yeah maybe people don't know that and
they spray and then they are wondering
why the lamps are going off at a certain
point yeah because sulfur will eat your
doodas you know it's like it's like that
you know so actually with these lamps uh
I produced most quality moms because HPS
was good also before that but in a
certain time you know in winter time
when you don't need so much eating then
but now it's like the electricity went
so high and you need sufficient light uh
you need a setting when the the light
the density of the light is so that you
can see it on the internodal spacing of
the moms you can see it on the on the
stem uh how you you can see it but the
thing is they need more feet they you
need to feed them more calcium magnesium
iron sulfur sink mongan Bon mden you
know Trace elements and all those stuff
because they will eat up more because to
use all of this these photons that come
down right now lead light some people
will tell that it's not so good for them
I understand it why because they were
used to grow 30 years under HPS and
metalight and the product was really
good and now with lead lights the
product is not there for them cuz they
they went from one facility where they
had HPS and they're like okay I have all
this uh air conditioning right and I
don't have a lot of dehumidification
won't need that and then they go to LEDs
and it's the inverse right you have less
heat production so you don't need as
much HVAC in terms of the the cooling
but you need a lot more dehumidification
because your
transpiration uh under LEDs is just way
higher because your photosynthetic
Potential from that led is it's just
more ideal light than HPS for um for
cannabis growth so you just I I've seen
other people run into that problem where
they go from one to the other and they
say oh LEDs don't work that well and
it's like just keep your temperatures a
little higher keep your humidity a
little higher but make sure that it's
not getting out of whack yeah yes yes
always like this there is always balance
of things you know the the metastas of
your body you know is the same with
those things right yeah yeah like the
the metabolic
rate yeah yeah the yeah the metabolic
rate yeah yeah you know absolutely yeah
it just goes up when you have more
energy input so for example you know
when I caught a mom that is that has
been reving for the last three weeks but
I was not cutting her for three weeks
and she's like putting out these really
branches you know like w and then I CAU
her the next time I I'm not going to
feed her a
lot you know I cut her I when she's dry
I give her a normal pedigree and then
the next time when I uh uh uh water her
then she gets a lot of food but I need
to cut out the ba the basic of her from
from beneath to up just to leave the few
uh uh Nas that I want to shoot right
that one so that is how I create good
stems with clones that you don't have a
lot of when you have too much density
the all these small branches underneath
they eat away the energy for the Clones
that you want to cut from your mobs yeah
what are you um what are you typically
feeding uh like what strength of
electrical conductivity for your normal
moms what are you feeding your clones uh
you said you cut it back a little bit
after you cut moms what are some of
those different parameters you run yeah
uh the water from the tab is 0.4 0.5
right with my place uh normally have a
regime
of uh for the the Clones in the in the
chamber for the first 10 days I don't
feed them at all from the time they are
cut they don't feed them uh and from the
10th day on they gave I give them 0.3 AC
so
0 0.7 0.8 when you when you measure it
yeah and I use a very specific uh you
know uh bio NOA company Bova yeah I
think I've heard of that before green
green one and they have hydro super mix
it's a specific uh it's a specific uh
product which is working really good
it's is it just like a one part
vegetative uh applic one part vegetative
application and you you use it like it's
mpk and you use it as that and you just
you know it's like made for made for uh
hydroponic systems sure just like it's a
mineral do do you find that you have to
add any additional calcium or
micronutrients or anything like that I
add also from con you know the
ronic ronic is always uh it's a root
root B root booster or or
from what's in the booster again risot
tonic it's called and it's you know the
tree that is made that is growing next
to rivers it's very if you cut a branch
from that tree and you stick it into the
ground it will
root Willow Tree okay Willow Tree yes
willow tree and the willow tree is the
base of that product that that is what
guy the guy told me from K you know that
he said actually the concept of of the
risot tonic of the of the uh product of
root enhancer sure uh it it is actually
from willow trees you know and they got
it things like like it it things like
you know
it it does not smell very good when you
open the bottle yeah but uh Willow was
where yeah Willow was where people found
um what was it aspirin I believe
initially was like Willow shoots you
could you found like the the same
component for aspirin and then I think
it also even has a significant amount of
uh IBA the indo3 buic acid in it and so
people could use that for um giving to
their their plants to help promote
health and one thing that uh I found out
recently that I know a lot of people
don't know but you can use aspirin if
like if your plants have like a a vroid
like hops lighten vroid or something
like that if you add aspirin like just
your regular aspirin to your nutrient
solution and I don't know the exact
amount so look it up people but um
it'll promote a healthy plant and reduce
some of those viral symptoms which is
like if you need to limp along to a
harvest or if you need to keep something
alive just long enough to make sure you
can get healthy cuttings off of it and
then either put it through tissue
culture or something if it is a viral uh
pressure you can use things like aspirin
to to do that and with a willow extract
you're getting both right you're getting
uh the promotion of this oxin for heavy
root development as well as this
potential pathogen suppression overall
Health tonic I guess you could say so
that that's really fascinating I I could
see how especially for moms if you're
feeding that you know you're maybe
raising the overall oxen count in the
plant so that you're rooting uh your
cuting root fast you know and and
vigorously they have to be hungry yeah
you know not hungry that they start to
yellow on the Le because they start to
to get the nitrogen from the leaves they
will suck it
because sometimes when you root it on
rock wool it happens much earlier right
because there is no uh you know there is
a it's neutral medium it has no food
inside you know the speed based stuff
the easy plugs they have a little bit of
nitrogen inside and so but this stuff
doesn't so if you don't use the hydro
super mix stuff you know some some kind
of mpk uh you get faster yellowing but
the root is still there so as as as soon
as you put it into a medium which has
some nutrients it will work right yeah
but the thing with the mom that you
asked me before where do I go with the
EC it's very interesting for years I
have in a
regimen a regime that would be between
1.0 to 1.3 EC for the vegetative moms
you know sometimes now where I go until
2.2 or
2.5 but I do it once uh every 14 days
only fascinating yeah but you have to
know what I put inside to get this
2.5 not Nitro not nitrogen and not
phosphorus it is
all uh iron calcium
magnesium uh uh and all the trace
Elements which is zinc Boron mongan mden
uh uh it is you know it all the trace
elements with the microe elements yeah
mcro elements is NPK this is the macro
elements the micro elements is calcium
magnesium iron uh yeah and then you have
this zinc and Al all the trays but the
trays is so important for the mom heal
that normally you have to give her a
decent amount of those stuff every 14
days when she's getting older because if
you don't do that she cannot eat
anything else she cannot if she doesn't
have this she cannot eat the phosphorus
and nitrogen and [__] and nothing she she
will lock you will lock it down you will
add the the nitrogen but she will not
eat it so you found that with your mom's
the the limiting factors are usually the
micro elements rather than the macro
elements you feel as though you can you
can provide a steady amount of macro
elements to them but by increasing the
micro elements you sustain Healthy
Growth over a longer period of time yeah
cuz you keep keep up the you keep uh you
unlock uh because if you don't have the
micro elements the mcro elements are not
available to the plant sure yeah it's
just limiting the whole like rabisco
cycle and absolutely a chain yeah
absolutely well you know that's that's
super fascinating cuz I um we we've just
kind of slowly increased the EC of our
mother feed over time because we've just
found that in because we we're under
LEDs for all of our plants indoors and
once we reached the certain level the
limiting factor seemed to always be the
nutrient load because we had like high
ppfd really nice uh vapor pressure
deficit um air flow was great high CO2
levels when needed um and so we just we
like well they just need more food and
we've now gone all the way up to I think
it's like 3.8 to 4.0 EC on our on our
mother feed and they're just healthi as
can be flowering right yeah no no no
just on the mothers for ineng w very
because they we just get these super
thick piy stems now where there's you
know there's no Hollow stems and I know
that's a whole debate Within the the
Cannabis scene as well as Hollow stems
versus non Hollow problem to to root
definitely Hollow stems are are a
problem in general because it just means
that you're missing something in the
overall plant food there's there's no
benefit to the plant to having a hollow
stem people will be like oh it's a it's
a nutrient straw they're they're just
stucking water up that's not where the
water goes no uh Nick we call also it's
like a hemp tra we call it the hemp tra
hemp plants make that right because
that's which which is cannabis but
but hemp we don't like to have it hemp
way you know no well cuz like the Flo
and xylm right those are going to be
contained within the outer part of the
stock of the plant whereas the inner
pith is just kind of like the bones if
you think about it right it's just
building structure so that the plant can
hold itself up so if you want healthy
plants in flower or in veg you want a
lot of of pith in it but if you're you
know growing for fiber alone then yeah
you don't want pith you want it to put
all that energy into fast vertical
upward growth all in the syum and flum
um so yeah I've heard that before that
it is a hemp trait and that it you know
if we're looking for drug cannabis then
hemp traits aren't necessarily what you
want to be promoting and one secret uh
wolf one secret is if you pick males and
Gabby would disagree now but I it's my
version if you pick males never pick the
first flowering ones because they carry
a hemp trade interesting yes don't it it
will not people say like yeah the the
faster flowering males will be the
faster flowering females it's not right
it's not it has nothing to do with that
that's so funny it will not it will not
relate you can have a late flowering
mail which will be much more drug tra
but that's fascinating I've never heard
that as a drug versus hemp trait I've
heard it as a uh potential for interex
trait where if you choose males that
flower too early it means that they
really want to show that as well yeah
yeah but but Nick interex trades are
actually hemp trades also because sure
interex trades are wanted in the hemp
industry right you just need to produce
uh homogeneous crop so if there's
intersex traits that means that it's no
longer what dious right it's it's almost
more manous at that point so it's going
to be very
production you know you have it all in
one plant you have the male and female
parts on one plant you have it seeded
already you can drive through the
machine through it and you harvest it
and you have seeds that's it that's
industry yeah y so but we don't we are
not industry we are craft so so this
craf thing is let's let's uh I I can
just tell people that if they looking
for males from one line uh try to find
the middle to late ones those are the
ones those are for sure yeah it's very
fascinating cuz I whenever I've looked
for males I've always uh looked for the
first flowers because I like to have the
flower initiation happen early
especially if I'm going to grow outdoors
in uh Northern latitude I want to make
sure that I have a fast initiation of
flower so that I have a faster finish
potentially as long as I'm still
shooting for those um those traditional
indica or like Himalayan Afghanistan VAR
Idols that are going to have a shorter
flowering time um so that's really
fascinating I think it's really
interesting how everyone has their
unique approach to what males they look
for I I will not tell that I'm right you
know this is not this is but this is my
theory only I I'm in love with cannabis
like you are also and so sometimes it's
like people have too much of uh you know
seriousness in Insight of like no you're
not right and you know he hates you now
and
man I don't hate nobody it's like it's
it's up to the person how you approach a
thing and what is your own experience
with it you know why I would lie now
here to you you know it's like
absolutely I don't care about you know
how much anybody hates me now because I
said something that he's not uh agreeing
with but I like to have kind of people
also to be invited into the show to have
a different opinion than me that would
be great you know I
like if we all had the same opinion it
would be an echo chamber we don't need
that we don't need the Yes man you know
always say you say something and I say
yes
yes there would be no conversation you
know and honestly like I don't even look
at flowering times as my first indicator
of a male when I'm looking for it I'm
looking at structure you know I want I
want healthy side branches big vigorous
you know giant leaves healthy green
growth all on my uniform uh feeding
schedule you know I'm not going to
change something for one male or another
I'm going to be like which one does the
best at this standard um it's is UN
sometimes it's this theme R you know I
choose between I had to choose sometimes
between two you know I I Pinn it down
already to two males and then I had to
choose one of those males you know how
how the the last thing that I did
because sniff it or everything what you
said now is was there with those two
Mals but then how how it's like rob it
Rob it Rob it smell it smell smell it
it's like this one or this one this one
or this one yeah it's going to be this
one and that's it you know and then it's
funny because the next year you might
have had a different a different choice
because your pallets going to change
maybe next day would have a different
choice you know cuz maybe you were not
smelling that right that day you know
that's like but some do you think that
people that are uh high class breeders
today that all of these people are able
to just find males like that you know no
it's like I don't think so no it's like
it it is like you know nobody can really
tell I would just say like that nobody
can really tell and uh people should try
try it out why not you
know even now that I said the early had
warn that they don't should be used use
it now so you will see and you can go
and [__] me up you know like say Sasha
you were so wrong when you told this
look I got this Elite clone now from
that male that was too early you know
look how nice this plant is yeah that's
funny I mean it it is something where
people have to have their own experience
to make their opinion on something like
that and you know you have your
experience that's why you have your
opinion I have my experience that's why
I have my opinion but it's not like
either one of them is correct or wrong
or you know it's it's just our own
opinions right yes yes definitely so you
know since you you know you've grown for
I don't know more than 20 years right
you've uh done outdoor crops indoor
crops pivoted into a um a clone company
from where you were making you know your
own flour for your own consumption so
you've seen a lot of the different
aspects of the industry especially
working with these European European
Standard committees that require you to
have uh you know one set of standards
for one country that shipping to another
set of standards for another country
that you're shipping to so you have to
tie all those together and make your own
set of Standards to make sure that
you're compliant you know you you have a
lot of experience witnessing these
different sides of the industry and we
didn't even get into it on this podcast
but from previous episodes that we've
had you on you know we know that you
travel to events like spannabis or the
um the German uh cannabis Exposition all
these
different uh all these different things
that you've seen that you've had
experience with makes you I feel like I
I always say this but it makes you a
great person to ask this question where
do you want to see the Cannabis industry
go over the next 5 to 10 years and let's
make it more specific about your area
not necessarily on a global uh stage but
like within your Market what would you
like to see change or where would you
like to see it go I would definitely
like to see it being decriminalized you
know
uh I you know in Austria where I have
this business is still illegal uh in my
country where I live it's absolutely
illegal everything even clones are not
allowed to do you can only grow hemp
yeah but the thing is uh the industry as
itself you
know my problem with it is that
um the big players will take over you
know like there will be no this kind of
I My Wish would be to have a craft uh
flower dispensary you know one day you
know behind what I do as a business of
my library that all of this Library
would be available to people that come
to my place like all of these clones are
also in flower form here and with good
wine and good beer and something to eat
you know right and like a touristic
stuff you know like Spa think you know
like enjoy your life think yeah uh but
industry as itself I would like to see
it to be decriminalized in the sense so
to be to be able to grow your own wheat
at home for your personal use and then
the industry that uh would allow people
from all kind of you know areas to join
it which will not be possible actually I
know this is all like this is all like
fairy tals what I tell now what the
corporations are taking over it's like
here like even more than us Market it
here is even more specific they don't
even want the people to to to to get
access you know like they they want
straight to the
hardcore pharmaceutical wheat and it's
there is no social clubs there is no uh
coffee shops there is no uh hom growing
there is no you can just buy it you know
for big money you know y but actually
it's so problem that uh people grow it
already so much and it's so embedded
into the culture already that is
actually then it's even more uh you know
the citizen will even more protest and
even more he will be self sufficient you
know he will even more try to get his
own good stuff so because hom Growers
will always produce better weed than the
industry remember that that is with
tomatoes the same thing sure yeah
tomatoes from your own garden will
always taste better than the one from
from Supermarket absolutely it is the
same analogy actually it is very simple
yeah the industry will the industry
beside us you know it will if it start
to legalize here then after few years
like Kevin JRE already told and I agree
with him that you US market will come
here absolutely it we we we stand no
chance here against your Market we have
we have no chance but we can have little
islands of
craft Productions that will be
maintained I can tell you this until I
leave I I will maintain this but uh this
will be something interesting yeah but
it's not for the masses like good news
music was not for the masses in the
beginning right you know but then the
people realize the truth and then again
we come back to you know it's history
repeats itself again yeah right I
couldn't agree more I feel like there's
just too much stigma still and we need
to be able to break that down a little
bit podcasts like this help because we
provide a more uh more insight to just
each of Our Lives how we go about
you know promoting this plant caring for
this plant uh producing this plant and
you know I feel every day brother and
there is so many people that still look
at it as this criminal activity but
normalizing the conversation like this
is very important because we allow for
people to see that these are just two
people out there growing you know clones
for you flower for me all the like we're
just doing it right that's it's nothing
it's not that big of a deal it's just
like any other any other crop and we're
trying to make sure that our what we're
making is not I don't know if we want to
say it's the best but it's the best
version that we want to put out there
right and uh so I I do feel as though
you know a little bit more uh or a
little yeah more decriminalization not
necessarily legalization with standards
and rules and laws let's be realistic
you know because
you know it's like legalize it yeah I I
I always lived like this you know but
now man after so many years of listening
to legalize it it's like hey first of
all let's decriminalize it let's put a
foot in the door first right you know
what I mean it shouldn't be a question
of legality and illegality it's a plant
we should just be able to grow it you
know absolutely if if that's if if the
need is to make some sort of dichotomous
key of legality versus illegality then
we're already kind of fighting a losing
battle um at least that's how I I feel
about it me too man it's like I I've
been born into illegal Market already
and it was always illegal right so for
my grandfathers maybe it was not but uh
that was in the beginning of the century
you know before it was illegal you know
Ed you know you know that uh that
footage of Henry Fort banging a hammer
on a on a Ford car have you saw that see
made of hemp yeah and that was before it
was illegal right because right after
that because he wanted to make cars bu
built from hemp material uh fueled by
hemp fuel you know he was crazy guy and
uh actually the whole system you know
Dupont came you know which made nylon
right nylon pent and Dupont sent Henry J
anslinger to be the head of the daa
right what we know today is the the drug
drug enforcement agency right and Henry
J hensinger is the guy and his people
that actually turned cannabis into this
kind of stuff that we know today right y
absolutely very and but behind him is
Dupont and Dupont is the corporation
that owns the pent on nylon which is
plastic right and they didn't want to
have uh hemp Plastics no at at that
moment we lost the war we lost the war
because nylon was created and destroyed
our planet our o oceans are are polluted
with it instead of hemp Plastics which
would be the second option and we [__]
we [__] up it is interesting to look
back at history and see these inflection
points where something changed and
you're like it could have been different
You Know Jack herrer was the guy that
came up with the video you saw that H
for victory it is a video that he
actually get from some some archives and
he released it as you know that can see
that in 199
1943 uh the government of USA legalized
hemp again like they really legalized
wheat just to make uh materials for for
the Army you know again for the wars you
know I didn't know that yeah hemp for
victory that is Jack I have look I have
to look back into that yeah man hemp for
victory you will see it's a they it was
illegal wheat was illegal for 1925 or
something like that right
1926 and then it was legal between
1943 and
1945 yeah for production of of uh fiber
for the Navy and for you know and it was
that and and Jack found that video first
they don't want to give him you know
that would be a story man maybe somebody
in the community knows about this story
but I know as a Slovenian guy that I
know that this video this footage was
found by Jack and he released it and
first they didn't want to give it to him
and then he released it that that he
actually showed how corrupt the
government actually how hypocritic it is
to actually allow something in a certain
time and then forbid it again you know
like they they did they make it illegal
then make it legal again then make it
illegal again and now make it legal
again that's how it is
absolutely it's it's a giant hypocrisy
it's it's very frustrating at times you
know when you smoke your first joint you
know that y exactly I've seen those
experiences happen real time um well
with again with all of your experience
uh one of the questions I do like to ask
is what would be some advice that you
would give to new Growers if there was
something like one little piece of
advice that you think is uh up there
amongst the highest value advice that
could be given to a new grower uh to a
new grower now in this time I would that
my advice would be Google [__] you know
Google Google because at our time we
don't have Google we don't have the
internet we don't have no source of
information we had to make all the
mistakes you don't need to make all the
mistakes right but be be patient and try
to to be focused on information not not
try you know it's not the way that
everything should be thrown at you and
then you have to absorb information like
what you know of course plant seeds yeah
and then of course try it yeah and also
not only cannabis try to grow your own
food that would be my advice also it's
it's all the same thing yeah just get
into the garden start doing it get into
the garden start also if you're living
in big cities no problem have a balcony
if you don't have a balcony you have a
you have a on the south side of the if
you have a southide window you can plant
anything just do it it's so beneficial
for you it's a it's for the mind you
know we are built for that you know I
know that one thing people don't think
about especially when it's just like
those within the Cannabis Community is
you can take your uh extra grow tent set
up and grow some Tomatoes or some
cucumbers or something else in there
it's yeah and you'd be surprised at how
well it's going to grow uh oh yeah you
know it's going to cannabis is such a
heavy feeder that when you do something
you know a little a little easier like a
a cucumber like a lemon cucumber or
something that just grows very
vigorously and prolifically you're going
to not know what to do with all of that
all those cucumbers all those Tomatoes
or Peppers you know definitely and it
can be like a whole another uh outlet
for the hobby if if it is like a a homeg
growing hobby that you're developing and
so yeah just start growing something
it's not that hard and it it's really
rewarding it is for the for the mental
thing we need we need this as people we
it is we are connected to this stuff so
long absolutely yeah I wish everybody
that uh you know you know we don't live
in very easy times you know it's a lot
of things are going on in the world and
we will not get into it now me and Nick
and uh it's like we all should be aware
that your your neighbor is your brother
don't treat him as somebody because
maybe will be a situation that you will
need your neighbor you know don't be
don't be like stop born and look just
like that in your life money is not
everything yeah you should actually uh
human relations are much more wor than
anything yeah y absolutely that's a I
mean that's a great sentiment to sort of
wrap up the podcast on um I do have a
couple of last minute questions that I
like to ask uh and I feel like you might
have heard them before from me so we'll
just get right into them but what is
your favorite strain of all
time well
[__] [__] as a librar and you have too
many options I'm sure it's a pro yeah
that's a big problem uh one of those
would be the headband and one of those
would be the the super silver haze man
that are so very different strains right
that's so funny that you said that cuz
headband uh is my partner's favorite
strain and Super Silver Haze is the
first strain we ever smoked
together so the odds that those are your
two favorite strains is really
funny yeah but they are combining the
the thing about kab is what I really
love the energetic racy sativas and the
head stone couch lock body like like
golf ball
smell you know like I'm not really
really into skunks you know I was and
skunks are okay
but it's not my thing I mean you know I
always like
do you like uh you know how the market
has kind of changed into this whole like
purple candy gas thing where that's all
the people want I am one of I feel like
I'm one of the few people that has no
problem with that because you know if
it's sweet and gassy all at the same
time that sounds delicious and oh yeah
the fact that we're going for all this
photogenic quality to the the buds that
we're growing just makes it that much
more enjoyable cuz there's always a
visual aspect of picking up up the
flower breaking it apart grinding it up
rolling a joint looking at it you know
that's it's a whole part of the The
Experience one of my favorite smokes in
the last uh time now is American cut
that I got from finest it is called
cross and it's uh Sunset sheret sherbet
biscotti sunde cross sounds good and
it's like it's it's candy gassy which is
normally it's gassy but can it's very
fru sure very very like fruit it's un
unbelievable smoke yeah I I I do find it
really funny when people are like I
don't want that I want something you
know I want some old good green wheat
I'm like feel free you know I don't I
don't mind that at all
but the stuff is really tasty it is it
is but sometimes when you then get this
super silver haze again which is really
light like green you know like light
green
and then you smoke that like it's like
the instant somebody comes into the room
it will he will be like instantly you
were smoking the
Amnesia everybody here in this area they
will tell you it's
Amnesia uh Amnesia is super silver ha
that don't not many people know that but
Amnesia is just a coffee shop name for
the wheat for sure there was there was
no Amnesia I mean s will be angry now if
if I tell it like this s released
Amnesia Haze but Amnesia ha is just a
super silver haze version I mean it's
super silver haze cross to some hazes
but it's the the super silver was always
shorter on the flowering time for hazes
because hazes go more than 13 weeks and
the super silver hazes that we grew here
are like 10 weers
10 11 weeks maybe maybe
nobody goes to 12 weeks yeah yeah here
some some some people do but in general
people who grow for a market they they
use to if if they grow H they go for the
for the amnesia for the super silver
because it has this some even uh get it
in nine weeks you can put it on the
market in N weeks you can actually some
people will think that it's right cuz it
has that effect it has the quality but
if you go over 10 or 11 week you have
top shelf you know you have the that's
it and that is you know still long you
know 10 or 11 weeks for uh for
commercial production is a problem yeah
yeah absolutely and you can't cuz it
like for the most part you can if you
produce really really nice sativa versus
really really nice indicia and just
using those terms terms as a
representation of the flowering time um
so like an 8 we versus a 12 week right
you can't then charge one and a half
times for the 12 week right if you're
getting $1,000 per kilo let's say right
mhm uh you can't then of of you know a
runs or a candy or something like that
right you then can't say well I have
this super silver haze that I grew for
12 weeks I want $1,500 per kilo no you
can do can't do that no no one's going
to say oh it's worth that much more
because you grew it that much longer
they'll say this is still a pound of
weed I can only sell it for so much per
gram right there is only you know in
this area here where we live in the
Balkans and Austria and here this areas
uh the Amnesia cut uh of they call it
the core cut core cut because a guy from
England named
core his his synonym on the Forum is
core mhm and he put out some
Cuts that's why it's the core cut
because one guy named core put out the
cut so it's the Amnesia core cut which
is high pro seeds it's a Holland based
company but actually the genetics as
itself as a parental genome is the super
silver H yeah yeah and basically just
super silver but they they they popped a
lot of seeds to get this 9 to 10 weaker
right phenotype which is so popular
since 15 20 years it's around here wow
and yeah it's still it's still people
still grow that and uh it's still around
it's still sold in many shops uh but you
have to understand that this is a very
rare pheno type of super silver haze
it's very rare because normally it's
it's very productive and very fast
finishing for us for a super silver sure
I mean normally the super silver ha will
give you in 12 or 13 weeks a product
like this one wow you know yeah it's
yeah I mean that's also why you can't
change your your price per pound on
those things because no one's going to
say oh like how prove it that you grew
it for 12 weeks you know like I found
someone that grew this for nine weeks
it's the same thing so why why
shoulds you know the col trains came and
they actually they dropped the the
production of Amnesia here this the
Shiva cut the the the the super silver
haze cut the super it's very it's grown
very very much less than it was before
just because of col Trends sure because
they took over the market here in the
last three
years it is the last two years it's
crazy 3 years ago it started the first
col STS came yeah and now it's like it's
going everywh yeah it's everywhere and
it's going to go back also
which is which is okay it's okay yeah
the market fluctuates it's you know the
the demand for what people want is all
based on what I feel like is
commercialized you know like what is
popularized through Instagram or Reddit
or all these other different forums uh
or even you know in pop culture right
you can have a a uh an artist of some
band uh or or you know rap group or even
rock and roll just all these different
um music genres where well they'll
mention some sort of cannabis strain in
their music because it's just what's
popular to them at the time and all of a
sudden the demand for it goes up and
everyone's got to start producing that
because there's just you know increased
demand within the market so it's it is a
Fickle market and it just it is going to
continue to fluctuate um and I think
that headband and Super Silver Haze are
also some of those uh you know they they
have a good foundation where I don't
think they're going to go anywhere
people are always going to want them
because they have good experiences with
them um
and so with those being your favorite
strains who would you say is your
favorite
breeder Shanti
Bobo right off the bat what uh what
makes him your favorite
breeder he's he's uh down to earth
mentality he's uh when you meet him you
look him in the eye you ask a question
he will tell you straight away cool with
no with no
uh I mean I love this kind kind of
persons you know down to earth so much
and the accomplishment I mean there will
always be beefs again you know people
will some people will don't like him or
something I don't care I met that guy
and I talked to him and uh I really
loved the conversation really Co I mean
there is other there is others yeah but
straight away to say how much uh he is
influential to me and how much he has
done for the community and that he still
is producing keeping a low
profile uh and having uh much more love
for his family than his business yeah
that is very impressive for sure I mean
sometimes you know breeding cannabis
isn't it isn't rocket science right you
know no you can just have a little
pollen chucking event and create some
seeds find something great and all of a
sudden you call yourself a breeder right
so so and you know they they they asked
this Shanti you know they asked him few
years 10 years ago they asked him so
what are you doing because this time it
was already you know Autoflower
feminized was taking over the market
everywhere and what are you doing what
are your new strains you know and he was
looking like that new trains you know
like I'm he did the CBD crew at that
time right he had some new trains but it
was really scientific based uh company
which produced CBD based trains one:1
ratios like 3 to1 ratio like really CBD
strains they produced it so he knows
about breeding right so when this guy
was asking about new strains he was like
same old story you know same old we we
do uh uh no feminize still and we we use
males and females you know so the old
breathing techniques what we use you
know and that's that the base why why
you know you know you have so much tools
now today Labs that can preest if it's
male if it's female sex testing you have
carabin you have everything more
accessible today so why not stay on the
stable uh systems that provide good
stable genetics sure you know and
thentics to it just apply to analytics
for breeding purposes then to have like
for feminized production okay it's okay
but don't you know for for breeding for
purposes of collection and
preservation ization is not the point
you know you you you pin it down to one
phenotype self thing you know that's
that's not preservation you know
preservation would mean open pollination
and a lot of genome hidden in a group of
family right I mean that is Preservation
and I think real breeding has to do with
preservation more than it has to do with
uh pinning down to specific phenotype
right I mean they are two different
goals right
one if you're trying to preserve
genetics then open pollinating using
large ver large uh populations of plants
to provide uh
large uh phenotypic variants uh so that
you're not bottlenecking your breeding
projects um that's one style and then if
you're you know inline breeding reverse
back Crossing back Crossing trying to
lock down certain traits for production
qualities or for desirable qualities for
an end product that's a totally
different thing and both they're valid
right you know because we like our drug
cannabis so it's going to require some
very intensive breeding practices to get
to something that people are really
excited about versus you know if it's
just something where we're trying to
make sure that we don't lose the access
to a genetic pool for maybe future
breeding practices or just for
preservation sake just for the sake of
preserving uh what what's in that
genetic pool then yeah goals one other
it's it's it it really depends on what
you're trying to do and I I agree so I
agree with what you're saying it's when
you have somebody like Shanti Baba who
is um he's kind of sticking to what he
knows doing it as best as he can and
trying to perfect those practices
versus creating or chasing some hype
right yes yes yes yes yes again those
are just two different mentalities and
two different mindsets so I that's
really I see why you have a lot of
respect for him in terms of trying to
maintain stuff especially as yourself as
a librarian of cannabis maintaining
things that are 20 years old it's hard
work and lot people that want to do it
yeah and also not a lot of people want
it right now no I still keep yeah they
will and always it's the same thing
people come back and they ask you then
you know why you kept it for so long
again because from time to time you have
these deals for these cuts and then
still you are like yes you know and
these people come and then yeah and also
they they give you a feedback hey thanks
man it's the real thing right like for
the plank cut for example I got a few
months ago I got like hey man thank you
so much we got a plank cut back again
from you it is the same thing that we
used to smoke 20 years ago yeah it is
like that's it that's it this the cut
you know that's it and that was for me
was like yes if I have one of that kind
of customers I'm sa you it's worth it
yeah absolutely well I just have one
more question for you then um what is
the most memorable cannabis related
experience that you have whether it be
smoking or growing or just anything
cannabis
related wow for example definitely will
be more than smoking
growing it is even more a virus to me
than using it as a drug recreational
drug it is actually
more the growing part was always more uh
infectious for me than than anything
else it's like and a specific memory of
conies would be for example you know
smoking it in Spain like you know the
best sativas in Spain the bubble H the
Moroccan har that that was imported the
the the you know the the Mongolian ditch
weat the all these kind of memories that
you you you were smoking economies all
around the world but then the best
homegrown wheat it was always here for
me uh I I never met I never saw better
wheat that I could produce it myself for
sure so it sounds just like you know the
growing aspect of it like it's just a
large memory all with a bunch of aspects
tied together that you know this just
been something that's been such a part
of your history that maybe there's not
just one that stands out but kind of the
overall aspect of there's been so many
good memories but the ones that always
bring me back are the the
Homegrown one I have you know my late
dad you know he died like 13 years ago
my father and he was really uh one of
the first hippie Generations in
Yugoslavia know they smoked hashish in
the' 70s you know uh imported from from
turkey and um he was like also he told
me about LSD and those stuff you know
like he he he his idols were Jimmy
Hendrick and Janice Joplin and you know
that that stuff you know I grew up with
that kind of music so and actually when
he found the first Riza that I was like
12 years old 13 years old and he found a
Rea in my room what's a rea ARA is the
paper the smoking paper the big one the
big one you know not the small one for
tobacco he found the big one and he said
he asked me what are you using them for
and and I I said for tobacco and he said
are you smoking big cigarettes right now
huh so next day man he waited with a
rolled joint and he smoked with me the
old joint I was 13 years old my father
you know it's like you will first smoke
with me and then you can smoke with
other people that's cool and if you need
wheat you come to me first and that
that's what I did after that you know
it's like cuz he knew what was good not
yeah yeah that's awesome I I had a
similar experience and I'll I'll get
into that in a in a future episode but I
think you know when you have your first
experience or uh one of the really
memorable experiences if it's with like
a a parent or something that's pretty
cool I think that's awesome because he
had you know that is not bad parenting
actually he was he was he cared so much
right he cared as a parent that I would
not get into bad circles right cuz there
was there was a lot of heroin there was
a lot of cocain was not at that time but
there's a lot of drugs man it was really
hardcore you know so better was that he
you know to know what your kids are up
to is better than not knowing right
absolutely when there's a lot of um you
know set and setting in terms of how you
experience almost everything right you
know whether it be a drug or food or uh
alcoholic beverage or even just you know
uh a concert right something just like
an experience if you're in the right
mindset and the setting around you has
maybe an energy that you're looking for
or you know if if it's like an upbeat
positive thing then you're going to
experience it one way if it's you know
negative angry you're going to
experience it another way and so to have
someone who has as much care for you as
you know a a parent potentially could
then you you might just the maybe the
idea behind it is to provide that set in
setting where it's not going to be
a a a problem and not an unenjoyable
experience you know the sentence would
be do not deny your kids the education
ever fair enough ever you know what I
mean if if it's like rolling a joint you
know like don't deny your kids the
education you
know look at teach
them I love that you know a little bit
of joke aside but it's a lot of Truth in
that no absolutely be be honest to your
kids be honest you oh I mean if you li
to them they're going to yeah if telling
them not to do something is the easiest
way to get them to do something right
absolutely yeah so I mean by by showing
them that it's safe that there is or
that there is safe ways to conse assume
cannabis that there is um you know
different products on the market some
that are benef you know that are good
some that are potentially bad harmful
you know these are things that yeah I I
don't think that it necessarily needs to
come from a parent but someone who's
experienced older uh with care you know
and they're and they're doing it from a
a place of care and concern versus
punishment and Authority right yes I
think that that's a really important
thing um well Sasha this has been a
wonderful conversation and I really
appreciate you um for the listeners that
don't know he just kind of hopped on to
this podcast today because we had to
Pivot a little bit from another uh
person that was going to be joining us
but um we have been waiting to get
Sasha's story about growing and a little
bit more of his gardening techniques and
thoughts behind that on here so this was
great thank you so much I really appre
appreciate you coming on today and doing
this with me thanks man yeah was nice to
talk to you absolutely it is you know
getting this information out there like
I always like to say it helps grow the
community and that's the way we grow
that's the way you grow all right well
we'll talk
soon bye byebye
[Music]