hello and welcome to the way we grow
podcast a place where we're going to
have interviews with people about their
cannabis story their Journey with
cannabis and kind of what led them to
the Cannabis Community the cultivation
community in specific and today we have
Chad Westport or at chad. Westport on
Instagram he is a cannabis educator a
content creator a breeder and of course
a cultivator and he is also a sustain
Agriculture and small farm system
graduate hey Chad how are you doing
today doing awesome Nick thank you for
having me and Gabby uh it's a pleasure
to be here I'm looking forward to the
conversation I am as well too and uh of
course we do have our co-host today
Gabby bronstein Gabby how are you doing
today I'm doing great unfortunately I
got to be in the car but since you're
running the show today I figured we
could do that yeah no I think it's going
to work out fine just to have you have
you here with us um you can also find
Gabby on Instagram @ SII Gabby Kem dog
and I am Nick wolf also Mr Wolf grows on
Instagram and uh yeah so um Chad uh I
kind of want to leave the first part of
the show open to just kind of ask if
there was anything that's on your mind
cannabis growing related today that is
something that's kind of like eating at
you or occupying your brain space and I
just wanted to see what you were
thinking
about always man 365 days a year year
24/7 my brain is typically on this plant
or something related to it there there's
a lot of thing a lot of directions that
could go there whether it be like grow
technology whether it be like the
direction of the industry but one thing
that I always like to really highlight
and you know I think this is probably a
theme that you touch on with a lot of
your guests and throughout the show I
personally feel that the people who are
doing it at home the people in the grow
tents people kind of on the smaller
scale are always going to be the soul of
this industry the soul of cannabis the
people will like move the plant forward
we're facing an interesting time where
there's going to be you know a lot more
exposure and a lot more availability
which is great but it's also going to
come with a cost however the people who
are doing it you know for finding that
next unicorn or you know helping their
sick neighbor those are going to be the
people that carry it forward so that's
what's always on my mind is you know the
homeg grower is always going to be the
soul of this plan I fully agree with
that um so like with with what you're
think you kind of brought up like
unicorns or like the um you know cuz
people are just always super excited
about the the really really nice looking
flowers so like what what is your
opinion cuz we we did have a talk
earlier in one of our episodes about um
between Gabby myself and Cosmic about
where the next sort of unicorns or like
the elite Cult of ours are going to come
from like do you have an opinion on that
yeah I mean it's it's it's probably
going to come from your your taste
makers your hit makers that's how a lot
of the things have just over time blown
up once we've gotten you know past 2012
once we've gotten into you know
Washington Colorado has like pretty
proper Med systems and they've gone
recreational we've seen H this word kind
of drives me nuts but the the Cannabis
influencer we we've seen the rise of
that and we all know like I was
listening to Cypress Hill Hits in the
bong you know got a in chronic the AK-47
the Alaskan Thunder those were like the
first strame names I ever heard back in
the s so it's been going longer since
2012 but I think the next you know the
next hotness is going to come from a
taste maker whether that has longevity
or not that's to be seen so something
with like longevity and legs I still
think that's probably going to come from
a hom grower or you know a small craft
grower when I say a small craft grower
I'm really thinking you know 100 or 50
or less plants for
sure there they're going to kind of have
that longevity to keep it going if
something has good medicinal effects if
something has the qualities that we're
after that's going to stand the test of
time and so when you say taste makers do
you think that like the people that have
this branding or recognition behind them
are the ones that are finding the
strains or just bringing them to the
attention of the public cuz one thing
that I like to think about is like
almost all the different strains that we
have that would be considered these
either hot flashes in the pans or even
if they did have those legs that you're
talking about and kept on going and were
very popular they don't seem to ever
come from the people who made them
popular yeah I mean I agree with that
you see you know a lot of people have
sourced to different companies or
different people within this industry
that we all know and they kind of you
know once they check mark give their
kind of seal of approval that's when it
takes off but that's just kind of basic
business in a sense like you have to
have distribution you can have the
greatest product in the world but you
have to have a way to expose people to
it you have to have a way to just get it
distributed and that's where those kind
of The Taste makers come in yeah I I I'm
convinced that not many of them are the
ones who actually find these things but
they have enough feelers out there
absolutely they're the ones we made a I
don't know if it was a short or
something like that where we asked the
question and I mean I I feel exactly the
same way as you do that you know
hopefully it's going to be a homeg
grower that finds the next Elite but
he's going to need some help marketing
it bringing it to the product uh to the
to the masses or else you know it'll
never be considered Elite if people
don't know about it right yeah it
doesn't matter if you grow the best weed
ever but if people don't hear about it
or know about it if you know it'll never
have that lasting time where people
recognize that as as such an important
strain something else I want to touch on
real fast is you mentioned cannabis
influencers and I want to be very clear
that that's not what wolf and I are
trying to be we want to tell stories and
we want to be cannabis
inspirers we want to inspire people to
grow about grow cannabis and think about
cannabis but you know we're not trying
to be the next influencers they're not
too far off but I see what you're trying
to say
Gabby
there's influencing
inspiring yeah there's a difference in
motives there you know one is kind of
more self-serving whereas the other is
really about you know propagating the
good for everybody the education that
that's so important it's been such an
underground industry for such a long
time now all of a sudden it's above
ground and we have you know corporate
and I hate to say the term Chads because
I'm a Chad but I'm not that kind of Chad
but there's a bunch of Chads out there
that have no freaking clue about the
plant but they're very good at marketing
and those people don't know the story
they don't necessarily know the roots so
important to know so that's why you know
the inspiration and like the shows I've
been watching your channel it's good to
get these stories out there before
they're just kind of like paved over and
it all started with cook you know yeah
we have any sort of cancel culture
within the culture we want to make sure
that all the stories are told and
remembered so something else that I want
to make sure we do excuse excuse me I
want to make sure that we early on in
the podcast have you tell about your
podcast because you know sometimes
people don't listen all the way to the
end and so I want to make sure that
people know like what you're doing today
and how to find
you yeah well thank you yeah I you know
like you I'm just kind of out there
trying to share the story and education
is really the Hallmark of what I'm doing
I want to get people growing this plant
has been in my life for a really long
time I realized after a while it's
medicinal benefits to me knowing that
and knowing that there's a lot of other
people out there that could benefit from
it I just want to get people growing and
so that's a lot of what I focus on on my
channel is just different ways you know
introduce you to different breeders I
grow a particular style but I'm open to
anything as long as it gets a person
growing so that's a lot of what I do on
my channel but I also do like to tell
the history I did a series with uh Tad
hassi from Kiss Organics it was called
history we went back we interviewed a
lot of people that I think today's like
if you're just turning 21 which is the
legal age and you're coming to cannabis
you probably don't know these people but
they've had such an impact and I saw you
guys te shorts with wolf the other Dayal
God that guy has an amazing story and
funny enough we ran the same streets
doing the exact same thing 30 years
apart that's really fascinating because
we did just have a a really like a
three-hour long interview with him
yesterday and uh yeah it was really good
um name of your podcast or like or any
of that yeah the yeah sorry I a I am a
horrible self-promoter that is one thing
I just like to have a good time and
enjoy we're here to help you with that a
little bit I appreciate that on YouTube
Chad Westport is the name of the channel
chad. Westport on Instagram as Nick uh
had mentioned earlier but a couple of
the shows I you know there's a seed
collector show which I focus on just
showing off seed collections introducing
people to breeders different strains and
maybe some grow reports and profiles and
maybe they like it but I also do a show
uh it was called the best Grow Show just
because long time ago diesel boy was a
drum and bass DJ and he put America's
number one drum and bass DJ on a CD and
he wasn't but because he put it it stuck
and then all of a sudden now he's
America's number one drum and based DJ
so I put it as the best Grow Show but it
it got a little too egotistical towards
the end there not really but I'm just
like ah I can't say it with a straight
face so I just changed that to real
cannabis real cannabis is where I have
the conversations with those craft
Growers with those home Growers with
again the people that are going to be
keeping this tradition alive cool very
cool definitely sounds like we're doing
similar stuff but I don't see it as
competition I see it more as we we help
each other grow by generating interest
in these topics
collaboration absolutely and it's such a
big world I mean just even like
strainwise regionally you know we were
talking um a second ago about you know
that that hom grower needs that outlet
to kind of get it to people there's a
lot of strains like GMO is one that
always just pops into my head as an easy
example in I'm in Washington state I've
been part of the legal Market here for a
long time I didn't really start seeing
that show up to like 2018 2019 out here
and everybody's like ooh wow this is the
hot new thing and then I talked to some
friends in Michigan they're like yeah
that's so like 2013 bro so we need a lot
of people doing this we need people in
different areas because we're all again
from where or how we had to operate
before we were all just a bunch of
little clicks and that's how a lot of
famous strain started you know and they
kind of mov but now we can expand so I
enjoy you know again not looking at it
as competition we're just making a
thicker book for people to read
absolutely I like that and we learn from
each other you know I you know I'll be
honest with you I haven't gotten a
chance to watch too much of your stuff I
watched a little bit but I'm an advid
cannabis podcast Watcher you know like I
watch a ton of stuff on the future
cannabis project the first smoke of the
day you know I'm I'm trying to soak in
as much of this stuff as I can and you
know to me like it's hard to get
enough it is and here's a perfect
example of of of why like I love
absorbing the content and you guys
probably love absorbing the content for
years with the story of sour I kept
hearing about this guy Staten Island
would we ever know who he is would we
ever hear from him I don't know years
that was the story well guess where we
are today so it's cool how things kind
of connect sometimes it's pretty fun
thing is is I I didn't know anyone
wanted to hear from me people were
talking about and then I was given this
nickname Staten Island I'm like yeah you
could tell I'm a little salty about that
but honestly the way it was told to me
was and I won't mention his name the guy
a guy on another podcast was like yeah I
heard you're really private that you
know and I and I said who told you that
because I've never been accused of being
private before I've been out in the open
you know since
the
latees you know and I've been talking to
people about growing cannabis and so the
idea that Gabby would be private that
was just like what are you talking about
but you know once I found out that
people were interested in hearing from
me and I started telling the stories
well now I can't shut
up no but it's that's why we have a I
feel like we have such a great following
already is because the stories seem to
be authentic with without it
being uh too much of of self-promotion
so I cuz I I do sometimes find that like
some of the other shows that I've
listened to personally when it does come
to like people with the self-promotion
you can really tell the difference and I
I feel like we have this little bit of
an authenticness coming about the way
that we tell our stories because it is
more towards like letting individuals
tell their story how they came to the
plant or how the plant came to them and
um and and kind of just like the organic
nature of that so actually I do want to
ask you a question because this is the
way we grow podcast it's just a segment
of The Craft Growers Network I do want
to know how you grow but firstly I
really want to know what you grew first
and who taught you how to grow plants in
general and it doesn't even necessarily
need to be cannabis like for me for
instance my grandma taught me how to
grow a garden and then my dad also
reinforced that leave this uh but and
that was just more like a small tomato
or
um uh like tomato garden or cucumbers or
just other little produce things my
grandma actually had uh sorl from France
that she brought over and it I still
have the same cutting of it from the
same root stock that I've kept going now
for years and years and years and so
that's like one of the things that I tie
to my growing story but I want to hear
yours as it pertains to you know where
you where you yeah I mean I wish I had a
better story and I wish I had a mentor
but growing up like I was a city kid you
know I grew up in the city I did not
appreciate nature I had no interest in
growing or anything of that in my teen
years again I was in the Pacific
Northwest in the I do not know what
brick weed looks like so being pretty
spoiled
there yeah but you do know what some
shitty beaster look like oh God yeah oh
some some really crappy beaster yes we
were raised on beaster here but
apparently whenever I mention beers
people sometimes especially the East
Coast they're like wow that was the good
stuff that wasn't no Mexican but I I
didn't start my first pot plant I didn't
know anything about photo period I
didn't know anything about nutrients it
was just like a throw it in the dirt it
came up got maybe three sets of lease
and then I was like what do you do with
this and then I killed it between that
and then actually growing again I had a
cactus for two years and then I managed
to kill that as well I'm just like ooh
not a good sign but eventually
eventually when things were a little bit
more LAX in Washington state and I did
actually get my medical card I was able
to go into the medical dispensaries I
could pick up seeds I could pick up
clones and that's how I got started with
cannabis and unfortunately for me I
didn't have a mentor like it was all
kind of self-taught the there were
forums back in the day but that
information was like 5050 on whether it
was good or not so what
was this what's that uh around what year
was this like 2010
okay there were you know there were a
few books uh Danny Dano he had the show
called free weed it was back on the old
High Times podcast Network so that's
where I got a lot of information to
start and some books but I just kind of
progressed from there I started you know
with your basic soil grow your Fox Farm
and your three part as you see other
people do and then just it's it's
progressed through a bunch of different
styles and you know they say cannabis is
a gateway drug it is it's a gateway drug
to gardening because now I have huge
beds outside where I grow vegetables I
grow all kinds of things things that
flower or things that finish faster than
cannabis sometimes which is nice right
but today I I'm I'm doing more of an
organic approach I'm not going you know
full hippie as I like to say with worms
and beneficial insects and adding in my
own poop to it no I like working with a
kind of almost a super soil a soil with
enough nutrients in it already but from
organic sources and then I just do a few
top dressings uh cuz again I wanted to
get people started and I know that if I
can take nutrients and that kind of
aspect out of someone's first grow they
may be able to pay more attention to the
plant and they may have more success
versus someone who's trying to measure
things so that's the road I've been
going down for years is trying to find a
simple soil for people to use what sort
of top dressings do you like to use and
like uh yeah like talk us through like
the the 15minute elevator pitch flower
cycle for a organic Gardener indoors
with top dressings yep okay so top
dressing is just a combination of I
could grab the bag but it's a bunch of
meals oh gosh I do you know the brand of
course I'm yeah it's a kiss Organics um
okay cool yeah do I have it let's see
here oh sorry stand up bone meal Alfalfa
potassium sulfate insect fras gypsum W
lastiny soy protein got my my little
notes there nice and so so for like
flowering what pot size is going to be a
big determining Factor also the length
of your vegetative period is going to be
a big factor when it comes to you know
like water only soils or super soils
bigger the pot means the bigger the
battery the longer it will last before
you have to feed it 5 gallon 7 gallon if
I'm going a 45 day vegge sometimes I'll
check things out which is a real quick
veg and I'll go uh a three
gallon
typically cuz with Organic ingredients
you have to think really two three weeks
ahead because it's not immediately plant
available like a synthetic nutrient
would be so a lot of times what I'll do
is a few weeks before the flip I'll put
on a veg top dressing which doesn't
really start to become effective until
that transition period I've already
switched it to 1212 but the plant
hormones are just starting to change I
find you know a little extra nitrogen
boost through that period feeding it as
if it were a veg plant is still
beneficial it just kind of kick starts
it off into the flowering phase and then
at about two weeks after flip you're
still a little bit in the stretch I'll
come back and I'll do another top
dressing with a with a bloom formula
because there's a veg and a bloom
formula for the dry amendments and then
I'll typically let it ride because what
I'm working with these days is I'm
really focusing on kind of like 60 days
or plants if it were to go 70 days I may
top dress again at week five just again
it takes a few weeks to become available
but that is typically how I approach
flour I do have some organic bottle
nutrients if I need a foler spray or
something that's a little bit more
immediate but yeah it's it's it's really
simple it's really hands off which is
good for a lot of people I think yeah I
totally agree that's kind of like the uh
the way that I've seen a lot of people
growing with uh with Organic amendments
especially with top dressing do do you
happen to like reuse your your substrate
afterwards are you remediating it in any
way and and uh replanting in it after
you let the the root stock Rod out or
anything like
that I'm going to start using reusing my
soil indoors typically what I have done
is I have brought it Outdoors to that
big bed that I have out there now like
nobody should have that much perlite in
their Garden but I do um I've been so
yeah you know actually I think it I
think it was wolf uh that told me if you
use black food coloring and you run it
through the soil it may dye some of that
perlite a different color so it's not as
obvious I haven't put it into practice
yet but logically I'm like all right I
can see it that's funny yeah but yeah I
I am going to start reusing it and and
amending it I'm working again with Tad
husy from Kiss Organics I'm working on
my own custom soil blend something that
works specifically well kind of
universally but specifically with my
genetics again to where somebody could
like pick up the genetics pick up the
soil follow my Sops that I've shown them
on the video and they should be able to
get a similar result but that does
include go ahead sorry when you say
pickup genetics are you talking about
from seed stock or a clone stock
or yeah I right now am just seeds Okay I
haven't done any clones um there there's
some different reasons for that again
you're kind of giving it all away when
you give out your special clone I have
the Westport grape juice is is like my
special thing um I do have that backed
up with one person is growace killer a
John he's out on the East Coast he's
wins Awards and he has won a few Awards
recently with that and his 818 headband
he he Blends the two rosins to make
hachimaki grape juice I took second at
davo in Massachusetts he took third at
the Pelle polar turp Wars recently but
yeah clones I'm kind of keep those close
to the chest right now but the seeds
people can get and that's what I meant
by you know pick up genetics pick up
genetics pick up the soil follow the
procedures and you should get the same
results so we're hoping could you
describe the Westport grape juice the
the breeder cut for people just cuz you
know I've seen it on Instagram a few
times but I've never actually heard the
the
description yeah so so the Westport
grape juice as far as effects people
like to go to effects something that I
typically go for in the evening it's a
little a bit more relaxing and sedative
without knocking your like intelligence
level down a few pigs kind of just lets
the muscles just kind of relaxed I
really you know I enjoy it I'm able to
have like you know how sometimes you get
into those deep conversations and then
it's like 45 minutes later and you're
like wow we went deep on that one but it
feels like two minutes that's kind of
how I get with it yeah um far as like I
you know I personally enjoy it the
profile though like taste and the aroma
so the aroma while it's growing you'll
get almost kind of like a carnival candy
grape to it but as it ripens and as it
dries and cures it matures into more of
a like wine grape almost like kind of
like a red like with body something with
body I can't think of a better word so
like like almost more like a like a
Cabernet grape or something where it's
it's a little more uh acidic almost
citrusy with the grape in it it whereas
like a conquered grape would be like a
pie grape smell okay more towards the
Cabernet but I don't really get Citrus
or acidity from it there is cream to it
so it has kind of a nice on the inhale
on the inhale you get that that mature
wine grape with some creaminess so it's
kind of smooth it it rolls off the back
and then when you exhale there's that
like little patch in the back of your
throat that always gets dry and you're
like that little patch just a hint of
gas touches that patch on the way out
okay so wow that sounds really good you
don't get it from The Upfront profile
you don't get it from the you know
initial hit but yeah when you're
exhaling it just that little bit of gas
tingles you there and that's kind of
made it stick out and was special for me
and then just the way that it grows it's
commercially viable like it stays short
it stays squat which for me is important
and for you know the people that I'm
aiming towards home breeders and Tents
that's very important keep it short keep
it tight keep it squat it doesn't
stretch a whole lot I would say onetime
stretch if that and then just it just
chunks up with like nice thick golf ball
buds so it's from a commercial aspect
commercially viable but from an
enjoyment side yeah the the profile and
the effects are just something unique to
me and other people are enjoying it too
I mean that it sounds really great
personally love purple and grape
cultivars just growing up in the Bay
Area I had access to a lot of that and
so it's nostalgic for me I've I've been
running at the uh commercial facility
that I've been managing what uh it's
called Beach grapes from Oni seeds we
have a number 12 cut that we hunted and
it's uh very much conquered grapes with
that kind of like creamy but also like a
lot of fuel gassiness on both the front
and back end and so things like that
just always kind of they're really good
they they hit the pallette for me really
well yeah so let's see you said you
transitioned from Cannabis to vegetables
not the other way around which I always
find fascinating because it was the
opposite for me um
so when you first started growing
cannabis what was what was your first
successful grow like I had beginner's
luck like my first two or three grows
were were really beginners luck they
they went very well I didn't do much
feeding of them again Fox Farm that that
soil has a little bit of a charge so it
will get you through a little bit a
month or so of nutrients but I started
with the premise of like I just want to
see what the plant does again not having
that Mentor not having that background
of gardening I'm just like okay I need
to see what the plant is going to do
naturally before I start adding all
these other things in so I know when I
start adding these other things in it
did that so that's kind of how I got
started it all started with again bag
seed which most people will start with
and then you know I mentioned the the
Washington Medical system 2010 2011 uh
was when it really kicked off in
Washington and I was able to get access
to you know professional seeds and I
always H my first professional cut was a
Jax cleaner to uh from TGA genetics at
the time subcool still to this day that
is what I judge every lemon strain off
of they hunt the the dispensary I got
the Jax cleaner too from they hunted it
they put out a killer clone like that
it's so good it's it was so and it was
like a lemon cleaner it wasn't like a
lemon candy there there was a lemon head
taste to it but it was so astringent it
ate the rubber ring around the top of my
ball jars like that's how astringent
that Jack's cleaner 2 was so that was my
first Pro Cut as I like to say I you
know I have never had a great lemon
strain like the closest thing that I
could ever think of was like a really
good Jack herrer or something but that
was more on the floral end with the
Citrus to it and so I I've always been
like envious of either like the Jax
cleaner or the lemon tree or the lemon
up even i' I've heard great things about
lemon up I don't know
like cuz I got really tired of orange
flavored stuff it just seemed that it
eventually went from being like this
nice citrusy orange to almost this like
dirty kind of musky orange uh like the
rinds yeah like kind of almost weak old
weak old orange I did follow up that Jax
cleaner too with the agent orange from
TJ at the time and that one reminded me
of almost like the scratch and sniff
sticker type of orange like it was
friendly it was approachable that was a
good one and then you know like K but
then it went to like kind of like you're
saying it morphed a little bit into like
Tangi and mimosa and those two like I
personally enjoy them but they're
they're like black licorice nobody is
like yeah it's cool you either like it
or you don't absolutely that's a really
good comparison people are like yeah I
hate that and I'm like yeah I like it
it's cool so um with your the Westport
grape juice what or or actually any of
your strains cuz I kind of want to know
more about your breeding program what's
uh what's your breeding style like do
you like to do line breeding do you like
to do back crosses or are you making
feminized or regular seeds and sort of
like what generation have you taken
certain things to and and made these cuz
it sounds very stable what you're
dealing with to be able to provide a
soil specific recipe and even an
environment and irrigation strategy and
feeding strategy like I I find that to
be super impressive so I want to know a
little bit more about your your breeding
style yeah it's kind of a little bit all
of the above and things happen slowly
for me I'm just the scale that I'm able
to do it I have a lot of really good
testers so like I can run 500 of
something to get a good idea of what's
in it no problem I just can't do it
personally in house so that's a huge
thing so feminized though a lot of new
Growers like the feminized and with the
Westport grape juice know people have
seen it people heard people talk about
it they wanted it so I'm like all right
I'll do you know I'll do a S1 I'll
feminize it make a first generation of
itself I was hoping to get something
that was going to be like a spitting
image of it I did not get that it was
kind of shocked me there there were
basically five distinct phenos that came
from it whereas I really thought I would
get one maybe like one and a half I got
five distinct fenos from it there's I've
got a video up there which shows the
grow of all of them it shows all of the
fenos start to finish uh there's a lot
of also good feedback out there for
people interesting thing that popped up
with that one and then I'll talk about
back Crossing and lme breeding I
mentioned that gas that little bit of
gas on the exhale a second ago I easily
where that came from after doing the
selfing like three out of 10 are going
to be all gas single note nothing but
and the easy way to spot those very
easily is you know your leaves will
typically grow like this the tuck Leaf
you know it wants to grow like this all
of the leaves on those gas ones will
grow like that so that was kind of an
interesting surprise cuz I hadn't done
any selfing before on anything I've
always gone with like line breeding or
bat crossing right now um I'm I'm doing
a little little bit of probably more
backat Crossing than Li braiding
although I do want to do lion braiding
and and I say that because I'm working
with the Westport grape juice and I've
been working with other plants that I
like and that I'm very familiar with and
then I'll put them together and I'm I'm
going through and seeing what is really
dominant and what is seemingly recessive
about that plant compared to some other
ones and then I do have regular crosses
as well as the feminis with that so I am
at one point going to be bringing back
to the Westport grape juice to see if I
can lock that in more cuz I would love
to get that in like a solid stable seed
form I just don't have it yet so that's
kind of the goal I'm working to and
because it is feminized line breeding
isn't as easy but bat Crossing because I
have outcrossed it to Other M so regular
seeds that makes my life a little bit
easier just takes time though yeah no I
I've done a little bit of breeding
myself and I think the Fest I took
something to was an F2 and I found that
it was like stabilized between like two
different specific uh structural
phenotypes but then the actual chemotype
and that the tarpine profiles were
vastly different and the effects were
also vastly different amongst the
structural similarities so I was and
then I had to move and I lost a lot of
the space that I had for breeding so I
was like oh well this is going to go on
the back burner for a little bit but I
do like the idea of back Crossing just
because locking in those those traits
and and it does create some bottleneck
events in certain cases but it does also
kind of remove a lot of the recessive
traits or bring the recessive traits
forward that you're looking for so I I
can definitely appreciate that and it I
just want to know like so where where
did you get the idea of creating this
recipe specific soil for for your
specific strains and is it something
that you're working on for just one
strain or are you trying to create it
for multiple strains yep um for multiple
strains it's you know it it should be
more of just like a general feed even
though it's specifically gonna work with
what I have nothing as far as my
genetics right now are outliers as far
as like oh it it you know it needs extra
phosphorus or like oh you have to like
cut this at a certain page they're all
basically General feeders so there's
nothing outside of the norm which is
good because that's going to catch the
majority of other strains out there
there will always be the outliers and if
I come across that we'll be able to you
know easily tweak the recipe to do
something like that but yeah I I want to
kind of set people up for success and
and real quick back to the breeding
thing one one way that I kind of try to
make my life easier or set myself up for
success is I I cross it with a lot of
older stuff a lot of amster dam genetics
um I travel there every year those
things over there are not exactly sexy
but they're very stable in and that's
not sexual expression that just means as
like you plant 10 you're going to get
like 9.5 looking the same out of 10 for
sure so if I grow that and I'm familiar
with that and I've grown what it gets
crossed to and I'm very familiar with
that it makes my job a lot easier
looking at The Offspring versus if I Hot
Hot and Hot Hot where I'm just like oo
sweet 20 Expressions what do I do now
well and and working with a stock of
plants that are from hopefully a far
enough removed genetic population will
also help create some stabilities in the
Offspring too so that yeah that's a
wonderful idea I really like that and
vigor absolutely absolutely that's a
wonderful idea I really like that so in
your growing time one one segment I'd
like to add into this show that I'm
going to try and sneak in here at this
point is what are some issues you've had
with growing that you had like the most
learning curve adaptation from like what
helped you the most in your growing
Journey as it pertained to an incident
that you faced
you know sounds kind of funny but like
watering properly makes a big difference
there's growing throughout my years i'
I've come to realize like you can grow
and it will turn out good but when you
really nail everything like from your
watering from your lighting to your airf
flow you do see a really big difference
in results so the the watering was one
that I think it was that was my limiting
factor for a while Solutions like Auto
Poots or self-watering stuff or you
could get like a blue m tensometer a
water meter and you you use it as a tool
to train your hands or to train your
eyes I mean we all know when a plant's
thirsty or it's overwatered but there's
still that like fine line where it still
looks good but it's thirsty so that was
one of them but to tie into that as well
probably the biggest thing that I
underestimated was VPD vapor pressure
deficit combination of your temperature
and your humidity the math between those
is what kind of drives you know
transpiration plant sweat uptake from
The Roots that's a way to really drive
and steer your plant again without I
didn't know about VPD for over a decade
and I grew just fine but once I learned
about it once I really started to
control those parameters I started to
see differences and I was like wow I was
missing out all those years you can grow
without knowing it but when you know it
it's it makes a difference I want to
just emphasize that point for all the
listeners about VPD because I've heard
in a lot of other podcasts and other
other spaces that people will say you
know VPD is OV exaggerated and how
important it is and they'll say you
should just focus on making sure your
heat doesn't get out of control or that
your temp um or that your humidity
doesn't get out of control and I feel as
though the funny thing in saying that is
somewhat contradictory because by taking
both of those into account you are
paying attention to VP just without
doing the calculations and I feel as
though another huge aspect to the vapor
pressure deficit is also the interaction
with the radiation in input to the plant
from your lighting Source how so I I do
agree that the vapor pressure deficit is
kind of a determining factor of the
transpiration rate but the driving
factor for the transpiration rate is
going to be the photosynthetic uh
potential within the plant due to the
lighting at that point and so by you
know by increasing the lighting you're
going to in increase the need to
transpire and your limiting factor then
is the VPD within your environment of
how fast the plant can transpire and
have the active transport of nutrients
and so like what led you to um seeing
that as such a important factor like
what did you notice in your plants that
made that uh sort of the discovery that
made such a huge difference for
you um kind of in the morphology and the
color of the plants the way that it was
able to handle nutrients the way that it
accepted the nutrients and utilized them
more effectively you know it almost
seemed like the leaves like the fingers
became wider they were happier to you
know just like stretch out and I'm a
happy leaf and again it's it's it's one
of those things that you can grow
without paying attention to it and so
many of us did for so long and that's
why some people you know poo poo it as
not being Uber important because well
you can grow without paying attention
but when you do pay attention to it you
can notice differences and that's
usually you know cuz I have commercial
experience
as well I've gone to school for some of
these things as well a lot of a lot of
the tips you know as as a hom grower or
someone who coaches hom Growers I always
say Size Matters and CO2 is is kind of
an example I always use for this for a
homeg grower that's like your last 3%
when you're 97% dialed and you have
everything working and it's just rocking
and you're bored with life toss
something new in there but there's so
many things as far as like temperature
intensity of your light that need to be
in place otherwise it's not even going
to work and if you don't have those
basic things down first then it's all
for not so a lot of the things that we
hear you know again Size Matters is for
commercial scale CU if I have four
plants in a 4x4 and I get two extra
grams off of each plant big whoop but if
we go back to my commercial facility
where you have over 60,000 plants and
you're getting two extra grams that's a
big freaking difference yeah so there's
a lot of things out there that are meant
for you know just fine-tuning it or
commercial that it applies to your hom
grow as well but it may not be as
important but VPD is as important so
yeah pay attention to that I agree
wholeheartedly and and within that last
3% or however many percent people are
operating up to like you know what
whatever they have that capacity of
production for I feel as though there's
also even stages in which to implement
those last 3% items because like let's
say you that CO2 is one of those last 3%
items you don't want to implement under
canopy lighting before you implement
CO2 right or you don't want to implement
like a higher uh EC feed if you're using
Hydroponics or a more intensive feeding
schedule for top dressing or like worm
casting teas or sprouted seed teas or
other things like that if you aren't
getting enough lighting to the plan or
giving it enough CO2 for the high
transpiration rate that you're looking
to get all those nutrients transported
and so I I totally agree that's it I
feel like a lot of people do think that
implementing something cuz like you said
bigger is better and it's I feel as
though there's there's a positive way to
spin that in the industry for hom
Growers as well and then in some cases
people overgo on things and and they um
they'll they'll over Implement before
they have the ability to sustain those
implementations um I think that's a
really great
point and and you mentioned bigger is
better too and that's another like
keyword or like red flag that I always
give to like home Growers when because
companies always want to talk about
bigger is better and oh I got you know x
amount more yield I always say what are
you growing for is it biomass or is it
cannaboids because there are different
things you can do some things will get
you more biomass and if you're
commercial or you know whatever cool
biomass is what you're after
cannabinoids though there's certain
things you could do to increase the
canabo I'm a big fan of drought stress
at the end to try to increase cannaboids
absolutely as a personal consumer
medicinal patient homeg grower I'm more
interested in cannabinoids than biomass
I agree wholeheartedly with that I think
you know and then there's also a way to
have a Best of Both Worlds scenario yeah
but U that's also part of the last 3% I
feel like like you want to push for
quality and then you can push for yields
but at one point you are going to see
diminishing return on your quality uh if
your yields are over pushed and uh I
feel like that is an issue a lot in the
commercial space But even for homeg
Growers a lot of people are thinking how
can I get the most out of this and they
should just be thinking how can I get
what I can do the best out of this yes
and that comes from growing a plant
multiple times which I don't necessarily
see a lot of new Growers or home Growers
doing you have to become familiar with
your plant that's what people used to do
back in the day they had whole rooms of
monocrop one thing and they knew how to
grow it well so yeah you have to take
your
failures yeah sorry I interrupted you
but yeah I feel like you got to take
your failures and stride too because uh
o if if you just I've seen too many
people go oh I've killed this plant I'm
never doing this again and uh that's
where I want to say no look look at how
look at what happened and and and say
hey I can not do that next time or I can
figure out what happened and and do
better so I do see that in the community
as well mistakes make us better if we
pay attention absolutely AB absolutely
it's only a failure if you don't learn
from it yes and I'm I'm big fan of that
one cuz again it's not a fast growing
plan which is why shows like this is so
are so valuable you can crowdsource the
knowledge you can squeeze a full year
into you know three months or a few
months of of just learning and paying
attention so sharing the information is
important well so I I kind of want to
take us back to your cannabis Journey so
you were homeg growing for however long
and kind of tell us what transitioned
your hom growing into the commercial
space and what that looked like for you
and whether you're still participating
in it or why you exited that that space
or or what you're you're looking at
there perhaps even for the future y um
well currently I'm looking I'm in
Washington state but I'm looking for a
license in Oregon there there's some on
the secondary Market but nothing that
makes sense to me Washington has pushed
out the medical people it's pushed out
the Mom and Pops the the licenses are
capped they have Haven issued new
licenses in years and they aren't going
to issue them so I can't now that the
medical system is gone in Washington I
can't play which sucks looking at Oregon
to that but my transition kind of
started was I have a a background as an
audio engineer and I worked in that for
many years and in 2016 the company that
I worked for was
sold and it sold to a company uh out of
China uh that basically bought the name
and bought the reputation of the company
and were just going to do things their
own way but the owners were very
freaking cool they were the most amazing
job or time in my life ever long story
short they set it up with the new owners
because the majority of us at that job
were so specialized in what we did
there's no jobs in this country to do
that so they set it up to where anybody
who wanted to you could go back and the
new company pays for two years of
schooling so at that point point I had
already been involved with music I had
been making music but I went to school
to understand why when I turn this it
sounds good because I know when I turn
this it's going to sound good but why
and so in 2016 I had already been
growing cannabis and I was getting
pretty good results but short of having
that Mentor Mentor I didn't really
understand the why behind a lot of these
things and as my audio teacher taught me
that's always stuck with me he's like
you have to know the rules before you
can break the rules because once you
understand how something works you're
able to manipulate it to get the results
you want and so 2016 I went back to
school I went to uh sustainable
agriculture and small farm systems it
was a two-year program up here in
Washington in the scaga valley which is
actually a pretty Powerhouse as far as
nation's um fruits and vegetables we're
we're big on blueberries here and the
cosmic crisp apple with Washington State
University I was part of the field
trials for that during that time so that
was exciting that is really cool yeah
and that's that's how I kind of I kind
of forgot the original uh question but
that's that's how I got into the
commercial aspect or the deeper aspect
of doing what I do is that 2016 career
change and schooling for sure and and so
once you went to school and and you
gained this knowledge of the sustainable
agriculture where did you go and and put
those practices into use for cannabis
yep uh so I don't say the name of the
company just because there are ndas and
things like that okay but I don't say
that because I typically trash their
practices and how they ran their
business so it's like I can talk about
one but not the other well let's talk
about your experience so that people
know kind of how different aspects of
the industry work and uh whatever you're
comfortable with talking
about yeah thank you and and again I
it's I won't be too elusive it's you
know 2017 2018 it was the largest indoor
grow in the state of Washington and
they're still one of the larger
companies um out here they tend to
change their name every couple years
because what what they did
is the funding was from a Russian
fishing oligarchy so you could probably
connect the dots there but they had a
lot of money to invest and they would
build these awesome facilities and then
they got bugs so what they would do is
they would build a new facility and then
bring the [__] plants from the old
facility to the new facility so that
facility had about 2 years before it was
burned again it's when you take people
who have been growing in a house and
then all of a sudden give them a
warehouse that's what I was dealing with
and I I I got brought in um I helped
them bring in their first harvest that
actually turned out good I was there
from when they went from in the red into
the black but just the the Sops there
were lacking the safety protocol was
extremely lacking which is why
ultimately I left but just also you
can't give plant you can't give 60,000
plants the same love I can give six
there's a lot of things that you have to
do commercially to protect your
investment that I would never do at home
but commercially you kind of have to do
these things I like I can't tell you how
many people have smoked my arm hair like
that's just a fact people have smoked my
arm hair out there so yeah I've smoked
my own arm hair you're just defoliating
in these big beds and you're just like
you come home you're just like sticky
and then eventually we did you know get
leaves and stuff when when you were
starting up there were a lot of things
that were learned as you went along so
that was kind of fun to be there for
that process too uh because a I got to
play with other people's plants and B
make mistakes on them because they would
tell me to do and this turned out good
sometimes they would tell me to do some
like ludicrous stripping and I'm like no
way I would do it and I'd come back
three days later you would never tell I
went in there and did it so I was able
to learn a lot of cool things that way
too cool and were you was this company
were you initially brought or attracted
to this company due to the the growing
style considering you went to school for
sustainable agriculture I assumed that
you um would look then for a company
that applied or implemented like either
living soil methods or some sort of
organic or uh sustainable practices you
know I wish I had the the option to
choose from that there are a few good
companies around here that do it that
way but they're typically small like
three four people maximum run it and
then they'll hire people for like the
Harvest and for trimming this again be
the largest facility it was a full-time
job it was grow but I I I learned
quickly the less you know the better
they like you so I you know gung-ho as I
was with the knowledge that I have the
passion I do I came in there I was like
oh you know you can make this change or
like hey I spotted this little bit of
you know like sticky residue on one of
your leavs that's probably something to
look at but they weren't necessarily
interested in that so okay work your way
up from the bottom and the higher you
get the more they'll listen to you but I
started down here so I just kind of went
in as the grunt and they promoted me
pretty quickly two different things but
no it was never something where I was
really able to implement my vision or a
lot of the knowledge that I had learned
but again it taught me new knowledge and
new Sops of way of doing things so yeah
I wish I could find that that perfect
marriage out here but it was really just
like okay now what do I do I had worked
at this Audio company for like 10 years
I just gone to school for two years I
don't want to go get a normal freaking
job so I had to drive an hour away cuz
where I'm at there's a moratorium so I
had to drive an hour every day just to
get to this job but it was worth it and
I was only late once so I made the most
of it I've definitely been there before
I moved recently I was driving to the
the same place I work at and it was like
50 minutes every day there and 50
minutes back and it does become the
drive becomes tedious but podcasts help
good audiobooks help right so it's uh
but I feel that it commuting is
sometimes one of the the worst parts of
working did you uh happen to move on to
any other commercial spaces after this
one or was that kind of where you you
left it after your experience there yeah
I kind of left it there because I
realized and again knowing some people
with other grows in the area I realize
it's never going to be the way that I
want to do it it's never going to be the
way that I fully believe it should be
done and there there's some good reasons
for that and there's some crap reasons
for that but it's never going to be done
like the way that I want to do it or the
way that I think it should be done with
because I'm patient first like again
coming from the medicinal days Patient
First like you're not oh well what can I
put on this just so we can get it to
harvest or like H we we'll cut off this
top Cola which we did we cut off hand
cut the top Cola we hand Trimm that and
then we sent that for testing after
rolling it in ke so there's things that
are just standard practice that I don't
agree with I didn't want to play that
game I transitioned from that grow
through the connections I made into
working at a dispensary I worked
security there and basically was like
the Chief Information officer so I could
tell you anything about everything and
that was for me more fulfilling because
I got to help people who were new to it
people who older people there's some
cool stories but that I've never touched
cannabis before uh so for me that was a
little bit more rewarding and then from
there like covid hit we were in
essential industry so everything was
closed but us and it just became a [__]
show and I'm like I'm just going to do
my thing so here we are here we are here
we are well that's I'm glad we kind of
like brought the story up to where we
are now for you so I do want to know
though because you are kind of within um
the space as an educator and as someone
who uh I I would assume keep their
finger on the pulse of the industry and
how it both affects hom Growers and
other things where do you see the
cultivation industry going uh whether it
be from a hom Grower's as uh from a hom
Grower's perspective from a consumer's
perspective or even in the commercial
space because I'm sure that you still
have connections there just through the
the interactions that you have within
the community where do you where do you
feel as though it's going to be going
over the
next 5 to 10 years so my my big picture
optimistic Rosie Cloud's vision would be
that it becomes federally legal which is
going to open the doors to the big
players kind of like the anheiser bushes
it's going to push out a lot of the
middle tier people that currently exist
and dominate the market I'm not going to
cry for them because they pushed me out
they pushed the mom and pops out so it's
like taste your own medicine but what
that's going to do hopefully the federal
legalization it will create those big
players it will create the or bushes but
that's when craft will succeed I think
ultimately for small people like me for
those you know 10 lighters 20 lighters
that's what we need to see because we're
never going to be able to compete on
price it's a commodity uh you can do it
on scale particularly if we allow
imports from other countries the price
is just going to it's quality and the
uniqueness that are always going to have
a market and so hopefully that's where I
see it going that's that's the you know
pie in the sky for
sure if that doesn't happen um I think
there's just going to be more
consolidation in the market I think
there's going to be less interest
commercially less interest in finding
the new thing versus something that
works under these particular Sops that
are cutting costs and basically an
economic plan but then you flip that
back to the homeg grower we're going to
keep looking we're going to keep
searching for those unicorns we're going
to keep finding those different flavors
and that's something that I think the
the legalization as we know it now has
been a big Catalyst for is to find all
these things cuz you went from you know
let's just make up a number here you
went from like a thousand people popping
seeds to all of a sudden now you have a
100,000 you can get through so many more
things and pick out so many different
varieties faster so hopefully that's
what we see from the kind of the home or
the Craft Market is we'll continue to
innovate we'll continue to push the
boundaries of experience everything is
going to get you stoned at this point
pretty much everything is going to get
you stoned so it's about the experience
to me so that's probably where I really
see it going if it doesn't go pie in the
sky but it's going to be more experience
related for sure I agree wholeheartedly
with that I you know I've always thought
it kind of mimicked or uh mirrored the
the transition from alcohol prohibition
to the Beer industry but I I do feel as
though the timeline might be truncated
on that a little bit where we're going
to see kind of whether if it if it ever
does go federally legal and I I put a
caveat on on ever because it's I feel
like we've always seen it to be right
around the corner um and it's that
corner keeps getting further and further
away so if if it ever does go legal then
I do feel as though there is going to be
a huge takeover absolutely of corporate
interests and then we'll see a lot of
Home Growers or small craft Growers who
are
stilling the support to their local
community and and local consumers to
succeed while some of the mid-ranged
ones or or where the production of
quality is not as heavily regarded or if
it just isn't there will be kind of
gobbled up by the larger corporations to
allow for more space for their probably
not terrible probably unfortunately
it'll probably be smokable you know
it'll probably be something where if
you're in a pinch in a state where
you're like I don't have anything with
me but hey it's legal now so I can just
go to the gas station and pick up a pack
of whatevers you know like I feel like
that it won't be terrible because there
will be some standards in place like but
I do I do see how like you're going to
have your just like you have your Kors
drinkers you're going to have your
people that are looking for what's their
the local city is producing for them as
well and I'm from the Pacific Northwest
again we're this is where micro
breweries came from like when it comes
to micro Brews it it really started here
so I've had the example of that laid out
for me for a long time
uh something that I paid very close
attention to because I think it will
mimic that but we still have to have
that hurdle fall before we can have that
farm totable experience where you can go
into the brewery or you could go into my
grow and you can sit down and get a
little tray with eight different strains
on it and you can try them all so yeah
I'd love to see that and particularly
for the smaller people that's something
we tried to get in the Washington market
for tier one which is the smallest tier
direct to consumer Farm to Table uh cuz
that's really the only way the little
guy can compete out here that didn't
pass so you can't do it but that's still
a hope and a dream I I kind of was I saw
that and I was hoping that that would
pass as well because I kind of had hoped
that there would be a push in some areas
to go back to Medical um with states
rights being such a big issue as of as
of late and allowing for people to make
those decisions within that state I was
kind of like cuz the Oregon Medical
Market was really great as well I'm in
Oregon and nice it was a Market at one
point but where they kept the medical as
just the ability for those patients to
receive a discount at a dispensary but
that no single producer could then still
claim medical on their production of the
plant or that there would be any
standards to back that up kind of
defeated the purpose in in my eyes but
um I'd always hoped that something like
that would come back but I do agree with
you that that is a little bit of a pie
in the sky hope at this point we we've
come a long way from just 10 years ago
so 10 more years who knows keeping the
fingers crossed and staying optimistic
but I'll be growing either way did
absolutely add a 5 to 10 your caveat to
the question so you're completely fair
in that assessment
absolutely did you just invite I kind of
wanted to leave perhaps the last part of
this show here open was there anything
more within the uh cannabis space that
you wanted to talk about growing related
or otherwise no this is this has been
great I appreciate appreciate the
questions it's been a fun conversation
and I think the theme that hopefully
people take away which is you know what
I would just reiterate is just continue
to share your knowledge continue to
share the experience because we're going
to get so much further faster if we do
that and if we build substance behind
what we're doing not just a flash in the
pan not just a cool a myar not just you
know the next hit song we build
substance to it we're going to get a lot
farther like 2012 I started out my first
like foray into public education senior
MMJ Network seniors medical marijuana
Network those are the people who have
the biggest Reefer Madness stigma
associated with cannabis in my mind
those are the people who could probably
benefit the greatest from Cannabis
whether it be aches and pains just the
daily things but the education there is
so important because they think you're
going to hell and you have to smoke it
neither of which are true so through
that education through that sharing
through providing substance real world
practical applications for these things
we're going to get a lot farther so
those are the things we need to continue
to push now it makes me a little sick
again I said earlier I'm like horrible
at self-promotion because that's not
what it's really about for me but
there's some people who would much
rather talk about you know the new myar
or you know what event they're going to
and how many grams of this they had than
actually building that substance so
hopefully they're gone not all of them
probably will be but yeah keep keep
building that substance folks that's
what I would add to the conversation I
guess for sure and honestly in my
opinion I feel as though anything that
helps end uh stigmatization to cannabis
is uh positive media in my eyes and so
when people do get really into the whole
myar thing or what what uh who's
promoting who and on what platform and
and all that you know it it does become
a a little bit monotonous at times but
also it doesn't hurt the industry as
much as it helps it in my eyes just to
help bring more awareness to the fact
that people are trying to normalize this
and so uh I do agree though I prefer to
have more meaningful conversations about
it with people that are in this for the
Long Haul and and about it for the
medicine and the plant and the community
and the way that the plant and the
people interact and how they help us
interact with each other even in a
greater way so I do wholeheartedly agree
with you on
that and you make an you made an
excellent point there this plant brings
so many diverse people together it's
amazing it is it has blessed and changed
my life just in that one fact alone so
yes I'm glad you mentioned that for sure
yeah um well I do actually have a couple
of little like wrap-up questions that
are going to be a little bit of a
quickfire because you know some of my
favorite Canabis shows have those at the
end and I just feel as though it's worth
it as a community to tie those things
together together ubiquitous what is
your favorite strain of all time if you
had to choose one and if you have to
choose a couple try and put them in
order right okay I I'll go with the one
that goes to the top of my head most
most of the time is the cam 91 cam 91
just a fantastic strain something that
has been around for a long time
something that is often imitated never
duplicated but I found a producer
actually there is one
commercial cannabis that I will go out
and buy and it's this this one company
they they call it pre 91 chem which is a
little suspect to me but yeah 91 cam is
is where I'm at as far as my uh desert
island strain goes do you do you are
you right on are you okay with sharing
the name of that company I I assume it's
a legal Washington recreational producer
just for people to know where they can
find Chad westports go to commercial
cannabis
yeah um so it was Elevate e v e l and
then they changed the name of the
company oh God I have a jar in the other
room I think just look for it it says
pre 91 cem that's the only time I've
ever pre 91 cam it's weird red and black
graphics on the jar it's like 35 bucks
for the called
plaid I know who you're talking about
but no no okay I don't think so plaid
had the Melvin which was something that
interested me too so that I score yeah
that I did catch oh God I'm sorry I'm
blanking it now I don't you know what
when we when we post this uh I'll try
and post like a short of this or
something and you'll have to comment on
it with the correct name fair fair
enough cool um so after the favorites
train who is your favorite breeder of
all time other than
yourself that's a dang good question so
like James L is a person who I would
probably consider like the mentor of
today just cuz I've been watching his
shows and following him and actually
having a rapport with him for about four
or five years so I've probably learned
the most directly from him as when it
comes to breeding he's also got a really
awesome book out right now but I also
want to toss mean Jean from mesino
freeorn selections out there that guy is
an amazing Storyteller he's an amazing
librarian I can and I've talked to him
many times I could listen to him for
four or five hours talk about straining
history his processes because you know
it's like going to school helped me I
always say you know there's a lot of
people it's like well education is the
best there's other experience is the
best education and experience is the
best in my opinion because abut
education you're going to miss out on
those little nuances like you know me
and Jean would have that you only get
through experiences you're not going to
be able to read that in a book and then
if you just rely on experience sometimes
that can turn you into a dinosaur
because you're not catching up with the
current times so yeah experience
education are the two best but Jackson
mean jeene from Menino Freeborn
selections that guy's like a thesaurus
or a dictionary encyclopedia he's smart
how about that yeah he definitely is I
um I've
always yeah yeah he is I've I've always
enjoyed listening to him whenever he's
on a podcast uh he always has a wealth
of knowledge and especially when it
comes back to goes back to like the
different crosses and the lineages of
different things and uh how they play
into each other and I'm always just I'm
always impressed by the any strains that
use his his strains as the parent
lineage especially with like black lime
Reserve that one I I feel like is in so
many different things nowadays it's
pretty ubiquitous it is I just popped a
precursor to that too from him it was
from 20121 but it's his black lime
number two so it's before the reserve
but the black lime number two
times his cherry limeade and I've been
sitting on those been sitting on those
for a couple years and I just popped
them and they're you know their
seedlings This Tall right now so I'm
super excited to see what comes to those
and honestly I hope I get a mail that
I'll be able to do some work with we'll
see we'll see that that sounds like a a
you know cherry limeade to Westport
grape juice sounds like a a juice bomb
if I've ever heard of one so I'm I'm
going to be interested to see
Flor there I like it the 7-Eleven
suicide yes exactly that sounds pretty
great so uh last question of these style
of questions it's a two-parter so what
was the first time you ever consumed
cannabis and then what is the most
memorable cannabis experience memory
whether it be smoking or seeing a plant
or otherwise that you've had the first
time smoking I don't exactly remember
but I was a very early teen I'm pretty
confident it was in the the power line
Trails the power trails out behind the
neighborhood with probably Tommy and a
couple other guys so seventh e8th grade
is really when we kind of got into it I
remember actually getting busted with
pot before I had smoked it uh really
with my friend uh my friend uh so my
friend Greg rip he was a he was a
character I smoked cigarettes so I had
camel cash and you in the camel cash for
the Zippos and I had a cool camel Zippo
and he's like well I want it I'll give
you five bucks and some weed I sure
whatever I need five bucks and so we had
gone into the bathroom at school to do
our little deal and his brother was
standing outside and his brother runs
inside he's like the principal's coming
and he totally like blew it cuz
apparently he was just standing outside
like this saw the principal ran inside
and he knew what was up and so I of
course had it in my hand at that time
and I'm the one who got busted with it
but uh uh a couple weeks later and
another detention I took it back from
his drawer which he forgot to lock along
with some brass knuckles and a couple
other cool things so I got my [__] back
um but that was the first stuff you
smoked then too yeah well it was yeah
the earlier time like I don't remember
smoking weed I don't remember how that
hit me but uh U yeah that was one of the
earlier times and then probably the most
like memorable experience actually
before you get into the memorable
experience because your story spurred my
memory and how similar it is to my first
story I have to just throw it in here
really quickly so when I was in high
school cuz I actually didn't even know
about cannabis I think until I was in
like sophomore junior in high school
which is really odd for growing up in
the Bay area but I I wanted to try
cannabis cuz I also I smoked cigarettes
and uh my one friend was like well you
want to smoke something else and I was
like like what and he's like oh you know
weed man and so I was like oh well you
know what I've heard of that I think but
yeah why not I mean I smoke cigarettes
and uh so he's like all right I need
like 20 bucks and I'm going to go get it
from this guy in the high school parking
lot at lunchtime and then uh do you have
something to put it in cuz we got to
then keep it on us until we go home and
so I went to like the army surplus store
and got one of those weatherproof match
containers like it's a metal canister
that like screws into itself and hinges
out and we stuff like you know a couple
nugs in there in in the dime bags and I
I put it back away in my pocket and I
carried it in my pocket all day and uh I
get home at night because he's like all
right we'll meet up you know like this
evening or or the tomorrow evening or
something or before school the next day
and uh so I get home and as soon as I
get home my my mom and my dad are like
waiting in the front area of our house
and they're like I've heard from my
friend I won't say his name from my
friend's dad that you might have
purchased cannabis at school today and I
was like uh you know and I don't know if
you've seen the key and peel skit where
they start sweating bullets I felt like
that was me at that point just like what
the what the [__] how do you know cuz I
didn't tell anybody other than the guy
that I got it with but apparently he
told some friends do look but I hadn't
smoked it or anything and it's in this
like actually possibly the most
smellproof container I could have chosen
for that small amount and I was like no
I don't even know what you're talking
about and I walked my way out of it
somehow but I I count that as being
caught because I
then you know I don't think I slept all
night because I was trying to figure out
what I was going to do with this little
bit of weed that I thought was going to
end my life as I know it and I go back
to school the next day and I knew my one
buddy who had talked about weed before
where I think I even heard about it and
I was like I'll just sell it to him I'll
just be like I just need to get some of
what I sold it for back and at least
what my friend put into it I'll take the
loss but I got to pay my one friend back
and be like listen I lost it here's the
money and so I did that and then about 2
weeks later we he found out my friend
that had gone in on it with me found out
that his uncle was like a big time
grower and distributor out of humble and
got us some really good blue dream and
we smoked
that there you go and this was probably
like two that's one strain that I do
miss it got so popular that people
stopped growing it and still around it
feels like it's almost diluted now like
what's the good Blue Dream where's the
original who's got the Santa Cruz cut
who's got this other one so yeah I I do
remember it though and everyone made it
made a lot of people's careers you know
like uh just with the yields that they
could get without having to put too much
effort into it so let's let's go back to
the most memorable cannabis experience
for you like if you had to think back
what's the first thing that pops your
mind or if you take a second what what
is what is that memorable cannabis
experience there's a lot of them that
were involved cannabis as part of the
story but probably the two the two that
popped to my head that were specific
cannabis one is the interview that I did
and I've got to interview him four times
now but Tommy trong like if you rewind
to my teenage self watching Up and Smoke
saying one day you're going to sit down
and be friends first name basis talk to
him every year with Tommy Chong wouldn't
have believed you um so that for me is
is a cool one but actual smoking it
plant experience itself is was in
Amsterdam again I've been going there
every year for quite a few years now I
wish I was going back in the 90s and
2000s when it properly was the hey day
but I wasn't old enough for traveling at
that point but I do and I have written
for centi seeds I have almost a 100
published pieces on their website and
their blog and one of the more memorable
experiences was when I went to the hemp
and hash Museum in Amsterdam my buddy my
boss Mark took me gave me kind of like
the private VIP tour but he took me down
stairs into the secret garden which is
no longer there which is why I'm saying
it but they had a grow down there and we
got to just smoke look at all the plants
that were coming up plants that I was
about to write you know descriptions for
just sat there smoking and enjoying our
time underneath the uh Museum that was
probably one of the more memorable
smoking related experiences with
cannabis that sounds quite memorable
I can only imagine I I mean cuz uh you
know it made me even think like watching
old uh like cops like the show Cops
where they would go in to the people's
house and they'd be it' look like a
normal house or everything would be fine
and then they find the door to the
basement they go down and it's like you
know 20 HPS lights the whole place is
red with everything fully flowered so
I'm just that's what I imagine you
walking down into at the time is
something that is just like this fully
HPS out basement where it's maybe you
know 6 or 7 ft High ceilings or
something like that kind of cramped but
filled with plants yep every and
everything down there is is dank just I
mean the it's below the water table so
it's like water kind of just like
absorbs in the concrete walls and you
just always have to deal with that sort
of like moisture and humidity they had a
few different chambers because they were
growing in different strains but you
pretty much nailed the description like
funny this place has heated floors
that's weird for the Netherlands no they
just got about 20 HPS underneath it so
yeah that's funny that's funny well
welcome back Gabby uh we actually were
just wrapping up the last few questions
did you have any questions for Chad
before we um we wrap up the rest of the
show it's nice that we've opened the
lines of communication though because I
would love to you know have you guys
come and talk a little bit to uh just on
my channel like just kind of spreading
awareness trying to introduce people cuz
I like what you're doing it's this has
been you know again a really fun
interview Nick thank you for these
questions it again kind of gives me an
idea of where you're coming from and
what you'd like to see and and if you
haven't felt it yourself we we're we're
walking the same road which is also
passion for the plan I definitely did
feel that and I I really uh I appreciate
that feedback as well you know this is
actually the first episode that we're
doing of the The Way We Grow podcast
where I'm hosting it trying to be a
little bit more focused on the growing
side of things and people's Journey as
it pertains to Growing but also kind of
mixing in their own personal story in
there because I feel like it's very
important to get bring it as a little
bit of a holistic approach and I I'm
sure Gabby also really appreciated
having you here today because we are
doing this collaboratively under the
title of craft Growers Network him doing
the gabbing with Gabby show me doing the
The Way We Grow podcast and then
hopefully adding more shows in the
future so yeah just wanted to say I
really appreciate you being here and uh
were there any plugs any thank yous
you'd want to give out to anybody any
awareness last minute awarenesses you'd
like to bring up yeah thank you again
for that opportunity if if viewers
really want to learn more about me or
check stuff out Chad
westport.ma gear merchandise but you'll
also find links to the writing that I've
done for different companies if you go
to the info tab um it will tell you a
little bit about me but it will also
give you links to specific companies
I've written for it also will give you
specific links over to the YouTube
channel you can find YouTube which is
Chad Westport and my Instagram which is
chad. Westport listed along the side so
yeah if you go to Chad westport.org that
will really get you pretty much any
place so many shout outs I always tend
to not do them because I don't want to
forget somebody but since I did mention
John the gross space killer uh big shout
out to him he's doing big things out on
the East Coast with his rosin so yeah
yeah thank you for having me and thank
you for everybody that's going to watch
this and watch us on the replay if you
guys leave a comment let us know what
you liked and what you want to see in
the future I know both of us would
appreciate it helps guide our car yeah
absolutely we're in a car we'll go with
that analogy absolutely no and I again I
appreciate you being on here thank you
so much and uh yeah we'll see you guys
next time on the way we grow