[Music]
Hello and welcome to another episode of
the way we grow podcast, a production of
the craft growers network. I'm your host
Nick Wolf. Today we actually have two
guests in the house. Uh one is chief
science officer Dr. Tassa Sali and
research director Dr. Alfonso Geredo Lea
of TUMI genomics. Uh, Tasa Alonso, how
are you both doing today? Oh, we're
great. Good. Good. Thanks for having us
on today. Thanks. Awesome. Yeah, I'm
really excited that you guys are both uh
here today. Um, like we were saying
before the podcast uh started, Tasa has
done a lot of these podcasts for
cannabis growers and um cannabis related
content. So um you know and for our
listeners as well this is going to be a
little bit of a different show because
normally we in interview growers um both
like homegrow and commercial growers to
gain an insight into their world but we
don't usually have two doctors in the
house where you guys have uh an immense
background in both um genetics research
and um cannabis research specifically
and and pathogen prevention and testing.
Um so now I have been told uh Alfonso
that you have also some experience with
cannabis cultivation uh as a home grower
and at a research level. So I would love
for you to draw from that experience uh
to kind of be the grower in the
conversation. And Tass, you know, like I
said before, you've been on numerous
other podcasts. So we're going to kind
of stay within that vein of thought here
as well to best serve the listeners. Um,
but honestly, if we uh go off on a
tangent, I'm super happy to let the flow
of the conversation just carry us away
and I don't plan on stopping it. Um, so
I wanted to spend the first part of the
show to gain a little background on both
of you and how plants and science came
together for you. Uh, whether it started
off with one or the other or if your
involvement in both sort of developed in
tandem. Um, and then for the second part
of the show, I want to talk about tumi
genomics and how home growers and
commercial cultivators should be aware
of pathogens, how they can best mitigate
them, and the steps to take if they
detect a pathogen in their grow.
So, um, let's, uh, start with you,
Tassa. um because I feel like I've heard
so much about how you um operate through
TUMI, but I don't really know about your
background with plants. Um and maybe you
have told this story before, but um when
did you first become interested in
plants or science? Uh or was it
something that they kind of came
together uh in tandem like I was saying?
Um yeah, so I guess plants have been a
big part of my life for all of my life.
Um, I grew up out in the country in
Colorado in a in a house with a big
backyard. And my um father's a master
gardener, so I spent a lot of time in my
childhood just following him around. Um,
you know, and he taught me how to
transplant plants and how to see when
they're sick, how to see when they have
like diseases and issues in the bark or
whatever. Um and you know obviously he
also had a huge um collection of indoor
plants and so I just kind of grew up
around plants. Um as you can see that
continues now. Yeah. Um and so uh
gardening's always been something that I
love. I love being outside. I love the
smell of the dirt and growing things. Um
my cat's going to video bomb us here in
a second. Come here cat. Oh that's fine.
Well, as you can see we're lovers of
cats here.
We have a lot of pets, so there we might
get video bombed at any moment. Um, but
yeah, and so I mean, I've always loved
being outside. I've loved growing things
and living things. Um, and I've also
always loved science. Um, I've been just
been interested in the way the world
works, the way life works, how it works,
why it works. Um, pretty much my whole
life. Um, and I would say I, you know, I
got into biology and science and high
school. Um, you know, taking all those
courses and then I went straight into it
in college and it's just been something
that's always fascinated me. Um, and so
I once I discovered research, it was
like I was home. It's to me it's like um
there's all these questions that people
don't know the answer to and you just
wonder but for the first time in my life
you could answer a question that nobody
knew the answer to. Um and then for a
short period of time you're the only
person in the whole world that knows the
answer to that question and that is just
so exciting.
Yeah. And it's like solving a big puzzle
and so for me it was like exciting and
it was fun and it was interesting. Um,
and oddly enough, I went into what is
called RNA biology. Um, and specifically
I studied um the structure of RNA. So
that's like um it's like a the
three-dimensional shape that molecules
take um and that particular shape
carries information that tells the cell
what to do with it. Um and I did my
whole uh uh doctoral dissertation on
that and I also did my posttock on that.
And then when we um moved into cannabis,
and I'll let Alfonso tell the story
because he has the LA I think he started
uh earlier with cannabis than I did. Um
uh we started looking into vyroids and
vyroids are threedimensional RNAs that
adopt a specific shape and it's that
shape that carries all of the
information about how this they're
treated in the cell and how they become
pathogenic. And so it just felt like um
you know between the plants which I have
always loved and um you know discovering
all of these pathogens which are
terrible but super fascinating to me. Um
it just felt like the perfect
combination of things to um sort of make
a career and make one that I really
enjoy. So that's awesome. Yeah. Yeah. I
I really like that it kind of coalesed
together because um sometimes I feel
like especially in the cannabis
community that I um participate heavily
in, there's a lot of misinformation and
people approaching this plant as
something that's really magical and um
uh kind of like exceptional or special
or uh different than other plants, but
in so many ways it's the exact same as
uh any other crop plant in that it can
um harbor pathogens, vyroids. Um the
movement of these vyroids and uh
pathogens and pests are also kind of
universally known and they have been
known for a long time. And so when we
try to separate this plant
from everything else that it's connected
to within agriculture and horiculture,
we start to lose sight of some of the
more well understood methods of remedies
that we can take for um you know a
myriad of different uh problems that we
might uh face as growers.
Um so you know applying the science
while you are also loving plants it kind
of opens up your eyes I'm I'm sure as uh
you've experienced to where you can be
like well no I can just take I'll take
this information kind of Frankenstein it
up a little bit because I can you know
use the information that I have for this
other plant and just apply it right
there and look boom it works. Um, so
that it is really cool to be kind of on
the cutting edge of something like that.
Uh, where you're like discovering new
things that you're like, "Oh my gosh, I
can take this and apply it to something
else." And um, that that's that like
feeling of discovery has got to be
tremendous. Yeah. No, it's actually it's
been incredibly cool in cannabis because
there's so much that's unknown. Um, and
you're right, there's there's a huge
body of literature in agriculture that
we can lean on. And you know, cannabis
is an amazing plant, but it is a plant.
Um, and I would maybe argue that maybe
plant, all plants are kind of amazing in
their own way, and there's probably a
lot about them that we don't appreciate.
Um, but, you know, in cannabis, like you
can read all this literature, but
there's a lot that's just not known. And
so it's really exciting, you know, to
have a grower be like, well, I just
seated this mom plant that has hoped.
What do I do with those seeds? Are they
going to have it, too? And I'm like, you
know, I don't know. Let's do a research
study. And so, um, it's just really fun
to be in that position where you can
just be like, yeah, let's just set up a
research study with a grower or, you
know, um, another lab and industry. And
there's just so much to discover. Um,
and and there's always an opportunity to
discover more cool things. So, it's it's
a fun place to be in the sense there's
so much unknown. So, Sure. Yeah. And you
know, just to get a little bit off topic
because of something that you said
there. Um, when it comes to cannabis
seeds, I know that I believe I've heard
either you say before or heard elsewhere
that um, it's like 90 or
95% potential if it's um, the female
plant has hopen vyroid that the seeds
will become infected with hops laten
vyroid. And um I might have my numbers
off there, but I was curious. Is this
something that you're finding on the
seed coating or is it something that
you're finding within the germ plasm of
like the seed? Yeah. So that's a great
question. Um so the answer is both. Um
wow. The flower of uh for a cannabis
flower for a plant that's infected with
hot plate and thyroid has an incredibly
high level of vibroid. I would say it's
the it's the tissue that accumulates the
most vyroid. Um and then second of
course would be the root. So um on the
outside and even in that seed coat the
chances of finding the vyroid just
taking that seed and throwing it in a
tube, grinding it up and doing a PCR on
it is very high. It's like 90. I mean
some of the plants even 100% of those
seeds will test positive. Um there is a
difference though. that doesn't
necessarily mean that if you pop that
seed that the seedling will have hop
late and vyroid. Um we've done studies
together showing that um the chances of
the actual seedling having hop late
vyroid vary between 20 to 50%. Um and
that depends a little bit on the
cultivar and the level of infection of
the mother. Um if the father if the
pollen carries it in it's in our studies
was much lower. it was like 5% of those
seedlings. Um, but if you say you have a
packet of seeds that all came from the
same mother and you want to know did
that mother have hop late and thyroid
sending that seed in one or two of those
seeds and how doing a PCR um if it if
the mother did have hop late and thyroid
you'd be able to tell just by a few
seeds because the chances of finding
like that are incredibly high. Wow.
Well, thank you for indulging me on my
little tangent there because I I just
find that part really interesting as uh
someone who likes to pop cannabis seeds.
Um yeah. Um and you know, just one last
question on this first part for you,
Tasa. Uh when did you first encounter
cannabis? Was it uh something that you
encountered already as a research
scientist or did you have some
experience it with it prior? Um yeah, so
this is a great segue into talking to
Alfonso. Um so he's the director of
research and development. He's also my
husband. So um I mostly encountered
cannabis and growing of cannabis um
through Alfonso. Um he's been growing it
for a very long time. And so um uh
probably we've been together for about
20 years. So um you know the last 17
years or so. But that introduction um
happened when I met Alfonso. All right.
Cool. Um that's funny. my my parents, it
was the other way around. My my mom
introduced my dad to cannabis uh when he
moved out from the Midwest to the to the
West Coast.
Um I feel like that's a story as old as
time, though. So,
um Alonso, let's let's uh hear a little
bit about um when you first became
interested in plants and uh or science,
you know, whichever came first or if
they came together uh in unison that
like a let's hear your plant story.
Yeah. So um so I became interested in
plants is I think I can remember I was
always into the outdoors and plants just
being around plants just make me happy
just gave me like a good feeling
and times that I was not feeling good I
could just sit around pants in a forest
and it would just like calm me down and
make me go through the ideas.
Uh so I in science uh I was as a as a
kid I was um had really ADHD to the
extreme. So I I wasn't a a very I was
not a good student in high school or so
I thought that I will never become a
scientist or anything like that. And
interestingly like when I um tried
cannabis for the first time when I was
around 17 18 years
old it gave me a a a sense of I could
just sit down and be able to read
something that I have never experienced
before. So that kind of opened the door
to to the academia and science um
um I guess
journey and so so then so then I I guess
I I moved to to to the United States
from Peru back in
1997 and when I was here and I decided
to go into graduate school, I found that
I could just smoke a little bit and I
was able to to to to read journal
articles and and all these like um
literature and so I started consuming
cannabis in grad school very often and I
actually did my dissertation
uh with cannabis because I wasn't able
to sit down for like eight months
every single day and write 12 hours a
day. It was it was kind of like intense.
Yeah. But it was in that moment in which
um I has was always already growing in
my basement since 2012 2000 in Colorado.
It became like um you will be able to
grow with your red card, with your
medicinal card, which I had
and I was growing in my basement.
And I the the the buds were incredible.
They were like awesome and I was
everybody was like, "Oh yeah, you can
grow cannabis." But in reality, it is
just a plant. I can grow any plant from
whatever. And so it was just a moment in
time in which everything went to
hell. Everything like it was just like
no more like resinous or sticky butts.
They were all like a fluffy thing. And I
was just like, "Okay, maybe the pH, the
nutrients, the the media, the the tent,
the
water." I went through all these thing
like for like four or five years.
Wow. Erh and then after that time
uh we Tumi started and we actually
started in doing
COVID and then when we transition into
cannabis we designed the PCR test and I
said well we can use my plants as a
negative control and they should be
negative because right and so then they
were always positive and they were
Oh, this test sucks and we should like
redesign it and it's hitting something
in the cannabis plant. It's always
positive. It doesn't matter. Doesn't And
then somebody gave me a plant, a little
plant, a little clone. And I I used that
one and boom, it was negative. And I was
like, I can't believe I was dealing with
hot plate and vyroid for the last four
years. So, wow.
2015 to 2020.
Uh so so so then that's how I realized
man there will be a lot of people out
there having the same problem as me and
I cannot even imagine if I only had four
plants or five plants at the most. But
if you have like an entire like facility
full for acres of of of cannabis then
you this is going to really affect you
right. So yeah, so that's I became
um aware of like this vir could do to to
to the plant and to the growers.
So then um I in in kind of like
interesting parallel because at the same
time when I was writing my dissertation
I was writing about an enzyme called RNA
polymerase 2 which my dissertation was
about like when the DNA has genes and
this machinery needs to know where it
starts and where it ends and if like I
think like 5% of the DNA is coded by
genes and the other part is not. So we
were interested in see how does the
machinery knows when to
stop. So I was writing about this and
hope vyroid when it gets into the cell
it uses the same machinery to to copy
itself. So as I was dealing with hope in
my own grow without me knowing I was
digging into this same machinery in the
literature and knowing all these things
about this enzyme and it was just
curious to see that I was
um dealing with this in my grow and I
was probably at that moment I I knew the
entire literature of that enzyme which
goes back 40 of 50 years of of research.
Wow. So you were able to kind of apply
all of that previous research to the
current problem which was the hops late
and thyroid that you were facing. Yes.
Correct. And but also at the same time
there was is very little known about it.
It is because the cell uses the
machinery to do something similar but
not the same. the vyroid is exploiting
that to on its
own
benefit, but it's not like what is
intended to do. But
that actually works in the favor of the
vyroid because it makes a lot of
mistakes when it's copying itself. But
that's what the vyroid wants because it
wants to evolve and and and mutate and
try to adapt to the different strains.
So that's why maybe uh people say and I
experienced it myself that when a plant
is infected with hope platon vyroid is
strain dependent on what you're going to
see and it may be that that's due to the
differences in
um mutations in in in in the vyroid
which I think are called quasi
quasi species quasi species or something
like that. Okay. Yeah, that's really
fascinating because, you know, I've seen
a bunch of people deal with hops and
thyroid and it just completely wreck
their grow, but then I've also seen
people who just not
outcl they'll they'll keep, you know,
vibrant new mothers uh for their
production and um and replace them at a
regular interval where they're not
building up a sort a sort of um a
threshold that then creates these
devastating effects. And I've even heard
of people using things like putting
aspirin in their um in their nutrient
feed because the acetaminophen will will
um affect the rate at which the
um the vyroid builds up in the tissue. I
I believe that that's the how that
occurs. Um if if you guys know anything
more about that specifically, I'd love
to hear your thoughts on that.
No, I haven't. Um yeah so first the the
strain dependency so it's it's really
interesting um we've we have actually
done a study um in collaboration with
state house in California where we took
12 different strains um we cut clones
from them um from mothers that were
confirmed negative for hobble vyroid and
we infected them as clones um and then
we grew them throughout their lifetime
and we tested them every couple of weeks
and sort of followed the vyroid
infection and all these different 12
strains. Um, and it was really
fascinating because we found some that
were incredibly sensitive. Like, um,
they were super stunted, super messed
up. We'd lost a ton of yield. And with
those particular strains, I think, um,
you'd be unlikely to be able to outclone
it or outgrow it or even even if you
took really really good care of those
strains, they're just so sensitive that
they just kind of like crapped out. Um
there were others that seemed resistant
like um it was really difficult to get
all of the plants infected. The vyroid
load grew incredibly slowly and even
though they were all positive at the end
of the study, most of them we didn't see
a huge drop in yield um or THC levels or
anything like that. Um and then there
was one strain which I thought was kind
of terrifying that was super easy to
infect. um it like skyrocketed thyroid
level instantly and grew all the way to
adulthood with zero impact at all. It
was like tolerant. Um which is great for
that strain, but it kind of functions
somewhat like a Trojan horse if you have
that thing in your facility because
you're like, "Oh, this thing looks
great. I'm just going to clone it and
I'm just not going to worry about it."
And you're like silently spreading it um
to all of your other strains. So um it's
it's scary. it's super strain dependent
and um you know there there are certain
strains where I do think that it would
be possible to um clone so frequently
because the vyroid it it either is
traveling very slowly or it's
replicating slowly so that you're never
going to see a major impact. Um it does
continue to be an infection risk for
your for the rest of your plants. So if
if you are doing that, it's important to
be aware that you're cloning plants that
are positive so that you can be
incredibly careful about touching your
other plants. Um as far as adding
aspirin, um I think that they're
probably the the ideas there is the
salicylic acid um which is a plant
hormone that can um sort of
elicit the immune system for the plant.
And so um adding that um can um there
there is evidence in the literature that
it can slow um thyroid replication or
the accumulation of thyroid in some
crops. Um the the evidence isn't like
you know outstanding. It's like 8% or
something but it it it can help. Um,
although I I'm still a proponent of just
um getting nice clean moms and testing
to make sure that you don't have it and
just just like preventing it in the
beginning instead of trying to treat it
after the fact because that's incredibly
hard. Yeah. Um well, what are if we
could go over maybe a few symptoms that
um growers might uh find where they
might want to then be on the alert or
potentially start to look into getting
the plants tested for hops and thyroid.
Um and if we could go over kind of what
you might see in a vegetative stage of
growth as well as what you would see in
a flowering stage of growth.
Um yeah so and I guess to let if you
have any symptoms to add just just throw
them in there. Yeah. So symptoms are
incredibly variable. Um if you see
symptoms um some of the more common ones
with hop late and vyroid are going to be
um the plant will get stunted. Um it it
has kind of irregular growth. So
normally like the branches are going to
come off at like a 45 degree angle but
with hop late and borate they tend to
come off horizontally um which makes
them very brittle. So if you have a
plant and you like go like this and all
the branches break on the way down
that's um really characteristic of
hopllay and vyroid. Um you can also see
um leaf discoloration, chlorosis um
abnormal leaf shape. Um it does affect
the growth of the root system. So the
the leaf the leaf size Yes. The leaves
can be small yellow. Sometimes they over
they're not like the big thin leaves.
They're like little smaller.
Yeah. Absolutely. Yeah. Um and then the
root system also can be affected. So, if
you if you have clones and they're just
rooting incredibly slowly and you don't
have like any sort of environmental
reason to suspect that they dried out or
something, um sometimes that could be a
sign that the mom plant had hop and
vyroid. Um what sort of time frames are
you seeing on the the cloning process?
Um and that that extension that you're
mentioning. Yeah. I don't do you have a
feel for the time frames like when you
see the like it's take long it takes
longer to root the sick ones. Yeah. So
that's that's interesting. I it's like a
very strain dependent I guess.
But
uh I I will say like what I have seen
like what happened to me is like when
the clone is infected with HVD and
because I I'm growing them the infected
ones and the non-infected ones and if
one day I forget to to water them
because I was away or you know like the
usually all the leaves kind of like drop
and kind of like the plant feels sad But
you add water and it kind of like
recuperates. But I seen that for the hot
plate and vyroid ones, they they can't
deal with it. They just the majority of
them, they just die and the leaves
become uh like dried up and crispy
and yeah, I don't know if Yeah, I mean
it's it's about a 2x decrease in root
mass. So, it took about twice as long
for it to get um to that same place as
as a healthy one. And sometimes they
don't they don't make it at all. Like
you just don't see those really nice
white roots. Um and it just depends a
little bit on how sick the mom was, too.
Um for sure. Yeah. Yeah. But this the
bottom line is like it's very hard to to
to figure it out just by eye. probably
if you are using seen it a lot and
probably your eye is
already used to it to identify it uh
but for that reason I think is it's good
to test and um you don't have to test
like a lot you have to test smart like
at at a specific point like you have to
test for example the mother before
cutting the clones and you have to test
the clone phones you you test you know
like it is um kind of like building
protocols and SOPs so that you can't uh
test in a smart way and you don't have
to spend that much money on it but you
protect yourself for sure I I heard um
test early um and test often um and then
you know if you have a pretty you know
good uh assurance that you don't have it
then just don't bring any genetic in
that you don't uh know where they're
coming from. Yeah. Yeah. And Yeah. And
also another thing is like if you
like sometimes me I want to smoke some
cheap wheat that you find at the
dispensary. you don't have much money
and you just like usually those cheap
weed that look like little butts and
stuff may be full hope and
vir you may pass it that way so it is
important to I think like use gloves
especially if if you're a stoner and and
protect your
clothes it is very easy to to pass it.
How how late have um you tested uh dried
flour? Like how how long after it has
been dried has hops late and thyroid
been detectable and transmittable?
So um so we we actually haven't done
those studies but um Zamir Punja from um
Simon Frasier University in Canada did a
big study where he um took flour from
dispensaries all over the place and I'm
going to space the percentage but it was
like 70 to 80% of the flour he found
over there was infected. Wow. So, it's
incredibly common and like I said, it's
it's in a very very high level in the
flower. So, even if the plant um got
that infection later on and it and then
it didn't impact the flower because it
wasn't infected for very long, the
flower itself is still going to have a
lot of um vyroid in it. Um vyroids in
general can be stay um active for about
3 months in dried tissue. It usually
requires like kind of rehydration um and
then it could become infectious. Um some
studies say up to six months. So it kind
of depends on on which vyroid you're
looking at. Although those studies like
you were saying there's a lot of
literature in other plants. They were
not done in cannabis with hopen vyroid.
So that's a guideline. Um, in general,
if you're if you're getting weeded, uh,
grinded up weed all over you, just be
real careful before you go in there and
cuddle with your plants because it's um,
super easy to transmit it and then
you're going to be stuck with years of
frustration, not just your plants. Yeah.
Yeah, that's such a good point because I
don't feel like a lot of people would
think about that, but um, it it does
make sense if you are already seeing
detection on the outside of seed shells.
Um I mean that's basically the same as
the dried flower at that point in terms
of uh what environment those those
vyroids are facing um outside of the the
living tissue. Um yeah that's very very
fascinating. Um all right and then um
with the flower morphology and the the
um you know other symptoms you might
face or um find in flowering cannabis
plants. What are some of those? Um yeah,
so um unfortunately hop late and
vyroid's biggest impact is going to be
on the flower. Um it basically um the
the flowers that come out of infected
plants especially the susceptible ones
are you're going to lose a lot of
density that be more like the fluff. Um
the canabonoid content both THC and CBD
go way down. um you don't see the same
type of tricom formation and they just
don't produce as much turppen and all of
that and so they're basically you know
like the the disease the nickname is
their duds. Um uh pretty much it just
tanks the flower completely.
Wow. And then um like are there are
there any uh cases that you've seen
where the symptoms only present in part
of the flowering plant or perhaps like
one branch? Um but everything else is
kind of looking as you would expect it
to look. Yes, absolutely. Um so one of
the important things to realize about
vyroids is they're they're like um
molecules. They're not like living
things that have the ability to move
about the plant on their own. So um when
a plant gets infected like say you cut a
branch and you cut it with a dirty tool
and the vir gains access it has to move
about the plant with the photo
assimilates which is basically the the
the goo inside the plant that's trans
transferring the energy of the sun or
the lights um to areas of the plant that
can't make their own energy. So the
vyroid is going to move from what's
called a source to a sink. And so sink
areas are areas that can't make their
own energy. So, it's going to go to um
you know new growth that hasn't doesn't
have the capability to do photosynthesis
yet or it'll go into the roots.
Obviously, there is no photosynthesis
going on there which is why testing the
roots is so useful because it it has to
go down there because it that's it needs
the energy from the foliage. Um but it's
the bottom line is it's not going to go
to every branch. um at least not right
away. And sometimes there can be a huge
delay like two months or whatever like
the lifetime of the plant. And so what
ends up happening is you can see exactly
what you described. Some branches are
going to look super, you know, infected
and sick and the buds are going to be
terrible and then other branches are
going to look just fine. Um because the
vyroid either hasn't traveled there or
hasn't been there long enough to build
up enough of a load to really impact the
plant.
For sure. Um and then in terms of
um oh let's see I lost my train of
thought there. Um so with with like the
the flowering cycles then um and you
seeing it only in one branch uh
potentially or across uh an entire you
know canopy if if the viral level is
that high in the mother plant. Um other
than uh you know a de decrease in flower
quality maybe um could you describe some
of what you might have seen in some of
the plants that were more resistant but
still with um a reasonably high level of
uh vyroid uh presence within the tissue.
Um yeah so that's so that's the sort of
trick that hop late and vyroid plays on
all of us. Um, if the plants are
somewhat resistant or tolerant, you
often don't see much of anything. Um,
and so you can look across a canopy and
be like, "Everything looks great. I
don't need a test, whatever." But it can
look very asymptomatic. Um, so it's it's
it's important to know what the symptoms
are, to know that something might be
percolating in there that you need to
test for, but it's also important to
realize that it can exist
asymptomatically. Um, and it's still
important to confirm, especially if
you're bringing in new things, that it's
not sick before you put it next to all
your important mother plants. Um the
other really important observation we
made is that if plants test negative or
have an incredibly low vyroid load at
the kind of at the end of propagation
like the 2 to 3 week um time point even
if they end up building a pretty high
load by the time they flower out um we
don't tend to see symptoms. So, for
example, you could have a plant that
accumulates thyroid very slowly and um
let's say you're veging. You you keep
some for veg or to replace your mom's
and it builds up that load slowly. You
may not see it in the first couple of
generations and then maybe in the second
or third generation all of a sudden the
clones have enough of a load that when
they go into flower it's affected the
biology enough that now you're going to
see it. Um and so in a sense it can kind
of sneak up on you as well. So, um,
really if you just keep a few moms that
are clean and you test them, you know,
consistently and you can cut off those
moms and then they can be propagation
mothers. You don't have to like have
thousands. But that's the best way to
protect yourself. Um, because you can't
rely on the symptoms uh because you just
might not see it right away. Sure. Um
and um along the same sort of line with
the symptoms that you might um associate
with hops and vyroid, are there any
other pathogens or vyroids that can
cause similar symptoms that may be less
pervasive but um but might be almost
like a false positive if you're just
trying to visually identify what's going
on in your garden. Yes. So, it's
important to recognize that symptoms
like leaf discoloration and stunting are
incredibly generic and there's a
plethora of viral or pathogens that can
cause things like that. And so, um just
seeing those symptoms, it's something
that hopen vyroid should be occur to
you, but it's not necessarily a given
that that's what your plant has. Um the
the vyro the
vyroid sorry the collection of uh
vyroids and viruses that impacts impact
cannabis
um is kind of under studied right now.
So we don't know a lot about it. Um
there are a few like alphalfpha mosaic
virus um tobacco streak
virus. Um what else would cause those
symptoms? Uh there's beet curly top
virus. Um, these have all been
characterized in cannabis. Um, most of
them are going to be more of a concern
if you're growing outside. Um, but it's
all possible that it could be caused by
those types of things instead. Did you
want to add something? Lettuce
chlorosis. Oh, yes. Lettuce. Thank you.
Cool. Uh, yeah, because I feel like
sometimes um, you know, there's a little
bit of a a dog whistle when you hear uh,
HLVD. people start to freak out and they
just think, "Oh my god, every little
symptom that I notice in my garden where
my plants don't look healthy, that's got
to be that's got to be it, man. And the
world is the world is coming to an end
right now." Um, and so I've I've even
heard of kind of stories where people
have chucked out their entire genetic
collection because they were worried
about one plant and then they realized
they had been using the same scissors or
scalpel for the past year and they're
like, "Well, of course I have it. I
don't I don't even want to spend the
money to get it tested because um you
know that the same money that you could
spend on the tests in some cases you
could just spend to get the genetics
back from a clean source. Um and even
nowadays you know you can get them as uh
generation zero clones from tissue
culture labs that are going to provide
you a much more uh secure way of
acquiring genetics if they have all of
the um the paperwork and documents to
match. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. But the tissue
culture is is is is important to know
that it's not
100%. That it is a very you can imagine
just u like what they're trying to
isolate is a bunch of little cells the
merry stems but the
adjacent cells that are not the stem
cells are right there. So if you're with
a scapeole, it doesn't matter how many
times you done it. If you just cut it a
little bit on the wrong part, everything
will be contaminated. So the tissue
culture, even if it goes through tissue
culture, those people that are doing
tissue culture should check that if the
vyroid has been eradicated. I also have
heard although I have never done it but
I have heard
from people breeders that that they have
been able to outgrow the vyroid by just
cutting the the the the shoot the the
epical shoot and they they say that they
have to cut it three four five times
that sometimes is like very lengthy more
than a year process.
So they were saying like it's not worth
it. But you can imagine if that shoot
grows because it grows pretty fast and
you haven't had the chance for the
vyroid to get there and you cut it, you
you you have a chance to to out compete
the vyroid. I guess for sure. I've I've
heard the exact same stories and uh from
a a bunch of different people and um you
know I feel like that does give a lot of
hope for what was called you know like 2
or 3 years ago the the potential
um super villain of the cannabis
industry because people were losing
entire yields uh entire rooms worth of
yields out of um their facilities over
the course of uh a given space of time.
And um I I could see especially with
kind of the downturn that the cannabis
market has been facing lately in terms
of the price per pound and the overhead
cost and the operational cost. Um that
like all of them are going in the wrong
direction for there to be a decent
profit margin. And if something like
this where you could say look I have
this this population of plants and if
they have hot latent thyroid I can face
you know a 50% yield let's just say loss
and uh that that alone would be
devastating. It might not even be
tenable at that point. Um, so I I that's
why I'm like I'm really excited to get
this information out to people because I
do feel as though
um where there is a lot of potential for
yield loss and um crop failure even
there is also a lot of hope for how you
might be able to prevent it, combat it
as well as uh ameliate those those
issues overall.
Um well, you know, I think we've gotten
a little bit of a good background now on
both of you guys and um I think I want
to kind of move into a little bit more
about Tumi Genomics and what you guys do
there. So, if you could uh both go over
a little bit about your roles at the
company and maybe any exciting projects
that you're working on currently.
Um you want to start? Yeah. So, I mean,
I guess just a a quick background on
Tumi Genomics. Um we are a pathogen
testing company as well as a company
that provides um guidance and
recommendations for growers. Um so if
you do have an issue, we don't just give
you a test result and be like, you know,
good luck. Um uh we do we do a lot of um
consulting and building pathogen
mitigation programs for growers. Um and
kind of as aside uh when we founded TUMI
genomics or we founded you know the
company in general we founded it with
the concept that we wanted to bring um
you know basically kickass science or or
great science to industries or
geographies that are underserved. Um and
I think the cannabis industry um when we
discovered it was you know it was
exactly what our company was founded to
do. Um and
so our main focus at TUMI genomics is
providing you know not just that testing
and the pathogen mitigation and all of
that but also the information and the
research um that people can rely on.
It's done correctly. It's done with the
right controls um you know so that we
can sort of start chipping away at some
of the misinformation and the unanswered
questions so growers have what they need
um to be successful. And um I think you
had brought up, you know, like people
are like, "Oh, I'm screwed. My whole
life is over. I'm just going to throw
everything away." And um I think that
there's a lot of fear around pathogens
and cannabis in general and especially
around hop late and thyroid. And one of
the most important things for me is for
people to understand that um with
information, you can combat fear. Um
there's no reason to feel like you have
to be terrified of this thing or it's
going to ruin your whole life or the
world is ending. Um there's a lot you
can do to protect your facility or your
grow. And there's even a way we've
helped people um who have like rampid
infections kind of build up a clean
stock or you know a a sort of a genetic
bank of very healthy mothers and then
slowly over time work through um moving
the vyroid out of the facility without
having to shut operations down and lose
a ton of money because it's not you know
whether you're a home grower or you have
a huge facility you don't always want to
be like and now I'm just going to cut it
off and have nothing no flower at
Um and so the the whole that's the whole
basis of this company is really to fight
fear and to bring information to growers
so that they are empowered to to do
something about this. Um and so with
that the way we do that is through um
research with academic um industries as
well as with um industry uh like
cultivation partners and things to sort
of answer some of those questions. Um we
do testing um we we test plant tissue
for you know our the main three that are
going to ruin your life are hopen vyroid
fuserium and pytheium. The fuserium and
pithium are mold or mold like infections
that can tank your plants or your entire
facility. Um and then we also test for a
myriad of other um you know viruses and
pathogens that are are much less common.
But if the symptoms warrant it warrant
at that, we can also test for all of
those things as well. Um as well as
providing um pathogen mitigation
programs. So if you realize your
facility has 30% infection, what do I
do? Um we will get on the phone with
you. We'll learn a lot about your
facility and your practices and then
we'll identify ways that you can correct
um the issue like a testing plan that's
within your budget so that you can start
to work through it. and you know kind of
correcting some of the cultural
practices around sterility and you know
uh people movement and all of those
things to sort of make sure that um that
it's cleared out. Um also if you have a
pathogen like a a fungal infection um we
we help people track those down so we
can test your water, your air, your
growing media, kind of figure out where
it's coming from, why it's happening to
you and then build you a plan around
that to sort of get yourself out of it.
Um, so, um, we'd like to think that
we're a complete scientific solution.
Um, that we're partners with growers and
we help them work through these issues
and and come out the other side clean
and successful.
That's awesome. I feel like that's super
important. Um, cuz sometimes just
giving, you know, like uh it's kind of
the difference between like leading uh
the horse to water, right? Like you can
you can lead them there and then if you
just leave them there, they may or may
not drink. But if you kind of show them
that you can drink the water, right? And
then how you get through all of these
problems, you know, potentially if it's
if it's a a pathogen or a vyroid that
you're facing, that's such a a huge
benefit to add to the services that you
guys are providing. Um because it is
really hard to figure out then what you
do. Uh especially if you're, you know,
you're already dealing with flower rooms
and environmental parameters and
irrigation maintenance and oh, you got a
drying room that you need to have
trimmed and all this other stuff that
like the life of a grower is very hectic
and can be very uh time consuming. And
so to add then the extra stress on top
of it of something like a pathogen or a
vyroid, you know, it's it's uh almost
like dealing with a pest infestation
where you have this huge battle in front
of you that you see and you go, I I just
got to kind of toughen up and buckle
down and and get to it. And um I feel
like sometimes maybe the fear of these
different pathogens and thyroids is
because you don't really see the damage
until it's too late.
And the the path to fixing it is not as
easy as applying a pest spray where um
you know pests are already such a big
problem that it's like the next level of
hell is vyroids because you you have so
much it's so much is unknown to the
grower in the moment. And
uh yeah, that's it's great that you guys
do provide sort of the whole holistic
package um for growers. Um that's
awesome. Alfonso though uh let's hear a
little bit more about your role with the
company and uh any potentially exciting
projects considering you are the
director of research. Yes. So I have
developed the all the test services that
we offer. But
um in in particular we are aware that a
p the PCR technology is kind of
like 20th century technology is has been
around for 50 so years. Erh so we are
trying to move uh away from that into a
more
um 21st century uh science uh
technological tests. So we developed the
the tumi globe for for for growers to
test in their in their facility for
hopllay and broid and uh and that's
important because it is it costs the
costs a lot because a PCR machine is 50k
and the reagents are expensive it's time
consuming preparing and so we were
trying to basically develop something
that
to overcome all those things. So we did
our tumiglow and um and now I am working
on basically making a uh the fuserium
equivalent of the tumiglow so that
growers in the grow can test for HOVD
and
perfuserium and probably I haven't
started yet but probably in the next
year we will be doing the same for
pithium and other common diseases that
you will find at the same time there's
uh there's this technology called um
next generation
sequencing in which we are uh trying to
get into it because it's becoming with a
year's super cheap to just instead of
you asking me does my plant has
hopid you can ask what does my plant has
and then the NGS or next generation
sequencing will be able to tell you all
the all the pathogens that your plant
may have in in that mode. Wow. And and
and and and the costs are like super uh
low compared to PCR. Is it is it
something to do with like having a it
has like a bank of
um references that it can use versus
having like a direct reference of like
having the you know the the confirmed
positive um and then you take that and
compare it to the information. Yeah.
Basically what you do is just just
sequence the entire nucleic acids DNA or
RNA of the so you will get by by by by
default a bunch of the plant stuff uh
but then uh you can focus on the
pathogens non-plant sequences and on
online free there's libraries uh
databases of uh of all these pathogens
and their sequences. So you basically uh
with a computer byformatically you can
see okay this sequence which is repeated
100,000 times in my sample what is it
and then you go to this database and it
tells you okay this sequence is this
this pathogen awesome yeah so it's like
a a better approach than the old PCR
technology and I'm sure you could even
then kind of apply some of these
different AI learning models and um kind
of sift through that information even
faster and more accurately. Yes, this
this technology is uh going
uh advancing at a very high pace like
that's awesome. Uh, you know, that's
also just another level of hope for the
growers where it's going to allow for
such a more comprehensive testing
um scenario for them where they're going
to be able to just find out that much
more about their plants and what they
can then do to help improve their grows
overall or their yields, their health of
the plants, and all those different
things. That's that's great cuz I bet
you there's probably a lot of other sort
of combinations of pathogens or just
little issues that would be something as
simple as applying like a
um like a oxyos or a zerol or something
like that to the to the plant and be
able to kind of kill it off, take a new
cutting, outgrow it, outstrip it and um
and be free of that potential issue. Um
so that's really great.
Um, so you know, I I like to do this
podcast for both home growers and
commercial cultivators because I feel
like there's a lot of information that
can uh help both of them um but at
different in different ways in a lot of
a lot of times. And so for the services
that you guys
provide both for home growers and
commercial uh growers, when should
people uh potentially look into getting
testing done for their plants uh like
what I know we kind of went over some of
the signs and symptoms, but um if you
were to go to uh say a new grower and
they they've heard of hops late and
thyroid, right? um they know that they
can get tested, but they go, "Well, I
don't I'm just growing a plant. I don't
know if I should get it tested or not."
Or as a commercial grower, right,
they're not seeing yield loss or or
anything um significant. Do like what
what are some of those things that they
should be aware of where they go, "Ah, I
need to start looking into testing."
Um,
so I guess my take on it is
that prevention is always going to be
significantly cheaper, faster, and
easier than um, trying to mitigate it
once it's spread in your facility. Um,
and often you don't see anything like
you were saying until it's gotten really
bad and then fixing it becomes this
thing that feels very overwhelming and
requires a lot of intervention. Um, so
if you know if I were starting a brand
new grow and I was bringing in new
clones, you know, the first thing I
would do is go to my clone provider and
say, "Hey, did you test these clones or
did you test the mother that you cut
these clones from?" You know, for
ideally hop late and thyroid and
fuserium um because you don't want
either of those in your facility. Um,
pytheium um can be not quite as bad, but
obviously you don't want to be bringing
that in either. So, um, confirming if
you can that the clones you're
purchasing are negative is step one. Um,
if you already have mothers growing in
your facility, um, I would definitely do
kind of a baseline test. Um, ideally,
the way people are organizing their
mothers is that they have, um, it kind
of depends on the size of your facility
and how many production mothers you
need, but you have a smaller subset of
plants that are called, um, nuclear
stock. Um, so let's say, you know, if
you need 20 mothers of each strain, you
have a few moms that are um, uh,
represent that strain, but they're kept
in a separate place. Even if it's a
separate table in the corner, and you
know, even if you're a home grower and
you have stuff going on in your
basement, you'll have a little tent
with, you know, one or two of each
strain that you like to grow that are
protected that you you keep the bugs
away, you're very careful when you're
handling them. Those should be tested
periodically. Like I mean ideally you
test them before you cut clones off of
them and you test the clone that will
become the replacement mother. Um so you
know depending on the cadence of how
often you're replacing those. Um, and
that's to make sure that nothing sneaks
in and sort of, you know, is sneakily
moving about your your basement or your
huge facility until it, you know,
basically kicks you in the ass six
months later and you're looking at this
huge loss. Um, so I guess the the the
short answer, that was a really long
answer. The short answer is um I don't
think there's a time when you should
like say and now I start testing this.
It's a continual thing that you do and
it it doesn't need to be thousands and
thousands of dollars, but it does need
to be something that's worked into your
regular process. Um because if you skip
that and you work without information,
it's kind of like a ticking time bomb.
You don't know when things are going to
go south for you. So, it's better to
just prevent it at the offset. Um,
I was just gonna say that in my case
when I since you were talking about Nick
about the how you sprout seeds h I I
have found that before sprouting them
like sticking them into 10 to 20% bleach
for one minute uh it is is
is important because if the HVD is in
the outside of the coat it will destroy
destroy it or if any
fungi anything fungal like is in the
outside it will also destroy it. So it
it is a you know it will just take you
one minute. Uh I have not seen any uh
decrease in germination rate. The seats
are pretty tough
and so yeah so that's a a good practice
to to to do before you sprouting your
seeds for sure. And um is the other
product that you can use is it called uh
Zirkcon or is it uh uh it's Verircon?
Vercon. Thank you. Zirkcon I think is an
allergy medicine.
That does sound familiar to me. Oh, I
don't know why my mind went there, but V
and Z, you know, they're they're at the
end of the alphabet. Same same side of
the alphabet. Yeah. Okay. So, so Vercon
is the other product that people can use
um also potentially by for seed washes
ahead of times just to give yourself
that extra assurance. Um, and when
you're using the bleach on the uh seed
wash, do you recommend letting that
bleach fully dry on the seed coating
after removing it from the solution or
do you rinse it with water? I rinse it
with water. Okay, great. That's good to
know. I know that sometimes uh like with
different chemical applications, you
need to allow it to like either fully
dry in the air be so so it has the full
effect. You know, I rinse it with water,
but I have uh many times forgotten
like stone and you're like, "Oh, well, I
forgot." And but they they still do
great. Cool. No, that's great to hear. U
I feel like some people think that
bleach is the the complete enemy of a
grow, but in a lot of ways, it's
probably one of your best friends to
make sure that things stay clean and
Yeah. It's the enemy of your clothes.
The clothes. Yeah. Yes. Fashion. Yes.
Enemy for sure.
Yes. And I And even with things like um
hypocchloric acid, it still has the the
chlorine molecule in it. So that it's uh
it'll test for on chlorine strips at the
same, you know, in the same way that
bleach would, but bleach just is that uh
hypocchlorite rather than um
hypocchlorous, which it seems to be as
though the hypocchlorous acid has a
little bit more of a gentler effect on
biologicals, but um still makes the the
surroundings sterile.
Yeah. Yeah. And so unfortunately like
sterile generally means that you're
killing, you know, it's usually fungus
and bacteria, right? And that's that's
actually a lot of the pathogens that
you're going to need to worry about,
especially the fungus. Um, vyroids are
weird. They're they don't have um an
outside coat. They don't have any lipids
or fats or proteins associated. It's
just genetic information. And so the
stuff that will work to decontaminate
vibroids is the the list is very tiny.
Um there's bleach obviously which
thankfully is super easy to find
everywhere and cheap. And cheap. Yeah.
Um and you know you're diluting it 1 to
10. So it's one part bleached, nine
parts water. So you're going to use it
pretty slowly. Um or that Verircon 2%
although I do like to tell people it's
only one study that that was shown to be
effective. That doesn't mean it's
effective in all vibroids, but the the
doesn't have nearly as much data as
bleach does. Bleach has like it's
basically the positive control in all
studies. Like if somebody wants to try
something new, they're like, "Well,
bleach should work for sure. Does it
work as well as bleach?" Um, and so um
it it's it's important to remember that
that one is the most effective for um
for decontaminating stuff. For sure. I I
I always suggest a 10% bleach solution
for anybody. Um that it is just it is
it's cheap, it's accessible. Um you
know, I always tell people to make sure
that they're soaking their cutting
scissors in a 10% bleach solution and
making sure that they sit there for a
minute. Uh if you're not like agitating
them, you know, vigorously. Uh and I I
believe that I've learned that from you
through the um uh We the Growers
podcast. Uh it was very informative uh
information that you gave people there.
Um and would you mind touching briefly
on why people shouldn't use alcohol to
um try to help prevent the spread of
vyroids? Yes, absolutely. Um so
alcohol's uh mechanism of action is
going to be to um dehydrate proteins.
And so, um, people use like isopropyl
alcohol and stuff, you know, like it's
hand sanitizer. Um, and that works fine
for viruses, um, and bacteria. Although,
I'll be honest, it doesn't it's not
amazing, but it does work. Um, the
problem with vyroids is because they are
just naked genetic information, um,
nothing in the mechanism of action of
alcohol works at all. Um, and actually,
um, alcohol stabilizes, uh,
genetic information and so using alcohol
actually will stabilize vibroids um and
make it easier to infect the next plant.
Um so there was one study where they I
think this was using potato spindle
tuber vyroid but it has the same
structure as
hoplenyroid. Um and they basically uh
took the infected scissors and dipped it
in water and then cut the next plant and
the transmission rate was like 70%. But
if they dipped it in alcohol, it went up
to 90 to 95% transmission. Wow. Um, so
you're actually you're pedaling
backwards by using alcohol. So just
don't use that. Um, it doesn't work at
all on vibroids. It just makes it worse.
Or the flame torch, which Yes. And flame
doesn't even work on vibroids. They've
done that experiment as well. So um,
which is amazing. They're that is crazy.
Tough little buggers vibroids. They're
it's wild. They're very stable. Is there
a heat threshold for for um destruction
of a vyroid or can they withstand
basically any heat that we would be able
to apply to them? Um so there is a heat
threshold. I believe it was 140 degrees
Celsius.
That's really hot. I don't know what
that is in Fahrenheit, but um it was
like almost 300 degrees. Yeah. But um
they did do, for example, a pro a
propane blow torch that did not cut it.
So, um, they're very heat stable. So, I
would, you know, bleach is so easy. It's
so accessible, it's so cheap, and it
works like that. So,
um, I just recommend that to people
because I don't have investment in a
bleach company, but work. There's just
so much data. I'm like, this just works.
So, for sure. Um, well, that's that's
great information for people because I
feel like the uh, you know, a lot of
people will just be like, "I have
alcohol for my scissors because I use it
to clean off all the the gunk when I'm
trimming my weed." And um, so I'm just
going to use that to spray everything
down. It smells like alcohol. How can it
not be clean?
Um, but it it's very important to know
that it will help even spread the
pathogen further. Um, and I believe I've
even heard before that it's used uh in
like in vitro um reproduction of vyroids
like you can use alcohol to kind of help
proliferate their spread um within the
alcohol or maybe it was just that it
would spread easier if then applied to a
plant. Uh yeah, so I mean alcohol is
used frequently in the lab um to help
precipitate. So you can take um like
genetic information can actually become
like a solid and you can precipitate it
into like a little like particulates at
the bottom of the tube. Um and alcohol
helps with that process. Um and it's it
makes them very stable. So if you if you
store them in alcohol in the freezer,
they they last much longer than if you
stored them in water. And so that's why
that's why it helps to transmit it
because it makes them more stable and it
kind of helps them precipitate into
these little particulates. Yeah. It
concentrates it. So um yeah, it's it's
it's a no-go for for vibroids. But they
don't replicate in the alcohol. No, no,
no, no. They require like like Alfonso
was saying, they require that machine
that exists inside the cell. So they
actually have to be in this in in a
living cell in order to replicate. Got
it. Okay. That all great information. Um
so uh I mean we've talked about bleach,
we've talked about the vercon.
Um and those are just kind of the
chemical ways of destroying or
potentially destroying the um the
vyroid. Uh, are there any other
practices that home growers
um might might uh use to help prevent uh
pathogens or um help uh prevent the
spread? And then also uh in that same
line of thought, uh what are some of the
treatments that people can use?
Um yeah, so I mean I would recommend
starting from the beginning. Um, if you
bring something new into your facility
or or into your basement, um, you need
to have a quarantine area. So, that can
just be the corner like underneath a
lamp with a bench or a little tent or
something. Um, and make sure that you
put that plant there and it has a
separate set of tools. You use gloves
when you're messing with it. Um, and um,
test that plant. Um, test it at the
minimum for hot plate and vibrate. And I
would test it if for serarium as well.
If you want, you can test for pytheium
also. Um, those three are going to give
you misery if you find them. Um, do not
put them next like in the tent with your
favorite strains until you make sure
that that plant isn't infected. Um,
generally I would recommend two tests
about uh 2 to 3 weeks apart just in case
the vyroid was at a very low level in
the beginning. Um, and this is just
really important when you're bringing in
new genetics into a place where you know
it's clean. Um, while you're waiting,
obviously you want to be looking for
bugs, um, any kind of weird
discoloration, any other funky symptoms
that you're like, "Oh, okay. I don't
really want my plants to have that." Um,
and so just be just be scouting those
new clones. Um once you put it into, you
know, the tent or or the mom room or
whatever, um you want to be just very
careful, especially with your mother
plants, um it's always good to wear
gloves. Um you can, like Fono was
saying, you can have vibrate on your
hands if you're smoking or grinding. You
can also have like fungus, bacteria, and
you just don't want to be touching your
plants with your naked hands. Um, if you
like to garden outside, which I do and
it's awesome, but like things like
ferium, pytheium, and other kinds of
molds like, you know, betritis and all
sorts of nasty stuff is outside. So, if
you're coming into your grow in your
basement or in your into your facility,
you need to be aware that it could be on
your gardening clothes. It can be on the
bottom of your shoes. So, um, just throw
on like if you just get a a lab coat or
even, you know, change your shoes out
like Mr. Rogers before you go down
there, something like that, so you're
not bringing stuff in um to your
facility or into your basement. Um and
then as you're working with your plants,
when you you have your gloves on and
you're moving from plant to plant, if
you'd make a 10% bleach solution and put
it in a little spray bottle, then you
know, you can be like trimming or
whatever with a plant. You're going to
put your scissors in the 10% bleach.
Just spray some on your hands and rub it
around. Um and then you shake it like
that. It's okay to touch the plants with
the 10% bleach. That concentration isn't
going to hurt them. Um, and that's to
just sort of clean them so you're you're
not the big vector there transferring it
from plant to plant. Um, it's important
to remember the roots have a very high
level. So, ideally, um, your plants,
especially if there's water at the
bottom of your tent or they're on a
table and there's runoff, they're
elevated a little bit so the roots
aren't sitting in that runoff water
because you can transfer it through the
water. Um goes for fungal pathogens. Um
and remember things like clonal trays or
if you want to do a flood and drain or
something like that, that's another big
transmission risk for um hop late and
vyroid. Um, and then, um, obviously
insects. There's just information coming
out right now from CSU showing that, um,
uh, I believe it was aphids they found.
But kind of any insect that's going to
chew up and get on the sap, like on
their mouth parts or whatever, and then
they go to another plant, you could
transfer it like that as well. Or pets.
Yes. Worried. Cats. My cats like to chew
on the leaves and I there's not any data
out there, but I can just see if my cat
is chewing on the leaf and then it's
going to chew on the other one. It could
It makes sense, right? And then another
thing that I seen that happened,
although there's no data to it, but one
time we had like a plant which was
negative and a plant that was positive
right next to each other and we were
using it to test um just as our controls
for the lab. And we noticed that one day
they got fungus
nets and all of the sudden the the
negative plant was positive. Sure. So
the fungus nuts has
this stage in which they're when they're
before flying they they they leave in
the soil and and they feed on the roots.
So that's I think like a way for the
vyroid to to get wings and just fly to
the other side. Sure. I've I've heard it
uh be transmitted with root aphids as
well. Um, yeah, any anything like that,
it it I mean they unless they're
producing some sort of chemical in their
body that's going to destroy the vyroid.
Um, but as we've previously discussed,
there's not a lot of those chemicals
that we can even use in a lab setting.
Um, and so I it's doubtful that the bugs
are producing uh chlorine in their
bodies.
Um so yeah I' I've heard that before
that um uh pathogen pressures can
definitely increase with uh pest
pressures because of the the
transmittability through the the the
pest being the vector.
Um let's see. Are there are there any
other vectors that you that you feel
like growers should be aware of that um
we may not have touched on yet?
Um, see, mechanical is going to be the
most common way. Um, you know, seed,
it's possible. Um, so you should
definitely be testing seed. Um, and like
I said, one seed from a seed packet if
if all those seeds came from the same
mother is sufficient really to determine
whether or not they're infected. Um,
insects are definitely a possibility.
Water transmission is real and there's
plenty of data to support that now. So,
you need to be thinking about that.
um you know roots touch each other like
if you have things super super close
together and the roots are like kissing
that's a possibility too. It's not the
same with the foliage. If the foliage is
really close as long as there's no
breakage um where there's like sap
transfer between two like wounds or
micro wounds um you're okay there. Um
and and Alfonso was saying um you know
other other things you don't think about
like your pets, your cats um and and
anything you bring it in from the
outside. Remember that weeds are vectors
too for a lot of people. I have a
quicken um yes and it does it is in the
pollen as well. So um be careful with
that too. I I do have a question about
the foliage. Um, is there any potential
for it to be released through the
moisture that the as the stamata are
sort of uh transpiring? Because I know
that, you know, sometimes you get the
leaves that will overlap, let's say,
from two plants that are next to each
other and when you pull them apart,
it'll be a nice wet layer on both the
top and the bottom of the leaf that
we're touching. Um, now that's not
necessarily a wound, but it could be
considered like a a transfer of fluids.
Um is there any potential there for
uh the vyroid to transfer?
Yeah, so there's no evidence that it can
transfer um like you know with
respiration byproducts or whatever for
plants. Um it's it's mostly going to be
contained you know within the cells of
the plant and in the sap which is kind
of how it travels around. Um and but if
there's little cuts on both of those
leaves and it we're not talking about
like you know half the leaf is missing.
it can be really like microscopic.
That's sufficient to transfer it between
those two leaves.
Great information. Um yeah, it's just
prepping people for uh being able to
look at this stuff with an educated eye.
feel like is so important because um you
know I I've now kind of busted one of my
own myths that I had uh heard where it
doesn't necessarily need to have like
the the sap like the phm or the xyllem
transfer uh but it could just be like a
contact transfer which um that's really
good to hear that that's not necessarily
an easy way for that to occur uh if at
all possible. Um, so keeping yeah,
plants elevated. I love that idea,
especially for drain tables where in
facilities there's a lot of um times
where I've seen, you know, based on the
construction of those uh drain tables
there may be a dip in them where it does
build up a little water, but it's not
too much to where you're creating like
um hypoxic environments within the root
zone. You're just, you know, giving them
a little bit extra water compared to all
the other plants that are on that table.
um and they're still using it up, but it
is then at that point transferring
between three or four plants or
something that are in that that dip in
the table. Um I I will say one of the
biggest I think details that a lot of
growers miss is um the rooting gel when
people are cloning. Um a lot of times
they'll dip that clone. They're super
careful about everything and then
they'll cut clones and everybody gets
dipped in the same shot glass. like you
know 100 plants same shot glass um but
that is a gaping wound a clone you dip
it in that shot glass and it becomes
like a little hop and brood inoculum and
you're basically inoculating every
single clone as you go through your
process um so be really careful like
thinking like that like what am I
sharing between these plants and is
there you know either something that
comes in contact with the roots or or
like clonal gel that I'm sharing and
even though I'm really careful I'm I'm
infecting all of these clones by using
the same gel for each clone. Um yeah,
and growing media is the same issue. Um
we had one grower submit their growing
media that they were reusing the cocoa
and it tested positive. Um
so I I would recommend not reusing it.
If you do choose to reuse it, you should
sterilize it. Again, 10% bleach. Um I'd
probably give it a good 10-minute soak
just u to kill off anything else that
might be in there. and then rinse it
really well. Um but um yeah, reusing
stuff between plants, you got to think
about that. Pots, tools, growing media,
everything can transfer. Composting.
Some people
compost. Oh, this plant is doesn't look
healthy. I'm going to compost it. But
that's like the worst you could do.
Yeah. And then reusing it on the healthy
ones. That's Yeah. Sure. Oh, that's a
great that's a great point. Um, I've
heard in in like living soil bed systems
that that's also one of the the, you
know, kind of the death death touches to
those beds is if you have hops and
vyroid because typically you're leaving
some level of root mass behind when
you're um transplanting with new plants
for another cycle. Um, are there any
ways to
potentially kill off the vyroid in
living soil beds or other um, substrates
that are reused? Uh, cuz I know that
sometimes that can be a significant
investment for even a home grower. Um,
if they're doing like a small 4x4 or a
2x4 fabric bed and they buy all this
soil to fill it or they spend all this
time to create their own soil at home.
Uh yeah. Are there any
potentially are there any ways that you
can potentially remove the vyroid from
the soil? I guess. Yeah. I mean, I I've
had this conversation with lots of
growers that have this really awesome
living soil that they've been they've
had for years and they've worked on it
and it's really wonderful and rich, but
uh unfortunately any treatment that's
going to remove the vibroid is going to
destroy everything that you love about
your living soil in the first place. Um,
so what about leaving it untouched for
like a year? Yeah, it's I mean I don't
the studies on what how long I think
it's 6 months. So maybe you can let it
sit for a very long time. Um, I'd be I'd
be wary. I'd want to test it just to be
sure before you reuse it. But I mean,
honestly, the best way to protect your
living's soil is don't just don't plant
anything in there until you test it
first. Like don't don't go backwards and
be like, "Oh, I've planted something
with positive in my living soil and that
this was so important." Like put it in
quarantine, test it twice, and then put
it in your living soil. Um and then you
don't have to worry about it because
it's not positive. So yeah, that's the
best way to go about it. Yeah. And I it,
you know, in my mind I'm thinking even
if you let it sit for a long time, um if
there's any root mass left, then there's
still potential for the vyroid to
replicate, right? And so the 6 month
mark is probably after the last
replication occurs. And so if you have
food for it basically in there for a
couple years, then you're still looking
at like a couple years plus 6 months at
that point for it to potentially be um
okay. And maybe there's even a little
pocket of other
uh biological material in there that it
can latch on to and and continue to
proliferate. Um, are are there other
Sorry. Are there other Go ahead. Sorry.
Are there are there other biological
tissues that it could latch on to to
continue to replicate itself other than
um plant plant matter like So yeah. So
so it can't it's not going to be able to
replicate in dead tissue per se um
because it it requires a living cell and
it has to go it has to go into this
special place in the cell called the
nucleus. So once the tissue is dead
dead, it's not going to be replicating
necessarily. Um, we have to remember
though, it's not alive like the way we
think of like a fungus or something
being alive. Um, it's it's almost like a
toxin. It's like inert. So once it's if
it's there, it just hangs out waiting to
be rehydrated and uptook by a living
cell and then it just does its thing
again. Um, so really what you're
fighting is how stable is this? How much
thyroid is in my living soil? And how
long do I have to wait until it actually
degrades? And the the answers to all of
those questions aren't known. Um, the
one thing that has been shown for a
vyroid similar to hoplenyroid called hop
stunt vyroid is that it can be taken up
by fungal pathogens and replicated
inside of those. So um if there's like
fuserium or maybe I mean we don't know
all the pathogens or organisms this
could happen. They could even be like
you know indifitzer or you know other
types of living things in the soil. They
may take up the vyroid and keep it
replicating until you plant new things
in there. So,
um, it's really one of those things
like, you know, your living soil makes
your plants really awesome and you've
worked very difficult on it, but if
there's something in there that is just
going to make everything tank, then it
it's not worth keeping cuz you know, you
you have it because they make your
plants successful, but keeping the soil
at some point if it's infected works the
opposite way.
Yeah. I guess it's like
um if uh you know if you you invested
all this time into it typically a lot of
people when they've had you know a
living soil bed for a couple years um
but that investment might not
necessarily be worth uh the pains that
you will then face from hotlen fire or
or fuserium or something along those
lines. Um, so that, you know, it's it's
kind of one of those tough answers that
I feel like people do need to hear that
it it might just not be worth it. You
know, no matter how much time you let it
sit there, there's there's potentials
and um opportunities for it to be an
issue in the future. Um, so that's
that's good. It is, like I said, it's
that's that's a tough one though. I
could only imagine having a whole
facility go
down, you know, 100 light room all in
living soil beds. That would be
devastating. Um, yeah. No, absolutely.
It's it's one of those really hard
things to to mitigate, you know, and
fuserium is worse to be honest. It in
out in the field the spores can last
like 3 to 5 years and if you're you're
in like a a more protected environment,
it's they can last up to 10. So, it's
just it's just not something that you
want to mess with. Um,
so, wow. I did not know that they could
last 10 years in an indoor environment.
That is frightening. It is. It's
terrifying. And that's why, you know, I
mean, hoping vibra is an insidious
pathogen. It can sneak into your grow.
It can spread everywhere. But, um,
fuserium is devastating. If if it really
takes hold, it kills thing. It can kill
an entire room in like a week. And the
plants are just dead. And then they like
melt into the table. Exactly. And it
it's it gets in the water system. It
gets the growing media and it can go
airborne and then you're just looking
at, you know, like a nuclear option. So
you really want to test for that. You do
not want that to be in your facility or
your basement um at all. Awesome. Yeah,
that's that I mean that's not awesome,
but it's awesome for people to know that
that is uh can be more devastating. Um
you know it's it's kind of the unspoken
vyroid that a lot of pe or uh pathogen
that people don't really talk about too
much because when it does happen it is
just kind of like well I guess the
game's over at this point.
Um, so, um, you know, we did touch
briefly on tissue culture before, uh,
and how that can be an option to help,
uh, either potentially remove, uh,
vyroids or other pathogens from a plant.
Um, but are there any other uh points on
tissue culture that you feel like people
should be aware of? Um, do you want to
take that? Um well specifically
especially like remembering that it's
not
100% that it doesn't work like that and
um it could it could be expensive
uh to do that if you have several
genetics strains that you have to clean
up.
But also it does it does work in the in
other crops I guess protected like in
similar to in grown in green houses
um they they use it successfully there
and uh but I'm sure that it is attached
to a testing protocol. So like the
tissue culture has to be tested for sure
to know that the the the culturing of
those cells was successful without any
pathogens.
For sure. Um I do I do like that there
are a lot of practices within tissue
culture that um within aseptic technique
that kind of allow for you to help
mitigate the transfer of pathogens. um
like even within like let's say you have
something in tissue culture that does
carry a pathogen with it um you have a
lot more fail safes and uh and stops in
place to help prevent the transfer of it
to other uh tissue culture that you're
working with at the time. And then if
you can prove that you have no pathogen
or vyroid in that uh in that plant
tissue, then you can proliferate it from
that small amount of plant matter into a
much larger population to then help um
provide that genetic uh cultivar to
other people um in a very safe way as
long as it's, you know, not entering a
facility that already has a bunch of
these problems and isn't going through
some sort of quarantine phase.
Um it I I think that tissue culture has
a lot of potential uh at least
especially within pathogen prevention
and um
remediation. Well, you know, this has
been a wonderful conversation, guys, and
I feel like uh we we've gotten a lot of
information out there to people that
they can kind of make actionable within
their own gardens, which is very
important to me. Um, but I do like to
kind of wrap these up uh as a cannabis
podcast with a little bit more cannabis
focused questions. So, um, quick
question. Do either of you currently use
cannabis?
I I I tend to be more the edible type,
but um, sure. Oh, well, I mean, edibles
are still, you know, a form of cannabis,
I feel like. But, um, you know,
I, as someone who is also a user of
cannabis, I feel like there's a lot of
there's still a lot of stigma within the
professional world of people using
cannabis and incorporating it into their
professional lives successfully. But um
Alonso, like even with what you said
earlier, it was almost cannabis that
allowed you to um develop all these
different skills because you were able
to finally sit down and open a book and
you know have the attention span. Yeah.
The
stigma that society has created that if
you smoke cannabis you you you must be
lazy or unproductive or unsuccessful.
But I think that's a misunderstanding
and that's not true. It's just probably
something that came out in the dark ages
to you know bring down cannabis and all
these manipulations that the government
have done
or you know I agree wholeheartedly. I
mean I um I think it's so important to
show that uh professionals you know of
your caliber both of you being doctors
are pro cannabis that's something that I
feel like uh it opens up the door to
more people who want to enter the
different STEM fields but might think
that their passion for cannabis or um
you know other other illicits
like magic mushrooms for example and how
many potential um benefits there are to
the different alkaloid components within
mushrooms. Um you know and and then with
cannabis it you know people think that
that's their barrier to entry that
that's what they want to study um or
that they want to make sure that that's
continuing to be incorporated in their
life whether it be through a a medical
application or a recreational
application. I mean, no one tests you if
you drank alcohol the night before when
you come in to work the next day, but
that can be devastating for a heavy
workload. You're going to come in and be
more fuzzy and hazy and uh with less
ability to do things than if you smoked
a nice joint the night before. Yeah. But
I I would like to add that cannabis
research is is in infancy, like it's
just starting.
And if smoking cannabis uh does not give
you this effect that it doesn't make you
like productive or it it takes you the
other way, maybe cannabis is not for
you. There's different diseases out
there that are coming out that are
potentially death threatening that that
people are not aware. And it's just like
it's just depending on your genetics.
Not everybody is get affected by it
because as we all know we we are our
cells are covering these receptors for
canabonoids and it might be that your
genetic makeup is not conducive to that
and you should be aware of that too.
Sure. I mean there's even things like
the cannabis hyperis syndrome um where
that can be devastating to someone's
entire life and uh it it is all as far
as we know up to this point cannabis
induced and um related. So it
I absolutely agree. I mean, just like
with anything else in life, some people
have a tolerance for it and some people
don't. And some people can, you know,
some people can be functioning
alcoholics and and do amazing work while
completely uh you know, at the bottom of
the of the barrel. Um, and so it it is
very much independent uh or subjective
in in a sense where you need to make
sure that you can handle it. Yeah. I'm
sorry, say that again. be careful and be
smart. I'm saying to the people that
want to use cannabis and
and in in in or or want to or want to
follow what I'm saying it is like what
my life experience was like that but I
do have friends that is the opposite and
sure and and you have to learn to listen
to your body and what is it telling you.
Sure. And because cannabis is also, you
know, it's not a it's not an aspirin and
it's not um like a typical
pharmaceutical where there's one
component that's the active ingredient
that's going to have a very universal
response across most humans. Where
cannabis, you know, it has different
tarpin profiles, different cannabonoid
profiles, uh other volatile organic
compounds. Um, and all of those kind of
play together and uh can cause vastly
different responses. It's sort of why so
many people say, you know, they love
cannabis because variety is the spice of
life and they can have a huge variety of
different experiences all from
technically this the same plant. Um,
just different different genetic
expressions within that plant.
Um so yeah I think that that's a very
good point to bring up that it it's not
a universal
uh you know we we shouldn't put it in a
good bad dichconomy. Uh it it is uh very
much uh very much subjective and
everyone can have a unique experience
using cannabis.
Um so you know just a couple more
questions for you guys but um and and
take this one in whichever way you want.
uh Alfonso, you uh having grown cannabis
and Tessa, you having researched plenty
of cannabis, but is there a favorite
cultivar that either of you have
encountered either uh through research
where maybe it is just, you know, it it
never catches hops and thyroid or it
never has an issue if it does have it or
maybe through the growth characteristics
of how it grows. Um, if there's
something that you find extremely
uh favorable for your own desires.
Yeah, I I I prefer the old school what
they people call the old school strains.
Old the OG strains. Yeah. Like the
Northern Lights number five or AK-47.
Those are my favorite. But but recently,
not that long ago, I brought uh some
seats um from back home.
um some some land races that grow in the
mountains of Peru. And I actually love
it. It is kind of
um similar to having a glass of wine.
It's not like very potent like in the
THC kind of probably probably one to one
THC CBD probably one of those things. Uh
very mellow and
[Music]
very active. you you you want to do
things. You you you want to get the next
thing done, the next thing done. And
yeah, I really like like land races is
strange. It's just the flowering time is
like 95 days or something like Oh my
god. But that's crazy. Yeah. But I I I
love that. like I I I'm not a very I
don't like the the strains that are high
in in THC
or I prefer the the the other
way. I'm just getting older. So, no, I I
think that it it has a lot of benefit
for people, especially when you do find
like a true onetoone uh THC CBD. Those
tend to work really well for people that
have like high anxiety or um you know,
the their attention span might need to
be, you know, tweaked in one way or the
other. Um I feel like those always tend
to work fairly well for people. Um but
you you know you can never really find a
95day cultivar on the commercial market
because it would be um you can't charge
more for something that you grow longer,
right? It's uh and so it then becomes
that much more expensive to create that
final product. So I always say for home
growers, they should absolutely try
growing out um something that's like an
equatorial strain because they will
never experience that to its fullest
potential unless they grow it
themselves. Um and uh and so Tassa um uh
yeah so I your your favorite cultivar.
Yeah. Um to smoke um I don't have as
many cultivars in my pocket as Alonso
here. I actually don't know anyone that
has as many cultivars in this pocket as
him. But um um I tend to favor the ones
grown outside. I haven't read any of
that literature and I don't understand
like why that is um or what the
scientific basis of it is, but um um
they tend to make me less anxious. Um
and I also prefer the ones where there's
a little bit less THC. Um I and then the
you know I take gummies sometimes um if
I like like my brain is spinning at
night and I can't sleep. Um, and they've
actually been like gamechanging for me
cuz you know if you take a benadryil or
something, the next day it's like
somebody hit you in the head with a 2x4
for like hours. Um, but you know, you
can take a gummy and um, the next day
you just fall asleep great and the next
day you wake up and you're just feeling
good and you're ready for the day. And
um you know to me it's it's phenomenal
that there's a stigma around that
because it's just so much more gentle um
and effective than all the stuff that
you could get at the doctors if you're
like oh I can't fall asleep. They're
like you know here's an ambient and
you're just I can't remember what I did
last night.
Well, um but yeah, and then um from the
science side, um I don't remember all of
the strains, but I do remember one
specific one called Motorhead, um that
we had an incredibly difficult time
infecting with hot plate and vyroid. Um
you know, it it it built the level super
low. you know, we I think we inoculated
15 clones and something like two of them
had a very very low almost undetectable
level and it took like entire flowering
um time frame in order for it to build
up enough vyroid you know for it to be
like a reasonable level. So, um, from
the science side, like that one was a
pretty good one. When it comes to, uh,
resist or, yes, to resistance, um,
tolerance, Illuminati tended to be it
would it it got infected like that and
built up a super high load, but it did
not show any symptoms. Um, wow. That
would be your your Trojan horse strain
to watch out for. Now, I will qualify
that with that was that specific
motorhead and that specific Illuminati.
And as we all know, you could go and buy
those strains and they may behave
completely differently because um they
have the same name, but genetically
they're not, you know, the same plant.
And so do be careful. For sure. Yeah.
There's a a lot of I feel like uh
confusion through the way that seeds are
marketed within the cannabis industry.
And um so usually when I refer to like a
single plant, I'll refer to it as a
cultivar like with uh normal
agriculture. And um then a seed would be
like a genetics, right? Or or or a cross
or a uh um a strain perhaps uh if you
want to go down that path. But um yeah,
I feel like that's that's good
information to have people, you know, it
the fact that there are the abilities
for plants to com completely almost like
ignore the fact that the vyroid's even
present and uh uptakeable by the plant.
It'll be nope. I'm don't really care to
have that whatever mechanism of action
it is that's causing it to not be
uptook. That's just very special in and
of itself. And then also the fact that
you can have a ridiculously high
threshold of viral pres or vyroid
presence within the the tissue and that
it just doesn't even affect the
flowering time or the the yield or um
the final product. That's amazing. Um,
yeah, it's a very it's very cool and
it's it's a place of super interesting
research because if you could figure out
the gene or genes that keep the vyroid
that that are that are involved in
transmitting it around the plant like
the transport or the replication then
you know maybe you can breathe that in
to the strains that you like and just
kind of create a bunch of resistant
things. So, it's definitely something
that, you know, if I had like clones of
myself, I would be doing those
experiments all the time,
for sure. Um, all right. And then last
question for both of you. Uh, what is
your most memorable cannabis related
experience, whether it be something in
the lab or even a a personal use
experience or or otherwise? Uh,
um, that's a hard question. Yeah, it's
you know I I figured it would be kind of
one of the harder questions that I
asked.
Lucky maybe you can start. I can think.
Um yeah, I mean I guess you know I
honestly like from the lab standpoint
the most the most memorable one was
after you know two months of frustration
being like boy where I've designed
hundreds of PCRs like what's wrong with
me? realizing that the plants we have at
home are actually positive and that's
why we can't get the test to work and
that's why the weed sucked for so many
years was um pretty pretty memorable
from a science standpoint um and kind of
cool in a sense because you're like oh
my god how many people are struggling
with the same problem we are and you
know we're scientists we had no idea
that this was even there um you know and
then from a personal standpoint you know
I guess I we I'm probably one of those
people that Alfonso cautions about when
it comes to smoking cuz um I definitely
can't have a big joint and go to the lab
that I would maybe I'd have fun but I
don't think smart would come out of me
at all. Um you know and there's
definitely strains that I have to be
careful with because I get you know
anxious or freak out or you know so
those are those are memories. Maybe
they're not good ones per se, but um um
but I, you know, did the discovery of
edibles and being able to fall asleep at
night when I'm feeling anxious and just
having that just I mean get like the
medicinal like I don't get high or
anything. I just fall asleep and then
the next day is pleasant for me. Like um
it's been a huge thing for me in my life
and and I'm I'm glad to be alive at a
time when I could use that legally to
feel better. So that's awesome. Yeah.
For me, I don't have a specific thing
that I could
remember. Uh, but I do like the social
aspect of cannabis that um it doesn't
matter if you talk English or whatever
language or whatever background or race
or religion you are. You just smoking a
joint together. you're like um it's kind
of like feels connected
and you share things and I don't know
it's something like
brings you humble and
uh listen listening and understanding
other opinions and I think it's the
social aspect for me is is something big
for sure. Yeah. sharing a a joint or
something is a great equalizer um across
all different barriers that you might
face otherwise um social or economic or
status based. You know, if you light up
a nice joint and people smell it and uh
and u want to hang out and smoke, it's
it's easy. And then you like talking and
and you get to know this person and
where they coming from, their
experiences
and it is great. It
is equality for you know for
for everyone. Oh I love it. Well again
guys this has been a wonderful uh
conversation uh Tessa Alons. So I really
appreciate your time. I know that you go
both are probably extremely busy um with
how many different grows and operations
you must be serving at this point, but
um yeah, this has been great. And you
know, this this podcast uh is designed
to help people learn new processes uh or
help perfect other processes that they
have. And I feel like we've provided a
lot of information today that will allow
them to take a look at uh some of the
the cultural practices of their grow
operation and potentially prevent
massive issues from arising in the
future. As well as, you know, maybe take
that first step and get some of their
plants tested that they haven't uh been
doing yet and kind of been putting off
because of uh financial or um
stubbornness or otherwise. Um, so yeah,
this has been great and uh I really
appreciate your time. Of course. Yeah.
No, absolutely. Thank you so much for
having us on. It was Thanks very much.
Awesome. Always a pleasure to share. Y
All right. Well, you know, getting this
information out there, uh, like I like
to say is how we grow the community and
that's the way we grow. So again, thank
you guys. Thank you. All right. Byebye.
[Music]
Bye. Hey. Hey. Hey.