this episode of gabbing with Gabby is
brought to you by the Breeders direct
Seed Company in my opinion the Breeders
direct seed company is your Premier
Source for clones and seeds and they are
the only place that you can get the
Gabby Staten Island collection so visit
breeders direct for all your seed and
clone needs
[Music]
what's up everybody this is Gabby Staten
Island with another episode of your weed
stories this week we've got our special
guest Boston Bob um before we start I
just want to say a couple of
words um we're recording this on New
Year's
Eve and
I had gotten a message from
Bob that he wanted or that he enjoyed
the show and that you know if we wanted
to have him on the show that uh he'd
love to do it and when I asked him a
little background about himself and I'm
going to read this he says I'm a hobby
breeder I release seeds through FCP with
all proceeds going to Peter for the good
work he does been doing podcasts for a
couple years main focus is on projects
and methodology I tried to share for
small Growers um he'll said I smoked in
the 70s hint at my age U my first IG
account closed two years ago with 900
picks and 15,000
followers and so the first thing I
thought to myself was you know this is
great because I've been having some
major players on the show like um Kevin
JRE and Michael will seagull who I think
is super important and I wanted to try
to have some
smaller um
more I would say you know regular people
doing the show so we agreed and we
scheduled it then yesterday I called Bob
up you know just to SK you know talk a
little bit before the um the podcast
today and I didn't want to get too much
information um because I like to be
surprised when I do the podcasts I like
my reactions to be genuine I don't want
him to retell a story but he did start
to tell me a few
things and I have to say I was just
blown away and while um Bob may not be
as well known as Kevin JRE or some of
the other people that were going going
to interview on this
podcast he seems like an amazing person
with a compelling story and so I know
you guys are going to enjoy it Bob is a
professional and he does not um he does
not sell cannabis everything that he
grows he gives away and because he's a
professional he wants to stay Anonymous
so we are not going to show Bob's face
on this podcast unfortunately for you
guys you're going to have to look at my
ugly mug this entire show so if you're
wondering why you can't see Bob that's
why and with that um Boston Bob tell us
your weed
story first of all thank you for nice
introduction um and a pleasure to be on
the show with you today
Gabby so where do I start you you want
you I would like you to start with your
first cannabis exper experiences you
know when you first started smoking when
you first started growing you know funny
stories about your past and cannabis and
then you know we can work towards the
cool things you're doing today with
breeding and you know I don't want to
give up too much yeah and then we'll get
it to males because I like how we we
started like we started and stopped that
conversation yeah we're going to the
conversation will will weave in that out
wherever you want so I guess the very
beginning um I probably SM not probably
cuz I know I did I smoked weed in
1970 so I was in seventh
grade I was in private
school and uh it was more a school
for wealthy
delinquents so and my parents didn't
have money so my grandparents paid and I
get sent to private school and I smoked
weed in seventh
grade and
actually uh I got
caught I got
suspended I told my mother it's the
first time I have a smoke pot and I
can't believe I got caught the first
time uh I went back to that school and
then in eighth
grade I got caught again with four other
people
they let the other four people back into
school and I got kicked out
permanently and I told my mother I can't
believe only the second time I smoked
pot I got caught
again so I'm I'm thinking she probably
didn't believe it but you know I was a
kid was it true no absolutely
not I was smoking weed all the time um
it it it was a very early introduction
so and back in those days
we weren't even getting really brick
weed um we got Panama red and aaoca gold
those are probably the two main
strains or they didn't even have names
for strains back then but we were
smoking Panama Red aapco Gold on
occasion if stuff was really dry you'd
get some brick weed but brick weed for
me uh didn't come till later so we
always smoked pretty good weed and back
in the day
uh at least on the East Coast it was
called a lid and it was either
four-finger lid or a FiveFinger lid and
for me it was 15 bucks cuz it was Panama
Red and that's what we smoked so that
was the beginning for me
um and then you know going through high
school and that kind of stuff and then
out of high school and into my
20s I think for a while I was a pretty
good wake and
Baker um
yeah I think another turning point was I
think I was
a sophomore in high school so that would
have been about
74 I bought my first
pound uh it was Mexican brick I paid $90
for the
pound so um that that was my Early
Adventures as a young age and I smoked
quite a bit and and then frankly in my
mid 20s I I kind of get out of it and I
was out of the game for 25
years um you stopped smoking Canabis for
25 years I smoke a couple times a year
that was it but I went I literally went
from you know I'd smoke in bed before I
got out of bed and then in my mid 20s it
was um I I had different focuses and I
just kind of gradually stopped smoking
wheat and back in you know when I was in
high school I had some plants in a
closet you know who who knows if I even
knew what 1212 meant back then um but I
was trying to grow weed and I grew it in
in the in my basement Closet in in my
mother's house what year was this
approximately oh 74 and
75 and what were you using for light oh
just a flour just a
lamp just just a lamp hung upside down
in the closet keeping it on I mean I
honestly I don't even remember smoke any
of it I just remember trying to grow it
get it in the closet
um you know cuz there was always seeds
right you you you any weed you got had
seeds in it I think the other thing that
I remember and I remember this very
distinctly CU it was
probably
1971 or
72 I smoked my first
cinia didn't have a name the only thing
that today that I can think of that
looks like it is like Fruity Pebbles
like it looked like Fruity Pebbles all
the other stuff was you know Panama Red
was dark green with a little bit of red
hint the aaoca gold was you know green
gold weed it it was always pretty
consistent in terms of the color through
the whole bag and then somebody got this
weed and all we called it it was just
called camir at the time and it was had
some Reds in it had a little bit of
yellows and greens I I mean it was
really goodlook weed it was very upwe it
wasn't indicia so you know worst case it
was a sativa hybrid back then and the
only thing we knew was it came from the
Pacific Northwest so that was the first
time I ever smoked Cinema had no
obviously no seeds in it the weed was
unbelievable I still remember it today
um yeah it was really really nice and
that was it's either the end of 71 or
the beginning of 72
so that was a big change for
me so then I guess my real
reintroduction was
probably 10 years ago 2014 2015 I was
out in Denver I forget the name of the
dispensary but I bought a strain called
Cindy
White
and it was unbelievable weat just
absolutely loved it up happy High
clear um and it made me
realize that I could grow weed and make
weed in in any direction I wanted
because of the different stuff out there
so that's when I kind of Dove back in so
it's probably been 10 years almost 10
years um and then I just started
collecting I just you know I I did a
bunch of emerald cups and met a whole
bunch of people
uh did
Instagram
um and and really just started
collecting and building a library right
so honestly I probably
have 300
strains and what I do is if I'm bre if
I'm doing breeding or I'm doing a
project they all revolve around a line
or two lines I want to bring together so
I've got this huge library and then in
addition I I'm not even I don't do a ton
of seeds anymore unless I'm doing some
kind of hunt um because somebody else
will have done the work and picked a
really good cultivar so I can use a cut
of that cultivar which we can talk about
a little later on from different people
out in the you know in the community so
somebody else has done that work and
I've done that myself I've I've got a
few strains where you know I find a
really really good plant and I've passed
the P plant out to to a couple people um
like you mentioned before I don't sell
anything so I don't put any restrictions
on it people can do whatever they want
with it good plant's a good plant and I
wouldn't have been able to do some of
the stuff I've done if people didn't
give me good plants so I I I try to keep
that Circle
going um I an interesting story so it's
got to be at least five or six years ago
I'm on Instagram I've got you know
15,000
followers you know a bunch of kids a
bunch of you know it it was a it was a
you know it's a it's a good amount of
following but that was not my intent
like I mentioned to to you the other
day Instagram is my notebook right I'm
getting older and it's easier to forget
so instead of my notepads and in
addition to my notepads where I'm
keeping track of everything and and and
and writing everything down when I do
something I post it on Instagram so it's
a lot easier than digging through
notebooks I just flip back through the
pictures and I'm like okay I did this
then this went in flower then this is
how many days I have left so I I like
Instagram because it's like my video
note or you know actually it is it's my
video notebook but
so uh show the I sent you one picture of
the plant in a
basement it's the last one I sent
um it said I think three number one or
basically it's a it's it's an almost 8ot
plant and that plant is pr1 Panama
Red so what happened is that a male or
is it a female yeah that's a male oh my
God yeah we I we were joke I I I posted
it when when I opened my new Instagram
account a year or two ago I put that as
one of the first pictures um but
what happened with so it's a it won't be
too long
but I was at the emerald Cup in
2016 and spent a bunch of time with John
at snow High
seats and Snow's always had some really
good land race stuff right he he likes
the esoteric long
flowering so you know we we hung out for
a pretty good amount um really enjoyed
talking to him we've done a couple
things back and forth since then but
what he did was he gave me a bud of
Panama
Red and on the bud it ended up I think
there were almost 40 seats so we did one
grow and it was good I mean it wasn't
special but it was good and then we did
another grow and I picked a mail which
was panar red 4 just you know notes for
myself so that I know what I'm doing we
separate the males and we start growing
out the
females and
literally 3 weeks into
flower you know where everything should
be showing and the pistols are coming
and it's you know 3 weeks is pretty good
to Heaven flower we looked at one of the
plants and it was a male so the entire
time the the maale never showed anything
and then finally around the third week
in flower realized there's a male in the
room and it was an absolutely beautiful
plant thought it was going to be a great
girl so what I did is I junked the the
original male that I had selected and
took him and put him in that seller and
that's the picture you have of that male
and that male literally was probably 4
and A2 5 feet tall and if you look at
the plant the top two feet of the plant
this not e this barely any leaves it's
just straight flower I mean it it it
pushed out flowers like you can't
believe I mean we would joking or right
when we collected pollen we collected on
a fulllength mirror like a like the
mirror had to be 5et long right I mean
it was unbeliev all you had to do is
just take the mirror near the plant and
shake the plant I mean I was joking
around at the time that we were
collecting pollen with a shovel I I mean
that so and I probably bred that
plant over the next four or five years
at least a dozen times so something
about that plant is you know it's um the
photo that we have is you know it's it's
not the best photo and it's on Instagram
and you sent a screenshot of it but it
looks like a Christmas tree so like you
know often people will talk about like
you know a female plant that looks like
a Christmas tree this this actually from
this photo it looks like a Christmas
tree um pretty incredible photo yeah I I
kept them I I you know you clone you
know some days you're you feel like all
you're doing is cloning stuff right just
to keep it going but I think I kept him
going for four or five years and
everything I hit the same thing happened
it ended up with more
potency and carrier fene either went to
the top or be became one of the top
couple of turps so all the stuff was had
a little bit of spice in it and it it
wasn't quite pepper but it was more
spice um but it increased the potency I
think in every cross I did you know we
um yeah we hit a bunch of strains I
think I hit five different orange
strains um doesn't seem to didn't seem
to mix too well with some of the
blueberry stuff but it mixed really
really well with the fruit so I kept
most of it on the fruit side cuz then
you get in the spice and the fruit it
was one um called berer which was bag of
oranges from um Randy useful seeds who
um sadly passed away last spring um but
we went through five different orange
drains uh the buer story is kind of
it'll be quick but it's really kind of
funny so well they don't need to be
quick no I know but I I was going off
track I wanted to talk about the pan I
read and and one of the one of the
crosses and one of the interactions on
on Instagram but on the berer so we get
bag of oranges we grow it out um I get a
beautiful female and they and they're
all fem so
um this one turned black when it was
finishing and it was absolutely
beautiful so I pollinated it with the
Panama Red it's probably a 4ot plant
and I start from the
bottom and you know I'm crushing it up
I'm saving the KE I'm literally just
looking for seeds I don't really care
about the the weed so much as as getting
the seeds I went through the entire
plant when I got to the apical Bud the
last Bud on the top there was one seed
so in this entire breeding I got one
single seed and you know Murphy's Law I
didn't keep a cut of the B bag of
oranges so I couldn't so I couldn't go
back and do it again with the same plant
so I grew out that one plant so it's bag
of orange is in Panama Red so I just
named it
berer uh and the guys around here still
have it um there's there's a couple guys
that it's their regular stable no matter
what else they grow they keep it growing
I actually lost the plant about a year
and a half ago and got it back again I
don't know about two months ago so it
stays around it's an unbelievable plant
um and and because it was only the one
seed and I was afraid of losing it again
I created a bunch of uh s1s so I
reversed it cloned it hit it with the
you know hit the Clone with the reverse
plant and then made a bunch of seeds so
it's still out there um and
then maybe 4 years ago when Ren was
running useful seeds um I gave him a
bunch to give away his freebies yeah
it's just the Boop is just a really good
plant it's spicy on it's happy it's
really social um the weed's really
really nice and that was one of the the
the good ones that came out of the
Panama Red but when I grew that Beast
that story I want to tell about
Instagram is you know you get you get
all these different feeds you seeing all
these different plants um and and this
guy uh his name is Will lived in Seattle
and he crossed a killer Malo to a
pooya so the pya he actually picked up
in Colombia so he went down to Colombia
for two months trying to
sort the red right poter Roya and he
said after about you know so he finally
um um one of the highs he had which his
description is if you're sitting down
and you smoke to punya he said it feels
like you're being elevated off the chair
you just you're bing up off of the chair
so he way he brought those back to
Seattle and did did a couple of crosses
and he did this CR this killer Malawi
and he called it red
death so
I don't know how many he had he had a
dozen maybe growing and this one red
death number six just looked like a
perfect match for the Panama Red so I
wanted the plant and he doesn't know me
I don't know him so the pan I red so
will will hunted the punter Roya and
then he did the killer Malawi cross and
then he's got a dozen of those so
growing in Seattle and again nobody
knows who anybody is so I contact them
and I'm like I'd like a cut of the
plant and I said you know I'm come from
Boston I'm coming out to
Seattle um on a business trip and I'd
like the plant so he said
fine so you know time I think it was
probably a month between the
conversation and the time I was going to
Seattle and I'm all psyched CU now I get
to to do these you know these nice I I
get some Colombian with the pya which
which I like with the Panama Red The
Mala adds a little bit of little bit of
Spike little bit of little bit of Z zest
to it um and I think it's going to be a
really good cross so we're going back
and forth and about a week before I fly
out um he calls me up and he said um I'm
not going to be
around
so it's it's hard to frame it but like I
said you don't know who's going to be
who on Instagram so all of a sudden I
think I'm going to Seattle I think I'm
going to get this plant and then right
before I get to go out there the
person's telling me that
um that he's not going to be around so
I'm a little bit bummed out and um he
calls me back two days later and he said
look I rent a house and my landlord's
around he'll let you in the house he
doesn't know me for mam right so um I
fly out is his landlord meets me at the
house go inside the house I don't know
how he showered cuz the bathroom was
full of plants the back porch was full
of plants and I literally he left me
some um you know not chiam masas but
whatever he he he he left me some
scissors and two two water bottles to
take the cuts so he left all the stuff
for me opened up his house wasn't even
around I go out in the back his landlord
knew what was going on yeah yeah his his
his landlord was in a house close to him
um and also smoked weed so they're all F
so they're all fine with it um but I
literally went out on the back porch and
I you know there was a 10 12 plants
whatever there was on that back porch
and um I knew the plant right away so um
I went over and I checked and it was it
was the it was the number six so I took
a bunch of
cuts um and then I went to a supermarket
because this stuff still really
wasn't um you know legal yet and what I
did is I bought a
salad and I took the like three or four
cuts and I wrapped them into some paper
towels and then stuck lettuce over them
and put them in the thing like I was
taking a salad and I brought it on the
plane with me and flew back to
Boston you know what that is one of the
most
interesting ways that I've heard of
smuggling clones or you know moving
clones from place to place um I might
have to use that in the future because I
think it's actually a a great
idea um yeah that's crazy yeah so so I
brought it back in a
salad um BR read that plant and as I
typically do I've made a couple of of
different decisions but 90% of the time
I'm just naming stuff that's the name of
the parents right cuz I think it's
easier to figure out and if people are
tracking stuff down and they want
something from a line it's easier to
figure out so I named it Panama Red
Death um and the plants Panama Red Death
17 I I know a guy in the in the I I
believe he's in the black market in
brookin um he's been selling it for
years I actually sent him the cut that
the cut exist a couple places but not
many and he he's I it's been three or
four it's been at least 3 or 4 years
maybe more and he said it's um it's it's
one of his more popular strains that
people are buying so they like it it's
out there uh I don't have that plant
anymore I I I'll I'll eventually get it
back from him to do another line with it
but um yeah that Panama Red Death turned
out to be really really good weed
actually I I'm I'm I getting to the
point now where I've got to go to f3s on
it but the few seeds um that were
available that I put on uh uh the FCP
FCP site of over at dagger they those
move right away um and the interesting
part is when I give him to to Peter to
help raise money for the future cannabis
project I generally don't even say
prices like he can sell them for
whatever he wants he can do freebies
it's it's my way of helping him do the
stuff um and then and getting the seeds
out so people can grow hopefully some
really good weed so to to finish up so I
get the plant get it home I still never
met him he's never met me he let me in
his house hooked me up with the landlord
and then set me up with the equipment so
that I could bring the Clones back home
and now this I'm not real claring the
time but it was probably a year later he
was going to a wedding in
Maine and I said well stop by and have
dinner so stopped by with his girlfriend
and the wife and I had dinner and there
was you know theoretically they were
going to have dinner and head up to
Maine I think they left around 1:30 or
2:00 in the morning I mean we just sat
there for hours and hours and hours uh
and as it turns out he's he opened up uh
like a bed and breakfast in Columbia
he's gone he left Seattle um took the
young lady and they set up shop in
Columbia whether I ever get down there
to visit him or not will be interesting
but um yeah really really good guy and
and it's the same thing like I had no
idea what he looks like no idea on
anything it's like yeah stop over for
dinner and we end up you know I don't
know five or six hours just you know
kind of shooting the [ __ ] it was really
really nice but that was uh yeah go
ahead what I wanted to say is these are
the type of stories that this channel is
all
about there's good people out there
what' you say there's good people out
there there really is you know and it's
sometimes you feel like you know
everybody in the world is [ __ ] and then
all of a sudden you just
meet meet great people and I've had that
experience lately because of the podcast
I just feel so blessed that I've been
meeting such awesome people and and
making such great friends and I'm going
to say this you know right now that I
hope that this is the beginning of a
lifelong friendship for us yeah thank
you that'd be great yeah I you
know people complain about Instagram and
Instagram can be awful right because
we're doing stuff in legal states that
don't have any issues and they still
give the Cannabis guys a hard time so
that kind of sucks you know and then you
get the kids out there that you know
they don't finish reading the sentence
before they're replying back on
something negative because they know
everything so that that's the plus of
losing my account before is I've lost
those
accounts and now I'm dealing with people
who love the plant and and and like
making good weed so it's pretty nice you
know and you mentioned before how I
don't take any
money um I don't trade either right I
mean I'm I'm in a unique position where
I don't really need the money I'm
actually I'm in a position where I I
can't even take the money so I take
nothing and I don't even trade right
because if I
trade then trade implies you know value
for value and somebody could be
disappointed and I'd rather give and not
expect anything in return so the only
thing that can happen is I can get
something in return
sometime in the future and I'm only
going to be happy about it right I'm not
going to think wow that was a bad trade
so for me it's a really positive
experience all the way around I the one
thing I'll say about that and I heard
you say that
yesterday um when we chatted briefly
is I mean I understand you know you
don't need to trade and
but I think that you could trade if if
you just went into it with little
expectation you know like if somebody
says hey look I have something really
special I'd like to trade you for it um
you know you you would be giving it to
him anyway so if you don't s get
something that's you know awesome it
doesn't really matter you know but
there's a potential that somebody is
giving you something really
special so I didn't understand the the
no trading for that reason just
because and and the other thing is you
know someone someone's trying to give
something to you that they really want
you to have well that see you said it
though they're giving it to me I'll do
that but I'm not trade implies value so
I'm not looking for any value out of the
plant I'm just I'm looking to get it out
to people and
you know frankly I mean when it comes
down to it why am I doing it I'm doing
it for my ego I I want to make good weed
I want people to go Bost to Bob's weed's
really good that's what I want right I
don't need the money I'm looking for
accolades like I I'm I it's it's funny
hearing me say it but it's true like it
it's it's an ego thing for me I I you
know I I've done a bunch of stuff before
I understand breeding I got my OCD which
is is going to keep me wired in I'm not
going to be able to give up um so and
then and so I want I the value
proposition for me doesn't exist like
like actually right now in
Massachusetts there's two legal
entities you know one of them's got
60,000 square feet and the other one's
got you know Acres that they do
sungrown um I work with them I give them
the seats right I will I work with them
in terms of the genetics and right now
in Massachusetts it it's funny cuz I was
thinking about am I a homeg grower am I
a craft grower or breeder it's like I'm
not really a hom grower because I got
five different strains that are right
now in dispensaries in
Massachusetts and and I'm doing that
because those guys don't have to pay
anything I'll work with them to get the
right
strain and then you know they can run a
bench so I can see 80 plants right and
and then I can make a selection That I
Want from males and females that I could
never do on my own that would take me
years right I mean for me for me when
I'm going through stuff maybe I go
through 40 plants at a time but to be
able to go through a 100 and make that
selection you know I that's a pretty
unique opportunity and the weed's good
enough where the dispensaries can sell
it right cuz the kids are still buying
by the number so it's got got to be
strong enough for the dispensaries to
sell and you know this one place has an
R&amp;D room so they'll try different stuff
I'm like here's one I've never even
tested but the parents are really good I
know this and this is likely to happen
but you know we all know best intentions
right I mean just because everything is
great doesn't mean the weed's going to
be that good so having somebody who's
okay doing R&amp;D with you it's a huge Plus
for me so it it helps me get to my goal
of producing really good wheat do you
know if either of those
facilities um Greg chemdog is involved
in because I know that he's um in
Massachusetts um you know working at a
licensed
Farm yeah he's not on the tube that I'm
that I'm doing stuff with now he's not a
part to either of them cuz I I know who
owns this other one and it's just you
know it's a massive facility and they're
really good people so you know that
that's an advantage that I have
also goinging to think of another Panama
Red story so I got the
berer I got the Panama Red Death that
came
[Music]
in yeah that's been a a really great
plan you talked about the Panama Red do
you have any other breeding stories that
you want to tell or stories about people
that you
know Al so um Jr at Saturn Ilia seeds in
the last coup couple
years the pan I think the Panama Red
would go really good with Federated
Federation Hawaiian
sativa so I think he sells seeds he does
some stuff he's a really good farmer
nice guy and and we got chatting a few
years back to try to get it going so I
sent him
paen and it didn't
take and then he sent me a cut of his
mother and then I tried poen and that
didn't
take
and I got Panama Red Death
pollen uh and that was an accident and I
got maybe 20 seats I think I I got very
very few seats I think on that one um
but because of the Panama Red and
because we were both trying to get it
going and eventually I I'll you know
I'll have to go to f3s and and get the
panom my red back into that Federation
haian sativa I think he I think he's up
to either F7 or f8 so it's really nice
and stable it's an absolute you know he
gave me he sent me a cut and that the
plant's
absolutely stand out it it literally
smells like um like citrus shoe polish
like if you had a can of black kiwi shoe
polish and and it and it was you poured
citrus acid on or orange is that's what
it smells like it's it's it's it's a
great smell it's a really clean up high
love the plant um and because of that I
think I've bred that thing three or four
times already you know and and in my
this is just my opinion I like I would
never do a filial generation
increase on somebody else's
plant right because they've done the
work
and for me to go and and take it in a
different direction than they were
taking it it doesn't seem right to me so
if I get a plant from somebody I get a
cut um I'm basically only doing
outcrosses now on a rare occasion I
might go back and do a back cross with a
plant that I really like but that's
pretty rare I I I doesn't seem right to
me to take somebody's work and go ahead
and do F2 so like in JR's case I've read
that that Hawaiian
um I think four times and then what I'm
doing is I'll send him 100
seeds right so that if you he he could
he can give them away throw them away
grow them do whatever he wants but you
know it's it's my way of saying thank
you for um for letting me have that cut
so I I still have that cut right now
it's it's a really nice plant and it all
started again with that the Panama Red
mail the one thing that the Panama Red
mail did for me
was it made me
Focus even though it's anecdotal because
it's a oneshot deal um the males that
show last you know we we we we started
to chat yesterday about the mail piece
which I love um honestly I have more
much more fun hunting males than females
because it's a little harder and you
have to have a little yeah a little but
you know it's interesting it's it to me
it's intense
right it's it's not the perfect male
it's the perfect male for the cross like
what do you trying to get out of the
Cross and and and what's that what's the
intent on the breeding because if you
have two people with the same set of of
genetics and one person's looking
for you know tall wispy you know 16 we
plant and somebody's looking for tighter
nod something that they can grow inside
it's likely I mean it may take some time
but it's likely that that both of those
people can find a male that will help do
that job so there's not one perfect male
to do all the jobs you know we like you
know we mentioned DJ Short real real
briefly and that at least and I don't
know him but my understanding is he
likes a male for a structure and and
doesn't add anything so that he can keep
the female traits that he likes and make
a bigger bit a stronger plant right so
with that intent he's looking for a
specific kind of male me personally I'd
rather have a male bring something to
the dance right I I'm I'm looking for
the combination that's going to increase
me something and that so I've had a
number of people tell me that that's the
way they breed
um which way where they want a male
that allows the female to
shine right but then it seems like
you're not really making a cross you're
just trying to get your female into seed
form you know so I really don't
understand that logic okay
so particularly when you doing regular
seeds
so I have a friend that he he does a lot
of
feminized and for
feminized and you know we both agree him
and I that selfing can cause problems
right so he prefers to use a male that
has traits of
vigor um flower size and yield but he
wants something that's not going to give
the
tpin okay and that way you know if he's
Crossing it to you know whatever let's
say
runts the progyny is going to be runs
and that it's not going to have you know
the tpine and even the high of the
parent plant so when you're doing
feminized plants
I I guess I can wrap my head around that
but when you're doing a cross with
regulars it's harder for me to
understand why you would want a male
that isn't giving much besides
fertility you know so no I so I agree
with you I I my preference is I want the
males to bring something to the party I
you
know and if you so do turp profiles I
test all my stuff so I know where the
Tes are I know where CBG CBC CBD like
especially lately when I'm doing the
longer flowering stuff I don't want any
CBD at all because all it's going to do
is it's it's going to muffle that that
nice high from the long flowering so I I
I go through and and test everything so
but on that on your piece I agree with
you that the meals that I I like I want
to bring something to the table that I I
will say though I'd like clarification
from you on s1's MH because I've never
had a problem with self and plants and
and I've never I've never had a problem
with any of the seeds and my guess
is 90% of them come out just like the
mom right I mean I guess I don't
understand whether everybody's taking
separate clones or their STS or or
reversing a plant and taking seeds from
the plant that's reversed now if you did
that and I I posted on one of the forums
recently because guys were talking about
sing and seemed like they were doing it
for the first time and they were getting
the you know the ratio right for so you
know sodium tho sufate and and the
silver nitrate to get that going but I
think maybe an issue with some of the
fem is
is they're taking seeds from the plant
that's being
reversed now then I could see an issue
because now you're stressing the plant
and you're asking it to produce its
babies at the same time you're putting
it under that stress so how many people
do that honestly I have no idea maybe
Nobody Does it I think I think that
that's what most people are doing yeah
that's crazy I mean you you you you set
up the you you clone the plant
right and so if you especially if you
want to keep it you get two or three
clones and then you grow the
Clone till it's you know two weeks in
flour a week and a half in flour so so
it's just starting to kick in and and
stretches slowing down then you start
STS in the other plant so the plant
that's producing the female pollen is
hitting the Clone it's not hitting that
same plant I mean technically it's the
same genetics but it's physically not
the same plant so now you've got a
healthy female taking in pollen I've
never had problems I've never had a male
come up I've never had any kind of real
pheno variation
heroism
zero and the one thing that I now and
and again I don't have the data to say
this is true
but my guess
is the harder the concentration of
STS it takes to reverse a
plant is how stable it
is so some some of them you have a
really really tough time I think those
are less likely to pass on um the
Herms I think the hermaphroditic traits
if you if you used an STS solution and
let's say you know you used a just call
it you know five was your solution which
is a combination of the two and and and
you put half the solution on the plant
turned really quickly then it's not that
strong a male that's also why I like
these late showing
males right I mean that's i i i the
Panama Red showed me what a strong male
and through the progyny it proved itself
it was a strong meal it added strength
it added the the spice it did all I
wanted so if I get down to having four
males left you know um I'm not picking
the one that's first in flower
especially everything else is even what
what I've generally done over time
because I feel pretty strongly about it
is I'll start with 40
plants and when I put the males in flow
I take the first 10 to 20% that show sex
and I just kill them I I don't even I I
don't even flower them out I I want the
ones that show up at the at the end now
doesn't have to be the very last one but
I want them in the last
25% because I think those are stronger
it's it's hate saying it but the old
adage about the you know the buck and
the the old buck and the young buck up
at the
hill and and the Young Buck says hey
let's run down there and get get some of
the get get get a female and and the old
bug says you know what let's walk down
and get them
all right I mean honestly I think that's
the way the males are I I think I think
if they take longer I they at least in
my experience they've been
stronger and so you've tested it out you
you've done the the ones that flower
faster and the ones that flower
slower I I did it once other than that
and it it's the ones that that flower
early I have no interest in at all well
I'm going to let me make comment about
this
um I I don't believe I have as much
experience breeding as you do you know
you've been doing this for focusing on
it for many
years but to me and I hope you'll not be
offended by you know what I'm going to
say because it's not directed directly
at you it's directed at the idea oh okay
go ahead okay but the idea that we can
select a
male based
on how fast it flowers a stem rub um the
structure of the
plant to me it's a little bit of
arrogance you know and I think that the
only way that you can really know what
this male is going to give you is the
same way that we only know what a female
is going to give you and and that's by
growing it and so the way I do it you
know particularly when I'm going to do
like an F1 hybrid is I try to use as
many of the males as I can
separately so let's say you know I start
20 seeds and I get 10 males okay I'm
going to try to keep those 10 males you
know clone them and one at a time I'm
going to flower them with the
females then you test out the seeds that
are grown with those and then after
you've seen you know the 10 different
males what they've produced then you can
select because we're not guessing we
have data you know
and that to
me is the only way I can see doing it
you maybe it's because I don't have the
skill set but I also worry you know my
my family heritage is Jewish so I guess
Jewish people they worry a lot but I
worry like what we could lose when you
do that by having that arrogance in
thinking that you can visually make a
selection
so I can't disagree with you because
because the only real true
test is the
progyny right is the male producing
something that's better than something
else but the reality is to do that I
mean right now my average project takes
years work oh yeah I
mean so yeah I I I I mean I can't do it
so I I live and die by the sword I I
have um I'll give you an example how how
about an example how my stuff didn't
work so I got
lavender um it's gone out to a couple
people it's a absolutely great
plant um and I bred it to a chili
verie which was called chill lavender
turned out to be a fabulous strain um
I've still got one of the girls that
I'll have for a long long time it tests
high it's got flavor it's a really nice
high so it's it that breeding worked
really really well and the lavender was
a plant that worked really really well
so then I I took a chil avender mail so
chili Verdi and lavender and went back
to the lavender
again to try to make it a little more
creamy I want a creamy kind of floral
and when I went through and picked the
mail
uh was so first of all like I I I talked
about you know last to show but honestly
I probably my number
one um item that I'm looking at is root
growth right I I I need to see good root
masks because then I know the plants
will have Vigor and the plants are going
to be healthy if if if I've got you know
five of them and two of them the roots
look like hell and the and the other
roots are twice as much um I'm not even
going to look at those plants they
they're they're gone because root root
growth is Big so then I got structure
then I got different growing Tendencies
I got Leaf morphology depends whether I
want to do a complimentary Cross or you
know I I want I want to have a a
conflicting cross where I'm going to
bring something out so there's different
reasons to look at the mail but so I
used my general process of root growth
structure last to show and then I bred
it for the lavender batross now a bunch
of people have grown it out and the
weed's real good but
somehow I brought out these recessive
traits and they have weak
branching so the weed's really good and
if you know if you grow it in a A scrog
or a sea green or something like that
it's probably going to be fine but the
reality is the branches can't hold the
way to the buds and it's not because the
buds are giant they're just weak
branches yeah they're weak
branches you know and and may may maybe
I could silica or calcium up and and and
change the feeding but the reality is it
doesn't have the structure it doesn't
have the structure but so let me um so
that was add something to that real fast
yeah so um and you know you have to
understand that I come from a different
generation than you um my generation was
the chem dog generation and you know
that's kind of what I'm known for
but if the chem dog was a male for
instance and we were
using these type of
selection
processes it would have been
tossed because it grows like [ __ ] it's
it's not a strong
plant
um yeah it's it's it's a it's a poor
grower um with poor
structure um
but then it's
producing the highest quality flow with
the tpin that we love right so that's
why I believe that the only way to
really know is to grow the stuff out and
you know to be honest with you um if the
chem dog was grown you know I believe he
only had like six seeds or something
when he started this but if he had 100
seeds you
know that plant might have just been
lost you know
because it it literally grew so poorly
and it was a difficult plant to
feed
so you know I know the work is
impossible to do it's not like it's
difficult you know
but it's one thing to say hey look you
know I'm I'm just doing the best I can
in an Impossible Project
it's another thing to say I'm selecting
it because of this because this is what
I think makes it
better because like I said you know like
the most interesting thing that I've
heard as far as selecting a male is
someone told me that and I've never done
this that people will reverse a male to
get it to put out female
flowers so that then they can rub those
flowers to try to get um a smell off of
them a tpine not just a stem rub but
like of an actual flower I said oh well
you know that's at least giving us more
information to to go with I don't know
how valid it is well so let take the
take that that statement right there
so if I'm going to look for a
male let's say that I'm looking looking
for a F1 male to make f2s so I've
already grown out a whole bunch of
females I've already picked the one that
I like best and and we would tend to
agree that it's not terribly hard to
pick the best female after you grow a
whole bunch out right right you're right
you you test it you smoke it and it's
the one you like or not so now I've
already grown at least one maybe two
runs of the females and
and if it's an F1 and let's say the
stuff isn't crazy you basically have
three main phenotypes right you got 50%
that are a combination of both parents
and you got 25 that lean to the mom and
you got 25 that lean to the dad so and
if the one you picked the one the female
that you like the best was in the
middle then you generally know what the
leaf morphology looks like you know what
the node structure looks like so you
know what that plant looks like so now
go run 30 or 40 Ms and you're going to
have the same distribution roughly of
the phenotypes so now you take if you're
if you're breeding to the middle then
you can Lop off 50% of the plants take
the ones that lean to the mom take the
ones that lean to the dad and get rid of
those now when you're looking at the
male I'm still looking at root growth
I'm still looking at structure but and
when I'm looking at the leaf morphology
what I'm really trying to do is I'm
trying to pick a m
that looks as close to the female that I
like and that's how I'm going to get to
my f2s and and the reality is it's it's
nothing's going to be identical but it's
going to be close so now when I get f2s
even though I'm going to get a broader
range of fenos right on the f2s I might
have literally you could have up to 10
different fenos right stretching from
the mom to the dad but you find that
next one and and you find the plant
that's similar to the male that you used
before which is similar to the female
now I can do a back cross and that gives
me something that's very very close to
the original mom or I could try to pick
two that are the same which is a little
more risky bottleneck it even farther
and then produce the f3s so it's the
intent of what you're trying to do with
the male
so it it really depends on intent for me
and and I think you're right that
progyny decides the
mail but except for this lavender fail
where I'm not happy with the structure
of the plant going through the process
when I'm trying to do an outcross or or
a complimentary cross I know kind of
what I'm looking for and I'm and I'm
looking for that in the plant and the
other thing is you grow a bunch of
plants and I send them to the lab and I
know what the tur profile is
so I know that I want to highlight a
certain tur profile I I don't want to
bring merine in right like what I'm
doing right now and I who knows if I'll
be successful I want terpinolene and
carop philene and I want mercing way
down on the list
right but it's not necessarily easy to
do because mering's all over the place
so I'm testing the different plants I
know what the structure of the plants
are it's one of the reasons it takes a
couple years to do do it because you
you're out there going through a couple
of different runs like I the people that
I and there's plenty of Growers that are
much better Growers than I am and I
think the people that I respect that
grow most of them have said the same
thing you you get the the plant dialed
in on your third run the first run
you're finding out about the plant the
the second run you're finding out really
trying to dial in the feed and the Third
Run is when you actually
in the plant so how long's it take to do
three
runs right and that's just to find one
plant so it it takes a lot and and to to
run a 100 or to even to run 20
males and then breed them all out and
figure out which is the best by smoking
the progyny you're looking at two or
three years yeah right I mean it's time
to do it it takes a long time so you
live by the sword you die by the sword
I've had some really really nice ones um
and I like I said the weed on the
lavender it's good weed but unlike chem
dog it's not so special that I'm willing
to take this viny flopping over can't
holding up the buds plant right um and
the one thing that I would say on the
approach that I tend to use for
males is I don't
think the plant that you trying to get
to um has to be I don't know how to say
this I I want structure first like I'm
not taking a special plant
necessarily and then saying I'm going to
breed to this because it's a special
plant doesn't mean I haven't done that
but what I'm doing is if I get a male
and I want to breed it to a a a female
that I like I want obsessive root growth
right I want to see that thing just cuz
the old adage of more Roots more fruits
still applies so I I want massive root
growth if I don't get the root growth
I'm not using it actually we don't have
to bring up the the graph right now but
catfish is one that I've worked on for
the last little bit and I was trying to
hopefully find it a male and I had two
females that literally were 50 to 75%
more root mass than any of the
males so seeing that I just killed all
the males I'm like if I don't have a
male that's good enough to have the same
root growth as one of the plants I'm
selecting then I'm going to have to go
through it again and maybe when I go
through it again only the females have
good root mess I I'll find out the next
time I try to do it but I I I think if
you create the Next Generation with a
strong plant and to me a strong plant is
root growth mostly
now those seeds now if you find the
special one it's still going to be a
strong plant when you take one of these
other ones that you know the roots
aren't that strong the plants kind of
spindly but the weeds really really good
you breed that you you're going to have
a lot harder time I think if you bred a
stronger male to that
series then you're going to end up with
stronger plants and you're still going
to find something so I I'd rather start
with a strong plant first but will you
find the the next chem dog will you find
the next bag seed that turns out to be
great I mean probably
not right so I mean that's kind of my
two cents on the males I the other thing
is I I've been fooling around with
pulling out recessive
traits that to me is a is a lot of fun
because if you have really good quality
plants and I can pull out the recessive
traits now I'm getting something that
nobody's seen
before and and if the genetics are good
on the plants that I'm using which I
think they are and I hope they are then
it's likely that 25% of those plants
could be special I'm not expecting them
mall to be
special
um yeah actually I wouldn't jump in
Cosmic before you do yeah I want to
introduce you to our co-host Cosmic
Cosmic this is is Boston Bob and um
Cosmic is actually the guy that helped
me record my first podcast and he's a
regular co-host he like you is a
professional and has a has a day job so
he's not always often able to start or
finish the podcasts when they
begin but um I love and respect the guy
and so he's always invited to to be our
co-host so welcome Cosmic and like to
introduce you to Bob man what an intro
thank you Gabby and Bob is very nice to
meet you yeah nice to meet you Cosby I'm
working on my intros okay doing a good
job Bob thanked me for his intro too and
and um they're both truly
heartfelt I want to bring up we we we
talked about the males we talk about the
seeds and intention so cornbread Ricky
um who is one of the the two guys at
Swamp Boy seeds
I had a conversation with him with my
son seven or eight years
ago and it made a really really big
impression and it it's a kind of a
different way to think about things he
said there's only two kinds of seeds
that's
it the seeds where you grow a
plant and you grow and get what's
expected from the
plant or or you try to find a plant and
those are the two kinds of seeds you're
either growing or you're finding and if
you look at the the the retail
Market especially in dispensaries right
or cultivation
facility those guys get mother plants
and get 200 clones and all the weeds not
not it's not close it's exactly the same
it's the same plant
so I see the value in doing the
first which is making seeds where if you
grow a plant you get the plant you
expect right and you plant 100 seeds
nine you know 100 seeds 90 of them are
going to be the same kind of plant so
that really takes place probably around
F4 maybe if you're lucky F3 but F4 F5 F6
they're all going to be like that and
people are are getting the lines but the
other side is
do I want to buy a seed and grow Jack
herrer right there's a couple guys that
have f8 f9s I think they're beautiful
plants right and and there's a whole
bunch of
strains that have been filial generation
enough into the
seeds
where you know what you're going to
get and then there's the people who want
to find a
plant and the find a plant to me is much
more fun I I think the interesting part
is I think a bunch of people who buy
seeds don't necessarily know the
difference between growing and
finding and and I think there's less
information available when somebody's
got seeds whether they're buying selling
growing that they know where they are in
what generation and what to
expect right the most people probably
realize f1s you're going to have three
main
phenos not many people I think realize
on F2 you could literally have 10 or 12
fenos and
then you know Gabby like you said if
you're running a whole bunch of stuff
like you're running that's close to open
pollination even right so that starts
the whole process over and if you get to
F3 and F4 then you expect some kind of
consistency in the
cultivar but who's growing For What and
when you're buying do you know what
you're actually buying you're buying to
grow you're buying to find
so I like the finding
the finding is much more fun because if
you find that special plant you clone it
you give it to your friends it goes to
the dispensaries they're selling on the
market versus you know getting a stable
line but the way that you may find that
plant you probably have to use a plant
that's come from a stable line right
because if not you get in these poly
hybrids and all the stuff is the same
yeah right so what I found is you can
work a line and then bring in something
that's that's been worked you know let's
say F4 to F7 that's going to be stable
bring it into something in a in an
outcross and then find something that
wasn't there so I think you can do that
but that's that's you still need both
seeds right you need the grow seed you
need the fine seed and then how you
bring in them together bring two grow
seeds together you know you're going to
get something you bring two two fine
seeds together I think it's more po
hybrid and I I think it's a little muddy
so um actually might be a good time to
let's talk about the
cfish okay um and is that one that you
sent the photo of it is so okay let me
pull it up well actually yeah you know
go to the albino first all
righty so and I got to look for mine too
okay give me one
sec so albino
it depends where you see it but the the
numbers are 1 in a th000 to 1 in 10,000
you get an albino plant and this is 100%
not variegation it's an albino plant so
what I
did was I bred to bring out recessive
traits did I know I was going to get the
albino I had absolutely no clue right
but when I when I show you this other
one and we go to the chart on um on the
cfish
uh I I thought there's a there's a way
to bring out recessive tra so do me a
favor bring up uh the one that's number
three it's kind of grayed out it's a p
it's a p pedigree chart so what happens
is and I think I I thought this came
from Miracle
15 which is the male that capul used to
make the Mac
one and the reason I thought that is if
we're on the the number three graph Now
with uh the
catfish
so cfish then the parents and go to the
grandparents so in the
grandparents both dads are fish piss
they're fish piss number
four um has been a really good strain
for me uh and I'm going to go off topic
just for a second and for Gabby so in
this particular one Gabby on fish fist
when I when I selected the male
not only did I go through my regular
process about root growth and structure
I actually put these in flower pulled
off all of the pollen sacks and then
sent it to the lab to have the stock and
the stems tested for
THC and the variation was 1 and 1 half
to 2 and 1 12% with most of them around
two and fish piss number four uh came
out at almost 2.6% THC just From the
Rough plant itself so that's actually
how I selected this male and this is
another one where almost everything I've
touched um like the Cecil's green and
the macf fish Mac fish is in at
dispensaries but Cecil green is is still
out in the dispensaries the fish piss
has done really really well so I this I
don't know really what to call it but if
you look at the Top Line and and you go
up from Catfish to Cecil's green and
then look at the parents fish fish piss
and OCD M15 so what Top Line I see Fish
piss and then Underneath It O ocdm 15
right so those are the parents for
Cecil's green so what I'm doing and and
literally it takes a couple years to do
this I take the fish
piss and I breed it to OCD
M15 and there's nothing related in the
OCD M15 to fish piss so it's an
outcross then drop down to the bottom
parents underneath that and it's fish
piss and Mac one right okay so same
thing there's no relation but what
happens is if you take this two that a
circle OCD M15 and Mac 1 and go back up
they both have the same
Father which is M15 of Miracle 15 which
is the the the lone mail that cap used
uh to make these plants so I
intentionally want the
great-grandfathers of the unrelated
plants to be the
same so when the fish piss goes in and
it meets Mac one it's interacting with
those genetics on the bottom to make Mac
fish and then when the fish piss goes
into OC dm15 it's making Cecil's green
these are two different plants but the
difference is if you look at the
genetics behind it the dad's the same
and then the grandfather or the
great-grandfather is the same so what
happens is when the AL match up on the
genes whether it's a a multi- alil gene
or just the two it's going to probably
make
homo recessive traits you you'll find
something that that was didn't exist in
this previous generation like you got to
go back three or four generations to get
this done so when I did this I figured
I'm going to get some weird stuff this
is not a
complimentary uh breeding whereas if I
did similar plants and brought them
together this is a contrasting a
contrasting breeding where I think I can
bring out recessive traits so that's
actually why I did this and then if you
go back and you look at the the um the
albino the AL oo which is supposed to be
one in a, is 20 to 25% of these
seeds right so literally they grow up as
seedlings there's zero chlorophyll so
somewhere back in the history and I
think we figured it out it's actually
the the miracle 15 father starf
fighter so there's some type of
recessive trait all the way back in that
starf fighter Gene that has has
something that shuts off
chlorophyll
um and so what happens is that's how I
get them and I literally it's 20 at 25%
which According to mendal which is what
you should have right when you when you
split those fenos and the re and I
always thought it was Miracle
15 and um I got a note from Rick who
runs U mosca seeds if you know mosa
seeds he he's come out with some really
really nice stuff he I I like him a lot
he was tell telling me in his pink
animal crackers he's had the occasional
albino and if you look at the pink
animal crackers he's got a bunch of
starf fighter in there and I and I know
the fish piss so I was pretty I was
pretty sure it didn't come from the fish
fiss and that it came from the the you
know the Mac dad um so I bring out
recessive traits
now so if I grow out 20 seeds and 20 to
25% of them are albinos I don't even
have to pick ones to kill they're dead
in two
weeks right I mean there's no
chlorophyll it can't grow and basically
the codons generally hold food for what
10 to 14 days before you got to feed
them so the plant stays alive while the
cleon's actually providing food to the
plant and as soon as the codons run out
of food plant's dead so something we
were talking about was grafting and I
know we're in like Fantasy Land you know
now for a moment but I was thinking
about it after we spoke so I grow San
Pedro
cactus and there's been a you know many
occurrence of variegated plants and um
some
albinos and when they're found the only
way to grow them is to graft them to
graft them to something that does have
chlorophyll and so you know we were
talking about like could you graft them
um these albinos you know to you there
was no benefit to me you know although
I'm not I don't I'm not saying I'm ready
to do the work either there's there's
curiosity and so what I wonder about is
a couple of things number one could you
actually graft something so small and
delicate um you know cuz C this you know
they're they're much bigger even as
seedlings you know they have a more of a
structure to to graft to and a Seedling
the stem is so thin and soft I don't
know how you would um how you would do
it but what I was fantasizing about was
if you could get a albino like this to
flower and
finish the tur profile on that would
have to be super unique
because it has no
chlorophyll you know
so you know
because the chlorophyll has a strong
impact on the way the flower tastes and
so to smoke a plant or consume a plant
that had no
chlorophyll I just found it as
intriguing yeah and you know my thoughts
right I I don't think it can happen you
don't think you can graft it no I I mean
maybe in a lab with somebody who is
really really good at it maybe there's a
chance I I'm going to send you 20 seeds
you can do whatever you want you you
graft it I'd love to
see but for
me you know it's it's um you know
Chinese proverb good luck bad luck who
can tell right for me it's better
because I'm looking for something
special and I think you don't get
something really good without something
bad and if there's something bad there's
likely something good right it's kind of
you know the kind of the karma thing in
nature so the plant's automatically
calling
25% so now I've got kind of the middle
phenos and and the fenos that lean
towards the fish piss so my feno
variation in these is
smaller right I mean they're they're
relatively consistent with there is some
pheno variation but in this particular
strain I have I found one plant uh the
number
11 where the other plants are mine and
caropine which is you know kind of a
standard profile it's it's and and the
weed's kind it honestly the wheat's kind
of special but this number 11 and the
other the the the ones that I tested the
the T pinoline was
minuscule this number 11 that the uh
terpinolene is twice the turpine rate of
anything else in the plant
and and I like I could tell when it was
growing I could tell halfway through in
flower it smells like sweet turpentine
like it's a really really nice plant and
I honestly I think that's the recessive
traits from that same line coming
forward and I think it's coming from the
star fighter and the Colombian and I
think the star fighter created the um
the albino piece and I think that that
really high
terpinolene that that that the the tur
profile that's coming out of that plant
I think is coming from the Colombia so
if you look back it's like five
generations back so I got a chance I
still have to grow it inside because I
grew them all outside last year or this
year I I got to grow it inside and see
what the real timing is right like
exactly when I go to 1212 find out how
long it takes to flower but I think I
can get that kind of soaring Colombian
high in a structure that I can grow
inside with a shorter flowering
period and and honestly in this one
um one of the guys that that the guy who
first grew these is out in LA and he's a
ganji he he went through the ganier
program and he sent me a note that it's
the most thought-provoking weed um and
and that's what I got I um you know we
we talked about how long I've been
around for in the beginning it's
honestly the most thought-provoking weed
I've ever smoked I I actually when I and
it's happened to me twice in a week so
it wasn't just a One-Shot deal I gave it
some space and I tried it again but I
was I was thinking about a process and
then I started thinking about why I was
thinking that way about thinking about
the process it brought it brought me to
this like metal level of thinking and
it's like I've never had a buzz like
that maybe you know maybe on
that excuse me may maybe on that c or in
the 70s but like I've never had anything
like this so I I'm 100% working this PL
and it's because of the recessive traits
so and like the OC just to finish up on
this the OCD M15 was a larger stretchier
plant and everybody knows what the Mac
one's like right little Stout little Lea
ear leaves a little more shiny like so
these plants were different even though
they were kind of related so when I
brought them in with the same male I
think I've done this process gives me
the recessive
traits um and I want to talk a little
bit about something similar you have any
questions on that at all or you good
well the one thing I wanted to say is
first of all this is a
uh it's a learning experience for me and
I'm appreciating it something that you
mentioned earlier earlier was how
there's two different types of seeds the
seeds that give you what you know you're
going to get and the seeds that give you
the hunt yeah the hunt right the ability
to hunt
and that is super true you know
that's you know that's exactly correct
and I think that knowing whether you're
what you're looking for in that sense
and having you know know the the ability
to maybe get something like
that
um that's that's what people want and I
think that often that's not what is
delivered you know like when you buy a
pack of seeds
from um most seed vendors it's kind of
like you don't know if it's going to be
consistent or if it's going to be you
know the hunt and and for instance like
let's say seeds are sold at a dispensary
to a you know a closet grower and he
sees the picture on on the pack or on
the flyer of it you know they wonder is
is that what they're going to get and it
made me
remember you know something I always go
back and think about was when we
purchased the super skunk from
Sensei you know I think we had a couple
of packs and we started them
and the uniformity was
incredible you know to the point where
we were able to just make a selection
and get rid of the rest of them
because they were all the same yeah cuz
you work the line yeah and I would I
would hold the catalog it was a paper
catalog from Sensei and I would hold it
up against my bud every single crop that
I grew it just to be like holy [ __ ]
that's what it is you know and that's a
pretty amazing an amazing feeling that
you're like I actually got it because
when we bought the seeds in Holland
we're like are we getting ripped off are
we going to get what we want out of this
and particularly with the super skunk it
was exactly it and
then you know that was when we were more
beginners that growing and when we were
looking for something specific now the
idea of a hunt and being able to find
something
special that is probably the most
rewarding thing because you're not
pulling out it's
unexpected you know so when you find
that something special you know through
the
hunt that's you know but actually think
about what you just said right so
sensy that consistent assume just make a
general assumption the F the F4 or or
higher right so so they've got some
consistency but in the in the older days
especially in the the straight black
market days you wanted to know what you
got yeah so so when you bought seeds
they were generally worked lines because
you know if especially if you were
humping up in the woods and you had to
do stuff right you don't you don't want
all sorts of surprises you want a nice
row you want a nice Gathering of similar
plants and then what's happened is as
the as the the home Growers have come in
and everybody sells seeds you get all
these different f1s so to get that stuff
you got to go to somebody who's worked
the lines and how many people really
work the
lines and it does exist like I I'm doing
a little bit but it takes a long time
right you got to know the plants I mean
you got to believe that said you know
there were years making those seeds that
group right and and they get and they
getting to where they want so in this
market you you got more of the
findoms and and I think if you do these
um these hybrids yeah the poly hybrids I
don't think you find much right so I
mean and it's just my opinion I there
might be great weed but I I I think you
got to bring out recessive traits from
from plants so
I'm not inventing something I'm not
making something I'm trying to create a
condition in the genetics where I'm
bring something that was already there
just hasn't been seen yet so that's kind
of fun to me like I like that a lot but
I wonder sometimes when people are
buying like it it like take the catfish
with the albinos somebody buys a pack of
10 seeds and they only plant two right
cuz how many people actually go all 10
like for me I'm doing I do 30 or 40
right but there's a ton of people that
grow one or two seeds so if you bought
those catfish seeds and you grew two of
them and they both turned white and died
in two weeks you're not a happy camper
right well if you if you know in advance
you know it's got to come with something
on the stickers saying hey 20% of these
seeds are going to be albino and will
die within you know 15 to 20 days of
them being planted so you know the good
news is if they plant two out of um 10
seeds and they're albinos probably you
know the other eight ones will will not
be you know so we we had one guy who got
eight out of 10 ELP yeah it's just you
know and so that guy you know
considering who you are you just send
them another pack of seeds and you know
or tell them hey if you want to grow
something else but this is how you find
something special you know this is this
is why it's this is why it's work and
not just come easy right and if it was
easy everyone would be doing it you know
but it but it's not and you know hard
work pays off so let me because I it's a
it's a nice followup I think to this one
can you put up the um the pedigree chart
for number four doing that too I wanted
to kind of bring up a point about what
you guys were talking about as far as
like consistency with seeds too and you
know a lot of the seed companies uh
these days their catalog is constantly
changing you know they always have new
strains every year you know there's
always like a new line coming out but
some of these other companies especially
the old school companies you know they
have the same strains year after year
and I think that is a kind of a good way
to um to show that you've been
consistently working with those strains
versus oh I just want something new to
sell you know and next different yeah do
you hear me Cosmic either that or it's
[ __ ] yeah of course because like
sometimes what these seed companies are
doing is they're just putting any seeds
in the pack and so for instance if you
order clone G for instance so that I'm
not you know putting anyone on blast but
so if you or excuse me seeds the seed
genetic G right and they've run out of
those they'll just put whatever they
want in the pack
you know and that's why it's important
to buy um genetics from reputable people
that actually care about what they're
doing you know and care about their
reputation more than they care about
just making one more cell yeah so but I
mean I know for a fact that um that's
common practice you know with with many
of these seed companies you know like to
give you an example you know people make
a trip to Holland and you know buy some
seeds most of these people are never
coming back anyway you know so you know
and they want to have the full catalog
of seeds always so I think there's a lot
of people that don't have proper ethics
in the game you know and so it's it's
important to
know who you're working with mhm
absolutely I'm sure Bob agrees with that
too I do I I stay pretty
tight um let's look I got that I got
that chart too number four yeah we got
the number four up so um Frosty
mcfish and frosty fish is the dad and
the macf fish six is the mom so it's the
same mom as catfish right okay okay but
now this is a complimentary
breeding so
the two go back to father grandfather
you got the two fish pisses right in the
third column and then underneath it is
boss Frost which I got from uh Patrick
at pico Brands he's out in he's a
California guy he was very nice and gave
me some S3s from this boss Frost which
is just an absolute monster so I grew a
whole bunch of those and bred this one
and then you can see on the bottom of of
the same grandparents it's fish piss
with Mac one right so
now phosphoros and Mac one they have
nothing in
common so I'm not going to get the same
kind of a le battle on the jeans because
they're separate so fish pisses one over
boss Frost for a Leal position and the
same thing with Mac one so when I when I
did this
breeding I assume this is a
complimentary breeding and I'm going to
get much more
consistent
phenotypes and it's exactly what I got
the all the plants basically look very
very similar and the pheno variation is
basically in stretch so 20 or 25% will
be a little taller and 20 or 25% will be
a little
shorter but if you looked at them from
above and looked at the just the the the
leaf morphology and and and not
necessarily the not they all look the
same so this was done to try to add even
more cuz the fish piss added a lot of
potency to Everything I did and none of
the fish piss Prodigy came out less than
probably 24% they're all 24 to 30% all
the different prodigies I've had with
fish piss like this Frosty fish this is
still in dispensaries and and this is a
couple years old but that's that's still
in dispensaries um um so you know kind
of valid Ates the potency so I did this
as a compliment cross and I wanted to
show it so that if you looked at the
other en cfish and you look at this one
they kind of look similar but what are
the differences the difference is on the
on the on the way back on the mom's side
I've got relations that I think are
going to conflict when they finally come
together and give me those recessive
traits and in this one I don't have that
and if you look on the very bottom left
this is a note from uh year and a half
ago I think this would go really good
with Miracle glue and Miracle
glue is from cap capulator and it's
where's this note at it's it's right
under the four it's it's one of my notes
from 2023 oh it says medical glue right
so what I'm doing is I'm always looking
at the pedigree to find out is it
complimentary is it contrasting am I
going to am I going to increase pheno
variation am I going to DEC increase F
variation so that's why when we started
talking about the males that also plays
into what I'm looking for am I looking
to create conflict or am I or am I
looking to complement the line so if you
look at this breeding with the frosty
mcfish you got boss Frost which is
Gorilla Glue and Mac one well Miracle
glue is basically the miracle 15 which
is the um the dad of of Mac Ju
and Gorilla Glue so both grandmothers on
this are going to match the plant I'm
going and it's actually a project I'm
doing right now I've already selected
the miracle glue um
female was done in a bench with
40 and it was in an R&amp;D room and all the
plants got PM except for this one
plant and it there's a picture on my
Instagram I didn't send it to
that the the fan leaves are covered in
trikes like I've never seen oh I
actually saw that page that picture on
your Instagram yeah so that's that
that's this miracle now the plant's
smaller right it's probably not going to
work for the guys in the dispensary
because they're not going to get the
yield yield from from the lights because
it's a small plant but instead of
picking the plant that was more robust I
want specifically to G to breed Miracle
glue number four which is very PM
resistant and was just absolutely loaded
with trikes so
now this Frosty MC fish that I want to
breed into it I literally am doing it as
we speak I watered them this morning I
got 13
males and as I mentioned before I I'm
really a big fan of root growth I'm I I
I still take my notes once a week on on
what I think root growth is but the uh
the primary driver for a male selection
to breathe to this miracle glue is PM
resistance so if you look at my tent
right now I got 13 plants about eight
nodes High and the and all the leaves
are touching every other leaves there's
no space between the plants right I got
13 decent sized plants filling up a a
4x4 I turn the air down and I shut off
all the
fans and and and I'm in a I'm in a
basement of a 30-year-old house I don't
have a problem getting PM all right I
can get PM anytime I want to get it so
uh so far I found three plants that had
pm and then I clean them I put them back
in and I rotate them so that they all
eventually over the next month will all
end up in a different spot so if there's
a real dead spot in the tent that that
one corner is always getting it or some
plant in The Middle's covered by leaves
they're always getting it I literally am
rotating the plants around now and I'm
telling you I'm doing as we speak so am
I going to be successful I have no idea
but my goal is if I'm really going to to
go after this miracle glue this is a
complimentary breeding because it's
generally the same I get to add in the F
the the the the the proven plants from
the Frosty mcfish and if I'm lucky out
of these 13 plants and it's not a huge
sample but out of these 13 plants if I
can find a couple that don't get PM
while the rest of them are getting PM
that's the primary motivator for me
selecting a mail so like you said grow
them out check the progyny do that stuff
like we were talking about in the
beginning I think that's fine doing root
selection and and morphology to match
something that's fine in this particular
case I already know the weed's good I
know the plants are good can I can I get
lucky and find something that's PM
resistant and breed it to another like
plant that's PM resistant that should
increase my odds of getting a really
nice plant that is less susceptible to
PM so that's what I'm trying to
do it's funny because it reminds me of
another strain in the sensey Seed
Catalog trying to remember I think it
was the Oasis but I'm not 100% sure but
it said that it was spider it
resistant and we wanted to buy that
strain for breeding because you know
this was in the '90s we really didn't
have a clue about how to deal with
pests and you know getting a strain that
spider might resistant that's like okay
got to have that you know so powdery
Milo resistant is
uh definitely a good quality but I mean
generally you know any of the plants
that are more vigorous and healthy are
going to be more resistant right yeah
but these are all you don't even have to
you don't even have to create a powdery
mildew Factory like you're trying to do
over there to to find the ones that get
it first you know you could pretty much
look at the plants that are strongest
and healthiest will generally be the
most
resilient that type stuff if you go if
you go look at the page they're all
solid I mean it's I mean because I I
I've you know my my intent is to breed
that way for root growth and solid
structure so out of the 13 I I actually
killed one this morning and and it's
because in the two times I tested it got
PM each time and it was one of the
weaker root plants so I no matter what
happens to that plant I would never use
it so I as of this morning I'm down to
12 but to go through that
process I mean you can find them I've
seen them you see them on a bench you
know plant the I I've got another one
that's it's a ghost dog it doesn't get
pm and and so I found a couple other so
in in addition to doing the stuff I like
with the long flowering I really want to
get this done because I I know it's good
weed and if I can create that other
input where these these jeans hook up
together and and give me some PM
resistance that's a big especially in
New England in the fall it it's a it's a
huge
plus you guys might one thing I wanted
to do at this time I wanted to direct
people to your Instagram which is Boston
Bob Mass no funky underscores or
anything just Boston Bob Mass yeah so
everybody go uh give them a follow only
if you're not trolls trolls stay away
trolls stay away so so so before before
you go let me let me finish up with one
thing can you throw up the number two
the picture of the plant
outside sure um are you growing
hydroponically or um with soil soil only
um how are you uh keeping track of the
root growth are you just popping it out
of the the container there and taking a
peek I that's why I don't I don't use
fabric right because you can't pull them
MH or or maybe you can but I can't I use
plastic pots I I and um I flip them all
the time when I when I start when I
start my seedlings I actually start my
seedlings in a 7 oz cup so I'm actually
looking at the root growth in the first
two weeks okay so I track that then they
go to a Solo Cup maybe sometimes they'll
go to one gallon I try to I try to upart
a minimum of three times four times if I
can so each time you know I'm I'm I'm
not using micro High I generally use
recharge I like recharge when I when I
dust my holes um and I I I just I
constantly check and I I try not you
know I I'll if I make a decision early
it's it's amazing actually over time and
it's not always true so I want to say
that it's absolutely not always true but
if you track root growth from a 7 ounce
to one gallon to a two gallon to a three
gallon you'll find out that the ones
that had the strongest root growth in
the first couple
weeks they they're the strongest plants
like throughout the whole cycle of the
plant now my guess is that's 80 to 90%
cuz there's always some that come on
late and they're really great plants so
it it's not a determining factor for me
but it's a piece of data to him now I
forgot so this th this
plant and the reason I'm showing is just
because we've talked about cfish mafish
number six was the mom we talked about
Frosty mcfish which is a complimentary
breeding that I'm going to use to
Miracle grou this is the mom so this is
from the
2022 23 24 I think this is this is a
2022 season I
think uh and that plant's 12 feet tall
and every one of those colas is bigger
than your arm he those are impressive
colas yeah be seated or not seated nope
we just growing the
plant um but so I use coasta main soil I
I don't use any
folur I keep the process really simple
and it gets rain or it gets watered and
that's about it I do some I do I do do
some IPM but I'm not I'm not doing
anything to accelerate the growth but
this
plant and just like the Mac right I mean
you know you don't get a ton of seeds
you get some different variations I was
joking around the stuff that comes from
Mac 1 is gems and junk which I like cuz
you can you can can the junk early and
there and there and there's some gems in
there so
um but when I talk about the breedings
and the intent and the males to be used
this is the girl I got in
22 and it takes years right you got to
grow out a couple to find the right one
then I find the right one it's like okay
what's going to be complimentary what's
what's going to go into this like I I
know that all the fish piss going to
have merine and carop philene in them
right so if I want a complimentary I'm
going to do something that's similar to
that I'm not necessarily going to hit it
with a with a you know a plant that's
all
piny right because I'm not sure what
that intend what that's going to produce
I know that if I take a a mercine and
caropine plant or or genetics that are
heavy in that then I'm going to get a
complimentary and I I may be able to
find something even a little better so
I'm always looking at the plants and
figuring how they can go together and
and with this one plant I did a
complimentary which we just showed the
frosty MC fish with a very uniform it's
really good weed and then I showed the
cfish which has got this bizarre
thinking man's weed in the
um um in the albinos so they both came
from the same
mom right I mean or or the this mom was
a key in both of those breedings and the
plants are going to be completely
different so you really can direct the
plant the way you want it to go well I
you can try like I said you're going to
have some fails but that's the fun far
for me I just wanted to show this CU we
were talking about all the the the moms
in the other breedings I know we haven't
scratched the surface with you so I hope
we can make some time you know like this
is ultra long form
over here we're not looking for you know
like before you said oh I'm just going
to tell you this quickly we don't want
you to tell us stuff quickly um we want
the the long form story but you know
that just might mean that we have to
schedule part two also I want to ask you
if you would want to do our other show
with Nick which is called The Way We
Grow I know he would love to have you on
because that one more focuses on
the way you grow you know and we can get
into depth on um on that but you know we
still have a little time and I hope
you'll accept my invitation to come back
you know as many times as it takes till
we get your story out there you are uh
the answer is yes and thank you and and
I'm the same as you he you start you
start talking about weed you could talk
about it forever well we probably don't
have time to even get into it but um I
still wanted to ask it just so you can
start thinking about it Bob um for the
Mac one I I've heard um and I don't know
if I'm pronouncing this correctly uh you
know it's that's what happens when you
read things you don't really speak about
it but I've heard that it's a triploid
uh which means that it has like a third
chromosone and it's one of the unique
traits of the Mac one but uh another
thing about that is it makes it really
hard to breed with um for some reason it
leaves you with a lot of immature seeds
and again this is just something I've
read about so the fact that you've
actually worked with this plant um it's
very interesting to me to hear you know
from your experience first hand um about
how that plant reacts to you know
breeding projects so Mac
one I I've seen the triploid back and
forth I I don't pay a ton of attention
to it because I know what the plant does
and I know what it can do right
so to me the plant itself is important
but not off track I I don't know that
I've ever got more
than 70
seeds off of a Mac one and and it it's
generally in the 25 to 50 range um and
they give you an EXA and it's kind of
strange we we we just finished talking
about that Frosty
mcfish
so no nobody really tells you what they
get for seeds because everybody wants to
buy seeds that they can't that nobody
else can get right so they don't talk
about the different numbers that Frosty
mcfish in a 4x4 tent at a 4ot plant gave
me
9,000
seats
and I'm growing them right now they're
all growing they're all German they're
all solid 9,000 seeds that that same
size plant if it was a Mac one would be
seeds and it's one of the reasons why
you don't see a lot of breeding in with
the Mac 1 cuz it's more work and you're
not going to get a ton of stuff like
that Mac fish 6 I don't think there's
any more seats I mean most of the ones I
have I have mac I did a Mac red which is
around I've
never I never released
it um it's around here but it's the same
thing I think I've got you know enough
seeds to maybe go and find one more
plant but we grew them over three years
and you end up basically with the max
you end up with one plant cuz you just
you don't have that many to search
through but yeah 100% it's it's a very
tough plant to get seeds out of I I
didn't even get dead seeds you just
don't get
them okay and is that a trait that
you've noticed it's passed along to The
Offspring that it's produced no cuz I
used the the Mac
fish um gave me a ton of seeds and then
the frosty Mac fish gives the plant they
gave me 9,000
seeds but you know the the mac's a nice
strong plant and and and it adds a whole
bunch of
frost and and the thing is you if you
bring flavor into it and I I tried to
bring the spice into it and the the fish
piss brings this kind of umami flavor in
um you bring flavor in
like talking to Gabby before about uh
you know the mail bringing structure and
stuff stuff like that without bringing
something to the party would not be a
great idea for me if it was the Mac one
I think you bring something into the Mac
one and you get something better
out but when you get see honestly when
you get stuff you're going to get some
junk like they're going to be squirly
and everybody wants to try to save that
squirrly plant because it could be the
next chem dog right I I I've never found
any success dealing with the squirely
plants coming out of the Mac I've tried
a couple and and from you know now it's
I I I know which ones are going to well
I think I know which ones are going to
turn out better so I'll focus on them
but yeah it's a it's an interesting
breeding plant I gave it up I mean
saying I would
never filial generation it so I did my
breedings with it and I passed it on to
a couple people as it was passed to me
so I have I haven't had the Mac one in a
couple
years yeah so we only have a couple
minutes left so before we go I wanted to
see if there was anything you wanted to
add we've already discussed that you'll
be back soon for part two and hopefully
be doing the way we grow podcasts but is
there anything you want to say before we
go today no I think you're doing a great
job I I um that's why I sent you the
text I I've watched a couple of them I
watched with Marcus I watch with you
know JRE I it's it's it's kind of fun
and and honestly if you look at your
subscribers relative to your um I don't
know what you call them yeah reviews
people are watching nice high percentage
so that you've got a good group of
people who are interested in the plant
and that's always a good place to be
right I mean we we can only watch the
the Australian podcast and we can only
watch FCP and we can only watch a couple
of these so much and you're out of
materials so you you know you have the
ability and potential to bring new
material and and and you like the story
format I I like what you're doing so I I
congrats to you
I like I said I I appreciate it the love
that we're getting on this podcast it
it's
unexpected and so so appreciated you
know like I don't think there's anyone
that couldn't use more positivity in
their life and it's been great you know
like every day I send Cosmic and uh wolf
a message saying look at look at these
comments and look at how many more views
these last videos got and like people
ask like what are you doing we're like
nothing it's it's totally
organic
um you know we don't we don't promote it
any you know at all um we've just had
we've been lucky to have really
interesting
guests join us right away we've been
lucky that somehow I mean can I ask how
did you find our
podcast honestly I'm not sure yeah
because like when I look you actually
you know what uh Mark Mark yellow oh
right okay because we we interviewed
Mark right I think Mark posted that he
was coming on and then I'm like oh and
then I'm like oh I mean so you know
there's couple thousand people follow
him so that's you know and and okay so
that's probably a good chunk right there
you
know yeah and I mean we did the video
with Kevin JRE and he's just like um
well I mean somebody's probably doing a
search for his name and Kevin's got a
pretty big
fallowing yeah I mean like I said we
we've been lucky to have good
guests and you're definitely included in
that like I said uh and and I think the
proof is in our text message I agreed to
have you on the podcast before I knew
anything about you and then I started
talking to you and I was like holy [ __ ]
this guy's pretty
ridiculous you know and with a great
story
so yeah I mean and you know what at the
same time what I like if if I'm giving
away plants and somebody gets better at
breeding then someday I may use that
plant to cross something else cuz I want
it with the same parent so the more
people I can help the better the
genetics are going to be and that's
that's a benefit for everybody so I I I
truly enjoy it I really
do you know earlier in the podcast you
said you're doing this because of you
know your ego but I don't really think
that that's true it is kind of true I
mean I think that a bigger part of it is
how much you love the planet
you know it's cool that it feeds your
ego too like like I said when people um
thank me for doing the podcast and tell
me how much they love me it's feeding my
ego a little bit but I am still doing it
because in the end I love it and I love
having these conversations so it can be
both you can feed your ego and you can
love the plant and it's clear that you
love the plant we even spoke um about
yesterday how if you to choose to stop
smoking or stop growing you would choose
to stop smoking because you just you
just love growing and breeding the plant
and well it's honestly it's it's OCD
what happens is is OCD kicks in and it
just happened that when it kicked in on
weed 10 years ago it kind of never went
away and it's become
primary I did Greyhounds for a bunch of
years I ra I drag race motorcycles like
if I get into did Greyhounds did you
breed them yeah it's like becoming a
very common thread that all of the great
breeders that I'm that I'm meeting that
they bred dogs as well I mean I get all
the stud books I used to study horse
breeding I mean half of the thorough
Breads in the world come from like five
horses right in five Arabian
so you know I I the breeding is
fascinating I I love the genetics
well we really loved talking to you and
I'm going to call you back immediately
after the new year and try to like fit
you in right away because like I said I
really want to release I don't want to I
don't want people to feel like I'm
teasing them and dragging them along and
making them wait weeks for part two
again I'm grateful for you Bob I'm
grateful I'm grateful for you reaching
out yeah happy New Year guys
[Music]
this episode of gabbing with Gabby is
brought to you by the Breeders direct
Seed Company in my opinion the Breeders
direct seed company is your Premier
Source for clones and seeds and they are
the only place that you can get the
Gabby Staten Island collection so visit
breeders direct for all your seed and
clone needs