[Music]
What's up everybody? is Gabby Staten
Island on the Craft Growers Network. And
of course, we're joined by my co-hosts
Cosmic and Sasha, the Slovenian Hobbit.
And today, our guest is JJ Edwards from
Top Dog Seeds. Um, we've done a few
episodes regarding the sour, including
with Klopp, and it was definitely
something that was high on my list is to
have a conversation with JJ because he
was extremely relevant to the sour
story. As a matter of fact, far more
relevant than I am. You know, people
generally or regularly say, "Hey, Gabby,
I want to thank you for your involvement
in the sour." And I tell them I really
had nothing to do with it. I mean, I was
living on the West Coast and, you know,
we got the sour cuts out here and, you
know, I've grown a lot of sour, more
sour than than most people, I think. But
JJ was in the heart of the sour scene in
New York. He used to do business with
KOP. And so, um, really nice to have you
finally, JJ, and tell us your weed
story. No, I I appreciate it. And, um, I
don't deserve all those accolades. Um, I
was, well, I didn't say you were cool or
anything. I just said you were relevant.
You know, I was, you know, I was lucky
enough to be, you know, in the right
place at the right time. And um you know
and really a lot of those accolades go
to some of the other people that that
created the the Sour Diesel like you
know Klopp was part of it and you know
AJ had a big part of the you know the
distribution and getting the the
popularity out there. So you know I I
was just one of those people that were
kind of along along for the ride. But um
you know just I guess you know starting
from you know the beginning um you know
I you know I started first I first
smoked weed when I was 13 and I think
that was like in 1979 and it was I think
it was like a it was a snowy
uh Christmas day actually and we used to
go out shoveling snow to make money and
me and my neighbor and so We, you know,
it had snowed. We, you know, got our
shovels. We went out. We're going to
shovel some, uh, driveways and sidewalks
and, um, he pulled out a joint. You
know, he had some older brothers and I
guess he had gotten a joint from them.
And, you know, we were in the woods and
we smoked it. And that was basically,
you know, my first experience with it. I
was probably in seventh grade at the
time. And um so you know you know
growing up in middle school I probably
you know had a couple more
experiences with weed but it wasn't
really a a regular thing for me until I
hit high school. And you know when we
hit high school you know it was kind of
turned into an everyday thing. There was
people smoking. There were people
selling uh loose joints for a dollar
back then if you if you could believe
that. You know, people used to just uh
take a a marbor box, fill it up with
joints, bring it, you know, into, you
know, the school in the beginning of
school and you would be able, you know,
we had a smoking
section on grounds and so everyone would
smoke their cigarettes and we smoked our
weed there, too. So that's where, you
know, pretty much going up through high
school, I um, you know, when you're when
you're smoking and buying weed, you're
actually starting to sell it to your
friends and stuff. So like
unknowingly, you kind of just start into
the business if you're buying it and
your friend is like, "Oh, sell me
something five or $10 worth."
you know, and then before you know it,
you're kind of wheeling and dealing a
little bit, making trying to make free
weed basically back then, you know, and
so, you know, that was really my first
experiences really, you know, getting
coming up through high school. um you
know experiencing kind of the the
late7s you know early 80 well I would I
would describe the late7s as kind of the
chich and chong era and it kind of was
kind of the Panama
reds you know the poker golds the
Colombian golds
um and you were getting that as a kid um
I no I I had gotten the Colombian gold
one time and it was this really bright
gold kind of sativa.
Um, it was kind of grassy the way that
it looked almost, you know, but it
wasn't really loose, but it was it was
kind of loose but not super
loose, but you know, and my friend's
brother who was older, you know, we had
split um we split an ounce and we got a
half ounce each of it. And, you know, at
the time it wasn't he didn't say it was
gold or anything like that, but we I was
like, man, I've never seen weed like
this before. And then, you know, looking
at pictures of the real stuff, you know,
I recognized it right away. And uh so I
was really too young to really like
remember I was it was probably more
sativa uppidity high. I don't remember
it really being that devastating or
anything like that, but I was probably
too young to really
um recognize the the effects and the
specialness of it. you know, and so we
used to get some good tie back then, uh,
the Hawaiian, but really, you know,
leading up until, you know, I would say
81,82, everything was strictly import.
So, we would always just see the
Mexicans and the and the Colombians and
Jamaicans basically, you know, and the
ties would, you know, rarely come in.
But uh but then there was you know the
that's when the the real centy bud came
out and we called it the Christmas tree
bud and it was just this the the green
centy bud that came out of Cali. I guess
it was pretty much uh outdoor light
depth looking back at it. Um you know
had a little bit of a sativa twist to it
very piny and stuff. So, that was pretty
much like the first kind of kind bud, if
you want to call it that, uh, that I
experienced. Uh, other than the
Hawaiian, the Hawaiian bud would come in
and I remember that. Well, both both of
both of them were back then was 200
bucks an ounce. And so we're we're
talking early 80s and um compared to
like you can get an ounce of Mexican or
so for 40 bucks or 30 bucks. So that was
you know it was quite a big difference
in uh in in price. So, um, yeah, that
was really kind of my first experience
in in in in the in in the kind bud and,
you know, and as you know, um, you know,
I graduated high school and such and so
people started going into um into New
York City and and and scoring weed. And
so that's, you know, I started or a
friend of mine introduced me to someone
he had hooked up with and, you know, I
got an inn right away. And uh so we
would be able to go there and get 1,200
lb
uh 12 $1,200 pounds of uh pretty much
really good green maximum mids that were
kind of um we call them the you know the
pillows cuz they would you know you
would be able to break one up and fill
up a whole gallon baggie inside of you
that would be your pillow pretty much.
And so we would we would, you know, get
those and um bring them back to Jersey.
And so, uh, that was really my first,
you know, then I was able to tap into
the to the local scene of the exotics of
the stuff that they were bringing in.
And, um, so I was able to see a lot of
different stuff, you know, in the mid
mid to late, uh, 80s or Yeah. it because
I pretty much probably started going in
the city around
85. And so from 85 going
onwards, you know, I, you know, was just
had a, you know, a plug in the city. He
had an apartment and you could just go
up and cherry pick what you wanted, what
he had for
sale. And then I wound up I wound up in
the park in 1991.
Sheep's sheep's meadow. But we're
actually it was 92. Well, I first went
up there in '91. I scoped out the scene
and I seen it was just an open air drug
market kind of like, you know, the same
thing that you were doing in in San
Francisco in Golden Gate Park. And there
was a connection between Sheep Meadow
and Golden Gate Park because a lot of
the hippies that they would just travel
back and forth, you know, to both
places. And you know, you know, people
would mention to me Golden Gate Park,
that's where you go and you be able to
buy acid and buy weed and mushrooms and
psychedelics. And it was the same scene
in in Sheep's Meadow, you know, when I
first went in there. And so when I want
Sheep's Meadow was a really cool place.
Yeah. You know, like particularly in
when the weather was nice, Sheep's
Meadow was just like a magical place
where not, you know, cuz you know, the
Golden Gate Park over by the Hayda
Ashberry. It was really kind of a seedy
scene, you know. It was it was dark. It
was dark. Well, Chief was dark, too. if
you I mean on but what I was going to
say is in the summertime even Sheep's
Meadow would be you know would be really
there'd be families there too but in the
midst of all of that someone would pull
out a gun or I I I saw firsthand you
know I mean I got robbed there too but
it wasn't in the summertime it was more
like you know later in the season as
actually as it got more packed it got
more dangerous because it was hard to
see like the commote what was going on
at the time, you know, I saw some kid
trying to well, I I watched a scammer.
He used to uh he used to sell fake hits
and the guy was kind of big. He had just
gotten out of jail months beforehand and
I was aware of who he was and he was
trying to, you know, there's like this
young like 17-year-old high school kid
was trying to buy some hits from him and
they were fake and the kid was looking
at him and then he was like unsure and
then he had the money in his hand and
then eventually the [ __ ] dude just
[ __ ] yolked him around to [ __ ]
tried choking him out and grabbing his
money. And this was like just in the
same environment as you described,
families, kids, like it was just crazy
back then. So like you know it was you
know even though you know there would be
people like JFK Jr. up there um all
types of actors,
celebrities, you know um it it was a
really it was really a really cool scene
back then. But, you know, as I um you
know, before the before that, you know,
I um you know, so I first got in there
in ' 91, I started, you know, I saw the
scene. I I prepared myself for, you
know, during the winter because during
the winter, that's when all the good
weed would come in. So, like some of
these really good like high-end Mexis
came in and they were like, you know, it
was kind of like the Bratendica weed
back in the day. If you're in my the
botendica, you know, and that was like
really good Mexi and there was like
maybe a few seeds in there. So if you
were really slick, you were able to pop
those seeds out and present it almost as
kind bud. So um you know I had gotten
some of that and I that was the first
fakers. Right. Right. So I you know I
saw this you know the potential of this.
So, I was just going to bag up Ace and
just sell it straight up, you know. So,
you know, I got a good price on it and
and that's what I did. I hit the park
and I just started selling, you know,
ace of that Mexi out there and I didn't
really have any I didn't really have any
really straight Kind Bud connections or
grower connections back then. Like I had
my main plug and he would get exotics
here and there and whatever. So, but I
didn't really have my main connection.
And then, you know, uh, you know, one
day that all changed. You know, I met I
met Mike Klopp out there and, um, the
weasel. The weasel. Yeah. So, I mean,
when I met Mike, um, he had the skunk
one, two, and three. So, that was the
RFK one, two, and three. So you know uh
proceeding you know that that's when you
guys you kind of um you know did you
know your whole thing with you know the
RFK and you know how he inspired you to
grow and then you inspired him to grow
and then eventually Mike inspired me to
grow. So, it was like a really kind of
real, you know, full circle kind of a
thing, you know, didn't it didn't start
off like that. But, you know, but when I
first met Mike, you know, and I and he
was um he was just selling the, you
know, RFK one, two, and three. So, and I
was just, you know, he he was a grower
and I was just like, "Listen, dude. I'll
take everything you got." Cuz he had he
had everything broken down into
quarters. And he was like, "Oh, well,
I'm going to try sell all of them." I
said, "Listen, how much do you want for
him?" And I'll take them all. Boom. You
know, and then and and you know, so I
just wanted to lock him in. And
eventually I did, you know, and you
know, the the business, you know, he
started getting a little bit bigger.
Then he was like, "Hey, listen. You
know, maybe we shouldn't meet in the
park anymore. We should go down to
Wetlands." He's like, "You go down to
Wetlands on Tuesday. It's Grateful Dead
night. And you know, they have a a drum
circle and stuff, you know, you could
smoke weed, blah blah blah. And so we
went down there and it was like, you
know, it was really cool down there. And
so
downstairs in the wetlands where they
had all the pillows. Yes. Yes. Well,
they had a green peace meeting in, you
know, before that. So as soon as a green
peace meeting wrapped up, you know,
everyone would be just sitting there
hanging out with, you know, with, you
know, a guitar, some
bongos,
tambourine, whatever little instrument
you had, you know, and so, uh, you know,
once the Greenpeace meeting wrapped up,
then everyone would just start, you
know, start jamming a little bit,
getting the scene going. They would
start playing some, you know, dead
music. you know, some nights he had a
cover band. Uh, you know, so it was a
really really cool scene back then. And
um, so, you know, we, you know, that's
how we kind of first met AJ. And so,
like, you know, somehow or another, he
just kind of sniffed us out because it
was just me meeting me meeting Mike down
there, you know, and so, you know, we
would do the deal and, you know, then we
would be able to spark up and kind of
relax and kind, you know what I mean?
And so that's when we first met AJ and
you know he he sniffed out you know the
the you know the I think by then we
might he might have gotten the the chem
the the chem dog by then and um so
that's you know yeah pretty much that
you know he had the chem 91 back then
you mean the weasel not AJ no not AJ the
weasel had it and so you know he he
sniffed He sniffed out the 91 and me and
him were smoking. And then he just kind
of he's like, "Hey, you know, if you
want, we can go into the back office cuz
he was an intern for the Greenpeace
meeting and and also for, you know, uh,
the bar and stuff. So, you know, he had
a back office. So, we used to be able to
go right into the back office, you know,
and have like four or six people there,
break out all of our weed, just kind of
start throwing down,
smoking, selling this and that. And um
yeah, that's how that whole thing really
kind of first started. And um and that's
when, you know, AJ kind that's when
Diesel first got coined because he'd be
like, "Yo, you guys got any of that
diesel?" you know, meaning the 91, but
meaning like back then diesel was kind
of just a catch name for stuff that was
really strong, you know, so like a lot
of things were diesel back then, so it
wasn't just weeds. So, you know, that's
kind of where the the you first called
diesel and then, you know, I you know, I
remember smoking a a Jay with someone
down there and I and I passed it to him
and he's smoking on it. He's like, he's
like, "Uh, is this organic?" And I'm
like, I'm like, "No, I don't think you
know." At the time, I wasn't growing. I,
you know, I didn't know. I was like,
"No, I don't think so." You know, he
goes, "What's the name of this stuff?" I
was like, "It's called Chem Dog." He's
like, "Chem Chem." He's grown with
chemicals, this and that. And he's just
like, you know, because of the smell and
everything. Then he just started going
off on this tangent. So then after that,
I was like, "Oh, wow. maybe we should
just, you know, get rid of the get rid
of the cam and just kind of call it
diesel or, you know, so that's kind of u
kind of the direction it kind of went in
in the beginning with with the 91 was
kind of I had a similar I had a
similar feeling and story myself. I
don't know if you've heard it on my
podcast, but when I got the Chem Dog
from Greg, I was an organic grower.
And I was like, I'm not going to call
this [ __ ] the chem dog. Like, I'm
growing it organic. So, I I just used to
call it the dog, you know, because for
me at that point, I was offended by the
idea of growing with mineral salts,
which, you know, I've I've come a long
way since then, but yeah, I just called
it the dog, not the chem dog. Yeah.
There. And back then it wasn't called
the 91, you know, there was it was just
the chem right at the time. Yeah. But
there back then there was just like this
whole kind of hippie dippy kind of
organic kind of thing going on back then
and no one really had the really the
real knowledge behind all of it.
Especially back then, everyone was just
kind of trying to work with guanos and
other kind of stuff like that. And so,
you know, that just stuff just really
turned into a
nightmare in in the end. So, it was just
so much work and, you know, you know, it
was still really hard to pull off. So,
you know, especially if you're if you're
growing for production. So, uh you know,
you just got to really start making some
decisions on on really what what you're
doing. But back then, none of that was
ever really none of that was really
thought of. you know, is this a matter
of, you know, a lot of people just had,
you know, grows in their in their in
their closet or their bedrooms or, you
know, one or two lights and, you know,
that that's really how it started. You
know, people didn't start out with these
big elaborate, you know, five or 10
light grows. They were, you know, happy
just to pull one or two lights off, you
know, because we didn't know what the
[ __ ] we were doing back then, you know.
It was really a And also, we were
getting such a high price that with two
lights, we were making a great Right.
Right. You're right about that. It's
funny when you think about saying, you
know, two to five lights as an elaborate
grow, you know, but back then it was.
Yeah. If you had five lights back then,
you were just crushing. You were making
so much money. Yeah. But if you're
getting, you know, 4 or 500 an ounce
straight up, like and you and you can't
grow enough of it, like, you know, and
that's kind of like how it was because
really there weren't really that many
people that were really growing back
then and growing, you know, the super
fire stuff, you know, on top of it, you
know. So there, you know, there were
people who were growing, but you know,
when people smelled the Chem Dog, when
they smelled the Sour Diesel, you know,
it was something like they've never seen
before and people just started going
crazy for it. And, you know, and just,
you know, touching on, you know, the the
sour, you know, it was really, you know,
AJ that really kind of, you know, got
that popularized down in the city. And
you know at the time I was just kind of
you know selling weed and I was you know
I was close to the sources of you know
uh of KOP who you know where those seeds
first started off at and you know but
even before that Mike had made the
underdog which I don't know if you ever
remember the underdog and it was 91
times the well he's told me two
different stories on it. Originally,
when I first remember him telling me, he
told me it was NL Super Skunk Times the
91.
Now he says it was just the NL times the
91. But after after you know I didn't
after growing it and smoking it like
there was definitely some skunk in there
because NL's are kind of
blandish and and the 91 could kind of
you can kind of say the same thing about
it other than the cheminess to it you
know there is no real fun you know like
skunk skunkiness sort to speak to it you
know kind of like I would say the chem
is more skunkier than the 91
So the 91 I think is more like OG. Yeah.
And and really, you know, and it's funny
that you say that because I think the
same thing and and if you think about it
now, if the story that's true about the
OG being um now the guy that tells the
story says it was
um what did he say it was? It was Hindu
Kush times the em or the the emerald
triangle, which we don't know what the
emerald triangle was, but we do know the
Hindu Kush that he had gotten at the
time from Neville. Well, that was NL2
times um Kush number
four. And I've also I've grown out to
NL2 recently from Todd McCormick. And I
can tell you when you look when the
growth that of the NL2 compared to the
to the 91 and the Kush, it's they're
pretty much the same. you know, the the
tur profiles are a little bit different,
but the the
popcorn style nugs and the way that it
stretches out and everything, you know,
and even Neville himself when he first
saw the OG, he said he's like, "Yeah,
that's my NL2 is in there." So, he
recognized it. So, you know, I have a,
you know, it might be, you know,
different type of of a mixture, but I
would say NL2 is probably in both the
the the Kush and in the
91 from my experience, from what I what
I've grown out, you know. So, you know,
it's it's funny that that that you
mention that.
I mean, to me, it's obvious when when
you taste and, you know, most people I I
could say even today most people have
zero experience smoking the Chem Dog,
you know, the 91, but when I smoke any
OG or or the Chem Dog, it's it's like
they're sisters, right? I agree. You can
definitely you can definitely you can
definitely taste that. But, you know,
but then, you know, we don't know what
the the emerald triangle was, you know.
So, there that that definitely had some
kind of like gassiness it seems like
whatever. But to me, the question is
where does that where's that chem? Where
does that chem funk come from? And so
that's, you know, to me, I think it's
got to be some type of
Afghan or Hindu Kush or something along
those lines because you just don't
really get that fooliness really out of
any kind of like Mexican sativa or
anything like that. That's other that
that has been suggested in the past, you
know. So, you know, that that's the you
know, that's the question is where does
that like, you know, even with the the
chem you you get that garlic oniony kind
of thing going on and you know and then
originally you know you had the the 91
and the sister, you remember the sister
and the sister was kind of like the
sativa version of the chem like they
both smelled exactly the same but grew
totally different and the effects were
totally different, you know, where the
sister was more of that sativa kind of
more stretchy, more kind of uplifting
kind of, you know, but it still kind of
had that garlic oniony kind of profile
that the Chem D has. And the Chem D is
more of a more indigga, more, you know,
heavyhitting type of um, you know,
plant. And so even in you know um you
know there there's there's lots of um
hybrids sativa indiga hybrids even in uh
Afghanistan and Pakistan you know as you
get up north more as you're getting
towards the Indian borders in Nepal and
all that you know you start getting into
I think a little bit more uh sativa type
of plants that could possibly you
especially on the more going towards
India I would say that would maybe you
know display some of these you know
traits but you know all that is kind of
speculation on my part and you know I
don't have any real proof to really you
know behind any of that but you know at
this point we only kind of have that to
go on is what we know and what the
history of certain things are in certain
regions and stuff. And unfortunately, a
lot of that's been lost because of wars
and and and and stuff like that. So, you
know, there isn't like, you know, any of
us could really go on go on the ground
over there and try to do any kind of
research or whatever. But even what what
Kevin Jod Reed did was, you know, you
got to have a set of balls to really,
you know, go over there. You know, at
that point, your life is in these other
people's hands. You know, you know, I I
wouldn't feel safe unless I had an an
armed security guard with me at at all
times because just the the appearance of
you could just, you know, make someone
want to do something possibly. So, um,
you know, I I tip my hat for for to him
to, you know, for having the balls to do
that.
Yeah, I I agree. I would say you would
need more than one armed guard. Well, I
I I would want more than one armed guard
because what's one guy with a gun going
to do against right 10 people with a
gun? So, but so one question I want to
ask since you've got the Dancing Bears
behind you. When did you get into the
Grateful Dead? Um my first show
was spring of 87 at the Brendan Burn
Arena.
Opening song was Dancing in the Streets.
Nice. And you got the dancing bears
behind you. My first show was at the
same location but in 1988.
Brendan Burn 33088 was that shows and
the reason why I wanted to ask was
because well first of all because I'm a
dead head but second of all was you
didn't find Kind Bud at the Grateful
Dead shows and weren't able to make any
connections for for nice weed there. You
had to wait you know because you saying
you weren't getting any of that till you
know 91. Well, I was getting it I was
getting it some from my plug, you know,
in the city, you know, but it wasn't
like I was directly, you know, connected
to the grower or anything. And in here,
when I used to go into the shows,
everyone would go shopping park, you
know, in the parking lot on Shakedown
Street and everything. Um, but I never,
you know, when I went to the shows, it
really wasn't my focus to do business
really. It was really my focus was more
to enjoy myself, let my guard down and
you know have a good time and
everything. So, uh, you know, when
you're high on mushrooms and acid,
sometimes it's hard to navigate, you
know, doing things. So, uh, yeah, you
know, I so I never really made any
really major connections on tour or
anything like that. I wouldn't, you
know, I wasn't really a tour head. I
mean, I would go to most local shows,
the local shows, you know, I would, you
know, go out on the East Coast or, you
know, we would, you know, plan plan a
trip here or there, but uh, no, I I
wasn't someone that went on on on tour
on every on on every show or whatever.
And so, you know, I stayed within my
means and my bounds. And, you know, at
that time, you know, I was really just
trying to get my [ __ ] together.
and you know you and figure out life you
know because you know you know you're
trying to you know think about doing a
career and then you're hustling on the
side and so you see how much money is
kind of being made and you know it's a
hard decision you know and you know I
went the route of you know going into a
trade school and learning you know a a
craft in the union and you know and
trying to have some kind of legitimate
uh skills to be able to survive on other
than kind of hustling and and and you
know dedicating my life full time to to
hustling and and selling weed you know
and kind of looking back now how things
have kind of shaken out and you know
some of those people now that kind of
went the route of just doing the the
hustle now they find themselves in a in
in a spot now because of legalization
and things aren't the way they used to
and now they don't have no job skills to
survive on on the outside. Now you find
yourself 60 65 years old with no job
skills. You got minimal money. you
might, you know, own a house or have
some kind of equity behind you, but you
know, trying to, you know, uh, trying to
make money, you know, in that type of,
uh, you know, in today's, you know,
times and everything, it's it's really
tough. You know, back in the day, it was
easy for anyone to to pick up a job. The
only thing you had to do is pick up a
newspaper and look in the want ads, you
know, that doesn't exist anymore, you
know, like And back in the day in New
York City, you could be a terrible
grower and still make good money. Yeah.
You know, like you could grow shitty
weed, get a shitty yield, sell it wet
and still be and still and still be sell
wet and still be crushing. Nowadays, you
can be growing really good weed and
still struggle selling it and and
struggle selling it for a price where
you could actually even just pay the
bills to grow it. Well, well, now I
think you know, you know, it's really
it's all about the retail now. So, if
you if you're growing, you know, if you
got a home grow and you know, you got to
have your own customers basically. You
know, there's no more wholesale. So,
there's no more, you know, so all the
people that you're selling to are all
consuming it, you know. Maybe you might
get a few people that you know might
take something, but like for the for for
the prices
like and you know and and as a as a
grower, as a craft grower, what is the
bottom? You know what I mean? What's the
b what's the bottom per pound that
you're willing to go? So here, you know,
I don't think we've found out. Yeah. You
know, to me, I mean, anywhere there's it
ranges. It could be $24 to
$3,000, you know, and and it really all
depends on how good of a grower you are,
how good your product is, and and where
you're willing to stand, you know, and
if you're like, listen, my my my units
are 3Gs straight up, you know, and if
you're only producing X amount of
product and you're able to sell it
before the next crop, before the next
crop,
you know that's that's all that's what
you you know so it's better to have a
demand than have an oversaturation and I
think and that's where I think you know
the the commercialized legal market has
made the the mistake because they've
made these massive grows you know that
cost a lot of money to you know to keep
up distant payroll and just monthly
expenses is and just as you explained
like all right so you got it doesn't
matter how many square feet you have if
you ain't selling all that weed before
your next
crop
then you it's just a race to the bottom
you know what I mean so to me I think
it's being better to be micro being
small craft producing a higher quality
product that's going to sell out and be
in
demand and then then you could build
your business model off of that if you
want to upscale off of that. But
starting off off of these big upscale
projects just don't work. This doesn't
work. The majority of them fail. Yes.
And otherwise, well, the majority of
them are back door and pounds out the
[ __ ] back. And that's the only way
they are surviving. Everyone, not the
majority. Every single one. anyone
anyone that tells you that they're not
back throwing the weed is just you know
trying to protect their privacy and you
know you know and so to me you know if
you if you can do this craft thing and
then and go right from you know farmer
to consumer like that's the best
business model that there is. There's no
middleman. It's from from you know seed
to sale uh small small craft farmer
markets higher quality higher profits
you know you know per per unit should we
say now overall sales per year yeah you
may be limited but listen if you're just
you know you know one or two people you
know how many how much money do you need
every you know you know what I'm And
like you just got to be happy for what
for what you get
and just be thankful that you're doing
something that you love and getting paid
for it. You know, like I like to make it
the analogy of comparing it to being in
music where you don't have to be a
superstar. You could be a music teacher
and if you can make a living off of
teaching people how to play guitar or
piano and you're doing something that
you love and you're getting paid for it,
like that's a win for me. Yeah. It's
also a hard life. I I've done that. I
had my own teaching company. Um I was
going to say though, you know, with
those commercial growers, one of the
other things that they've done is
they've essentially flooded the market
and they've lowered prices
significantly. you know, I'm here in
Southern California and um you know, I'm
luckily in a position where I have a
career. I don't, you know, I I do my
breeding stuff for fun. I don't have to
rely on anything, you know, to help pay
the bills. Um but from what I
understand, you know, pounds out here,
even for high quality product, it's like
1,800, you know, two grand, you know,
for a pound. And that's for the best
quality product. Exactly. Exactly. And
And that's hard to get. I mean, most
people they're just they don't really
care too much, you know. They can go to
their local dispensary and get ounces
for what, 60, 70, 80 bucks, you know,
and in their mind that's what the price
is now. It doesn't matter if it's craft
or if it's commercial, you know, the
average person, you know, at least. So,
I remember I remember it was uh the
early 2000s or yeah, somewhere in the
2000s when Sunrown in California was
dropping below $1,000 a pound. And
everyone thought that that was the end.
They couldn't believe that they couldn't
get $1,000 a pound for their outdoor
weed. And today, that same weed is a
couple hundred bucks.
You know, like you you can get really
really nice outdoor weed, not greenhouse
for 300 bucks, 200 bucks, and like the
best greenhouse
weed, maybe not like light assisted, but
just greenhouse weed, if you can get
four or $500 for that, you're absolutely
crushing, you know. And and I remember
some oldtime growers that thought, you
know, $1,000 a pound. Anything less than
that was just how how do you survive?
And also think about it, that was $1,000
a pound 20 plus years ago. So with the
value of money having changed, you know,
it's it's become very difficult to make
a living growing weed these days is is
the reality. And also I think it's know
knowing who your customers are and and
trying to market yourself towards them
because right now you know the market is
just flooded with mids you know just
flooded you know so you know as just as
cosmic was saying like most
people you know weed is weed right to to
to people like us weed isn't weed so you
you you know so when you're in the mids
game like you're you're not really
particularly you
know trying
to you know uh overdo things for people
as as in promotions and stuff. If it is,
it is what it is. Where where you know
where where you're trying to do a more
higher connoisseur clientele then you
know you got to get people's attention
you know it's like you know and so you
know and really you know it it comes
down to the product speaking for itself.
You know, when something is that good
and and it's shown
around and then it gets recognized, you
know, then it becomes it becomes its own
thing, you know. So, you can't really,
you know, you can't really make that up.
The only thing you could do is you put
something in the market and, you know,
the market determines kind of like, you
know, what it is. And so, you know, when
you're dealing with a higher connoisseur
type of people that are weed nerds
essentially that know everything about
weed, you know, you know, so that, you
know, those going to be the your more
craft kind of customer, you know, where
you know, they come in, they're going to
want to know, you know, what's behind
the lineage of this and that. And, you
know, you know, you know, when you're
talking to a bud tender and they tell
you, well, it's a sativa. That's all I
know. it's a sativa or it's a hybrid or
you know whatever and
so I think you know you know knowledge
behind the product and the way that you
know you market yourself and all of that
and you know all of that is very
relevant in today's because you know
kids kids now you know you're on
Instagram and you're just kind of
scrolling through scrolling through you
know then all of a sudden you see that
picture of a of a bud with diamonds on
it you know and all of a sudden you stop
and look at it and you're like, "Wow,
that looks amazing." you know, and you
give it a like, you know, and you might
[ __ ] give it a fire comment or
something like that, you know, but you
know, and that's kind of like what we're
kind of um you know, is just like
driving down the highway and you see a
billboard with a bikini girl on, you're
going to take a look at it, you know,
and so everything is kind of like, you
know, uh you know, for for the moment.
And I think, you know, as as turpps are
now become a big part of of of the
equation, it's just not the looks of it.
Now you're talking about the smell of
things. And so when you open a open a
jar of that old school sour diesel and
you and you just smell it and you just
kind of like, you know, all all of a
sudden all of these other senses get
activated in your brain. You know the
smell of the the sense of smell is very
strong. you know, it's like smelling a
woman or smelling something that is
enticing and and so, you know, you you
know, I kind of, you know, compare
cannabis the same way because when you
crack that jar and and you smell that,
you know, and that's the first thing,
you know, how you how you judge things
is by the smell and now now you look at
it and you smells amazing and it looks
amazing that so that must mean that it
must be amazing, you know and as we all
know that's not always the case. You
know trying to get something to check
all the boxes is is is very rare. You
know there are you know a lot of things
that do fit that description but um you
know that's kind of like you know you
know where I think you know the future
is. You know it's just um you know it's
it's ever changing market. you know,
even when you're judging something, you
know, if you're in a contest or
whatever, you know, I could speak from
my past experiences being a judge, you
know, once you smoke like the fifth or
10th thing, the effect is non-existent,
you know. So, so by So, if you're
judging now, what are you judging?
You're not judging by effect anymore.
Now, you're judging by the way that it
smells and the way that it looks, you
know? So, Noto Dog mentioned something
similar in one of his podcasts as far as
the uh ego clash, which is a hash
competition here in California. And he
said, you know, you're judging so much
hash in such a short period of time
that, you know, after the first couple
of dabs, that's it. There there's really
no way to do it. Now the um the Emerald
Cup is a little bit better because they
give the judges like judging packs and
you know they have them for you know
over a month. So they're you know they
have time to go through it and you know
be a little bit more conscious of the
effect. But even with that they have so
many entries that they're going through
that it's pretty hard to judge the
height. No, it is.
Yeah. So, um I I wanted to we talked
about Klopp and the sour story a little
bit, but I wanted to get back to that
just a little because I feel like we we
glossed over it and the sour is
something that, you know, not only a lot
of people want to know about, but it's
also a a big part of the work that
you're doing today. Yeah. You know, so I
have some thoughts about the sour. You
know, I was, you know, I was there, you
know, um, buying weed from Klopp the
whole time. And so, you know, what we do
know is that, you know, seeds were found
in the bag of 91 that Klopp sold to
Vondo. And Vondo uh, lived upstate with
a guy named
Maxwell. And they both lived together.
And um they sprouted those seeds that
they found from Klopp uh that became the
diesel number one and
two. And um recently Maxwell went on a
different
podcast and he kind of elaborated on he
came, you know, because Maxwell was uh
he had dropped out of the scene. He had
started a
family, you know, and just really got
back on the internet.
within the p past couple years. And so a
AJ went on a podcast with him and they
kind of confirmed a few things I didn't
know really at the time. But so those
guys were both living together. Had the
diesel one and two. Um they were growing
that, but also they had in their room uh
the RFK I guess that Klopp gave them.
And they also had a purple Kush seed
that they had gotten from Kyle Kushman.
And uh you know, I've talked to Maxwell
and we've kind of bounced back and forth
some some different ideas, but we do
know that those four plants were in the
in the room. Diesel one, Diesel 2, RFK,
Purple
Kush. One of those plants, Herme.
Well, we do know that the RFK had a
very strong reputation of of of herming
and that was one of the reasons why
Klopp got rid of it. Especially if you
didn't clip off the lower branches, it
usually would throw a herm or
two. So, you know, that to me, you know,
that probably would be one of the
strongest candidates to that would have
harmed in the room and it it it it
pollinated. I don't know if it was the
diesel one or the diesel 2. Uh they grew
they grew out that stuff and uh sold um
that weed to a guy named
Manny. And Manny found the seeds and
grew them out that really became the the
sour diesel.
And so we know that um I I know I'm not
really I'm not 100% sure but um I'm
pretty sure that Vondo went out to
California and I don't know if he had
the Diesel one or Diesel 2 clone or he
had gotten seeds
from Manny but there seems to be some
kind of connection. I guess Vondo you
have when when was that?
Well, it had to be
Vondo I think that he left for
California in 94.
Mhm. And are you saying that he did the
uh got those seeds before then? Well, he
Well, all those guys were friends and
they were part of this Skynctity Albany
crew. So, because to give you to give
you a little information, when Vondo
came out to California, he had nothing.
Had nothing and didn't know how to grow
and I know this because I gave him
everything and taught him how to grow. I
was partners with him. So, he didn't
come out with the sour or the 91 or He
didn't have any of that stuff.
Yeah, you'd have to Yeah, you'd have to
um clarify that with him, but you know,
I heard that, you know, there was a
rumor that he might have had brought
seeds out there. I don't know if that
was true or not. You'd have to, you
know, have to ask him. And really, the
real players in the whole sour story is
really, you know, Vondo, Maxwell, and
Manny. At the end of the day, those
three guys, AJ, myself, and other people
were kind of involved afterwards, you
know, AJ more than me. I know that
um Manny, you know, he was connected to
the bro, you know, Keith in Albany. So,
that was, you know, that that connection
with the bro. Uh, the bro brought sour
clones out to Amsterdam at some point in
the
'9s. Um, I guess through Manny. Uh so
you know so really you know these guys
are still around you know and you know
you know you can really you know if you
can get Maxwell on and and Vondo on and
Manny on you know those you know those
guys are the ones that that really know
these really intricate details. I mean,
a lot of a lot of stuff you hear through
through, you know, different channels
through the years and and and yeah, you
know, the story changes because a guy
like Maxwell comes out after 25 years
and tells his his side of the story
where Vondo, you know, he's been around,
but he's never really really told really
kind of like, you know, what what
happened in the room or what strains
they had in the room. You know, there
was no really specific details behind
any of that until Maxwell came out. So,
you know, you know, as time goes on, you
know, these guys may be willing to to
talk to find out the the the details of
of everything else, but um as far as I
know, this is this is as much as we know
as as of right now.
Well, I just looked up at my phone and I
still have Vondo's phone number. So,
yeah, I I can give him a call. I don't
know, man. Yeah, you might. Well, you
can contact He's Wild Mountain
Cannabis. Wild Mountain Cannabis on
Instagram, but also, you know, you can
probably get through to him through AJ
because I think both of them are working
on seed projects together. So, um, Wild
Mountain Cannabis and AJ Sour,
um, those guys definitely, um, they they
did another podcast and they had
elaborated on on some of this stuff. So,
that was how I became aware of it. But,
you know, but then, you know, I got into
a conversation with
Maxwell and, you know, we, you know,
just, you know, I was kind of curious
about it myself. So, uh, there was
definitely some more to dig into.
Yeah, I feel like it's the the topic
that we will never we will never
completely get dug into, you know, and
everyone is kind of like, you know, on
the search for the real sour and what
happened to the sour? Is it real? Is it
fake? like, you know, so like originally
there was only one cut of the sour,
which was originally known as the AJ
sour because AJ was the one that brought
it down to the city and he was the one
that started selling trays of it, you
know, and then he was set he was setting
up other people like Wing Wang, you
know, he was setting up other rooms, you
know, and so and he was getting pieces
of the room. So it was in in his
interest to to spread the sour around
because there was uh there was never
enough of it, you know, and so like you
could literally just have well no one
could produce that much, you know, cuz
most people were only running like five
lights, you know, maybe 10 lights back
then was a really big growth. So, like
most people didn't have 10 lights, you
know, like the most I ever had was
eight, you know, and so, you know, back
then, you know, you know, you know,
things were scary back then. The bigger
that you got, the more you know, the
more of a chance something something
could happen and it all depending on the
logistics of where you were, the grow,
the building, your neighbors. We were
doing it all in home. Yes. We weren't
ever doing it in commercial buildings,
right? So, we always had power
limitations. Power limitations. And you
had neighbors to worry about, landlords
to deal with. So there was always, you
know, carrying bales of Promixing,
everything, you know, just, you know,
uh, getting garbage out the door,
getting getting stuff up in, you know,
just back the back and forth, you know,
carrying garbage bags at nighttime,
filling up a, you know, a Suburban
parked out front, you know, and just
speeding off and dumping the garbage,
you know, you know, who knows where.
But, uh, yeah, you know, it it was it
was, you know, it was different back
then. It was, you know, I I made a
video. I'm not sure if you saw it. It
was one of the first videos that I made
and I tell a story about how I lived in
on the third story in Brooklyn for my
first growth. Did you Did you hear that
story? That's That's insane.
I flushed all my soil and all my garbage
trash down the toilet. That's insane. I
was petri I was petrified to put it on
the street. That's how the cops would
find out, you know, like they were going
through people's garbage you know what
we did was we would just just get like
those big contractor garbage bags and so
you know you you're you're just hauling
the bags in and out of the out of the
you know building you know you just fill
up the trunk of your car and speed off
you know and back then there wasn't
cameras or anything around so you could
just pull up to really any kind of
industrial or commercial place and find
a dumpster or wherever you could find
some garbage cans or throw it off on the
curb somewhere where it's going to get
picked up or, you know, you can't really
get away with that kind of stuff now
with cameras everywhere, you know, but
back then, yeah, you you know, you
didn't want to have any any kind of
paraphernalia or anything in your
garbage, you know, empty fertilizer
bottles or anything of that stuff. You
want, you know, you wanted to try to
keep everything as clean and as quiet as
possible.
I found someone's dump like that one
time. I was uh working at for an office
furniture company and they had a
dumpster in the back. I went down to go
break out some, you know, break down
some boxes and I just started smelling.
I was like, "What the hell?" So, I
opened it up and sure enough, there was
these garbage bags full of like
premature plants that, you know, for
whatever reason, they cut them down.
But, yeah, it's so funny that you you
brought that up. Yeah. And that's what
you had to do back in the day. You know,
it's you know, the people that didn't do
that ended up getting locked up. Yeah.
And and also, you know, you didn't want
to tell anyone like you were kind of
like a hermit in a sense where you
didn't have people coming over to your
house. The only people that came over to
your house were the essential people
that knew that what you were doing and
maybe helped you out for watering when
you're out of town or uh some kind of,
you know, maintenance or help, maybe
helped you trim or, you know, help solve
a problem in your room or or whatever.
you you always had to have those kind of
people around. But outside of that, like
there was no one, you know, it wasn't
like, you know, yeah, let's come over to
my house and let me show you my plants,
you know, like you you didn't want to
tell anyone anything, you know, so, you
know, being anonymous was the key.
Yeah, for sure. I I tell another story
about how when I was already in
California, a friend knocked on my door
one day.
Oh yeah, that's the worst. He He didn't
know I was growing. Oh yeah. And this is
this is before peeping out windows
looking to see who is it? And then all
of a sudden you got to get enough
[ __ ] balls to open up the open up the
door to see who it is. And and it's your
friend. You know, you're expecting like
I was so [ __ ] pissed and he had no
idea why cuz he didn't know I was
growing. He had been to my house before,
but when he came to my house, you know,
there was nothing nothing out. And he
stopped by my house and he's like, I was
just in the neighbor. I was like, "Dude,
don't ever [ __ ] come to my house
without calling me first." I like And if
anything, that was a big tell. Like, why
got me so freaked out that I [ __ ]
just stopped by to say hello? You know,
paranoia. I feel like nothing's changed,
you know, cuz if someone stops by
without hitting you up, you're just
like, "What? What the hell?" Like,
"Who's at my door?" Well, I have kids,
so my my my doorbell rings all the time,
you know, like my neighbors kids are
always knocking on the door wanting to
find my kids and stuff. So, if I freaked
out on them, it wouldn't be good. Yeah.
I mean, I remember I was up at my house
up, you know, upstate in the in the cat
skills and, you know, I'm talking about
a secluded place where you don't even
get cell service. You know what I mean?
Like, so all of a sudden, I get a knock
at the door. I'm like, "Oh my god, who
is it?" You know? I'm [ __ ] peeking
out the window. I'm like, "Don't answer
the door. Don't answer the door." You
know, they they leave. They leave a note
there. It's a census. I didn't I didn't
I didn't I didn't send in my census
form. And so the census people were up
there knocking on my door. But something
as stupid as that became like a [ __ ]
major [ __ ] you know, anxiety attack.
And even, you know, up until today, I,
you know, I have PSTD. You know, I have,
you know, dreams of, you know, the cops
coming for me and and running from the
cops and, you know, if you've been
busted, you know, and I've been busted
multiple times, eight times, two
felonies, you know, but luckily all that
stuff has now been uh, you know, it's
all been cleaned off. Yes. because of
legalization, you know, but when you but
when you've gone through that trauma of
being locked up, being the having the
cuffs on you, spending a day or two in
jail, like it really does something to
your psyche that that that you never
really recover from, you know, and so um
yeah, it it it's tough.
Yeah, for for sure. People don't realize
the mecca that the Catkills is for
cannabis and has been for a long time,
you know. Yeah, it has been. Well, you
know, it's a place where you you're kind
of secluded and everyone kind of minds
their own business and you can kind of
come and go unnoticed. Like, you know, I
I lived at the end of a culac. I was the
only house on the culac. I mean, there
was one other one other uh house on my
street. Like, it was very very secluded.
Uh, but you know, I picked that location
for a reason, you know, and I was up
there for like 12 years and I never had
a problem until one day
um I, you know, I was cutting and um,
what happened was my septic um, it the
the pipe got crushed outside the septic
and so it it backed up. So I couldn't
take a shower, you know, and stuff. So I
was cutting and when I was driving home,
you know, down in 287, I got pulled over
by the state
cops and it became this whole
ordeal where, you know, I had a
fertilizer bottle in the trunk and I I I
just it was one fl one red flag after
another. I just saw the whole thing
envisioning the whole thing going down
because really the New Jersey state cops
couldn't do anything to me other than,
you know, arrest me for the the the pipe
I had and the gram or two of weed I had
and then charged me with
DWI. But they were very [ __ ] curious
about, you know, growing in the
fertilizer bottle and such. And so like
everything was in my name in the power
department. The power was in my name.
Everything was in my name. So I could
just envisioning the New Jersey state
police calling the New York State Police
and say, "Hey, listen. We got this guy
coming
down state, you know, run his name." So
they run my name. They get the power.
They look at the power bill. I see. And
I remember I remember cuz uh I was
getting the I I'd get my power bill and
they would give you a rating on how much
power you were using and they would be
like you you are number 100 out of 100
out of the most used p you know you most
used power in the area or some [ __ ] like
that. And I remember showing my friend.
I'm like, "Look at this." You know, and
so like uh so I can I envision them
calling, you know, the New York State
Police. Only thing they got to do is run
the power record. Look at the power
record. Oh, it's it looks pretty high.
Okay. So, we're going to go up and do a
walk around. And that's what they would
essentially would have done. They would
have came up to the property. Look in
the trash. looked in. Well, there was
never any trash cuz I I brought all my
trash down state. Like there was no
garbage collection there. So everything
I brought out and but but they would
what they would do is they would walk
around the house to see if there was any
tell signs of a grow, any smell, any
anything that would tip them off to be
able to try to get a warrant. And then
the next thing they would do is try to
make contact, try to find out when you
were there, try to talk to you, just to
get you to open the door and such and
and you know and just just anything to
tip them off so they can get a warrant.
So, I just, you know, I I envisioning
all of this happening and I was just
like starting to, you know, get popular
with the seeds and everything and I was
like, "Yo, this is not going to go down
like this." And so, I just pulled the
plug, you know, I I shut the I shut the
room down. And I I chopped every you
know once I got well I had chopped at
that time and I took everything out of
the out of the house all cuz it was
drying and I was like man they might
[ __ ] come at any time. So I was
paranoid. So I [ __ ] moved all I had
to bring all the wet weed down to the
city and dried it down there and bagged
it up. Then I had to get rid of the
garbage and then I had to break down the
room. And so the whole thing was like a
[ __ ] mad scramble within like a
couple and then they never came. I don't
know if they ever came. They might I
don't know, you know, there's but my
main thing was just [ __ ] pulling the
plug and get and ending the project cuz
I had already been up there like 10 or
like 12 years. So I mean that's a good
run in one [ __ ] spot, you know? So I
was like I ain't going to press my luck
to see what's going to happen next. I'm
just going to [ __ ] bail out now. So,
and I, you know, and that's what I did.
I shut it down. I sold the house. And
then I decided to come to Colorado where
I could, you know, grow legally and not
have to worry about getting arrested.
And I just wanted to make seeds at that
point. So, you know, and so that's
really, you know, how I really wound up
in Colorado was just that. And is that
where you're at still? Yeah. But now I
want to go back to because I see
sometimes I see sometimes you're in New
York City for like Yes. Yes. I want to
go back to New York, but my wife doesn't
want to go back. So, but now, I mean,
when I came out to Colorado, Colorado
was the mecca of the industry, of the
cannabis scene. Like, you they had just
gone wrecked, the first wreck state.
Like, that was in
2015. And you know now as you know other
states opened up people used their
experience to go to you know different
states and um you know so really like
everyone that that was here that made
you know kind of the mecca it's all gone
now. There is there is no more scene
here in in Colorado anymore. So now that
scene exists in New York now. And so,
and I don't think I don't really see it
ever really going away there because New
York is a very unique, you know, thing
in itself because you're dealing with a
mass population of people with the
majority of them having the money that
they have to get whatever they want, you
know, meaning like, you know, these some
of these super rich people, you know,
they just don't want the best. They want
the best of everything. And that was
really how the Sour Diesel kind of fit
into the whole equation of the New York
scene was because it was like the
quintessential the creme de creme of of
cannabis at the time. And so, you know,
just like everything else in life,
people want the best. And when they have
the money, they're willing to pay for
it. And they, you know, and that's all
that they want. They just want results.
They don't want anything else but
results. So when you deliver that, then
you can charge $800 or $1,000 an ounce
as AJ did and other people did. And
because that's, you know, people wanted
their stuff, they would prepay for it.
And, you know, that's how it went down
back then. It just was not enough supply
back then. So, um, you know, you're
dealing with a whole different type of
customer out there and and it still
exists today to where, you know, we're
doing these popup events and it's just
people, you know, it's basically people
that got, you know, two, three, four,
five lights and, you know, we all come
together and, you know, we have these
popup events and people could come and
they can go from table to table and they
could look for the best sour diesel or
the best kush or whatever they're
looking for and they, you know, or they
might like a specific grower or or or
whatever. And so they it gives the
consumer an opportunity to get a a
higher product and it gives the farmers
an opportunity to move their product
straight to consumer. And so and is this
safe? And it's safe. Yes. You know, it's
not legal, right? It's not legal. No.
And so, you know, and and I think, you
know, that model is going to continue to
exist because I don't think that the New
York market is going to be able to um be
able to compete with the product, you
know, like I mean, there might be some a
few, but like anyone that's mass-
prodducing any of these, the only people
that are going to be able to compete
with that are the micro grows. That's
it. You know, if you're one of these
guys that got or people that have a
brand Well, that's Well, see, that's
that that's the thing where the New York
market is. is now if you're a uh if
you're a wck grower like you can't like
you got to sell your you got to sell
your guy to a you to a
distributor and then the distributor I
don't know I don't know who brands if
it's the distributor or or the
dispensary. So like essentially like
you'd have to, you know, it doesn't
matter what your flower brand is as a
grower. If they're not going to brand
your flower as such, they can brand it
any way they want to.
So you can't brand your own weed there,
you know, and really uh essentially what
happens is all the power now becomes of
the broker because the broker is the one
that's going to that that is the
middleman between the farmer and the
dispensary. So, you got to sell to the
broker and the broker can be like,
"Well, I'm only going to give you so
much for it or, you know, and then he
can turn around on the other side, you
know, it doesn't matter what, you know,
on on the retail side of it, it doesn't
matter what they pay for, they're just
going to they're just going to charge
double, right?" So, that's pretty much
how retail works. So, as a dispensary,
you're going to buy a wholesale pound
and just double it at the minimum. At
the minimum, you're going to double your
money on that. So, you know,
as so, you know, those guys are are are
going to be making just as much as as
the farmer, so to speak. you know, of
course they got to move the product and
everyone's got to deal with o overhead
prices and everything, but you know, as
as the market, you know, shakes out, you
know, it always seems, you know, even in
regular agriculture that the farmer
always gets the short end of the
stick and he's the one that's producing
the
product. And so I think that's, you
know, a tragedy especially in cannabis
and really in in in in in any kind of
agriculture because if you know if
you're do putting in the hard work, you
know, you should be able to at least
have the opportunity to sell to the
consumer. Now, you know, in some
instances, some people might not be
geared to sell to the consumer and they
only want to sell wholesale, but you
know, as as a micro craft former, that's
what you want and that's where I think
it's going to be profitable.
You know, one question or one topic that
we've brought up here a number of times
in the podcast and I'd like to hear what
you think is how do you define a craft
grower?
That's a hard that's a hard question,
you know? And so I guess at the end of
the day it would be like the product. I
mean the quality of your product, right?
You know, and so and then I guess then
you can break it down to how many lights
and then you could break it down to is
it organic and then you could just keep
breaking it down more and more. I guess
if I guess to where what your definition
of craft is, but like to me craft is
more smallcaled should we say now what
that number of lights or what that
square footage is is hard to say. took
because you know even in you know a
black market grow you know is it 10
lights is it 20 lights like what where
where where
where is it you know where where it is
is is it's too much for one person. But
now if if if you have two lights and
it's crap, you're not crap. Right.
Right. You're not crap. Now and if you
have a 100 lights and it's
fire, is that crap? Yeah, you can
consider that, you know, but that is a
lot of, you know, to pull that off. Now,
I'm not saying that it's not possible,
but it it's a lot of work, you know, and
the guy with two lights can give his x
amount of plans way more attention than
the person with a 100 lights. Now, if
you got what if the guy with 100 lights
has 50? Yeah, I was just going to say
now if he's got like a you know you know
that many employees but there's you know
there's a balance of of a business of
the business part of it where you know
expenses take
over. You know what I'm saying? So it
doesn't you know there it's a very fine
balance of trying to find um trying to
find that that craft mark. I don't I
don't know what it is. And and in
theory, you would think the smaller the
better, easier. Now, you know, if once
you get that model down, can you upscale
that model into something bigger? That's
the question now. Is it 100 lights? All
right. But is that 10 10 rooms with 10
lights or is that 20 rooms with five
lights?
like is that possible you know so you
know I think you know there's a lot to
be you know dis discovered in all that
because most people that are going to do
a 100 lights just got one room with 100
lights. They don't have 10 rooms with 10
lights because now they got to have 10
air conditioning units, 10 uh
dehumidifiers, 10 of 10 more of
everything, you know. And so I think a
lot of it has to do with the cost of
things where people and I've seen this
over and over again where they get, you
know, x amount of million dollars, they
build out a grow and then they find out
the grow the grow rooms aren't aren't
designed properly and they're like,
well, we spent $10 million, you know,
well, you know, you guess what, you
know, you got to spend another$2 million
to rectify, you know, the engineering uh
defects in there and and so that's you
know a part of the problem where you got
people that are in cannabis that
necessarily don't belong in cannabis.
They don't come from they don't come
from they don't come from the culture.
They come from a business background and
they see everything in dollars and
cents, which you know, let's face it, to
to run a successful business, you have
to have a sense of that, you know, but
you also got to have a sense of a
long-term plan in sight of experience on
exactly, you know, how you're going to
do things. And so when you get a guy
that is, you know, you get some guy
that's a real estate guy that got a got
a a legal license and he's got $10
million and, you know, now all of a
sudden he, you know, uh, employ, you
know, employs one of these consultants
and he don't know what the [ __ ] he's
doing and and, you know, and it just,
you know, just a downhill effect all the
way down of of people of incompetency.
that are designing and building and and
setting up businesses that they have no
idea of of of how it really works.
Because in theory, you could have x
amount of plants that's going to produce
x amount of pounds and you're going to
get e x amount per pound, you know, and
then on paper, you know, it all [ __ ]
it's all at work, you know, you want to
be [ __ ] super profitable, but it at
the end of the day when when you know,
you fail your
testing, you can't get your product out
the door or you get your product out the
door and it's worse. half of what you
thought it was going to be. And so, you
know, and when you got these big
investments and, you know, investors,
you know, to answer to and things aren't
running like they supposed to. Um, you
know, that it it just doesn't work, you
know, but on paper, I mean, it really
does work, you know, but at the end of
the day, you got to sell all your [ __ ]
you know what I mean? And if you can't
sell it, sell it. it, you know, what
what's it worth? It's only worth what
people are willing to give you.
Yeah, for sure. Um, my my opinion on
what a craft grower is is has been
evolving and still trying to figure it
out. So, I appreciate you uh giving your
feedback on that. I remember when I
asked Kevin what he thought because you
know
originally my thought was look if you
grow this with love and with the
intention of growing the highest quality
product you know to me that's crap if it
if it comes out like that just because
you're Kevin said just because you have
those intentions don't mean the results
are going to be that. So that that's
what Kevin said. Kevin said the road to
hell was built with good intention, you
know. So, it's exactly that. But, you
know, one thing about size is that I
believe that, you know, some of the
larger
facilities, they also have
um, you know, they've built nicer
growrooms with more control, you know,
with, you know, monitoring that small
growers don't have. So, I don't think
that size is really what decides if it's
craft. I mean, in the end, it's the
quality that comes out. If the quality
is really good, then I think that can be
called craft cannabis, no matter what
the size of the garden is. Um, you know,
I'm a member of a group on Reddit and
it's called Craft Marijuana. That's
actually where I met
Cosmic. And um I was in the moderator
chat and this was the the topic that was
always coming up. They would say, "Well,
you know, this room is too big, you
know, so that can't be craft because
he's got over 30 lights." And, you know,
they they wouldn't want to post that
stuff. Or, you know, if it was a tent
garden and the guy wasn't doing a
perfect job, they didn't want to post
that. And, you know, I felt like, hey,
you know what? if you're growing with
love and like I said the intention of
growing the highest quality product that
that your goal
isn't to how do I make the most money
but if your goal is how do I grow the
best weed I like to think of that as
craft but you know as we continue to
have the discussion I realized that you
know I still don't know what craft can
be but also like with them in doing that
they're really not really helping anyone
Because even though that person might
have the right intentions, he might be
doing something wrong. And whereas
someone in the group could help him to
point out, hey, listen, this is what's
working for me or I see that you're
doing this wrong or or whatever. And you
know and really you know the you know
when you were in those groups and even
you know when we were on the forums back
in the day that's what it was all about
was trying to help each other you know
because everyone didn't have the
information that they have today. You
know, back then, you know, there was a
few books that you you were a few grow
books that you were able to get maybe in
some kind of underground uh bookstore or
in in the back of high times and then,
you know, then you'd have to get those
High Times mailed to your house. So, it
was always a, you know, a big deal and
trying to uh purchase information and,
you know, and so when you're dealing
with people that are all doing the same
thing and, you know, maybe, you know,
people using different methods and and
and really that's was really, you know,
the the the forms kind of brought all of
that together and then it also helped,
you know, shape the community whereas,
you know, someone in
California could mail someone in New
York a clone in New York can send
someone to someone in California. So
then then there you know there you know
it also opened up this big exchange of
of genetics that you know we we never
saw before where before like you had to
know someone like you know like if you
didn't know those guys in in Virginia if
you didn't know who who Greg was like
you know you never would have gotten any
of those cuts or anything because you
know and back then it was like it was
about all about who you knew and it was
really a very small niche community
where you weren't going around telling
people, "Yeah, I'm a grower this and
that," you know, you kept everything
under wraps. So when you when you
finally when when one grower actually
finally did, you know, meet another
grower under the right circumstances,
you know, it was like a match made in
heaven because, you know, you know, you
had some two alike minds and they could
exchange in information. They could
exchange genetics and so it just opened
up, you know, all of this, you know,
information for everyone and, you know,
the genetics also. And so, you know, you
know, that's one thing about, you know,
um, you know, the American weed scene is
we're very passionate. You know, we've
always been very passionate from from
the very beginning. And, you know, and
that's what is kind of what what kind of
drives us, I think, you know, and it
sets us apart from people in Amsterdam
and people in Spain and people anywhere,
you know, because now we're we're the
weed mecca of the world right now.
everyone is watching what the what we
are doing and and so uh you know we just
got to just keep you know trying to keep
you know moving things forward in the
right way and you know and I think
helping people and to encourage people
to grow and you know like for me I'm I
know I sell seeds so like the home
grower is my customer you know that guy
that's you know that wants to start
something in a tent with one or two
lights and you know he he's reading
about the sour diesel but he can't get
the sour diesel clones so he could buy
my seeds and try to get a good
representation of it and so that's
always been kind of like you know when I
was breeding it was always about
preservation for me in the beginning
like we would get certain clones and we
would lose them and then be like oh
they're gone forever you know and and I
would and I'd be selling the weed and so
customers I had direct feedback from the
customer and I'd Like they'd be like,
"Yeah, I like that Northern Lights." And
I'd be like, "Mike, what happened to the
Northern Lights?" "Oh, we lost it." I'm
like, "Dude, you know, like that [ __ ]
was [ __ ] you know, popular." And so,
um, you know, so when I started growing,
you know, and started coming in contact
with some of these clone only strains, I
was like, I got to, you know, at least
try to make some kind of, you know,
cross or get some kind of
representation. Even if it's not an
exact cross of what it is, if it's 70
80% of what it is, that's a home run for
me. So, so is that that, you know, and
so trying to, you know, and so I use my
experience and my taste in in, you know,
with the sour diesel and with the hazes.
And so I try to recreate those
experience for other people to try. So
they can buy a pack of seeds and they
can get the sourd or or they can get the
pith or they can get the chem or or or
whatever. So that's really, you know,
what's really been, you know, my main
focus in in breeding. And, you know,
it's always been trying to move and also
try just trying to move the, you know,
the gene pool forward as as we as as we
go along. We just want the gene pool to
get better and better and we've, you
know, you know, if and you know, looking
back, you know, 30 years of smoking, 30,
40 years of smoking weed, you know, I
can I can I can say that we've really
moved things forward. When I first
smoked that first joint in 1979 of some
Mexican or some Colombian crap or
whatever, where that doesn't even exist
anymore. You don't you don't see those
Mexi mids or Jamaicans or any of that
imports anymore. Actually, now from what
I hear, we we export where where people
in California are exporting to to the
UK, to Thailand, to to Europe. Like
people want, you know, to try the runs,
they want to try the sherbets and all
these other, you know, all these strains
that they they see and read about on the
internet. And you know and that's why
you know the internet is a very you know
powerful tool in communication you know
cuz you know you you know you could put
up a and I could just speak from my own
experience. you put up a a dank picture
or something of of of a plant someone
grew from your seeds and like yo that
looks dank you know I want to get some
of that you know and so you know it's
very powerful the you know the internet
speaking of which where do you find your
seeds now um I pretty much sell my seeds
wholesale to uh you know many different
people that sell um on Instagram. They
also have websites and stuff like that.
I couldn't really name all of them, but
I also uh sell seeds direct from from me
to the customer. If you if you email me
at topdog seeds at
protonmmail.com, you email me, I'll send
you a list and you can pick out what you
want and we can move forward if you
want. Um, I haven't really, um, set up
any kind of a, uh, legal website or
anything like that. Uh, just because,
you know, of of processing problems and
pretty much payment stuff like that is,
uh, you know, and top dog is to o p a
wg. Correct. Correct. So, he doesn't he
doesn't call it top dog. It's D A WG.
Yeah. Rich. And to be honest with you,
or not, you know, I'm always honest, but
uh I've been looking at your your posts
and stuff and the sour is it the ones
that I'm seeing photos of. Are those F5
or F6? Um most of them are F5s. I think
there are a few F6s that are out there
now. Um, so when I started the sour
project, um, I pretty much, you know,
had the original sour clone that we had
from AJ back from the, you know, late
90s, early 2000s. So I had that and I I
crossed it with the the trade dog and
the trade dog was Afghan chem and then c
backcrossed two more times to the chem.
So when I made that when I made that
mail, you know, I kind of was trying to
uh duplicate the chem, which I never
did. Like I, you know, I had gotten some
chem I did the same thing with the chem
dog and never got I was really looking
for that garlic onion chem like and I
really more or less got kind of like a
chemy kind of, you know, so I wasn't
really particularly happy with the
overall results of that. But, you know,
when I made that, I made it for also to
try to make the best male, like the the
strongest weed and the best male. So,
that was kind of my starting point, you
know. So, I just decided to make that an
outcross male. So, you know, so that
that that that plant kind of grew kind
of short, stocky, kind of Afghan kind of
chem structure. And so I crossed that to
the to the sour diesel which was tall,
stretchy, you know, kind of almost a
different, you know, opposite uh growth
structure. And so, you know, I I I c I
backrossed it three times, you know, and
trying to, you know, trying to get in as
much um of the sour genetics as
possible. And so then I from the back
cross three that's when I started you
know doing the F2s to F3s. And so when I
was making my selection throughout the
whole process, it was kind of easy
because I was always looking for the the
the taller stretchier plants that were
more kind of chem I mean sour diesel in
structure where you know we where I
would get some that were shorter and
some are kind of medium bushier type of
plants you know so the sour diesel has a
very unique growth structure and it's
very distinguishable. able. So that's
how I would, you know, make my
selections as as I went along. And so,
uh, you know, I would I would, you know,
I would get a female and I would try to
get the the, you know, the the growth
and the smell and and then I would just
try to find a male that had the same
structure. And obviously, like, you
really can't test that male out until,
you know, you grow the plants out. And
so, you know, you just really got to
make a conscious decision on on
selection and and and just and just move
forward and just trying to keep keep it
going and keep in breeding as you go
along until you find exactly what you're
looking for. And so, in the early in
early ones, you know, we were getting
like a a lot of shorter, bushier plants.
I mean, they did have the sour profiles,
the smell to them, but, you know, I was
really looking for the structure more.
And so, you know, I've really bred it
back to to the F6s now. And they're
pretty much coming out pretty uh, you
know, pretty pretty
uh, stable, pretty uh, in structure
where not every not everyone, but
they're they're all pretty much alike.
you know, you might get a few that are
kind of still on the shorter squad side,
but um I'm just really trying to get
everything to where it's all kind of
like the same. And so we're it it's
getting a lot closer now. And so, um I
just kind of like held back now. I've
done the F6. I just did a remake of the
F6. And so, um, I'm I got a couple
selections now that I've kind of have
out that I want to kind of just grow
out, um, and see, you know, how good
they are and maybe get them into
production and, you know, see
exactly, you know, h how it how it, you
know, how it turns out. But, you know,
it's funny how everyone is like, "Oh,
where's the sour? What happened to it?
It's not around anymore." And and you
know, like I was saying before, there
was only one cut in the very beginning.
And so really, you know, as those as
those cuts spread out, I think what what
happens is, you know, you you you know,
the the the plant is going to adapt to
the different conditions. So, if you're
if you're if you're running your room
with organics and uh soil and I'm
running mine with hydroponics and salts
and my grows got it's got PM, it's got
mites, it's got this, it's got that, you
know, I think over over a period of
time, you know, my sour is going to be
different than your sour. And so a lot
and I pick a lot of sour you know at
this point the sour is like what like
the
30 you know close to 30 years old now
you know 25 years old no I guess 95 90
yeah you could say 95 like 30 years you
know what I mean
so any any plant that's been passed
around for 30 years is going to be you
know is you know the genetic drift or
whatever epigenetic changes. Yeah. due
to you know environment to pests for
fertilizer to light to everything you
know and and I think that's why they
call it weed because it's it's adaptable
you know it does it doesn't just stay
the same and I think it's kind of been
proven you know even in in some clone
you know some plants where you can take
multiple clones off of one plant and
have three different plants from the
from the same from the same plant you
know so that in itself kind of tells the
genetic diversity that that's in one
plant. You know, if you can get three
different phenotypes off of three
different cutings off of one plant, uh,
you know, so, you know, all of that, I
think, you know, over time makes the
plant change. And so, I think really
what people are kind of looking for is
really that sour diesel woof, if you
want to call it that, when you open the
bag and you just kind of get woofed by
the smell of it. And back in the day, it
was very distinguishable of the way that
it smelled and everything. And so I
think, you know, the smell and the
taste. Yeah. And I think it's kind of
lost some of that over time. And and I
and I can just tell you from my
experience from other plants that we've
had for a long period of time that they
eventually they do go bad. Even like
that's what happened to the underdog,
the original underdog that Mike Klopp
made. Like originally that just kind of
crapped out. Now looking back, did it
have some kind of virus or something?
Something could have been going on with
it, but it, you know, something
definitely made made it degrade in
quality to the point where we got we
just let it go. And I think the same
thing happened with the super skunk.
like the super skunk.
Like listen, you know, everyone says,
you know, there's different stories on
it and and the one that Greg got was the
one that you gave him and it was the one
that Mike had and it was the one that
kind of got passed around in the
Massachusetts, New England area. And
from what I remember it being, like it
was super like when you open that jar,
you just got like, you know, you got
that super skunk woof, you know, but the
the butt itself wasn't super strong. It
was kind of light, you know, it didn't
get you super high or whatever. It was
not like the 90. No, not at all. You
know, it it was Bud Light, you know. So,
uh, you know, everyone's kind of chasing
the Roadkill skunk now. how they're
chasing the you know the sour diesel
and you know you know I don't know like
with the roadkill skunk you know maybe
there is someone out there that's got
something that but to me all of that
kind of points back to Afghan genetics
you know so if you really want to really
start from the beginning I think that's
where the original skunks come from
Afghans it's kind of been documented you
know through the years through different
people have written books
so on and so forth.
Um, and you know, so I, you know, I
think that, you know, the thios and and
all of that stuff, I think they
eventually kind of change over over time
and and depending on your fertilizers
and everything. Um and now with lights
changing
and you know we're kind of we kind of
have what we have you know and you know
there's always that chance of you know
someone finding a needle in the hay
stack and you know we you know but you
know you just got to keep looking and
you got to keep trying and you know I I
I've always you know try to do these
small kind of um little hunts of stuff
you know that's land race or you know
and a lot of that stuff is just for you
know my own you know personal you know
what I want to do you know and there's
you know some Tai stuff that I remember
from back in the day that I would like
to get back and stuff. So there's a lot
of things that we've experienced as
smokers that we'd like to you know
recreate or we'd like to experience
again. And so I think that's part of
like chasing the the nostalgia of
certain strains or whatever and is just
trying to recreate some of that. But you
know a lot of that stuff you know when
we first experienced you know I think
like the overall the overall um
tolerance that everyone has to weed now
is so much more because back in the day
like during the 90s uh there were
droughts. You remember have you ever
been in a drought where you couldn't
find weed? Like I I've been in through
many, you know, and the last one I
remember being in like 1990 in the early
90s where there was just no weed to be
found in the city or anywhere else. And
so, you know, so overall, you know, you
know, we say if you if you going through
a drought and you haven't smoked for a
few days or a week or however, how long
it may be, now you smoke something like
the Super Skunk and you know, on today's
terms maybe Bud Light, but back then you
were like, "Wow, I'm [ __ ] super
high." So now with especially
concentrates and dabs and you know and
the THC being at the highest that it's
ever been I think overall people's
tolerance are much higher and the
nostalgia that they remember as as a kid
or back in the day was because yeah just
because they didn't smoke anything in
two or three days and all of a sudden
they smoked something and got super
stoned and you know that would be the
case in and you know you could smoke
Mexican if you didn't smoke, you know,
and smoke for a week and get high. So,
the Jamaican weed used to be really
potent. Oh, yeah. Yeah. You know, so
like I mean it may not have been, you
know, kind bud, but that [ __ ] would make
you fall asleep. Oh, yeah. you know,
well, if you got that, you know, the the
that that that chocolatey uh lamb's
bread or lamb's breath or whatever they
want to call it, man, that that that was
the [ __ ] you know, cuz that was
actually kind of like chocolate tie kind
of and, you know, was it was grown, you
know, in a different environment, came
out differently, but yeah, it definitely
had some some really super good effects
to it.
I think another lacker is the novel
novelty, too. back when you first
started smoking, you know, it wasn't a
feeling that you were very used to, you
know, because I feel like that kind of
attributes to what I like to call the
high school high, right? Because how
often do you get high like you were in
high school, right? Well, if you stop
smoking for a week or a month, and if
you smoke, you will get that effect
again. Well, I I I can actually say that
the other day I got higher on weed than
I've gotten in years, and it was on sour
diesel. So, and I'm going to tell that
story in a minute, but before I do, I
just want to say because I want to
finish saying this that I've been
watching you on social media and I've
been seeing these sour and although, you
know, you're thousand miles away from me
and I haven't actually gotten a chance
to to try that stuff. It looks like sour
diesel. It does. You know, like when you
when you look at it, you're like, man,
that that [ __ ] actually looks legit. And
it has the smell to it. It has a smell
to it. So, it's really really really
trying to do a really proper hunt to
find that one [ __ ] really really I
think I think you did a good I think you
did a good job. So, really that's really
what really needs to be done where
someone can really do like a 100 or 200,
you know, plant hunt and really go
through that, you know. unfortunately
like you know I don't have you know
those means to do that that that those
type of of hunts and stuff. So, you
know, um just trying to, you know, uh
trying to really, you know, get people
to to, you know, and that's the other
thing like, you know, you can make the
best [ __ ] in the world if people aren't
willing to do it, you know, what what is
it, you know? And so, you know, I'm
fortunate enough where people, you know,
were are buying my things and they're
and they're reporting on it and, you
know, and after a while, you know,
things just kind of, you
know, the the reputation and the results
kind of speak for themselves. And so,
you know, you just got to, you know, I
just got to thank people that, you know,
that are willing, you know, to to to buy
and grow my stuff and then and and and
then report on it, you know, because and
a lot of this is, you know, like I said
before, like, you know, if if you can
create the best thing in the world and
if it doesn't get out there, no one's
going to know about it. And so, you
know, and and that and that's and that's
part of the whole thing. and and as a
community um I think you know it you
know you know sharing and and trying to
you know uh try to make things better
for everyone is you know in in the end
it it helps everyone
I wanted to tell you about the the thing
is here in Europe yeah your seats are
considered as craft as they can be you
know it's like uh people here in Europe
are uh actually your seats are very
rarely available but when they are
available people buy them and uh for
example in Austria I know there is a
three dogs clone circulating which is
really appreciated I mean you are very
well known as a craft uh breeder you
know I appreciate that but even like
like in in England where the star the
star dog became you know one of the most
popular strains like I had nothing to do
with that, you know. Someone bought a
pack of Star Dog over there and blew it
up, you know. So, like I can only be
thankful for that, you know, where, you
know, he he he blew it up and it kind of
took a life of its own and it things
were that good. That's what that's what
happens. And yeah, I don't really have a
main distributor in Europe, so to speak.
I'm actually I'm just been in touch with
a couple guys in Amsterdam and they're
going to uh there's one guy in Spain
actually and then there's a guy in
Amsterdam that are going to start um uh
carrying my seeds. But I do hopefully
plan to come out to Germany for the Mary
Jane event out is in June. So um so
yeah, just keep your eyes peeled for
that. Uh hopefully I'm going to make
that uh I've been contacted. I will meet
you there. I've been contacted by
someone and I've been invited. Uh I
haven't really gotten all the details on
it yet, but uh I think that's definitely
something that I want to um be a part of
that Mary Jane in the opening of of
Germany.
Yeah, that I'm really wanting to get
over there too because I I hear it's
it's a special event. Yeah. Well, now
you know it's pretty incredible because
everything is worldwide now and that and
that's just you know you know a
connection to the internet where you
know we can talk to you know someone
that's in Slovenia or or anywhere around
the world where they would never know
who Top Dog was if it wasn't if it
wasn't for that. And so now like the
community is now actually now a whole
world community where people in
Australia and Thailand and Europe and
South America like everywhere around the
world you know um it's it's really kind
of hard to wrap your head around. you
know, it was never really like my
intention to have this happen or you
know, uh, you know, when things were or
organically, you know, from from the
from the beginning, you know, you know,
that's the way things just happen and
things take a life of its own and you
can only you just got to kind of go with
the flow and just, you know, I mean,
just try to not be do something stupid.
Well, I mean, you you've had a legal,
you know, cannabis brand for for years
now. People have known Top Dog for a
long time. Imagine my surprise when the
Slovenian Hobbit messaged me telling me
that he's been hearing about me on the
internet and everything. I mean, people
were talking about me on podcasts I
didn't even know, you know, and they
gave me this nickname, Staten Island,
which, you know, you being from New
York, you you can relate to how shitty
of a of a nickname Staten Island. It's
gotten better. At least they've closed
the dump. Okay. Yeah, they closed the
dump. So, now it's just toxic
underground. But, but listen, you know,
back then we were doing what we had to
do. You know that as well as I do. We
were never like there was never any
glory that was part of this, you know.
It was always it was always danger in my
eyes like it in and the glory was
getting paid at the end of the day and
not getting arrested, you know. So there
was no like pats on the back or you know
internet you know popularity or any of
that kind of stuff that you know you
getting away with it was was your reward
and you wanted to just kind of keep it
at that. Well, now everyone is, you
know, waving their flag and, you know,
uh, you know, want to tell tell their
story where before, you know, you didn't
want to, you know, you didn't want to
say anything. So, you know, it it it
it's changed quite a bit now and, you
know, for the better, I think, of the
plant where I think now some real
research can actually get done into this
where, you know, you're getting uh
universities and, you know, other
establishments that are, you know, in
the
research department to actually do some
real, you know, real stuff in, you know,
and, you you know, and if you you know,
if you're looking, you know, you know,
just um on the passing of the skunk man,
but you know, the the re some of the
research that that that guy, those guys
were doing were just just light years
ahead of everyone. It's um you know you
know so really you know uh you know I
didn't you know agree with all of his
actions and and such but you know you
know I think that you know the the you
know they had a way they were so far
ahead of everyone that like we were
playing checkers and those guys were
playing chess more or less.
You know, I was going to make a podcast,
another one, um, just on this topic of
Sam and Neville, but since you mentioned
it now, I can't stop myself from from
bringing this up. Um, we did a podcast
with DJ Short, which hasn't been
released yet. I saw I saw the I saw the
clip of that and I was looking for it. I
was like, where is it? Where is it? And
it's like you guys are holding out. I I
no not holding out. I'm not like that. I
don't have like a Patreon yet where
members get it. It's just I've been
honestly I released a new sour myself
and it's gotten such a tremendous
response that I've just been slammed.
But um when I released that
um little
clip, I received some hate and it was
really the first hate that I've received
on my podcast at all. Like it I've
gotten nothing but positive responses
from everyone. It's it's really been
overwhelming.
And when I made this podcast and I put
that clip up just trying to honor
Sam, I received hate messages and some
to be honest with even
racist.
Um,
but you know, and I I just want to say
this again because I think it's
important
that I am not defending anything that
Sam or Neville
did. Whether they're scumbags or not
doesn't change the fact that they're
relevant and they've really contributed
to our community. And I don't know if
Sam did the things that he's been
accused of. I haven't seen any, you
know, proof of it. And I don't know if
um, you know, Neville was a drug addict
or any of the other terrible things that
they say about him. But Sam did an
incredible amount of work in cannabis
that probably or surely to this day no
single person has ever done. And
Neville, he made all these genetics
available, you know, like he was the
first person to put his face out there
and be like, "Yeah, send me money and
I'll send you seeds."
And so even though I received a whole
bunch of and the hate came from, people
just want to choose
sides, you know, they're either on team
Sam or on team Neville. And my guess is
that probably neither of them are
flawless human beings, you know, and
they, you know, but how can you deny the
tremendous like the work that both of
these guys did, the contribution that
they both made for cannabis, you know?
So yeah, you know, well, you know, you
it's kind of like today where, you know,
back then, you know, I wasn't really a
part of, you know, the '9s Amsterdam
scene, but from from what I've been
told, you know, it was very
competitive. You know, Sam, an American,
brought over genetics. all all the all
the genetics that pretty much Amsterdam
were founded on came from Sam, you know,
you know, they might have had something.
It's undisputed, you know. Yeah. So, we
can't really argue that, you know, and
so, you know, the the practices of some
of the the the Dutch business guys
uh were kind of
unscrupulous. Uh, and they never were
really for the consumer. They I mean,
even up until today now, like they're
very
unreliable. like uh I mean I think that
overall I mean they were gifted all of
those genetics and they screwed the
whole gene pool up you know pretty much
um you know getting away from the
original pro you know the original stuff
that that Neville brought over there and
really you know you look Sam yeah no I'm
sorry Sam brought over there but and if
you look at the the real history of it
all like you know the the real heyday
was really during the Neville period and
pretty much from the late 90s to the
early I mean I'm sorry the late 80s to
the mid 90s pretty much and really the
last harrah was kind of like the Jack
Carrer and then after that it all kind
of like all kind of like went downhill
and it was just kind of like a
reshuffleling of all
those the same genetics that you know
the northern lights the skunk the haze
the
Afghan you know etc and they're all just
kind of reshuffled and if you kind of
look at it now it's kind of like all of
that is kind of all that history is
repeating itself today where you got
haters on the internet trying to
discredit I mean they discredit you I
mean they're trying even Today I' last
two days I've gotten post uh reported or
trying to get my account deleted again.
It's been deleted twice already, you
know. So you got people that make up
narratives about certain people and you
know and it's just kind of like now it's
kind of like a reshuffleling of all the
cookies and you know candy stuff and
gelato gelades all that kind of stuff on
that realm. And so it gets kind of
history kind of repeating itself in in a
sense, you know, where it just becomes
so competitive that, you know, you just
want to take down the guy that's on top
or, you know, whoever you don't like.
And in in today's societies, it's so
much easier to try to cancel people
with, you know, someone just reporting
posts or or or whatever. My Instagram
got taken down. Yeah. like like you know
the um I believe that the person or one
of the people that sent me the hate
message he reported my Instagram and
somehow Instagram had me back on within
like 6 to 8 hours cuz I I was in a
panic. I couldn't believe well if you
appeal it if you appeal it you know a
lot of those things they find out are
bogus you know like how can you put uh a
sexual content on a flower picture how
can you put violence on a flower picture
you know and this is the kind of stuff
that's getting reported and and post
taken down for so I mean there's an
algorithm is there anyone that's really
actually looking at some of this stuff I
I I I don't think So, you know, cuz
there's probably million there's
millions of accounts. You know how much
of no you know how many thousands of
accounts this must happen to a day. It's
just it just you know can't do it.
Here's here's what they said about me
that I was supporting a dangerous
organization and individual. Yeah, I've
gotten that. glorifying a terrorist
attack, supporting violence against a
particular group of people, and
supporting or promoting harmful criminal
activity like human
trafficking. It's like, what the [ __ ]
You know, like I don't even know how
like, but because they reported me as
such a ridiculous thing, Instagram was
able to quickly see that that that
wasn't the case. And you know, luckily
they didn't [ __ ] with me for the weed
pickicss and right, but it just shows
you the female parts, but it just shows
you the power that some of these people
have that are nobodyies that can just
sit back in their mother's basement and
just, you know, just troll people all
day long. And you know, there's there's
there's numerous people out there that
do that on a regular basis. that's their
main content is just to troll people and
just to put negative, you know, energy
out there. And so, you just really, you
know, got to try to stay focused and
don't let other people define who you
are. You know who you are and you tell
people who you are and you don't let
anyone tell people who you are.
Yeah. Um, I don't want to drag on this
too much, but um, this person said to
me, "What gives you the right to mention
Neville in the same breath as Sam when
Sam died?"
And you know, I don't know if this
person is listening or not,
but I give myself the right to talk
about anything that I want on our
podcast, but I try to keep it positive.
I don't think I've ever talked negative
about anyone, you know, like that's not
and it's there's been and I've this is
the most negative I've ever been on on
our podcast. And I've had moments when
I've really wanted to like I have this
platform and sometimes I think like
should I use this platform to out out
these scumbags that are out there that
you know because people are out there
kissing ass to people that they don't
know, you know, and they're like this
person's so amazing. And it's like,
okay, first of all, this person is a
douchebag. And second of all, they
really haven't contributed as much. And
the Chem
Dog, people give me so much credit for,
you know, the Chem Dog. But the way I
see it is I just drove that [ __ ] across
country and and gave it to some friends.
I didn't breed it. I didn't pop the
seeds. I mean, I bred with it later on,
but uh most people didn't get a chance
to see that stuff. But, you know, there
are people that are just trying to
I I don't know. I know what you're
saying. I don't I don't want to I don't
want to take cuz and I'll finish real
quick because this is your show, not
mine. But, um like I'm way more proud of
this podcast that we've done in three
months than anything that I have to do
with the Chem Dog story, you know? And
when people, you know, give me credit
for the Chem Dog story and make it feel
like this is my legacy, it's like, well,
if that's my legacy, I'm a loser. If my
legacy is I just drove this plant across
country and gave it to some friends and
30 years later, that's that's all we can
talk about, you know. So, I'm I'm really
proud of this podcast. I think in a
couple months, we've done some great
things. The other thing that I think is
my real legacy is the garden spout, you
know, my grow shop. And I
taught so many people how to grow. And I
taught OG growers that were growing
outdoors how to grow
indoors. And so like those are things
that I can be proud of and and feel that
are my legacy. But the Chem Dog, that's
not my legacy, you know? And so I just
wanted to put it out there to the world
so that that people can get this
straight, you know, but you know,
honestly in in your defense, I know
you're the one saying this, but um
without you, you still played an
integral role, you know, with the Chem
Dog, you know, cuz part of the story,
right? Everyone has their
own everyone has their own little part
of it. That's that's the that's the
beautiful thing about it because if
there wasn't if there wasn't if there
wasn't a Mike Klopp, if there wasn't a
Gabby, like everyone's got their own
little if there wasn't a Greg Chem Dog,
like everyone's got their own little and
and and that's what makes this thing so
beautiful because it wasn't really
intentional. It is just something that
came to fruition for you know like you
were you were doing what you had to do
at that time to you were you know to to
to better your life you know you you
know and so you know the decisions that
we made in the past you know like we you
know doing certain things you know we we
were doing doing those things you know
to try to make ourselves better and to
make you
you know, things overall, you know, just
easier for, you know, people like that
that we knew. And you know, and just as
a kind of like touching on on the
Neville thing, like you know, Sam was
the one that brought all those genetics
over and you know, Neville did, you
know, like he he had an eye for for
certain things and, you know, like he
went outside of the the gene pool of
what Sam had gave him. And when he got
the Northern Lights and he went to um
you know the Pacific Northwest and
started collecting different strains and
stuff like that and so you know
um yeah a lot you know there's a you
know those guys were were were
competition back then so you know you
know they work they had work together
and and it's just like today when you're
working with certain people or whatever
and you know you you're good for a while
and then you have a falling out and you
know a discrepancy and then you know
that's how all of those all of those
rumors and all that stuff you know start
to spread and everything and um
yeah I mean well I mean the the
allegations something I'm sorry to
interrupt you the allegations are
serious no I know I know you know like
so like I don't want to minimize that
there are serious allegations against
both these guys, it just doesn't change
that they contributed, right? And I
don't mention anything about what type
of people they are. Like I'm not saying
Sam is a great guy and I'm not saying
Neville is a great guy. It just doesn't
change that they contributed. Yeah. And
that's true. And the thing you got to
remember is, you know, you know, since
can cannabis was illegal, like it
brought a lot of different people into
the scene, you know, that just weren't
there for the love of the plant. They
were there for more love of the money
because they had addictions or whatever
case may be, you know. Um, so you know,
it kind of changes, you know, the whole
thing when uh it just becomes more
cutthroat in the end. That's real,
really the bottom line is when you bring
a criminal element into
everything, you know, and you know, you
can be both. You know, you could be, you
know, contribute to the community and
still kind of not be the best person in
the world. And even today, there's a lot
of people out there like that. You know,
they're not their their interests aren't
really with the community or with the
plant is a lot of it is just kind of
like financially driven and kind of
selfentered.
uh everything about me and uh you know
eventually you know that gets recognized
and you know if you want
to you know have you know have longevity
in the game you really can't you know
conduct yourself like that cuz you know
you know eventually you know you're the
only thing you know back in the day I
like to say is the only thing that we
had was our
reputation and how good we on being like
I can vouch for this guy saying he's
good and the balls to do something. The
balls to set up a grow. The balls to do
something illegal to know the
consequences if you get caught that
you're probably going to go to jail.
You're going to go at the very least
you're going to get arrested and there's
a good possibility to go to jail. And so
you got to know all these things going
in.
And you also got to know that you're not
going to be dealing with the most honest
people in the world if you're doing
something
illegal. So, you know, the, you know,
the whole thing just becomes a becomes a
mess after a while once, you know,
things start getting, you know, out of
hand and and we're dealing with the same
[ __ ] today in my opinion on the
internet. you know, he's just, you know,
back then, people would just make up
rumors to disparrage other
people. And and it's the same thing
that's going on today.
And to me, you got to have proof. If
you're going to call someone a rat or or
whatever allegations you have against
them, you know, especially if you're
going to be called a rat, like you got
to come up with the proof and the
paperwork and and such, you know, like
otherwise and and even today, like, you
know, a lot of that back in the day,
like, you know, when we were on the
forums and and stuff, you know, there
was there was much more respect like,
you know, if you got called out, you
could easily get black ballalled from
the community and nobody would have
nothing to do with you. And that's just
not the case anymore. You know, like
those kind of people, flourish,
scammers, rats, you know, known rats,
should I say, you know, that are on
paper and they're still, you know,
accepted in the community. So, the
overall standard, I think, is really
kind of lowered now. And really, you
know, you just got to try to, you know,
surround yourself with, you know, a
likemind people that have the same kind
of morals that that that you that you
have. And really like a lot of the
younger kids now, they just don't
understand because you know all the
stuff that we kind of went through. You
know, the only thing that they know is
legal weed in Instagram and and so I
mean it it it's it's much more than
that, you know, when it really comes
down to the substance of everything.
Are you a 91 guy or are you a Chem D
guy? I'm a chem guy and that's really I
know that's really what what my focus
was from the beginning with the trade
dog, you know what I mean? So that was
always been like and and the thing was I
had the n I had the um the D before the
91 because I got the D directly from
Greg like in 2004 2005 shortly after he
popped and found it and he didn't have
the 91 then and at that point I don't
think anyone had the 91 on the east
coast. I think you guys had it out west
and brought it back. Well Klop had it,
right? No, he he he lost it. He lost it.
He yeah he he lo he he went to uh
everyone started growing that
underdog and uh so yeah but then
um but you know a lot you know you know
a lot a lot of my breeding comes from my
own personal tastes like the strains and
stuff like you know you're not going to
find any tarpinolene in most of my stuff
because I don't personally like
tarpenoline so I'm not going to breed
breed with those kind of plants. I did
do a breeding with like a super silver
haze star dog, you know, something like
that. But, you know, it's not a a
particular uh turpp that I that I like.
And so, like a lot of a lot of my
breeding is based on my personal uh
preferences. And so that's kind of like
where breeding almost becomes an art,
whereas it's it's it's the it's, you
know, it's what my personal uh tastes
are and my interpretation of it and and
such. And so, you know, you you know,
and that's where in the breeding you can
kind of put that personal touch in on
all of that on your selections and
everything because I and I do all of
that on my past experiences on smoking.
And so, like when I'm hunting for a
certain type of tie or a certain type of
haze or or whatever it is, it's because
I something that I had experienced
before. I want to try to recreate that
for myself and to be able to offer that
for other people to experience. And so
that's really, you know, where it kind
of you almost become an artist in a
sense. I definitely think it's an it's
an art.
And you know, the the best art is the
art that the artist makes because he's
inspired, not like, oh, I'm going to
make something that other people like,
this is what's popular. I'm, you know,
you're never going to make the best
product that way. If you make something
because it's what you love, well, either
either you lead or you follow, you know,
and so there's a lot of people that just
want to ride off of other people's
coattails and just, you know, and
so, you know, it is what it is. You
know, you you can't really focus on
that. That used to bother me in the
past, but now I can't, you know, I can't
focus on that. I got to focus on on
moving moving forward and doing what I
got to do and and block out all of the
noise around me, you know, and it's like
I try not to, you know, I try to keep
things relevant, but I don't really
focus on like what other people are
doing, you know. I try to focus on what
I'm doing. And if there's something I
feel that that something that they're
doing that that might fit into what I'm
doing, then I'll gladly incorporate that
and give them credit for it. I have no
problem. I've used other people's
breedings and stuff like that, you know,
and so um, you know, I'm very open to,
uh, really, you know, if you don't pop
seeds, the next best thing is is going
to be found in the seed. You know, like
it's not anything that we're holding
now. So, it's like you got to keep
hunting, you got to keep breeding, you
got to keep moving the genetic pool
forward and then try to create while
preserving. Exactly. While Exactly. You
know. Exactly. And so you want to you
want to bring things forward, but you
want to call on to the past too, right?
So I think Are you doing any tissue
culture? No, I've never done any of the
tissue culture. No, you know, um you
know, I just do regular seeds. People
are always asking me about fems and
autos and this and that. And to me, uh,
a male and female, you know, when you're
looking in into breeding, you know,
you're looking for hybrid vigor, meaning
you're finding a plant that's better
than both parents, you know, and so when
you get opposites, sometimes opposites
attract, you put opposites and you put
them together and you find, you know,
better things. And so you genetics is
it's very, you know, complicated, you
know, and sometimes it's a crapshoot,
you know, and you sometimes you got to
have a vision on what you want to try to
create. That doesn't necessarily mean
it's going to happen, like, you know,
but at least you tried, you know, and
just like I was explaining with the with
the trade dog where I was trying to
recreate the ChemD, it just it just
didn't happen, you know. But you know
what? the male that that I you know the
male that I used out of that you know it
became a a producer in itself with you
know became the foundation of of of my
genetic library pretty much you know on
certain levels you know so that's really
what you got to really focus on and you
know sometimes the glory doesn't come
till five or 10 years after you know I
can I can release a strain And you know
this that let's just take the African
haze for instance like I I released that
you know in like
2010 or somewhere in that area and you
know a guy in named Bronson. He he
bought a pack. He found this African
haze number 11 up in Maine and he blew
it up, you know, and it became like one
of his, you know, staple um strains, you
know, for himself, you know. But with
him blowing himself up, he blew me up in
in in, you know. So, you know, you know,
those things you can't really make
happen. You know, they just happen
organically and you just got to be
thankful for it.
Yeah, for sure.
Um, the Stard Dog, was that yours? Yeah,
the Star Dog. Yeah. So, that was
actually Does this look like your
packaging?
No.
No. No. Somebody's giving me these
seeds. They're probably, you know,
someone f to them or whatever. But, you
know, but but that was, you know, the
Star Dog, you know, I took that same
Trey Dog mail and crossed it to Chem 4,
you know, and then, you know, I then I
wound up giving um my friend some seeds
and he was friends with High Times and
he went to High Times. He gave Kyle
Kushman some seeds. He gave uh Andre
Grossman, the photographer,
uh some seeds. And uh Andre uh he wound
up finding the guava, the guava cam or
um and and then Kyle Kushman took those
seeds out to California and they those
guys grew them out and then they entered
the San Francisco Medical Cup in 2010
and got second place. So that really
kind of put me on the map, you know, and
those guys started, you know, uh, Leo
uh, and those guys up in in Humbult,
they started growing some Star Dog and
it became a production strain up in
Humbult there. So, you know, the, you
know, there's another instance where
where, you know, someone took my strain
and just blew it up and in the meantime
blew blew me up, you know, and so, you
know, I just got to give thanks to that.
Yeah, that you can't you can't make
that. You can't make that up and you
can't make that happen. You know, as as
much as you try, you can promote and try
to, you know, do as much marketing
behind your stuff and if there's no
substance behind it, man, people are
just going to smoke it and then it will
just get discarded, you know, and when
something's that good, this takes a life
of its own.
Well, before we go, I just want to do
something that I think is funny. So,
we're all brothers on this show, and
you're our brother, too, today and and
always JJ. But take a look at this
picture.
You got You got to move it a little bit
over other way. Other way, that's Can
you see that? Yeah, I see it. Yeah,
man. I swear you and Klopp are brothers,
you know. What do you What do you guys
think? Cosmic and and Sasha. That that
that's Listen, that's a young Clop and
an old me. So Oh, you still look young,
bro. No, you still look young. Look at
me, bro.
I I got to wear a hat to hide the glare
from the camera. So, and something else
I wanted to show you since I've been
looking at your um beautiful sour. This
is the
This is the new clone that I got. Nice.
Did you see the video that I posted on
Instagram about it? I don't think so.
No, I'm gonna have to look. So, so I
have, you know, what I've been
erroneously calling the original sour
because it's the cut that um, you know,
me and my friends have had and grown
for, you know, forever, for decades. But
like we were talking about before, it's
gone through epigenetic changes and it's
just not um, it's just not that good
anymore. It's it's not it's it's good.
It's just not the same. It's not I know
what it is. It's is it's missing that
woof. You know what I mean? And it's
like that's the first thing when you
know and and you know I can say like
some of my some of my seeds have one of
the back cross threes has the woof but
it doesn't quite have the you know it's
not doesn't smoke quite as strong I
would say you know. So, but in today in
today's, you know, kids now are just
they don't smoke to get high really, you
know, they smoke to look cool. So, they,
you know, they want to smoke some kind
of candy strain in the blunt and they
want to smoke in a blunt and look cool
all day, you know, and you know, it's
kind of a status thing more or less
where where me, you know, just give me,
you know, a little butter chem and and a
party a little party. the 91, not the D.
And and uh you know, I could take two or
three hits off of off of a little pipe
and I'll be [ __ ] way more higher than
the guy that's smoking the big [ __ ]
blunt after blunt after blunt of [ __ ]
candy, you know? So, it's all personal
preference, you know, and and what works
for me doesn't work for for everyone
else. So I can only go by what I like.
And you know the people that have the
same taste and appeal, you know, those
are the kind of people that that become
your customers that are attracted to you
because you know they have you know the
the same you know you know the same
thoughts that you have on cannabis or or
whatever. So, you know, you know, we we
find, you know, it's funny because, you
know, you you watch someone on Instagram
or on on social media or YouTube,
whatever, and you get a feel of who that
person is, you know what I mean? And so,
you know, their likes, their dislikes,
and you know, you kind of have a you
kind of, you know, have a you build an
image of who that person really is, you
know, without really knowing them. And
just like you had said before, like, you
know, you're you're picking sides or
you're liking people that you don't
know. You have no idea who they are. you
know, you're only seeing little little
little flashes of glimpses of their
lives on social media, and it's really
not who that person really is behind the
scenes.
Well, I that's why we're doing this
podcast and that's why it's not a
10-minute podcast because we want to
give our guests a chance to tell their
story and that way we can really get to
know them
and Yeah. So, yeah. You know, yeah,
that's why we're doing the show. Yeah.
you know, and it's like you'd only be
judged by the people that you surround
yourself with. And those are the people
that who really know who who you are,
you know, and and and that's what I was
saying before where don't let anyone
tell you who you are because, you know,
you tell people who you are.
Yeah, that that was great. Go ahead,
Cosmic. I know you got something else.
Sorry, JJ. I'm just a huge fan of your
work, you know. Um I I have I I believe
I 95 is your strain as well, right?
Yeah. I didn't I personally didn't do
that money Mike uh my partner he he he
made that he made that strain you know
he's not as active on social media he's
not on Instagram or anything like that
you may find him on um uh on can um IC
Mag uh but on the forums there but yeah
he doesn't really post too much he's
very kind of private personal family guy
absolutely well I mean I love the turpps
that you work with and I was just, you
know, as a fan of, you know, the the
strings that you've put together, I was
wondering what are you working on right
now and what are you most excited about?
Uh, I mean, right now I'm I'm kind of
like just kind of remaking the sour, you
know, I'm doing the F6s. Um, I I'm doing
a remake of the Stard Dog right now. Uh,
the dirty taxis have been really uh
wellreceived. uh they're making a you
know big impact on on the concentrate
game
and you know finding its way through the
legal market some of the facilities and
stuff so that's exciting to me. Um I'm
you know been doing uh some haze stuff.
I'm always working on the hazes. So um I
really been trying to um you know I just
did this new thing called the disco
haze. And so it's the cough times um
Chem D original haze. So that's more the
that original haze came from the Flying
Dutchman. And I believe that one's more
of a Thai kind of a haze. And so the
cough is the same similar kind of a
haze. So that one um yeah, that one's
really good. I'm expecting that to make
some waves soon. And uh yeah, you know,
just going through, you know, different
things. Um but I
mean, seedwise, just you know, just
doing some hunts and stuff like that.
And uh you know maybe I'm you know I'm
really maybe going to start maybe
starting to focus on uh some turpps a
little bit more but trying to stay
within my gene pool and maybe you know
maybe do a little out thing but I'm not
really sure you know exactly on on that
direction yet. But it just seems like
you know like I was explaining you know
before about the turpps and everything.
I think that is it's so much more um in
today's uh market on the way things kind
of smell you know and um like I said it
you know smelled a very you
know powerful
um sense and you know it's a big
determination on on the quality of the
flower where people are not looking for
effect as mo as much you know
So, you know, you just got to kind of
Well, it's like you said, too, with
Instagram, everything's visual based.
They're looking at what looks the
prettiest, you know, and that's in their
mind that's what sells. And so, I I
necessarily don't I kind of march to the
beat of my own drum, but I'm always I'm
always, you know, conscious of what's
going on around me and where the market
is heading. And so I, you know, you
can't really lose sight of that even
though you want to do your own personal
things and everything and you know
that's good in and everything but you
know you got to be you got to you got to
be diversified I think in today's market
where you got to do your own thing and
and you know your own niche thing and
then you can kind of touch on some of
the more popular things and you know you
just got to try to find a a nice rounded
program that's going to work for you
depending on, you know, how many lights
you're running and how, you know, I wish
I could [ __ ] run, you know, 100
lights and be doing like these big
population breeding projects and and
pheno hunts and stuff like that, but
it's it's just not possible, you know,
unless you're, you know, in in a
commercial facility and, you know,
things like that. So, um, that's not
really really what my main focus is
because the commercial game is just
[ __ ]
it's just horrible over all around, you
know, just like working in those places
and just it's just, you know, it's just
just not me. I'm more I'm more happy
just being kind of a small kind of a guy
and just do, you know, I would love to,
you know, be a legal brand and and all
that, but the way that, you know,
regulations and the licensing is set up,
it's just not set up for people to be
profitable. And it's like if I'm going
to invest my life savings in trying to
start, you know, a business, you know,
like, you know, I I'm going to I got to
make sure that it doesn't fail, you
know, cuz I, you know, at my age, you
know, there's not any going back, you
know, so I want to keep what I have,
what I've, you know, I've worked all my
life for. And you know, I have a little
piece I could, you know, work with, but
like, you know, I'm not going to do it
unless I know I'm going to get instant
results. And the way things or at least
a safe result. Yeah. Exa. Exactly. You
know, back in the day, at our age, we're
not taking so many risks. No, but back
in the day, if things were like they
were back in the day where you could
[ __ ] sell wet weed and, you know, it
didn't matter what it was. I mean,
that's like a nobrainer. Like, that's
you know what I mean? like I'm all in on
a situation like that, but it was a safe
bet. Yes. Back then? Yes. It's It's not
a safe bet anymore. I I won't mention
anyone by name, but you and I both know
somebody that was at Mike's wedding that
we're talking about could have been his
best man if I didn't if I didn't do what
the priest said. And to be honest with
you, he grew [ __ ] weed. like, you know,
like it was but he always sold it, you
know, like you were able to grow [ __ ]
weed and and by the way, if he's
watching, I [ __ ] love this guy with
all my might. That's why I didn't say
that's why I didn't mention him by name,
but like um yeah, back in the day, you
could grow [ __ ] weed and not cure it
properly and sell it for [ __ ] 6,000
to 10,000 a pound, you know? It was
insanity, you know? So, hey, I want to
ask you, is this your Instagram? Can you
see that? The Real Top Dog Seeds. That's
me. Yeah. Um, so I just wanted to make
sure and give everybody an opportunity
to check out JJ on Instagram at the Real
Top Dog Seeds and Do A WG. And actually
before we go, I I man, we'll keep on
having more questions, but weren't you
the guy that originally called the dog,
you know, that spelled it D A WG? Yes.
Yes. And my really tell us about that.
It was the Trey dog that really and the
star dog that really And so I really did
that just to try to set myself apart,
you know, from from Greg and original
Chem Dog guy. And so I didn't really
want, you know, I, you know,
I'm not the one that credit, I can't
take credit for the chem, you know, I
can only take credit for working with
the chem. And I can only be, you know,
thankful that it was passed to me and
that I was able to do what I did with
it, you know, and so, you know, I I
can't really take any credit for for the
chem or anything like that, but, you
know, I can, you know, take credit for
what I've done with working with it,
though. And so I mean when we got it,
you know, we knew it was something
special, you know, but back then like,
you know, we, you know, there was so
many strains back then. You didn't
really know the we didn't really know
the whole genetic pool like we know it
now. and like unknowingly like you know
it was the best weed that I ever got
back in the day but I'm sure that there
was other weeds that were just as good
if not arguably be better that that that
we probably lost you know and so um yeah
like I said I was just lucky to be at
the right place at the right time and be
able to get that strain not knowing that
it was going to be what it is today you
know which you know that that was just
dumb luck
for Sure. And I see on your Instagram
you have a Discord. Is that a good way
to uh you know if someone wanted to put
in you know an order or something? Yeah.
Yeah. The Discord is a lot more looser
and the way we talk and you know stuff
like that. And I also have another
backup um Instagram account Top Dog
Siege
JJNYC. So yeah, uh the the the Discord
is um is is a little bit, you know, of a
more stable platform where we could
actually have like conversations. People
can show, you know, uh what what they're
and really the Discord is not even
really about me. is like mo it's mostly
about the users and they're the they're
the ones that are posting what they're
finding in in in Top Dog Seeds and
talking about other strains that are
relevant and can you know just the
cannabis community and everything. So,
it's really kind of set up more for the
users and people that that buy the
seeds. And I try not to like get too
involved in in editing comments, good or
bad. You know, if someone pop, you know,
pops a pack of my seeds and they're not
happy, they say a [ __ ] or whatever the
case may be. Like, you know, that that's
their opinion. You know, I'm not I'm not
going to
cherrypick comments that are uh that are
good and bad to to make myself look
better. you know, uh, the proof is in
the pudding. And if 10 people say it
sucks, I would [ __ ] I would bet that
it probably sucks. So, you know, my at
the end of the day, my opinion doesn't
mean nothing. you know, whose opinion
matters are the people that are finding
the results, you know, and so if we want
to be honest about and and transparent
about everything, and that's the way I
I've always been, good and bad, you
know, you're not always going to hit a
home run. You're going to you're going
to, you know, get a a couple uh ones
that aren't that aren't going to make
the cut or whatever. And, you know, you
just got to live. you start editing out
the bad comments, then people know that
it's that it's not legit. You don't have
the like you don't want to edit out all
the comments, you know, all the bad
comments. It's just no, it's just and
even, you know, people can personally
attack me or say whatever they want
about me. Like I said, it doesn't mean
that it's true. I mean, but am I g, you
know, just because they said something
that I don't like, you know, am I going
to edit that that out? I may argue with
that person and try to, you know, prove
my point or whatever, but you know, they
have an opinion and uh in a point also.
So, it doesn't mean that it's right, but
you know, we can we can debate that.
Yeah. But opinions could be like
[ __ ] you know. We all got one and
they all stink. Yeah. No, some stink
more than others, you know. So, uh yeah,
you're you're right about that. So, you
know, you know, to me, just trying to be
transparent and honest and you know, you
you you just got to, you know, operate
correctly
and, you know, everything will, you
know, take its place down the road.
Well, there's a reason why you have had
the longevity you've had and I I think
it's because of that, you know. Well,
people, you know, you could ask people
who know me personally and they'll tell
me, they'll tell you who I am, you know,
and those are the people who know me,
you know, and so your reputation kind of
follows you and the longer you you're
around, you know, the more people can
vouch for you and, you know, it's just
something
that, you know, over time it just, you
know, it is what it is, you know, so you
just try to [ __ ] stay correct
and, you know, it, you And and if people
want to hate on you, then
then e even the best who if you're in
the public eye, it doesn't matter who
you are. If you're a singer,
entertainer, play
sports, anything, there's someone that
hates you. So there's someone that don't
like you for whatever reason. I don't
like their song. I don't like, you know,
I don't like their team. I don't like
this. I don't you know so it's something
that you got to live with you know and
and if you got a thin skin and you can't
take hate and you know I would say you
know being in the public eye is probably
not for you you know because do you
think it's do you think it's thin skin
or do you think that it could be caring
too much what people think about you
because well that too I mean I used to
think you know I don't think I have thin
skin but I do care what people think of
you. I I do. I do too. And back in the
day, it meant something when you were on
the forums, you know? It really meant
something because that's all you had was
what people said about you. You know
what I mean? So, you could be be black
balled out of the community very easily.
In today's world, it's it's totally
different now. you know, it's just, you
know, it's like kind of anything goes,
you know, with the scammers and copycats
and just, you know, just keeps going on
and on. Uh, so you just got to kind of
block all of that out and you know, you
know what's true and what's not true. So
when people are saying stuff that's not
true about you, you can't let that
bother you or show that person that it
bother you bothers you because they just
they'll just continue on and make it
worse. You know, it feeds the trolls
entertainment. Yes. you know, and and
some for some people that's what their
sole mission on the internet is to do is
just to try to, you know, ruin people
because their their life is sucks
themselves. So, they want to make
everyone as miserable as as they are.
So, Oh, uh, Gabby, you're muted.
I said, "I I really appreciate you for
coming on, JJ, and we could talk for
hours more and and we should we should
do it again. Um I think we probably
could do another show of two and a half,
three hours and and still not scratch
the surface." Yeah. No, there's just so
there's just so much out there now that,
you know, it's uh I mean, one thing
like, you know, I I do want you to come
back cuz I want to hear the stories
about how you were busted and, you know,
Yeah. There's no real behind any of
that. Well, it's not about glory, but
it's a it's still Yeah, it's part I
mean, it was part of our lives. It's
it's something that we had to deal with
on a regular. If you want to finish what
you were saying, and if you have
anything you want to say about the Yeah,
I mean I mean it is one of the best
strains that, you know, that that's out
there in existence today, you know. I'm
sure
that's a matter of opinion, you know.
But the thing about the 91, it it
doesn't have no taste to it. And I don't
think it's not it's not quite as strong.
Not quite as strong. That's what I think
it has. I don't think it's got the onion
garicky thing going on. How can you say
that? Yeah. But I I just want the chem
the 91 taste is what my that's kind of a
more desires and and the chem I I agree
that the chem might be more potent but
for me it's all about the terms. I don't
know. To me it's a little more blandish
the chem the 91. But I still appreciate
it. I love it. You know what I mean? But
it's a lot harder to grow too than than
the n the chem. The 91 is kind of like
the the sour diesel. It's kind of
finicky and sometimes it can come out a
little bit a little bit different than
others, but like um like like we've been
growing it and it's kind of gotten like
this little kind of purpley tip to it
almost now in in in the in in the turpps
that are coming out on it. Like it it's
uh kind of t almost like a
little purpley grapey just a little
slight tinge in there, you know? But um
yeah, it's funny, you know, that I think
it's kind of changed over the years a
little bit. How does the four uh I mean
the four was kind of found
afterwards and um so I guess that that
uh Greg had seeds. Well, I guess he had
like 12 or 13 seeds originally. Then he
popped I don't know how many maybe like
half of them or then he gave um the
other four seeds the Joe brand and he
found the chem one two three four and I
I wound up breeding with the the chem
four and that was the the one um that
was the best one out of the four and
like some people like to think that it's
it's not the same as a chem you know
that It's different than the Chem91 and
Chem D. And you know, they they might
have an arguable point there. It's kind
of hard to say, you know, because like
the one, two, three, four very all the
same. And whereas the 91 is kind of
stand on its own and the Chem the Chem D
and the Chemister were alike. So there
was like almost three different
phenotypes in there. And so with the
last four being popped last, you know,
there is some controversy of people
saying that it might not be it might
have been seeds of the chem or something
like that like a cross of the chem
should I say and not the original chem.
But none of that can really
I mean that story kind of checks out
because you know Greg had four seeds of
the original
ones and then years later more but the
thing the but but they said the same
thing about the about the Chem D and my
argument is like cuz he he he popped
them in 2005 or six or whatever in the
90 I mean the the Chem D and the Chem
and sister are almost exactly alike
other than one being more sativa and the
other one being more indiga but there's
no denying that they're they're not
sisters. Okay. So you can definitely say
that those are they're the same. And
then the 91 was in the same pop as the
sister. So those two are confirmed right
there.
So yeah, the last four seeds that were
popped that were totally different from
those two. I guess you can argue that it
could be that is can we prove it? It can
never be proven, you know, but I don't
know. It's just one of those. Yeah, I
was going to say is this one of those
things in cannabis that we'll never
know. We'll never know.
Right.
What Greg always said was, "You're
muted, cosmic." What What Greg always
said was that anything he grows is the
Chem Dog. Right. Okay. Cuz he's Chem
Dog. Yeah.
That if you were to rank those three,
uh, yeah, I would say Chem D, 91, Chem 4
for me. You know,
I'm growing Chem4 for the first time
right now. And Chem 4 is kind of funny
because for me when I grew Chem 4 it
always finished like 60 63 days. Other
people are like I take it to like 77 or
something like that, you know. And so
and even my star dog, you know, which is
pretty much Chem 4. He's kind of chem uh
chem arguably Afghan, but uh all of
those come out finishing pretty much
like the Chem 4, you know, they they're
all kind of kind of short squat uh big
buds uh finishes and usually like 63
days and stuff. So, um, yeah, it's it's,
you know, the Chem4, you know, the the
genetics are pretty dominant on on it,
you know, and it kind of has that piny
kind of little bit of fruiness to it,
you know, depending on the phenotype
and, you know, if it leans more chem,
which kind of like the Corey Star Dog
does, and or the guava, which is more
Chem4. So, that was kind of the
differences in in that in that cross
there.
Nice. That's very interesting. Yeah, I I
love all those trains. So, it's it's so
cool to hear the history, you know,
right right from you.
Well, like I said, JJ, we got to have
you come back on because we got we got
way more stories to tell. So, just just
let us know one's good for you and, you
know, and we'll get you back on. And I I
I really appreciate you spending 3 hours
of your day with us. I would like to get
on, you know, it' be nice to get on with
like Klopp or some, you know, get, you
know, Klopp AJ, you know, try to get,
you know, kind of a group thing of the
people that were, you know, were there
back in the day, you know, we if we can
get, you know, Vondo or Maxwell and try
to get, you know, some of this, you
know, the the the sour trying to sort it
out. Yeah. Sour diesel round table.
Yeah. I just don't qualify to be there
except maybe as a guest.
But yeah, I'll I'll know that Mike will
do a a video with you. I actually
thought about having him come on to do
this one, but I just kind of wanted to
do one with with you first, but Michael
do it for sure. Um, and then we can call
these I you know, I don't talk with uh
AJ very much. I'm in I'm in I got his
number. I'm in, you know, um, usual
contact with him. Yeah, let's do it. Let
Let's do a Sour Diesel round table real
soon. And until then, I hope you have a
Yeah, you too. I appreciate you having
me on and everything and everything's
going good for you. Oh, I'm sure I had
the most fun of anyone here. Okay, take
care, guys. Thanks, buddy.
[Music]
Oh