this episode of gabbing with Gabby is
brought to you by the Breeders direct
Seed Company in my opinion the Breeders
direct seed company is your Premier
Source for clones and seeds and they are
the only place that you can get the
Gabby Staten Island collection so visit
breeders direct for all your seed and
clone needs
[Music]
this is Gabby and we're actually going
to announce the new name of our show is
your weed stories and today we're joined
by Kevin JRE from Wonderland nursery and
from the Grateful head and many other
projects and of course Sasha the
Slovenian Hobbit our International
correspondent giving us some
International FL there and we're super
excited to continue the story with Kevin
JRE today um we had a great talk I think
it was a week ago and uh we weren't able
to complete it so we're doing this again
anyway here we
go what is that your smoking Kev uh some
cherry
pie cherry pie is one of my favorites
yeah know I love it too man it's just
it's just got it's it's a beautiful
plant it really is the
years you still have the cut obviously
no actually no I shared it out I I did a
bunch of breeding with it so I have it
in that form I'm just trying to you know
I mean I'm somebody that's collected
forever and there's a point in your life
where you just want less plants to have
to deal with in your own home yeah I get
it unfortunately that's how we uh I mean
you got to spread it out enough when you
do that because that's how we lose stuff
right oh totally totally and then you're
also at at the same time too put it into
put it into projects and then you can go
play around and go play with the tool
try to find it again through the hunt
yeah and like I said I I I if if I have
the ability to move the plant I move it
if you gave it to me and said Kev this
is for you you can't share it nobody can
breed with it I don't want it in the
system then I I I protect it and I've
always historically done that which is
what's let me access so much [ __ ] people
being able to trust you yeah I'm not
going to [ __ ] you on the plant it it
because at the at the end of the day I
can probably go around you and get it
from someone else too so it's just it's
just
this gentleman's agreement of if if it's
if I get it from you and you don't want
to touch then that's where it stays but
I always my entire career in in the game
I've always shared jeans and it's funny
but a long time ago that [ __ ] wasn't
popular people get pissed off because it
was um I want I almost want to call it
cultural elitism this idea a that only
the special people have the special
plants and I'm
like you don't have to be balling to be
special and once you got the right plant
it UPS your quality of life dramatically
if you know what to do with it and so
for me you know moving really valuable
plants into the
public it always pays off because one
you're doing something that's human and
second people that you give plants to
that are dependent on the plant and have
a different relation ship they're the
ones that actually hold it for 15
years so can I tell you a little story
yeah go back go big while you finish
rolling your joint I can roll it and
talk yeah um so I don't know how much
you know about my story but I had a
small little piece of the chem dog story
is I brought it out West I was the one
that got it from Greg and I drove it out
west and
at the time Greg had told me not to
really pass it around totally and the
only person that I gave it to was Jason
you know VA skunk yeah and he gave it to
one of his Partners Ben from IC
Collective yep and somehow after that it
really got
out and at the time not being as mature
as I am today and think thinking about
consequences like you you know you just
spoke about and also the advantages of
of giving out genetics I was kind of
pissed you know that it got out because
you know I was selling the chem dog for
6,400 a pound oh totally and so like out
right but but what I wanted to tell you
is so it got out I don't know exactly
how it got out but it got out to the
world and you know with maturity
I realized that Not only was it good
that it got
out but that it was responsible for the
creation of so many new strains that
wouldn't have happened if it didn't get
out so at the time I was pissed and you
know had regrets that had had gotten out
but now I realized that was a great
thing that happened and it really it
increased the Legacy of the
plant you know so at a point there's a
there's a time and place where it just
needs to get out to
everybody you you because we like we
like we know we got the grateful Head
Right which is the idea a
repository and people don't catch that
like if you're in in in professional
plant
breeding most professional plant
breeders can go into a genan bank and
get true F1 stock right they can get
they can get true inbred lines they can
get a stock that's deriv from two M
brand lines which is a true F1 so they
can work on
projects and we don't have that in
cannabis what we have is like really you
know these loose collections which which
I love because they keep things alive
during the the dark ages of uh law
enforcement raid and so for me some of
the stuff that I lost I lost because it
wasn't just one raid it was like a raid
on us and then then uh another room
another house gets hit and so you you
end up having things lost
and the ability to be able to keep these
plants alive just and a lot of it
is I just want to say it's a mark in
time it's like a memory
stamp and so when you when even if it's
no longer what it once was to you it's
something you know like I I connect the
plants to like that
AK-47 bought my
house that OG bought my [ __ ] Farm
like it was that single plant that I
multiplied into money that that did it
and so I always have this you know this
relationship mentally and it's it's it's
it's stuff like that that it's not even
about today's commercial usage it's just
that these things we touched and and
historically had relationships with and
so I think that the idea of like as many
people possible touching the plant as
many PE people possible moving it around
as long as somebody holds it in its
original form right and and what we know
now too is that when we hold plants in
original form I don't give a [ __ ] you
scrub and they don't you take a plant
and you expose it to 30 years of
impact that impact changes the plant the
plant picks that up and even though when
we use the word like genetic drift
genetic drift implies breeding and it
implies you're losing track of the
traits of interest that originally were
in your lens and so you're breeding a
plant or you're breeding a dog and
you're moving slowly away from the
traits that you were originally
interested in until they're no longer
present so yes you're breeding the same
line without the same traits that's
genetic
drift I'm just talking about like
epigenetic influence change where every
time you clone the plant every every
time it's it's sprayed with a product
every time it's going through some cycle
subtle change and degre it yeah and and
and modifies itself and like a really
good example is and I did this years ago
and I was talking to somebody about it
but I had a you know whole OG collection
right and so and I'm running all of them
so I know exactly they are not the same
plant right they are definitely
flowering time profile uh just all the
different factors that you would say hey
side by side the shit's not the same but
when we DNA them they all came out as
Josh do OG ghost OG right so they all
came out as this original and so the the
theory was that's all S1 right they're
all s1's but the truth of it was that
when we really went into the DNA
analysis they were all ghost OG and me
and the science team arguing about it
because they're like they're all the
same we're just calling them different
things and I'm like yeah but as a grower
they're definitely not the same thing
because the traits are radically
different but the ne but the DNA doesn't
lie and and someone online I was talking
to the other day a scientist out of
Europe was like DNA doesn't lie but it
also sometimes it's hard to get the
truth out of it because we have to
understand how to really look at what
we're seeing and it was this it was this
theory that when we talk about why
plants have changed over time and so
many of them have it's who held it and
how was it held and that's why you have
so many variations of all the similar
same plants it's this cut of that plant
and the truth of it is is it's the exact
same plant but it slowly mock ified
after two three four 500 colonal Cycles
can I respond to that yeah how about
like this as an example let's say we
could clone a human mhm and so let's say
there was a clone of Gabby Staten Island
or Kevin JRE and it was completely
identical
but one of these clones took care of
himself
differently okay maybe one Gabby Staten
Island eats nothing but
McDonald's and and Coca-Cola and and
fast food and and doesn't exercise and
then there's another one that um eats a
healthy meal you know healthy diet and
exercises when they're both
90 they're both going to look
dramatically different totally say oh
this this is these aren't the same
people but actually the DNA is the same
yeah when you look at DNA the DNA is not
going to tell devation right DNA is not
going to tell you how you were cared for
as you know as you you know go through
your years and that's going to have an
effect on the body of a human or the
body of a plant correct totally and we
we we were also you know the the
conversation was about where did a lot
of these profiles why have they
diminished why they no longer
so
extraordinary and I take a look at I'm
just like you know I said it I don't
think that it's so much any kind of
procedural change because that would be
easy to fix if you
were if you working with your plant and
you notice the change in the quality of
it from crop to crop you'd be like wait
a second I'm going the wrong way with my
process you typically wouldn't improve
it and so if your drying method becomes
more scientific and your quality
decreases you go back to War by field
right as a grower you're flexible with
what you do but when you and I think
it's the the age of chemical uh
cannabis that when we really started to
focus on pesticides and
insecticides and growth Regulators you
started to change the metabolic pathways
of the plant because the plant no longer
had the need to produce those
metabolites so it started to slowly shut
off that production route and over the
course of 2030 years and all the fuels
are the ones that you really see a lot
of this in in terms of they were so
heavily covered in
these
adulterant that over the course of 30
years of doing it they just stop
producing what's not needed and then the
issue is then someone's like you know
you scrub it right so I I thought if we
scrub it we go back to zero but no we go
back to the zero of that day we don't go
back to when it came out of the seed
right it's a nice idea but all you're
doing is cleaning up the plant but
you're not cleaning up the epigenetic
change TC doesn't [ __ ] scrub the
genes it it allows you to outgrow a
pathogen it but it doesn't undo what
we've done so I mean I and I love TC I
think it's probably the you know one of
the best tools you could possibly have
for you know modern day
cannabis because we have so many
different issues that are spread through
conventional propagation now because we
have all these different a forms
touching us and so for the first time
ever herb is touching everything because
its location spread from from a closet
to a field to the Central Valley and now
you're in the middle of some of the you
know largest a production Zone on
Earth the cross-contamination is
unreal but regardless you still have to
you still have to do the best you can to
hold the stock and it's the same thing
with like land race preservation where
the minute you take it out of the
country origin you're not really doing
land race preservation but you're
preserving what you can so I don't think
cuz someone said you know when when
you're trying to do what you're doing
Kev you're not doing anything and I said
well I kind of am though because really
what the goal is is to get people to be
aware of stock that's not what we would
call
domesticated to get people to be aware
of other cultures that produce cannabis
in other
forms and to be able to get access to
that material and that's the part of the
preservation that's really occurring but
the idea of preserving that material in
its true form can only be done in its
true form so like Colombia would have to
do its own preservation
you know um Gene protection California
we don't have any native stock we would
just work with what we have but Pakistan
Afghanistan India Lebanon you know Place
Colombia that's had you know four 500
years of cannabis in
place that's where I think that the
preservation has to occur but since you
we don't have control of that we do the
best we can so we work limited
populations ideally you know it'd be
like like Sam was saying you know 10,000
is the population you want where you
have full open po population of 10,000
into bread that gives you enough genetic
capture to say that you've captured the
the the qualities of a gene pool for
future preservation nobody's doing
10,000 [ __ ] plants on a preservation
it's just it's just impractical you know
we don't have that ability most people
are doing 10 or 20 seeds and think that
that's getting and they're and they're
picking breeding a lot and sometimes it
works if you you know the outliers
always emerge I think that the a good
story for people is uh uh super boo
right where the guy that does Super boo
came out of two 10 packs right so he
buys a pack of seeds of one buys a pack
of seeds of the other selects out a male
and a female puts him together he gets
Leafly strain of the
air and that's just phenomenal but now
people will see that and say I too can
do this and you're like maybe right
maybe maybe you know it's doesn't always
work and sometimes you can go through
100,000 seeds and if the if the the
alals aren't present that contain that
that that information that [ __ ] isn't
moving forward if you don't get to if
you know you can have one copy and then
a mutated copy if you're not the copy is
not present or they're both mutant
that's done you just don't have that
that information to move forward so I
think that we do the best we can but a
lot of it is is private people that do
Banking and you know you're one of them
I'm one of them you are you you you uh
you save plants too sash of course I
have a I'm a librarian you know I have a
facility in Austria where we have 35
different
cultivar uh in preservation form you
know we cloning moms traditionally we
going to do tissue culture in the future
so that is our perspective of it you
know I'm following you since many years
since you did uh Wonderland Nursery I
saw the videos where you are in the
nursery you know
uh and before I wanted to ask you
because you were talking about this
genetic drift I remember very clearly
that you were talking about Lou the 30
no jush in one video and you were
showing the plant and you were talking
about that you were doing uh Bashi and
gashi techniques to bring it back
because it was kind of sick because
these people that brought you this plant
uh brought you a sick plant actually so
you tried to actually how is it still
alive I mean do you still alive and it
got moved into the system the thing with
the Louie was the Louie came out of a a
group of Armenian Brothers in Los
Angeles and out of some crazy
coincidence I help out their
mother-in-law right like she's just an
older lady she's nice and I'm just nice
to her one day and I help her out with
the problem and she um uh gives my phone
number to her son-in-law and he hits me
up and he's like hey I'm I'm this dude
and so he rolls up in a in a a a Range
Rover with uh his crew they all hop out
in suits and they hand me a couple
clones and say this will change your
life and I was laughing cuz I already
had a whole OG collection right so it
just one more OG yeah but it was this
beautiful thought and it was a thanks
and I app I was just grateful because it
was like so pure where you helped out
our mother-in-law we're going to help
you with um the ability to make money
and the the issue was what we we we had
discovered with um like hop Leighton
because like remember I've been doing
this [ __ ] for a long time so like when h
l pops up we're all getting [ __ ]
hammered by it because none of us really
know we we know there's some kind of
mutation but we don't understand what it
is but I get lucky in that I get uh a
team of scientists that come to me and
out of SoCal Central Cal and and humble
and this this cat named Rick Crum a PhD
unist named Rick
crumb says hey what we have is we've
discovered some kind of pathogenic
problem we don't understand it we don't
have a name for it right now but we know
what it's doing we understand what it's
doing to the plant but we just don't
know what it is and we wanted to uh see
if you wanted to play around with the
project and I was like I'm down I said
because I was having a conversation with
this guy named Allan
Atkinson who's from um the probiotic
Farmers Alliance right right him and him
and Mike had created the
alliance and and Allen's background was
in um silage fermentation Anor
robics and so he had this belief that if
we return the system back to this
anerobic driven low oxygen environment
which is really what Earth is right
there it's very low O2 and when I had
this discussion with elain inam because
elain inam came to visit me after she
saw this so we could kind of understand
how do you define low oxygen
and it's really like this just line of
PPM how many parts per million a present
so she she was like if you don't have
you know oxygen driven compost tea it
won't work and I showed her Allen's sub
irrigation
system and she realized that there's
like this gray area that's in between
anerobic and aerobics and it just
becomes this determination of what do
you define as low or no
oxygen and what Allen's deal was that he
believed that if you put a plant back
into this sub irrigation system and you
allowed it to naturally you know Drive
its function we should see a return to
homostasis so he has a hypothesis right
and I said all right let's let's let's
see if we can turn it into a theory
let's try to prove the
hypothesis and I end up getting that
that plant from the lab and it's
infected and we know it so we put it
into isolation I put it into that system
and over the course of like 45 days it
basically just sat still I mean because
it was heavily impacted and impacted
would imply in this case it was a Girl
Scout cookie cut it came from an
operation that used to have 100% strike
rate it went down to like 3% strike rate
so out of the Thousand clones you know
they were getting 30 no way like I mean
yeah just low and so they said hey we
know this is impacted this is what the
impact is let's see if we can do it so I
take it and I put it in the system and I
sit it in this in this this chamber and
it just sits and all of a sudden I
started to see like the the the surface
cracking and you could see new cambial
material forming like these lines coming
up and as this new Cambio material was
creating it was shedding all its old
leaves and new leaves were appearing mhm
and once I had this new formation I cut
those clones and they all rooted and and
then I put him under uh light to grow
them up but I stressed one side of a
tray because it was getting too much
light exposure for its age and it
retriggered the Hop Laten and because I
had the lab constantly testing
everything we were like whoa so that was
when we discovered that if you can keep
a plant in in some form of homostasis a
Natural
Balance the The Hop L doesn't seem to be
an issue it can work with it doesn't
mean it won't transmit it but it didn't
affect its secondary metabolite
production doesn't that also depend on
the viral production by
weight doesn't that also depend on the
viral load like if there's a low viral
load impct it very much it does it does
but this PL these plants were covered so
they had high high load they were
absolutely falling apart which was let's
let's try because there was they didn't
understand that the degree of in they
the brilliant guys but you got remember
it's the dawn of this problem right same
with like russet mites and [ __ ] like
that where people be like had russet
mites I'm like well who the [ __ ] didn't
nobody knew we had them we we had to go
buy a microscope to identify the problem
because there was no predecessor before
us to identify it so when you're when
you're in an industry and you're like
you're first right you're you're you're
doing this at speed you're going to
catch all the problems and it's it's
it's interesting because when you get
into science it's the same for them just
because they're brilliant and they have
every tool known to mankind doesn't mean
they understand the problem they just
discovered so we're trying to figure out
is this something you can work with and
when I stressed those plants the ones
that got stressed reverted and the ones
that didn't didn't and I was like woo I
got you all we have to do is add some
stress load to the organism and the the
vroid reemerges so we knew that you
could have plants that that appeared
completely clean but without testing you
weren't aware you were passing the vroid
forward because your operation wasn't
overly stressing the plant and on the
ones that were
undressed meaning they were you know
kept with with the balance the the the
strike rate went right back up to a 100%
so we went right back up to a th000 out
of a thousand on the plug so it worked
well for them but it let me understand
how plants respond and how we impact
these issues so when I cut that um box
in and I already had the cut from from
on the Louie I put it in that system to
see if I could do the same thing could I
get it to return back to like an
original state and it kind of did the
same thing it it it it it changed and it
became a beautiful plant again and then
I shared that out into the public and so
a bunch of different people have it
Allen still runs it a couple local farms
still use it as their um component if
you got a copy of that you probably had
to have got it from me because it was
nobody that was it was an in-house OG
held by a group that did not share the
cut because it was super valuable at the
time I have a cross you know in my
facility we have a cross with it's
called zoft I don't know how you
Americans call it but it's Z A W uh TZ
it's from compound you know it's a
breeder cut from from Chris and it's
Louis the 1 G cross to Skittles totally
and you might they might have they might
have got that like when when node first
started note and conception basically
the majority of the plants that they put
into the system came from
me so like when when node lit up as an
operation it was through my collection
that they mined the majority of that
original stock before they before they
built the relationship with with Chris
right so you got you got Chris Lynch who
was compound who then merges with node
that becomes compound then they have a
Fallout but before all that took place
when node first lit up we were all going
to work together and they came over and
harvested a tremendous amount of
material from us to begin the project so
I'm not saying he definitely got it from
me but there's some plants that I know
without a question that [ __ ] was not in
the system till I put it in the system
MH and but it's a nice feeling it's
critical
you have yeah you got to you got to put
the genes in so that people can play and
at the end of the day it it it's just
about interest right if you can spark
interest in people and you know what
there's always a plant that's like
mythological unicorn in your mind that
if you could get your hands on this your
whole world would be better right that's
a beautiful thing and sometimes when you
get the plant you know the hype is
bigger than the reality and you're like
it's plant then other times you get a
hold of something and you're like wow
this is gorgeous I would love to smoke
this every day for the next 10
years and you don't know you just don't
and so the idea though is to create the
excitement and to get people to be
curious and then a lot of it is you know
for the for the older crowd which I'm
one of them it's this idea of like
trying to go back in time and touch
things from our youth because so much of
it's gone but it like I said it's it
changes that's this discussion about
Sour about Sour Diesel and all the you
know which one is yours and I'm like the
good one because when I ran 20 different
ones side by side that's the one that
stood out do I really give a [ __ ] what
the name is at this point no because
unless you're un and even from the dudes
that held the [ __ ] half of them lost the
[ __ ] you've been in the game long enough
you got raided you got raided your
[ __ ] plants vanished then you got to
get plants back from someone else the
minute that [ __ ] leaves your hand and
goes to anybody
else maybe it comes back the
same sometimes sometimes comes back
better some people actually you know
they're they're holding them in in
naturally lit spaces you got them in
supplementally lit green houses you're
running them under biological drive to
keep them healthy but the plants that
you
selected originally were under light and
chemical and rock wool and that's why
you selected the plant so like the idea
that every plant is better biologically
sungrown is not true because the
selection was done under artificial
light with chemical right so I'm like
it's it's the impact of everything
together that creates that
equation and people have to understand
it that you know I mean some of the I I
swear to God some of the best OG I ever
smoked in my life came out of Todd
McCormick's Rockwall block so you know
he's got the original OG but when we
were smoking it at his house I was like
goddamn Todd that's really good OG
cush and you couldn't deny it I had some
sun grown sfv that was cracking
but it had an influence that was a
little different than what my memory was
of OG because OG was all originally
indoor
driven yeah true I wanted to respond to
that by uh mentioning a comment that
Michael wolf seagull made in the last
podcast we recorded and he talked about
how there's I believe he said eight
Tarpin or six Tarpin that will never be
found on indoor cannabis because the UV
light isn't there unless you're
supplementing I believe he said with
like UVB which most people aren't going
to do so when you talk about the way
certain stuff taste if it was Su
grown or or indoor grown you're not
going to have that UV and then you might
not have those Tarpin which is what you
remember as you know the the flavor
profile of that and the lack the lack of
because remember they're they're all
you're you're you're making something
right you're going to use it like
cooking right you're going to you're
going to make a dish sometimes what you
added or what you didn't add creates the
quality and so when you're talking about
anything to do with secondary metabolite
profile and influence when you're
looking at like hop hop testing is
pretty comprehensive more comprehensive
than cannabis because there was no
illegality to it right but when you're
looking at Hop testing you can take two
identical hop cultivars that have a
single ppb difference in one metabolite
part per billion and you swear to God
they were two radically different
animals and we're talking everything
lines up flawlessly except one
metabolite at part per billion and so
our ideas of like looking at a COA is
like this is telling me something it's
not telling you [ __ ] it's telling you
what they want you to know but that
doesn't mean that that's what you need
to know it's good that we're Gathering
some information but it doesn't tell us
the whole picture no no because at the
end of the day right what about
Moonlight because moonlight's it's
reflection it how does that bent
Spectrum influence it and so when I I
got to do I got to I got lucky that I'm
not a [ __ ] scientist my mother was
right and so I'm always really clear
about what a scientist is it's extremely
f focused prove it multiple multiple
locations kind of thing but it lets you
understand that science is as powerful a
tool as there ever was but it's not
omnipotent it doesn't understand
everything until until it's able to
really kind of rip it into
pieces and I got brought in to do the
led development for Helio Spectra when
they first lit up as a business and they
came into North America I got selected
as the person with the operation they
wanted to do the the trials with which
was unbelievable because it was the
first really tunable LED plates you
could do anything with them they were
like 15 16 Grand a plate at the time
right full iPad control I mean [ __ ] that
they're talking about now that [ __ ] was
in
208 right so in 208 the company flies in
the president flies in team of
scientists fly in we set up the the test
operation I'm running the same Cult of
art but under their system and then
under my system side by
side and the the the part that was
fascinating was that the level of light
Engineers they brought in were brilliant
and there was a woman out of the UK
named Tessa Babcock that she she worked
for the Bill Gates
Institute
and she she was making sure that I
understood that it's the information
that the sun
provides via these frequencies that we
don't understand so she's just like look
she goes I don't she goes like like she
go I'm working for the Bill Gates
Institute she goes it's [ __ ]
unlimited money she goes there's nothing
but super Geniuses in the room she goes
I'm telling you we barely understand
what's taking place from sunlight we
really don't understand so what we do is
we do the best we can to create an
effect and by using steered tuning it
allows us to do some interesting stuff
and for the like and it was the and the
example was it was on on basil right the
plant and it was pertaining to certain
countries like
different Leaf shape they like different
length and elongation all they do is
dial in the Spectra to make that occur
she says all of these that you're
looking at she says I'm showing you all
these basle samples she goes it's all
the same [ __ ] she goes we adjust the
morphology through spectral tuning which
makes the country happy it's kind of
like like motor oil the the Americans
like golden oil Japanese like green oil
right so when you buy motor oil in Japan
and you pour it into your car that [ __ ]
comes out green when you pour when you
pour motor oil into your car in America
it [ __ ] comes out gold it's because
Americans believe that golden oil is
clean oil and it's good oil and Japanese
believe that green oil is good oil
that's it's an additive right has zero
to do with with viscosity or any of
those Shear factors anything that
implies fluid dynamics under tension
right when under pressure and heat it's
purely about what people like and what
they don't like and that's what was so
fascinating with you know the indoor
world to me and the tuning and the
adjustment and the and the focus it's
just that if we if you're if you're
using these things to hold things long
term over the course of 15 20 years you
have to have change and so it's it's
it's this reality that it it helped me
understand that like I was chasing skunk
for [ __ ] ever because had this
massive collection of it so I I for
whatever reason I was just really about
it so I had acquired a collection of
plants that all had a really really
similar Aroma profile but very different
morphological
traits and so I said you know and I lost
him in a raid in like early 2000 and
then the the mom room that we had as a
redundant mom room it got hit in an arm
robbery and the idiots that robbed the
spot thought it was a grow house they
didn't realize it was a mom bank so when
they came there was no flower so they
you arm robbery [ __ ] family gets held
at gunpoint they take the moms and
[ __ ] and it was done right we lose that
stock so I go back into the world to see
if I can find it and I'm digging and I'm
digging and I'm digging and and it
wasn't that like I'm going to be the
Discover of it it it wasn't about a
public like it has to be C it was that I
was excited about looking for something
that used to exist and when you when you
share hunts with people in a lot of
regards it inspires people to hunt their
own [ __ ] not just the chase that but the
chase what you wanted you wanted you
know I want the old piff cut I got way
back in the day because none of these
have that that what do you call it the
bathroom the bathroom test where you
walk in the bathroom and the shit's
still hanging in the air 10 minutes
after you burn a
joint it's that it's doing it's the it's
the Chase and I don't care what
population I went through and and this
created this whole online [ __ ] storm
about people saying I got the real [ __ ]
I'm like well if somebody's got the real
one break the [ __ ] thing out so that
somebody can at least enjoy it
and we haven't seen it so there's stunky
and there's things but it's just I
couldn't find it and I got to a point
where I just stopped looking because I
got tired of digging in the Jean Pool
like I mean someone said did you find it
I said no I said I dug for years I went
through all these populations from out
of the country I went through old
populations that I was digging through I
couldn't find it I I found stuff that
was really aromatic and I had I had a
skunk out of like
1981 like old old skunk out of the hills
of humble ancient held forever but it
didn't have that that we would say skunk
piss profile but its th all level was
insane and when you cut a clone off of
it it would basically fill a building
with that musky deep Arrow dramatic make
you kind of almost sweat when you when
you experienced it but a different
direction that I was seeking I wanted
that noxious you know skunk urine and I
couldn't do it and then the one day I
just realized it was okay that maybe
that was just what it was and that it
was a memory that I had an experience
once long ago that I enjoyed for a long
time and when it was done it was done
and I I started to see plants almost
like people that you hung out with that
you really enjoy hanging out with and
they passed away you're not going to go
and replace that person you're not going
to go find a new buddy new new family
member a new new anything that is that
you're going to you're going to get
different things and you need to learn
to appreciate different things and just
be grateful you got to experience it
when it was in your
hands Kevin is this uh the the videos
that show you uh uh drawing uh like a
line and then you say this is the' 60s
7s ' 80s '90s
make these circles right you make these
C yes it's it's it's spheres of
influence it's if we can get back far
enough and open up the population what
do we get into because every time we we
hybridize or move the plant
forward did and that's genetic drift did
we lose the traits of interest that we
originally were so attracted to and you
see it in in in in I'm fascinated by
dogs
because I I am I'm a dog freak at Heart
Right but it's it's it's doing
development on a dog and then there's
specific things of interest and as you
bred you lost track of the
traits and you weren't doing the job you
needed to do with evaluating the progyny
the children to make sure that those
things were being carried forward and
what happens is we do they call it like
paper breeding where you're looking at
the animals via a chart or you're
looking at plants via a chart and the
chart lets you understand where it came
from but it doesn't necessarily tell you
what is imparted from that plant or that
dog in its subsequent breeding
application so just because it came from
something doesn't mean it contains the
[ __ ] you want so yeah it's super skunk
from sensey but that profile you wanted
isn't in that pack so you can run that
[ __ ] because people that's that's the
illusion that you open up a population
everything's present you can go back you
can't if the if those genes aren't
present that [ __ ] isn't there you're not
going to have them just appear from
nowhere so I think that it's the and the
people of today will experience it in
the same way with the things that were
really prevalent and popular for them I
was making a joke about you know the
Legacy gelato cut because people love
gelato if they didn't love it it
wouldn't have been every it's kind of
like Skittle right it's a profile that
people really really like give it 30
years and people want to go back to that
Legacy Skittle cut and after 30 years is
it still tasting like powdered Tang you
know the astronaut drink right and if it
it might not and then people will say oh
it was way better and they'll be like oh
you're old you're reminiscing your
memories off you don't you're you're
incorrect and they'll be screaming no no
I know and that's that that's us we're
screaming no no it was better and people
like you're old and your memories fail
and well it was it that rendition from
that time was better than today even
though we have the most grow
knowledge like you know the amount of
information we have about how to
cultivate cannabis right now is
insane you couldn't have any more
[ __ ] knowledge because you had so
much money in interior development so
much money in exterior development and
then now you have science that can
access it via hemp holy [ __ ] like we've
never been smarter but it doesn't change
the fact that you're not going to
resurrect [ __ ] that isn't
there it's just
done you made a comment um the last time
we talked about how the US and Australia
had um the least amount of experience
growing cannabis in comparison to you
know like Pakistan and these other
countries that they've been growing it
for thousands of years but it it made me
think of something and does that mean
that because you have less experience in
years that you have less knowledge right
because you know I used to own a grow
shop in uh in Willets and there'd be you
know Old-Timers that would come up and
say well we've been doing it like this
for 20 years right but if you've been
doing it wrong for 20 years or if you've
if you haven't continued to learn for
those 20 years that doesn't actually
mean that you have more knowledge so I
guess my question for you was do you
think that even though we have the less
the least experience here in the US that
we have the least knowledge because I
think a lot of people would certainly
think that we've got the most knowledge
when it comes to cannabis uh I don't
know about that one I don't know I mean
if we're talking about indoor
development you you're definitely not
talking uh anything against Holland
right I mean there's when I when I study
Greenhouse work that's all plant
empowerment that's all Dr wheel that's
all that's all dut abis specifically but
that's pretty much is a very small
country it is it is
cultural their agricultural approaches
if you're not following that approach
you're basically going the wrong route
like I mean they're the ones that really
determine like you know Leaf temperature
is what drives the whole process right
so like so much of the information we
have came out of that area so do do I
think Americans aren't aren't talented
oh hell no and do I think that just
because you've done something for long
time does it make you smarter than
someone else not
necessarily but if you have a population
of plants that are present that have
been naturally selected through
environmental pressure then that means
you got 2,000 years of data in the plant
where for us our whole world has been so
erratic that it it broke these custodial
chains and it truncated the populations
we got down into very bottleneck
populations very specific so I think
what we did is when I say that we have
the least amount of time it means we
have the least amount of time for the
plant to
acclimate so us cannabis especially
because the the waren drugs and I used
Australia too it's the same thing it's
these two places seem to have the last
on the Cannabis food chain
and it it it's not a knock to either
place I mean it it really isn't but it's
just a statement of fact that if if your
family lived in an area for 50 years and
their family lived in an area for 2,000
years I would assume your
relatives and you should have higher
adaptation to that
specific I just know that my family is
all like eastern northern Europeans
right then we live in New England on the
coast for same house for like 320 years
what I know is that when I hang out with
my friends friends there's not one of
them that I'm not warmer than right
where like I'm wearing a t-shirt in the
winter everybody else is wearing a
[ __ ] down coat I seem to do really
well in cold weather and I don't even
necessarily like it it's just that I
seem to be able to handle it different
right so I just know that I've adapted
to that cold ass Eastern European
climate then my family moves in to New
England where we're on the coast of
Maine for [ __ ] three centuries
um I think that I my I've adapted subtly
to be able to deal with that temperature
better you know it it I don't get suntan
I have to wear like you know and I work
in the Sun but I have to wear a hat and
I got to wear you know some sun clothes
or otherwise I'll still get a a good
burn even at 60 years old my my my body
hasn't had enough adaptation but if I
lived in Africa and I and I breed and I
breed my children bread and bread and
bread and bread and you go 2,000 years
some of them are going to have melon and
content and that they're going to
definitely have an adaptation to it so I
think that that's what occurred it's not
that we're not bright or the Australians
aren't bright it's not to say that you
know anybody's I I always give the Dutch
credit because almost every single thing
you touch is Dutch you know like wolf
may have came out with the sea of green
with cannabis but the the idea stacking
plants in density was not foreign to
agriculture before that and and it's and
it's not to knock wolf because I know
wolf and I respect him he's brilliant
guy but the reality is so much of these
things that we do come from you know
other methodologies for me like you know
I I went heavy into sub irrigation right
and sub irrigation was how I ran all the
operations because it allowed you to be
able to flood beds and control the the
soak and then the the the Reflow back
that was all taken right out of Dutch a
but I would just do it in large diesel
driven buildings you know I would create
we would custom build the tables cuz
[ __ ] a tables didn't exist you
couldn't buy a pre-made table so I had a
carpenter I I worked with and we drew up
a blueprint and then I would fiberglass
the tables and then when I wanted to do
a project I just let him know hey I need
22 tables and then he would be able to
go get the cut list go purchase the
material assemble the tables glass them
and I would go pick them up in trucks
and bring them up to the operation so
you know we would we we would using
tools from other countries because those
things weren't readily applied at that
time you could get like a a 3X3 table
because that was all that was like the
original plastic table was like the sun
systems and the American Hydroponics up
not far so I knew Janeiro he's passed
away but I and I knew his kids and
Michael was the other uh guy um Christ
Christensen right and so I knew him from
the store but we weren't friendly jaro
was a little a little cooler in some
guards and I knew Jar's kids and but the
3X3 tables just didn't grit out right
because those were designed for solar
systems spins lower lower intensity
light where what I wanted was to stack
thousands over 16 square feet so that I
could I could get what I wanted which
was quicker cyclical time heavier yield
per square
meter and so we just custom built the
tables but all that stuff was stuff that
I was learning going to college for
plant propagation
so once I really started to you know dig
into where the knowledge came from [ __ ]
I mean between Israel has given you all
your science on cannabis predominantly
right most of the deep research on on
profiles and molecular weights all
coming out of Israel and the Dutch are
given you pretty much you know almost
every
Greenhouse has some it has to they're
the ones that did all the work but what
we did is we took cannabis and turned it
into this this cult before it was a
product that was in countries once it go
to the US the US turns it into a cult
and because the US and like it's my
opinion but the US has the ability to do
something most countries don't which is
project that [ __ ] into the world through
the
media so the US is what really hyped up
so much of this stuff and then if you
take a look at the
internet the internet kind of goes along
and you see like OG Kush was one of the
first things spoke on the internet Girl
Scout cookie was like to me the first
plant that was really exploded through
the
internet because that was the only way
people could still access and so I was
never big on forums I was on a couple of
them and I check them out but for a lot
of the Forum cats it was a community
that they needed because they didn't
have one in their lives because they
would they were too hidden but all those
years from you know for me from 25 to 50
from a 60 I've been in Humble County
where that [ __ ] wasn't hidden so every
single one of your neighbors was sparked
up everybody around you was sparked up
so what it did is it allowed
you a different type of relationship way
you didn't feel like you were on your
own you know living in a vacuum whereas
if you were on the East Coast Midwest
you know places like that you really you
really didn't have an ability to ever
kind of come out and talk about weed
publicly you had to use the forums even
living in Sona County it was like that
what's that I said even living in somoma
County it was like that so totally yeah
son is different son is you have yeah
humbal humble's an out of control Outlaw
County in terms of like [ __ ] you we're
GNA go big radically different I would
say Mendo is way more craft same thing
with somoma they're more craft
orientated Mendo was more craft
orientated Humbolt was go as big as you
possibly can 10 that there was no
limit there was just no limit that
bigger was better bigger was okay that
that wrapping yourself in money was not
a bad thing and so humble was different
that but people talk about what's the
Legacy strains Humble County and I'm
like what everyone sold because the
minute that [ __ ] was moving in velocity
those cuts were here and being produced
and that product was leaving and feeding
the country so humbal was different but
it it allow just like right now I don't
really I I'm online but not to the
degree a lot of people are because I'm
actually able to work in the world you
have other resources oh totally for a
lot of people the only resources they
have is what they can find online yeah
and and I think it's a lovely thing and
I think what it's done is it's created
it it's it has a duality you're living
in on the online world that's your
community that's what's right because
it's you it's it's it's we get centered
it's like you you you don't really
have I would say
um an open idea mentally because no
matter what it's you're looking at it
through your eyes so no matter what you
do you're filtering information through
your
biases and it's just what we naturally
do it's it's it's human anything
different than you your sensors tell you
be wary and that's a survival Instinct
right but when you develop it
and that becomes true and real the and
it's it's we had this discussion the
other day it's the idea about like we
use the word craft I I gave a lecture on
Craft so what I did is I interviewed a
bunch of people on what is craft and
their opinion so I asked them what's
craft and then I ask them and how do you
grow and each person their method fit
their identity right like craft is what
I
do it it's it's it's only by hand and I
said and how do you grow only by hand
and then person was craft is these
things because they use drippers craft
is only indoor in living soil no no
craft is understanding how to dry back a
block to get the best expression each
individual had
identical reflection of their work into
their
identity and and that was my point of
that lecture was the craft is Wild and
Free it's anything you want it to be
because and it's not your intent because
intent doesn't do [ __ ] in life because
what they say uh the road to hell is
paved with good intentions it's about
what happens from the intent it's the
actual experience of the person you're
trying to create so you can't Define
that you're a craft operator if everyone
who smokes your product says it
sucks that's true not [ __ ] craft
right just leave you're really C craft
is a dramatic word right k r ft and it
really implies by hand and The Craft and
that's like an 1850 word right it comes
out at the same time the Arts and Crafts
movement comes out which was this fight
back against the industrial era so the
industrial era is emerging all this
cheap shit's being produced and this
group emerges and says that's not what
we want and what people didn't
understand was that that arts and crafts
craft movement wasn't about this really
high-end [ __ ] you looked at at the wall
it was a screwdriver that had a really
beautiful handle it was a hammer that
when you held it you wanted to hold it
it was Craftsman tools yes CRA it was
about things you use daily frequently
but at a higher level because those are
the things that had gone through mass
production had changed and the reason
why that whole craft movement worked was
they had a craft like Symposium that was
that was held and it Expos people to it
so from like you know 1850s 1860s all
the way up until the Great Depression
this craft moving kicked ass and I
researched it originally because I used
to do fine woodwor as a hobby and and I
started getting into architecture in
terms of like studying periods and there
was this Craftsman era in in Homes at
that turn of the century that was about
and and it return returned again later
in in in time it returns again in the
2000s where it was this change to go
back to smaller homes with higher
quality details where a bigger house
wasn't more important than a Better Door
Handle than a better sink than than the
elevation of the rooms in terms of
ceiling height to change the feel so
taller Heights give you more expansive
thinking shorter Heights make you feel
more more secure and so it's a justing
the ceiling Heights and spaces it's the
lighting it's the the feel it's the
detail it's you're doing wood workor and
highlighting this this this artistic
expression versus what became known as
the mcmansion which was these cardboard
houses that were [ __ ] caverns and
everybody's like look at my Cavern is
house but you go to you you go to touch
the door handle and it's a cheap door
handle and you feel it so the thing you
touch every day is the door knob and the
door knob sucks so we kind of returned
back into this craft world for people
who had the money to buy the mcmansion
but wanted more of this internal
stimulation from the things they touched
and did and so when I was doing all this
work on Craft and just trying to
understand the argument because each one
of us constantly says what's the
definition of craft it's an acre tops
it's no drip systems it has to be
sungrown by biologically driven to be
craft and it drove me into really
research and I I had done all this wine
research for the appalation project that
that I had helped work on and it was the
same thing it comes down
to how do you view a thing and do people
view it the same and so you know there's
going to always be this dissension and
it's just kind of what it is and so I
just say look if you're somebody that is
living right now and you're 19 years old
you're smoking your favorite [ __ ] you
might want to just hold on to that plant
and hold on to it for emotional sake but
just realize in 30 years the odds of it
being the same plant you smoked when you
were 19 is probably pretty low yes
similar but subtly
different and even with TC scrub because
the thing is the plant if you wanted to
return to the norm you'd have to go back
to the parents and you'd have to have
them in the same situation they were in
when they did the work because they're
passing that information onto the
progeny so there's always change in even
in Pakistan when I went to all the
villages I was like you know what's your
what's your like native stock and your
at your village and they said we really
don't have any Kev what we do is we
constantly share material with other
Villages around us and stock that'll
come in from Afghanistan will move in I
got partners that are Iranian that their
my my partner's Iranian his family still
lives in Iran they cross the border and
grow dope in Afghanistan and then bring
the seeds back into Iran and then ship
the seeds so I got a bunch of seed stock
that got moved via that route to
me but it's their selection what they
wanted what the market wants and then
they narrow the
population that is a change so like what
what I learned is that there's no way to
preserve any of this unless you can
preserve like a good seed batch of that
original material and you're able to
preserve it in some kind of repository
where it's held at the the right
moisture it's held at the right
temperature you're doing germination
testing and once you get to a certain
level of um germination failure you have
to do another repopulation of it and so
that's where really you know like
Australia and the
us we're we're the last in line
we have some of the stricter laws on
cannabis I mean [ __ ] you know how much a
pound in in New Zealand's going for
right now almost nine grand so New
Zealand and I started laughing I said
I'm flying to New Zealand um you know
what I'm saying I'm like [ __ ] I think I
can hide a couple pounds in the tree so
you know you get you know you three
pounds you're talking
27k um that's pretty
interesting so the the the the
restrictions of still so dominant in so
many places it just change and I just
think that people just need to be be
aware of that that's just kind of what
it is and I don't think I'm I'm I have
some handle on this I just know that no
matter where I go and what I dig into
you see shift
and it's okay it's okay that you know
the things are different than they once
were they they can't be the same as they
always
were you know Lobster is small when I
was a kid a lobster would lay across
your table I was from my my whole town
that I lived in the The Village right
was all commercial fishermen right there
be the dragon either doing
shellfish uh which is you know cogs and
clams or you're doing are you doing
lobster and crab right so I grew up
eatting Lobster so much that it was a
normal food
item this [ __ ] was huge you used to have
to get these giant Channel loock pliers
you you weren't using hand crackers you
couldn't get it around the goddamn
bottom of the claw had these huge
channel locks You' use and as a kid you
weren't even strong enough to break it
you have to use a freaking Hammer [ __ ]
um you don't see that anymore swordfish
used to come in different colors it was
like yellow swordfish pink swordfish and
and it was all basically you know uh you
know big blue but you don't see those
variations when you buy swordfish
anymore you don't see the subtleties in
the species you get this and so I just
realiz realiz that those things that I
once had as a kid we probably just
overfished it wiped it out it's just no
longer
present yeah and that's how it the gy
pool also goes now in modern kobis uh
industry right yeah the the it's it's
it's so brother with sister with cousin
with uh grandmother again with uh
grandfather again you know all the time
the same families Collide each other
it's they sexy and it makes it easy and
so you know but the problem is it was I
got into this the other day right and
and I I I don't know if I said it right
but we would piss some people off but it
was about big a doesn't pheno hunt and
everyone started screaming they do but
the thing was I got to work with the guy
that developed GMO corn for Monsanto
right so I don't know if it gets any
[ __ ] higher than that in the food
chain and right and so he was you know
he's brilliant PhD but like he he when
you people don't catch it when you get
to a certain level in breathing there's
only so many companies you can actually
go work for and get make any money and
that's basically you know uh a bear
which is now Monsanto
senta um BASF there's only there's only
so many companies where you're skill
just like when you're a brilliant
neurosurgeon you're not working at the
local [ __ ] emergency room no you
can't you can't pay back your doctor
your doctor debt right you got to go
where the money is right so you go 400
500 Grand into school debt you got to go
make the cash and you
also need to be able to use the tools or
otherwise you're not really satisfying
your
desires so I get lucky in that in life I
get to bump into these guys and and and
they were astounded that cannabis was
you know pheno hunting and that there
was no no inbred populations to pull
from and he was like Kev he goes we go
to the corn bank and we basically go
grab inbred lines that we work with he
goes that's what took so long in
cannabis was for science teams to iMed
the populations that they were going to
use for their hybridizations and I was
trying to tell somebody because people
were saying you know science guys can't
do [ __ ] and I'm like all right so you're
still riding a [ __ ]
horse right so you're I got you still I
got you you you sa across the [ __ ]
ocean in a rowboat if it wasn't for
Science and hold D no air conditioning
no ice you know what I'm saying so like
I don't worship at the alterous science
but I know damn well what it can do when
you give it time and
money MH and it was the idea that lines
are what they work with they try to work
so even if it's a [ __ ] tomato where
you have a A variation of a tomato
you're not doing it by clone when I go
buy tomatoes when I buy some of these
old anti Antiquity Tomatoes they're from
seed because when I take the seed out of
the Tomato we recreate it my girl holds
those seeds and does it is it a [ __ ]
exact copy of each one no there's subtle
shifts but the majority of the traits
pretty much breed
true that allows you to have enough
genetic variation to hopefully ward off
future pathogens which is the issue with
the inbreeding [ __ ] is that when you
take a look it's the problem with the
fuels is that when we got into doing you
know work in the United States so much
of the Afghan work um because you don't
have any humidity in Afghanistan and
Pakistan I'm talking so low it blows
your mind you dry up in the winter I
mean I'm talking like your you your the
the skin on your lips cracks off it's so
dry so you're drinking gallons of water
when you are not even warm because
you're so dry you can hang herb and it's
drying in the room as you're as you're
looking at it it's crazy how bone dry it
is and I really didn't understand how
the [ __ ] you could get such agricultural
like quality with so little water and I
I I realiz I got you it's glacial flow
so atmospherically bone dry but because
you have a you know 27,000 ft cap of of
of you know historic ice that's
constantly moving and flowing down as
Glacier that's where the water comes
from they don't worry about betrus and
they don't worry about PM but when you
move those materials into the
us all of a sudden you now had these
pathogens and the the material that we
bred and and use inherently had that
trait of
susceptibility it it it spawned like I
always tell people I said don't tell me
any fuel that you're touching didn't get
covered with some Eagle at some point in
your
life I'll tell you the amount the amount
of that [ __ ] that got used well the
thing was I got lucky that I knew how to
read an MSDS sheet and so wasn't willing
to use it and my mother my mother wasn't
about what I did at all my mother was
somebody that I could I could call on
the phone and say hey ma um what do I
need to be aware of with these products
and she would send me the information
right and she would just send it from
her office and say here this is what
this is wow so it helped me understand
that all the stuff that we were
using was absolutely cumulative in its
response and that at some point in time
you would saturate with this [ __ ] and
the ability to be able to get it out of
the system and so and it caused problems
too because like for us at the nursery
we we we ran a bio nursery and so we
were getting hammered at times trying to
understand how do you really use
biological Pest Control at scale so I
always get some people talking [ __ ] but
what what no one can talk [ __ ] on was
the extraction companies that I worked
with I was the only [ __ ] vendor they
could get clones from and make product
that could go into a system that was
tested so
you're you have to go through these
evolutions of how do you take tools that
are effective and replace them with
natural
systems and it's what really helped me
understand the the issues we were going
to face with Organic agot scale because
there is no other crop that's run at
that density level they want herb run at
biologically right you don't you just
don't have that level of of density in a
in a house and the the plant count and
the No No ability to use
tools so it's just everyone relied on
these things but those things changed
the plants and they they allowed us to
use plants in projects that we really
shouldn't have used and it's the same
issue with like feminization people are
anti- feminization and I used to be
anti- feminization too because we notice
micro seeds in the lab right so when the
when the product came in the the lab
that I worked with brilliant lab
scientist were like keev they always we
always notice these microscopic seeds
that come in a lot of this feminized
work and so I started to have a a
disbelief in feminization as a tool but
what I learned was that it's it's
incredibly powerful tool to isolate and
trap traits of interest it's just that
when you do
reversals the plants that reverse the
quickest are also the ones most prone to
intersex
Tendencies so you're trying to chase the
money but you're also weaving in then so
the idea then is you go through the line
and you got to go select out and I'm
just like that's my whole point with
this fenal hunting [ __ ] is
that cannabis was a seed line that you
ran and there was enough diversity
within it to give you some protection so
the part that's so interesting
is they they they they have identified
you know on the chromosome where this
marker is that says this is the gene
that that controls your your PM but
what we know is that you have all these
Interlink
genes that that many genes combined
cause an expression so as we start to go
in and start to work with cannabis and
start to you know crisper it a little
which is remove it shorten it or you
start to identify traits and you only
select for those we don't know the big
picture impact of what that
does because we've never done it so it's
the beginning of like what are we doing
to the actual plant itself and because
cannabis is so unbelievably complicated
as a
plant
and almost every other AD crop is
basically evaluated by tons per acre
right bushels per acre right so like
when you breeding corn which someone was
like you know breeding corn I'm like
[ __ ] your feed in the world um I don't
think you quite understand the impact of
that where like you're you're feeding
countries with a product the impact is
massive it's only viewed as a success if
you're getting more in that field and
that would imply that it had it had
protections installed into it to make it
happen but whatever it is what matters
is you get more with cannabis that's not
how we evaluate it it's not about more
it's about that you enjoy it and because
you have this human
evaluation it's very different it makes
it tough and so for me the question is
you know are we going to be able to use
science and humans together to steer
true breeding populations that can be
used in
hybridization access to Gene Banks to
bring interesting material into projects
and the ability for science to look at
stuff in a way to help us that aren't
scientists understand how do we how do
we use scientific principles in our
breeding but steering the end product to
be consumptive quality not just measure
because analytics and coas and all the
other [ __ ] it it gets you to a
Target but we don't know the the riddle
I always call them The Riddles they're
they're many things together create the
answer we don't know what we don't know
totally and and I think that that's
important to say and and I don't think
and and I and I know that there are some
people that are absolutely you know
drowning in weed like we're talking you
know Sam I was on a a podcast with with
uh Dave Watson the other day right Sam
skunkman and [ __ ] gu spent his whole
life drowning in weed I mean drowning in
it like I don't know if anybody went
that damn deep he's he's like the hash
makers I met in Pakistan where when I'm
talking to an old guy and I'm like when
did you do this he goes oh he goes my
first memories are being like three
working with my father in the hash room
beating hash and he goes I I I know any
other life and he said and neither did
my father and neither did my father's
father he goes we've been there for
1,800 years making hash and he goes and
the techniques have evolved because
we've got different material to work
with the quality of the fabric basically
they beat on and the understanding of
how to work with it but it was when he
was holding a piece of hash and he was
rolling it in his fingers and it was
moving through his hand I just was kind
of mystified by it because it was like
2000 years of hash touching was being I
was seeing it he you know he was
probably in his 40s but and looking like
he in the 70s man living in the
mountains is rough but the way the hash
moved in his fingers I just was like wow
just forever it's it's almost like you
know you're
born uh a a a Roth child and Rothchild
wasn't the original name right they they
had it that's a name they took but your
your your you have a a a genius father
who has sons that kick ass and every kid
after them was shaped and groomed by the
time you get to right
now how smart are they in in money if if
all you've done is instill information
every generation and you're only
selecting and and doing that route at
what point are you really really
talented at something you know so I
don't see myself in that route I I I I
I'm lucky that I got the experience so
much and I have some opinions and
there's some [ __ ] I know is fact but a
lot of it is to be just still
mystery and I think that that's why I
like herbs so much is that it's what I
don't know that's cool the the know one
[ __ ] gets dry you're like yeah [ __ ] I
know no but it's the mystery is the fun
part you know it's funny that you say
that because I don't know if we talked
about it the last time but I have strong
opinions on certain subjects right but
it would be exciting and amazing if I
was proven wrong mhm like I don't have
this ego where like I Want to Be Right
I'd rather learn something new you know
so I I think I mentioned it the last
time we spoke about like the debate
between organic and inorganic in a
container grown indoors and I just think
that if you try to do it in a container
indoors in 2 months
you're going to have a hard time doing
it organic in comparison to using
minerals but if someone were to show me
oh look how easy it is to do it organic
and you're going to get a higher quality
product I would be so glad that I that I
was wrong you know so and what's about
Labor too man it's I know you need
basically you know like we kind of have
some ideas that you need at least 15 to
20 gallons of soil as a sink for a plant
in order to get enough material to
access to work in what we would call
like a a living indoor system but when
you get into two and three gallon pots
that shit's tough and it just requires
very
frequent supplementation where you're
adding more material and a lot of it
just comes down to work it's it's it's
the same thing
with if you're running a blue mat is
that cheating where the plants the the
the the moisture level in the media is
telling it when it needs to be wet
versus by hand when you feel the plant's
needs and I just think think cheating we
we fight over this [ __ ] all the time and
what matters is that the method that
you're using works for you and it
produces good quality
cannabis because I I consume I consume
salt pot that is excellent and then I
consume some salt pot that's pretty damn
Bland where it looks with Organic though
right yeah remember back day organic
because it's carbon based but we're
saying that you're using chemical
delivery as your nutrient source as long
as we're not using chemistry on the top
end of the plant I agree I I'm not
having I'm not I'm not so picky where I
won't consume anything that salt based
grown I will it's just that what I
notice is that some things that are
salt-based grown just don't have the
same quality as things that are
organically produced and organically
we're going to we're going to say is as
biologically driven or I call it exate
driven the plant sugars are Drive in the
[ __ ] process right plants driv in the
process I use the word organic with it
and just so that that we have a context
because the words get used so
interchangeably but chemically driven
meaning you're using you're using a salt
solution to you know do the
uptake um I see some incredible cannabis
that comes out of that as well and I
think that some of the
mixes um give better results than others
depending on what cultiv are depending
on what person so you kind of you got to
be able to say best is a very specific
phrase that implies a thing not all herb
grown outdoor is better than all herb
grown
indoor I hear it all the time and I'm
like it's not true and I was talking
about you know uh the concept of
appalachi and valuations
and I said if we utilize the same say hi
you want to say hi hi hi hi that's my
son Wilder want to wave his name is
Wilder okay hi Wilder all right you'll
be good I love you so it was it was this
idea that that the French had this
incredible appreciation for the land and
all these
details and that's what created you know
the wine industry was this incredible
appreciation for all this [ __ ] the
[ __ ] truth of it was and you get into
that 1850 Zone there was three kinds of
wine red white and
Ros and it was the world's fair that was
in Paris that prompted the French to
realize that they had the world in their
neighborhood we might as well highlight
a region and bring forth appreciation
for wine and how did they do it they did
it off the two metrics the the price
point current market price point and
utation of the
brand and then 70 years later they
Define the AOC which is your this this
appalation of origin where' the product
come from what's the impact of the
product and this is most definitely real
regions without question have impact on
products you can't you can't deny that
and and my my point of contention on
this this this lecture I gave though was
that if we follow that convention today
right we follow the French's convention
today then jungle boys and cookies would
be grand crew because their [ __ ] sells
for the most money in La alien too right
most money in Los Angeles most
well-known brands people lost their
minds and they were like Kev you've lost
your way you you're like a you're an
outdoor turn coat and I'm like I only
have an outdoor farm that I produce
product from I'm just telling you that
these beliefs that we're holding so
firmly today if we back they said but if
we went back I said if we went back
they'd have electricity too so they
didn't have the ability to light
anything up in 1850 or you wouldn't
call operating in a greenhouse gas lamp
technology right so like using lighting
to change the photo period which is all
based off the scoto biology which is
chicken production so chicken production
educates people on agricultural
production what did they use to change
the lighting black out cloths and what
[ __ ] gas lamp not electricity well if
they didn't have a gas lamp you wouldn't
have gas lamp technology right you still
wouldn't be doing any kind of flower
forcing so they obviously used the
technology they had which was a goddamn
candle can can you explain this a little
bit better to me as far as how cuz I
don't know anything about chicken
breeding or oh
totally what what Farmers noticed was
that hens laid better under certain
light conditions
durational Light breaking up light
patterns and so they call that scoto
biology and it's it's almost it's it's a
very similar parallel to me as the
parallel to Bricks so BRX right so so
the idea of measuring sugar as a means
of determining when a crop should be
harvested was developed for grape so
this individual develops the science to
determine when is a grape
when do we Harvest we because remember
we're just we Harvest off all this [ __ ]
there's no science it just has to be
empirical it has to be through our eyes
only so they said there must be a way to
do this and so they come up with an idea
hey we can measure
sugars they they they they run a strip
through a refractometer you see the
level and they say okay this sugar level
is higher than it was a week ago we have
a greater sugar in the product this
sugar should give us a better end
product because that sugar is going to
convert into
MH once you apply the fermentation
process well the next question was can
we apply it to all foods and all of a
sudden bricks based agriculture is born
but it's based off of first when do you
pick a grape and then it became how do
we drive nutrient density into all these
crops so scoto biology is the first step
in light manipulation with plants
because it's it's Farmers being a W that
if we manipulate lighting we can impact
chicken production well someone said
what else does it do and do I know who's
who did that no I don't need to I just
need to know where it came from where
the idea was it B was it born and then
how did it evolve and so then they it
evolves into glass house and they used
to call them green houses were called
glad glass hous they also called
conservatories and that's all 18 that's
all you know London east Europe people
withone had conservatories which let
them grow tropical plants and cold
environments because it was a
flex the whole the the the wealthy
always flex and the flex at that time
was these was these beautiful mazike
gardens and
conservatories and it it even continued
in the US all the way up into the 70s
with like when Silicone Valley wealth
started to explode in the 70s early 80s
all the wealthy went big on landscaping
and then real realized that the next
step was Winer reacquisition and so
that's when you started to see
California wine being touched by all the
mega wealthy as wine owners wine
investors because it it allowed them to
flex on something that allowed them to
lose money on the investment but reduce
capital gains on their income so like
all these things that we see have all
these impacts that shape and change so
Glass House technology they they weren't
growing that [ __ ] till they figured out
how to [ __ ] trap you you know um heat
and UV inside a structure you weren't
getting flowering to occur or not
getting it to occur without that gas
lamp technology so if we call you know
the original Green Houses glass houses
and we call it gas lamp that means they
were using technology they were using
science so what we do is we we we hold
these things in our mind mind is the
purity of what they did but when the
French created the system this was the
foundation and so me and a bunch of
these cats from that that that are wine
based got into this argument and then a
bunch of people that know me from
cultivation got into it saying oh my God
you're destroying the world of organic
outdoor and I'm like I'm not I'm simply
stating that when they created these
systems it was using the information
they had at that time and so we have to
look at it that same situation
today wherein Kevin have you ever heard
about Rudolf Steiner he was an yeah
Austrian architect and also very
esoteric at that time he he was born in
1861 and died in 1922 25 but he actually
is a marker in European times he lived
in Switzerland uh most of his time I
think uh and he has a center of esoteric
you know he's a and he's like somebody
that uh this hippie generation that was
then you know like in the 60s or 70s
here in in Europe in Eastern Europe also
was looking up to like building your own
your own house you look for
architectural like Rudolf Steiner or
Fred hund vaser you know the the other
Austrian they have no uh sharp edges you
know they all all everything is from
nature everything is like with waves and
uh it's like everything like even in USA
I think guys did few years ago this
Earth ships in New Mexico the desert
yeah that kind of philosophy to to
involve to go into the nature to to you
know that that is us actually that kind
of people we are always interested uh we
will be working until we die you know oh
yeah there's no there's no end of it
there's no no there is no pension you
know it's like there is no I mean
pension in the sense that you would stop
working on something you know cuz you
you you you seem to me like a guy that
will be like written in history books
you know like uh something you do know
yeah yeah man you're infected you are
infected with the virus you know of uh
researching Canabis until you until you
die you know yeah there's no there's no
way it's it's really it's funny but like
when I started growing in the 70s it was
outdoor in my grand mother's Garden yeah
and then I you know in the in the in the
80s I get into doing indoor and then in
the the mid 2000s when we're allowed to
really go back outside because there was
some loopholes in the
law you know you returned to your
outdoor cultivation and as I started to
get older I started to realize that with
legalization if I had the ability to
spend the rest of my life legally
cultivating I wanted to do it outside in
a biological system and it was just
purely
because there was so much mystery that
remained that it let me be in wonder
where when I'm in technological systems
I'm amazed at the complexity of the
technology but there's a disconnect
that's different and I'd spent so many
years [ __ ] decades you know grinding out
indoor
operations that I wanted to finish my
career Under the Sun and it's almost
like a complete reversal of no Tech and
I call it like you know natural Tech
where you're you're using natural
systems and you're forced to bend to
that
constraint and you may only get you know
a a a a true vintage year you know every
just like wine 20 20 you know two out of
10 four out of 10 tops so out of 10 year
period only two to four of those are
going to be what we consider a vintage
year where phenomenal conditions but at
that moment in time the product's
unbelievable and like coincidentally
this was one of those years this was one
of those vintage years where this is
probably one of the best years of
cultivation we had in in the Triangle
probably the last decade minimum and to
be able to be part of it was incredible
to be able to watch this this climate
just bring out these
qualities I dig and but does that mean
that I think it's the only way no and
just because I like it and I think that
it has a a low impact on the environment
does that mean that everyone has to
follow what I do know I'm I'm that's the
whole point of me being Buck Wild my
whole life and and and running around
was I don't want to get told what the
[ __ ] to do I'm not I don't want to get
told the [ __ ] what to do kind of guy so
I don't usually try to tell other people
what to do it's just what we try to do
is put information on the table so
people can take from it from the open
and plate as they choose and if they
want to refute it they refute it if they
want to use it they can use it but it
allows us to be able to work I think
more
cohesively and I think that that's what
I really wanted out of the experience of
like public cannabis was being able to
look at a thousand different things and
get a thousand different viewpoints and
we're all able to kind of come together
on some generalizations we all agree on
and then there's some [ __ ] that nobody
agrees on and that's what lets us stay
hungry until we find out I think I said
this before but we don't want to be
influencers we want to be people that
Inspire yeah totally right you know like
I'll tell you how I do it and if you're
inspired by it then that's awesome um
one thing I wanted to ask you is do you
know a guy he's a uh teacher here in
Soma County Bob Canard I don't know Bob
I'll I'll send you an uh a video to
watch from him but I I like to talk
about him because he was my organic
gardening teacher at the Sona County uh
at the Canta Rosa JC and it was so
inspiring um what he told us was that we
had to grow two plants for the Earth for
every plant that we gr for ourself so
that we're never depleting it and holy
no no that I love it when you went to
his
farm at First Sight all you saw was
Weeds
right it's just like weeds everywhere
and then as you walk through the field
of weeds you see the plants that are
growing you know basically almost
covered in Weeds um and the food that we
ate there was it was like from the
Garden of Eden it was it was incredible
and while I loved growing organic he was
the one that made me
realize can't really do this in a short
period of time in a pot no it's it's you
know it's like it's the
IND yeah yeah and and so you know people
think when I talk about how I don't
think you can grow organic in a pot in a
couple of months they think that I'm a
hater of Organics but no I I just feel
like it's a longterm thing like he
bought a piece of land that was in
really bad shape and he didn't go and
dump truckloads of compost to grow in
there you know because that's right he
built it you know using the biology and
by using plants to feed the
soil and uh like I said I just wanted to
ask you if you knew about him because
he's really inspiring and I'm going to
just send you a link um on some YouTube
videos from him because I think you'd
enjoy them I would I would cuz that's
what what got me really fascinated with
Simplicity was the one straw
Revolution and the idea that this this
Japanese gentleman Chang the entire
country's approach to
agriculture through the the simple fact
of putting straw on the ground and then
having chickens [ __ ] on it or ducks and
so you only you and he he knew you only
need to have you know like 10 ducks for
every quarter
acre and so over the course of you know
20 30
years he ends up adding you know two
inches of top soil and he's just like
that and it it was
this forever View and it helped and when
I got lucky that I got to do a I spent a
lot of time with the regenerative
groups and it was this same thing it was
that it's a forever process it's not a
race it isn't like you build this thing
and it's done and it just works it's
it's forever and it allows you to
understand that it if you just work
towards your goal you'll get to it at
some point and it's the process of
working towards the goal like everything
it's like whatever we do the work is
what really defines the outcome I mean
you you win a lotto ticket it's easy you
scratch a ticket but the odds of that
are like you know one in 400
million so very limited chance of
success but if we work towards a goal
and you chip away you'll get closer to
it and even if you don't get the exact
goal the process alerted you to many
Pathways to where you want to go and end
up having alternative routes that
work and I just think that we as a
culture have become so instantaneous in
what we
demand we don't ever want to put the
time in and we don't understand that
it's the actual time that's the gift
it's not the end product as much as you
think it's the work
the the process changes you it it Sands
off your rough edges it's kind of like
being out in the desert the the wind and
the sand just slowly start to round off
all the
lines and that that worn smooth look is
is comfortable to the
eye there's a there's a a feel and I
just think that we've we've become so
instantaneous that we don't really
understand that you know you're you like
to me you never get to the end
because then when you get to where your
goal
was it allows you to be able to see
other goals from that vantage point that
you couldn't see prior because you
didn't have the skills or the experience
or the wisdom to understand but once you
spend five years trying to figure
something out and you get to a point
you're like okay this is how much I know
this is how much I don't know and you're
able to kind of figure do you want to
continue down that road or you want to
start a new path and and to me that is
the the world of Agriculture and pl and
there's just Mysteries we don't
understand because maybe we're not meant
to you know I don't I don't think I want
to know every detail I don't I don't the
idea of engineering humans sounds great
because you'll you'll get rid of all
these diseases and you'll get rid of all
these
issues and you also take away the very
thing that makes human life valuable is
that it's limited if you live forever
would you appreciate things the same
way you know I me you don't so what you
what you and as you grow older you
realize it because you know I got a lot
of friends of mine that are dead you
make sure that you you you are a little
bit more thoughtful in the in
interactions and you make sure that you
enjoy these little moments a little bit
more profound because they could end and
I I think that when you start to have
you know no
risk what's the reward
worth and that's an opinion so I mean
I'm not saying everybody's going to live
that life but you know the the the
strugg philosophy strugg a philosophy
it's it's not an opinion it's a
philosophy and uh it reminds me of uh
the conversation that we had before we
ever recorded together and I laugh about
this now and I I actually brag about it
is that we're talking about Master
Gardeners you said oh you said you're a
master gardener and so what I did was
now in my bio I write Gabby bronstein or
Gabby Staten Island open quotes Master
Garder close quotes by Kevin jrey
totally cuz Kevin JRE called me a Master
Gardener it was like one of the I
blushed but it's genuine what I wanted
to say is that what I say is I don't
want to master anything this is what I
said to you and I'd like you to repeat
what you know what your response was I
thought the Master Gardener term was
kind of like well this means I've got
nothing left to learn I know everything
and I'm not going to learn from you
because I'm your master and and you gave
me a different um definition of it and
not only did it make me feel good that
you said I'm a master but it also made
made me think about things differently
just like you did when we had the
conversation about you know what is
craft cannabis because honestly after
talking to you I think I was wrong which
like I said I like being wrong but like
what I thought about craft cannabis
today is different than what I did
after our
conversation totally the what people do
is they they they they put titles on
themselves because it makes them feel
good and and and that's okay we all we
all need some
self-affirmation but when you're talking
about a
craft something done by hand then we can
say that there's Craftsman Crafts
People and almost all crafts have an
evolution of development we start out
out as as apprentice you're you're
unskilled and you need to be
supervised as you develop that ability
you become a journeyman you're somebody
that can work independently but you're
not qualified to run a project you don't
have big picture perspective when you
become a master at a craft you have an
ability to run a project and educate
Journeymen who then supervise
apprentices so my family was filled with
master welder Master Carpenters master
plumbers Master electricians when I was
in the military I worked for master
diver does that mean that that Master
diver and and and the first Master diver
I worked for was a guy named Payne Bosa
mate Master Chief Payne what a what an
appropriate name this guy was hard as
[ __ ] but brilliant but at no Moment In
Time the any of these people at the
Master Level ever think that there's not
more for them to learn
but what they know is that they're
probably the most qualified in the room
at that moment and that their job is to
run the
project and so when you're a master
cultivator you're able to do that I'm a
Master Gardener and I said that to
somebody and someone said and what makes
you think so I said University of
California Berkeley so it's really
simple that they I I [ __ ] took a
program and I passed the test and it
allows me now to do one very specific
thing it lets me communicate
agricultural principles based off of the
database of UC Berkeley so that way what
we have is we have consistent
information but do I think that that's
the end or be all of all things no it's
just that they know that we can say this
because there's
proof but that's why footnotes there are
there are footnotes you know when you
read literature there is footnotes and
footnotes means that you go and search
for or in because this information that
somebody writes down has to be valid you
know it has to come from
somewhere what your hypothesis you know
people today don't even know what
footnotes are and why they are standing
for you know if sometimes one book can
be I mean for example here is a a book
of bamboo it's called the big book the
book of bamboo by David F you know it's
American guy and it's a it's a
encyclopedia where you have uh after
each chapter you have uh footnote you
have like the secondary literature where
you can search for more books and this
book is actually the gateway to like 500
books oh totally yeah which is really
specific really really specific you know
and because they're taking they're
saying that this does this based off of
the work that this person did prior and
it it's a respect for others work and
you're not trying to say you invented it
you're just saying hey I I endorse it I
use it I'm letting you be aware of it
but this is the person who came up with
the
idea and
so otherwise it becomes this you know
everyone's like you know your master
it's just like people use the word
improperly but if you're in trades the
master plumber who's running the project
doesn't say I'm not a master Plummer I'm
I'm just a like it's a [ __ ] title
it's kind of like saying you know when
you're CEO of the company or you're the
COO or the CFO or the CTO or whatever
the [ __ ] SE Suite you are you just say
it it's your title it's just what it is
does that mean that you're the only one
on earth no does it mean you're the best
one on earth no it could be you know if
you're if you're talking about you know
somebody running one of these uh Venture
Capital firms and they're carrying a
trillion in value I would say that's
probably a pretty intelligent CEO but in
general it just
States a a fact and in cannabis to me if
you're a master at it you're you're so I
wouldn't consider myself a master indoor
grower because I no long like I I study
and I research and I work but that's not
where I put my time I shift it over to
how to plants work with operations how
to plants work with
people and it lets me lets me work on
what I like which is biologically driven
Sun grown that's where I want to spend
my time as a cultivator but I research
indoor and outdoor and mix light
operations continuously so I can
understand impact on cultivar selection
and on cultiv our performance so I kind
of figured out where I really enjoy what
I do so I have to understand how your
operation works but I know rippers of
people that are far smarter than I am
and in in all these different areas that
I'm involved in I just try to be in
intelligent in integrating all these
things
simultaneously that's kind of like my
skill set is that I can pull out of a
giant bag and put it together into a
ball
but the ability for me to say hey I know
someone better in every room is
critical because then what it does it
always makes sure that you're crystal
clear about your level and rank and and
that isn't something that most people
want to do because you you have to be
comfortable with yourself to do it and
what we have is I think a society of
people that unfortunately been beat down
because you're living in the media so if
you're not if you're not rocking really
nice [ __ ] you don't have all these
things all this stuff you're not
somebody and so you need you need
validation I think that's like with
cannabis that was like the big issue
where when the world of legality was
coming in everyone in cannabis said well
they don't have our skills well yeah
they [ __ ] do and well they don't have
our genes yeah they do they do so what
is it that you have what do you have if
everyone has all your secret [ __ ] you
don't have anything except pissed off in
anger and rage and what needs to happen
is you need to say I got you I need to
go and tighten up my [ __ ] and continue
my educational process but who wants to
do that when you're making lawyer money
out of your closet right so like it's
tough when you when you incentivize
things
financially it makes you think you're
smart because we measure everything in
money money is the only thing that can
be anything and everything is measured
against like I tried to figure this out
a long time ago but cash has a really
unique position in the world because
everything we do is measured by that
pretty much and it can become anything
so money is this is this flexible bill
of exchange that that doesn't rely on
coincidence a why
and so we use that as this thing so when
you're making a lot of money you don't
think you're making any mistakes you're
like look how much I'm making look how
well I'm doing you don't really
understand that it sometimes a lot of
times it's just straight luck so even
with
investment you get into something early
you blow up you're brilliant do that
[ __ ] again and you're going to find out
that you're not necessarily so good at
that is what you thought but you got
lucky and that's herb to me so many of
us got lucky and I got lucky in that I
realized in my late
30s that we were going to get the living
[ __ ] kicked out of us when this went
legal I had no question I had no
question because I was researching
commercial a I went to school for it and
then I go into uh you know like
floriculture you know development of
potted plants flowers and I start to
really look at those operations cuz I
got access to them and I'm like oh we're
going to get murdered they're going to
kick the [ __ ] out of us because their
level of efficiency is crazy and the
public in
America as much as people don't want to
admit it we're mids country we would
rather have schas board all you can eat
than 9.99 yeah yeah cheap that's that's
America man we rely on it right we've
been we've been taught to be bulk
consumers since birth for Generations
now we've been shaped to purchase
indiscriminately bye bye bye so I just
said oh we're going to get murdered and
so I'm like whoa and it it forced me to
start to really relook at what I did and
re look at my Approach and and try to
understand where is my pathway forward
when I know I'm not going to get to
compete with infrastructure you can't
compete with people that can raise $200
million and just because you raised 200
million doesn't mean you're going to
exist either but while that money is in
play everyone around you that's
competing against you is getting blood
because they're able to use the money as
the beating tool and then if if they
succeed they continue if they fail they
go away but if you're trying to if
you're trying to compete with somebody
that's operating at below margin and
they're dumping and you can't and the
market doesn't give a [ __ ] the Market's
like what $6 weed even better nobody
wants to you know like people talk about
I don't want the Primo [ __ ] and I'm like
no America's pretty much low-end [ __ ] or
we wouldn't have a proliferation of fast
food the way we we
do we we love we love bought cheap
[ __ ] do you think the the the what is
happening now in Europe in Germany for
example uh that it will change a little
bit the game also in USA because you
know like you're not federal yet right
you have certain states have legal
legalized but now for example Germany
started in Europe like a like a first
move you know in the direction of
legalization so many countries will
follow actually I
think I work in Germany like well I
worked I
worked I don't say I work in Germany but
I work in other countries that provide
to
Germany and
so we we we we still have our position
and at some point in time when the
United States when the United States
goes federally
legal when the US turns on its machine
it's hard to compete against I mean
we're not China
China can basically out compete anybody
but a lot of it is because and China the
you know the the Chinese are brilliant
historically for you know [ __ ] Millennia
but they also have very low restrictions
on on OSHA right know job safety and
environmental EPA and OSHA is a little
off so it it allows them to be able to
have you know competitive Advantage but
when you get into cannabis that's going
to be going through the level of
scrutiny that they're looking at and
right now they're talking like category
for you know more and more stringency on
the
stuff the United States has an ability
to absolutely turn on a factory but
we're we're so caught up in our own
[ __ ] and we made so much money for
the government off the drug war that
they don't ever want to get rid of it
like it we can't get rid of it we're
addicted to that drug war money or you
wouldn't see if you kind of look at it
like look at it historically in the US
right methamphetamines
in the the 70s legal you get them
prescribed to you when I was a kid right
when I was like 12 13 you go to a party
they would be all this methamphetamine
in pill form at the party so you'd have
a couple beers and and grab some of
these things you be wired out of your
mind right that [ __ ] was coming out of
your grandmother's medicine cabinet this
[ __ ] wasn't on the street well they they
get rid of the
prescriptions they do the analoges that
goes into like diet pills and then it
just Begins the whole meth Revolution
you go into opiates right we we schedule
all these uh synthetic opiates we
schedule as schedule three which means
they're easily accessed we saturate the
country to the Limit Beyond
Comprehension then we restrict same with
meth we saturate restrict create an
illegal industry now we have a drug wall
we can fcking wage since the 70s against
meth it it's been the last so many years
against an opiates but you take a look
in the fenel crisises across the country
because people can't access
pharmaceutical oxy like they once did so
the the drug war is we have drugs that
we create we saturate we remove we
penalize and it's this system if you
look at it you I mean I can point to a
whole variety of different products that
that's been done with that we're
addicted to that duality of money we
want to make the money on people using
the cash to influence the system to add
that money into into the world and then
we want to punish the [ __ ] out of him so
that we can keep the prison system
moving you know I mean like I don't
think people catch the American system
where I and I didn't catch it either but
I got a a dude I was in the military
with and he went on and got into uh
prison guard his family uh got him into
the into the prison guard world and it
was a good it was a good world for him
he did you know did well financially and
had a good life so he and I maintain our
relationship but he was saying you know
I I run a cabinet shop and I'm like what
for rehab he goes no we sell the
products and I said how much you make he
goes my division in this prison does 180
million a year and I said let me get
this straight out of the [ __ ] prison
in Pennsylvania One Division of of your
of this little prison is doing 180
million in [ __ ] woodwork sales I said
how the [ __ ] is that possible and he
goes we create the GSA products we
create the products for the federal
government he goes it's all contract Kev
he goes we make the metal desks or the
wood desk that they put in all the
offices he says so the desk is like 25
$30,000 desk he goes it's costing us
[ __ ] 200 bucks to make it and I said
where's all this money going he goes
into the investors that built the
privatized prison industry and I started
laughing because it made me realize just
how [ __ ] undereducated I am about
this reality that the American system of
of of drug enforcement is really eing
prison systems that create products that
get sold at the federal government and
the money chain is so thick and deep
they'll never get rid of this [ __ ] so
the us we just just like we just kicked
the farm bill down the road another year
right on the thca hemp issue and and I
don't I don't really care one way or
another how it goes
because it's it's above my
control but the idea of how they
manipulate and move this it depends on
how much money they're making and who
benefits and the ability to maintain
that Duality it's the same with
California when I talked to the I had
the I had the governor of the [ __ ]
state in my office like so I don't
really I don't know any of the dope
Growers that had like every major
politician in their state come and have
lunch with them in their
office and I asked them I said why do we
have all these you know cannabis deserts
in California like why are there so many
places that we're not going to to be
able to have cannabis and he said it's a
capitulation of the law enforcement and
I said I don't understand and he said
law enforcement won't approve legality
of cannabis in California they won't
give us a go-ahead on it they'll fight
me
politically and that fight politically
will keep me from being reelected so he
goes so they use their Lobby to control
what takes place because the money that
you make from drug interdiction isn't
part of your like disc every budget so
they don't get to keep all the money
they have to cut up the pie but the fact
is they're able to have a budget that
they use and then they're able to go and
steal as much money as they can get
their hands on that they get to use to
do all their other [ __ ] and he said
they're fundamentally addicted to the
money and so if Cali which Governor said
this uh Gavin Nome H so if that's
something that I'd like to see printed
right there right I mean like it's it's
like he's admitting oh [ __ ] you can't
you can't say that [ __ ] out loud though
I mean I'm telling you because we had
the conversation in the office did he
said it out loud or it was privately to
you well he said he said it out of his
mouth to my ear but we were in my office
oh so he's not going to get on a stage
and say that [ __ ] because I asked him I
said why do you guys got to you know
what's the what's the power of law
enforcement in terms of political and he
goes they have the most powerful Lobby
there is he said the number of times an
election has been won by somebody who is
not in favor of the political of the of
the police group is almost negligible
there's almost none so it's this risk
where you have to support law
enforcement so heavily or what they do
is they give you a vote of no
confidence and it states to the public
hey we have no faith in this person
keeping you safe and they've done such
an effective job in creating that
illusion that it's effective and so
that's the problem with the US is that
we're making so much money off the drug
war [ __ ] that there's no need it it's
the same argument that I I got to meet
one of the lead scientists from senta we
met at an event and he actually had
followed me online right so he
approached me and said hey I follow your
[ __ ] and he said and I just wanted to
talk to you about weed so we're talking
about weed and I'm asking him I'm like
are you guys in weed and he goes no he
goes and I said how come he goes we're
Global Food he said we feed the Earth he
goes we don't give a [ __ ] about weed
money he goes when we get into weed you
will know it he goes cuz we have a
couple million dollars a day in
disposable money we can spend just on
R&amp;D he said so we when we enter weed
there is no question you will know sent
is in the room because you're not going
to [ __ ] with us and I was like whoa but
there was no need and I said so just not
the money and he goes no it's also the
risk he goes if we build infrastructure
in America in a country that's federally
illegal he goes we could have
nationalization occur and they could
take our product and and a good example
of that is years and years ago I had
remember Franco that used to work with
uh the greenhouse yeah yes Franco he was
a sweetheart of a guy St Hunter yeah he
was he was a lovely guy too he was a he
was a former military got into
Hospitality management and then he
becomes um uh aon's partner and they
they do all that work but
he comes into Humble County in like 207
maybe 208 to um see if we want to
contract to make seeds for the
greenhouse and it was hysterical because
he comes to me and he's like we want to
pay you
$100,000 to make seed and we're laughing
because at that time you know you're
making that [ __ ] a month and you're like
you he was going to make millions on it
give you don't understand I'm talking
100,000 and I said look you got to go to
some other country and go [ __ ] those
people over because that doesn't work
for us I said why didn't you go to
Africa and pull that [ __ ] there and he
said we did but they nationalized our
whole operation and took it from us so
it's this risk of working in countries
that they'll take your stuff and so me
and me and Franco become friends and we
maintained a good friendship cuz he was
a good guy but I'll never forget that
$100,000 cuz it was like [ __ ] Dr Evil
you know a million dollars and they
laugh a billion
dollars but it was the same deal in
that you don't really
understand what's at stake and how many
people are making money off of this and
so we see it as it would be good for us
well we're not really if if if any
American believes they have any value as
a citizen you're you're [ __ ] deluding
yourself you're you're just a cog and a
gear and a big
machine and so I think that at some
point when the US gets involved you'll
see some changes globally because that's
what we do AS Global [ __ ] business
and we'd be able to we'd be able to
utilize our tariffs we'd be able to
utilize blockages we will
manipulate but until that happens with
silo you know California Silo we can't
sell the Oregon Oregon can't sell to us
and the hemp is what got around it the
hemp's what's letting everything move
but if you were to build a business
today how much money would you risk if
you know that the farm bill is going to
be Revisited in a year and if the farm
bill is going to get Revisited in a year
does that mean that you have any
longevity after that so I just don't
worry about it as much what I what I
look at is I look at countries that can
produce product and sell so that would
be you know in my case Canada South
Africa those countries then I can work
with to get product moved into Israel
Australia
Germany and it's all legal it just lets
me come in and help them understand how
we would adjust the supply chain and how
do we find products that work in these
markets and how do we optimize a
production of those products and if we
can do all of that then then I'm doing
what I need to be doing so I can learn
how to function when I get to that point
where the US can because my whole game
with my farm was I figured at some point
we'd be able to sell our product in
other countries and if I wasn't trying
to produce 10 million pounds of flour
I'm only trying to produce you know a
th000 pounds half a ton I shouldn't have
such a brutal time getting rid of it
globally and it would allow the farm to
have a good resonance and let the farm
do what I wanted it to do which was
produce good herb because the Farm's
impact is
positive is this Farm still Port Royal
yeah yeah that's yeah because that's
that's the that's like your brand name
it it has another name in terms of how
the county you know the state sees it
but Port Royale Place yeah yeah it's
it's a stunning I'm on the the lip of a
Caldera of a dormant volcano so like the
whole [ __ ] Caldera falls off behind
me thousands of feet and I'm above the
fog and I get true South Exposure and I
have incredible water coming out of that
mountain so like I'm the Watershed for
bu Creek so I got some really
interesting [ __ ] going on and and I just
spent the last eight years brawling it
out with the
county over who owns the water so
California is obsessed with owning your
water so it took me eight years to win
this fight but then they said Hey in
2045 we're going to come back at you
again and see if you still own the water
because that's what they want is control
but that mountain just always produced
really good herb and I have an emotional
connection to it and that's kind of how
I wanted to finish my career was just
running that farm up on that edge of
that Hill you know and and don't give up
yet part oh I'm not I I don't end your
career yet we still we still need your
contribution no no I'm done this is this
is I want to spend my life doing what I
do beautiful I'm not because someone
said you know when do you retire and I
said what do you do when you retired die
yeah you get old and die and I'm like no
I want to continue with my life so it
just comes down to the what your desires
are and also to understand your
reality what is the reality of your
existence and you kind of got to be
comfortable with it and so the US the US
is the us but if you're able to you know
work in any other country then you can
start to practice you can start to get
the experience you need to be able to
understand what's needed what is these
more highly regulated production
methodologies and distribution
methodologies that are
required and what works in these markets
and what doesn't and how do you optimize
supply chain and so I mean I'm having a
great time learning and it's been really
effective like it's it's worked for
every company the companies that I did
the work for in Canada succeeded the
companies I did the work for in South
Africa succeeded
so it it just lets you practice and Play
and Learn and that way I I don't sit
here wondering like what's going on in
in California because I mean our whole
our whole cannabis system basically
collapsed which is mindbending that
Michigan is making more tax revenue than
California right like that's it's almost
it's people like I'm talking no no I
don't think you understand nothing
against Michigan Michigan's a beautiful
place and they grow some really good
weed but when we're talking about
economy you're talking about California
the fifth largest economy on Earth LA
County by itself that six million people
cluster is like top seven top eight in
the world where if you just broke La
free from the rest of the United States
it would be in the top 10 in terms of
global performance
financially that shit's California and
we're we're over here down in like 187
200 million tax Zone when it should be
in the billions and and it's just a
total mismanagement of a system and it's
it's just the nature of what we're where
we're at today and I just think that I
just quit complaining about the the lack
of fairness and I just said [ __ ] it man
it's I love growing I love what I do I'm
just going to work with it and that way
I can at least enjoy what we have which
is the ability to do what we're doing
right now we're on [ __ ] live we're
talking about dope gr like that's just
it blows my mind because you remember
when you we first started out like I
never wore a weed shirt I had no weed
[ __ ] like I I changed clothes and cars
and spots all the time so I never looked
like anybody that would you know arouse
suspicion you were living undercover so
much you didn't have a normal life
you're it's so funny you're only your
only friends you hung out because if you
hung out with regular people and they
found out what you did a lot of them
would get so [ __ ] mad and I realized
it wasn't cuz they were anti-drugs it
was
because you exemplified freedom and the
idea that me regular person could have a
life better than you where like I don't
have to go put up with I call it patty
cake I I don't got to go play patty cake
at work every day I just got to do it
myself that's not bad and for most
people they didn't really get that they
got to play
the go to work put up in the boss's [ __ ]
work with crazy ass co-workers get paid
minimal suck up 40 50 hours minimum of
your life a week you only have a weekend
off you can't afford to go anywhere
you're not going on vacation and and I'm
over there flying to Hawaii during the
middle of the week just so I can get out
of the area and you're like we had a
pretty good life and it made people
upset that and to me it was they were
upset because I was just a regular guy
so like you [ __ ] it was like they were
mad you know and and it's a between envy
and jealousy you know what I'm saying
jealousy is boy that's a beautiful
jacket I wish I had one and envy is like
how come that prick has that
jacket one is you you want the thing and
the other is you're mad at the person
who has the
thing and what we had was really Envy
over our lifestyle because we didn't
have to do that we had the ability to
take a Tuesday off and go to the park
with your kid when I when I wanted to go
to Europe and travel around on Europe
and do stuff I took my kid with me when
when my son got the opportunity to go
and get invited to Russia to train the
national team I could afford to [ __ ]
fly him when my brother got
opportunities to compete globally I
could afford to fly him and I like we
had privileges that regular people
didn't and they were angry because they
did everything they were told and they
followed the rules they did all the
right [ __ ] and it wasn't real it's the
same with medical cannabis people that
are dying to this day still won't use
cannabis to help with the issue because
of the stigma that's been put on
it so it's just what it is but I you
know I just I can't I can't change the
world but I can I can try to be decent
to people in
person again you want to be an inspirer
yeah no I'm not an influencer the [ __ ]
is that it if if I could influence
anybody it hopefully be influence your
children to be nice to other people like
if if when I see my kids being kind to
other people and when I get the report
card and I see the good grade of nice to
other children polite and respectful to
other people I know I did well but all
the other [ __ ] really
is just you if you're if you're bright
you're [ __ ] bright right
nobody I'm somebody that did well
academically or I do well in those
situations because my [ __ ] brain
works well that way so that's a gift
right for me I got to struggle with
other things those are the things that
I'm really proud of is the [ __ ] that I
don't do that well but I had to work so
goddamn hard to get good at like that's
and you're laughing because you're like
to no one else is at anything high level
but to you you basically started out on
your hands and knees and now you can run
and know you're not the fastest runner
in the world and you're not trying to
say you are but to you you know damn
well it used to crawl on your hands and
knees and I think that it's those type
of uh internal victories that give us
satisfaction and when you're fighting
this struggle on your own and you're
doing things you're very different to
other people you don't attack them so
like for me when I look at like online
trolls and [ __ ] I laugh because if
you're spending your time trolling I'm
like oh you're a miserable [ __ ]
in real life and and if I can see
thousands of your prolific I'm just like
you spend in your whole life online
talking [ __ ] which means you're not
doing anything in your life and so it's
a really good indicator of of the
quality of your life and I I just think
that unfortunately many don't
have they haven't found yet a place
where they're happy because once you're
happy you really don't give a [ __ ] about
other people's
lives you don't need to get in there
[ __ ] and [ __ ]
ah yeah for sure I love trolls some of
the fun and I and I like it when they
troll me sometimes I even help them
because I'm like you're not trolling
hard enough let me give you some more
info yeah for real you got to let me
laugh because I'm just like I ain't
woring about you um and this [ __ ]
doesn't matter to me if the internet
[ __ ] blew apart today I'd still be me
I'd still be here you still have your
plants I yeah I'm still doing what I'm
doing I'm I'm I'm I'm working and if the
electricity went out then I'm cracking
seed and I'm doing it only in the summer
it'll work it it's no matter what it'll
work and it's just really bending to
that
reality it's such a beautiful attitude
you have man you know I like
that power out we'd still be cracking
seeds in the summer period no matter
what I'm doing what I'm doing I don't
give a [ __ ] it's G to happen but I don't
I don't get so caught up in it and I I
just know that if I spend my time in
Rage I can't turn that off and be with
my kids and my gal and my animals and my
friends and be positive right and and
positive just means you're just not
bringing negative [ __ ] with you I don't
have to do a thing say a thing be a
thing I just be that you enjoy the small
small things the small moments the the
the real moments the that's the what's
life is all about actually 100% it's
it's the Nuance that's what we talked
earlier about you know this forever life
where the thing was forever it just even
with cannabis it made me realize just be
grateful you experienced it when it was
at its Peak and be aware that the things
you see today are gorgeous also and that
you're seeing them at their Peak and
that when they change over time it's not
that our memory is faulty it's just that
there's change it's like going back to
your neighborhood where you know you
lived in a place that was it was bad you
come back and now it's good it's been
clean it's been gentrified you go to
places that were were good and then
they've become bad in the way where the
they've been gentrified right so like
the cleansing of gentrification helps
bad areas but it also removes all the
[ __ ] flavor
so it's just enjoy it while you're in
the room there is one thing I wanted to
to to say is like you know Rashon you
know the the perspective you know we see
every everybody sees the same thing but
Rashon you have your own for example I
live in Europe right we have these
grapes here because I live in a Vine
Vine producing area I told about it in
the last podcast a few podcast ago where
it is called the Isabella the grape and
it's called it's very it's very sweet
you know it's big big blue grapes or big
white grapes and they have a really
certain certain Aroma and we have a cut
which is like the vapa cut
from from Paradise seats and it has this
this Aroma you know like the grape the
Isabella grape and last time I listened
to the podcast with Noto do and crybaby
and crybaby told like in one moment you
know the European they don't know how
skon smells because they don't have you
know we have skunks here but we don't
have your skunks M you know what I mean
in USA you have those skunks that you
you call skunk and we don't have them so
I actually realized that I never smelled
skunk like you would say it's skunk you
know but I I I don't know that what this
smell is skunk for you something else is
skunk for me you know like it's it's a
different
you know it's uh because for example in
my area everybody that smelled in the
'90s that's that started uh the wheat
indor wheat started to to be present in
the market everybody that smelled indor
wheat said it's conk it doesn't matter
if it's Haze or if it's uh it's if not
Haze or it does not matter with the type
of uh genetic but everybody says indoor
wheed is skunk you know that is still
today the the slang word punk you know
or like the the word amnesia for the
haze in Amsterdam where everybody forget
the wallets and they don't know where
the hotel is and you know that's why
it's Amnesia actually it's Haze it's
super silver haze interesting that's how
that's where that word came from it's
kind of like right now gas gas to us
implies petroleum right it it implies
this this petroleum like Aroma but to
kids today gas just means heat SO gas
could be anything where we say gas
someone goes yeah this is gas and you're
like that's not gas and they're like
yeah no it's gas because they're using
it it's connotation
denotation it's what the word means and
what we believe it means and a lot of
these arguments are that because at the
end of the day everybody gets triggered
and the internet it it's funny but the
internet creates a situation where
people can get triggered quick and then
instantly call you a name they call your
name right away you're a [ __ ] idiot
and I was laughing I'm like this is so
interesting I said I wonder what you're
like in real life you know what I mean
because like oh
damn I think we can guess what he's like
in real life it's it's interesting but
it it doesn't allow there to be real
conversation and for me the the problem
with that is that there's so many people
that lurk that they're online but they
lurk they never get involved in the
discussion because they don't want it's
not that they're they don't know what
they're doing either they're they're
probably the smartest people in the room
they just don't want to get caught up in
the dispute they don't want to get
engaged in more
drama and for
me I I do my best to not get engaged in
drama where I just don't like we can we
can go at me all day long but ignoring
yeah but when you Happ to attack me
personally on [ __ ] especially if you
don't know me right you don't know me
but you're attacking me I'm just like
you just looking
and the best thing that anybody can do
is basically ignore that person because
it destroys them because all they want's
attention because if they post on their
own platform nobody looks at them but if
they [ __ ] around on yours they get
engagement right it's be able to feel
good and and and and it's just it's all
good everybody needs to feel good in the
way they do and it's just the problem is
what we do is we dissuade people that
don't like
drama from entering our space and I
think that that's like the issue with
cannabis and you look at cannabis and
it's the same thing where you know
cannabis was this extremely diverse
industry incredible amount of diversity
in every aspect and now when you take a
look at it it's almost no diversity and
I mean there there's no I don't care
what Equity program they create it's
still run by basically a bunch of white
guys like me and and even though I fall
under the equity guideline meaning
multi-time [ __ ] fon
um it's just not fair and then you take
a look at the number of women that are
in the industry and it's minuscule and
so what you have is you have this filter
that basically filters out people who
want to get in who don't want to deal
with all your [ __ ] and they just
want to get into a new career they
thought that being in cannabis would be
something positive being around people
in can be positive but that's not the
Cannabis
industry that's that's cannabis
consumption and cultivation meaning that
you're your own cultivator so if you're
growing at your house and I'm growing at
my house and Slava is doing at his house
we can all have a conversation about
growing and and feel the goodness of it
because we're not trying to monetize
that situation but the minute you
monetize it all of a sudden it changes
it dramatically and the canvas industry
is a [ __ ] mess no diversity it's it's
and it's not healthy and you can see it
because it's so narrow band in its its
overall
wh we have a million different
categories but at the end of the day
that it's some very limited selection be
honest Kevin very simple question next
season what what you're going to grow
next season you know genetic wise you
know cuz you obvious obviously are high
profile guy for that I'm really
interested what you will say now like
what you are going to grow next season
let's see well um it it depends if I I
know what I'm do on my own meaning like
I have a a an Afghan cherry pie that I
did some work on and went through and
selected out a a stunner and I would
love to see that as a rosin product hit
the market because it just threw down
but it threw down a product that just
shakes you like almost almost unpleasant
level strength so I'd love to see that
get out into the public because the the
people I smoked it with just loved it
but Lucky in
that I can produce product without white
label so I can produce product that um I
don't have
to uh sell I can produce it for a
company but I get my name on the bag
right so I'm I'm I'm I work with cookies
on that and I produce varieties that
come out of the R&amp;D
facility and then the team tells me what
they would like to see produced and I
produce those products and we turn those
into fresh frozen and they they go into
the cookie world as a cart but it's a
great relationship because it's my label
on B so it's not it's not like I'm white
label and I'm actually getting the full
credit for the product and the ability
to do that is pretty good for sure I
think um only the most
respected breeders and cultivators will
will get that honor right like because
also putting your name on the bag is
bringing up the brand at this point it's
good for both parties I me at the end of
the day you know the farmers have a hard
time getting their product into the into
the store
and when I can produce a product and get
it into the store that's a success would
I like to be able to just do what I want
yeah but at the end of the day I'm a
grower so I grow what sells and then I
can work on some stuff that that doesn't
uh I I have one question I want to ask
you before we go and then we do a wrap
up okay um so one question I wanted to
ask you was your thoughts on breeding
and selection of males yeah because and
I'll just give you my quick feeling on
it I don't feel like I have the
experience to choose a male I think
that in many for many people I think
it's a bit of undo arrogance that they
have that saying that they can select
the male
because how do we really know when like
a female you can see it you can smoke it
in advance you know what you got a male
you you're making your best guess so for
me the best way to do
breeding and it's difficult is you know
if you have many males you cross your
females with them one at a time and then
you see what comes out from male one 2
three four as many as you can do and
then you know but you know people are
like well I did a stem rub or I reversed
this male and made it FL but it's like
how can that actually tell you what
you're going to get I I feel like
choosing one male is arrogance it it
well it it it is if you you're going to
select down to one though because
sometimes one male is the only male that
carries the traits that moves on in but
that's after testing all of them many of
them right so for me what I do is I I
look through the population of males and
if it's going to be open population
preservation I'm using every male I can
right but if it's trying to be selective
then I need to choose the males that
have the traits of interest that I'm
attracted to mostly and then see that
they pass that forward so sometimes you
know you go to do that's the problem is
that when you go to do breeding work
what we do is we Chase current money
where we're like oh it's hot right now
let's do this and the truth of it is is
that what we want is we want to be able
to say look the thing that I'm working
on has real value period because now it
takes away the time frame and it lets
you say okay it's going to take me a
year and a half to really figure out
what do I want to work with and and once
you start to work with a line you can
start to notice that certain traits come
along with it where the plants that have
these profiles seem to have this odd
Leaf anomaly the plants that have this
trait seem to also pass this trait on so
you'll start to see odds a propensity
for things to occur but the only way you
can determine anything at the end of the
day is is through testing the progeny
and that's where you know working on
marker assisted stuff is that they're
going to say look this plant we've
identified the trade of Interest this is
where it exists if we can find it on
this plant that means that plant has the
potential to pass it on but if that
trait doesn't exist in the plant there's
no to pass it
on and so most most breeding is kind of
that's why I say it's kind of half ass
because we don't we don't go at it from
this comprehensive view but it doesn't
mean that we haven't created some
beautiful stuff it's just we don't have
a line we have a cluster that we select
from and the goal is to be able to put
as much into this line as possible so
that when you [ __ ] with the line you get
a large portion of that pretty desirable
right well nice one I I appreciate that
response and uh with that I think we
will wrap it up and let Kevin get to his
family and and to his plants but um I
did want to I did want to say again I
don't feel like we've even scratched the
surface of your story so I got some guys
I want introduce to you too man I think
I think I love your work and I think
that there's uh two really quality
people that would love to go so get back
on it brother greaty I appreciate to
both of you
[Music]
okay this episode of gabbing with Gabby
is brought to you by the Breeders direct
Seed Company in my opinion the Breeders
direct seed company is your Premier
Source for clones and seeds and they are
the only place that you can get the
Gabby Staten Island collection so visit
breeders direct for all your seed and
clone needs