[Music]
what's up everybody and welcome to the
your weed stories on the craft Growers
Network and today we have a very special
guest Jorge
Cervantes and Jorge Cervantes
he has inspired more people to grow than
anyone that I know through his books the
indor marijuana growers Bible as well as
um he had a more straight book for the
straight audience called growing
indoors and these books are in so many
languages Jorge how many languages are
your books in now 11 11 languages 11
languages yeah yeah and so like I said
he's inspired more people around the
world to grow cannabis than anyone that
I know was so happy to have him on the
show
Welcome oh gee gee Gabby thank you thank
you so much you know I mean we've known
each other for a heck of a long time
yeah it's been 20 years yeah I know I
know we used I I I used to have a house
in California in somoma which is pretty
close to Willets it's is not that far
away yeah and it's and I was just
watching the um the interview with Kevin
jodrey and he told me to say hello yeah
yeah yeah yeah I love Kevin he's great
he's done so much good stuff man I mean
when he started that Wonderland Nursery
dang that I mean that was that was great
but see he's one of the guys and one of
the things he said in his interview was
was his timing was good because he got
into it publicly at the perfect time you
know and for me my timing was horrible I
mean I got into it when when it was like
about as illegal as you could get you
know I figured it was going to be legal
but yeah I mean I I would I I wrote the
first book there in uh
1983 and you know there's a full-blown
drug war going on or War on Drugs going
on but that might have added to the
popularity of the book uh no [ __ ] I was
I see uh the problem is you couldn't get
into the the big Distributors didn't
want to hit didn't want to carry it and
then within no time I got on the theft
list because what theft theft steal as
in take away something that's not yours
MH and the reason PE because then they'd
have to lock the books up they'd have to
lock them up and so people were
intimidated they were afraid to go buy
books so they stole them yeah so they'd
steal them it was it was faster easier
and you know they risk getting caught
there yeah but I was on the St the the
theft list for for Barnes and Noble and
and borders and God all of the big
stores yeah and um yeah so that was
pretty tough and then you know I I mean
I had a lot of trouble people didn't
want to um well printers just didn't
want to print it I I I had a heck of a
hard time finding a printer and um the
first book actually I printed it myself
I printed with these hands I didn't have
any money either you know nobody want
take any chances and I remember uh what
was it Andor press that was one of the
one of the the uh companies I sended uh
submitted a manuscript to he they said
over there that everything that
is everything that needs to be written
about cannabis has already been written
and that was yeah yeah yeah yeah that
was pretty funny that's still not true
no not even close I mean we're we're
just scratching the surface
now um yeah so anyway I I mean the book
was rejected reject Ed nobody wanted it
they said it was a dumb idea and all of
that and uh so I printed it myself and
self-published it in that way I was I
was good for timing because that's when
self-publishing started I bought a kpro
computer a k a kpro computer and was
able to do typ setting and everything
and it was it was tons of work tons of
work yeah that was pre- internet I'm I'm
looking you can go to my
website
uhon Das ces.com
jes.com and you can see you can see my
history it's uh pretty pretty complete
actually um I don't have the last few
books on there I've that I've written
but yeah I published more than 50 books
50 books I can't believe it I I I I
didn't realize I'd publish that
many um yeah oh I love this photo over
here with the fake
dreadlocks yeah yeah
yeah that's pretty pretty
funny yeah hey so um what I wanted to do
if you willing to um humor Us is I
wanted to start off as early as we can
so for instance like your first
experiences with
cannabis okay yeah yeah I and
you you may have to ask you know
qualifying questions and stuff because
well so when when was the first time you
saw cannabis when was the first time you
smoked cannabis and you know eventually
we'll get to the first time you grew it
well I
saw I saw the leaf and stuff cuz see I
grew up in a small town uh small
agricultural Town Ontario Oregon and
it's right on the border with Idaho
and everybody lives out there I mean
they're they're all Farmers everybody's
a farmer you know uh that's the main
main occupation and or having to do with
farming and um so it's very very
conservative and uh you know there was
all of those gosh I graduated high
school in
1972 And I think the first the first
time I smoked it cannabis was 71 when I
was a junior in high school cuz it
number one it was hard to get uh it
wasn't real common to to see yeah
1971 and
um uh we you know I'd heard all kinds of
Horrid things about it everybody was uh
there there was a big anti-cannabis
program anti- anti-pot program anti-
marijuana program
uh going on and it and it was in the
schools and everywhere so I mean I
couldn't I couldn't wait to try it and
um so what happened one of my friends
scored a a a three finger Mexican lid
that Mexican dirt weed I mean you guys
from Europe don't know about that stuff
but it's it's like the paraguayo or
something it's it's like really bad um
uh actually we know about it because uh
we have yeah we have a similar thing in
Europe which was the
Albanian kab you know yeah you know
there was certain places you know this
was the same thing like you had with the
Mexican I think you know oh yeah yeah ve
very very much so it's the Albanian is
actually yeah it's um you know because
of Transport the same the transport was
so bad you know it was all seed it was
bricks inside from from roofs uh you to
make it heavier like it smelled like
fuel gas I mean real because they
transported it in the trucks you know in
fuel we didn't have so much fuel smell
but we had uh uh but we we put rocks in
the kilos you put rocks in there and
also uh rocks and I remember I found all
kinds of my favorite was uh lizards
lizards there was always lizards you'd
always find lizards oh my gosh yeah they
be always be running uh
sh and um yeah yeah yeah uh but we
bought uh an ounce of that it was like
$10 us you know cheap and uh half of it
was stems and
seeds and so we all went out in my car
there was four of us we taken a a pipe
from my a tobacco pipe from my father
and because there's no head shops
nothing you know and so we we all get in
the car and start smoking cannabis you
know start passing this around and
finally toward the end of the end of the
uh the ounce I Got High I mean seriously
high and it was great it was nothing
like anybody had ever explained to me or
anything I mean it was it was [ __ ]
wonderful I couldn't get enough I was
and I was driving the car and it was
like I was in the movie I was in a movie
watching myself drive a car it was the
first major hallucination I had and it
was I I loved it I loved it and uh yeah
that was well that that's what hooked me
right there um and then there was there
was a lot of things that happened then
too because for example people adults
that I
respected they would just buy into the
drug war or War on Drugs
and and they wouldn't ask any questions
they just believe everything they just
swallow everything and so what happens
was I thought now look if you guys are
dumb enough to just believe something
that somebody tells you well I I can't
really uh go along with that and I like
to do my own homework and so I do my
homework and I find out that all the
information comes from you know like the
anti-drug agencies so I think huh okay
so what's the truth what's what's going
on and so I figured the people that were
that were um saying the same things as
as everybody else you know the um what
do you call them the anti-drug guys
um those guys were just sheep and
they'll follow anybody so heck with them
uh I can't really trust them and then
the people that don't that uh do their
homework
um they're only reading one thing you
got to read everybody you got to look at
everything and so I've just figured I
was getting bad news bad bad bad
information straight away and so I never
bought into that drug war and I never
believed any of it I just I mean cuz it
was pretty straightforward is a a way to
control people and that's it it um yeah
so I um yeah and then after that that
was in high school and then for
University I went um I well I I spent a
year here in Spain and and uh a couple
other places but it but the SEC but I
spent another year in Mexico I went to
Mexico and that's when we got really I
really do
it because the first thing happens was
uh oh the
theor the the director of the University
gives us a big speech and everything
about cannabis and how bad it is and
stuff and then this guy says I'm gonna
go smoke a joint uh and he walks right
through like right in front of everybody
I thought well that sounds like a good
idea I'm going to go go with him and the
next I mean I I I've been in I've been
in Mexico like 48 Hours you
know and then the next day uh that's
when I got my bought my first kilo uh
kilo there yeah I thought you were going
to say the next day I got thrown out of
school no no they wouldn't throw you out
of school you had to get uh uh you had
to get you had to be really bad to get
thrown out of school um yeah yeah I mean
maybe uh no I don't know anybody that
was thrown out nobody's thrown out they
just look at things differently there
yeah and so I got really into it there
and uh stayed with it and then when I
got I graduated
University and I I mean I'll be darn I
didn't know what the hell else to do
except to start growing so that's what I
did I just that's what I did for living
I well actually I had a garden business
I moved to Santa Barbara
California and had a garden
business and then I grew part-time up in
the hills and stuff and then did really
well I was uh first year that was
the uh let's
see still in the 70s mid 7s yeah mid 70s
but I grew for a couple years made a
made quite a bit of money and um then I
got in the bought a Volkswagen van and
uh moved and then took a road trip went
to uh South America in the in the
Volkswagen and that was um well that was
it was okay until you got to Central
America
because oh [ __ ] that's that's when the
Lo Sistas the Sistas from uh El Salvador
was it Sistas or Sistas sanist Sistas
sista as sista aswi yeah sista one uh
but when they uh they were around and I
met these guys that
said um they were driving through
driving through their Central America
and the Sanita stop them and they
requisitioned their
vehicle uh they just took it off of them
basically and they gave him a receipt
they a receipt
you can have it back after the war
yes pretty yeah exactly that's what
happened so I thought that was kind of a
bad idea to continue there and um so I I
I sold the car in America and then went
to uh got on the airplane and went to
Chile because my partner my business
partner had already already gone down
there but my goal was to um
well to do a lot of traveling but um to
learn more about cannabis in South
America and I was just I I don't know I
was gone about six months and we just
just there's so much other stuff to do
that's all I mean just kind of goofed
off for for the better part of six
months no I guess no actually I think I
made it more close closer to a year
that's right yeah cuz I wound up in the
Amazon that's right yeah but um anyway
when
I when I got back um back to the United
States before you talk about the United
States did you make it to
Argentina no that Argentina Argentina I
didn't go and I didn't I I went I I go
to uh Chile and Bolivia Peru um I didn't
go to
Ecuador um and then Columbia I didn't go
to until later till I I spent quite a
bit of time in Colombia here the last
few well not not the last couple years
but about 5 years ago I spent spent
quite quite some time there yeah okay
nice so you came back to the
US yeah yeah back to the US and
man I'll tell you um it everything
changed it was it was rough that I mean
that's what you remember camp
campaign against marijuana planting in
Northern California mhm where see the
big problem was with this it was
freaking drug war or when camp
start oh I don't remember the year I'm
bad with all CU because I thought Camp
was a little bit later than like some of
your story oh yeah yeah definitely later
it was quite a bit later yeah was like
late 80s think because that that's uh
Tom Alex Ander used to I I didn't want
to skip over the Tom Alexander part so
that's
why but anyway go ahead talk about
Camp yeah um no anyway I moved
uh no I started I started growing there
and then let's see but yeah basically
and then um gosh I moved to
um yeah moved to Portland Oregon and
that's where I wrote the first
uh marijuana horiculture book so so was
this was this before or after you were
involved in sensia
tips um no that that was uh before what
I did is I I uh I wrote the marijuana
hor or the indoor marijuana horiculture
I called it then because the only thing
you could get a hold of was Steve
Murphy's or Murphy Stevens's book um
yeah and there was a couple of yeah a
couple others but they were pretty
lightweight and because there wasn't
much information so um yeah this one
this one that's and and then the Halli
lights were all new and they' gone from
ver Mercury lamps to highight lights and
that was in the early 70s and that's
when all of this started and there was
just tons of really bad
information people just they didn't they
didn't have a [ __ ] clue of what was
going on uh most the time something
never change right well yeah you know I
mean there's so many there's so much
information
now and that well there's just not that
much or there wasn't that much at all um
so that's when I decided to to do the um
do the research and see i' I've been
gardening my whole life and I had the
Garden business for a couple of years
and even though I don't have a degree in
in horiculture or or a hard science even
soil
biology
uh I know a lot about gardening I mean
I'm just you know handson so uh what I
did is I I went to all of the the
lighting companies uh let's see there
was uh Sylvania and Phillips were the
two big
ones and got all of their literature and
found out everything I could and then I
put the two things together information
about lights and then information about
uh uh gardening and then you know I'd
been grow I i' grown for by that time
about about five years and so I put all
of that information together and then
for me I'll tell you the smartest thing
I did back then was this was
to put a survey in there a 10-word
survey or I mean a 10 question survey
and ask ask people what they wanted to
know you know I mean it and and then so
I was able to tailor the book for the
for the
Growers um yeah but where that survey
where was that survey published how did
people see the survey right in the book
I it it was right in the book your first
book yeah I'm still looking over here
may maybe I put it in an envelope or
something I don't know it's okay I'll
take a photo off of your uh off your
website I'm going to I'm going to take a
few photos off your website including
you with dreadlocks
sure sure no
worries hey I want to quickly introduce
you to Wolf he's also a co-host he has
his own show on our Network as well and
um okay he he's really busy today so he
couldn't join us on time but like okay
like I said everybody wanted to have an
opportunity to be in involved and and
like I said to say thank you oh thank
you so much for joining us nice yeah no
worries no anyway you asked in your book
you put a survey in yeah um to ask
people what they wanted yeah and I
remember uh let's see well to the the
survey served a couple of purposes one
is to find out what the audience wanted
and uh two to find out how what their
knowledge level is
and they're you know I
mean like when you give a lecture when
you uh talk to talk to people you just
generally ask them what they know so you
know how to speak to them so you can
speak at this level proper level and um
yeah I remember the last question on the
survey was did you uh a thief or a
policeman Harvest your crop
and you know there's quite a bit about
security and stuff uh there but yeah
yeah that was all old old times tough
times uh my family thought I was crazy
uh I had to have two sets of friends
people that knew people that
didn't um I I
felt yeah I mean it it was pretty hard
on the Hedge you know uh going against
the entire world like that
um I kept people on my side or you know
found people were on my side you know
the to legalize cannabis but man yeah it
it it was just hard times a lot of
sleepless nights a lot of times being
paranoid
um you know like I said and and and I
grew for a few years so it was
um I had to sell it you know there's a
lot of comp there was one guy this
listen to this there was one guy that
shows up at my
house I I I wrote a letter to the editor
in The
Oregonian and from that people got a
hold of my address and came to my house
two different oh [ __ ] oh yeah this
really [ __ ] up man this one guy shows
up he shows up he's got a pickup truck
and it's covered with a tarp right and
so so what he had done is he had he read
the book grown all grown about a ton of
ton of
dope harvested it all put it in his
truck and came over to my house to
figure out what to do with it was it all
wet still yeah it was all wet and it w
it it was like parked right in front of
my house you anyway so this guy showed
up to your house with a truckload full
of
of fresh cannabis that he didn't know
what to do with yeah about a ton and he
says well where can I sell this stuff I
didn't even want to look at it yet now I
looked at it through the window and it
was like hanging out the tarp and stuff
and that I mean that that's pretty uh
that would have been a big deal the
whole town would have known about
Portland's about half a million people
uh that would have been that that would
have been bad news uh God just all
little little little things you know um
what was another one there was this
other guy that came over and I'm sure he
was a narc cuz he wanted me he wanted me
to sell him some
cannabis or tell him where he could find
some uh but those were the those were
the two ones that I recall um yeah but a
lot a lot of PE a lot of other things
too like I was a member of the the
Publishers Association
um well several of them in in the
Northwest
and people just hated me like some
people like me but about half of them
just [ __ ] hated me ju before they'd
seen me or anything and they would blame
me blame me for their children's
problems and and you know you got to be
careful when they're they're like that
you're in public you know because
they're pretty upset
but one time I did say I ain't the kid's
dad you better look in the mirror
[ __ ] I just had it I just had it
you know I'm still curious how did they
like find you like on the street did you
have a photo of yourself in your
original book were you not Incognito
like in the later ones no no no no they
they came to my house you said two
people showed up to your house but then
you said that like people on the street
would see you and blame you for their
kids oh no no no on the street not on
the street uh in the Publishers group in
the Publishers group yeah that's where
they cuz cuz I was very very careful
with the identity that was um now that's
a kiss of death man um you could you
couldn't travel anymore if you you know
you have a felony you start running into
trouble with uh traveling and especially
if you want to move and it comes up
every time well shows up every time you
cross a border that's the big problem so
you go into the little room and you have
the conversation about 10 different
times with the same with different
people and it's it's real
unpleasant yeah and then let's see after
that after
that hydrarm got a hold of me and they
wanted me to put a catalog in the back
of the book so that's what I did I put a
catalog in the back of the book and we
sold indoor garden
equipment and that worked really
well um this is the same Hydra farm that
I know yes the one I didn't know that
part of the story because later on they
beca well santell was Diamond lights
right no no that was they started oh
you're right hyro Farm was in sanell too
but um Francis great Boulevard that's
what they became so paranoid about weed
later on you know so interesting started
off they got popped in green Merchant H
yeah they were one of the what uh6
stores or something I don't I can't I've
got the stats here uh but one of the I
don't know 80 stores 40 stores I can't
remember that got they got po but 100
but 120 of my friends went to jail I
know that that's why they made the
change to to be a little bit more
careful I guess yeah they were uh real
paranoid for a while but you know it's
understandable it's it's your livelihood
and you know you could go to jail that
Jail's not
fun like you said people did go to jail
yeah lots of them lots of them so there
was there was that and then after that
yeah and and
then about a year after that I opened a
uh a garden store in Portland Oregon
and that went that went pretty well um
but I was I'm really a shitty business
person when it comes down to it so um I
had a manager there that was quite
dishonest and uh he pretty much ran me
into
bankruptcy um by not paying attention to
this that and other thing blah blah blah
uh so that that was pretty rough but I
do remember
before uh before green Merchant I
remember on two separate well no three
four five five or six occasions two
different narcs came in I remember them
very well I could Pro well they're older
now but I could probably ID them still
because so you said you had a garden
store but it's just like what we would
call a grow shop that was a grow shop
yeah selling selling gear for for
cannabis Growers you weren't selling
Bonas and ferns I was going to say now
in there shops are like yeah I sold some
shade plants indoor plants we had a
greenhouse yeah we we we sold other
things sold a few uh um or but your F
your focus in your head at least was can
100% cannabis or should I say Tomatoes
Tomatoes what was the name of the grow
store uh let's see
oh Northwest yeah Northwest Garden
Center
Northwest Garden Center and about what
year was this yeah and then that was
geez so I hope I wrote that down
um that
was early early 7 or early early 80s
early 80s let me see if I can find a
copy of my this straight book
okay now what I what I did what I did
here this is this is the newest edition
of this book the marijuana marijuana
horiculture but um I took this book this
book here sanitized it and made this
book some of the photos in that book are
from my shop yeah that's
right that's right all color printed in
China but yeah that's right they are
from your shop I well that's you were
taking product pictur is at my store
yeah yeah yeah exactly uh you still owe
me a
check for
what this but but this book um did did
quite well actually uh because it was
for the employees the employees could
read it and know what to do uh know how
to help help clients and then clients
could read it and have a good idea and
it gave people something to talk about
you know different types of tomatoes
except you know that that the funny
thing is um you know cannabis has got
some really unique characteristics like
some well yeah exactly it's uh yeah
dioses big deal big deal and it also uh
it's a short day plant you know so it
flowers there's only a few okay like
poin poinas Napa cabbages you know
Chinese cabbage they call them also and
um let's see Christmas cactus those are
and C cockal bur there's a bunch of
plants that are short day plants right
so um you kind of have to I'm I'm glad
the cops didn't read these things
because yeah I mean if you read
this if you read
yes I mean you be it'd be really the
thing is you'd have to know a little
something about marijuana to know that
in the first place right yeah yeah so
even if they read it they probably
wouldn't have a clue did it like talk
about flipping your tomatoes to 1212
oh no I have to change I you're that is
good though I have to change I have to
change plants for that but you know not
a lot of people grow
poas I mean they'll get them they'll get
them in the winter and grow them for
Christmas but that's it but anyway
anyway so so this one did really well
did really well and but I get these
phone calls or not phone calls but
letters letters and uh later I would get
uh emails that would say
hey there's this guy named George Van
Patton and he's been ripping off your
stuff you better you know I mean there's
a big copyright violation there and I
write back and say oh that's so bad blah
blah
blah but it was a good joke we had we
had a fun time with it you know what's
funny about
that is I was just talking to a friend
of mine the other day and we were
talking about you and you know he called
I don't know if he called you George
because we were actually talking about
Bill
Ross oh yeah yeah yeah Ross yeah and so
Ross always called you George yeah you
know and yeah you know I've known you
for over 20 years I still don't know
what your [ __ ] name
is uh you're still that guy with the
sunglasses and dreadlocks as far as I'm
concerned that's
uh we can keep it that way if you want I
just wanted you to know that I thought
it I thought it was funny
most people keep it that way that
because uh you know my given name George
Van Patton one of my is your given name
yes okay so now now now the facts are
out that your name is George van I kind
of thought santes might not be your last
name
but yeah well yeah I um yeah cantes
no um oh yeah I was talking about guard
gardening indoors and then and then
later later became a green Merchant
green Merchant were you around for green
Merchant or did you was not I actually
started growing right after green mer
Merchant so like when I met when I met
Bill he was super paranoid because you
know they had just come to his place and
and give him a whole bunch of [ __ ] but
before we talk about green Merchant I
think one step like I said I don't want
to forget talking about somebody that I
know is you know dear to the two of us
is Tom Alexander and you were involved
in sense Amilia tips right right right
yeah um actually yeah I I mean Michael W
SE says hello as
well oh okay cool hey wolf he recorded
he recorded with us as well oh cool cool
cool um yeah the thing is with um uh
well given name Tom Alexander I always
call him Alex because well that's what I
call him but anyway yeah we spent we
spent a lot of time together lots of
time together we would go to uh the the
national Book Fairs you know um and we
were always like the The Crazies The
Crazies of the book group because there
see we were in small press and small
press back then uh they were growing
really fast and they were quite a quite
a uh a force to be reckoned with and we
had our own well you know small press
and it's just small smaller presses but
a lot of leftists and a lot of
alternative people and stuff that we
will hang out with and then we will also
have the uh the party
Suite we would pull all our money get it
and and and get a suite Alex and I would
uh do that we get a suite and then we'd
all always bring uh lots of
dope and we were quite popular quite
popular everybody everybody would show
up at the at the suite but we usually
get I don't know anywhere from 30 to 70
or 80 people um Ken key showed up one
time uh that was really good uh yeah was
that was nice that was a hit uh who but
yeah fun time and anyway um we spent all
kinds of time we went to to that to
trade shows probably for 20 years 20
years yeah and that it it was rough
times because there's a bunch of people
that hated us and and um but most of
people liked us because see book world
is pretty pretty liberal even um you
know Librarians every everybody you know
you think it'd be very conservative
they're not at all conservative think
people should be able to express
themselves but yeah yeah we spent tons
of time together he moved out here from
Connecticut from Connecticut yeah and uh
stayed at the farm in fact he'd be a
good idea a good guy to interview oh
it's already in the works good good good
yeah uh he stay at the farm which was uh
Ken stepen gin you
know excuse
me I asked you if it was Ken Key's
Farm no no Ken key was in uh Eugene
Oregon right uh This was um oh what's
what what's his name gasin Stephen gasin
and he was in Tennessee and they called
it the farm um yeah was the biggest
commune at the time well those guys are
still
there yeah yeah one of one of my
employees is like part of that family
and he actually or one of my
ex-employees um he actually like I think
it was like five or 10 years ago he went
back so that they're still there really
excellent excellent because I because
Stephen Steph passed away like five six
seven years ago
now I know he went back there like 10
years ago that you know I don't know
what happened if if he had to leave
because if they closed cuz he died or
something but they definitely existed 10
years ago cool cool cool yeah because I
knew I knew Stephen from um from The
High Times he would go to go to the high
times fair the Cannabis Cup that was the
biggest thing happening oh yeah and then
way back way back this was this was
early on right after I published the
book
um or not within 6 months 6 months a
year uh Neville was selling seeds out of
uh the seed bank in out of uh the
Netherlands and he'd already set up the
um the Cannabis castle and stuff so I
spent a lot of time there I would I
would fly over to Netherlands regular L
um three or four times well yeah three
or four time four times a year probably
for about five or six years yeah that
was early on early
on um and I also helped
Neville uh get some different cannabis
seats like uh what was it you brought
him genetics from the US well I no I
didn't bring them I figured since I was
not I was not making any money I will
put people together but I'm not going to
traffic anything because that's the way
you well you can't write you go to jail
you can't write you can't share any
information you got to stay able to
work um yeah so uh what did what did we
get uh the
G13 uh and one of the afghanis because
there's basically four four genotypes of
Afghani and um big bud big bud was the
other one yeah and you know big bud
that's like a main breeder a main
breeder now um and they changed all the
names and stuff uh yeah and uh that's
when I smoked the the uh Haze for the
first time
and it's was my favorite and it still is
I love Hayes it's the absolute best um
yeah but over there God and it was
really interesting the castle because
what he did he that Neville did and he
passed away God four years now four
years ago he was yeah
Australia yeah um but anyway he had
started ed
u well what he he he he made a lot of
money dealing hash and that's when he
got into the breeding because he knew
how to breed canaries he learned all
about breeding in Australia when he and
gu is guy is really really smart really
smart good science background too uh and
he goes he goes and he buys over in
nagan which is right next to Germany he
goes and buys
uh right on the wall river right on it
uh this great big old house and they
used to call it the the big the big
house by the dyke that's right across
the river from
Nan and then
uh and then because and the house was
from about 1820s 18 yeah 1810 1820 so
all those old houses have a big stable
down below the the um the basement is
usually a stable for the the horses to
stay so what he did is he made in the
different Stables he made different
breeding rooms and then he got a
jackhammer and and made uh ditches
everywhere in the floor jack hammered up
the the concrete so he made a a maze of
of ditches and then a a low place so he
put a sump pump so he would uh and then
then he then he got the the rock wool
the the slabs cut them into short pieces
and then got a Camile he cover them with
plastic so it would have these little
pots like this this you know this this
high of Gro down uh rock wool and then
that way he could move his plants all
over the place but it was very very
efficient real simple you know very
quite quite Dutch yeah but actually
Neville's from from Australia he left
Australia because he had
a he had a a legal
problem legal problems seem like we all
get legal problems sometimes um yeah but
I spent T tons of time with him and that
was a real
education um great times great
times um we spent a lot of time in
Amsterdam back then that was the only
place you could go
and then I remember I went back to uh
went back to High Times there was one of
the writers that was working for High
Times I won't mention but it was going
to Netherlands all the time and he said
that he said that Neville wouldn't talk
to anybody but him I thought well this
kind of sounds funny so so I I call him
up on the phone cuz his phone number was
in the High Times I call called Neville
up and I and I started asking him
questions and he says yeah mate come on
over come on over hang out so that's
what I did I went over and hung out and
um yeah learn learn tons tons from them
in fact there's uh photos photos from
the
uh from his from his original well
cannabis Castle in my books yeah that
was quite a time God I think about you
know
the old days the old days it's like see
this he got this like 40 years ago I I
mean I say that I can't I can't freaking
believe it myself you
know long yeah my friends are dying you
know we're all old hell I'm 71 years old
you know okay you look great buddy oh
man one question that I had for you is
like you know you're 71 years old how do
you have that beautiful hairir
I mean oh yeah I got look at me bro look
what's happened to
me well that's a that's a gen when I met
you my hair was down to my rear and now
you know
like same we got to get some pictures of
Gabby with long hair yeah good idea good
idea there's a couple Gabby that uh
those dreads that you
had that picture is the best this is
going to Happ have to be the the like
cover shot of our video right here I
love
that that is no well see I did those um
I came up with those because because of
uh High Times High Times wanted me to
shoot because I I'd moved up to oh hell
I forgot about this I moved up to BC
Canada um and was living in in Langley
which is right just right out or not
Langley but um the hell's the name of
that town uh it's it's just the first
suburb on on the Highway south of
uh south of of uh
Vancouver I'll think of it a minute I
don't know yeah I was up there a couple
of years or not not quite two years and
uh yeah that was God a real education up
there that's when everybody was growing
up there that was when
uh was that the ' 90s I don't know it
all Blends together after a
while
um yeah I spent yeah but anyway we we
High Times wanted to do a video and so
we shot the first video up there uh
forant uh ultimate grow here we go I got
him right
here there was three of them look at
this one that's your photo from your
that's the book
yeah but I did ultimately I did three
videos with High Times oh wow and yeah
yeah but these were the only and and
then they pirated these all over
YouTube um and that was really a good
deal because that's got me out or my
name out all over the
world um yeah but the the reason I I
came up with that this guys was so I
could shoot this
video and people wouldn't see my
face uh CU like I say it was still
pretty spooky spooky times back then but
Canada everything was wide open you know
so that was um you quite quite different
but yeah up there you know I I met met
the went over and hung out one night at
the Hells Angels hell angels
Clubhouse yeah that was that was kind of
a trip and U the angels are real big up
there and then um yeah did oh lots of
stuff lots of stuff um I guess it's so
long it it's not
incriminating but anyway there just some
stuff I just well I think you should
tell the stor incriminating cuz I
promise you that law enforcement doesn't
care
anymore they don't well that's that's
good um now I'm trying not well now I
never never smuggled back and forth
across the
border uh knowingly you know I maybe a
mistake
or it wasn't like I was plan moving
loads and stuff but like i' move them
I'd move them inside the US that was
like normal
in the god the 70s early yeah mid 70s
that's yeah yeah I was uh mid to late
70s I was moving loads up and down the
coast all the time that was what was
your closest
call
oh breaking down on the highway breaking
down in in know I had a Volkswagen bus
U and I was sleeping in it it said the
car broke down and I was sleeping it and
the cop came by to ask me if I was
okay and that was that was pretty close
how much how much do you think you had
with you no I forgot about growing
another time when I was growing in in um
when you in Santa Barbara up sanro
Canyon um it's just south of Santa
Barbara in
monito um
what had happened I I had a a cestine
garden up there and was growing it was
pretty good size I had a pump and
everything I had to go up there early in
the day and and
uh pump water and stuff it because
nobody no nobody should be able to hear
you know you don't want a punk going off
in the out in the middle of
nowhere and one time somebody the the
forest service they'd lost somebody got
lost up there and they were they were
reporting them and they thought I was
the Lost
guy yeah so I was coming back down I had
a bunch of dope on me right so I'm I'm
I'm coming back down this Trail I think
everything's cool and the next thing I
know this this damn helicopter over me
and they were following me and stuff so
you know I mean I could see I could see
a guy look at me
I thought dang that's not
good probably know you know I mean cuz
it's easy you know everybody's paranoid
so uh or I was paranoid and anyway what
happened was
um I had I I I hid I went and hid under
a oh there was a big rock and I went and
hid and I H all my dope and everything
and stuff and then uh
and then I come down and then I walk
down and I meet these guys from the
forest service and I think okay well
this is it you know I mean I
better better be real casual here and um
they asked me if I'd seen anybody if I'd
seen anybody else up there because and
and that's when I figured out they were
looking for somebody else not me and
that was that was spooky though because
I didn't know any different but they
were going to go near your garden
that's like like while they're looking
for this guy they could have stumbled
across where you were growing yeah it
would have been hard it would have been
yeah that's true it would have taken
some effort yeah it would have taken
some effort yeah no I had several layers
of security for
sure um yeah yeah several layers but
anyway that that worked really well and
that that actually the second crop was
the second crop I pulled out of there
was great because because that's when
the price went from $500 a pound to 12
to $1,200 a
pound and um yeah from one year to the
next you know that's more than double
right two and a half times as much so oh
so I you know what year that was huh do
you know what year that was
708 78 79 79 what sort of what sort of
layers of security were you using
uh one of the things I do is is uh it's
always you put uh duct tape on the
bottom of your shoes so they can't match
you with the shoes they can't match you
with the footprints and they can't say
it with you and you have to take it off
every time so you got to have that duct
tape on you which is kind of a it's a
little iffy that and then
uh another thing is a would take the
branches and well first you have to find
a sunny location and then you have to
find a place where you can pull the
branches over the Cannabis so it doesn't
look like there's a square cut out of
the out of the brush there and um yeah
that's and and and so you have to plant
plant plants in several different places
and in order to water it might take you
know one 20 minutes to water just
because you have to walk several
places yeah so uh but that that was the
security I tried setting up a camera
they didn't have anything decent back
then it would have been crazy and then I
don't know you could only you'd had to
develop the film uh but those those were
the main things and then the other
security thing was was doing doing
everything I would have to go up there I
had to I had to haul up their you know
uh PVC pipe you know cut it in 10t
sections and you know you look pretty
conspicuous with white pipes yeah and uh
hose a pump a pump that was that was
that was Heavy uh were you like pulling
water from a a like a a nearby stream or
something yeah there was a creek there
was a Sedro Creek and fortunately it ran
it runs all year I don't know if it does
still but it did back
then yeah but anyway that's that's uh
time passed time passed I think people
just don't don't
realize how difficult things were back
then um yeah and then where what what
did we do what did I do next let me see
here well one one thing I can say while
you looking for the next phase in your
life was I thought it was really funny
that you said that you were really
paranoid and and you know something that
I wanted to bring up is that paranoia is
something that people always said yeah
when
I but I wonder if that's just because of
the illegality of it right like people
don't don't get paranoid when they're
drinking a beer you know because it's
not illegal you know so like 18 or 17
and drinking a beer at a party and the
cops show
up right yeah yeah there there you go
you know I don't think I I don't think
weed makes you paranoid I think the
illegality of it makes you paranoid well
I don't know I'd argue that there's
social aspects to it too you know like
there's been times where you know
hanging out with friends get super
stoned and you're like oh my God like
are they talking show you like what the
hell they talking about like you start
spiraling out and yeah but I think I
think you think that when you're
straight I think you are you know what
the deal is you're actually paranoid and
it has nothing to do with the
[Laughter]
weed for like 20 years so you
know light of hallucinations and stuff
you could it may have something to do
with I so I remember one time uh well
like for example those Dutch guys for
example they they never get paranoid
they never get paranoid uh when they're
growing when they're around it and stuff
because it doesn't have the same
penalties that that it does in or didn't
that had in
America uh but nobody that I knew ever
got
paranoid and then one time though I have
to say uh who was it Allen Allan
dronkers uh Ben son you know from ceny
seeds um he said yeah I've heard about
this paranoia and stuff and he says it
almost happened to me one time I felt a
little bit and then
um and then he said he goes I just smoke
another joint and went
away next time Cosmic take that advice
if you get paranoid just smoke another
joint actually you
know the the thing is that in Slovenia
for example now it's still illegal the
the the Cannabis right but it's so much
used now in it's so it's so much is is
more I I said in one podcast uh that
it's the most tolerant country to
Canabis in the world maybe right now you
know because it's it's been yeah it's
been used also for not only for
recreational but also for medical well
people make this Rick Simpson Oil for
many years now you know so it doesn't
matter what kind of perspective on life
you have when you have a garden which
many people do they grow Canabis and May
they never smoked a joint you know but
they grow it and they make oils from
that you know and you know it's like a
movement it's like a big big part of it
it's also why it will be legalized maybe
soon maybe also because us will maybe go
Federal maybe Germany now because it
started to legalize or decriminalize it
you know so it's but you you hit the the
point when you said that the Dutch guys
never get so uh paranoid we because the
penalty in Europe for this was not big
you don't go to jail uh just growing few
plants you know it's yeah it's never
going to happen you know it's like no
way you know it would be it would be but
that's how actually my theory is that
Canabis craft Canabis breeding uh is
much more in USA uh developed because of
you you did not have this access we
could get seeds from Holland very very
very easily you know because we're in
Europe but you had this border you know
between us and Europe had this really
you know daa searched all the you know
they they had a system I
mean it's a very very very different
perspective you know but we still have
illegal illegal a lot of illegality you
know many states are still illegal in
and many countries in Europe are illegal
like I know uh you live in Spain right
or can you tell a little bit how you
decided to to to move to Spain or when
you know maybe if I'm not jumping too
far you know um
no just excuse
me I want oh let's see um yeah I I I
spent a year here when I was uh in in
University I went to University in
Valencia and um uh which is the third
largest city in in Spain so on the
Mediterranean and that was that was in
the early 70s and so I would uh uh I had
more freedom here than I did in my own
Hometown um and it's always that always
stuck with me and when I moved here I've
been here about 25 well yeah 25 years
I've been here 25 years so back then uh
California was the only place that was
legal 98 right so um or 96 96 I can't
remember anyway
um
uh yeah here here
it's it's tolerated it it's tolerated
it's kind of like a little overwhelming
a lot of people moved here from all over
Europe to start growing uh which is kind
of a problem uh because the albanians
are here that's a big problem because
they have like a pretty those guys are
the roughest Mafia there is in the world
um I'm convinced but um yeah because I
met with the police and stuff to find
out how we can work together they said
no uh we can't work together they don't
want to help me at all uh and we
couldn't get pictures I couldn't get
pictures with them or anything but
um yeah the thing is here we've got uh
well used to be
LA and then then then
isasa is the new is the different law or
the newest newest one but basically it
it's tolerated you can have have a small
quantities for personal use uh you can
grow and it depends on which part of
Spain you live in I live in uh Catalonia
or catalunia and here is liberal quite
liberal uh just like it is in the the
bass country and um yeah so here we we
don't have much problem you don't want
to smoke it in front of the cops or
anything because you get a ticket 300300
EUR 300 to 600 EUR for your first
offense and yeah it's kind of a pain and
those cops now listen to this they've
got those electric
motorcycles electric Mo you can't hear
the B coming oh [ __ ] and they're no it's
really rough and
you it's there all of a sudden my God
anyway uh but we've got we've got
smoking clubs here or private clubs and
the
club you you can have any kind of a club
you want but some of the some of the
things you can you can't do or advertise
can't advertise your club or advertise
the Cannabis or um have a front window
you're you're supposed to have
everything closed and not have a sign on
the front door but you can look
everybody a lot of people up on the
Internet so you know it doesn't really
matter that way uh you just search for
cannabis club
Barcelona
yeah
yeah yeah y that's it and that's it and
you'll find him uh but too you know
you've got to have national ID to be
able to go in some clubs make exceptions
you know I mean it was like the wild
west for about about five years things
happen slowly here so if I go there now
they don't let me in um you come over
and uh come over and hang out I'd take
you to Club I I I I could always get
people in oh no but like just like your
average American Tourist would they be
able to go into one of these uh
clubs pardon would would like an average
American Tourist be able to go into one
of these clubs or do you need to have
some sort of local connect to bring you
in local ID and but you can you there
there's several clubs that that break
all the rules you know right but there
there I mean because see there was and
there there was another one these guys
where in the heck were they from from
Central Europe somewhere I never went
over there but they had like you know
20,000 members because you have to sign
up and you know you're only supposed to
have like
uh yeah so like 20,000 members and they
were they were moving some real poundage
out of there I mean some serious kilos
and um tourists everybody they have
people people would go to tourist areas
and recruit recruit tourists to go over
there um yeah that it was pretty wild
for a while um and that's when spannabis
had started or well spannabis was going
pretty good been going about 10 years 10
12 years and somebody got the great idea
to you know because when um all all of
the civs came out for separating making
the ice hash uh they would
uh at spanis you could go in there you
could take in like 10 pounds of dope in
the front door give it to some give it
to these guys that wanted the the stands
they would separate it they'd run the
tumbler all night or had a bunch of it
separate and and they would take 25% for
doing that and then they would give you
just a chunk of hash back
and that that lasted that lasted one
year and then
they that
anymore but yeah here spannabis used to
be the the biggest
uh the biggest Trade Fair in in uh the
world and then Las Vegas took it over
now it's now it's uh
Germany uh but like I say it's uh
cannabis is tolerated here uh we've had
a we've got a very old hash called
culture um Morocco is just right across
the the straight of
jalter so um yeah and I remember when I
first got here that actually it was uh
they have um well they sell several you
know lots of different grades Ash but uh
katama you know katama is just right
over there in in the Riff mountains of
Morocco um but they have you know they
would package usually in in 100 100 gr
plates plas they call
plas and then they will Al and they will
put a stamp on it and the double zero
double zero stamp which usually is the
highest grade in general and you can go
in like in in November oh that's the
best month because they have uh the
cream you can get yeah yeah I see I see
Sloan yeah yeah yeah Poland you know I I
smoked I mean I been to to to Andalusia
a lot and to Barcelona I go every year
you know I have a lot of friends in
Spain a lot you know so I really know
what you're talking about you know you
know years ago I took bubble BS with me
to Spain you know because we used to
make hash for that you know the bubble
hash this was in 2005 or something you
know or four you know and uh these
andalusians you know uh they were
showing me their inner Gardens you know
in the houses because all of them were
grow weed growers indoor outdoor
everything you know so there was a lot
of cannabis but still they told me that
there is so much hash but just flour is
just in the season when they had a
little bit of flour you know more or
less it was all hash culture in the
third or fourth generation already right
yeah exactly exactly no for for Trans to
make the transition from hash to
cannabis that took about 10 years uh
because now cannabis is more more
popular than hash here but it took a
long time because you know you could go
get your your beot they call them they
call 10 grams 10 grams they usually call
it an
acorn um yeah 10 grams but you can
buy and the best the best has is the is
KERO KERO I KERO from the ass KERO you
you guys I mean it's pretty gross but
you they they take the tin ground pieces
and wrap them up in cellophane or yeah a
plastic wrap anything and then swallow
them swallow them and um you can average
person here's important stats average
person can get about a kilo 2.2 pounds
in their stomach and all the way up to
about
here come up to here oh my God and after
that 200 grams up the
butt a double
Dicker takes three days sitting in a
bathtub to get rid that stuff to pass so
I have a question for you Jorge it
sounds like you have experience are you
a ketto no no
NOA from I I've never been across the
border with uh KERO has maybe just I
don't three days in a bathtub though
man that's
crazy lots of water and then you have to
hang on a on a bar and and
like down okay I think you've officially
told the best story ever told on the
show can you can you describe the what
you were talking about the crema or uh
if you if you make it too the cream
cream the cream the stuff that was like
the the really nice stuff they call it
butter it's uh that's like the blonde
[ __ ] yeah not so not so um uh but it's
soft and pliable because it's it's it's
new it's new and you you don't but you
you only get it right then because
otherwise it gets oxidized and stuff but
this is more of a blonde color and it's
pliable
it's pliable like that and uh a little
bit it's not like you know a lot of
times you figure the hash will be hard
like your phone you know
um yeah and then it's got a
consistency you use a knife to cut it
always a hot
knife and um yeah it's
uh it's it can be sticky it depends on
the quality as as far as the stickiness
goes um and if you're lucky it won't it
won't have too much like U camel [ __ ]
smell because camel [ __ ] because they
made the camels eat it too no I don't
know about I don't think they'd waste it
like that I wouldn't
uh I wouldn't give a camel my
do what was I don't know I think I'd
rather a camel do the smuggling for me
than me
I don't know I'm gonna I'm G to catch
some heat for that oh right right they
probably have a have a way bigger
stomach and a way bigger
[ __ ]
yeah oh yeah I didn't think about
[Laughter]
that who's gonna bring over a camel that
be kind of you'd have all that
documentation and
stuff you got to have a veton call yeah
they probably want to quarantine him for
a while that's
B no it's [ __ ] up we shouldn't talk
about that that's animal
abuse yeah uh yeah you're right uh I did
a video on it pulo yeah just we'll put a
link yeah put a link on the bottom of
the show notes yeah it's it's on my um
my YouTube
channel yeah we'll put all of your links
on in the description to the podcast so
people can
find uh your legit stuff not just the
counterfeit my buddy over in Russia did
this but it's uh they pirated it in in
Russia in Russia and
um uh dubbed it they got a professional
uh dub artist to to overdub it and they
didn't and they didn't put uh uh what do
you call it uh subtitles on it yeah so I
was pretty impressed you know even
though they took it but I know hard as
hell over in Russia all of those guys
you know I mean I got a lot of Russian
friends I I mean there's good guys some
really good guys kind some other ones
pretty tough guys they're kind of funny
but um yeah it's uh well it's important
to get the information out but yeah I'm
uh actually quite quite big in Russia
here I'll show you this oh here I got
these
now here it is I didn't
see who
is yeah yeah and I was like I have no
idea what language that
is it's Russ Russian here here's another
one this was Chinese Chinese man
Japanese Japanese yeah yeah yeah I like
on the Russian one that it shows you
just pointing to a giant cannabis plant
like you know we'd miss it if you
weren't pointing it
out yeah and here's the here's the other
mugs and then here's the this is the
original book that I printed
myself wow and it's 90 Pages oh man you
got that's really cool I did the artwork
myself it's not very good there was more
but this book book
um actually yeah
there's this book did uh it's it first
year it sold 6,000
copies uh which and that's just in the
Northwest and that's uh pretty darn good
that's without bookstores selling
it yeah right yeah uh like you said
everybody hated you yeah yeah well they
I was just was too Danger it uh like
marketed how did you get it the in like
the word out that you had this book at
that time with no one uh wanting to
carry it I got my car drove around all
the head shops and would sell them and
then I most usually had to leave them on
consignment because nobody believed that
it would
sell and because they didn't know what
the hell was going on and um yeah that's
what I did and then so it took and then
also I had uh uh two Distributors on the
west coast Homestead
books and uh from Seattle and uh was
owned by my good friend of mine David
tlan and all and then the other one was
last gasp of San Francisco Ron Turner
down there and those guys would also
distribute to head shops and some
bookstores but not the main stream book
stores what year was that and how much
were you selling it for this was
1983 and I was selling this for
8.95 Wow 8.9 yeah 8.95 and I fered it on
a a
multilift multilith
press and stapled it all this stuff it
was so much work but I guess it panned
out after a while I mean people needed
the needed the
information how much of that information
do you think is transferable to today's
growing
culture except for the
life pretty much all of it I mean you
know I mean PL plants been growing the
same for the last you know um
Millennia
um some stuff doesn't change gravity is
still the same as it used to be you know
but there's more more precise
information now there's more specific
information on nutrients nutrients were
the big thing everybody you know they've
got the best nutrients blah blah blah
well that's where all the money was you
know it it it costs about a nickel or 5
cents to to make a a gallon of fertili
izer that you can sell for $30 or $40 or
more so that's a pretty good markup and
that's yeah and it's a consumable right
yeah so Phil from kic when I told him
you were going to join the show he said
oh that's exciting ask him for me if he
could make a single revision to his
famous nutrient chart what would it be
and I just think it's funny that you
know we asked the question and you said
that that's what had changed was
nutrients but uh would you make a
revision to your chart you mean the the
um the excesses and deficiencies it
could be um could be these here this is
the older book and then I made a newer
one in the
encyclopedia which is
uh which is
here uh
and there's a series of drawings like
this right yeah I think he could be
referring to these the
new
um I would I would just tighten them up
a little bit there's more information
I'd interview more
people and but everything's correct this
is all know funny those nutrient photos
the the the photos that show
deficiencies that was all we had as cul
cators you know like back in the day you
know when you couldn't talk to people
about this there was no
internet and with that book you know
we'd look at our plant and be like is
that nitrogen deficiency or is it
Calcium
deficiency
and yeah like I said so many Growers
would love to just chime in right now
and say thank you for that book it was
just amazing and if you came out with a
new book we had a it just you know I I
purchased every addition that you put
out during my growing growing career so
yeah yeah there a lot of people have
because just is the only place you could
find the information can I be so bold as
to make a suggestion for your next book
sure so something that I learned you
know I don't
know 5 10 years ago should have been a
lot longer is because we've always been
using your book and those diagrams to
tell us what the nutrient
defici what it doesn't address is what a
combination of nutrient deficiencies
would look like and so really hard
that's really hard because right but the
point is is that people too often look
at the book and they say oh this is what
it is
but now you can send Leafs out for
analysis and the leaf analysis is going
to show you something very different
than that book is going to show
you oh yeah well because you've got
you've got a combination of different
nutrients right uh what you can what I
can do here if you you know you read the
text it's a lot of times this is
confused uh calcium for example I'm
looking at that that entry now it's
confused with lots of things so that's
that's quite important what it's
confused with root disease excess
nitrogen ammonium magnesium potassium
there's not enough pages in a book to
show pictures of all possible Comm no I
I don't think you could I just want
people to know that like for instance
let's say you have nitrogen and Calcium
deficiency okay because they're both
confused you could actually have both
defici when add calcium unless it's
calcium nitrate maybe that would solve
the problem because you'd be giving it
calcium and and nitrogen um you know you
may not be addressing the problem so
particularly on a commercial scale when
the farmers can afford to do it I always
tell people that they should be doing
Leaf analysis their entire crop at least
at least the first couple of times so
that they can figure out what's going on
and you know there's a lot of arrogance
in Growers and they look at it and go oh
that's a calcium
deficient but that
arrogance it slows them down and like I
said luckily now we have testing we have
tools available that we didn't
have that's right actually in America
they don't test that much uh for uh
genetics is what I think uh they could
be testing a lot more uh when you talk
about arog um and Growers or breeders
quote unquote does tell you that uh
before it goes into be before it goes
into each one of the explanations of of
each one of the nutrients that 99% of
the times these happen together these
nutrient I guess I haven't read the book
in long enough or I don't have the most
latest
copy you know I could see the future of
this too um utilizing AI um AI is being
utiliz in a lot of medical testing you
know for uh cancer screening especially
but um potentially someone could create
an where utilize the phone's camera take
a picture of the leaf and then it can
analyze it using AI to you know say this
is the possible causes of whatever
you're seeing on your Leaf you know
Apple already has that on my Apple
watch or I mean my Apple uh computer
let's see I'll find a plant picture but
it does it it'll identify plants the
thing is it needs the data first to
input that thing I did is i' I've been
making books you know all kinds of books
I got uh well 11 languages I had the
first good Dutch Marana benon is here I
had the first one Marana benon first a
good
uh yeah n van shik did a lot I did a lot
of straight books
vegetables
Hydroponics um oh yeah here's another
one the the the Hell's Angels you know
from um the the the really rough guys
they're the ones from Laval Laval uh
Canada it's the suburb of
Montreal and they're the generally
considered the roughest Bunch there is
because they're they're tough guys
anyway they uh they pirated one of my
books they PIR the Bible yeah and so I
called them up I got the phone number
and called him up and um the
conversation ended like [ __ ] you well
[ __ ] you well [ __ ] you come over here
and say that [ __ ] you and anyway that
was pretty much the end of it I was I
tried to sue him but uh then you had to
collect the money and the lawyer wants
to get paid first so I couldn't do
anything so this is this is what I did
this was my my uh
Revenge what I did is I went to China
and I made the book
uh color full color and what that did is
it made it too expensive for him to
steal and so I look at it as like yes it
was really a good thing I'm so glad they
took the book I'm very happy um yeah but
I've done a lot of other other ones
German
German uh that was a biggie that's done
real well done outdoor books indoor
books you speak
German no no it's it's a hard one to
learn it's a hard one if you don't learn
it from when you're young you know and
so many Germans speak
English or we're trying to find some uh
European people to do the podcast with
with Sasha and Germany is is huge right
now so we're hoping oh oh yeah Vincent
weed is really a good guy he's he's he's
like number one he's he's great guy
great guy um there's tons of Interest
now in in Germany the market went up
really high and then it's then it went
down we'll see we'll see what
happened um what happens in the
future um they sure had a big Fair this
year though or last year last year did
you did you go uh Slovenian no uh until
now Mary Jane I will go this year I will
go to Mary Jane but friends of mine are
going there I'm going to Barcelona every
year you know this is for me but now
Germany because it's legalized I mean
definitely and I have a I have I sell to
Germany clones you know I'm I'm selling
just today went out five six packages of
clones for German Market you know
because home Growers can buy buy ICS now
you know it is it's opened up it's a
limit five plans a person I can send but
uh yeah the market is open and the
beautiful thing is that uh I as a
producer I have a really exotic uh
Library you know for for the market
because Austria is a big market for for
this so if you don't have your own
selections your own connections that
gave you genetics uh then you cannot
compete on the market because
if you just have few old cuts that
everybody else has you know it's like
you know you have to you have to be able
to compete on the market that is for
sure in any cannabis business I think
you know any you have to be able to to
be smart and to to to change with with
time yeah excellent excellent oh oh that
so so those guys so you're shipping them
out of Austria then yeah I'm shipping
them out of Austria over over normal EXP
Express Mail
wow that's good and they don't get well
there's I have a European passport also
for that so that means that you get
checked once a year by the governmental
official uh you know it's called AAS and
they they make tests and they see if
everything is all right and then they
they give you the uh the passport for
next year again you know so it's that's
yeah it's a system thing yeah Austria
has really turned out to be a good place
I got uh other friends that are quite
productive
there
yeah yeah gosh so you know I just want
to make sure we did and you know it was
totally cool but uh we skipped forward a
little bit and I wanted to find out if
you had any more stories from the
8 um stories around we mentioned Tom
Alexander a little bit but I wanted to
make sure that you mentioned your time
at Samilia
tips yeah well I mean I wrote for senia
tips I didn't uh it was Alex's magazine
he started it and it was his 100
100% And they he was in business about
10 years before uh green Merchant
happened because green Merchants is uh
well that's what shut him down because
all of his advertisers quit um they were
out of business uh and that's when he
started uh growing
Edge yeah yeah growing Edge and that was
that was uh quite a good magazine when I
get him on the show it might be a good
idea to have you on too because then we
got you know two old friends telling
stories I'm sure you guys have a bunch
of stories together I got one quick
question before we wrap up and you know
might be a pretty quick answer but I
mean you've seen the evolution of
cannabis throughout decades you know and
I'm sure you you had favorite strains
you mentioned Hayes as one of your
favorites
um I guess this is kind of a two-part
question how does Modern cannabis you
know compare in your opinion to kind of
what you grew up and what you saw evolve
throughout the years and two you know
what would you say your favorite modern
strain is okay yeah modern strength um
let's see it's uh actually it was really
quite strong some time ago but I was a
bit spoiled because I've been fortunate
to be
around um
expert Growers all the time
um but it it it has improved it has
improved there's just much more
information now a much larger
selection but I have to be honest I
think the Jean Pool is pretty uh pretty
polluted uh there's not consistent
breeding plants you know true breeding
plants there's there's not so many of
those
people that are quote unquote breeders
are not formally
educated uh because breeding is usually
about numbers numbers lots of numbers
you got to be really good with
math um you know
uh that that part's
changed
um the lower end cannabis is gotten tons
better lots better used to be the
Mexican dope you get here you know I me
you'd be lucky to get 8%
or you'd get in America and it would
smell like
ammonia right right yeah it did yeah
very well could yeah sometimes sometimes
not but it depends on how wet it was
when they press yeah they'd press it
when it was fresh it would
mold yeah yeah well a lot of times
that's what they do they use those uh
those adobe brick
presses jump off yeah
they do and then modern strs I I like
old stuff to be honest I mean you know
there's there's new stuff but and and
and also I got to admit this I don't
have the best palette I don't have the
best uh tast buds uh I can't distinguish
things so well uh a lot of people say
they do but I know enough about smell to
know that I am one of the many and
there's very few maybe you
know the top end is 5% and then of those
there's 1% of that 5% it's a super taste
you know so most of the time when you
hear things and people tell you they
they experience stuff uh they're going
on memory a lot of times I can grow CBD
here in fact I'm going to start that
pretty soon grow
CBD um I'll start that in the in the
base
where I've got uh got a deal going with
uh AC Infinity AC Infinity theyve got
all kind well actually they've got
really cool equipment I'm pretty they do
yeah I like their stuff yeah and it's a
top end and it's also uh everything's
digitized a lot of people have been
mentioning to me that they like their
that they like their
gear yeah yeah it's well it's true
actually they uh I was over there
hanging out we went on a couple week uh
yeah twoe trip around the uh Northern
California we're in
Garberville uh didn't make it down to
Willis but down gar Garberville and and
over to the other side of the mountain I
so you were at the Ridgeline Farms yes
yeah those guys were great yeah great
yeah I'm watching you partner yeah face
I'm a Facebook
stalker I actually had one one question
also before we wrapped up um considering
as Cosmic said you've seen the evolution
of of not only uh the different strains
over the years but the evolution of
growing uh in both like a home growing
and a commercial aspect what do you
think is like the single biggest
Improvement that you've witnessed take
place in the cultivation
space
LEDs LED lights because they made I love
that answer OBS everything else
obsolete uh they had too there's just
too much heat coming out of those uh
allies they're uh sodiums there there
and there sodiums as well and the
combination lights uh well you know they
go either sodium or Hy but you'd have to
you know you could drive them with a
bigger Transformer but they burn out
sooner
um yeah that's that's got to be the
biggest thing um yeah and also the
Spectrum on those lights is is just much
much more conducive to
growing one I want to add one thing to
that so and and I also if if you have
one more moment I want to make sure that
Sasha doesn't have any questions he
needs to ask too but um I think that
environmental
control is actually had more of an
impact than the lighting because High
Press sodiums and
Hy do a pretty good job you know but one
a major issue that cultivators had had
is lack of environmental control and so
now I believe that more people are
trying to control their environment and
that's having a really dramatic effect
on you know how the plant grows yeah
it's interesting interesting to say that
because uh as as this industry developed
all the money was in um fertilizer
that's where you make the money
fertilizer okay you sell the fertilizer
that's where the biggest markup was
that's where all the energy went was go
into the fertilizer my fertilizer is
better than yours it's consumable yeah
and it's a consumable and thing and the
air you can't see it you know you you
look right through it uh people don't
realize just how much how how important
uh ventilation is or air circulation
have no clue there's no way they and and
uh before you couldn't measure measure
the CO2 level really uh inexpensively
there was those tubes that you suck the
chemical through right and get a
chemical reaction and have to
read some color which is pretty
difficult it's not a digital readout
um now you've got CO2 monitors are
really inexpensive or fairly
inexpensive um and also it can be
integrated together too fairly easily
before you'd have to have oh oh relays
and set up your own system basically and
have a basic knowledge of of electricity
and you know when the timer goes off the
fan goes goes on and you know products
Harmon yeah he put out the first yeah
another OG maybe we can get him on one
day but he made a controller that would
turn off your CO2 when your exhaust fan
came on and it's just
simple yeah I would just like to thank
you man because you you don't even know
how important your your book was for us
at at the time where we were a new
country know we were in Yugoslavia you
know people in Yugoslavia had your had
your book also you know like this is
crazy man it's like right I I've seen so
many people Growers you know having your
book on the Shelf in those places you
you don't even know man it's like you
you did something really you really did
a really big contribution to the
community to the culture you know as
itself Global Community you're a real OG
you know a legend
you you
know he doesn't have a big ego that's
also what makes him such a beautiful
person okay well I just I did my part
you know the part that was different
with me
was with different with me was most
people would get information and they
would take that information and make
money with it and keep it to
themselves my goal was to go the other
way to do the opposite of that and it it
it was a lot of hard work for a lot of
years but it's finally it's you know
finally pays off everybody everybody
else is happy too yeah that's awesome I
I want to leave you with
this one of my favorite musicians um I
think you you might love him too was
Jerry Garcia oh yeah and I used to have
friends that would leave the dead show
early to go wait at Jerry's hotel to get
an autograph and say hello to him and I
always I always thought they were crazy
cuz I used to say I'm here for the music
I'm not you
knower groupy to go right but the thing
about it is now that Jerry's passed one
of my biggest regrets was never being
able to just say thank you yeah not to
ask him for something or to take a
picture I mean I'd love that I'd love to
have a picture of me and Garcia right
but just to say thank you and I know
that every single person that watches
this podcast
the one thing they're going to say in
the comments is thank you and I know
that when you go to you know span or the
Mary Jane um Festival you know people
want to talk to you and ask you
questions but I know the number one
thing that happens is they say thank you
so with that thank
you yeah yeah thanks for joining us
thanks I mean wow I feels great
wonderful um well I just look at as I
did my part you know stood up was an
awfully big part buddy yeah I mean I've
known your since high school about 20
years there you know
so I've been telling all my friends like
oh shoot I'm GNA talk to Horas that's so
[ __ ] cool dude like this first book
was published before you were born bro
yeah it it was on my shelf when I was a
baby like my my dad had it for sure
that's where I feel I feel old yeah damn
it I I tell people you're my old friend
but it has a double meaning you're old
and we've been friends for a long
time
that's that's do you just have the
garden spout I don't I don't it burned
down and then I never opened it up again
oh burn this is a wrap for our show
with that he joined us today um hoping
that this is just part one of many parts
and you know I said before maybe when we
have Tom Al alander you could you could
join too and we could have two old
friends telling stories I think that
would be spectacular but anyway for now
we're going to say goodbye Jor bang up
[Music]