[Music]
what's up everybody this is Gabby Staten
Island with our Slovenian Hobbit Sasha
and our guest Vince weed and welcome to
your weed
stories anyway um on our last podcast
with Vince we you know we talked about
his history and everything but we wanted
to talk more about what's going on in
Germany and Europe as far as
legalization and so we wanted to have
him back um I think many Americans are
completely unaware of you know the
situation in in Europe and how things
are progressing
Germany as far as I'm aware and uh Vince
will give us more information they
legalized
cannabis and now they're considering uh
revoking it there's just like a whole
bunch of drama so let's get into the
drama and welcome Vince swed thank you
very much for the second
invitation um here in Germany it's now
exactly after work so this is my my vape
to get into the mood for this
podcast yeah um before you go any
further I wanted tell you we got a
tremendous response to our last video
and people were asking about the ball
Vapes I even went I went into my local
head shop that I've been shopping at
since
1991 and they knew what a ball Vape was
but they did not have one and so I
requested one I said hey look my buddy
Vincent weed said I need to have this so
uh I'm trying to get my hands on a ball
Vape and like I said everybody is uh
looking at that thing and like what is
that and I was like I you see the CLS
it's vaping it's not burning and do you
see the
clouds yeah it's so satisfying like I
said in the other episode when I have
been smoking 25 years
pipe and yeah this is my My Vegan My
Vegan pipe smoking now and the most
important thing is um what's what's uh
satisfying um a little bit of pressure
on the lungs and a huge amount of vapor
and um the good thing is with the wall
Vape it's a one hit on point termal
extraction so all the turbs and
cannaboids get really in once and it's a
beautiful way um yeah it's not really um
something new new I think the the
technique behind that it's old but it's
fought in a new way and yeah in Germany
the ball Vape is it has really a hype at
the moment it's crazy because out here
people don't know what it is and we
think of California as and you know the
us as being on the Leading Edge of this
type of stuff but uh yeah people don't
know what it is the closest thing that I
had to it and it it's nothing like it
was there's a product from Vaper
Brothers you you might be familiar with
it it's a wooden box and inside there's
a an element that's covered with glass
and then there's a bowl that's glass
attached to a hose and you put the hose
right onto the heating element and you
draw on it and you get a nice um Vape
from flower which um you know I really
like it um what I do not like which is
more popular out here is the volcano
you're familiar with the volcano I'm
sure definitely the thing about the
volcano is the Smoke Gets stales you
know like it takes so long to fill that
bag and then by the time you consume it
I just feel like the flavor is
affected yeah I would say I'm very
interested in getting a ball Vape yeah
this is the the thing um a vape or the
the when we say the old school Vapes
they have a long session it takes like
five to 7 minutes to extract all the
cannabinoids and the tpin and for me
this is with my ADHD takes too long and
this is why I use like the ball Vape or
a dino VAP and these are all Vapes which
really extract everything quick and it
doesn't take seven minutes and the
volcano have also this uh balloon and to
be true I never um felt had the feeling
for this Vibe because when I'm sitting
and I'm enjoying cannabis when I get
this and the balloon is blowing up it no
it's not my type of consuming
cannabis and one thing I'm not a fan of
the volcano at all we spoke about
cartridges last time and do you know
what I have here this is
crazy this is crazy I don't if I have
light yes I have to show you the
quality I have Vape cards made by myself
in under 1 hour and now and this is why
it's so crazy it's not made from hash
Rosen it's made from flower Rosen from
pressing the flower till having a consum
consumable vape it took me 1 hour and 15
minutes and the the thing is which is so
mind-blowing is that when you see the
quality this is flower Rosen yeah and
the thing is that the German community
is pushing hard everybody wants to get
out of his free plans he can grow now
not with the legalization I call it
decriminalization um they want to get
out the maximum and my job as a cannabis
educator is also to onboard the people
as easy as possible
to different topics of cannibals and
when you tell somebody to produce to
wash ha to dry the it to dry the hash
properly then to press Rosen from hash
it's a long way then then to BU to make
your own cards but in Germany because
there is such a huge need to do it now
by yourself because it's the only legal
way people also have been looking for a
way to get get it out from flowers and
it's the fire in fire out game I took
some beautiful flowers from my buto
rainbow I pressed it really as flower
rosin and then I took a small jar and I
decarbed the rosin and
I the word in English I hom
homog I homogen in German um to H um how
you call it I don't can't pronounce the
word I don't know how to say it in
English either uh H uh um to to make it
homogen you know homogenize it
homogenizing it exactly and by that you
get a little bit more viscous
consistency and the new cards can handle
that because it's no coil it's nothing
inside it's a
ceramic um part which heats up the
flower rosin so you don't have the
problem with all the lipids and fats
which are also in flower rosin so this
pen from pressing flowers to consumption
in 1 hour and 50 minutes so I will drop
also a YouTube video about that soon on
my channel so I'm interested in um are
you using like a a rosin press like we
have out here yeah definitely I um using
a 10 ton press and I have it since four
years from one of my partners um graa
it's called it's standing exactly here
behind me so
yeah can you yeah excuse me because um
back in the day when rosin first began
we were using like hair straightening
irons to make rosin but you can't use
fresh flour in that you have to do it
with hash nope that's not true sorry to
to yeah look look you can do go ahead
tell me me
so when we recorded today the episode
for YouTube we thought
about okay if we make a video where we
use a Rosen press let's say 450 bucks
and then we also say we are using an
infusing machine which can hold the
temperature perfectly other 250 bucks
okay so we said ah the the onboarding
barrier 600 bucks is quite high so what
we did and this is like I try to educate
the people I told to my cameraman let's
try if we can make it with the hair
straightener because a hair straightener
bucks the cartridge under 10 bucks and
you just need like a budget of € 30 to
make it with a with a hair straightener
and we did it also with flower without
Rosen bags we we took a
flower wait a
second we took a
flower and we pressed it to a small
ball and this ball helps you pressing it
without a b surrounding it so
this we put between perment paper and
the hair straightener and we pressed uh
four GRS and then we took all this
flower rosin which is a little bit dirty
because you don't have the filtration
through a bag and then we activated that
and that's now in my Rosen pants so we
really did it with a low entry barrier
for the German
community did you decarb it yes um when
you press the flower it's not viscous
enough so we uh we placed it by 110
celus for 25 minutes and then um during
the cooldown time it was still so liquid
that we really could fill it in the
pan without a syringe or
something so this is how I love to
that's cool I can't wait to see the
video we'll drop next
week well send me a link and you know
this video will take that much time to
to get it up as well and and we will put
the link in the video hey you guys chat
one second I want to grab
something uh Vince what is the the
temperature you are using uh when you're
pressing with the with your uh Ros
impress what what what do where are you
normally with the temperature um I
press uh flower Rosen between 75 and 80
Celsius for let's say 200 to to 250
seconds and um there I use the Rosen
bags
between at the beginning I was using 120
but when you get more for Quality also
when we talk about flower rosin you can
also there go for a little bit better
quality you lower the Micron I would say
um my average B is now 72 Micron and if
I say okay the the return the amount
isn't important but the quality must be
high and I want to show somebody really
good good good good flower rosin then I
would say I also can lower it till 45
Micron but for sure the
return drops yeah so and for hash I
would say there the thing is that the
thca get also into a liquid uh phase
over 70
celsus and with hash you also have the
possibility to press it through the
Micron sometimes with a lower
temperature like let's say 65 but also
for hash Rosen um I would say I go
somewhere
between 65 72 7 free so and then with a
25 micron double bag and
yeah the next question would be what is
the strains that you that you press
which which of those strains that you
are working on gives you the most or the
best uh do you have some favorites yeah
the problem is that I'm growing now
since the 1 of April again and I didn't
had um the time and I'm also not allowed
to have more than free free cannabis
plant so it's not possible for me to
build up a library at the moment um if
if there wouldn't be this barrier I the
first thing I would have done on the 1
of April to pop I would say all my seed
stash I was collecting over the last
over the last years and then making
instantly a pheno hunt before I start to
do other work but now I um I had really
to be quite selective so I popped some
beans from a bacho
rainbow and um from a Belgian breeder OG
n a j j yeah and um OG nut I I don't can
pronounce his new name I know that his
nickname usually is Tango on reverse but
um that's another story and his genetics
it's a
[Music]
um the buto rainbow I think it's um a
buto it's a lato the the melon and
crossed with a rainbow bels crossed
rainbow bels so and this strain was a
really good washer I had luck from the
first seats I popped I had like 5.5
nearly 6% return by washing it so
definitely good genetic and also by
pressing it to Rosen beautiful
plant that's considered like super
high-end yield for for watching yeah and
this is why I keep this plant you have
to imagine I'm allowed to grow free
plants and I'm growing just in flower
too and having the the gelato as a
mother for sure I already spread some
clones to some
friends this will be a genetic I think I
wh constantly working on the next I
wanted to share something with you guys
I got a new cut of Sour Diesel I don't
know how how good you can see that I see
the structure and I see the SD I see
immediately the sour
diesel yeah beautiful with the small
tailing kics coming out this is exactly
what reminds me the good old my God it
looks like a rock
man so my friend came
over with this and he said hey you know
I want you to check out this Sour Diesel
and before he opened up the jar I was
like oh my God that's
that's the best Sour Diesel I've seen in
decades and uh so I got the clones and
um I've been smoking it every day and
honestly I I you know as I talked in the
other shows I I use my vape pen a lot
but ever since I got this sour I've been
smoking like five joints a day so I
really need to get a ball Vape really
need a ball VAP because that way I would
be like I'd be like Vince smoking the
ball VAP uh ball Vape on the show and
instead I'm gonna smoke these joints and
I want to do uh free advertising I
really like this product and I I know
you you're not big into smoking but this
is called King Palms I know them and
it's made from a palm leaf and when I
first saw it I was like there's no way
I'm going to like it cuz the leaf is
it's kind of thick yeah you know and I'm
used to smoking with thin rice papers
but I'll tell you they smoke so
smooth and and cool you know cuz it
doesn't let allow it to burn so fast I
really love it now it's a little bit
embarrassing because you got to pack a
pre-roll and I have this little funnel
that I use to to make my joints which is
it's embarrassing when you're in public
and you're doing that and people like oh
this guy can't roll a joint I can
actually roll a joint but I really
prefer these King Palms I think they're
really nice and on top of everything get
them also in Germany um they're yeah
well known it's an elegant product you
know it's an elegant product so I'm
going to mute my microphone while I roll
my joints but in the meantime Vince
start telling us your weed Story start
telling us a little bit about the state
of cannabis in Germany and
Europe so you started the episode with
the legalization I can't call it a
legalization ation yeah um it's a
decriminalization so um
our in a lot of ways that's better in a
lot of ways that's better no no not not
I mean here in the US legalization has
destroyed the Cannabis Market um you
know making it not a
crime it brings in people and characters
yeah that's a much better angle I got
your your entire ball
Vapes so um yeah you you said at the
beginning uh how is going how is the
legalization going on on in Germany or
in Europe um I will talk today about
Germany uh it's not a legalization it's
a decriminalization but in a German way
so the law it's called Ki
cannabis c n g for cannabis gazettes
cannabis law in English and the the law
starts by the words cannabis is
forbidden but okay so it's just they
open they opened um or they
decriminalized
consumption consumption is now
legal and cannabis is still
illegal but under certain
circumstances it's allowed so the
circumstances are you are allowed to
grow free Plants but
you are just allowed to store at home 50
gs so how would you we know everybody
here in the podcast knows that just with
one
plant we will get illegal again so there
is like a um a tolerance like from 50 to
60 it's not um a felony you would say in
the states I think oh so it's not a big
crime but it's already a crime so
everybody who harvests more than 50 g is
still
illegal you are allowed to carry 25
grams on the street okay but what's with
the outdoor Growers who want to grow
completely holistic approach full cycle
with nature using the energy from the
Sun and store let's say a k at home for
the whole year the whole year to W to
wash some hash and all this stuff so
this is so what about hash is it the
same limit yeah so hash so extraction is
not allowed so now we have to be [ __ ]
German I don't call it extraction
Frenchy canoli also said it it's a
separation it's not an extraction we
don't pull out with a with a solvent
some out of the plant we separate the
tricomes with seing and water and cold a
technical process but that's called for
me separation now and this is allowed
but then we come to Rosen and there I
bent the rules to the maximum Okay Rosen
for me no solvent so what are we doing
we are doing a heat
sing We take something and we heat it up
which we before we can heat it up we
cool it down and now we heat it up and
we press it again through a through a
mesh and what we separate is the waxes
and some residues in the hash so we can
produce rosin and to be completely
German we don't call rosin an extract
it's a concentrate so because to
concentrate something is the different
defination uh than extracting something
and having an extract because the German
law had in mind when you read the law
and bro we have been reading the
law hundreds of time each
word and there is
um one important thing in the in the
part where where they talk about
extraction it's also written in the
sentence something like to extract te H
C or CBD so the the um the straight um
mono component this is extracting so
yeah and this is how we we ended up with
we can talk a little bit more about that
with a law which is
completely unlogical it's not it it's
not fought from the perspective of a
cannabis consumer and from a cannabis
grower
and yeah
um like yeah this is why we have to be
German and we don't call it an extract
it's a
concentrate but can you tell a little
bit about the you know how actually they
say I heard about it that it will be a a
few years of trying this law like zoa
they call zoa is the is the in English
you call it uh Vince can you tell a
little bit about how they actually
scheduled the the the law actually they
said it's going to be in three phases
like the phase one which already started
then uh it will because of five years of
trying the law and then they will
evaluate it and can you tell a little
bit about that that because I heard now
that they just don't want to go to step
two step three they just want to have
step one over you know
like okay
are we stressing you out asking you
these questions because you look like
your mind is about to explode yeah it is
you have to imagine um the last two and
a half years we have been um we have
been really in a law-giving process so
my daily thing was to read news and to
get headaches and
um
it's it's a little bit messy this law
okay so and what Sasha was asking is
they had three pillars they wanted to
enroll afterwards each pillar so the
first pillar is De uh um
decriminalization or legalization of
consumption allowing the home grow
allowing clubs cannabis Social Clubs
also there we can we'll talk a little
bit about later and by that you have you
are not allowed to share cannabis with
your friends okay okay imagine that we
are not allowed to share I am not
allowed to to to trade or to give you a
present
okay completely nonsense when you think
about cannabis culture yeah and the
beauty of sharing butts with other
Growers or to share a joint or a pipe or
a vape or something so like what about
somebody that can't grow because they're
sick don't have a space so this is
exactly the thing so if you are just
able to get weed legally by growing it
yourself or from a club in the First Act
of enrolling this law you have a problem
if you are not a
grower you can't get weed this way and
there are no clubs or now it's the first
Club opened but we will talk a little
bit deeper about the situation with the
clubs in a few minutes but there are no
clubs at the moment so it wasn't that
the clubs had time to pre start building
facilities growing so that from the
moment wheat became legal it was also
able to get it if you're another grower
in a club and to get member in the club
so because they also um said they
thought it will be quicker to enroll
enroll the clubs but it's such a huge
project to start canabus Social Club
where they cut the S out it's not
allowed to smoke together in the club so
it's not a so cannabis Social Club it's
a cannabis club yeah it's a at the end
it's a facility which grows the wheat
and people can pick it up and smoke it
alone at home and are not allowed to
share it okay
so and the second pillar of the law is
that they wanted to
start testing in different cities to
open dispensaries under a huge um
observation and
evaluation and um to see also how that
work and the third thing this is far far
away I would say 10 years in the future
maybe seven if it's quick but I said 10
years in the future that we will have
cannabis
dispensaries where you don't have to be
a member and where you can go
completely like in the states and some
states after work
bro what do you want yeah bring me some
sherbet okay I will pick up Sour Diesel
let's meet later so that's will that's
in the Far Far Future so what's going on
at the moment excuse me what's the
difference between a social club and a
dispensary I mean I understand a club
you have to be a member yeah but so what
I mean like that works in Spain
right uh the problem is in
Spain that the whole club thing also
have a lot of Black Market Vibe yeah um
if we talk true uh if we want to be uh
completely straight what's going on in
Spain they also are not allowed to earn
money so but they somehow get the money
out of the club for sure so the the
thing is that in Germany they wanted to
prevent this by giving the clubs just a
small scalability a club in
Germany is limited by 500 members so you
can't scale it up isn't it the same in
Spain no I don't know how but orad told
me that there was a limit okay a lot of
clubs give a [ __ ] well they don't give
well I mean there's one thing about
having rules and then there's another
thing by abiding the rules I mean you
said something that you're not allowed
to give your friends weed well if he's
your friend
you know he's not going to tell the
police right I mean is something you
know it's like you're not allowed to
give weed away to a cop okay right but
you know if I'm in German let me just
say this if I go to Germany I hope
you'll give me some weed bro like you
know I
mean I'm kidding but you know it's like
you just can't get caught we have to get
one step back why this law is possible
okay under German and European and
international law okay the the argument
the the the punchline is for this law we
want harm reduction for consumers and
Society okay then we have this is the
the the the um the spark for this law
okay but then we come immediately in
trouble
we can't legalize because in this moment
we get in
trouble in on the European level because
there's also contracts that all the
European States um uh will try to
suppress drug
trafficking and blah blah blah blah
blah and on the international law it's
the same yeah so there's the single
convention and all the stuff where if
you are deeper into legal ing movement
you know that countries who want to
legalize have to get out of the single
convention Canada did that Colombia uh
did that for coke leaves and then they
um they bring the law into into uh work
and then they get back into the contract
and nobody says something but Germany
wanted to be German so they asked the
European Parliament if it's if it's fine
to legalize completely and they didn't
get the right response and they saw okay
if we want to get this law with the with
the fort of harm reduction for society
and and
consumers we have to make it like a
trial because then Germany was able to
go to the European Union and say okay we
will bring this law and we will evaluate
after four or five years and our goal is
to test if we can reduce the harm by the
end consumers because of all the
ingredients hairspray and fertilizer
which are used to um to higher the the
the weight and there's so much stuff the
people here in Germany have been smoking
weed with hair hairspray and sand and
metals just to to have more weight on
the wage to get more money so it's
crazy and this will be evaluated so and
I'm sorry you
know uh I've been around for a minute
and I've heard about a bunch of stuff
being added to weed but never hairspray
no look in in
uh uh Sasha maybe you can help me V what
means Bly in English uh can you maybe
have a look because this is something
really important to to tell the people
so this was the reason why I started to
grow 15 years ago
when 20 50 years a 15 years ago it
started that they laced wheed with
hairspray they laced wheed with crushed
glass yeah they they crushed glass so so
dusty and then they covered the the
butts and it went till the thing that
the growers in the grow already were
putting stuff on the butts when they
were growing that it's inside the but
and that the weight of the whole Harvest
gets higher okay
and poisonous I'm sorry one more time le
le a whole city got got um poisoned by
Le in the
wheat that it was in liik yeah and and
there was there was coming in a batch of
wheat into the city under the black
market which was laced with lead so it's
[ __ ] toxic people were smoking it and
immediately the people went into the
hospital and this is the thing this is
what's going on or was going on in
Germany so and this is a good argument
for the politicians who wanted to
legalize hey we have to reduce the harm
we have to give the people access to
clean weed and this is what we are now
we we are it's not legal but it's
allowed the end consumer can grow it by
it by himself and now clubs are also
starting we have now 120 130
clubs in the making which will have each
500 members and we need like if we want
to supply whole Germany let's take
calculate the hom Growers out and we
just would use clubs we would need like
5,000 5,500 clubs yeah we have in
Germany we say between 4.5
till five six million consumers so and
the clubs is not like bro do you want to
open a club with me you will bring the
lights I will bring my tent no it's it's
more bro do we want or do we we have to
open a compy or a structure which is
under the same problems and hustle as
building up a real company because there
are so many rules to build a club in
Germany ah the 500 members are just
allowed each person to pick up 50 grams
a month and not in once because on the
street in Germany you are just allowed
to run around with 25g in your pocket so
you have to go twice to your Club to
pick up your maximum amount of 50g in a
month and you have to sign that you are
not in the other club so it's really the
that the viewer of the podcast and The
Listener understands what's going on the
government the politicians who made this
law they fought it through the
perspective of how can we reduce harm
responsible consumption
and to push back the black market so
from their P perspective it's okay if we
if we just allow them 50 GRS which is
from my perspective from a non-smoker
bro 50 gr it must be a junkie yeah we
know it's different but if you smoke
pure 50
g can happen and they I'm Smoke 50 GRS
in the next week so
and may probably more definitely more
yeah I'm smoking five joints of this a
day so I mean that's that's just a you
know couple of days and this is the
thing they wanted to to they thought if
we limit that and we do that and just
um then we will reduce the consumption
we know that a consumer consumes what he
consumes the most important thing is if
you if you allow the social thing
I think that in our community I just can
talk from what I am knowing surrounding
me if somebody has a problem with
cannabis and we think he should smoke
for a couple of weeks a little bit less
I can tell him that because for me it's
important and if he's a friend or
something like a friend this is nothing
which occurs when you are in a bar
drinking bro you maybe should drink a
little bit less you get drunken too
often but if I have a friend where I see
that he has some problems in his head
and I go to him and I tell him please
smoke less because I see him and if we
bring the consumption just that
everybody smokes by its own we
can't be together and uh have an eye on
our surrounding people so you know what
you're making me
realize you're making me realize I have
no friends
no one's no one's telling me to smoke
less you know I honestly I'm L you know
I I think about it
myself you know um and I'm pretty open
with the fact that I'm abusing
cannabis I know I am now it's like I
just love it so much and always want to
be with it you know but I know it's it's
abuse you like because I I do
it like I don't have to have re to often
huh maybe a little bit too often or
maybe sometimes you smoke a joint
because you love it so much even if
you're still high bro that's normal but
the thing is what I say if but that's
abuse right it
depends it depends so the thing is that
in in my friend Circle it was normal
that when we saw that
somebody wasn't on the line in his
life we as a friend we talk to each
other and sometimes it was also bro
maybe you should stop smoking for a few
weeks or lower it and I know that's
weird from our community it's not in
other countries that I have seen that
because I'm German I'm living here I
live here in the Cannabis culture but um
and that's something that kids will hear
from their parents yeah and look you
know but when when legalization was on
the horizon I realized that
something that there will come some
responsibility also with the
reach um content creators have and I was
quite lucky that I stopped combustion
it's not that I completely stopped I
also smoked joints but not at home
anymore like I said in the first episode
and by that I don't have to tell the
people what to do or not I I'm just as a
role model and they talk to me also in
streams and everything and then I just
give them an inspiration to try a
different way consuming cannabis and it
works and um for me man I have periods
uh like you yeah but it's important also
to have an eye on your buddies when they
get a problem with it so I say if you
are settled in life everything runs
well it's your amount of cannabis you
need or you laugh to consume so go for
it
yeah yeah you know
um I have a quick change the subject
moment okay and then I want to get back
to it um do you know how many of your
viewers or listeners are from outside of
Germany or Europe like how many people
are listening to your
podcasts um in the US is what I want to
know and before we go any further I
don't know that I properly introduced
Vince because he was on our last show
but you know Vince
is he's got a lot more experience doing
this podcasting than I do and he um he's
influencing a lot of people in Europe
and Germany he
has your YouTube channel is Vince and
weed is that correct yes and then you're
going to have to remind me I know it's
the same on Instagram but with some
funny letters to yeah not get blocked uh
w33d so instead of the E it's
33 Vince
w33d on Instagram thank you very much so
no
because one thing I love about doing
this show
is people are inspiring me and and you
are like I I
think you know what you
do that's exactly what I want to do you
know I just wna I just want to be real
you know what I mean I just want to tell
people how I feel and and be real and
you are very genuine you know and also
you're not like you have to do it my way
it's more like look you know maybe you
should consider not smoking so much weed
next week it's such a it's such a
delicate approach that honestly you
don't expect from Germans you know in
the US look um I would say something
after this vape and dab because this is
a beauty of so here's some
Rosen Rosen weed double
dagger so
um the thing is really that
um when I gave myself the name Vincent
wheed um I did it because I have also
like like a code with my
Community 24/7 for
2710 yeah I have 247 cannabis and
cannabis concentrates in my
head and then when I told the story a
little bit in the last podcast so if you
want to have it a little bit deep deeper
list in the first episode I I am living
cannabis or like a legal person also
years before legal ization in Germany
and I stand for cannabis and then when
legalization came my work
load quad tripled yeah it it went
through the roof and I'm I I was
consuming so much cannabis that I
couldn't form on the level I needed and
I went straight into a small cannabis
midlife crisis
I was feeling the first time in my life
that at the moment I'm smoking
definitely too much was like 100 grams a
month with a little bit side
extracts
and I wasn't functioning on point with
all the um all the
responsibility business second company
family
um all the stuff
and then I had the problem that okay I
can't lower my wheat consumption or stop
I'm Vincent wheat yeah this was my inner
inner dialogue I thought bro what's
going on wheat isn't good for you at the
moment and I think you have to stop weed
smoking weed and what will the people
say you you are
cannabis and then I said okay I have to
take a decision I don't feel well so I
have to lower my weak
consumption and I took the decision to
communicate that straight with my
community and what came out of that this
is the only moment I call myself an
influencer when I really Influence
People For A Better
Living this is where I call myself like
that the community feedback was
outstanding people said bro it's exactly
what I'm in at the moment and good that
you say that I will do the same and then
two three four five weeks later in my
streams I stream really regularly with
my community I'm really close to
them the feedback came in bro this was
the best thing I got a little bit
distance I didn't stop but I lowered and
my life is better and I see things from
another perspective and I used this
moment to stop combusting and all this
and the feedback was really was feeling
on the other side of the of the of the
monitor in the Stream that there have
been people affected positive by being
completely truthful to myself and don't
hiding it I I'm I'm also truthful now I
thought okay maybe I just will do I will
tell them that I smoke and show it and
but that's not me I'm now seven years in
social media and I never changed
something for it for what I don't tell
everything no private is private but I
am the person I am yeah if you like me
you like me if you don't like me okay
that's totally fine yeah I kind of think
people that don't like you must be dicks
no bro I'm saying this as an outsider
yeah I also have
personality and sometimes it doesn't fit
and that's fine I also had to learn that
my ego died so many times I'm surprised
anyone likes me to be honest with you
cuz I being from New
York I just feel like most people in the
world would find that really offensive
the way New Yorkers act and talk even
though I'm far what the typical New
Yorker attitude that you think I can I
can sum it up pretty easily this is what
I think of a New Yorker when you live in
New York City you have to be prepared to
walk down the street somebody bump into
you and just not give a
[ __ ] because you're going to bump into
so many people that if you have to stop
and say I'm sorry or excuse
me it's a major life sucker it takes
years off it's just it's just so common
you know you are in a different city and
you bump some in somebody and you don't
and you give a [ __ ] and this person get
offended because you didn't uh I mean I
can't even imagine anywhere else in the
world where that be acceptable you know
like if you bump into somebody and you
say excuse me it's all good yeah if you
bump into somebody and just keep walking
like nothing ever happened you're going
to get hit from the back of the head or
something you know it's just like that's
even more rude than bumping into someone
is just not giving a [ __ ] yeah you know
um I have family in New
York but besides I also have family in
New York yeah so I never really want to
go back except to see family okay and
pizza the pizza's good yeah I I I I am
really this is on my list to visit New
York again I was maybe 15 20 years the
last time
there I you know I want to get back to
the legalization stuff please but I at
the same point I want to make sure we
have enough time for these stories too
because it's it's one thing to
tell about you know what the state of
cannabis is in
Germany which we we do want to know and
it's another thing to get to know who
Vincent weed is and for me that's just
far more interesting so I want to make
sure that we spend a little time doing
both let me think about what is
definitely look let me think about
what's definitely important that the
listener of your show should know about
German legalization
what's going
on first of all where my heart is
pumping because it's so beautiful to
see the hom
Growers they are pushing out such a
beautiful
quality
immediately you saw the
culture getting through the surface yeah
and you like I said last time everywhere
you see sashes
people sharing having a great time and
living the first time this feeling I
don't have to
hide
beautiful and I we have a situation at
the moment where the people are afraid
that they will take that again away from
us because the the government Who
legalized they had huge problems we have
problems in the world and these problems
uh resulted in that they didn't finish
their um their four years of how you
call it the leg um legislation yeah so
we have now new elections a little bit
earlier and we have the problem here
also in Europe that
the the politic political landscape
became
quite extreme in many
ways
and we have the situation in Germany
that we see a
shift to and I don't want to go deeper
into it to more
conservative
parties and this conservative
parties they say we want to they really
say that we want to uh re re uh how do
you call it um rewind no um to make it
backwards how you say that in English to
undo yeah they want to to uh to to take
away the legalization again or the
decriminalization how you say that in
English in if logical
sentence just
did
okay so and the thing
is I don't think that it's so easy
because you have to think about also if
and this is the beauty of uh democracy
4.5 million people in a state of 85
million is what per definition a
minority the Cannabis consumers in
Germany are a minority but they became a
huge law yeah it was a huge work for the
politicians to implement this law okay
and this is why democracy Works a
minority the Cannabis consumers got
their legalization to consume beautiful
but
now um with the new
elections the people think that the
conservative parties will take it away
and I tell them
look they also conservative people are
smoking wheat and
when you will take the law away you will
criminalize instantly 4.5 Millions oh
people again
yeah and I don't think that this will
work with Society because now they saw
that this that my neighbor where it was
smelling like weed he and now he's legal
and he's not becoming a crazy person by
smoking weed now he's a criminal again I
think this will be a for also with a lot
of people which don't consume
cannabis and also to take a law
away isn't that easy so we will get into
rough water in the next
years and we don't will get a
Improvement of
our unfinished cannabis law so what will
be my perspective for the next years we
will fight in the
new room we got we can we just will be
able to work with this law and this is
it so this is everything so now uh okay
so you are back again I've been here the
whole time okay I said I said that I
heard we will have to work with this law
for the next years let's say five 7 10
and now it will be really a fight
between the conservative and the
Cannabis Community how to
to interpret to interpret oh sometimes
my English to um see how the words we
have to um bro how can we say that in
English
um
interpr how we see the written law yeah
inter do we have to to push the
boundaries a little bit more to the left
EXA the example is Hash an extraction or
is it a separation this will be stuff we
will fight in front of the court yeah I
TR listen to my words we will fight for
so many things there will PE will be
people sharing wheat and we will have to
fight that this will become legal yeah
we will have to keep fighting that hash
not that hash but that Rosen stays legal
it's not clear that it stays legal we
have to fight for it yeah with
arguments it will be crazy but yeah this
is a little bit the situation I don't
think that we will get um taking away
this decriminalization but I don't
believe that we will have improvements
in the next year so we have to deal with
that you know when legalization happened
here or even prior to legalization when
there was the medical
marijuana there was silly rules as well
and you know it it took time for for
things to change so I think the fact
that they're being deliberate like the
way you described it at the beginning
that they're really trying to think
things through and and reflect on what's
going on sounds positive at least um the
rate of things happening is obviously
painfully slow and I think the the
biggest frustration is like the EB and
flow of what the politics wants for it
you know like here in the US once the
door is open it's so wide open there's a
rush of people running through there you
can't close it and to me
it's it's hard to understand how a law
could change so dramatically so quickly
back and forth you know it's like that
doesn't make any sense it's not
progress no and also in a in a sorry for
the listeners in other countries but in
uh working democracy it's
not that easy till close to unpossible
to
re purpose a new law again backwards
instantly yeah we don't have this
institutional rights which where some
where a single person gets so much power
to go there and say no that's not
reality anymore
sorry and um yeah I'm really
uh fighting for democracy and this is
why I'm a little bit relaxed because I
know this is still working here in
Germany yeah so I mean what's the deal
with you know in the US what drives this
entire thing through
legalization is money and the government
makes money
so arent don't they want to get there
taste and once they get their taste
they're going to want to be drinking
like you know the gluttonous pigs that
they are do you know that we used the
money because look I studied economics
and I studied economics because I wanted
a long time ago become a politician yeah
and I understood that we don't need we
don't need uh we need everybody in the
polit in the political uh area but but
um we also need people who understand
economics laws Society everything yeah
so and I said not that much people
understand the economy and the economy
is the most influential part for the
politics
and it's by that I was saying all the
time we have to use the argument earning
money for the
government to our um benefit and there
was a really important step in the
German legalized movement where the deaa
the German hemp
[Music]
um group it it's a company but they make
lobbying for cannabis yeah and
they used
money they raised to pay uh how can you
say that in English to pay um a
consultant from the German government an
expert in economics yeah who was already
have been used the last years by the
German government they raised money they
went with this money to this expert who
is Consulting the German government and
said to them please make a study how
much money Germany would make when we
legalized so this is a trick Why by
using an expert the German government
was using already by themselves for
other topics they say okay he's an
expert now because he comes with a new
topic cannabis we can't uh tell um say
no now you are not an expert anymore and
he made a study that if we legalize I
don't have the numbers in my mind at the
moment that we will save like 4.5
billion a year with all the effects of
tax um lowered um uh police work less
work in the court less people in prison
and all these effects and this was an
important thing also to show the people
who maybe haven't been convinced by
social Improvement of Il
legalization by money Improvement for
the
government you the weapons from the
government against them
yeah yeah I
mean I'm pretty confident that that's
the way it works in all countries that
have it you know yeah the government
makes money then they're interested if
they're if they're not making money you
know they're getting money from the
alcohol lobbies here in the US you know
I mean and
pharmaceuticals so the the only reason
why you know this this is allowed is and
you know conservatives like money too
yeah but I have to to
highlight a few politicians the names
are Bart
binard
um kmen veger and Durk Heiden
blute this three politicians and also
there are more but this have been the
visible
politicians which did it really from
their
from their bottom of their heart because
they understood that there are
people becoming criminals with no reason
and there have been also some
politicians who fighted for our movement
because they they they are no consumers
I think
Oh I thought I switched it off I'm so
sorry no worries you have crickets yeah
these politicians really fighted for
cannabis without the money in their mind
they did it because they believed that
we really have to reach the point of
harm reduction for
society I mean that's great and I I
believe you know obviously they should
be more of those but it's just way
easier to make the progress that we want
to make when they have you know
government has the financial incentives
you know yeah but unfort true it's uh
this is something this is why I'm a
little bit tired at the moment when you
started to talk about the political and
legalization part I'm tired yeah and I
have so much respect for people who are
fighting since decades for this plan
because I would say I'm fighting 10
years with
a a lot of investment of my energy and
time and it's so drowning energy
drowning and it's depressing to to to
read all the time political stuff
because it makes something with your
mind yeah um sometimes I I also prefer
not to know so much about the whole
thing I think some joints would be a
little bit more relaxing and but yeah
sometimes they have to use cannabis to
get through all this [ __ ] from
politics but actually WIS I think it is
very depending on the manipulation
aspect of politicians in this moments
right now because you know uh as you
said before it is very much impossible
to change the law back you know in a
fast way yeah that is impossible the
next thing I would say is civil
disobedience
that that will happen if this is going
to be the case it will be much bigger
problem for the government which they
know they're just playing around with
with this is always politics does it all
the time they are like feeling time or
filling time with manipulation all the
time lying a lot and I think cannabis
will the green wall will fall in Europe
yeah um and this there are so many
connected effects also the states it's
crazy I can remember when we had like
two states in the in in the US yeah and
now you look on the map where have we
come where have we come today that it's
nearly 5050 or a little bit more 52% of
the states I don't know which is the
situation now in America but and also in
Europe your home country is also
thinking about to change something you
said okay you are waiting that something
happens but it's a it's such a
small
development and changing the society and
it's slowly step by step we never we
never can start to run even if we want
it's impossible it's really slowly steps
then the grandma see that their nephew
doesn't get
Crazy by smoking a joint on the on the
family party and then my parents the
same at the beginning 25 years ago they
thought I will ruin my life and they
said to friends oh my son is smoking
weed and I am so afraid and today it's
yeah my son is a successful family
father working his ass off and yeah and
he doesn't have a problem with cannabis
and it's working so it it's
went through the friend circle of my
parents and it changed here and there
opinions also from non-cannabis users
and this is what we need and slowly
slowly I'm positive all the time also if
it's
hard my opinion also is that uh other uh
countries in Europe will follow German
model you know they will this there is
no way back uh and after that will
happen uh some years will take and
Germany will see it and they cannot they
will have to Pro do the progress you
know and also the data will come out now
the data that CRI the criminality
dropped that there is a lot how much
money was was saved by not that the
police does not do this rates anymore
you know like this data will come now
the politicians can lie on TV about it
that it's not like that but when when
when real experts will come out with
this data it will be over they cannot
you know they will not lie more about it
because they can't then you know but we
are waiting for for those people you
know I mean don't trust any statistic
you didn't uh
[Laughter]
faked yeah but
yeah let's see and I really can invite
you to come to Germany um it's beautiful
to to see what's going on here with the
cult
um there is in the summer the biggest
Cannabis Expo it's called Mary Jane and
so many satellite events so many
sessions
cups venues and you really you I think I
I don't know how is it in in states
where it's now legal since
years but in Germany the people are
starving to live this culture
together it's
beautiful Sasha is trying to convince me
to go it's not very hard I just got to
figure out how
to how to pull it
off yeah bro I'd love to go so yeah yeah
yeah and good Growers and also the
extraction um the the concentration
artists to be
German not the extraction artist um it's
crazy what's going on the quality of
Rock skyrocketed in the last N9
months from really a lot of flower rosin
on the homeg grower level now bro now I
wash my Harvest or I wash a whole plant
and I go for it it's
crazy beautiful to to watch the
people Master the
craft do you know some people that are
doing the dryy sifting also not only the
do you know some people that do the dry
sifting because it's a little bit
different right and what are they using
you
know it's another art
yeah the people are experimenting a lot
and I think you can expect a lot of
innovation from the Germans in the
upcoming years the same would
have happened in all the other legal
states in in the US but um the German
engineer in mindset is there trust me
they are working already their ass off
to bring a lot of helpful devices and
Innovation to the Cannabis
Market can you tell a little bit about
the Barcelona fair you you go to span
year I I know that because I follow you
also last year I saw live from you was
stalking him and you just admitted it I
know I he's a he's a personality kind of
man is like I of course uh he had he has
life appearances during spab you know
and I'm also there you know I sometimes
I look out for these kind of people to
just to see we yeah this is this is what
the Cannabis Community is all about to
connect to learn and exchange with each
other and um the spenibus is a
beautiful beautiful event um so the last
years Spain was a little bit ahead of
Germany with the Cannabis
situation and by that the spenibus which
is every year in the middle of March was
the the come together for the whole
European cannabis scene Market culture
and in the last years the Americans
because they companies from the states
are also interested in the European
market they came and more companies from
the states came and more so it was
really the perfect Cannabis Expo week
because in Barcelona a beautiful city
with good food you can pay H you can
afford and in March the first warm sun
sun comes out in Europe and then you
have all the kind of a social clubs like
400 in the whole city and you you have a
Vibe every everywhere a little bit High
everywhere you see cannabis related
people you go to so many events you
enjoy the beach you smoke good and you
go to an
expo and now we get also our Mary Jane
and Germany quite big and the companies
which went also to the spend are now
coming to Germany by that something
changed now for me for business the
German Mary Jane is better because it's
my home town I would say or it's a how
you say in football it's uh if you play
yeah home game and by that I will go
this year to the spenibus and to enjoy
more the vibe and not going to the Expo
free days
and going there more a little bit as a
tourist it's a beautiful thing and yeah
one thing you didn't mention about um
Barcelona is the people it's beautiful
so you know it's so warm yeah you know
like I I love that place when I went to
Barcelona I was like this might be the
only city in the world that I could live
in you know like I I don't live in the
city right now yeah and Barcelona you
know I don't want to live in New York La
London you know Berlin I don't I don't
want to live in a big but Barcelona is a
special City it's and I think the
biggest thing for me is the people there
are pretty awesome you know you you meet
family not friends you know you're like
oh my God it's like these people of my
family forever and yeah I I definitely
miss everybody also if it's for a trip
to Europe visit
Barcelona you will fall in love for me
definitely my number one city in Europe
and after that comes
Berlin so really come to Germany also in
June June is our biggest Expo in Berlin
if somebody wants to experience the
German cannabis culture it's the best
moment to come to the Mary Jane so and
go ahead Sasha I think you
muted I wanted to ask you uh me as non-
German if I come to Germany and smoke
weed is is it still I mean it's just for
Germans to have 25 GS with you or also
me as a Slovenian hobit coming to your
place and having I mean that's you know
it's it would be unconstitutional I
think to not to just have Germans yeah
no no you are legal as a human being
yeah but the the thing is if you come to
Germany as a tourist and you have weed
in your pocket and the police asks you
where you got it from the best thing is
yeah that that's the problem because
they can say okay you are not living in
Germany you haven't been growing it here
you are not allowed to be a club member
in Germany so you board it on the black
market which is still
illegal but to be true nothing will
happen uh
so yeah you can
smoke and if the police in the look in
in Berlin nothing will happen nothing in
the in in the south in Munich maybe but
it's more to to bully you because they
don't will send something to your
country's government that you have been
consuming cannabis there blah blah
blah so and one more thing I wanted to
ask you that I've been contacted by a
fair in Germany for for next year um if
I want to participate on the fair as a
producer of you know as a cannabis shop
and I said to them I'm a producer of
clones so how about this I I wanted to
ask them if I can drive with like
thousand clones in my van to Germany
with with a PL pled passport that I have
uh and they did not know me giving an
answer you know they they they it was
like tricky because if I go through
bararia you know with the van with with
thousand clones in the back you know now
we come again to the German stupid
cannabis not we don't want to go too
deep now no no just the
surface the definition of a cannabis
plant is a
plant with
pistols in
flower or with sex expression in flower
and we thought that a
cutting or a clone is by this definition
not a cannabis plant just cannabis
plants
are allowed in a circum way but not
legal but seeds and cuttings should be
legal by the German new law the problem
is in the moment you put the cutting
into soil even if it's just such a small
container we still thought that we could
win the argument that it's not a
cannabis plant because it's not
flowering and it's
small but the BS
is that a lot of people got raided at
home and they had cuttings in small
container and the the the court said
yeah it's a cannabis plant and now we
are stucking in the fight with arguments
which the problem is we can't fight as a
community on one point focusing our
energy this fight is f um is f fight by
each individual which got in
problems it's so the to answer your
question to come to Germany with 3,000
plants in small containers of soil would
be
illegal if you bring them in rock
wool
maybe then the thing is if it's legal in
your stay in your country where you're
coming from you don't have to expect any
persecution even if you get something in
Germany
so yeah it's the question if you go with
rock wool just
rooted gray
area but they try to take it away from
us and and another question is which
where is following Li this how is it
possible that I as a non-german citizen
could sell clones in Germany but you as
Germans cannot you know what I mean yeah
because because when if I want to first
of all if the judge says also a small
plant in the smallest possible container
with soil is a plant we have a
problem and then is the other problem if
if if the judge says okay I get your
argumentation that your plans are still
in rock wo just rooted let's call it a
cutting that's legal but where did you
cut that from ah you have a mother plant
yeah it's a old plant in a big pot it's
huge and even if oh I see preflower
sorry it's
illegal but I thought you were allowed
to have a few I thought you were allowed
to have three three but not four as a
private person at home not in your
company facility for production and
economical purpose bro it's [ __ ]
Germany and it's ridiculous because
others other countries can sell clones
to your country but you as German
citizens are not allowed to do it I me
that's it's in Europe we have a law if
something is legal in other countries of
Europe it should be legal to transport
through whole Europe but with cannabis
it's
different what can I say
say
prohibition yes Maria yeah and I don't
think we spoke about this what's the
penalties so like you know as far as if
you have more than that 50 some odd
grams I think you said a little bit more
it's not a big deal but you know it
starts slow and it increases yeah
um like you there are different type of
penalties also for the clubs can get
penalties if they don't follow the rules
and it's um I would say
if if you really stay between the 50 and
60 G it's
more
and when you are above 60
G the law still will
try to [ __ ] you so
and there are Judges who got it and say
no I don't take the case yeah we let it
fall it's fine but this is nothing you
can rely on so it's illegal still yeah
so this is the situation we are living
in so the penalty is vague so for
instance if you were growing five or six
plants instead of the three plants that
you're
allow you don't really know what you'd
be facing for penalties it depends on
what judge you appear in front
of maybe a
fine
€700 something isn't that worth is yeah
isn't that worth
it um no because they have they have a
sneaky
way to fist
you in the moment you get in front of
the court first of all they [ __ ] you
they let you pay the fine but then they
come from the back door with the [ __ ]
driver
license and they take your driver
license away because they make a test
and then you have um more than the
allowed amount in your blood because
it's the level is really low and then
they say okay yeah just €700 everything
is fine but um you a cannabis consumer
ah yeah um we we think you are not
capable of differentiate between driving
sober or driving high and yeah um prove
us that you are capable
of um separating that and that you are a
responsible consumer and they take your
license away and the whole process uh is
not just the fact that you are not able
to drive to work or to um drive your
kids to sport or to make the grocer
grocery then also it cost you
between let's say three till sometimes 6
7,000 to make tests to pay the lawyer
all this
BS
so yeah this is still the problem more
it's more than the 700 bucks yeah it's
more than the 7even it if if you don't
have a driving license it's just a just
that alone but you can understand that
it's but in Germany you're allowed to go
to October Fest all weekend long and
then Monday get on the autobound when
when they when they stop you and you
have 100 bottles of vodka in the
trunk they don't assume that you have a
alcol problem if you don't smell you can
say it's for the party I um I buy it for
the next three years and nobody will
question that in the moment you oh
man yeah uh in the moment in the moment
you have a little bit too much
cannabis you are a criminal again and
yeah by the way my wife is waiting for
dinner this is now my wife called me oh
well we let you go to dinner hey yeah we
could talk for hours and I hope we can
again I hope we can talk for hours again
definitely do it again and then talk a
little bit more about genetics growing
smoking dabbing all this
stuff what we love and this is the the
the reason why we do all and get all
through this pain of legalizing movement
and everything else can you can you put
me through one more like I just want to
go back and ask the one question and
then I'll let you go you never answered
how much of your audience is from the
US uh not
um on YouTube not really that much maybe
you have
some some people living in the states
they all in it's all in German all in
German look I took a decision seven
years ago when I started YouTube I
YouTube wasn't that what it is today but
I asked the question ah on English the
English Community has already so
much and for sure it was okay if I do it
in English which isn't perfect
by the way um I will compete with the
hall English creators and I will miss
out my local community so the decision
was quite fast set German lower reach
internationally definitely but serving
my
community and it was the best decision
of my life so definitely to make it in
German yeah well I I won't argue with
the second half of what you said about
you know giving to your community doing
it for your community and
also the time that it would take to do
it you know in other language I just
feel that um I'm enjoying talking with
you and hearing what you have to say so
I think other people would too and the
reach is important not like for a you
know Financial response but
just so earlier you said something and
I'm going to end the show with this you
said that there was one time that you
were an actual
influencer and I'm going to say what I
said the last time is that you inspired
people because when you influence
something that's just like a minor push
it's temporary but when you inspire
people that's something that's
longterm you know
and you know I'm a podcaster in the US
would I see you as competition here no
never I would see you as inspiring no
okay and so and
so personally want to see you do more in
English Okay because I think you I think
it's important to you know you have a
valid perspective to give to people so
selfishly I'd like to see you dedic
dedicate a little bit more of your time
to English and if you want to be you
know if you wanted to be on our show
that would be great but you know I like
I said I'm enjoying listening to you I
appreciate you coming on I hope we can
schedule it again real soon because I
don't feel like we ever come close to
finish you know it's like when you're
just with friends the conversation
doesn't end right every weekend we get
together and we just talk again and so
yeah I'm I'm super grateful that we got
to spend this time with you Vincent and
you inspired me about a few
things thank you really also for the
kind words yeah really let's come again
together and then go really into the
childish passion which is burning all
the time in our hearts it was really um
yeah today was to be true really for me
it's hard I had the moment I stay away
from politics and I I have to a little
bit it's a responsibility but I'm
focusing on the garden and other
projects that will come big project well
we we did our uh episode on the politics
we don't have to do that again right
yeah let's do we got it out of the way
TP talk next time yeah we'll talk TPS
[Music]