this is a production of Cornell
University I did a a sabatical two years
ago I think three years ago I forgot
already in New Haven and then we have
this big do you think we can turn the
the first row of lights
please we have this uh bigest snow storm
I think after the hurricane sanding and
and I spent about three days trying to
get out of my house I did I did my PhD
in Florida and I thought I knew what
Winters were about and then I go to New
England I spent one very long long
winter there and then I I sent these
photos to camil and Monica and they told
me no that happen in in itaka every
single day for a few
months so I learned really that I love
the tropics that's what I
now if you are a plant biologist
probably I don't need to tell you but if
you are a geologist the diversity in the
Tropic sounds really amazing so one
Hector in Ecuador has most more species
of trees than the entire Continental USA
so it's a huge latitudinal gradient in
diversity from the tropics to to
temperate latitudes and and St has been
in Panama for almost 100 years last year
we missan put a 100 Years of research in
the tropics because we all there are
very interesting in understanding why
there are so many species in the tropics
and you have to answer that question
from many different point of view
because it's not that an easy question
to answer but first let's say what is a
tropical neotropical rainforce so what
during the next 50 minutes is what I I
will Define as a as a tropical
rainforest it's a part combination of
climactic parameters floristic
composition Forest structure and plant
fomy that's what I'm referring to a
neotropical rainforest so a climate if
the Minal precipitation is about 1.8 m a
year so it's rains a lot the Minal
temperature is about 18 degrees celus
the floristics if the if the the forest
dominate abundance and diversity by
certain families plant families like Fai
moresi and on AC for B
AC also by the forest structure that the
the forest is multi-stratified so you
have several layers of the forest and
also that the top layer that is called
the canopy is
closed and is dominated by anges by
flower imp plants by close means that if
you get this photo was taken from a
canopy crane something we have a St in
Panama is like a capsule that you can go
and see the forest from above that that
is something that is very hard to see
from the ground when you go and and see
the forest from above you realize that
every single space in this canopy is
covered with a leaf because most of the
Light in the Forest is trapped within
the few meters so the trees they really
need to to reach the canopy they want to
do a lot of photosynthesis and also
plant physynergy
without edges and also has a drip de so
when I see this characteristics is what
I will call an neotropical
rainforest now if you want to track
vegetation over time well probably all
your data will come from Continental
sequences and having a tool to be able
to date the Continental rocks is very
important otherwise you always be lost
in time and you don't have for aifer or
anop Plum to do that
to do that we we to solve that problem
we use pinology this is a real example
of a well drill by a an oil company in
Colombia just before I joined this
company like 13 years ago just after I
finished my PhD I start working for this
oil company and and this is a
cross-section of the food Hills in
Colombia and this is the well they drill
and as you can see here in the first
track they did they drill from here here
to here over our almost three months
they spent $20 million from here to here
and as you can see they were parallel to
the same bed so they thought they were
going across the strata but they were
really along the same time profile
because they didn't have a tool to
during the drilling to say well we are
stuck in time we need to change the
direction of the of the drilling bit so
I joined this company and over many
years we use pollen as a tool to solve
this problem and in the tropics penology
has been used for almost 60 years
because plan evolution is a fantastic
tool to track time over time so we
develop some that is called a
biographics on Asia so we went to many
different sites in Colombia Venezuela
and Ecuador and we count a lot of pollen
grains almost a million polling grain so
you you realize I really love polling
grain so many size many different
samples
and based on all this information we
develop a biographic sonation that that
is basically a hypothesis on plan
Evolution on when a particular species
originate when that particular species
go extinct and so forance this is an
example of one of the of the events in
this zonation and this is the extension
of this particular species tell us that
we are in 61.9 million years the
advantage of working with old companies
is that every time you do this bio
sonation you have you are testing that
hypothesis in the next drilling rig and
if you do a mistake and you tell them
that you are in 65 and you are in 61 and
they end in a different rock you know
right away that your hypothesis was not
correct and you will have to find a new
job and we develop a a method called
maximum we use a maximum likelihood
approach to assess the probability of a
given of assigning an age to Any Given
sample so in instead of saying oh this
rock is a late myosin we say we use a
pro bar and it will tell us the
confidence we are on any given age for
every particular sample so for instance
this sample here taken at 400 m has a
probability of having this age uh with
this probity so we are doing that for
every sample we date in our
analysis now you also have to consider
climate now this idea that the tropical
La tropical plants need live very close
to the optimal
temperature has been really rooted in in
the literature for many years and it's
very easy to understand why you will say
something like that so in this graphic
we have me anual temperature here and
here me anual precipitation and every of
these dots represent a floristic plot
within the tropical belt and as you can
see here you by changing the
precipitation you can go from a tropical
rainforest here in red to a dry forest
in blue to a a savannah a grassland or
to a desert here in green but also you
notice that you don't find almost any
tropical forest no matter what you where
you are above 28° C so you may think
well that's that's the the
the optimal for tropical plants today
however if
you search the temperatures of the
tropical land within the tropics
represented here by this red line you
will realize that there is not really a
place within the tropical belt that has
a minimal temperature above 28 28 point
degre celsus so perhaps plant tropical
plants cannot leave Beyond 28 because
there are not really many places in the
tropics today with a temperature higher
of 28° C now if you are a geologist
probably you know this have seen
this cure many times and it represent
the proxy for the temperature of the
botton of the ocean by measure the Delta
o of foraminifer ventic foraminifer
going back from Zer to 120 million years
and as you and this is a very good proxy
for Global temperature of the bottom of
the ocean that could be correlated to
the ambient temperature of the planet
and when you compare today with most of
the the the last 120 million years we
realized that being in a cool planet is
a very rare compared to most of the the
over the past 200 million years so most
of the time the planet has been much
warmer than today now for years we have
this dichotomy we thought well perhaps
the tropics are very stable and the
Tropics work like a thermostat so no
matter if the global planet is warming
or cooling the the the temperature in
the tropics will be always stable so
will will something like that you the
poles get warmer or cooler but the
tropics are always static and because
it's very stable climate that the reason
we have so many species there now over
the past 10 years we have been using
different techniques to assess the
temperature of the tropics during past
Global warmings and as you can see here
we are using plants Tex
86 biomarket in a in a molecule in the
ocean isotop on foraminifera one of
these techniques for instance this this
snake body Ling of a of a snake we that
is called tanon that we found in the
seron formation about 60 million years
old in the northern part of Colombia
just for comparison this this is a a mod
boa of 4 M 4 M long so this Titan was
about 45 to 50 ft long about 1 meter in
diameter and weigh about a ton and was
very common in the paleos of the
tropical forest of Colombia and today if
you if you measure the how long a snake
is versus where do they live because
they cannot control the inter temper
internal temperature you will realize
that there's a very good correlation
between the land of the snake and the
and the minol temperature of a place and
when we apply that to the F record we
realized that the tropics were much
warmer before than they are now we did
this compilation of all the empirical
data we have on tropical temperature for
the past 120 million years about 9 5,000
like 6,000 data points across the entire
geological span from 25 to today and you
will see that in the mid Cretaceous the
and this is just for the tropical Bel
the temperature the minol temperature
were about 7° C warmer than today during
the early Soso in mostly during the
early eosin the temperature was about 4
point de C warmer than today so the
graphic in the tropical belt will be
will look like that the temperature in
the Tropic has been warmer than today
and probably you already know that the
CO2 has been also much higher than it is
now the last time we have such a low
levels of CO2 you will have to go back
to the Carboniferous and so CO2 has been
the constant rather than high CO2 has
been a constant on the planet now let's
see the tropical fossil
record now we are going to divide this
the block that follows in two different
settings one the creation and other
Theos because the floras in the tropical
be are really fundamentally different
and so I call the crasus a non anos
sperm Tropical
World we know from the Poland record
that the oldest angiosperm don't have
any geographical pattern so we find them
both in high latitudes mid latitudes and
low latitude we still don't know really
where the all this angiosperm the the
the belt the latitudinal Bel that the
oldest SP originate one of the oldest
fossils are very tiny plant plants like
AR fructus fructus from
China now this paper was published about
20 years ago by liard and Peter K and he
compiled all the literature we have
about the all the plants within the
cretes and he produced this graphic that
has been used many many times showing
how the angel spurn were very few at the
beginning of the Cretaceous and by the
end of the aous the anges Dominate the
Flores you can and if you see all the
data points he used for analysis you
will realize that in the trop this is
age and this is Paleo latitude of microf
floras and and poen Flores that most of
the data he used came from tempered
regions he didn't have at this time any
any publ locality within the tropics for
the entire cretes and most of the
samples for the polling were done for by
a strateg graphy always just focusing a
few markers that were used by all
companies especially in Nigeria and
Brazil now when you look at the philogen
so plant Banis they take all the plants
they analyze DNA and produce these
philogen that where you express the
relationship on taxa many of the
philologist and the new philologist are
confirming this that most of the orders
of the angiosperm were evolved
by the senan about 100 million years 90
to 100 million years ago as as you can
see
here now this led us to publish this
paper 10 years ago with Chuck Davis from
University of Harvard saying well we we
we have all these families and orders
back in the M cretes therefore you will
expect to find a a mod tropical
rainforest tropical rainforest similar
to what we call today a tropical
rainforest back in the mid Cretaceous
and we published this paper in American
naturalist but at this time I have very
little record empirical record from
tropical plants and over the past 10
years we have been working very hard on
assessing the record and now I think we
were totally
wrong we don't see a that in the fal
record so we go back 136 million years
and to Easter Colombia this beautiful
Flora called s Felix not a single angos
sperm we move up in time to the opan
alvan and it's still the angos sper in
abundance are very very very little
about only 2% of the entire pal Flor
when you do countings of the different
elements of the
Flor you go into the middle cenomanian
with all the phog are saying well most
of the angern are already the orders are
already there and still the angp
represent just a small percentage of the
Abundant distributions of the
Flores even more that the the
latitudinal gradient in the ear
Cretaceous is either flat or inverted so
when you compare the diversity from
temporate latitude to the tropical to
the tropical latitude the the high
gradient we see today is is not there
now let's move to the end of the
citation to the mastrian so we have been
working on these coal mines in close to
Bogota so this this guy goes down in
these mines about 300 met and you can
see all the fossil plants in in the in
the roofs of of the coal mines and but
something very striking about this Flor
is that it like the typical components
of the modern tropical forest has many
palms and many families or taxa that we
don't have any idea what are they when
we compare the floristic composition of
this mastrian Flora with today most
common elements most common families in
tropical forest here represent by These
graay Bars and in red we have the
families we find in the mastrian Flora
you will see that the water this
mastrian Flora is not really
floristically a tropical
rainforest it's a forest that lives in
the tropics but is very different from
the forest we have today in the tropics
now you go back you go back to the
Cretaceous thary boundary probably all
have here about the the meteorite strike
the yukatan peninsula when you look at
the the pollen record in tropical
latitudes in Colombia especially we have
been working on a few cores one of this
is called the Alito where you can with
Poland you can get to a very fine
statgraphic resolution and you look at
the pollen the diversity of the
Poland going from 70 million to 62
million you see we saw a big sharp
decrease in the in the diversity and
about 75% of all the species that
wearing the mrican go extinct and this
level is also represent a fundamental
change in the Abundant distribution of
the Flor we went from a Flor where only
50% were angiosperm to a Florida is
already fully dominated by angiosperms
in the paleos not only that but when you
look at the abundance distribution of
the seeds and fruits you will see that
in the mastrian Flora all the fruits or
seeds are very tiny while in the in the
paleoin you have a wide distribution
from the small seed to Big seeds of
fruit that you can see here so I I think
this this event the tertiary the
Cretaceous ter event changed
fundamentally the structure and
composition of the tropical rainforest
we from a forest where the canopy
probably was open and dominated by
gymnosperms at alaras probably to the
canop closed canopy dominated by anger
we know
today we can look also at the venation
density in the fossil leaves so these
are closeups of fossil leaves and as you
can see we can see the very fine bation
of the of the leaves back in the pelosin
or the
mastrian now if you go today to a Rain
forest and you measure the venation
density of all the leaves from the
bottom of the forest to the top of the
forest you will see that there is a
strong bodal distribution so in the
canopy you have a very high venation
density and in the under story you have
low venation density and it's probably
you you could explain that because well
if you are here in the canopy you want
to maximize the amount of photosynthesis
you want to do because you are exposed
to the light and if you are in the in
the lower level with the light is very
diminished you don't spend so much
energy having a lot of veins because you
cannot do a lot of photosynthesis but
you you can see that this closed canopy
will give you this bodal distribution of
the forest
today and you see that in the liter so
you go underneath the forest and you
collect the leaves in the liter you will
see the same Bodel distribution that you
see represented in the forest
today we compare the the venation
density of many different floras within
the tropics and temporate latitude from
from the alterian to the paleos as you
can see here and only until the paleos
we see this bodal distribution that this
typical of modern tropical rainfor is
represented here in Black compared to
all the different distribution we see
during the
cretas we think this is an evidence that
not only the fistic composition changed
but also the structure of the forest
itself changed as well
now this change I think not only
affected the forest itself but also the
climate probably I think Camila told me
that Kevin Boyce came here a few months
ago to give a seminar and Kevin did this
beautiful study where he did a climatic
modeling of the Amazonia but instead of
having angos sperm he put gymnos sperms
and because the gymnos have a very low
venation density the leaves are smaller
they a transpiration
or the photosynthesis they do is slower
than the anus so he run this climatic
modeling and the results were really
staggering so just by changing the
forest from a angiosperm to genos sperm
the temperature represented here by the
the precipitation represented here by
the blue of the
gnos no the by the yellow the the
geosphere the precipitation dropped by
35% and the temperature increased by 3
degrees C and the L of the dry season
increased by two month so having a
gymnos forest there make the tropics
warmer and and drier just because the
effect of the transpiration of the
leaves had on the on the climate itself
about half of the rainfall that happen
in the Tropic today comes from the
transpiration of the plants
themselves so the
lessons I think we we can learn from the
Cretaceous that but the the end of the
Cretaceous the angos lack biomass bio
biomass dominance and did not rule most
of the landscape in the tropics even
though they were Diversified it doesn't
transer that into ecological dominance
that probably they were a lot of TRS and
herbaceous and mostly come in in flood
Plaines and dist habitats and I think
it's a fantastic example how
morphological Innovation all these
characteristics that make an angiosperm
and angiosperm lacks ecological success
by at least 55 million years and also
that the the change in landscape
occupancy lead to a change in tropical
climate now let's go to the second
chapter the the entire sosid where we
see a canopy that is already dominated
by yerm and I'm show you going to show
you one of the oldest tropical
rainforest as I Define it that we know
today and it's from suron just to keep
in mind the seron is within the
precipitation rate of modern tropical
rainforest but the temperature was about
a degree and a half warmer than any
tropical rainforest
today and that's how we think that the
this rainforest look like with these
giant snakes and huge massive crocodiles
and big turtles we have been studying
this in the in the s Coal Mine this is
the biggest open pit coal mine in the
world every year they remove the same
amount of material that was removed to
construct the Panama Canal and the the
mine has been operated for almost 35
years it produce about 3 million tons of
coal per year just to give you a a sense
of the size of this mine there are about
seven pits like this one and
this this here this tiny dot here is one
of these if you have been in a coal mine
one of these huge trucks that
uh that people in the Min industry use
that so it allow us an amazing
opportunity to to look for fossils so
it's just a collage of many of the
typical plants we find in in in the
suron we have legums many other fossils
now as we did from with the mastrian
when you compare the seron the pelosin
and in red the families we find in the
fossil record there with the modern
families today you see that
floristically seron is already a
neotropical
rainforest as I told you we have this
not only the the forest the biomass was
very large but also all the the animal
seems to be really
huge we did that this model of Tiano
this is my son you see has a very long
hair and and I haven't been able to for
him to cut the hair because he said I'm
jealous that he has so this model has
been traveling for the past two years
now it's a museum in I think
in Seattle and uh did was done by an
artist in
Canada so the the the seron also show us
that the families that dominated the
rainforest in the paleoin are still
dominating the exan neotropical rain
Forest now when you move from the paleos
in up in time you will find
this called the PM the paleos eosine
thermal maximum and this is a a unique
interval in Earth history that people
have been a study all over the world for
many years because it's probably the
closest analog to the warming we are
having today the temperature went up by
5 to 7° C in in 10,000 years that even
though probably the fastest in the
geological record is about 10 times
lower to what is happening
nowadays
when when you see all the climate models
that have been done to be able to
reproduce the
PTM the only way to reach the
temperature of high latitudes to the
empirical levels that we know happen
during the PTM is pumping a lot of CO2
in the atmosphere
so in this particular Model H and
cavalero they they had to go to 4,500
ppms of CO2 remember today we are in 402
bpms that's the only way you can reach
the temperature that we find in the high
latitudes but when that happen you see
here in the South America they they uh
propose that you just have a dead zone
in the tropics because the temperature
will reach Beyond 45° C of minan
temperature so it means that during
middle of the day the temperature can go
up to 90°
C so we have been now because the PTM is
only 10,000 years is the beginning and
the warming and then 190,000 years for
the cooling so the whole interval is
only is only 200,000 years and in rock
that could be represented but only 1
meter or 2 meter depend sedimentation
rates so we spent many many years almost
15 years I I look for many different
sections all over Colombia and Venezuela
and finally we find three sites where we
were absolutely sure that the PTM was
located we one of those we have to go
with the a helicopter and the Colombian
army look likes geology so much that
they went with us to collect in this
particular site and this is those are
are the three sides and here this bar
represent this block represent the PM
and in green are the taxa that are
present in both and this is pollen in
the three panels and as you can see we
we found the opposite to what we were
expecting we were expecting a high
levels of Extinction during the PM and
very low levels of origination and what
we saw was just the opposite that the
there is a a huge spike in the
origination rate
in the PTM and the levels of Extinction
are very
low so we when we calculate the per
capita origination of exension rate we
see that during the PTM the origination
went up not an high exension as we we
anticipated now when you look at the
many different phog of different plant
groups like The Orchids or the ptic
firms even the original form of Art our
agriculture but this is very tricky on
The Dating itself but many of them seems
to show that during the early in
something is really
happening now that also beg the question
that probably this cl cl climate model
is not correct because would be very
hard to to explain how can a plant live
at A Min anal temperature of 50 degrees
C that's almost at the physical limit of
many of those plants so it means that
that we don't have a very good way to
reproduce the climate during global
warming there there's something missing
in the climate system that we don't
understand that is amplifying the
warming in the poles while maintaining
what by and also increasing the
temperature in the PO in the equator but
not at a high degree as we see that in
the post there something something
really missing perhaps the C two
sensitivity is larger than 3 de cus that
we have been assuming for a long long
time now we continue up in time you will
see during the
entire paleos eosine osine and
myosin and this is once again the
temperature of the bottom of the ocean
and if you move in this direction is one
you move in the direction is cool and
this is the plan diversity of the
northern neotropics look through the
Poland record and as you can see there
is a good correlation between the
long-term trends in warming and
increasing diversity and the long-term
trends in Cooling and the droing
diversity and we see that happen in a
very short time scale like the PTM and a
long time scale during the
senos now it seems like every few weeks
there is a new paper in Nature and
Science anticipating the collapse lapse
of all the the ecosystems in the tropics
because of the current global
warming and well there are many bad
things that happen to plants when you
increase the temperature so the the net
production decreased due to increased
respiration the photosynthesis slow down
yeah many bad things a lot of leaf
stress so how come this we anticipate
that the plants will not function very
well the temperature is very high but
the fossil record show the opposite well
really the temperature of the leaf is
controlled mostly by the temperature of
the Earth the CO2 and the moisture in
the soil it's not only temperature and
when we go back to the paleos for
instance we always see high levels of
CO2 and high levels of rainfall we can
assess rainfall by looking at the leaf
area the bigger the area of the fossil
leaves the bigger the precipitation and
so we can assess the precipitation of a
given Flora in this case the sah was 3.5
3.4 M of rainfall and there are many
experiments has shown that The Temper
the photosynthesis of the
planting the plant can do a better
photosynthesis at a higher temperature
when the CO2 are higher especially if
the precipitation Elevate the negative
effect of the warming in this experiment
we do with the Cloud Winter eici ology
at the strike where we put all these
plants in enclosure with the CO2 was
double of the amount that we have today
and here then black is the experiment
with the elevated CO2 and gray is the
experiment with the the CO2 we we have
today in all of the cases the pl plant
water use efficiency increases as the
CO2 goes up and this is just the
proportion of the water that the plant
uses versus the proportion of the water
that the plan losses in the in the
photosynthesis and evap transpiration so
it means that when you have a lot of CO2
the plants don't need to use as much
water as they used before and perhaps
even though the temperature goes up as
the CO2 goes up they don't need to be
exposed to the high temperature as uh as
today now also when you increase the
temperature
you may think well perhaps as the
temperature expand toward the temperate
latitude the tropical rainforest here
represented here in this green color
will expand to higher
latitudes if you do that for the
eosine and you use the temperature
gradient we have today and the
temperature gradient we have in the
pelosin you will see by that by
increasing the temperature during the
early o Waring you will find 18° C so
the temperature I I told you was the
boundary lower boundar is tropical
rainforest you will find that
temperature down in Patagonia in both
cases so you would expect for the
tropical R rainforest to expand to our
tropical
latitudes now these are many hypothesis
on biome Evolution during the early eing
the green is the rainforest and as you
see many people has predicted that the
Forest will expand to Patagonia high
latitudes other say no perhaps you will
have a very dry area during this uh Soso
warming we did the analysis of comparing
many of the fossil record we have here
with many of the fossil record in Chile
and Argentina and we realize that the
the tropics don't really the tropical
rainforest don't expand to our high
latitudes during Global warmings but we
see is the development of a of a new
biome that that a paleontologist in
Argentina called The Mix paleoflora
Romero and Romero published this about
in 19 I think
1978 and he already gave us the answer
40 years ago that really the tropics
don't expand to where to high latitude
during global warming but what you see
is the evolution of a new biome adapted
to temporary areas during winter that
are not so cold and you see a very
distinctive abundant distribution in the
most important families between the
fossil record of the neotropics in the
eosin versus the lower latitudes in
South America during the
EOS so this Soso fossil record show us
that the temperature correlates with
diversity at long and short time scale
that probably tropical F plant families
already have the genetic variability to
cope with high temperature and high CO2
and uh there is a strong Niche
conservative the trop as I happened to
me living in New England for during the
winter that we don't live you are living
in the Tropic is very hard to move to
high latitudes and probably that the CO2
climate sensitivity is larger than 3 deg
C now I'm going to show you the last
chapter of this story and it's the bir
of a new ecosystem
the
savanas in in Orange is the distribution
of modern savanas today and we really
depend on savanas most of our
Agriculture and most of the people live
in savanas because it's much easier to
live in a savan that in a place where
it's raining all the time and you can
explain why we have dry Sons today just
by the atmospheric circulation of our
planet you will always find dry sons in
the subtropics
because of the the difference along the
with the equator and high
latitudes and indeed many people I
showed you before has has uh shown that
they were savanas or grasslands back in
time like in the early
years however when you look at the plant
phenes or many of the most important
families that live in savanas or citic
environment today you will see that most
of them in did show originations back in
time but the actual radiation happened
within the last 10 million years so
that's very interesting know why you
will expect to find always dry Z back in
time why you only see this big radiation
happening within the last 10 million
years now we have been studying the
empirical record of these dry areas over
the past few years one of these is
called casettes here in Northern part of
Colombia that today is basically a
desert beautiful place we have been
collecting there for many years this is
Camila Martinez here collecting years
ago beautiful place close you sometime
you will see these huge sand dunes and
there is a massive called the makira
mountain that is in the middle of the
desert with cloud forest and and rain
forest that is an an island among this
big big desert and in the desert itself
we find a lot of fossils like this uh
this is the the skull of a
gavial or these asoan those are the the
TS of these animal that look like a like
a kind of a
hypot but from South American origin
once you clean the fossil that will look
like sometime you have gavials like this
is
called and remember they are coming from
this very dry desert today many species
of purussaurus is one of the biggest
crocodile that ever existed was very
common all over the neotropic this
animal couldn't fit in this room and was
very common in W at that time you find L
giant armados
capivaras this very large
freshwater turtles like the stupis see
the size of the this guy so you can get
a sense of the size of this fresh water
turtles are related to the chapas that
do they live in the Orin but they're
about this size or you find these giant
guinea pigs about 700 kilos 2 met tall
yeah very productive
ecosystem so this is how we think the
cetes look 3 million years ago permanent
Rivers a lot of uh biomass
and this is how cetes looks today we
also went looking into the Janos of
Colombia the savanas and you haven't
been in the savanas it's an amazing
beautiful place you see all these
grasslands and you only see trees along
the water
Crossways now this is a place difficult
to study because there are no out groups
but an oil company drill a core one of
these places and we were able to study
entire core and this is the Poland
record of the grasses and this is the
geological time going from 23 million
years to today and as you can see even
over the up to 7 five million years you
don't see any evidence of grasslands in
the Janos of Colombia today so probably
the savanas also evolve or expand during
the last three or four million
years now if you think think about the
expansion of all these dry lands here
and also all the
sados this is a an area that used to be
occupied by tropical
rainforest now today we know that there
is a very good relationship between area
and the number of species the larger the
area the number the higher the number of
species so if you do the opposite so
instead of increasing the area you
decrease the area of an ecosystem well I
will predict a large Extinction across
many different CL
so I think if you look at the phology of
many of plant families today in the in
Amazonia there must be a significant
reduction in diversity over of the past
five million years that probably because
in the DNA if you look at phog is very
hard to do to look at a phog something
doesn't exist today so probably there's
a fundamental bias in the way we analyze
philogenetic data to assess the past
diversity that we don't understand very
well but I would expect that the
diversity in the Amazonia has dropped
over the past 5 million
years
now I always thought that the plos was
really boring that nothing really
happened there but over the last years I
realized how really critical the mid
plos was and really change the climate
state of our planet so if you look at
the the the temperat record for from 60
million years to today you see that
around 3 to 2.7 you see a fundamental
change in the this term of very warm
climate to what we see today this
oscillation of warming and cooling
during the since the glaciation is start
2.7 million years ago and also that the
CO2 has been
changing uh over time at least during
the glaciation inter glaciation we have
been going from 188 0 parts per million
to 280 parts per million and we are in
402 parts per million so if you could
summarize this climate State what we are
now today is a conjunction of four
factor that we have not seen at least
for 400 million years the first one is
that we have very steep latitudinal
temperate gradient from the equator to
the pole that today is about 50° C so
you go from 20 7 Cel in the tropics to
minus minus 20 in the poles if you go
back to the eosin it was 32 to 14 so the
increasing the temperature gradient is
the strongest we have seen in a long
time the second point is that we have a
strong temperature gradient between the
Eastern Pacific and the Western Pacific
that's something we haven't had in a
very very long time the difference in
temperature from the sea here in front
of Australia to the temperature of the
ocean here in front of
Ecuador the third the first time we have
ice in the poles permanent ice in both
pole and the first time in a long long
time that the CO2 has dropped below 200
parts per million and today not a single
climatic model has been able to have
these four elements in their modeling to
reproduce of the climate of the early
plos so there is something is still
missing out of the climate now we know
that what controls a very large degree
the different ecosystem within the
Tropic is not really the temperature but
precipitation how the amount of rainfall
and the lane of the dry seas and you can
see that very easy if you go to waita
this is during L event in 2011 when a
lot of precipitation was brought here to
the northern part of Columbia
and this is Elo when precipitation drops
and these are changes that happen within
three or four month and green is the
vegetation you see how you go from a
really desert to very low grassland only
by changing the precipitation within a
single year now within the tropics what
controls most of the precipitation is
the the intertropical Convergence Zone
so this low humid low pressure belt
that is moving all the time along the
year so when you have winter in the
southern the the itcc is always moving
away from the from the hemisphere that
is the coldest so during the winter in
then in the Norther in the southern
hemisphere the itcc move north and
during the winter in North America the
itcc mov South so if you are here for
instance you will always have rain
because the Bell goes up and down but if
you are here for instance during the
during the winter here you will get the
rain during the winter here you get the
dry season and that's what brings the
the rain now but that works when you
have ice in both poles we still don't
know what happened very well if the ice
is only in one pole in the south in the
North or we don't have ice in any of the
poles we don't know if for ex if we
don't have ice here or here if the itcc
gets wider and doesn't move very much or
the precipitation increase all along the
way with very very few empirical data
about precipitation that is really the
the key factor here rather than
temperature
so the final conclusion of this last
chapter is that this is another example
of how morphological Innovation the fact
of you being a
grass lack ecological success by 3
million years so we see all these L
lineages evolving back in the eosin but
you only see large diversification and
the copany of landscape within the last
10 million years we also predict that
large deduction in
tropical uh Forest coverage and also
that model most climate models fail to
predict the lack of extensive savanas
during global warming
intervals and I think just to summarize
what everything I told you we produced
this movie of the biomes over the past
five 55 million years so each color
represent a particular biome and we have
been using G plates
to to assess the biomes so we'll start
in 55 million years and we'll end today
so in Green Forest the black here the
tropical rainforest from the the the
North American
latitudes it went very fast
no yeah just to end
sometimes as you see the the funding for
geological science has been dropping at
least in NSF in Colombia and many places
in the
world but when you realize that over the
past 150 years we went from 280 parts
per million to 402 parts per
million
and if you go back to the last
glaciation 20,000 years ago we went from
8 180 to 280 so only 100 parts per
million in 20,000 years and here we have
been going up about three parts per
million in in only 150 years and that
402 is very close to the levels of CO2
back in the plyos so the last time we
have a CO2 like we have it today you
have to go back five million years you
realize that we are really in a massive
Global experiment to reproduce a climate
of the past and probably geology and I
think what we do the the pale climate
the Reconstruction and ancient ecosystem
is really critical to understand and
predict what is going to happen because
all the historical records that people
is using to build climatic models or do
experiments are B based on historical
records and none of the historical
records human had by looking at the
temperature precipitation over the past
200 years has had levels of CO2 similar
to what we have today you really have to
go back to your geological record to
reproduce what is will be happening and
is already happening over the next uh
decades to
come just to give you a sense of that
this is an experiment that has been
running in front of my building and so
we have these two green houses and in
this greenhous we have the CO2 as today
so the ambient condition 402 parts per
million in in this one and in here we
are trying to replicate 280 parts per
million so the CO2 we have 150 million
years ago and has been a lot of work so
we have here a very large column full
with calcium carbonate and we have a
sensor of CO2 here and every time the
CO2 goes above 280 we suck the air
between this capsule and the CO2 combine
with the carbonate and that drops down
the the CO2 and what we have here is is
corn CM Ma and we are assessing the the
how fast the CM is the corn can grow in
different CO2 condition and you already
see how the CO2 the corn in the high CO2
in the CO2 of today is growing really
really fast compared to the CO2
150 years ago but we're spending a lot
of funding just to replicate how the
climate was 150 years ago this is just
incredible and I think the one of the
clues is going to the field not to the
study the f record of the tropics that
is mostly an Explorer and sometime you
find like these big trees at 4,000
meters of elevation in the altiplano in
the Peruvian Andes thank you very much
for your
[Applause]
attention question I was struck by the
comparison of the models of the Halos
climate maximum that weing these 45 to
50° centigrade and you comparing it with
with the what you saw in the fossil
record is it is there a way for you to
actually to calibrate those models by
telling people how hot it really was and
be wise from the fossil record yeah we
have the tical determination we have
from temperature are about
32° but this just compound the problem
because you have to reach the
temperature of the almost close to the
pole to 14° C without increasing the
temperature in the tropies on 32° C and
that's
impossible yeah no matter what
combination you do of heat ocean
transfer yeah there is a fundamental
component of the climate that we don't
understand and that reason we are not
able to replicate we don't are able to
replicate even the early pene climate
that is just a small example of the
climate back in the early so we have a
long way to go and when you see all the
predictions we do for the future they
are based on
on the historical record and we have
this CO2 we don't have data about that
we just don't know there are so many
many models have predicted that around
450 PPS of CO2 there is a you could have
a climate State change so for instance
you could transform a savannah into a
brain Forest into a canopy Forest
because of the CO2 is much higher than
but it's not a gr gradual change but a
threshold change so you have one system
and then you have the next system and
the change is really really fast and we
are approaching to that so I hope before
I I I see the the CO2 at 450 and we be
a I was correct looking forward
to I understand some aspects of
ecosystem um so the reason that we would
have the Savannah climate situation
develop that's a climate change not it
wasn't controlled
by biologically available
grass spread into a new system because
climate change or are you saying that
the boundaries of
trunk because grass
itself no I think you need first need to
change the climate like increase the
land of the dry season so you expand the
land escape and then the grasses as the
the area increases you have a radiation
but the grasses have been there for a
long time yeah the problem is to explain
the absence of extensive savanas back in
time why during the a using even though
you have this worker culation why we
don't have extensive saan back in the
fil
record is is it possible that
the
transation faster turnover precipitation
rainfall
evaporation uh keep the tropics cooler
than otherwise might be yeah I think the
key is is one so Mo yeah clouds has
experiments of fight growing at 45 de C
but if you put enough water the plant to
okay but this is a control experiment
there is a point
that but not not so much survival of the
plants but actually increasing the heat
flux into the upper atmosphere into
space by having a a phase change
yeah at least in the PTM we see we think
that the biomass increase and we don't
see an increase in the in the we see an
improvement in the water the water use
efficiency so that's that extra water
that the pl is not using it could be
used to produce more biomass or could go
back to the atmosphere and from clouds
and perhaps depending of the Elation of
the cloud you can go from cooling to
warming the clouds are very tricky but
it could be another fact factor that is
is letting the the tropies cool while
the whole planet is is
Waring but still the difference so there
is a large degree of temperature that
you have to raise the temperature in the
PO but at the same time maintaining the
temperature just warming 5° and the
other is like 15 that's that's a
l the um mix P Community looks like was
the historical State when you have
higher temperature high CO2 do are those
tax still extinct and restricted and
like would you predict that they would
expand again in similar regime in the
future or are they all extinct and we
need to start over
plan no I think you go to CH those are
the remant of this mix it's just very
restricted yeah because we don't have a
temporate area with a decent
do you see a possibility for Rising CO2
again agriculturally or whatever for
theforce to expand
land
practices yeah that's really the
critical plan for part the the
deforestation because even though we're
increasing the
CO2 High very high the amount of forest
cor is has been
decreasing like crazy I've been living
in Van for 10 years and Dian is this
region colia and and 10 years ago you
could go to the end that is only 2 hours
away from Pary and the whole thing would
be covered with for and you go today and
it's just just want to cry most of the
forest is gone so there is not really
this cooling effect of about aspiration
because the forest is not there anymore
I went to Brazil to
Bonito three years ago they have this
this is the P beautiful Forest what used
to be a forest and you go there and
because the price has been going up
because a lot of people love soil this
extensive area that used to be this
pantal Forest now are converted into
soil Fields so fi that you can you
cannot see the end of the fields and
they are transformed were transforming
within the last 10 years so investors
from all over the world to fund these
hedge funds have been buying F
soil and transform the landscape at a
rate that that is just unparal so all
this coolant effect is is G we don't
have that but we have in the extra
Z2 yeah so it would seem that kind of
the not the only mechanism you have you
know pretty high CO2 to keep the tropics
cool it's just to have a pretty
permanent cloud cover and and I don't do
you have do you have any paleo indicator
for for for light level um that might
tell you that you know that the the um
if you really had permanent sort of pod
cover that you could um pick out in some
way I don't I don't know if there's any
physiological characteristic that is
related to that and the canopy leaves
right obviously the under story is
always going to be dark but is can you
see anything in the canopy that might
say gez there wasn't as many photons
well that's I think that's the only
possibility we have and i' been thinking
about that for a few years now and we
still having find a proxy to to measure
the but I love to to do that yeah we
have thinking for exploring theum in the
cuticles of the leaves but uh the
signals yeah we still need to do all of
empirical work in the forest today to
understand the relationship between
theum and the leaves and the cloud cover
because the clouds we don't have many
data on cloud cover that's something
that even today is not not
a yeah but that's a critical component
to this whole the
uh in in previous uh warming events you
showed there was a pretty uh speciation
outpaced Extinction pretty
dramatically uh and if this were to
happen again would you kind of predict
the same Ratio or would you kind of
predict a human influence well the the
problem is the scale of the change so
here we once again we increased in 150
years what uh took
uh and over the past 20,000 year we only
increased the CO2 100 parts per million
so the rates are so we never had such an
incredible rate that it's very hard to
tell what the populations are going
going to especially with high levels of
deforestation so yeah I wouldn't predict
that oration because most of the species
will be gone but at the end our species
only 140,000 years old and from the fil
record we know that any even species on
a has last 3 million years if you are a
very small animal big animal small PL
and a 3 million years so we have been
here only a small fraction 5% of the
typical duration of a speci and and
don't imagine the humans here in 10 th
years even a thousand years for me we
already 7 billion and if you look at the
fossil record over over the past 3.5
million they have been a lot of mass
exting and probably ours will go extin
will take a lot of exp with us and
geologist come from another planet look
our deposit record will just be a blink
in the the geological history and life
will come back again with different
rules but we be G but at least if you
are a geologist that's a fantastic
experiment because you we are living it
that's soet that geology is so important
that decide to invest 7 million people
were creating environment that we don't
have a
presid have a geological perspective to
appreciate
that well perhaps on that
though we should thank again Carlos for
really
[Applause]
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu