my name is Don vians I'm um a professor
in plant breeding and genetics in the
school of integrate of plan Sciences
here at Cornell and uh we put together a
program for our first hemp field day um
ever where um fortunately we have some
nice looking hemp for you to be able to
see and i' noticed everybody was kind of
roaming around looking at it and you'll
have opportunity to do that little bit
later on as well but uh we have a lineup
of some of us here from Cornell who are
working with hemp and we have quite a
few people and the number of people are
growing who are interested in working on
different aspects of hemp in terms of
research and extension and um and we
also have uh Chris log who I'm not sure
he's here yet but oh there he is
wonderful uh he's from the Department of
Agriculture and markets who is going to
be uh talking a little bit later on
about the uh potenti uses the marketing
of hemp and also some of the regulatory
issues that uh that Growers need to keep
in mind I noticed that uh looking at the
list of all of you who have uh signed up
or enrolled online for um this field day
uh that there's a wide variety of
backgrounds that you come from and
interest that you have about hemp so
what I would like to do is to keep this
informal um certainly there are uh half
a dozen or so of us who are going to be
giving talks but to keep it informal
almost such that as you have questions
or even comments or want to get into
discussion about anything just barge in
at any time to do that okay so uh so it
would be more fun if this was more of a
two-way discussion or a multiple way
discussion than if it's just us up here
uh lecturing to you uh so keep that in
mind um we also have um assembly woman
Donna leardo who is somewhere close by
but I don't think she is here there she
is oh wonderful so she she's just waving
her hand there I wanted to recognize her
because she is the one who initiated all
of the discussions about industrial hemp
and the potential uses here in New York
state and um and the subsequent
legislation and and um essentially paved
the way for us to be able to I mean
without her we wouldn't be having this
field day right now essentially so let's
give her a round of applause for what
she's
[Applause]
done and certainly anytime that you want
to contribute to the discussion feel
freee to jump right on in so so again
we'll keep this very
informal um so what I'd like to do is to
start out by just telling you how we got
into this research here at Cornell
University in the first place and uh and
it started last year with the Department
of Agriculture and markets who made some
funding available to us to to start out
by evaluating varieties of industrial
hemp that come from Canada and Europe um
by and large and to see which ones will
perform the best under our conditions in
New York state until we have time to
actually do some breeding specifically
for New York State conditions so that's
what this set of Trials is all about
here um there are a couple of people who
will explain more about this um a little
while from now so I won't try to steal
their Thunder but um but by the time we
went through all the the regulatory
approval process that had to be done in
tandem we couldn't do it all at the same
time uh it wasn't until late August of
last year we were able to actually uh
purchase some seed and obviously that's
too late to get some good experiments
going but uh but my research crew uh
planted out some small trials only about
a mile in that direction from here um at
the 1 of September last year not to
really get good data on on harvest I
mean by the time that froze um sometime
in November it was only about 6 or 8
inches tall but it at least it gave us a
chance to um to see how well we could
establish some experiments they actually
tried out two different planners and got
some good data so we have a little
experience behind us before um doing the
real trials this summer and you can see
behind me that that it was very
successful in establishing a good trial
there um so that's what last year was
all about um but what I'd like to do is
to um turn this over to Dr Chris smart
to describe uh more of what the research
plans are for us here at Cornell and uh
not only what we're doing now but what
we plan to do in the future
and um and and what's happening in terms
of of of production around the state in
regards to research Chris is a u
professor in the um section of Plant
Pathology and plant microbiology in the
school of integrated plant science um
and she's the one who's coordinating all
that we're doing here with Industrial
Hemp in our College uh and on top of
that she's uh she's also a director I
know you're interim director but
essentially you're director today I'm
director oh are you today is the day oh
wow okay so she is she is a director of
the school of Integrative PL science so
Chris well thank you Don and and welcome
everyone to Cornell uh it is a beautiful
day and this is uh a really remarkable
hemp trial Don and his his crew have
done a great job um in terms of the
research that we're doing here we now at
cornal let me give you a bit of a
history um last year in 2016 there were
15 or 16 States across the US that had
Industrial Hemp research projects this
year and and Don's group was one of them
uh it was really fantastic that he was
this year there's 31 States so
Industrial Hemp is booming and and we
have a lot of folks to collaborate with
across the country um so it's really
nice that um the state has enabled us to
jump in and and really um get on the
wave of industrial hemp that's happening
right now in terms of what we're doing
um we now have 11 scientists at Cornell
that uh they and folks in their Labs
have projects on Industrial Hemp last
year this time we had one so uh so the
state has definitely got us enthusiastic
about Industrial Hemp we also have um 10
Educators from Cornell Cooperative
Extension across the state that are
involved in bringing information uh to
Growers about how to grow hemp and and
uh you know what can we do this year in
terms of hemp and how where are we
looking to the Future so that's really
exciting uh in terms of some of the
research that will be doing um there is
a research project actually um that is
run through Cornell but uh it's actually
a state funded project where this year
there are 29 Farms that are involved in
the research project these are farms uh
that are all growing the same variety of
industrial hemp that variety is Anka the
reason we chose Anka was not some
amazing scientific literatur driven
reason it's really the that we could get
a hold of at the time we decided to do
this large scale project um but it it is
a dual purpose um uh variety of hemp so
it'll be interesting to see how it does
on these 29 different farms in terms of
the research we know what the history of
the land that the Anka is being grown on
um we know we have soil tests and um
we'll have weather data we'll have yield
data so uh we'll know really how this
variety does we have Farms from Lake
Erie all the way way down to Long Island
uh Growers are amazingly entrepreneurial
we have Growers that are growing for
fiber and for seed we also have um
Growers that are uh uh growing plants in
the greenhouse and transplanting them
out uh to extract the medicinal
compounds the nonhallucinogenic
non-thc uh medicinal compounds and
they'll be selling those and then we
have Growers that are actually
harvesting two to three week old plants
and using them uh for baby greens uh and
salads and whatnot so uh I've been
amazingly impressed again continually by
The Growers in the state of New York how
entrepreneurial you folks are and um all
the different uses and and creative ways
that you can find to to thrive uh in
this farming environment it has been a
tough year we've had a lot of water uh
my background is in sorry Jen my
background is in uh Plant Pathology I
study diseases of vegetables and if
you're a vegetable girl you know it's
been a tough year it's been hard to get
in because of all the rain um but our
Growers have gotten the hemp in it's
gotten in late and uh we'll be
enthusiastic to see what we learn at the
end of the
season um in terms of other research
projects um uh Larry and Larry smart
who's a a plant breeder um in the school
of Integrative plant science as well uh
he and Don vians are going to be
establishing a breeding program one of
the things that we learned this year we
Don's group knew last year is that um
because of the permitting issues that
Chris log will talk about you know you
know moving seed across state or country
lines can be extremely difficult and so
it'd be really great to establish a seed
production industry here in New York so
that New York Growers can buy seed
produced in New York um uh alleviating
some of the permitting issues and that
will be coming online um but but just
starting a breeding program from scratch
takes time and so um we're also working
with um local seed companies to try to
find ways to import the seed more
smoothly uh than what happened this year
um additionally uh in that program uh we
will be establishing a um a THC and CBD
CBDs are the nonhallucinogenic compounds
medicinal compounds produced by hemp uh
a testing facility that hopefully a year
from now um both researchers and Growers
will be able to use um to determine what
varieties have uh higher levels of those
uh medicinal compounds uh when grown
here in New York
so those compounds do change depending
on the environment depending on water
content and depending on heat so uh
that's going to be an important aspect
of our program we have a plant
Pathologists that's going to be studying
plant diseases we have an entomologist
that's looking at insects we have a
system scientist who's looking at how
hemp fits into a rotational system um we
have uh also I I along with a
microbiologist are looking at uh the
microbiome you've heard that you know
what's in your gut and on your skin skin
helps make you who you are healthy and
things like that well we're actually
going to be looking at the microbiome of
hemp to see what kind of microbes grow
on hemp and how that might impact some
of the products that we get out of it so
that's some of the research uh that
we're going to be uh doing at Cornell um
and and we're really excited actually
just to to be involved with the Growers
and to learn from you guys you know what
your needs are but also uh what you're
learning on your farms and how we can
bring that back and feed the those
questions and those Solutions into our
research program um I also want to say
that we do have a another a field day in
Geneva on um uh Tuesday August 15th so
the Geneva plots uh we have Cornell has
a campus in Geneva it's about an hour
north of here so we have four trials
here that Don group will talk about
today we have two identical trials to
these four in Geneva and um those trials
don't look quite like this so when we're
in Geneva we'll actually be talking
about some of the struggles that you
might have if you're planting a hem crop
um you know this this is beautiful as
I've heard you know some of the
researchers are like wow if I knew it
was going to look like this you know I'd
grow in a heartbeat um but what happens
when a field gets drown out what do
things look like um what disease and
insect pressures do you have and things
like that um so we'll have some of the
extension folks there and we'll talk
about some of the some of the issues
that uh you could have if you're if
you're growing a hemp crop um and with
that I think I would turn it over to is
it your folks back to Don um some of you
who have uh stood up close to the hemp
here may have noticed that these green
varieties here that are in bloom um
there's a lot of bees in there
bumblebees and honey bees and so forth
they're really doing a lot of
pollinating and appar love him for
pollen Source um also was thinking as I
came out this morning and I was looking
um not straight in this way but um from
the other direction particularly there
this stand is so thick that um that you
could easily use this for you know like
they have corn mazes and stuff like that
the
pathways so maybe maybe once the uh
regulations allow for that to happen uh
we could have hemp mazes so we'll see
what happens in the future um next up um
U we're going to have a couple of people
from our research program talk about the
actual trials that are going on here to
um evaluate varieties for our conditions
here in New York State um so I'd like to
introduce uh two people to come up Jamie
Crawford who I really have to um to
acknowledge has done a lot of work to
make uh the logistics of all of these
things that we're doing with hemp happen
um she's been very instrumental to to
pulling off a lot of of things there so
Jamie is a research support specialist
on the uh Forge breeding project which
is the project that I lead but of course
now we're into hemp um research as well
and uh along with her is Amelia uh yafi
who is U actually completing an
internship with us um she's actually
from Sunni kobal skll and has to do an
internship in order to complete her
degree requirements there at cobal skill
uh so she became interested in
industrial hemp and uh we took her on as
a an intern to work with the the hemp
project this summer and um has done a
lot of really nice things there so I'm
going to turn it over to the two of them
good morning um I have a bunch of things
to tell you and I knew I forget so you
have actually a handout for what I'm
going to talk about it's called 20177
Industrial Hemp
trials so um the very first table on
that sheet shows you our different
locations for our trials and the
planting dates so the trial you see
behind me right here this is um this one
was planned to June
9th and you can see it's done very very
well um the one directly behind me this
is our grain and Dual Purpose variety
trial
and then we also had four entries that
are exclusive fiber varieties and so
those are the next block down so those
of you interested in fiber should go and
check those out as
well um so you can see we planted well
Kristen mentioned how far behind the
trials were in Geneva they were planted
later so we planted a second trial on
this exact same soil type the day after
we planted the first Geneva trial and
that is what down at the far end so you
could be able to see a little bit of a
difference a difference 3 weeks can make
um the varieties are still photo period
sensitive so you can see that even
though they are much shorter they're
still starting to flower at about the
same time um within the last two weeks
luckily we've had uh two people from
different Canadian seed companies come
and visit us and they've said that even
though it's planted later it will still
be hard harvested in like let's see so
since it's there's a 3-we difference in
planting there'll probably be a week and
a half difference in harvesting time so
it's it's not going to be you know it's
not the full 3- week difference for the
Harvest so you can see our other trials
on on here so we have one other trial
here in itha that was planted on on what
I would call a challenging soil so it's
what we plant we planted a trial on it
last year and what we planted with a
grain drill so it was planted about a
1in seating depth it just didn't come up
at all it was terrible so we planted it
this year with a 4in seedar aiming for
about a half inch seeding depth and
then bad luck right about two days after
we planted it we got a rain and then two
nights in the
40s and so um the emergence in that
field is not what you see
here as sort of an understatement uh in
the trial right behind me we're
averaging between um between 10 and 18
seedlings per square foot and on that
other trial I was just talking about we
were averaging between four and seven
seedlings per square foot so it was a
big difference a big
difference um and then we have the two
trials planted in Geneva one of them on
a moderately well- drained soil and so
on a somewhat poorly drained soil so we
know we have those in New York state and
then our last trial is on a gravel it's
the only one that had a lot of rocks so
our last trial was planted in an organic
system in on the in Freeville and so
that was in that was rotating out of red
clover and then we planted hemp into it
so we're really looking forward to what
we see in that one so the plots behind
me each one is
well this is sort of the joke some one
of the students pointed it out to me
after I printed out the so our plots are
4 feet by 20 feet so everyone can make a
a 420 joke there you have to have one at
a hemp meeting right
so and then each entry is replicated
four times throughout each trial
um like I said we we were aiming with
our grain drill for about 3/4 of an inch
for a seating depth in all of our trials
except for the East Ithaca one where we
aim for half an inch
um and then if you want to look at the
back you can see a list of the varieties
that we have in the trials so we've got
13 varieties that are listed as grain or
dual purpose so the ones you see on the
signs here the four fiber Tri four fiber
entries which you can see down there and
then there's also some contact
information for the seed companies that
we got these varieties from so for
future trials we do we do hope to get
more entries um we want to be able to
show for the farmers of New York State
you know the full spectrum of what's
available to them so there's a couple
other seed companies in Canada that ran
out of seed this year so we're hoping to
get some of their entries from Parkland
for next year and um yeah so next Amelia
is going to talk to you a little bit
about some of the notes that we've taken
yeah I always wondering uh why didn't
you just culture the Cannabis that grows
organically here in indigenously in New
York to start a project I already have
cold weather and the soil hardiness
cannabis
h
i
it's that would not be commercially
available to Farmers right now like the
purpose of these trials right now is to
see what farmers can purchase and plant
in their fi Fields right now so like
yeah I'm here I'm trying to talk to you
about the variety trials that we have
that's part of a a future breeding
program right so the whole idea we would
of course you know native hemp varieties
are of interest in breeding programs but
for the trials like this is what a
farmer can get seed of and plant next
spring so that's that's what we we need
to show okay any other questions before
I pass yes sir the variety that has
that's 3 weeks behind do you expect it
to grow to this extent or it will never
do that I don't think it will ever get
quite this tall um they were I can
answer that uh once it starts the photo
period change it stops its uh growth
upward produces flour or seed uh the
gentleman who came last week he he is
the one who markets Anka so Ruben Stone
he was saying that they have areas where
they've planted Anka
in beginning of May and that's like 15
feet tall
so um yes Jamie aren there there a few
varieties that are Pho perod in
sensitive I thought that one up in
Canada
at I think that's what Larry actually
wants to bre there's nothing to stay
neutral yet but that would be one of the
first p
I was
already yes so um I'll bring in Amelia
and she's going to talk about some of
the notes that we've taken on the trials
so far hi
so um I'm the research intern and with
the help of some of our student
employees they've been collecting data
on our trials um on a weekly basis most
of these data include notes on uh height
stand and flowering as you can see all
of our varieties um are flow are in
bloom now I think the fiber may just be
beginning uh the fiber varieties have
been much slower um to to
begin um and something I've noticed is
there's vast differences between arm
Manish and dises varieties and for those
of you who don't know um dous varieties
are the ones that have male and uh
female plants that are separate and
Monisha plants produce male and female
parts on the same plant um all of our
dious varieties um began to bloom uh
sooner and they had um they did so much
more vigorously at first and then their
growth sort of slowed down whereas the U
mishas varieties have continued to um
grow a lot more at a much more steady
and linear
rate um we plan on combining the our
grain and Dual Purpose varieties um in
the fall when about 70% of the seeds are
mature um so we're expecting to do that
probably September October and our fiber
trial will be harvested uh when 20%
flowering
occurs so that's all we have for now
there was there was a note in one of
your um handouts that the the mishes are
only used for breeding
they not generally put in the field I
was just curious
why whether the are breeding
varieties um that are Manas I think
there are some varieties
already just because just had a comment
that said minisha cultivar are generally
only grown by plant freeders is that
that they're just not as advanced or is
that they produce less seed or
I'm not sure that
that's true because a lot of people
prefer money varet because they won't
lose 40% of their crop due to dead male
plants so that's why I was just curious
yeah will you be using the seed from
these in future plantings what about
cross-pollination between any of them
no um no we plant we plant certified
seed in our
trials and so we won't be saving any
seed well we will test the quality of
these seeds for um different oil
production but when it comes to planting
again we're going back to the certified
seed
bags and it's illegal I me was point out
that it is in fact illegal to save the
seed why why is that uh Chris so you
have to buy it every
year it it has to do with Federal
de intellectual property is well there
is yeah that's there are some varieties
that sign
absolutely but it's also illegal at
least our our permit does not allow us
to
hold can you these plants right down
but is that
legal so what are I mean under your if
you have a license to do that then it's
illegal it is legal
oh sorry the question was can you clone
the plants can you put them into tissue
culture and that's absolutely something
that we're going to be doing here at
Cornell in fact the director of our
tissue culture facility is here today um
but you have to have the appropriate
licensing from the company Who Sold you
the seed and you also have to have the
appropriate permits so that Matthew
doesn't get thrown in jail we we like
him and we like him
at um will breeding efforts focus on
ities or strategies that won't
necessarily incur as many licensing
issues or material transfer agreements
for Farmers that will not Ur well I mean
so like eventually ideally people will
be able to save see of H and won't be
breeding from varieties that
might previously have such um
restrictions on
them by state in Colorado are the states
that
have
yeah yeah I'm not sure how to answer
that question yeah I didn't
uh I didn't quite hear the whole
question there something about breing
what well well I if some of these
varieties um I have licensing agreements
that you can't repeatedly save seed is
that legally towards the companies that
own the variety on top of Federal
Regulation oh yes that's so that's
absolutely right that happens with the
most crop species uh even with Alfalfa
that you see the plots behind you there
uh that we work with on a project as
well
um especially the private companies will
uh go through what's called plant
variety protection uh some will actually
patent their varieties and so that's a
legal process so that makes sure that
that you or I cannot pirate this their
seed and call it our own variety uh they
put all all the expense into the
research and development of that variety
and producing the seed and so forth they
want to protect it so that they can get
some payback so that they continue with
with their efforts there uh so that's
just part of the legal protection system
uh it's not part of the drug enforcement
agency or anything like that uh but it's
just just part of the system to to make
sure that uh companies are protecting
their own interest so forth and and I
don't say that in a selfish way that's
that's kind of the way it needs to be in
order for companies to have the
incentive to put all the the funding
into research and development of
products like this does that answer your
question well I just wondering if you
then breed off of varieties that um have
those protections do those like just
continue forward so if we do that uh we
need to go to that company and ask if
they would allow us to do that and and
and sign an agreement and of course we'd
have to pay them a royalty on on um any
varieties that we develop from their
materials uh usually there's a royalty
basis uh per pound of seed you know so
many cents per pound of seed that we
have to pay back to
them there's a couple patent attorney
over here there's a couple different
issues going on you may actually be able
to patent a gene sequence you can't
patent the whole genome but you might be
able to patent a sequence to give gives
it a particular characteristic in that
case any of us wouldn't be able to grow
a hemp plant with that particular Gene
sequence in it because then we would be
violating their patent um but if you
enter into a license agreement with one
of these companies then there's a
potentially additional restrictions on
top of whether or not you can actually
breed with their plant technically you
know by the patent law itself if you
breed with their plant and then produce
something without that patented Gene
sequence you might technically be okay
by the patent laws but but by the
license agreement you you might not be
okay right right any other questions
about anything related to that yes do
you have any plans to test autoflow for
oil autoflow yeah uh we haven't thought
about that at least I haven't but that
might be an interesting thing to
do how much the seeds cost how much the
seed cost uh Jamie what did we have to
pay for
that need to give you the mic
to so for the seat cost it's it's
probably
$2.50 to $3 a pound for the seat and
then you pay for all of the testing that
they have to do through apis to get it
imported to the United States and then
the shipping is extensive on top of that
as well and then I don't know what did
we work it out to Chris do you remember
like it was uh 50 roughly $50 an acre
yeah had roughly $50 an acre for the
seaa and that was for that was for Anka
that yeah that was also when we bought
it in bulk so we bought 51,000 lb of it
and got it at about 50 so it would be
about $50 per acre how many pounds per
acre 30 30 pound yeah so the question
was how many pounds per acre and we were
planning at 30 lbs per acre which was
about the $50
range yes in addition to testing for the
oil quality and the fiber content will
you take a look at the pharmaceutical
value of this crop even though I know
it's not intended for that purpose yes
we're very interested in doing that so
uh uh what we would like to do is that I
mean Sunni Bingington has a
pharmaceutical school now and uh we we
talked to them about a year ago about
interest I know they're working with
some other people now too but uh but we
would like to get some people interested
in looking that right so the question
was I think if I heard it right I think
the question was are we going to be
looking at other non-thc medicinal
compounds yeah basically yeah so um uh
this year again we're getting that up
and running so we'll just do it as a one
shot deal we have um at cornal our uh
BRC bio Resource Center um we'll be
gearing up for that so we'll test for
THC and then for the um cannaboid panel
uh and then next year the idea is that
you know we we'd have more time to plan
a a more rigorous scientific study and
and
we would probably do um different
timings but at least for this year we'll
get um information from the 17 varieties
at least a snapshot H and we'll do that
for each of our six locations that has
the varieties I'm glad thanks for
clarifying that Chris because yeah we
can't we're not doing everything this
year this is our initial year but but in
the future we would like to do that so
yes uh don same question I asked you
before about harvesting equipment want
to sort of throw it out if if you guys
have what are you guys doing for
combines are making uh adjustments to
your combines if there's any specialy
equipment you guys are looking into or
if anyone
has so I think that's a general question
for everybody um Ed and I were talking
about that before we started here uh
about Harvest equipment that you use and
it would probably be different for the
fiber varieties versus The Grain and
Dual Purpose varieties I mean I've heard
I've read that U that people have used a
combine for the Grain and Dual Purpose
types but sometimes there can be some
problems with um with all that stalk
material wrapping around the the
components of the
combine um so that is an issue anybody
have any experience with that or
thoughts on that clients in North
Carolina who using a hand decorators
using what a hand hand decorators oh
okay
yeah I knew a farmer in Vermont that
actually left a remainder of the
Hempfield because it took about 2 to 3
days just to combine 4 acres oh really
um and they had to repeatedly stop and
unwind the combine and uh resharpen the
blades whatnot because the fiber is just
too much for their John Deere Combine so
that could be an issue and I know that's
a common issue um throughout the hemp
industry right now is the hardest thing
of it yeah so that's that's something
where um some some agricultural
Engineers could come in handy to to work
out that system but there is I mean
obviously there's a lot of fiber in
there even in the grain types there's a
lot of fiber I mean otherwise this tall
material wouldn't stand up like it would
I mean we're just catching up with the
rest of the world here are there the
machines in other countries
Australia challenge it's always been
challenge always my company is
associated with some Partners from the
University of Taiwan and we've been
doing this in China for they've been
doing this in China for many many years
but entally you could buy a piece of
Machinery that actually separates all of
it seeds huh oil uh any any of the stack
so what is your company name again the
industrious that to write that down I
might
pie okay thank you other questions
before we go on to the next
speaker
here okay here and then here I'm curious
what you'll be doing next year or any
research on like the systems work what
follows hempwell how to deal with all
the fiber
in the field for next year yeah I mean
Chris can help me answer that because
she's been she and she and Larry smart
have been thinking about this I mean one
of the things that we want to do too
right now we just have uh these these um
variety trials just on Cornell land we
would like to spread that out some
throughout the state I mean right now
producers several produc producers are
just growing Anka but we would like to
get some variety trials more widespread
so we can get a better idea of the best
varieties for New York State conditions
not just on our experimental Farmland um
so that's one but Chris I don't know if
you want to contribute more to that can
you guys all hear me so um yeah in in
terms of on Farm or or rotational
strategies um there's a scientist Matt
Ryan who's in the soil and crop science
uh section of sips and he's going to be
looking at integrating hemp into his
system study and then in addition to
that I think you know one of the things
that we can do fairly fairly easily is
right now we're looking at what is hemp
following at the 29 farms and there are
some interesting things cuz there were
some Growers that you know sprayed and
were ready to prep prep for soybean but
they couldn't get their soybean in
because of the rain and now they're
putting hemp in so we'll be able to tell
you know did the herbicides that were
put on to prep for soybean are they
attack you know are they an issue for
hemp so in some ways the 29 Farms are
helping us with that the other thing
that will be helped with is that we can
go back to them next year and see if
they're having issues you know what are
they following and are they having
issues so we can follow that for a while
so so right now we are developing our
systems approach but we can use the 29
Farms sort of as a as a real life you
know scientific study to see what
happens so um and any of you you know if
you if you once you guys start growing
hemp and you know anything that you
found has has affected the hemp either
that you did before the hemp goes in the
ground or after it's coming off going in
the next next year I mean that's all
really valuable information that you
know we hope to learn from you
guys any other questions before we move
on yes I was curious to know if you
watered this or if you just relied on
here yeah we've had plenty of rain you
did irrigate it once to start with
didn't you Jamie um we had one dry spell
in June and at that time we weren't sure
the DEA was going to allow us to plant
in all of our location so like we need
this to survive so we did irrigate it um
for I don't know just a couple hours one
morning at the very early seedling stage
but um none of the other trials were
irrigated we just were just like we need
this to survive what happens if it cooks
and so there was an act of desperation
here just to make sure but um and it
turns out it probably would have been
fine but um but none of the other trials
have been irrigated
you obviously it's been an unusual year
um last year was so dry and this year is
so wet and if you put the two years
together it averages out but but that's
not the way the plants act they don't
work on averages um so you know with all
the rain that we've had this season each
week we wonder well is the foset going
to turn off and then it's going to turn
dry the rest of the summer and you just
never know but it's it's just it just
keeps on going so so with I mean we got
this planted late later maybe several
weeks maybe a month later than what we
really wanted to plant it but yet it's
it's growing very tall and so you know
we've had plenty of moisture to keep it
going this season so other questions yes
do you have any faculty positions
opening up at Cornell or anyone know but
for cannabis genetics I know and a lot
of you people are kind of taking on this
as a new plant but what about people who
specialize in Hampton cannabis turn that
over Chris but I'm not aware of any new
faculty positions right
now all right we do have new faculty
positions but but uh the the ones that
we have right now are not um they're not
cemp
related shouldn't they be um well so I
think actually to to answer that
question quite seriously I think that I
think that um hiring a faculty member
for a 40 30 or 40 years stent or 20 30
years stent um you know is a is a
serious Endeavor and and I think that we
don't know yet how well hemp is going to
do in New York I mean this is really the
first time that it's been out and so you
know I think we need to give it a season
or two to figure out how we plug that in
to our research portfolio um and and
footprint across the state you know to
make sure that you know we still have
have folks that are working with our
vegetable Growers and our field crops
Growers um you know just to make sure
we're very well-rounded and so I think
um the people that are on hemp are you
know we're all in and I I feel like you
know we're we're covering it quite well
and um in the future if it continues to
expand then we would certainly look into
that area I mean we have the advantage
Chris mentioned earlier that there are
11 of us um on the faculty working on
this and um we we're all coming from our
different areas of specializations put
together as a package where we're
cooperating together to you know to to
look at the complete package so it's not
just breeding or genetics but it's all
different areas of of research that
we're uh working on here and that's
really what it's going to take that's
what it's going to take the work because
it's not just one area specialization
that we need to be focusing on but we
need to look at all aspects of of
production and so forth so okay yes hi
I'm curious uh is there a thought about
uh building communities in terms of um
uh worker cooperatives and such so that
uh the extraction devices and the
processing devices can be brought back
to the farm farming communities that's
all where all the money is you know it's
one thing to grow the plant but to
manufacture and farm and and to process
uh into you know the 500 different us is
that's where really the money is so I'm
wondering if there's thought about that
yeah I'm not totally sure what your
question is about the uses of the
equipment back to the farm so for
instance in North Carolina there's a big
movement of building farm worker
cooperatives where they will buy the
extraction equ so that the farm that
money stays on the farm okay right if
we're seeing this in marijuana on the
west coast Farmers don't make any money
it's all in the processing and and
building the market so I'm curious as to
whether Pell or new YK state is
thoughtful and thinking about building
those sort of marketability yeah so we
from New York I think is here Pard me
Cheryl are you here there you are okay
yes so we have Cheryl from Harvest New
York Corner corate extension do you need
to mic no and I don't have an answer to
that right now I am familiar with what's
going on in North Carolina I don't know
that any thoughts been given that to
that yet I would say too it's just too
new yet so far um so um I know Chris is
where's Chris here he's going to be
talking about talking about processors
towards the end of it um but I don't
have an answer right now to it's a great
question
though okay um let me move on WE we'll
have more opportunities for questions
we're not done yet this morning um but
let me move on before I introduce the
next speaker though um I might mention
some of you may have noticed or maybe
you didn't notice the tall fence that's
around our experimental Farm here um so
that um fence is there because we have a
lot of deer problems around here and um
you know you see some Ford species
behind you alal and so forth if we
didn't have some way to control the deer
um we wouldn't be able to to collect the
data for our research purposes that we
need to collect so so I don't know Ian
people have asked me if deer are a
problem on hemp and I don't really don't
know the answer to that we haven't had
experience with it yet have have any of
you U heard anything about whether deer
will bother hemp at all Yes uh in
Vermont um I was told that the seedlings
um the deer really liked but as the hemp
grew tall and more fibrous the deer just
left it alone okay too much fiber in
there so it might it might depend thear
really if we didn't have this fence here
they would be eating our alala but
leaving the hemp alone okay I in
col
okay do you know if it's mainly on uh on
young growth yeah he was growing for CBD
but he didn't say at what point they
were okay yeah I'm growing for CBD in
Oregon and we've had no problem with
here at all and we have multiple like
four different Farms going right now
different areas so we've been very
fortunate none of them PR down okay did
everybody hear that so he said in Oregon
they they haven't had any problems at
all with the air so okay let me
introduce the next speaker um you know
anytime you have more and more acreage
of any kind of a crop species and and
right now we don't have that a lot of
acreage but it's it's growing um but
whenever you have that um it's it's
going to be susceptible the various
disease and insect problems um so Dr
Gary burstrom He's the um the chair of
the department or of the section of
Plant Pathology and plant microbiology
within the school of integrated plant
science uh and he does a lot of research
and extension activities on diseases of
field crops and um Elson Shields our
entomologist was going to be here uh but
he's um some things came up and he's not
able to be here today but he did tell me
about a few insect problems but Gary if
you've seen any insects in your okay
I'll let you talk about diseases first
thanks Don so uh I I uh will confess
that I'm I'm a student of a uh of hemp
diseases at this point and trying to
learn everything I can along I suspect
with a lot of you here so uh as as Don
said I've worked in uh in field crops
for a number of years and uh we uh are
are looking forward to getting a better
handle and inventory on what some of the
pest problems are on Industrial Hemp and
I've also spent some time talking to
some colleagues in some other parts of
the country and some of these recent
visitors from Canada about some of the
things they've encountered but uh by and
large we're going to use these variety
plots uh in itha Geneva and other places
and these distributed Farms across New
York state to try to inventory all of
the uh pest issues that uh that we find
and typical for a new crop like this uh
a lot of these pathogens tend to be
rather specific in the in the crop
species that they attack so we could
reasonably expect as we expand the
acreage and intensity of the crop we may
not see a lot of these pest problems now
but we uh we can anticipate that they
would increase the more that we grow the
crop uh intensively on a particular Farm
or or more
extensively um so I think most of you
aware there are no pesticides of any
class uh used on the crop at this point
and that includes fungicides and that
also includes uh seed uh treatment
fungicides uh Dr alen Taylor is going to
talk a little bit later uh on the
program about the some seed treatment
technology uh one of the things we would
be concerned about is what protection we
need to get these seed seed seedlings
out of the ground and uh we one thing we
have noticed in a number of the
locations at at at fairly low incidents
not really causing an economic problem
but we could see even in this fairly dry
season uh we have seen a number of the
water mold uh pathogens attacking the
the uh seed and seedlings uh that under
less favorable conditions for sewing the
crop we could anticipate more problem
and uh in the vast majority of field
crops and vegetables we uh except for
Strictly Organic production there's
often a uh a seed applied fungicide or
water mold active uh material so that's
something that we would be looking at in
the future as a a possible uh means of
controlling some of these problems um
we've also seen a fairly small incidence
of some uh of some wilting and and Crown
and root symptoms at at low incidents
and I could uh share a whole long list
of Latin names with you of the kind of
organisms that we're finding there but
this this point we're just taking an
inventory and uh some of this goes back
to what Chris was talking about the
microbiome there are a lot of fungi and
bacteria and other things that are just
normally present and uh just Define some
of these things doesn't necessarily mean
that they're they're causing some kind
of a plague on Industrial Hemp so part
of the research going forward will be
taking some of these organisms uh trying
to inoculate them onto healthy plants
and seeing if they do uh cause disease
and uh down the road uh I mean I'm very
excited about this uh breeding program
that'll be going on we'll look at some
of the principles uh plant pathogens
that we find associated with the crop
and may be doing uh or someone in the
future will be doing some purposeful
screening of some of these varieties
with some of these uh potential pathogen
problems um it's been mentioned a couple
of times about cropping rotations and as
a plant pathologist that's that's a A
Center focus for me is not only can the
organism survive in the soil or
potentially come in with the seed
but in many cases some of these
organisms uh will survive on the debris
that's left behind in the field and that
be the bridge from run growing season to
another and coming back what I said
about the specificity of many of these
crop diseases uh so for instance if we
were planting this crop after a grain
crop like corn or something like that or
a small grain there'd be very very few
organisms what would interact and cause
problems on those two crops uh the
closer they are related so we could
expect some dcot plants to be a little
more closely related uh to the uh hemp
than than some of our monocot so we're
going to be looking over time to see if
there's any carryover of some of these
pests one that does concern me long term
and has been a problem in Canada and
some other places is white mold uh it's
a fungal problem that is already quite
uh rampant in our legum crops and some
of our other broadleaf vegetable crops
so in soybean production probably our
biggest disease problem right now is uh
is sclerotinia white mold and that's a
very broad Host range fungus and it
survives the survival structures of the
fungus called scler roia they will
survive in the soil for a number of
years and uh so certainly white mold is
something we'll be looking at in the
hemp and particularly in rotations that
would include vegetable beans dry beans
uh soybean things highly susceptible
crops to to white mold so uh rotations
are very important in this sense as well
um so I don't want to talk at you a lot
here I want to make you aware that uh
that we're very interested in learning
more uh first about what the diseases
and potential disease problems might be
and obviously the long-term interest is
how to manage those uh I will mention uh
two people from my program Kevin Meyers
in the back year and Jamie Cummings will
be working in our lab to do a lot of the
diagnosis and uh of potential disease
problems and and work with this uh with
this new crop so um we would be
appreciative of anybody seeing anything
in their fields um and and letting us
know uh we'd be glad to diagnose
problems in our laboratory get out in
your fields and look so please please
keep us informed and let us know how how
we can be a help to you so um another
thing just to quickly say that one of
the main advantages against diseases is
just the vigorous rapid growth of this
crop and that's one of the things I've
I've learned from talking to colleagues
in other places yeah we see some Leaf
spots yeah we see some of this and that
uh but the crop basically outgrows them
and and that is an advantage with this
crop uh and that it's timely planted in
appropriate soils um another thing we're
not weed scientists in our in our
program but uh Kevin has been taking
some notes in the various plots about
weed density and you know a great
take-home message here is he said a a
tremendous correlation between the weed
uh density in these plots and what the
original Stand was from the emergence
success in emergence of those plots so
the best defense against weeds
especially in the absence of any
herbicides to use is just to have a good
crop establishment have a good initial
stand and very often uh that this will
be sufficient to out compete the weed so
a pretty good strategy if you can do
that any any questions or comments some
observations others have made yeah
please what is the closest uh normal
plant in New York that family
relationship to hemp and if you I I
would say hops hops would be the closest
can you then say that whatever attacks
hops diseases or pests
similarly probably gonna attack me o
only as a very general uh uh statement
uh e even within a a plant family
there's tremendous specificity in uh in
these pathogens there are some things
that would be candidates that way a lot
of the things that attack through the
soil the water molds the Feria rise
octonia some of these things tend to
have a fairly wide Host range a lot of
the leaf spotting type organisms are
really rather specific um and I think
things like the Downey Milo's Chris
would be pretty separate from the Hops
and the and the uh the hemp in this case
so uh the more this the more pathogen is
specialized uh the the you know the less
we worry about that uh for related crops
but definitely that's something we'd be
looking at and there are some candidate
things we'd be looking at uh but I still
come back to to white mold being the
biggest concern that way because it's uh
very very broad Host range the weeds as
well as cultivated
crops anybody observe anything in your
uh on your farms at this point
uh okay we'll keep us in mind if we can
help yeah David jry in in regard to some
of the pest uh Farm viability is funding
um Jen Gilbert Jenkins at Morrisville
with some plots this summer specifically
to look at insect pests I don't know
that she's doing much with diseases but
certainly with insects and she might
have some good information to share
Chris Becker has been interacting with
her and we have had a few things arrive
at either Chris's lab or mine in
connection with that but yeah we would
absolutely love to plug in with that and
get all the learning we can out of out
out of these plots that are established
yeah and we've also provided funding for
her she's planning to do a Statewide uh
trial next summer uh on fertilization in
him okay and on 10 different farms
around the state so we provided some
funding for her to to buy the Seed
already for that so that's good to know
thank you thank you um Don would you
like to say a few things about uh What
uh insects that uh yeah so again Elson
Shields has been working on this he's in
our anology department but unfortunately
he was not able to make it here after
all uh but he did send me uh a list of a
few insects that he's observed in the uh
the hemp uh around the state so far uh
one of them is a lius bug it's maybe a
quarter inch uh big bug there that um
eats the growing tips of the of the U of
the plant but also the reproductive
parts the floral parts of the plant
which obviously could be very critical
on the grain types or the Dual Purpose
types there so that's one of the things
that he's keeping a watch on another
insect um which is actually prevalent on
a lot of species is potato Leaf Hopper
and we have problems with that on our
Alfalfa uh if we don't spray an
insecticide or use a resistant variety
uh but apparently he's been seeing it on
on Industrial Hemp as well a third one
that he mentioned is thrips that's a
very very small insect uh but that could
get into the floral Parts uh they eat
pollen and so forth um and some of the
things Elson didn't mention it but some
of the things that I've read is that uh
people are suspecting that some of the
major insect problems on corn could
actually be a problem on hemp too uh I
don't know the validity of that or
whether people are speculating at this
point but things like corn army worm and
some others there so so it is critical
that entomologists be looking just like
Gary does with the diseases there that
we have entomologists looking at insect
problems um so that we know what uh
challenges that we have in front of us
so um so if you have questions about
insects I probably can't answer them but
you can ask I would think that the
insect pressure would build over time
once there's more crop available oh
absolutely same for diseases and insects
um you know as as the acreage increases
across the state um certainly there's
potential for more problems will be
there as well good
point other questions or
comment okay so um I'm going to turn
this over then to uh Dr Alan Taylor um
one of the problems that we've already
been confronted with there's one of
these varieties in here which I think is
this short one is it Jamie that had low
germination uh one of these was anyway
was it down there okay but one of the
varieties um was from seed that was a
year older than the rest of them and the
germination rate was really low and uh
even though Jamie compensated with that
to have the same number of pure live
seeds per square foot so that we're
comparing apples and apples and not
apples and oranges um still the um the
stand density was not as great as some
of the other varieties so the seed's
important as Gary said we need to get a
a good stand establishment so we're very
pleased that Dr Alan Taylor from the
horiculture section in the school of
integrated plant science is working on
the the seed aspects of this thanks for
the the
introduction as Chris mentioned there's
a number of states that have really have
doing research on hemp and a colleague
of mine from North Dakota State as an
agronomist was given a talk last year
and really talking about seed quality
issues St establishment issues a lot of
these seed related things and my program
here at Cornell at the Geneva a
experiment station we interact with a
lot of different crops vegetable crops
but also industrial crops so I thought
at the time I said this would be really
a
good uh project for my laboratory to get
involved in and then here less than a
year later here we are whereas Chris
says we have this Cornell hemp team it's
really a Consortium of Faculty uh with a
wide range of expertise all kind of
focus on this so I think we're going to
be able to make quite a bit of uh
progress and a relatively short amount
of time as we're we're working on this
also as Chris mentioned really good
partnership with aged markets and things
like that and being able to uh kind of
work at the regulatory level with this
and getting it out as well as the
research and the Outreach that we're
really so good at here at
Cornell we obviously see as we're
looking at here that that with seed
obviously the plant breeding and
genetics has a key role in what the
plant growth and development is but
another key aspect of seed is is the
seed quality and really the quality is
sure as you're buying seed if you're
spending that at least $50 an acre to
establish it's a major input into
growing a a really a field crop like as
an agronomic crop as hemp would be so
you want to make sure that you're really
first of all getting the good quality
seed um as right now for these trials we
have all the the uh the grain types or
the multi-purpose types here and there's
also other trials with the fiber types
we have 17 seed lots that we're working
on uh about half of those are from
Canada the the rest are from Europe from
Eastern Europe poon Ukraine over to
Italy France are the production the
origin of those seeds so we're looking
at a pretty good kind of cross-section
of commercial seed all those seeds have
to be imported here into the United
States so there are aspects that really
need to be addressed as far as the
quality for that sort of uh Commerce
coming into this country
there's really two aspects of seed
quality we always think well the seeds
got to germinate to grow definitely the
case but another aspect especially those
that are not involved with agronomic
crops or or different seeded crops is
what we call the seed Purity what the
Purity is is if you're buying a bag of
seed and that could be a bag of wheat
could be a bag of hemp seeds is what
else is in that bag you want for example
down there you want the hemp the anchor
variety but what else could be in that
bag there could be weed seeds present
there could be other crop seeds present
and also what we just generically call
this inner material just other materials
be broken seeds trash materials Stones
things like that so in these 17 seed
lots that we're working with now uh
Michael loose who's Works in my program
he was the former manager of the of our
New York State seed testing laboratory
and that seed testing laboratory is now
moved to Albany but with Michael's
actually running the uh the germinations
and the purities on those we're seeing
some of these seed lots and again I
don't have enough data right now we're
still doing this to have as a handout
but some of these over 5% iner material
so basically we say it's pretty trashy
seed that we're getting again if
somebody's buying this you want to make
sure that you're getting good quality
seed but probably the the the two keys
that we're really concerned about in
this Purity are weed seeds for us to
import seeds to receive the seeds uh
there has to be an aphis permit
conducted where that what we call a
noxious weed exam noxious weeds are
seeds which are really defined by law
that are harmful to agriculture so you
don't want to have those in the bag
because you're also planting those and
also just other common weed seeds things
like that that may also be present so so
we're going through these samples right
now in and just kind of testing trying
to get as much information on the
quality
aspect for example
with the the Canadian seed lots that
we've gotten is they're close Partners
to us they have their seed certification
system just like Phil has a seed
certification program here the basis of
the two programs are the same as we look
at seed certification they have
different levels they have a
certification number one level and
number two so how do those differ they
really differ based on the quality the
level one is the high quality seed is so
the germination uh needs to be 85% or
higher and just two uh weed seeds can be
present in just one other crop seed in a
25 gram sample where are these other
crop seeds coming from you ask we do we
do not have a herbicide that can be used
in the seed production field so if there
was oats and we've seen oats as as
contaminants as other crop seeds
sunflower a lot of those seeds are also
coming over in your seeds so again we
want that to be as clean as
possible just as we've uh again let's
use that
criteria with the 85% germination and
the 70% germination of the 17 seed lots
that is being tested within the Cornell
system this
year only five of those had 85%
germination and higher so again we
really need to have high quality seeds
for that good initial stand
establishment
nine of those which is about half had
over 70% so so again what you know when
this eventually up to be a commercial
crop what you're getting is very
important because that really starts the
basis for that so that's kind of where
we're at right now is in this I'll say
characterization the quality assurance
aspect to make sure that the farmer
ultimately has high quality
seed the next part is it's already been
mentioned there are issues early
germination events early seedling
emergent stand establishment issues with
the hemp crop and again I learned from
this from my colleagues in out of state
so this is not a New York problem it's
not unique to us they have the problems
in Canada they have it
throughout the seeds in themselves I'll
just say are just have generally a low
Vigor they tend to be weak germinators
once they get going you can see they
they grow like heck but that early phase
which is a very very sensitive phase and
we need to get the plan establishment
again for that crop to canopy which is
providing the weed management as well so
so everything really rotates and getting
off to a good start with the hemp
seed now since we're not able to use uh
labeled of chemical pesticides including
chemical seed treatments then my
laboratory is interested from the
research point view of looking at some
development of some technology so
that'll be kind of where we're going
with our research two areas one is Gary
mentioned uh a lot of the the damping
off organisms which are going to be
ubiquitous in our soils here pums things
like that what sort of a of of a seed
treatment could we use not a chemical
seed treatment like a captan or tham or
or an apron but what else could we use
that we could still apply and so we're
kind of going to our toolbox where I
work with organic vegetable seed
Productions and not seed production but
seed quality as well and so what can we
take from that area as an organic seed
treatment so that's an area that we're
going to be moving into that so we can
get some protection uh from some of
these early uh attacking early soil born
pathogens the second aspect is again
they are inherently low Vigor seeds
and again we've don't know enough yet to
really to be able to really Define the
Vigor except doing a germination test
but we're we're relying on on people
that have worked in this crop for a long
time so in that regards uh again kind of
some other work that we're doing is what
we're calling bio stimulants bios
stimulants are compounds these are not
pesticides that are applied to plants to
enhance plant growth and development so
we've already done work with seed
treatments with some of these
biostimulant type of materials natural
type of materials no pesticidal effect
on them at all what would they do to a
hemp seed so again you know we have a
lot to do ahead of us so we'll be ready
for next growing season to actually to
test some of these things but that kind
of gives you in kind of a a quick
summary where the seed science and
technology program is at the Geneva egg
experiment station with Cornell uh
focusing right now in the seed testing
aspect seed quality just to make sure we
we can characterize the seed lots that
we're working with but then the the
future research and development really
kind of rolling up our sleeves and
developing some very practical seed
treatments that could be used on hemp
seeds to enhance plant establishment and
early season growth thank
[Applause]
you any questions along the seed
line yes I'm surprised by the substan
reduction in germination from that 2017
to 2016 Lots was my understanding was
that 2016 lot was the one that needed to
have the seating rate adjusted and I'm
wondering if that's somewhat more unique
to hemp maybe because of the high oil
content um because most other crops I'm
familiar with wouldn't show such a
dramatic difference between was just one
year as long as that seed was handled
reasonably well a really good question
and we're looking at the issues of seed
quality but also in the case
uh if we have carryover seeds uh things
like that uh there are uh kind of as we
look kind of cross the board of seeds
some seeds are just naturally shortlived
seed like a soybean happens to be a
shortlived seed other crops just tend to
be like a tomato seed is a very long
live so there's just sort of like my
lifespan compared to you know the my pet
dog the dog has a shorter natural
lifespan than I do so you have some of
that so so the hemp kind of fits into
that as far as just the genetic basis it
is a high oil content seeds but some
seeds so there's not a strict rule of
thumb on on oil content for example the
tomato seeds which is a very long live
seed is a very high oil or lipid content
seed so there's a lot of things we
really don't know but but from again
kind of what we have seen is that the
storage especially in a carryover
situation can be an issue and so for
example the these companies that uh
we've talked about up in Canada the
seeds that they're producing last year
the seeds that were using so they they
are produced harvested they have to be
carried
over of these three seed lots of Anka
that we got all the same variety three
different seed Lots from this is from
their germination conducted up in Canada
from two are in the upper 80s one is in
the 70 and I
said why you know in in a nice sort of a
way why did that happen are these
carryover seeds and they said no they're
all har Ed one was harvested a little
later and may have had a little bit
higher moisture content that went into
that over winter storage that higher
moisture the seeds are just going to age
faster so so there is just so you can't
even say variet how things are going to
respond you really have to look at the
seed lot level but even like I said in
the example where we have lots and lots
of that seeds for the commercial uh uh
use this year there are differences
between those three seed lots and again
they are attributing it just to that
it's high higher moisture content we can
check that moisture content we have you
know we can we can look at that but
after the Aging has happened and Seed
there's nothing we we we can't go retro
on this but but at least we can
characterize that is knowing what the uh
the moisture should be and safe storage
very good question thank you yes sir
that moisture content is that dictated
by when you
harvest early Harvest more moisture late
Harvest less moisture as an example is
that what is that possible so so what is
going on during seed development and the
later phases of seed development is is
the seed on the mother plant is drying
down what they would like to do is
ideally Harvest at the right moisture
content and then that could go right
into storage however if it is immature
seed it's going to have a higher
moisture or if it's rained or so so so
that seed moisture is just going up and
down with whatever the environment is
going on so if it's a high relative
humidity
if there's wetness it's going to be
picking up moisture from there so the
ideal thing is that you want to harvest
at the right moisture content and then
go into the storage and things like that
have you determined what that moisture
content is I I only have some things
that I've written but we've not actually
characterized that so I don't I don't
want to I don't want to speculate on on
that right now but thank you that's a
that's a that's a good point because
again is generally when when we're in
more of the seed or the seed buyer right
now New York is not a seed producer we
really are relying on what has happened
Upstream with the seed companies what
they've done with seed processing or
what we call seed conditioning sorting
the seeds doing things like that uh and
as I and and I just want to head one
other point on on seed size again as
we're doing this Purity we look at the
seeds we're also taking we have the
Thousand uh seed weight or thousand
kernel weight they call it but you do
see varietal differences some are just
larger seed than others but even with in
the sample we have there's a large
difference in seed size there's small
seeds medium seeds large large seeds and
again we want uniformity of germination
we want uniformity of stand
establishment that does not set us on
the right foot if we're already starting
off with a wide range of seed Sciences
within the same seed lot so again
something else uh uh something else we
need to kind of look at a little bit
there too uh any other yes sir so just
with uh your other grain and and crops
you have seed seed Foundation here that
checks for quality and and uh D inerts
and everything else to me it looks like
the hemp is kind of a
rogue introduction to the to the seed
industry and I would suspect that
importing these seeds from other
countries similar to grain you're going
to have those imperfections you're going
to have those variations so I'm assuming
uh aphis EG and markets uh seed
Foundation they're going to work at
developing uh some some basic standards
for the seed or is this just going to be
a open Forum on whatever whatever comes
in
well multiple points that you're making
and all really all really good with
because the the bottom line is we want
to assure a New York grower that's going
to be planting the hemp that they have
good quality seed uh I I think if we
look at Canada Canada started this 1998
so they've been doing they've been
growing hemp for many years and these
seed compan I would say are pretty
mature they're not MPA type of companies
that are just you know going out here
whacking some seeds off and threshing
them out and selling them now these
These are big operations and when we're
buying you know a 750 kilogram totes of
those that are coming in that's a big
seed production facility that they have
I've not seen it but it's they're
they're very mature in that they've also
have their own seed certification
standards for for example to make that
number one certified has to have the
high germination of 85 or better but
just a few seeds now if it turns out say
just one other crop seed and then two
weed seeds if that sample they pull has
four weed seeds in it even though the
germination is 90% it drops it down
automatically to their certified level
number two the grower doesn't really
know that they they just know it's a
it's a level two certification it's a
lower grade they don't know why they
have but but we can track that down and
know so so I think in and their system
they're using both the Purity as a
criteria for high quality and the
germination and it's really it's well
it's it's a good system it's a little
different than what we do here in the
States but it is a good system so you
know if you're getting that number one
certified that you're getting very good
SE yes sir so the numbers you gave us
earlier on the rates of germination
those were provided by the um vendor at
their certified levels okay there
there's two things so when I talked
about the Anka the three seed lots of
Anka I don't even have the third seed
lot yet everything's pretty pretty new
and then it's it's not only 50 mil from
from itha to Geneva but it's just
cumbersome I'll just put it that way and
moving seeds around even within the
Coronel system so we have not done any
of the testing on these three ankle Lots
what I'm saying is we do have samples
from all of these types along with four
other fiber types that is where we did
the actual germination and we're doing
the Purity right now we're we're that
new into this when we have this field
day two weeks from today in Geneva I'm
going to be able to talk more than I can
now just because we're the you know
we're generating the data as we speak
you'll be able to compare that data to
what they certifi that's that's
ultimately what I want to be able to do
yeah is is we're taking out of a little
baggie a sample compared to them going
through their large inventory so we want
to make sure that what we're saying is
representative not that anybody's right
or wrong it's just being really
representative yeah exactly good yes uh
how do you find deal with uh seed death
I'm not sure if there's patent laws or
things like that surrounding seed um so
say somebody took a a top of headed one
of your plants here and took the seed
and replanted it what kind of
repercussions would there be legal those
are more the legal aspects and we kind
of talked about some of that but but
basically it's it's not legal you'd be
dealing with trespass in addition to the
yeah there so there's I'll say multiple
issues around doing something like right
so how is Cornell able to import is it
under the context of research Jamie
really did a Yan's job of of doing this
Jamie you want to talk on on acquiring
the seats for Corno I think I think
Chris is going to cover all of that
regulatory stuff okay okay perfect let's
stay tuned and we'll get that question
answered for you yes sir yeah did you do
a moisture test on the incoming seed
from Canada so you know what least level
it was
there we have not gathered that data but
what we do have with the samples that
are still in the original bag so we can
go ahead and Sample out of that what
we're really concerned about is when we
get a small when you get a 100 gram
sample which is like a cup full of seeds
and that's in an open porous container
and it's a humid day or a dry day that's
all going to change so we really need to
go back the best we can to that and then
take a deep core out of that then we
will have a more representative but yeah
as you know as every this whole season
kind of progressed and getting things
there's a lot of would a could have
should is and there always isn't doing
research but this was really a hurry up
type of a year to get as far as we are
right now I think next year we'll be
more in place with doing those quality
right as soon as we receive the seeds
excellent point we need to be really
good seedsmen here on our side as well
okay yes ma'am do you um do all of these
plants have a THC and cbdc profile have
they been tested yet and is it available
anywhere for us so we can know what THC
quantity or what CBD and what types of
CBD is it cbda cbdb just CBD do the have
have these varieties been tested for
that yet that's all to be done correct
Chris did you hear the question yeah so
the question was have have all the
varieties been tested sorry for THC and
CBD levels um and the varieties were
going growing here we test here um but
in Canada there's a actually a really
informative website um like on Tero
Canada fact sheets and they have fact
sheets that cover lots and lots of
different things and one of the things
they have is a list of varieties and um
those they found to be low or high THC
contents and and I can't remember off
the top of my head if they have cdb in
there as well um but that's a a very
informative site for
you okay
thank you really really good questions
and uh again there's a lot of Unsolved
questions but we we are addressing these
so so thank you very much for your
comments and questions okay thank you
Alan I need that uh other
microphone okay so so our last uh
speaker is Chris log who um I really
appreciate came the long distance I mean
most of us are right here on campus or
with Alan little over an hour away but
Chris came quite a distance uh from
Albany to be here um Chris is the
director of the division of PL industry
in the New York State Department of
Agriculture markets and he'll be talking
about some of these regulatory issues
like the question that was asked um as
well as potential markets here so thank
you very very much for the opportunity
to be here today I know I'm going to get
lots of questions so I'm glad I don't
have notes that I'm going to follow um
I'm just going to start out a little bit
and tell you sort of how we got here um
Gary described himself as a student of
hemp diseases I have become a student of
hemp it's the been the School of Hard
Knocks there's some people sitting out
here that have been very very helpful to
me in learning about this crop um so
it's been a couple of years that we've
been working on hemp and as all of you
know we started out at the department
with a pretty conservative uh program
that limited our research Partners or
limited research uh permits to folks who
were uh affiliated with colleges and
universities and institutions of higher
education uh this spring we were able to
open it up and and bring some Farmers
into it and some other folks uh and then
of course added a number of research
partners with the uh Anka trial this
summer um so we're definitely sort of on
the track towards a a more liberal
approach to this um I want to talk a
little bit about you know the Authority
for any of us to be doing this so the
Authority for any of us to be engaged in
this uh comes from the 2014 farm bill um
and basically what the 2014 Farm Bill
did and I'll just paraphrase uh
basically it enabled uh universities or
institutions of higher education and
state Departments of Agriculture to
engage in industrial research pilot
programs so on the good side the farm
bill doesn't Define what a pilot
research program is and it doesn't
necessarily Define what
commercialization is that in a way is
sort of a double-edged sword it's a good
thing it's not defined it lets us sort
of figure out what the boundaries are
but I think the other thing that you
need to keep in mind if this is
something that you're considering doing
that at some point along the way
somebody might say hey you're up against
the fence you're going too far okay and
uh we are dealing quite a bit with uh
Department of Justice and
DEA and um I have to tell you they've
been extremely helpful to us I think
they've been pretty responsive with
Cornell and Sunni
Morrisville but this is out of the
ordinary for them they regulate
controlled substances from cradled grave
in the case of hemp they regulate the
seed and then they step away from it so
this is new territory for them as well
the other piece that I'll throw out
there uh is that the farm bill will be
uh up for Renewal or renegotiation in
2018 and so uh we need to be aware that
you know there could potentially be some
changes in that language in the farm
bill and so that's one of the things
that's on my tick list from a policy
perspective uh working with some of our
policy folks in Albany and in Washington
DC to make sure that we can continue to
move forward so uh going forward with
the 2018 farm bill you could see the
same language that was in 2014 you could
see a step back away from that that
maybe restricts us more or you could see
from a federal level maybe some
liberalization um so we need to be aware
of that from the policy perspective the
other thing I'll say on the federal side
is is that you know we've had some very
high level discussions with uh some of
the federal folks and and again they are
uh frankly they don't answer a lot of
questions directly so if you start
asking me questions about federal policy
I'm probably going to be a little Cy too
um there is also if you go on our
website you know you can you can check
out a number of documents that are very
very important from a from a regulatory
and an authority perspective uh the
three things that I would say you want
to be looking at and be aware of on the
federal level are the wording of the
2014 Farm Bill uh the wording in the
2016 Omnibus budget act that's very
important as well uh and then the third
piece is is a guidance document from I
think July or August of last year that
came out from DEA FDA and USDA so those
are sort of the three guiding documents
that are out there there's still a whole
lot of gray in this what we've tried to
do as we've moved forward with this uh
is to build a program that is if you
will a safe harbor for folks who want to
get involved in this we want to try to
keep you uh as Farmers Growers
processors what have you uh sort of in a
safe place from the federal perspective
but at the same time trying to move this
ahead and learn as much as we possibly
can um one thing I do want to uh
actually make sure everybody knows Kate
in the back there Kate is the person who
if you call our office and you call the
hemp 800 number that was announced a few
week weeks ago you will most likely talk
with Kate uh and she will if she can't
answer your question she's going to take
down your information and and get it get
the question to somebody who can help
you um so bear with us on that we're
sort of building this as we
go I want to make a just a quick comment
on the trial behind me here um this is
probably the best hemp I've seen not
that I've seen a lot but I was in
Kentucky a couple of weeks ago for the
hemp regulatory comp conference and we
were on several farms and basically we
were hearing all the same things that
all the Cornell faculty have said
today uh seed
quality uh emergence competition with
weeds the lack of herbicides if you're
if you're in a situation where you would
use an herbicide or another crop
protectant on this we're we're coming up
against all the same issues that have
been been identified in other states uh
so we're learning a lot as we go
along so a little bit about the process
going forward um I've from a from an
administrative perspective I've kind of
felt for the last two and a half years
like I've been a little bit behind the
curve on the timing on this um and so
we're always trying we're always on a
scramble to get things done and so our
goal going forward this year is uh for
2018 I should say is to try to roll out
um
the application process very very soon
and so I'm going to throw some dates out
there please don't come call me if this
doesn't come true and give me a hard
time I'd like it to open up uh for
applications during the month of August
that's this month probably towards the
end of the month because we've got some
uh vacations and some other professional
meetings that we our staff are engaged
in um and what that would do is
basically we'd probably leave that
application period open for uh several
months maybe into the middle or end of
October that's going to give folks
adequate time to develop their research
plan and again I keep circling back
around to that farm bill that allows us
to do research not
commercialization so the thing that I'm
going to weigh most heavily on an
application is what's your research plan
what are you going to be able to bring
to the table to offer uh as far as new
knowledge or knowledge
and that again we take a very very broad
approach to research it can be agronomic
it can be uh Pest Management it can be
marketing it can be product development
you name it you can probably make the
argument that it's
research um so basically getting that
out there August September October of
this year is going to give you folks uh
time to develop a good plan it's going
to give you time to start talking with
your seed suppliers in Canada the
European Union wherever you uh decide
you're going to get your seed from and
it also gives us a little bit more time
we actually applied for our DEA import
permit on March 17th of this year and uh
the DEA came out I think on June 27 or
something and they interviewed several
of us they took all of our personal
information names of our eldest children
where they were located all that kind of
good stuff and um so we're waiting on
our permit so next year hopefully that
permit will be in place soon I'd like it
to be in place before we go out with our
application for 2018 I don't know if
that's realistic or not so once that
permit is in place that's going to give
us the opportunity at the department to
play the role of the Importer so what
that means is if you were a uh uh
research partner with the Department in
2018 you would figure out what seed
variety you wanted or varieties you
wanted you would talk with the seed
company Canada the European Union
wherever and uh make all the
arrangements Financial shipping what
have you to get the seed into the
country uh and when it's imported it
would be delivered to Albany and at that
point you would come to Albany and pick
it up we would release it to you um so
that's kind of what we're looking at
going going forward so we're hoping for
a much more streamlined
process um definitely invested in this
want to be uh as helpful as we can to
folks um a couple things from the
processing perspective that was the
other thing um that I was asked to talk
about today so two things I think I want
to sort of talk a little bit about sort
of what I think of what's going on in
the industry I kind of look at the two
major issues that I think are facing us
almost almost like a set of book ends
you got the seed issue okay and we've
talked about a lot of the physical
attributes of the seed um as far as seed
quality emergence all that type of thing
you have the political the regulatory
aspects of it where can you get it it's
hard to get into the country okay need a
lot of permits so if this industry is
going to move forward I think the plant
breeding program and getting a domestic
seed supply and when I say domestic seed
supply I mean the seed supply within the
borders of New York state where this
product is under the state's Authority
is really really
important I'm not a plant breeder but I
do have a background in horiculture I
think we all have to realize that's not
going to happen overnight okay um I've
had a bunch of questions here and I
heard some questions here today about
about uh feral stands of uh hemp and so
that's definitely something that's sort
of on our radar screen we got to
understand what that what that is so
that feral hemp that's out there that
could be um that could be something else
we don't know probably hasn't been
tested for THC number one uh number two
uh we need to understand what the
genetics of it are so it could be the
foundation for a really good breeding
program it might be something that we
don't want okay and so it's going to
take some time to understand what that
is okay um the other book end that I
think is really really important um is
the processing and the marketing okay so
that's the other thing that is
potentially a little bit risky and where
we need to do a lot more work and have a
better understanding of uh what this
what this plant and what this industry
can do and uh you know there's some of
you here that have known me for a while
I was in extension for over 20 years and
actually this isn't very much different
than any other crop I talked with a hemp
farmer the other day and I said hey I'm
going to tell you the exact same thing I
talked to people 20 years about
strawberries Greenhouse flowers whatever
we can teach you how to grow
this but we can't necessarily teach you
how to sell it how to Market it that
part of it you guys have to really sort
of take the ball and and run with that
to a certain extent so what we're
working working on as far as marketing
is concerned is we have in our uh
division of a development we have some
staff who uh do work on marketing
efforts and we're uh at least taking the
step of moving forward identifying
processors within the state of New York
because again relatively easy if you've
got some hemp product you can in
relative with relative ease move it
about within the borders of the State uh
we're also identifying processors
outside the state of New York and so at
least we'll have a resource list
available to you that folks can look at
um and then the other thing is I believe
yesterday or the day before Empire State
development came out with some processor
grants so there are some funds available
uh to help to Spur the processing
industry and so if you call us at the
department and talk with Kate I'm pretty
sure you do have a uh you've got a
contact person at ESD now so we have
someone we can we can refer you
to
um seed seed certification certification
yes thank you um the other thing that's
on our tick list coming out of uh the
bill signing and the summit and really
related to my my comments about
developing a domestic within the borders
of New York seed industry uh one of the
things that we really have high on our
list to do is to develop some seed
certification standards so we've got if
you look in uh the agon markets law
there are seed certification standards
for all kinds of different crops that we
grow we work closely with the folks here
um New York uh State seed Improvement
and Cornell when we develop those
standards but that's going to be very
very important and really what it comes
down to as Dr Taylor said in a nutshell
is sort of consumer protection for the
people who are buying that seed okay uh
and that's really going to uh set the
set the stage for developing that
industry along with development of of
some genetics that are uh good for New
York as well as good for the various
uses of industrial
hemp with that I can answer some
questions I'm sure there will be some
there always
are yes sir uh with respect to the 2018
Farm Bill what are the political
pressure points that can be used to make
sure it's motivated in a favorable
Direction so the the question was uh in
regards to the 2018 Farm Bill what are
the pressure points as far as a
favorable outcome you know I think one
of the things with anything at a federal
level and and again hemp is a very small
piece of well actually not it's a very
large piece of what I've been doing over
the last couple of years but we've got a
lot of other issues where we're dealing
with the federal government and I would
just say in general there's a lot of
um anxiety among sort of middle
management folks and uh and federal
agencies um not necessarily a great deal
of of Direction I would say one thing
that we may have from a favorable
perspective is Kentucky is a big state
in hemp and so you have Mitch McConnell
with a leadership position uh and in
Congress and so that
potentially um you know helps with the
whole hemp situation but I think you
know try trying to predict what the
pressure points are is is pretty hard
with how things have been have been
working at the federal level at this
point so the the question is is on the
New York delegation and I think there's
been a quite a bit of interest from uh
from the New York delegation from my
perspective Donna do you have something
you want to add to that
yeah so uh we were just with Senator
Gill brand recently and she's one of the
main sponsors of the
2018 industrial Hamp farming act so our
hope is that um because of the interest
from largely from Kentucky Rand Paul and
Mitch McConnell and others and the
widespread support in places across the
country where it's growing that we can
get around those pressure points by
death pressuring for full passage of of
legalization we think that um is uh
looking um much more likely than it's
ever before uh I'm not positive how many
of our New York Congressmen have signed
on last year I think we had five um and
uh our Congressman uh had has recently
retired so he's not on the bill at the
moment uh but yeah that's our goal the
goal is to pass the industrial hemp
farming act and just make everybody's
life a lot
easier I'll stick around and kiss thank
you yes sir yeah I got a question
regarding the farm bill you know why
there there's so much effort by the DEA
and play on words when it comes to the
CBD extract part of the
plant if they try to make it like it's
THC we know it's not
THC they play around a lot of words and
I've read you talking about the
rescheduling classification not just
well yes rescheduled but also as part of
the form act they're trying to delineate
the
CBD and it doesn't sound favorable right
now so a a couple things is is there are
even some states and as I said I was in
Kentucky two weeks ago for the
regulatory conference which basically
was pretty much limited to folks from
State Departments of Agriculture there
were a few extension people there as
presenters as well so it was a pretty
open uh uh exchange and forum and even
some of the states have defined
Industrial Hemp as grain and fiber only
and have limited CBD
Research
um at the federal level I think there's
again um a little bit of a of a
disconnect perhaps if you will um
because some of those
products have not necessarily had
clinical trial on them and so there's a
hesitancy to move forward with
them
um and again I kind of would go back uh
and I'm not going to you know poke
another agency um DEA has been pretty
helpful to us DEA has been pretty
helpful I think to Cornell and
Morrisville I
think going back to my previous
statement regulatory
officials look for black and white and
there's not a lot of black and white in
this and so when you have a DEA
investigator or someone in a leadership
position at
DEA and it doesn't fit neatly into how
they've defined other substances they
really struggle with that and so I think
it's sort of a dis a discovery or a
process of trying to figure out you know
what's what we've taken a little bit
more liberal approach on the CBD end of
things
but we've also had a lot of discussions
with our State Department of Health over
the past six months about
CBD and you know they're in a role where
they're going to be backing us up on a
technical perspective because as I say
to my
boss do you want an entomologist a
Forester and somebody with a dairy
Science Background to be
evaluating projects that might have
medical or health implications it's out
of my wheelhouse if you start to talk to
me about the Agronomy or The Pest
Management I can probably look at that
pretty easily and tell if it's a good
project a worthy project if I have
questions I have probably 11 right Folks
at Cornell who can help me out with that
you start getting into some of the CBD
stuff and start to make Health claims
and that type of thing and even to some
extent nutritional claims we don't
necessarily have the back stop for that
right now and so we're developing
that how about you hey how's it going
good based on that line um of what we're
just talking about now what is New York
State's definition then of medical CBD
marijuana versus what I'm looking at
right now which is hemp with CBD oil in
it what's the what's the difference
there is it a gray area so thank you for
saying it's a gray area cuz it is a gray
area we're trying to figure that out you
know and one of the things that's uh a
little bit of a challenge is Is So
within the medical marijuana program
there are very strict quality control
standards in there very strict
production standards that's not stuff
that we have in the industrial hemp
current Industrial Hemp regulations it's
not something that frankly is in the
next iteration of the Industrial Hemp
regulations um but we're working on
trying to Define where those regulatory
boundaries are and and when other
agencies have to be brought in so we you
know we don't want to get in trouble and
we don't want anybody that's s sitting
here in the audience to get in
difficulty with either another state
agency or a federal agency and so I
think a little bit of patience a little
bit of working through it and we'll
certainly get
there a little experience in hemp and
marijuana and medical marijuana as a
police officer I might not be confused
by some of these taller varieties but I
definitely would be confused with the
smaller varieties not just based on its
look but based on its smell its texture
and that essentially there's not real
there's that gray area um so is egg
markets when people are applying for
these applications helping them reach
out to their local police to make sure
that they're aware I know we have a sign
but my neighbors would probably read
that sign and just report me for growing
marijuana so so the question was what
about you know uh uh working with law
enforcement as far as on Industrial Hemp
and so uh I don't have the regulations
in front of me but basically what we
currently have in the regulations and
I'm definitely is going into the next
version is a requirement for when you
get your Industrial Hemp research
authorization from the Department you
have a certain amount of time to reach
out to your local law enforcement agency
and let them know that you have this
permit okay and so each of the original
uh 10 authorization holders have done
that um and they report back to us that
they've completed it uh often times they
send us a copy of the letter or give a
reference to a phone call or what have
you that happened and interestingly
enough we've gotten questions on it we
had somebody actually call in um and it
came I don't think it came to my desk I
think it came to Tim's desk and uh came
to his desk as you have an industrial
ATT call well it was a county sheriff
and a fisherman had scampered up from
the
riverbank and apparently had walked some
distance from where he started fishing
and he came up in something that looked
like this and he called the called the
police and um so you know that
particular uh authorization holder had
talked with somebody within the county
sheriff's department but it some word
hadn't gone through the whole
organization so we were able to take
that call and answer it we also have had
calls from New York State Police uh
intelligence unit because some of our
authorization holders have sent the
license in um the license looks like our
plant life plant
industry uh plant dealer or plant grower
license and um when you photocopy it the
security paper The Watermark doesn't
show up and so they rightfully
questioned whether it was a re the real
deal or not did you want to add
something Donna
two things uh just for um for reference
in uh bingamon university has 15,000 uh
CBD Rich plants in the ground in a
raised bed format they're doing a
different type of grow uh their plants
were imported as cuting from Kentucky
it's IP that is IP protected material
that's been cut it cut and
cloned and the local sheriff was very uh
interested to come and see what was
going on but we've had across the board
support from law enforcement largely
because when they understand the issue
of
cross-pollination this does uh have an
impact on illegally grown marijuana
which makes them very happy some of us
not so much but some some people are not
happy about
yes so and since Donna brought up
Kentucky I guess I should address that
issue so if you look at the program or
the if you look at the US Department of
Justice guidance and you look at the uh
USDA the the three agency guidance
document from a year ago it expressly
forbids the movement of plants and seeds
among
states however there's another document
that says Industrial Hemp can move among
states that have um programs State
authorized programs and so the guidance
document doesn't necessarily have force
of of law behind it I will tell you that
the DEA is fully aware that plants and
seeds are coming from Kentucky and
Colorado and Oregon um the Department's
not going to facilitate that um but we
are not at this point going to forbid
you from doing that I think that will
probably continue to be a question that
we wrestle with a little bit um you know
some of the other states in uh that we
interfaced with down in Kentucky um
basically we're saying well once you do
that you don't kind of know what you're
getting into your state and so
potentially you have some issues going
forward um from a regulatory perspective
so if you do that you're doing it at
your own risk and anybody who's a
current authorization holder has read
all of the releases and signed the forms
anybody that applies you'll you'll see
the paperwork that's involved in
this
sir one of my wife's Canadian relatives
involved in the hemp industry up there
he says a nightly occurrence car pulls
up jumps the fence whack a few bushes
back in the car and away they go as a
grower or possessor of hemp in New York
through this program what are my legal
responsibilities should that happen on
my farm go back to bed call the cops
this is getting out into the Community
even what whatever it's in it so first
off I'm not an attorney I'm a plant
industry director but what I would say
is is if I if I held a if I held a
research authorization and that was
happening I would
first for our regulation you've already
got a relationship with your local law
enforcement that's part of the reason we
want you to call if you have our
research authorization that's part of
the reason we want you to call local law
enforcement so they know it's there so
they maybe can drive by a little more
often if they want to keep an eye on
what's going on but also so you have a
relationship so I would say you want to
you want to call them and report it um
and the other piece of it is is for
whoever's taking
it they have no legal protection once
they cross the fence okay if I cut one
of these now and I went outside across
that fence I have a controlled substance
and so any law enforcement officer
because I'm not a research authorization
holder in the program would have every
right to stop me so I would say you
report it and document that as well
because one of the things that you know
potentially happens going forward is is
you potentially get into a situation
where your neighbor maybe doesn't like
this kind this form of Agriculture and
decides they want to challenge you on
that so you want to have uh a good you
know good record that you have been
diligent about controlling this product
and keeping it uh from getting where it
shouldn't
be yes sir kind of a compound question
for you here Chris flowing from this one
um how do you establish the the chain of
title or provenance of the product that
you have if you do acquire it um by
appropriate means and you're a processor
Etc you need to have a certification you
know the bill of sale what documentation
will um essentially qualify you to hold
that product and then you had mentioned
earlier um that it's fairly easy to move
this product around within the state of
New York that suggests to me that it
might be a little bit but you also did
say identifying processors out of state
so I'm I'm curious is it uh is it
something where the raw product the raw
seed Etc is more difficult to send out
of state if once it's processed into a
product is that relatively easier to
send out sure so uh a couple things so
number one uh your first question was
sort of how do you how do you establish
the chain of title correct and so what
we've done up to now is is that we have
had our authorization holders if they're
sending a product to processing we've
added that processor as a site under
their existing license I think what
we're going to do going forward um is to
actually register processors and so we
don't Envision the registration of
processors to have a fee attached to it
at this point in time it's basically
you're filing with us to say you are a
hemp processor that way if you are in
possession um and really what concerns
us um is if you were a processor and
you're in possession of any propagative
material so in other words seed that
hasn't been roasted or denatured or
sterilized
um we want to have you as a processor
have a piece of paper in your hand that
says you're authorized to have that in
the event that Federal officials came in
and you know asked why you had that
product um the second part of your
question was again about uh the ease of
transporting product across state lines
raw productes so if you go back and
again I don't have the exact wording in
my mind but if you go back of the
Controlled Substances Act of 1970 it
actually exempts certain parts of the
plant even right within the Controlled
Substances Act now one of the things I
will say and again I'm not in the
business of poking another agency
especially the DEA since I need to get a
permit from them right now they don't
haven't if you in if you interpret the
Controlled Substances Act uh
literally you could make the
interpretation that hemp was never
illegal it was just really hard to get
the permits for it in fact nobody ever
got the permits for it over the past 50
years um so seed and plants probably
pretty difficult to get
from uh state to state that's going to
peque the interest of the DEA and I will
tell you in in our interviews they're
well aware of what's going on and have
what I would say is pretty good
intelligence um
the other parts of the plant should move
very easily among states that have an
industrial hemp
program North Dakota I believe last year
ran into some problems where one of
their authorization holders had a large
amount of material and I don't can't
remember what part of the plant it was
that DEA uh held for a period of time
and the Department of Agriculture and
the DEA you know got into a into a
uh war of letters and eventually the
product was released and went to where
it needed to go so I think we're going
to run into some bumps like that from
time to time and again what happened
last year which was I believe in was
either in December or January uh and
talking sort of informally with my
counterpart in North Dakota his take on
it was there was an Administration
change going on there was a lack of CL
ity as to where this was going and that
somebody at a regional level had decided
to take advantage of that change and try
to make an example so to speak so I
think you know I think as we move
through the 2018 Farm Bill process we're
going to have a much better sense of
what the federal Administration is
thinking and where we're going on
this yes ma'am so if you if you're
planting h on forested land CU I I've
had theft on forested property and this
was handled by the I guess the Forestry
Department of the State Police so if
you're planting him on a property that's
forested well let's say part of it is
forested and you planted
M um who do you go to if you have a I
think if you have a theft issue and
you're holding our you know if you're
holding our Ag and markets research
authorization
you would go to your local law
enforcement officials but you would also
want to be sure that we at the
department knew what was going on as
well and do you get signage to put on
the property so the current regulation
and again the current regulation that's
on the books we wrote those uh with the
research institutions in mind so frankly
they're a little bit outdated for where
we are right now as far as what's going
on in the state those orig regulations
did have a specific signage requirement
and going forward that's not going to be
in the next iteration of the regulations
because you sort of have a double-edged
sword with signage it can if you put a
no trespassing sign
here I'm not going to go in but if my
wife saw a no trespassing sign here she
would go in because she'd want to see
what was in there um
we tested that years ago at the
Washington State Governor's Mansion and
the Troopers took us out of there so you
know we we got like three steps up the
driveway it's not like in Albany where
there's a gate anyway um so you know
signage is really going to depend upon
your your situation um you know driving
up and looking at this from the road I
could tell it was hemp from the road but
I was looking for hemp if I was driving
by here and had no idea that it was here
I would just think it was some different
field crop so A lot's going to depend
upon upon your location the signage to a
certain extent you know one of our
authorization holders said hey we're
you're putting an advertisement on this
and he wasn't concerned about the local
kids going in the field and stealing it
he was concerned about uh you know
somebody else within a 5 mile radius
that was perhaps growing something else
and didn't want the pollen from his crop
to contaminate and IIT grow and having
it be destroyed because of
that yes um is there any answer as to
whether uh a farmer who's holding a
federal program benefit like through FSA
can grow under the New York
permit excellent question so the
question was uh can somebody who is
participating in some of the federal
some of the other Federal prog programs
like conservation Reserve or what have
you can they uh hold our permit and
participate without putting into
Jeopardy their other payments and so
we've been going back and forth quite a
bit with our legal council on that and
we don't necessarily have a have a clear
answer on that our legal council at the
department feels as though um with our
research
authorization there shouldn't be a
problem but that is not to say that
somebody at the county level in an FSA
or another federal office couldn't hold
something up so I think that's something
we're still working on and trying to
hammer that out and perhaps um you know
perhaps that's something from a policy
perspective that needs to be defined
better in the farm bill I do think the
bill that was signed here back a few
weeks ago the at the state level um
reiterates the fact that this is an
agricultural commodity and I think that
may help a little bit with this but
we're sort of on on tested waters on
that but it's a great question and one
that we've heard a number of times and
are working on so thank
you yes sir Chris uh mentioned we've got
what 31 States now that are involved in
research and hemp production of some
sort is there any uh uh group lobbying
effort uh on a you know going on a
federal level to
to look at legislation for the 2018 farm
bill I mean our current attorney general
is probably not hemp hemp uh friendly
friendly or sure I I think you mentioned
one other Workshop that he spells
everything po
so but but I mean moving forward I mean
as as uh as these states develop this
this Federal uh I thought that was going
to be one of the book The bookends you
were talking about is is a Federal
Regulation yeah I mean that one is that
one is for sure is is also in there um
so you know I've been asked actually was
asked yesterday to be sure to write up
you know my policy issues within plant
industry for uh the 2018 farm bill and
and uh you know was encouraged to have
several that related to Industrial Hemp
so I think we'll come at it from that
direction I also think that the uh
National Association of State
Departments of Agriculture uh will will
likely and that's basically the
Commissioners and the state directors
and and uh those types of folks at the
highest levels um will probably have
something from a policy perspective um
and then you know there's the hemp
Industries Association and some of the
other like vote hemp who I think will
have some some pressure from you know
the producer and the general public side
yor far and Farm Bureau probably will as
well I don't know is that in their
policy manual if this policy book I got
it put in there I got that 10 limit put
in there too we Lobby in Albany and in
um Washington and I make sure that I go
because some of the older people still
don't understand the difference between
marijuana and hemp and still legislators
like when you said there about five um
when Donna was saying that like there
really weren't when I brought it up
people were not in the last 3 years
understanding it now it's like they're
like oh yeah I've heard about this and
we're going to keep going and if you
want to contact your county Farm Bureau
and help support them and let them know
that people are farmers are interested
and if they don't know farmers are
interested in it they're not going to
want you know we Farm Bure supports what
Farmers want and if they're not feeling
a need from Farmers then they're not
going to want to support it you know
that I'm just a crazy hump lady so no
not at all cuz I had a question we heard
a lot about seed protection and cloning
protection but what about it's a
perennial
plant mm so how are we protecting it
from growing back perennial like if a
farmer cuts it down say with a Sith and
leaves the roots in the ground there's a
good chance it's going to come back on
its own or if they let it go to seed and
they don't collect all those seeds
before they hit the ground there's a
good chance it's just going to seed
itself so how how are we talking about
protection on that and like with apples
or other Farm Commodities is there like
a statue of limitations like an apple
that is cross bread they have a new
Snapdragon one I can plant it but I
can't sell it for 10 years and and then
I will be able to sell it as whatever
are there are there things like that for
this so prenal growth and so I don't
think we've really addressed that at
this point in time and perhaps that's
something you know I know that's an
issue
because what I've learned is when it
goes through the combine it does shatter
and so you do have a lot of uh receding
during just during the harvesting
process so that is probably something
that we've got to address at some point
going forward yep
yes is there any uh um interest in in
developing a market for the herd and
putting that back in the ground and
getting carbon credits I know there's a
lot of activity in India and in uh
Europe uh there's a whole market so we
actually have an authorization holder or
current authorization holder that has a
piece of that in their research plan to
be looking at that a little bit and I
think um I think uh uh Dr vians was
talking a little bit about the
systematics person looking at how it
fits into a rotation um and so there may
be some you know really good agronomic
and and carbon uh credit issues uh you
know that are benefits in a rotation
even if you weren't going to the extent
of growing it for grain or some other
purpose is there is there going to be a
cap on how many research license holders
um are going to be available for next
year so the C
was removed from the law okay so what I
would say to you is um you know we're
still going to require an application
we're still going to require the
application fee it's $500 for three
years and we're still going to as long
as the farm bill is in place and says
it's a research pilot program we're
still going to be evaluating proposals
um and you know making sure that that
the projects that we that we uh give the
authorizations to you know have a
research outcome associated with them
but we don't anticipate a limited number
now you know the other piece of it I
also need to be protective of the fact
that there are many important missions
that my
division is responsible for in New York
state and I have a limited number of
people out there to do this work um and
so we have export certification and
Interstate certification a of of many
agricultural products that are very uh
lucrative for the state of New York for
our Farmers we need to make sure we
fulfill that uh we have uh plant pest
and Survey responsibilities for invasive
uh insects and diseases that would uh
you know cause damage to the agriculture
of New York as well as the environment
we have to take that very very seriously
so I guess where I'm going is if I got
10,000 applications I probably
can't award or uh give out 10,000
authorizations but what we're hoping to
do is create an environment where we're
learning as much as we can going forward
for the time when maybe the industrial
hemp farming act sails through and if
it's no longer a regulated substance
then our role is diminished a great deal
I would say from a regulatory
perspective the other part that I'll
just throw out there is is I think
anybody who's involved in this for the
time being with it being federally
regulated as well as regulated at the
state level um you have to understand
what it is that you're growing you need
to know your seed source you need to
know that it's does meet the 3%
THC um and you need to do everything you
know in your power to protect yourself
as well as
protect um all the great work that's
been done to bring this from something
that everybody was scared to death of
two years ago to something where there's
you know 50 or 100 people under a tent
at itha talking about it so Donnie you
want to make a comment on
that I know we're running long but I
just want to make a couple of quick
summary comments first I want to thank
Cornell for putting this together this
is really informative um just wanted you
to know that she feel really good about
being in New York state right now around
this compared to other states who may be
permitting this I mean all of the gears
are in motion uh as hard as it is to
believe I have to pinch myself the
governor just put $10 million down on
the table for a processor grants of
$250,000 and we have a One-Stop shop and
a help line and and many many folks good
folks like Chris Lo and others uh in aam
markets who are very committed to this
what I'm hoping to see happen and what
one I wanted to leave you with from my
end is we're hoping that hubs will be
developing we're seeing a food and
beverage Hub starting to develop in
central New York we're seeing a CBD
pharmaceutical Hub starting to develop
in the Southern Tier Hudson Valley is
also doing some food and beverage and
and some other and some CBD but it would
be helpful if the Farm Bureau and farm
collectives could get more organized so
that we're not sort of tripping over
each other that you've got 10 Farms all
growing the same thing with a partner
farmer I mean a partner processor with a
market in line so we're not sort of in
the wild west here um the governor has
um directed all ire State development
all the regional Economic Development
councils to priority I this so in
central New York Finger Lakes and
Southern Tier where there's a lot of
money from the upstate revitalization
initiative they're looking for projects
and they want to be able to provide some
funding to to help this so we're lucky
in this regard so thank you thank you
everybody for going along with this
crazy uh Chris I have a question do you
make a list of the farmers available to
people who want to process so that we
know where to go get material so we have
not done that at this point in time and
so we're working through some uh some uh
foil issues on that and just trying to
understand exactly what we can and can't
release and so we probably will have the
answers to those questions in the next
couple of weeks because we've been
asked but there's I mean if if
processors are really
interested extension puts out
newsletters to all Farmers putting add
newsletters that you're looking for feed
or you're looking for fiber what you're
looking for for and they'll come to you
right and then no foil needed right
right so if you were to get a farm to
give you seed it has to be sterilized at
the fmer level or are you allowed to
sterilize so as a processor as a
processor you could sterilize it but the
other thing is is that from what I've
been told by some of the uh
authorization holders is one of the
things that they want is to be able to
use the unsterilized seed and some in
some product
and that there are some attributes of
the seed you know before it's roasted or
before it's denatured in some other way
that are beneficial and so uh what I
would say as long as it's not moving
beyond the borders of the state where we
can't really have any real impact on you
know changing that policy today um you
know work with work with us to figure
out how to get it to where it needs to
go yes sir clarify we navigate the gray
area um can you get an application to
grow for CBD only in New York state
right now submit one okay and as far as
the processes go our extractions part of
that
dialogue absolutely so what what's going
to happen um on CBD a little bit more
detail on that I guess I I glossed over
it a little bit so a little bit more
detail on that is is that the Department
of Health has asked us to put several
CBD related questions on the application
so that we can flag projects that need
to have somebody with a health
nutritional or medical background help
us to review and so um those are
probably going to go into a separate
pile and we will have a group of folks
from our department as well as from
Department of Health who will be looking
at those and trying to navigate those go
through the system and understand
exactly what it is that you're wanting
to do and what we're contemplating and
again this is early on and it's an
important detail that you ask about um
we'll probably we have a what's called a
research partner agreement so the way
the process works right now is you
submit an
application uh we act upon it we say we
like your project and then the next step
is we send you our research partner
agreement which is basically outlining
what your responsibilities as our
research partner at the with the State
Department of Agriculture what your
responsibilities are what our
responsibilities are and so in that
agreement on the CBD end of things there
probably will be some specific Clauses
that are inserted in there um that are
again trying to build you a safe harbor
within what we currently know about CBD
and it's every state is struggling with
the CBD thing because there's a lack of
clarity I can tell you one more thing
that that out in Oregon we struggle with
in Oregon had a th000 Acres planted last
year and they have 3,000 Acres planted
this year much of it for CBD M there is
not enough of infrastructure to do
anything with this material is so limit
limited on extracting facilities food
grade approved facilities you get old as
flour and it's going out of state to get
extracted because it has
mhm yeah and there's definitely some
challenges with that you know we were in
a processing plant in Kentucky you know
one part of it was for for food grade
work the other part was was fiber and
you know Structural Materials and uh you
know I think they said that's one of the
biggest plants in the country and it
wasn't very big so you know that's as I
said you know the bookends the seed and
the processing the processing piece is
vitally important going forward
um several people have mentioned grower
co-ops and collectives and things like
that and Cornell does have a a resource
in Bobby Severson in the Dyson school
that provides guidance in terms of uh
Co-op formation so there is that
resource if you would like to pursue
it thank you that's very
helpful so Chris maybe we should wrap up
and let folks talk to everyone
individually jul and walk around the
plaza bit sounds great thank you I'm
going to get some water
[Applause]