this is a production of Cornell
University okay morning welcome
everyone my name is Larry smart I'm a
professor in the horiculture section in
the school of vgr plant science this
year just to give you an overview of the
agenda and you we did print out I did
print out enough hard copies of the
agenda for everyone but uh there is a QR
code that will take you online and we
have the agenda and all of our handouts
are online uh because we do that because
I used to print out 125 or 150 handouts
and end up with 100 left over at the end
uh so we do have 25 hard copy printouts
of our handouts and we'll be
Distributing those as each speaker comes
up to the mic and if you do want to look
at a hard copy hand out you know share
and look over uh each other's
shoulders uh so in the morning we are
going to talk about this uh we're going
to start with uh our update from New
York State agon markets uh Tim sweey
who's our program director and then uh
we will talk about this variety
trial and then we will uh shift down to
uh the next stop and talk about some
establishment management techniques uh
seed treatments weed management and
rolling uh and then uh hopefully the
Bish fiber cut is
running uh and we will see how well
that's
working so uh then we're going to move
on uh Magic Kowalski is here from Poland
he's going to talk about uh some of the
different aspects of
reading uh in particular for textile
fiber
quality then we will have a pretty cool
demo of a Monarch Electric
tractor and uh finally we'll end up the
morning uh demonstrating our male Baylor
uh
so then we will all drive down to our
new hemp processing facility that we
call the hemp tent it's a fabric barn
and uh we will have a delicious Rusty
Pig lunch uh in the hemp tent and in the
afternoon we will see if we can get our
decorticator running and then we'll end
the day with an array of uh hemp
industry professionals and entrepreneurs
from New York
State uh so I hope uh I hope it's a
stimulating event we have a lot of
people from across the country here
attending uh academics industry members
uh processing folks uh so it should be a
nice networking event
uh uh let me just the last thing I want
to say is that everything may not go
great uh we've broken a lot of stuff in
the last week and have been scrambling
especially my new research support
specialist Jacob Bish has been putting
in long hours uh trying to get things
repaired in time for
today they may not work perfectly uh but
it will be real so it may not be great
but it will be real and uh that reflects
where we are in the hemp industry right
now especially on the processing side uh
so bear with us uh if you have some
suggestions to make things work let us
know okay I'm going to uh hand over the
mic uh to our longstanding and good
friend at New York State agon markets
they have been incredibly supportive of
our research programs
and uh but Tim is is also manages our
hemp Growers and he's going to give you
a little update and uh answer any
questions you have
Tim so I'll be the first thing that may
not work
great my presentation's on a PowerPoint
we have no screen so um that's okay so
we've been running the hemp licensing
program since uh 22 it's the current
iteration of it it's no longer a pilot
program and uh we are granted that
Authority by the USDA hemp Still Remains
a heavily regulated crop and you must be
licensed by the state in order to grow
it the license fee is $500 and you have
to have a FBI background check you can
have no uh felony drug related
convictions within the last 10 years uh
in order to get a license if you do you
would be
disqualified um I don't want to take a
lot of time going through the minutia of
the program because I don't think
there's probably a lot of Growers here
Larry U sorry I'm here with Chuck
Schmidt my colleague somewhere around
we'll be here all day so if you have any
particular questions if you are a grower
you can hunt us down and we will talk to
you oneon-one
um if you are a license grower
there's some things that you need to
remember if you are haven't yet done a
planting report you need to get that
into us they have to be in by the end of
the year um they're supposed to be in
within 20 days of planting even if
you're not planting you still have to do
it there's a box to check that says
you're not planting but if you don't get
it into US you run the risk of having to
enter into a a corrective action plan
which is just a lot more paperwork for
you so you don't want to do that um also
if you a grower and you're about to
Harvest you need to submit a pre harvest
report with us they need to be sent in
30 days before your intended harvest
date and then you would uh on that form
you would choose your sampling agent and
a lab that will do your testing for you
we no longer do the sampling and testing
as an agency we just don't have the
capacity so that is the Grower's
responsibility we have uh 28 I believe
certified sampling agents and 24
recognized lb that you can uh work with
to fill those
responsibilities sorry about
this so uh the Grower's license is good
for three years that's the $500 fee you
pay is is good for a three-year license
and since the program started in 2022
that means that licenses are going to be
expiring next year they'll start to
expire if you're a grower you'll be
getting a 90-day advanced notice that
you need to get your license renewed we
will be doing individualized
notification to everybody as their
license comes up 90 days out and
unfortunately I checked with the
USDA you do have to do another
background check for the new license the
background check can be no more than 60
days old when you apply when you send in
your application applications have to be
mailed in they can't be taken
electronically
for some reason they W let us do that
there's another $500 fee for the
renewal and this is uh these are just
caveats that I say every year if you're
planning to grow hemp know where you're
going to sell the hemp have a market
before you plant the stuff we have
people every year they plant it then
they call us at Harvest Time what am I
going to do with this we don't broker
hemp we don't have a way to set you up
with Buyers so know where you're going
to sell it before you plant also zoning
is a local issue in New York state check
the zoning where you're going to grow
you can't grow in a residential area
unless it's also zoned for agricultural
uses you can't grow in a
residence or an attached
garage know the characteristics of the
plant you're growing of the varieties
you're growing if it's got a tendency to
go hot stay away from it cuz if it's if
it goes hot it's not going to be any
good to you you'll have to destroy it or
remediate it in some way and the
remediation pretty much makes it
invaluable or not of any
value and because we have we're still
operating under the 2018 farm bill we
have not had a new farm bill yet the 0.3
total THC Remains the standard for the
for industrial hemp no more than
3% we were hoping for a farm bill last
year I don't think we're going to get
one this year so we'll see if uh next
year if we get a farm bill perhaps there
will be some changes I haven't heard of
anything
coming so uh or any changes coming and I
haven't heard of any progress on the
farm bill
so if anybody have any questions now I
can take them or we can wait till later
does New York exempt certified varieties
from compliance testing we have a list
of varieties yes that that um are exist
Ed from from
testing and there's
uh you have the potential of being uh
inspected once every once in your
three-year period you will be inspected
sometimes more the testing can uh the
sampling certain varieties can be
Exempted from it others will not if they
have a tendency to be kind of hot if
they've
been um hot in the past you're going to
have to sample those
when do you sample for compliance
testing how many days har so if the
question is when do we sample for
compliance testing 30 days out from your
anticipated date of harvest send in your
pre harvest report with the name of your
sampling agent we then um generate a uh
chain of custody
form that would get sent to your
sampling agent and they would call you
you'd set up your sampling date so it's
30 days out uh from your anticipated
Harvest is when the sample's
taken the question is is a total THC yes
it's total
THC any other
questions great like I said Chuck and I
are here most all day so hunt us down if
you have other questions I have I have
one
too uh so if if a field uh exceeds test
hot exceeds the 0.3%
limit uh you have the option to
remediate it and retest it right uh one
of my colleagues told me that that
remediation retesting and Remediation
does not apply if you were growing or
seed for planting is that true
you always do
this Chuck I would say SE crops
generally don't go hot most of the CBD
crops what we'
seen so so we did have a seed crop go
hot last year right and we we did we did
let him Harvest that and and so so that
I think we probably would take that on a
Case by case basis and see what
varieties they're talking about how hot
it is um you know we
were to remediate
it have to chop it up pretty much and
make it a homogeneous mess and the seed
would have been lost and we didn't want
that to happen so
uh we did allow that to to go okay you
we're not we're trying to
not we want people to be successful we
don't we don't want we don't want uh to
to get
people unnecessarily in trouble or have
to destroy their crop for for uh minut
problems but we we are beholding to the
USDA if we get audited and we have
something wrong we could it could
threaten the whole proam
so so yeah and you also like I said it's
make sure you're not you're not growing
varieties that tend to go hot because if
a field is hot it it will have to be
destroyed if it can't be remediated and
and and if you haven't sent in your
planting your pre harvest report you've
harvested it without it being sampled it
will be destroyed and you turn it
into
valeries you mean if it tests hot it
tests hot can you use the material as a
source for biochar for champ yeah if you
could whatever you do with the biochar
to make to make the the hemp
irretrievable and and no you know not
useable B illicit purposes yeah yeah I
think that'd be
okay okay a question what is your means
of
remediation what is the means of
remediation Chuck you want to handle
that one
yeah thank you yeah for remediation we
generally ask that the the power be
removed and then the remainder of the
drop be chopped up a
biomass um the flour can be chopped up
in that as well so you delute it with
all the leaf material and all the stem
material and then we send another sample
to the lab and most likely it's going to
be tested fine the problem is now you
have this product you have to
sell right what do you do with that I'm
not sure you have like a window of days
that has to be remediated yeah like
anything else you know once we find it
hot we got uh 10 days to tell us what we
do with it I talk to you talk about some
of the options that you have
ch a market for that cuz then you have
to get retested at your expense so you
want to throw good money up your bad if
you don't have a a use for it then it's
better just the
top okay okay great thanks very much Kim
you
bet
uh so uh growing yeah thanks a lot Tim
and
Chuck uh they have been incredible
Partners they they are are Partners in
this endeavor and uh as Tim said they
want to see Farmers
succeed
uh but having said that evaluating the
cultiv ours that you're growing and uh
uh I would my advice would be to grow
compliant cultivars uh cultivars that
have a long history of being compliant
under the current rules uh so that is
something that we have been doing in our
field trials for the last s years is
evaluating varieties testing them for
compliance and doing the fundamental
research to understand the genetics of
why those varieties produce uh THC and I
think we've been pretty successful at
that uh it is now really critical that
you grow compliant varieties if you want
to enter hemp seed meal into the animal
feed market so that has been an
incredible uh event in the hemp industry
is federal approval AFCO and FDA
approval of hemp seed meal as a feed
ingredient for laying
hem with the caveat being that that feed
definition has some pretty low limits
for THC and CB BD so that hemp seed meal
cannot have greater than two parts per
million t total
THC or more than 20 parts per million
total
CBD uh obviously those seeds are not
making THC it would be residue that
would be rubbing off in the bin of the
combine or through the harvesting
process uh but right from the outset you
want to be growing varieties that
produce low amounts of THC
uh this year you're going to see that
our field day is really focused on
fiber and a lot of those fiber varieties
do produce
THC uh so that's not an issue for the
hemp seed meal
obviously uh but but it's something that
my graduate student Luis monserat is
going to talk
about uh so Lis is going to give you
about a 15minute overview uh of uh 15 or
20 minute overview of his research uh
and the trial behind me here and then we
want to give you some time to walk
through the trial ask any questions
follow up with Luise on things that he's
saying and uh
then we are going to meet at that
speaker over
there uh
at uh
9:50 right okay okay so Luis it's all
yours thank you Larry hi everyone great
to see you all again uh many familiar
faces uh great great attendance is that
okay perfect uh so I always ask this
question when I give my talk who in here
is wearing or has any ham fiber piece of
clothing oh lower than last year that's
unfortunate um if you ever need a good
hat I would highly recommend this hat by
Ty or til I believe 100% H fiber so I
will encourage the industry once again
um yeah so my name is l mate I'm studed
my fourth year in my in this PhD program
with Larry uh focusing on fiber and
grain breeding and
genetics uh and you know as you saw last
like yesterday uh the USDA
characterization of General plasm is
important right so in order to do any of
the breeding in generics we need to
explore these cultiv we need to
characterize them I want to characterize
phenotypically and genotypically so
right now I want to show you my
phenotypic characterization here so this
characterization is not new it has been
done for many years uh um if I want to
if I'm not mistaken a century ago uh
list to do it started doing this in
1920s
1922 I believe uh uh and he started
characterizing General plasm from Italy
from China um and started introgressing
some of those traits in um the that
Geral
plasm uh in the Netherlands in 1994 they
did something similar assessing 163
accessions um and that was a multide
trial in 2020 I believe they assessed
123 accessions uh the same university
vaging university and they did an
international assessment comparing
performance in the Netherlands in Italy
and in France so this is not new but
this is very imperative uh to know how
how the cultiv performs and what are the
interesting traits there are so again
character is important at the USDA you
saw very cool traits if you walk around
the field you saw certain uh interesting
phenotypes certain traits certain Le
certain in fluoresence and certain Mishi
that was very interesting um so that's
what we are seeing here we're also
assessing that in a production scale
instead of a high plant density how the
per how the cul will perform in a
commercial setting uh to do that uh we
decided to do a dual on is on your right
side and a fiber that is on your left
side um uh the the fiber was planted at
a density of um 1.87 million plants per
acre I believe
[Music]
1.31 million plant per acre and the duo
was of 180,000 plant per acre uh I'm
sorry I I use metric units I'm trying to
convert to the uh imperial system um
yeah so as you can see uh the stand
count is very important important for us
because for fiber we want to minimize
the stem diameter so uh we have heard
from processors that they don't want
something that is thicker than an inch
uh or something that is you know uh the
diameter of a pinky uh and for the Dual
what we want is to maximiz the her
production as well as the grain
production so we should we should
actually uh enable that branchiness or a
little bit of branchiness for the um
yield of of fiber sorry of
grain um but I think it is important to
know that there are advantages and
disadvantages based on the type of
cultiv that you use the market classes
that you use so I would like to discuss
with you about
that for example um there are two sexual
difference uh what can I say uh
expressions in cannabis uh there is the
the isues and the mon isues
so if we have a daous crop uh there are
advantages and disadvantages with it one
D that is has has been uh approved and
corroborated well I want say approved
sorry corroborated by um a group in
Italy from 2022 I believe they observe
that male plants have a higher fiber
quality than female plants so in that
case when you have a daous population
then uh before the females flower you
objectively speaking will should get
better fiber yield now this assessment
has not been done comparing such yeld
with amonous and it makes it challenging
because you have to ensure you have the
same genotypic background except the
sexual differentiation right so but uh
for now we can say that in population
the males at least will have a higher
fiber
quality with the montias the idea is
that that quality should be more
homogeneous if you will right CU it will
be the same individual however if you
walk around and you see a demolicious
individual there will be a few males
over there it's it's typical to see
between 5 to 10% of the population
having
males uh another important um
characteristic with the Monas and the
isos is the east of
harvest um if you have a the populations
and you harvest for
grain that that would be at se maturity
by that time in aous population the
males will be sess and will be Reddit so
it is probable that that male will clog
your combine and I heard that before and
and sometime happens sometime you wraps
up and starts heating up in the combine
uh smoking and stuff so it could be a
challenge uh so that's why sometimes
montias is
better now if you look at the Monisha
individual I know I acknowledge there
are different types of Mishi there's
there are different uh inflorescence
types when you talk about mishas but the
European mishas in my in my opinion has
these clusters of male flowers that
eventually sess and they stay on the
female
plant uh so this is decaying material in
the inflorescence where the grains are
going to be harvested for human
consumption consumption are going to be
so that that is a little micro
environment for a potential pathogen
growth and uh some maybe some of you
know if you have ferum garum there you
may have omx in there so I don't know if
that would be the case but it's a
hypothesis I have that that could be a
potential um issue with amous individual
in that
sense
um the other question that I have about
the differences uh or a trade-off is
grain yield uh and again we have to
ensure that we have the same genotypic
background except the sexual expression
but are mous plants uh producing more ye
field than A's
population uh I mean you would think so
right because you have more than uh 50%
of the plants being
um uh female if you have a malicious
population you are objectively have more
grain but it's something that that we
need to assess because there are many
compounder factors such as late
flowering branchiness but that's another
thing to consider maybe malicious if the
plant is you know typically identical
but is mous maybe has more grain I
believe that uh new genetics has kind of
like that dra of thought a little bit
with their uh one of their uh
hybrids another parameter or important
trait that we characterize and we try to
make sense of is the flowering time and
there are advantages and disadvantages
with them and I would like to discuss
those with
you um so for fiber what do we want a
late flowering right because we want to
accumulate as much stock as possible
however during the Pennsylvania field
day I was told that for a specific
processor they don't want more than four
to six ft tall
plants um so I don't
know uh
but if you have a taller stem you will
have more Bast running along the the
main
stem um obviously you start getting more
hurt but when you have a l flower you're
able to uh accumulate that vegetative
growth over time accumulate more vast
you have an early flower in one that
would not be the
case uh another interesting thing is the
east of harvest when we looking at early
and late flowering if you have a late
flowering uh for grain for example that
plant will be very big that you need
very expensive and very difficult to
obtain piece of equipment such as the H
flx double cut right if you want to have
a dual purpose but if you have an early
flowering you need a regular combine
that you can you know easily
Harvest um for the fiber uh you may need
a fiber cut or um a s bar shouldn't be a
problem um but I think that you need to
reach certain height for that to work
cuz you going to have four bars on that
uh fire
C you can just use the T
Bar um One Challenge that we have OB
serve is the scal UPS late flowering
cultivars and early flowering also is a
very important step over very important
characteristic for us as a breed
breeders to to
utilize uh to scale up breeding lines or
cultivar if we have a late flower in
cultivar it makes it really challenging
to produce seeds here because by the
time that the seeds are maturing we have
a frost and we lose all our our seed so
makes it very difficult when you flower
very late so then we have to play with
other characteristic either okay we can
grow at Southern latitudes okay but you
know Florida there's a hurricane
everything goes to hell
right so it makes it very very difficult
uh however there are other parameters
that we can look into such as the
juvenile face of the plant we have
observed that certain germoplasm once
it's grown a very um at a very low sorry
short day length it will take a while to
flower it wouldn't flower like in two
weeks some do some do in two weeks but
some will take a month 20 days 6 weeks
and that is very good because he allow
us to have a growth that is big enough
for a regular combine to use when it's
growing in so we can grow in Yuma
Arizona in uh November SE uh December so
it makes it it's a good environment for
it but not all cultivat perform that way
so we need to assess General plasm to
see that juvenile face or that um
sensitivity to the critical
Dayland and just a little um sidebar
here when you're looking at Dayland I
will encourage you to include the Civil
Twilight in your measurements Civil
Twilight also uh prevents flowering uh
there's a group out of University of
Florida uh observe this and reported
this and I have been able to track down
and accurately uh compare my uh day
length from the field into a grow
chamber and I have observed those so I
would encourage you that whenever you're
doing measurement using day length
included C Twilight um
time we competition is another important
um phenotype to look into for our
general plasm and that would be probably
late to early flowering but I would I
would say that seiling Viger and leaf
area is another important parameter for
the week competition so we
want uh General platform that will have
a growth rate very high were able to
compete with the weeds a leaf area
that's going to be very large that we
can a were able to shade those weeds out
and you can see that in some of those
like there's no wheed whatsoever uh
obviously spray Sunland here um but uh
but last year we did an spray T I
believe and we have a nice we had a very
nice um with competition for some
cultiv and one an additional tra I'm
looking into uh uh which which I think
is very important and for some of you
may be more more than obnoxious com this
for me is seat size because what we have
observed that seed size uh does it it
seems to be a higher proxy for sealing
Vigor uh at least the general PR that we
have used that we have tested with large
seeds have large leaves which allow us
to compete with the
weeds preliminary speaking from a pilot
study that we did uh we have observed
that larger seats are able to perform
better in processing for de hauling so
that's that's good as well
um but I do acknowledge that the
challenge is when you're getting a pound
of seats you're getting fewer seats
that's a problem that's I understand
that but I think that the uh counter
argument for it is that you will
essentially need fewer seats to your
establishment because the ceiling is
going to be so high when you have lower
seats you need more seats in a bag sorry
you will have more seats in a bag but
you will use a lot of those seeds and
some of those will be th self thinned uh
or the crop is not going to compete with
the Wheats so what's going to happen in
the Harvest your bells are going to be
full of Wheats which may decrease the
quality and your seeds may have a lot of
wheat a lot of uh wheat seeds in
it um so I think think sit size should
be I mean we have done it with corn so I
think the same thing can be done with
hemp and I think it's a good um try to
explore and I'm constantly exploring but
what is the other characteristic of you
know hemp or phenotype of yes phenotype
of tra that we C the most I think Tim
was very clear about one of them that
makes hemp hemp legally
speaking the THC so so and that's the
perfect Segway for what we are going to
uh move on and that is selection for
populations breeding lines SL cultivars
that will be consistently below the
0.3% THC limit per driveway and that's
what we have done for our bring lines
Orsa Alta and Orsa Grande you will see
other two here 1380 and
1143 um these cultivar Embry lines were
actually selected for the production of
for the lack of production of THC or to
reach a limit below the 0.3 THC so this
was done with Market assist selection
developed by our lab and uh we are we
can ensure you that when you are growing
this cultivar by the time of sampling
and you're harvesting you are not going
to exceed that limit and we have
consistently observed that have been
certified uh by a third party lab so and
we have done the same thing for 1142 and
for
1380 and I will uh encourage you all to
look at the handouts and we can see our
potential yield in a small PL trial and
I understand small trial is no a street
trial we're able to reach about 20
metric tons per hectar per yes per
hectar which is like eight us tons per
acre uh and for your for your
understanding the average of five yield
last year was reported in the USDA
um uh hemp report it was two tons per
acre so that was the average and for Ura
Grande which is another cultivat in this
case we are promoting this a dual
purpose so we can get grain out of it as
well as the herd we're able to get um
about six metric tons sorry six um us
tons per acre and we're able to get
2,000 lb per acre of GRA of grain again
the average last year
was uh 558 pound per acre so what I'm
giving you is numbers that should
encourage you to um pursue hemp and
looking into the future and perhaps
getting interesting our cul as well uh
but again I think more importantly is to
test this recurrently and to observe
these yields and this uh performance
consistently year after year and not
just in the same location but
across the uh across the US and in the
handout for our bring you can see also
the yields in Kentucky uh well IA
Kentucky uh North Carolina Texas and
Florida so you with that you can
determine uh what your potential your
best cultivate could be uh not just for
fiber but also for for
grain um one trait that I feel like I'm
I'm forgetting is
the uh the fiber quality one which is
bass content this bass content has been
improved since 1950s if I'm not
mistaken um right now you can see one of
those um which is
579 uh this was reported well this
yellow stem or bright stem was
identified in 1950s if I'm not mistaken
uh by a German group they call it brid
stems uh this trait is very interesting
because they have observed in
2018 other General plasm I think caralon
iory
marant that has produced higher bass
content uh after recation compared to uh
green stem uh in 20 I think 2023 if I'm
not
mistaken um another group assessed the
performance of fiber 79 with Futura 75
and they observe a difference uh well
they observed that fi 79 was
37.5% B content whereas Futura 75 was
29.3% uh I have seen crazy numbers as
well in all groups uh out of lvia they
upset like over 42% bass content which
is insane but they have done it
allegedly um
so basically what I was trying what I'm
trying to say here is that this
characterization of cultiv have allowed
all people and have allowed us to
improve our um yields to improve the
traits that we believe are going to be
more Adept for the industry as well as
for Growers processors uh industry in
general and I think that um we are
getting that we're heading that way and
we have more ring lines in the pipeline
trying to assess to ensure that we are
not exing the limits for hand seat meal
to have high seat size or great seat
size uh to ensure a uniform flower in
time to make sure that we have that
parameter of distinct um uniform and
stable to meet as a cultiv so that we
can have that certification of
seeds and
um yeah I guess this is all I had to say
and those are my 15 minutes so
yeah I'm sorry
that does not go
hot our our none of our varieties are
essentially zero THC they will not go
hot and uh our varieties will be
submitted uh for plant variety
protection this
fall I have another question yeah go
ahead so when is the right stage to
harvest for example like fiber type and
also have dual purpose type so
when is the good time to harvest before
flowering or yeah uh the question is
what's the best time to harvest for
Fiverr and Dual Purpose uh fers so for
Fiverr it has been wildly researched for
many years uh in Europe um the ideal
time to maximize yield and minimize
quality uh quality loss and that is at
the onset of female flowering so you are
able to have those uh to stretch out
your your your your height your stem
length as much as possible but
minimizing the lfic that happens uh
during flowering F flowering so that
would be the time so what I do is
because I do not immediately believe
that every single cultiv is 50/50 I just
rate uh percentage of flowering overall
and whenever I see at least 50%
flowering in my population I decid that
that's time to harvest for fiber for a
dual purpose um so it is interesting
because have more issues and the issues
and I have to have a a Criterion that
will fit both of them so what I do is uh
I rate flowering again on a weekly basis
once I reach 80% flowering that will
ensure that for a manous population most
of them are flowering and for other
issues I have more than half of the
females flowering right and from that
point uh I track between 6 to8 weeks
after that point for seed maturity into
Harvest and I have observed consistently
that it seems to be around 6 to 8 weeks
it doesn't really change I mean it
changed within those 6 to8 weeks but um
that's around the time when you should
have for Dual
Purpose thank you
yep hi is there somebody hi Lou thank
you for your presentation I was
wondering about Ursa Al uh other than a
short critical dayline threshold what uh
other uh characteristics special for New
York Farmers you mentioned um uh the uh
mean dry Reddit F Versa at different
latitudes and it actually did pretty
well in Kentucky too so I was wondering
if you could talk about more what are
the specific characteristics of UR ala
other than
critical that make it special for new
Farm yeah so let me just uh BR that
question a little bit the question about
is about what is so special about Ursa
Alta uh
so we have uh using marker assisted
selection uh from very late
flowering uh land races from China we
have selected these two cultivars we
trademarked the name Ursa which is the
Latin name for bear that's our our
mascot uh so all of the varieties that
we produce in our Cornell breing program
will be trademarked with that Versa name
uh and these two first two cultivars
were developed with funding from the
foundation for food and agriculture
research and matching funds from
International hemp and they have been
licensed uh exclusively in the US to
International hemp for
distribution uh and Seed production and
we call them Grande Grande has large
seeds uh Louis is very fond of large
seeds and and Ulta uh is an exclusively
fiber variety we cannot produce seed of
that Variety in New
York uh so Ruiz what is so special about
Ulta uh well uh I don't know who of you
you attended the USDA but uh my my lab
mate uh Lucia vial uh said that
apparently is resistant to both ferium
and sorry not ferum septoria and Par
uh from her uh screening so that's very
encouraging um and very exciting to be
honest uh so that makes it special I
would imagine um if you look at the
plant also uh to meet the leaf area
makes it very special because what I
believe is that you can decrease the
stand count uh or the plan in density
and you still have a good wi competition
and uh narrow stem so that Lea area
makes it competitive compared to other
uh commercially available cultiv such as
Futura 83 the LI is is um much larger
than for 83 so I would say that makes it
a special as well U likewise uh Ora
Grand is also large uh has a large T
leaves thank you yep yeah a couple of
other things so uh we have not had the
opportunity yet to determine
decortication efficiency and Bast yield
but we collaborate with David suchoff at
North Carolina State University and I
believe uh our our varieties are among
the highest and vast fiber yield among
the varieties that he tested in similar
small small plop trials
so uh we we highly value that
collaboration with North Carolina State
and they have an excellent College of
textiles there where we will be able to
assess fiber quality of of these new eer
varieties other questions
yes um you mentioned that you want very
thin is it because the vast fiber ratio
is it because the equipment is not there
for thicker or or is it both why uh well
I would say both one is because of the
ratio the thicker the stem they lower
the bass to her uh ratio uh but also if
you have a stem that is a whole trunk
you will not be able to decorate uh from
what I heard from some I think one
processor was that if the stem is wider
than an inch it will not thecate so you
cannot process a high can avoid stem for
example but it's because the equipment
is not there I think it's because of the
I believe is because of the bast to her
ratio you will get more H HT than vast
and ultimately also the
equipment Ty Ty how are you
yeah tyer is asking how I'm harvesting
these plots so what I do is I harvest
one square meter that should be
representative of the entire pass so if
you walk around you will see some holes
in the middle that's where I place my
quadrant and harvest everything in it so
that allows me to determine a yield
based on that specific uh one square
meter yep question over there what Trace
did you use markers for when you
can you repeat the question the question
is um so for marazine selection we did
uh chemotype for chemotype 3 solely uh
so we'll have the this only these two
alos that we produce uh mostly
CBD uh and then the other selection
criteria that we use was flower in time
to make sure that uh is within one
window of uh it hasn't flower like for
several weeks but also like uniformly
like I don't know like let's say like in
in two three weeks you have everything
flowering or something like that as
opposed to flowering over several weeks
uh and uh a specific flowering time when
we want those to flower so for example
Sala will be harvested I believe at um
early and between early and mid October
that's the the window that we chose for
it yeah so just another point about
flowering time and what we've been
harvesting here so as you drive around
you're going to see some fields that
have already been harvested red red
we're going to demonstrate bailing
raking and bailing some of
those uh we're going to walk down and
look at
carmena uh where the Harvester is that
we're going to run the fiber cut through
that
carmena and for fiber that field is
already gone past the males have already
sessed uh and if you were harvesting for
fiber you're too late it's just about
perfect right now if you were going to
do a dual purpose Harvest uh because the
grain is mature in that variety uh so
the French varieties uh such as uh
future 83 and FIB were ready to harvest
what about three weeks ago yep for
fiber uh and as Louise said Ur Alta
won't be ready for another uh 3 weeks
yep which is ideal so it continues to
accumulate biomass over that time
because of its late flowering
nature uh yeah so the the last point I
want to make uh is that these small plot
trials are have been organized by my
colleague Bob Pierce at University of
Kentucky uh and we all work together
under
uh the organization of a USDA program uh
which is called a multi-state program
and that particular hemp research
project is called
s184 and you can Google that s184 hemp
research and uh our our project
objectives and some of our initial
results will come up when you Google
that uh but these types of plots are
replicated I think this year at about 15
different
institutions if you went to the
Lancaster hemp circuit you saw another
replicate uh that Alyssa Collins planted
at Penn
State uh but we have Ursa Alta and Ursa
Grande in all of those small plot trials
around the country so we will get very
good data from our academic colleagues
on the performance of those two
varieties anecdotally and Shelby Ellison
is here from Wisconsin David Gang is
here from Washington State uh they can
tell you how uh Ursa alt and urser
Grande are doing compared with other
lines uh that uh are in this trial uh
just one final note about because Sarah
is Raising her hand one final note about
obtaining seed uh you want to order your
seed as soon as possible if you could
order it now you should do it and you
should go talk to Robin dtit from canopi
us if you want
some of their outstanding varieties you
should talk to Sarah Mitchell of Kings
Agra seed who distributes International
hemp and Verve seed varieties and any
others and New West genetics oh yeah I
forgot about
them yep just one more Point here uh and
I don't want to forget my colleagues
from indd hemp uh they have an excellent
variety here which we've labeled SS beta
but uh commercially is known as IH
Williams uh named after our our deceased
colleague David Williams from University
of Kentucky so here you have uh three
excellent uh seed Brokers to talk to uh
if you want to order seed Valerie you
were asking about
cross-pollination so
uh yeah certainly in a breeding program
we would not grow anything any breeding
lines in the presence of these varieties
we want isolation preferably of uh 3
miles uh to make sure that there's no
cross-pollination and to maintain the
purity of our varieties that's also
critical during the production of
certified seed and the rule state if
you're going to produce seed for
planting you cannot have any other hemp
within 3 miles to make sure that uh we
maintain that
Purity uh in a monious variety it's most
likely
self-pollinated uh because the male and
female flowers are within the same
infloresence and obviously in the dous
varieties you have male individuals and
female individuals I I'll just say one
thing we note about those male
individuals they're very attractive to
bees uh both honeybees and
bumblebees uh so it is a good food
Source uh male pollen is a good food
source for bees but hemp is entirely
wind pollinated those bees do not go to
the female flowers
so yeah Sarah what are the growing
conditions is the crap shorter to me
than in previous years what happened
this season to keep thisp
short yeah uh you're not the only one I
noticed
that uh yeah I also want to the same
thing uh and what I've noticed and this
is one idea I have no idea sorry
hypothesis I have is that this field uh
after s rain fall rful events it gets
really water logged so I believe that it
may have suffered some it have suffered
from uh water logging stress and that's
why it has not uh riches you know
one um I believe so I cannot tell you
but there is another plan thing I at
this 3 weeks after uh you can see in the
back over there and those look way
taller um so they that field does not
suffer for that water logging so I would
imagine that water logging would be the
the main factor why they are shorter
what is the plan date uh this one was
May 20th that was June
13th yeah so hemp does not like to be
wet and it will stop growing when it
rains and when it's uh you know water
lost
uh the remnants of what was it hurricane
Debbie came through and gave us about 4
in of rain that day and uh this is
another uh sort of feature of our
research Fields here you see that we
maintain these 2 acre blocks and these
two acre blocks have been here for
decades and as we plow these blocks and
then maintain driveways in
between the soil subsides and they
become swimming pools so when when it
rains uh our Fields get flooded and and
you'll notice we have a 2 acre field of
Ursa Alta up on the hill there on the
other side of the
apples and when you look at that it is
tallest in the middle and the plants
have even DED around the edges of the
swimming pool uh because that's where
the water
pools uh so I'm actually uh trying to
get the folks here to knock down our
driveways and and to just plow
everything again and get rid of these
driveways and level out the swimming
pools that we have here okay uh there
are lots more questions you could ask uh
so definitely catch up to Louise or
other folks in my group wearing aggrock
shirts but I do want to give you uh a
little about 20 minutes to talk to walk
through the plots and uh see any
features
uh that you're curious about and then we
will meet at that speaker over there at
okay thanks
Lise so one thing we've learned and uh
you can talk to any of the researchers
here who have been trying to establish
hemp in Trials over the last six or
seven years that it could be very
challenging to get good stand
establishment of hemp uh it does not
like to be
wet uh so what I always tell my folks
when they're very anxious to get their
research trials going is to plant after
the storm all right I think a lot of
crops you would think oh I want to get
that seed in the ground and then it's
going to rain and my seat is going to
pop right up after that rain uh I do not
recommend that for him you want to let
that rain saturate the soil and then
watch the soil moisture and then
plant uh because when it's flooded it
will not come
up uh so that's one little
thing uh to think about is proper soil
moisture and depth and plant deep plant
down to your where your moisture is in
the
soil uh but the other critical
aspect is weed management and we are
very fortunate to have Dr ly soski here
who is our weed scientist at Cornell
agratech and has been doing a lot of
work on herbicide control and non
herbicide methods for weed management
and uh is also our state representative
to the ir4 program so I'm going to turn
it over to her and she's going to talk
about a little bit about herbicides and
sonin I think
hi yeah thanks for for for coming out
and thanks for having me and I'm going
to talk a little bit about some of the
work that we've been doing through a
USDA CPM project looking at hemp
competition hemp we control as well as
some of our ir4 projects so um hemp in
some Outlets has been reported as being
fairly competitive with weeds but I
think uh the work that we've done here
is that if you don't get a good stand
establishment if the weeds get a jump on
you hemp is not necessarily going to
catch up and frankly our work that we've
been doing across five states in both
transplanted hemp and seated hemp really
suggests that we're going to need about
four to six Weed Free weeks after
emergence uh to really maximize hemp
growth and yield so I do want to point
out that this is going to require
integrated weed management I think
everybody knows that pesticide uh
options are limited in hemp and and that
includes herbicides we have one single
herbicide and frankly we are lucky to
have that one herbicide for use in hemp
so I am going to point out if you do
have the handout here I do have a link
in it to a free book that you can
download from the Northeast s website
called
um integrated or uh sustainable uh weed
Management on your farm ecological weed
Management on your farm it is great book
talking about integrated weed management
practices and since we only have one
herbicide I do want to start off with
the integrated weed management practices
that we should be engaged in we should
be thinking about when we're going to
plant hemp the first is going to be site
selection than about the fields that you
have available to plant into if you have
Fields with really competitive weed
species really high densities of weeds
or perennial weeds like bind weed Canada
thistle uh that would be a field to
avoid so uh being very mindful about
scouting your Fields understanding what
the weed communities look like we have a
couple of pig weed species here we have
our usual pow amaran redroot smooth
pigweed but we also have Palmer amaran
and water hemp creeping into the state
and those weeds can grow up to 10 feet
tall okay so you need if if you're going
to be rotating into an agricultural
production field and there could be
Palmer amarand and water hemp that is
not a field we want to be in with hemp
we don't have the options for
controlling these species they grow tall
they grow fast and the the seed
production is enormous and so those seed
banks build very quickly another
technique that we can use as a stale
seedbed technique and this is going to
depend on your planting date and the
species that you have there is you can
allow species to germinate and then go
in and kill them either with a like a a
when they're at the white thread stage a
shallow discing uh you can go in with a
non-selective herbicide that you can
burn them down you can go in with a
flame weader this is something we're
doing with crays right now in their
organic beet production is letting the
weeds get up going in with a flame
weeder burning them off maybe doing that
two or three times before planting so
that seed bank that's already present
allowing some of those weeds to get up
and then get them killed so maybe when
it comes time for planting you are
dealing with fewer options uh fewer
weeds that are going to need to be
controlled seed bed preparation this is
for you know General crop management
having a smooth even bed if you can plan
into a smooth even bed you're going to
facilitate good seed soil contact you're
going to have better stand establishment
hopefully you're going to have more even
germination more even emergence and
growth and that is going to help you
have a strong crop stand because you're
going to want a Max maximiz crop Vigor
and stand development obviously choosing
varieties with high Vigor rapid growth
as is appropriate for what other uh
parameters you're interested in
basically you want to make sure that
You' get a good even stand you want to
minimize the space that's available for
the weeds to colonize and then when it
comes to harvest time making sure that
you're harvesting clean Fields first do
not go to your weediest field Harvest
that and then go to a field that's
relatively clean all you are doing is
moving weed seed from your weedy field
now to your clean field um Mike Hunter
I'm from New York State IPM we have a
separate handout and this is just
general for all your Harvest equipment
it is talking about weed seed movement
and Equipment cleanout please check this
out if if you are doing you know kind of
your grain your fiber harvesting whether
you're talking hemp whether you're
talking other crops we are moving a lot
of weed seed around we are moving a lot
of problematic weeds like the water hemp
like the Palmer hamr is coming in on our
equipment and this is a this is an an
easy strategy we can use uh to minimize
the spread of some of these super
invasive super problematic species now
the last thing I want to uh talk about
is is going to be
herbicides herbicides can be both in the
season seon with uh that of hemp we're
going to be talking about sonol land now
we do talk about if we can put hemp into
an effective crop rotation so if we can
get very good weed control in preceding
crops that can help us in our hem crop
but understand labels have rotation
restrictions on them okay there are
rotation restrictions on the labels and
you must pay attention to them those
rotation restrictions are there from the
EPA because of residue potential but I'm
going to tell you hemp is very sensitive
to a lot of herbicides so we got to be
very mindful we have to be thinking also
of what the carryover injury could
potentially be I have looked at about a
dozen plus soil applied herbicides and
I'm going to tell you what
about 11 of them have have killed him
outright so we've got to be very mindful
so it's it's kind of a double-edged
sword we might get good weed control in
one crop but the uh rotation
restrictions those potential residue
concerns that potential injury could be
an issue of rotating into the hemp year
so please be mindful and hemp is not
going to fall into a lot of those uh
crop rotation restrictions so it falls
under the other crop category which
tends to be much more
restrictive all right so on to sauna
land sauna Land is Our Only registered
herbicide it is a supplemental label uh
in New York state it expires on the 1st
of May in 2026 you're going to have to
go to the nice pad website and download
that supplemental label and have it on
hand this herbicide uh e the Florin it
is a yellow herbicide anyone who is
familiar with the wssa groups this is a
group three it's a dinitro analine this
herbicide is primarily effective at
suppressing annual grasses such as crab
grasses foxtails barnyard grass it may
have activity against some small seeded
annual broad leaves like Pig weeds N
Shades but it is not a strong broadleaf
herbicide I do not think about this as a
broadleaf herbicide think about this as
a grass herbicide
primarily uh it can be applied at rates
ranging from 1 and2 to 3 pins per acre I
believe we've used 2.5 in our trials
here these rates are going to be
dependent on your soil type if you have
a coarse soil and your sandier you're
going to go
lower now this can be incorporated two
ways it can be applied as a
pre-emergence so after the crop has been
planted applied to the surface and then
it's going to have to be irrigated in or
it's going to have to have rainfall fall
to move it into the soil solution where
it's active or it can be mechanically
Incorporated pre-plant Incorporated so
sonol land is applied it's Incorporated
you plant into it now if we have done a
study here on the campus and basically
we found pre pre-plan Incorporated
versus pre-emergence we had hemp uh
emerge and establish equally well with
respect to the weed control this year
the pre-plant Incorporated gave us much
better control than our pre-emergence we
had a very dry year we had a very dry
year so we felt that we got that uh
sauna land incorporated into the soil
solution uh physically better than we
would have done with the pre-emergence
the other issue we had is when that soil
started to dry down we started to have
cracks in the soil and our weeds started
to come up through the cracks completely
avoiding the herbicide
this has been shown in other crops is
that where we have dry conditions
pre-plan Incorporated may be more
effective than a pre-emergence
application understand if you're going
to be doing a pre-planned Incorporated
this is going to be a single pass
mechanical incorporation Tran similar
herbicide to e florland we like to do
two passes eth flurin is recommended as
a single pass if you have clumps and
clots if that soil is too wet you are
not going to incorporate that herbicide
well you are going to have patchy weed
control and you have the potential for
increased herbicide injury because
you'll have it concentrated in certain
areas as opposed to others I'm also
going to tell you if we get heavy
rainfall and we have flooded conditions
you will get injury from
sonan um it can do it that is uh um
mentioned on the label what you'll see
is stubby Roots you'll see swollen
brittle stems and you can just have
breakage right there and that'll be a
problem particularly if we get strong
winds coming through so just because
this is registered does not mean it is
100% safe you can get injury
particularly under wet conditions um
also the injury potential is going to be
increased if you don't have your sprayer
calibrated properly you're not putting
it out at the proper rate or you don't
line up and you have overlapping and
you're uh increasing the concentration
of that herbicide in certain areas um
the last thing I'd like to mention uh is
I am the the state liaison for the ir4 I
do the ir4 research for herbicides here
in New York and uh I do want to just
point out is that we do put hemp
recommendations hemp requests into the
ir4 program right now we are setting our
final our final uh priorities for the
2025 season there were hundreds of
recommend of requests that went in
across weed science Plant Pathology
entomology and all crops uh we have to
narrow it down to 40 so it's hard and
hemp gets too and but I'm going to tell
you I don't think herbicides are going
to be in the program for next year for
hemp um just looking at the ir4 food
requests in previous years we've
recommended did uh uh dual Magnum we've
recommended berox andil we've
recommended Stinger all all herbicides
that we've seen a measure of safety and
basically the manufacturers have said
they are not going to support this year
we recommended codm it is a grass
herbicide a postemergence grass
herbicide we heard back at this Workshop
the manufacturer will not support so
right now there are two other residual
herbicides that are kind of in the mix
and uh frankly just based on discussions
with the weed science team it's not
looking good from there's just too much
variable injury across the United States
so I want to just swing it back to what
I started off with I am not very
confident about the herbicide outlook
for the future just from an injury
standpoint and from a a company
standpoint with respect to regulations
legality and just their twitchiness of
being involved with hemp and it's its
current regulation environment um which
means that we're going to have to be
very very very mindful about the
integrated weed management again weed
Management in preceding crops again
thinking about herbicide residue and
injury Potential from those products
then using those alternate strategies
and I'm really very very very interested
in uh doing some more tests with uh the
stale seeded uh techniques going forward
next year I think that's going to be
[Applause]
critical L Len is trying to run away
before you ask any
questions questions for
[Music]
Lynn I I will say we are doing priority
setting right now and I I left so I
could come out here
Yeah question how many varieties uh was
the IDE trial on uh so that I cannot
tell you right now here is the other
problem and thank you for bringing that
up hemp varieties the the pre-plant
incorporation versus pre we just
the we we have just done Bea breski here
I have done other pre-emergence trials
with Ana and I'm going to tell you seed
Viger is really going to change that too
cuz we had some UNCA that did not have a
good seed Viger and boy herbicide injury
is magnified if you don't have good seed
Viger and that crop is going to struggle
to get out of the ground um it it trust
me we've seen it across crops the other
thing that I want to bring up about hemp
even with the sauna land the label says
it is not tested on all hemp varieties
and you have a lot of genetic diversity
in this crop now the USDA actually just
published a paper on field corn and
sweet corn on a a herbicide that we have
labeled and that we use regularly an
hppd herbicide and they found that there
was a whole genetic background across
all of our corn that's in some of the
sweet corn and in some of the field corn
and it makes that the varieties that
that uh were evolved from that more
sensitive to this one herbicide so that
is the other issue we can't test every
every variet out there we can't test all
the genetic background so you have to
understand there's always going to be
that potential for injury we think we
know everything about corn come on we've
been working on corn forever and we just
this year discovered you know uh a
genetic element that makes certain
varieties more sensitive to a herbicide
that we've had registered so just
understand there's a lot in that genetic
background that is going to potentially
influence the safety and so the you know
the sonol land label does recommend
testing on you know a small amounts of
of you know a a a planted crop at first
or become familiar with this uh in a
variety that you are going to use
because there is just that potential
okay last question DAV quick you
mentioned uh mechanical incorporation
pre-planting how deep uh I believe we
went 2 in oh just just shallow this is
going to be a shallow incorporation but
again I think it probably your soil
quality is going to be critical again
making sure that it's evenly
Incorporated in that 2
in yeah so that thank you very much Lynn
uh she is a wealth of knowledge so if
you have questions about uh weed
management uh please don't hesitate to
contact
Lynn and and she always gets back you
very quickly
so so uh that is a good segue David uh
for my little three minute uh discussion
about site
preparation uh so we use conventional
tillage on this Farm uh we use
relatively little no no till practices
here uh so all of our trials that you
see here were uh mold board plowed
dis and
then uh cam mulched I believe until we
got a a fairly well fitted field then we
applied the sonlin culto mulch to
incorporate it and the latest thing that
we've been doing is uh incorporating a
rolling
step and so I learned that from uh my
friend Corby midth of Kopi us that he
said in France
they roll all of their fields and so we
most of these fields out here have been
rolled after planting so the small plot
trial we seated it with our cone seeder
and then we rolled the
field and by doing that we ensure good
seed to soil
contact we get an A nice uh level field
uh if we were going to do the pre
emergent application of Salin we as Lynn
said we would have a nice level the uh
surface for
that
uh we ensure that the seed is buried uh
because bird predation right after
planting is a huge
problem and actually I think at the high
especially at the higher seating rate
for the fiber varieties those birds the
doves can pick out the rows that you've
seated at a higher seating rate and they
will just sit there and
and eat all your
seed uh it's not a minor thing don't
dismiss it uh and then the final benefit
that we see of rolling is that it pushes
the Rocks down and the first year we
started
bailing uh and then running Bales
through our
decorticator uh we learned that they
were full of
rocks so you need to be when we get to
the raking demonstration you need to you
cannot be too aggressive with the rake
uh and flip rocks up into your uh wind
rows because they will end up in your
Bales and you really don't want rocks
going through your
decorticator so by Rolling uh one
benefit that we see is uh that you push
the Rocks down at least to the soil
surface uh so we did a little study uh
this field that uh Jacob just started
cutting that's field
20 uh was rolled just make sure I get my
notes right uh was r before planting and
then we seated it with a John Deere no
till
drill the farther field uh the next two
acres down which is field
25 we rolled after seating because I was
talking with Sarah Mitchell and she said
oh you can't roll after
seating uh you won't get emergence
tractor the tractor wheels the tract
you've seen it with the tractor wheels
uh so what actually what I saw was uh
there was no difference in the stand
count at 3 weeks whether you roll before
planting or roll after
seeding and in fact you know this is our
roller uh we just parked it out there uh
so you can take a look at it you know it
it's not going to compress it's not
super heavy so it's not going to
compress evenly across the field but
what I saw is the areas where it did
compress and we had a nice smooth flat
surface that's where the seeds came up
first because of that seed to soil
contact so uh I I would all of our
fields around here we grow a lot of
alfalfa around our dairy farms those
fields are rolled uh before planting I
just think it's probably a practice you
want to think about uh for your grain
and fiber hem the
next the next thing we're going to hear
about is uh seed treatments uh so
Patrick McMullen is a PhD student in
Chris smarts lab imp Plant Pathology and
has done some really interesting work
and he'll describ this trial which is
behind
us good morning um so I like Larry said
I'm a PhD student in Plant Pathology
studying soil born pathogens and temp
and their management strategies um and
here I conducted a a small plot trial
looking at fungicide SE treatments to
control damping off and soil born
pathogens so as we've just been hearing
about uh stand establishment is a big
concern for ERS and um now that we know
how to perfectly manage weeds thanks to
Lynn hopefully um another piece of that
puzzle is pathogen management so there's
a number of soil born pathogens that
hemp is susceptible to including a
number of species of
pythium um that we have found here in
New York other areas of the US have
reported similar uh findings um as well
as different species of fusarium among
other pathogens uh so most of these
pathogens like pool wet soils like we
have here in the Northeast early in the
growing season when we're planting um so
as we've heard in some earlier
presentations soil drainage is super
important uh ensuring that your Fields
aren't planted in lowly spots that flood
easily those are great areas for
pathogens to just Thrive and take off um
if you're planting into wet wet Fields
the pipian will love that um same thing
with ferium they can uh lead to damping
off uh vascular wilts and root and Crown
rods so here I have been testing
fungicide SE treatments in a
collaborative project with both Larry's
lab and Alan Taylor's lab a seed
scientist here at Cornell they
thankfully uh treated the seeds for us
so I used
um several different fungicide SE
treatments there were two that were um
copper hydroxide products americop and
ultum um as well as a phosphite product
and phos phosphorus uh prudent 44 and
neutral and then we compared these to a
conventional fungicide uh treatment of
apron and Maxum which is flu oyal and
methoxy um so the
um the the coppers and phosphates are in
the works of being registered for hemp
but the apron and Maxum is not we were
using this as a research uh control that
we expected to work well as it usually
works well on the fungal soilborne
pathogens as well as the water molds
like
pum um so these seeds were treated and
then planted with a cone Cedar into
these small plot
trials and uh stand counts were
collected 3 weeks after post plan
as well as 6 weeks and then again at
Harvest um this study we completed fully
last year and then replicated again this
year that I'm standing in front of um
this year we added a an additional um
formulation of ultum that isn't on the
handout um but is on the field map if
you're looking at that so looking at the
data from last year we saw increases in
Stand counts for all of the Z treatments
um looking at the percent increase I
should mention we tested this on two
different fiber cultivars so there's
fiber 79 and Futura 83 that Luis talked
a good bit about in our previous
presentations um so we want to test
these on Two
cultivars And we saw numeric increases
in Stand count with all of these
fungicide Z C treatments at 3 weeks post
planting um with only significant
increases um of a 58% increase compared
to the non-re control in ultum and The
Prudent 44 in neutral treatments so
that's quite a large increase there 58%
compared to
non-re however then when we went to the
later uh stand count time points we did
not see significant increases although
we did still see some numeric
increases um at Harvest we also
collected biomass last year and saw no
significant increases no significant
differences in uh plant biomass between
any of the treatments compared to the
controls um so this year we replicated
that and we are also including a um the
same planting density as we did last
year 30 plants per square foot square
feet which is over here on your left
side and over on your right is a reduced
planting density of 15 plants per square
fet um we wanted to see if when a C
treatment is applied uh can we use a
lower planting density to therefore use
less seed um will that be will that give
us an economic gain that we're you know
putting less seed into the field while
increasing stand establishment um so
those trials are being evaluated
currently I'm going to be collecting
harest data this coming week so I don't
have those final numbers for you yet but
all that data should be available next
summer and hopefully give us some
insight into uh the best practices for
managing sort War pathogens I will say
one interesting thing that I saw in this
year's data was that all of the SE
treatments except for the conventional
um meth uh apron and maximum treatment
significantly increased stand count at 3
weeks post planting so these were the
copper and phosphite products however
not the conventional fungicides of
methan oxin and D oxin so um that leads
us to think maybe there's something else
at play here other than just soilborne
pathogens um maybe it's a a nutritional
thing that these extra compounds are
helping with we're not quite sure what's
going on because we would expect this
conventional fungicide to be quite
effective there's not a lot of known
resistance to it um and it's effective
against uh other soil born pathogens and
other crops that are infected with these
same species so um at this point it
looks like the future outlook for sea
treatments is quite well for improving
stand count uh stand establishment um
but we will be looking at some final
data here to see uh differences in
biomass at Harvest as well as uh stem
diameters and uh plant
height um so for now some of the uh best
practices you can do to avoid avoid soil
born pathogen management is is really uh
focusing on those cultural practices
right ensuring your well- drained Fields
um sanitizing your equipment and uh
trying to get a good stand early by
planting at times maybe not right before
a storm like Larry's pointing out make
sure you're planting in appropriate
weather um so I'd be happy to take any
questions you might have about pathogen
management yeah I just want to confirm
Patrick we did not apply sonoline to
this field correct yeah so these fields
were rolled um post uh seating but we
did not apply an herbicide
so yeah this is an anecdotal observation
and again you can talk more with Lynn
about it but when you compare our other
fields and drive around and see our
other fields that were treated with
selin compared to this
field uh there's a lot of grass in there
so I'm pretty psyched about Salin it's
pretty seems to be working pretty well
pre-plant
incorporation questions for Patrick
yes which copper uh copper the question
was which copper this is copper
hydroxide both of them yeah you've been
mentioning the um attacks eating the
seeds could it actually be that the
application TDE is increasing this 10
actually makes less oh that's a good
question yes uh so the question is uh
can the the fungicides make the can the
seed treatment make the seed less
attractive to Birds um yes I think that
can very well be true we don't have data
to support that we didn't test for that
in experimental design but I do imagine
that the birds are not choosing these F
side Tria seeds and the the non Tria
control was truly non-treated it didn't
have the film Cod SE
treatment these are some
stem St stem um I have not observed a
lot of that in my field I haven't really
collected insect data but I think we do
see but we really don't have that many
stemborers here it's not a an economic
problem in New York or
grasshoppers for which we are
thankful okay uh so our next uh series
of yeah thank you Patrick great job
we're now going to move on to a series
of equipment demonstrations and uh you
we're going to assemble so move
hastily section uh material dri faster R
more
evenly uh and then ultimately take less
work on your rake and Bor uh to be able
to remove that material once you see the
rake going through you'll start to
understand how 12T stocks are a little
bit challenging for uh that type of
equipment so uh it sounds like the
machine is getting a little bit closer
to us uh so I'll probably have to stop
talking now but if you look over there
you'll see thech
have something major happen we can be
there uh I travel around the country and
fall uh fixing equipment as necessary uh
working with Growers understanding more
and what you see behind us is our
current generation of machine uh but
every year we get better um we're not a
very complacent company I get bored
quickly I like to see stuff uh evolve
and so we're going to continue to evolve
uh pieces of equipment like this as an
industry changes but I also want to make
uh people aware that that while we do
develop this machine this is at the end
all be all of how to have Harvest H I
think that there's a lot of application
for for this type of machine in the
country but there's other types of
implements out there that that can work
as well we've developed equipment for
fors Harvesters uh that can wind R uh
material and then you can go back and
pick that up really just depends on what
your application is going to be what
you're going to Market with and that's
that's what you got to think about when
you're you're looking at growing hemp
when you're looking at uh processing
hemp what what's the end result need to
be and then work that backwards and you
usually get to the right equipment if
you started the equipment first and work
it Forward uh you'll often times run
into some bottlenecks that are really
hard to accomplish so um this is just
one aspect of it and I want to thank
Larry uh for letting us run the machine
today and uh uh being a part of what we
do with Bish Enterprises and I'm I'm
proud to be a part of what what people
are doing you here at Cornel University
can I uh yeah you can thank you Andrew
so you can see
that on this side I had a few more
cutting issues if you look to the other
side it's actually a very clean cut and
so crop conditions are very important
for your Harvest uh you'll know some of
you might have noticed we were cutting a
bit this morning it was really wet this
morning it was a little more difficult
than it should have been an 8: a.m.
Harvest is definitely different from a 2
p.m. Harvest uh and this is something
I've noticed with all of the field it's
been a lot harder to harvest traveling
to the north where to the South
uh it's a much cleaner cut the crop
Falls where it's supposed to in this
direction it tends to get pushed and I
get a little bit more lodging um you'll
notice I'm adjusting the height of the
machine up and down uh obviously you
want to get as low of a cut as possible
to get as much tonnage but in some
situations you might have planted too
densely the crop might be too moist and
you have to cut a couple inches above
just to keep that crop flowing smoothly
uh so there's a lot of infield
conditions you have to be aware of
outside of the machine itself
okay Andrew didn't mention this jacob
didn't mention it either but uh this
machine
broke uh what 3 weeks ago uh yeah it
broke as I was going to park it uh I
finished all my cutting everything went
well uh and then I had a weld fail and
steel fell on the ground uh so that was
a bit of a repair took me some time uh
we actually have the parts we show
people later anyone wants to see that
damage um but the most important thing
as Andrew said uh is we do stand behind
our equipment and so I was able to make
a call I was able to get something
fabricated uh and I was able to have my
part some time to continue harvesting
and most importantly to show it off to
you all here today so yeah so I gave
Andrew a call and he said yep we're
making a new tongue for you we'll have
that to you in a few days and he said
you know normally I question the
operator about
but in this case I guess I can't really
do that my
bad so again we really appreciate uh the
support of this Enterprises and I also
want to take a minute here to thank
Andrew as the leader of the empty
Coalition and for all of his efforts
tireless efforts in getting that first
application I think we're we're already
working on the next
application uh for for beef cattle is
that right you want to say a few words
about pemp be coalition Andrew yeah
that's my one of my favorite subjects in
the world I think it's the uh largest
opportunity to the hemp industry is to
open up the animal feed Market it's
going to reduce the cost of production
across the board whether you're whether
you're growing for herd fiber grain can
avonoid doesn't matter uh animal feed is
going to lower the cost of production
across the board uh I've been involved
with the feed Coalition uh for going on
uh almost 5 years now we worked on the
eggl chicken application uh for just
over three and a half years this year uh
we received a a recommendation from the
FDA back in February uh AFCO uh voted in
favor of this um at their F at their
annual meeting in San Antonio uh Texas
in August and so now the market is is
opened up it's federally legal to feed
egg Lane chickens hemp seed meal it's
federally legal to uh have that material
cross borders um no no interstate
commerce issues it's not a state uh it's
not a state regulation this is federal
so that's really exciting and and
Larry's Point what's next uh because we
can't stop with eggl chickens although
eggl chickens interestingly enough 5% if
we impact 5% of the egg Lan chicken
Market that's 670,000 needed Acres of
hem
uh to be grown in the United States just
for egg L chickens not Bo chickens not
roosters just egg layers so what's next
is beef cattle beef cattle and lamb are
up on the docket um we think we'll have
uh an expedited result with those we
have a tremendous amount of research
data uh available for those the fa
actually came to us and said that they
felt that our data was sufficient enough
uh to push an application through uh
without any further studies and that's
really positive to have that
relationship now with the FDA to move
these along so hopefully within about 24
months uh maybe 30 months we we could
see beef cattle approved um in in the
United States uh beyond that we're
looking at equin uh we've got some
studies going on with equine and also
looking at uh the holes and how uh
horses um benefit from the holes of the
seed uh which which currently uh we
don't have a market for at all and
beyond that then uh broilers we are
doing some work with broilers um and as
many animals as we can get studied on
we're going to continue to push this
forward so if you want to see the
industry grow uh contribute to the hemp
feed Coalition we're a good group of
people um we spend all of our money on
studies uh on application and and making
things happen for the hemp industry and
thank you Larry for uh bringing up our
[Applause]
and again with generous funding from New
York State uh Cornell is initiated three
uh animal feeding studies uh with
matching funds from the foundation for
food and agricultural research so a
total of
$500,000 and we will do a study on dairy
cows um boiler chickens and an e stud
with
Hy uh and we hope again to cooperate
with IND hemp
uh to provide that hemp seed meal uh as
a member of the FF hemp research
Coalition uh so it really is a team
effort and I'm glad we were finally able
to get our animal scientists on board
at Okay so we've cut our fiber hemp now
the next step is to let it w and dry
and uh you can go see how wet you can
walk through the field here but I wanted
to give an opportunity uh to our guest
from Poland uh Na kski hopefully my
polish is somewhat acceptable him his
name uh who's going to talk about uh his
experience in Poland with reading and
his company and uh the potential for
using him for
Tex thank you and for
wondering how to pronounce my name is
Magic um I've been asked to to introduce
to share my experiences with uh what
we're doing in Poland which is basically
a vertically integrated company which uh
gross hand we Harvest it we decorticated
ourselves we cotton IE it mechanically
blend it with cotton spin it into your
arm and make products the end products
that you can actually wear so um
afterwards or in the meantime you can
just compare that um stro which is still
the same thing that uh Jacob just cut
down like probably like two 3 weeks ago
um and it is supposed to be red uh it is
somehow red uh what I want to share
about is among the 10 years that I've
been growing H for different
applications for five years I'm focused
solely on fiber and when I say fiber
when Europeans say fiber they usually
mean what you're calling B uh not her
not the other applications so um The Bu
should um separate easily from the her
you can see that happening with the
green one that's why the a lot of people
are saying about green decortication
because you can actually get a clean um
strand of bust uh without any shifts the
problem with that is that you're
actually left with 75% of water which is
the average content of of water both in
fiber in in the in the B and in the her
and while it is technically speaking
quite easy to separate the green um but
then you need to find an application for
75% water in the her or you have to dry
it artificially you cannot dry it in the
field because you won't pick it up so uh
what we uh started doing 10 years ago is
winter reting which was done
accidentally by just forgetting or
actually not being able to harvest 200
of our Acres of of hand grown something
else um what is essentially happening
during winter is what happens in the
very traditional method of of water
reting which means allowing water to
dissolve the glue that is holding it
together that's what we're doing in a
duting du reting means you actually
leave it on the ground break it
sometimes depending on the weather and
allow the the moisture to set to to Aid
you in separating the um the bast from
the heart the better you do your rting
the easier your decortication will be
and the easier the cortication will be
the higher the quality of the end fiber
will be uh I see I've been traveling
across the United States for three and a
half weeks now visiting different
decortication facilities and I see not a
lot of people uh having a a a full
picture from the field from the sea
there's plenty of uh great knowledge
here about what happens in at emergence
rate what how to allow for the best um
count of of the plans but not those
people that have that knowledge usually
don't have knowledge about processing
processing and and the other
thing holds true as well people that are
great with
decortication sometimes even tell I
don't care about farming well they
should because if they don't do the
reting properly they will not do the
decortication properly and if they don't
do decortication properly the only thing
they can do with the fiber is insulation
um so how does it actually work what
what are the um the inner works of of of
our uh process we um we are in a
latitude of 55 North which is closer to
admont so Upstate New York is the
closest thing that I have to to European
conditions to polish conditions uh and
you can see the the differences that lar
mentioned earlier about the maturity of
the plants since we are not cutting down
our plants we let them die with the
first Frost which comes around mid
October so Ursa Alpha would be actually
The Marvelous plant for us because it
would die off without being mature it is
obviously true that the more mature the
plant is the stiffer the fiber is but
it's not exactly about maturity itself
it's about the weight that it carries so
if it's an mature plant that wents into
flowering but has actually pretty small
amount of of of grain the the head will
be light and it will not go into that
lignification that that strongly so we
are growing and and that's something
that I would recommend you to try
especially in the upstate New York um to
get as late blooming varieties as
possible plant them April May or
whatever and forget him for 11 and a
half
months just you can do pictures for for
your Facebook feed or whatever but
nothing else um nature will take uh
control of it and actually all the all
the water that is falling from the sky
whether it's um snow or rain or Dew is
actually entering the stalks but the
important part is that they remain
standing some people call it standing
writing because if you cut it down like
that and leave it till April it will all
mold you it will over R rting
essentially goes from rotting it's it's
a form of of rotting it's actually
that's microbiological processing here
right um so what we see with the crop
that is left standing in a field it gets
wet and then it's dried With the Wind so
it's actually a sort of water rating but
in the field the benefits of that are
you're not using any energy you're not
using any water H all the affluent water
that takes all those glues which
contains plenty of nitrogen actually
stays in your field instead of polluting
our rivers or whatever you do with the
water from way uh from water rting and
then it's much easier to decorticate the
only thing you have to do to decorticate
the fiber like that it's like if I would
pick up a winter rated piece of stro I
would be left with piece of Bast in my
hand and all the heart will be falling
down it's no longer separated to each
other you need zero energy to separate
it so the only thing you actually need
to do is to see it sift it just separate
it mechanically so how do we Harvest it
uh someone was saying that if we allow
the males to die off in a field then
they get dry and they get entangled in a
combined Harvester that's all true with
dry material it's much more difficult to
cut it with anything so we don't cut it
at all we just rake it
our most advanced piece of equipment is
standing right right there just a
regular rake like really the simplest
rake possible we just enter it into the
standing field and and it just creates a
windro without actually cutting the
plants down two things are happening
either the plants are being pulled off
including the piece of of root that
plenty of people say about this huge
root system that hemp has true but
actually the one that you're pulling out
is like an inch long and it has some
heart
it has some Bast fiber which is of poor
quality but it's still you still get it
um the other thing that might be
happening is it breaks at the bottom
because with all the snow that at least
in our part of the country we are having
snow in the winter usually uh with all
the snow at the very bottom the plants
become too brittle you cannot actually
Harvest it when it's freezing because if
it's freezing the plants become brittle
and you're actually destroying it um the
smaller the simpler the slower The Rake
is the better for the fiber you just
making a wind draw and then just bailing
it the very important remark is it all
depends on your processor uh during the
the pen State event that Lara mentioned
David suchu gave a very
um important remark that it's what you
what the farmer wants is what your
processor wants it's actually you're
doing it for the buyer that is actually
taking the fiber from you so even if
it's easier for you it's easier for them
it depends on what sort of line do they
have of what sort of bail opener do they
have and what's the end application of
it um all the stuff that is being
removed by rain water by snow and also
by water swelling when water freezes it
increases its volume when the water is
inside the the strand of Bast fiber that
that's basically fiber right but um a
lot of people say about long fiber that
technique is not applicable for long
fiber at all it's only for short fiber
but
actually I'm in the my minority in the H
industry claiming that there is no such
thing as one fiber there is only a
bundle of fibers that might belong
because the individual fibers if you
just separate it and then you see those
small white tiny things can just
everyone can grab a piece and look at it
later and those small white pieces of
something those are actually hand fibers
they're an inch long inch and a half and
that's what what you're witnessing with
cotton so we are using a cotton system
despite being a country where there's no
cotton at all uh so the United States
has a huge industry that used to process
more cotton than they do I I don't know
the volumes but basically you have
plenty of equipment that might be used
for cotton uh which is used for cotton
in some places um I've been actually in
in some refabric cotton jeans that are
doing it um one of of our colleagues
when I mentioned the winter wrting
process to him a year ago now he
actually did all the Acres this way and
he says he's actually having a lower
electricity Bild because he doesn't
really need to break all that stuff the
line can be shorter because even after
the most expensive decortication
equipment ever if you don't do your
wetting properly you will end up with
fiber contaminated with lots of um hers
which might be good for some
applications but it's definitely not
good for um textile application for
textile application if you use the short
fiber setup which is basically opening
the fibers mechanically Garing them ing
them whatever you call it you separate
it into individual fibers and where does
the de gaming process comes in into all
that a lot of people are saying about D
gaming D gaming is basically covering
your mistakes at reting that's the way I
see it h a lot of people I hear now are
are interested in green decorticated
fiber which is which has zero reading
and in that case in order to use it to
anything you need to undergo a de gaming
process which is basically making the
same thing that winter does for me I'm
calling it semi deam because it still
doesn't remove all the liins it still
doesn't remove everything but uh winter
red hemp is actually much better uh for
textile from my perspective using my
equipment than anything that's ever seen
it can be done all over across the
United States even where people don't
know they did winter rating they did
winter rating I've collected some
samples this April from North Dakota
which is like probably closer in
latitude to here but also from
California we actually spawn those
fibers despite people saying don't take
that that's that's just our mistake we
just forgot to harvest it I've seen
winter red hemp in California H which is
absolutely perfect it doesn't look very
well like if you compare what you seeing
in the field and you compare to this it
also doesn't look very well right it's
it's not what you're uh selling on on
advertisement of hemp that doesn't
really look like hemp but well you also
don't want to see how most of the things
are being done in between uh so um the
um the winter wrting process is
something that you definitely can try in
here I don't know how I'm looking at
TimeWise but probably judging by Larry's
approaching me it's probably closer to
the end uh so if you have any questions
I'm feel free to ask them now or I will
be staying here until the end of uh the
day today thank you
[Applause]
did you use just a standard rake and
just drive it slower or did you have
specialized equipment for your harvest
in say January or March or whenever you
did it I don't want to use any
specialized equipment because if you
want to scale it up and you want to
convince Farmers you want them to use
whatever they have so it was the very
regular rake um one important thing is
is the variety obviously you cannot um
choose any but with the rake literally
you can choose any actually one of my
Farmers because we grow 100 acres
ourselves and we also have some some
Farmers growing it for us used a larger
rake and it was actually worse because
with a larger rake the the force with
which it was hitting the plant was
bigger and it actually uh did some of
the it broke too many stems while it was
happening so a lot of shifts a lot of HT
was left uh on the ground so obviously I
cannot achieve the speed at which uh the
B brothers are doing it that's that's
impossible for me I'm I'm cutting a two
to three acres an hour tops when it
comes to length if that's what you
wanted to ask the higher the better like
I know some processors don't want long
um stems in their in their um Pro
because they are stiff like if you want
to um bail even bail something like that
it was just going to stand I don't know
English word for it but this way and and
it just doesn't get up in in the Bor in
our case it's already brittle already
soft so it doesn't really matter I'm
using the Bales with the whole length
which is like 15 16 fet tall and then is
being separated at the um carding
opening stage which is basically drums
with pin rollers and whatever you have
at at the cotton genin can easily with
slight modification open even the
longest Str of
fiber question comment on fiber
discoloration from
cladosporium uh it is essentially close
to Black when we take it from the field
which might uh well it does indicate
some microbial uh infection you might
call it or whatever but actually for
textile production which is our sole
Focus uh first when you open it up
everything goes into the dust bin so the
most uh problematic part of that is the
health and safety of the emplo employees
actually doing that because all that
dust contains some fungi that you don't
want to introduce into your LS uh but
then all the um mechanical processes
there are some fibers that are over red
when they're totally black that usually
means the strength is lower the strength
of the winter red hemp will be lower but
you don't actually go for klar
applications you go for cotton
applications cotton is not a very strong
fiber um so the the um the weaken spots
will actually be destroyed in in the
process in the mechanical processing and
then the
microbiological issues will be solved
when the the yarn is finished and you
weave it into fabric fabric is always
being water treated uh this was
sanforized which is like uh going
through the boiling water so it's we
don't really see it as as an issue ra
except except for the part of health and
safety of the employee which has to be
accounted for thank
you I have just one more I have kind of
two questions one uh so does winter
reting not eliminate the ligman uh is
that what you're saying and then my
other question is what do you do with
the residual waste actually uh take out
um well uh does it take all the ligin no
it doesn't take all the ligin you can
still run it through chemical de gaming
and still see some uh delignification
but I I I'm not an academic I just get
my fiber through the spinning meal we
have that comfort of actually being able
to run even several kilos through the
whole process and see if the end result
is good for me I don't really care if
there's ligin still left in it if it's
soft enough for me to wear and I'm happy
with it then then I'm happy with it when
it comes to to waste there is not really
any waste well during the um this the
the standing rting obviously all of the
fibers all all the all of the flowers
all of the grains falling down to the
ground or feeding the birds which
actually made me thinking when uh during
the morning presentation someone said
that THC testing is happening a month
before Harvest I'm harvesting in April
does it mean I'm THC testing in March
and I can actually grow High TC
varieties in New York maybe that's Al a
solution for hot varieties uh um and
when it comes to to the processing stage
you get the um the good fiber which goes
to spinning you got the her which
basically goes to any applications other
than animal bedding because of the
microbiological issues it has a funny
smell it smells like um
being in a village like you know the uh
I don't know the English word for it but
it's basically you don't one of the
decorators I asked him about it and he
said they did some trials and it doesn't
actually affect horses but it's not the
horses that are buying the herse it's
the herse owners and they don't want
this smell so uh it's used mostly for
construction and for garden mching and
the other the third part of of the
product stream is is a dust we just use
it for composting because we're not a
huge processor we rather aim to do all
the processing up until the very end
stage rather than just go big and do one
thing
[Music]
do you have trouble with weed control
like uh when you go to baale is there a
lot of excess grass there is although
it's not really associated with winter
rating it's rather with the fact that
we're using EU certified ecological
regime which means we don't do anything
with any uh other than mechanical
destruction because we are sewing early
May so we can allow the plants the weeds
to germinate kill them off allow them to
germinate kill them off but there's
still plenty left and most of them die
off before well all of them die off
before processing and the the uh the
processing we're using is so
mechanically aggressive that is actually
reduces all of it to dust I have zero
problem with Wheats in the end product
two things that are important to mention
is like it takes some of my nutrients
that's true and it takes some of my
processing space if I introduce a ton
into the decorticator or the processing
line and 100 kgs of that is wheat well
then I'm running essentially at 90 % of
of the capacity which is a Nuance but
not really a problem and one thing that
I think Steve mentioned to me is like
where you you just have um you're just
lucky with your weeds because some of
the weeds that are growing in here are
actually going through all the
processing lines so it it all depends on
what sort of Wis are they I don't know
the the Polish name for my WIS so I
wouldn't even try to translate
them great yeah very good
[Applause]
thank you very much and I think we all
have a goal of now coming to visit
Poland uh okay I just want to give you a
couple of again anecdotal notes Here uh
so this field to my left is carmena it's
an international hemp variety I I really
like it uh this was planted May
31st uh and you see that the grain heads
are if they're not mature they're pretty
close to
mature uh very similar variety offered
by Verve seeds is
Jurassic uh performs very similar uh
ssba uh IH Williams will also perform
like this I I like all three of those uh
last year we had a grower
nearby uh Harvest With a shellborne
Stripper header on his conventional John
Deere
Combine and most of that crop went
through the stripper header quite
well
and we were left with a
field uh of standing stems with nothing
at the top and I can just imagine what
magic just described to us you could
leave those stems to Winter W so you've
harvested the Grain and then you have a
field of standing stems with no foliage
and no grain head at the top that should
winterr very well
uh so I'm going to point to Steve and my
other folks who are creative engineers
and I think what we need is a straw
Walker combine with a shellborne
stripper header uh that's on an elevator
that you can drive through that field
and run the the stripper header at 8 or
9 or 10 ft tall capture the Grain and
then let's see uh what quality of straw
we get the next spring after we winter
Reddit okay that's my little anecdotal
suggestion okay uh so normally we would
have cut this field it would have been
laying there drying and starting to
R but because our our fiber cut was
broken we didn't get a chance so we only
cut it this
morning and we but we wanted to
demonstrate to you raking which would be
the next step so as this dries and
starts to W it will R differentially so
it will dry and turn brown on the upper
surface and then still be green on the
bottom
surface so we need to turn it at least
once and we also need to get it into
wind rows so we are prepared to bail it
uh so we have uh a hay rake uh to do
that normal hay rake uh we're going to
demonstrate that uh and that's all just
simple farming right that's what any hay
farmer would do not
complicated The Twist that we're adding
today is uh as we grow this crop we want
to be a sustainable as possible and here
here at Corno agretech we want to be the
farm of the future and we think the farm
of the future will be at least somewhat
electrified uh so we have one of the
first examples of an electric tractor
that's on the market uh that we
purchased uh and we have Rich Wildman
from agdo who is now our regional
distributor that's correct yes Regional
distributor for Monarch tractor and I'm
going to call up uh Cody light from
Monarch tractor uh to describe their
technology and uh then we're going to
see it run
I'll just I'll just start but then turn
this over to Cody um we're based in
Rochester um this is a 100% EV no diesel
no no fuel um rechargeable tractor it
also has the ability to operate
autonomously um we'll show you that
later on um Cody why don't you tell them
just very briefly the background of
Monarch and um so my name is light I'm
the regional sales manager for Monarch
here in the Northeast um representing
with with act too but this tractor is is
really started in 2017 and the
co-founders there's five co-founders of
Monarch that had the same vision that
Larry just just stated the
sustainability cleaning um being more
environmental friendly but then taking
it to another level of every Farm has
labor shortages so the future of Monarch
is also in the autonomy piece which I
believe that you guys will see an
example of that during lunch um but the
the core belief of the tractor is to be
fully electric and to give you that that
labor enhancing down down the road we're
going to have Chris drive it today but
while while he's driving it the the
sustainability piece kind of goes into
how the tractor is designed too the
original intent was to take a utility
vehicle and a tractor that came from a
Vineyard and kind of combine it into one
so if you look at the tractor the front
of it looks kind of goofy right the
front of it is I like to call it the
front so we give you a bed that can hold
up to 220 lb and we give you d-rings in
there to be able to strap things down
and use it as a bed like you would a
pickup truck or your utility vehicle um
the color of it though at the top that
kind of sandstone is supposed to
represent sand dirt the blue the blue
part is the battery that battery is
0 Kow 440 volts and that that color is
supposed to represent w
the dark gray is supposed to represent
Rock so we take the sustainability piece
all the way down to the color of that
tractor
[Music]
through a mobile app on our phone I'll
be able to see that I can see the video
cameras live from anywhere in the world
I can see how fast the operator is
moving you know if they hit something
and no one tells you about it well I I
got proof now of what really happened
right um so there's a lot of opportun
within this tractor I guess I'll just
I'll leave it there is there any
questions great so he asked about weight
compared to a comparable diesel tractor
warranty and runtime and I'll throw off
warranty so the tractor weighs about
5700 lbs so comparable to a
similar horsepower tractor we rate this
tractor at 70 motor horsepower 40 on the
PTO um it it is heavy but when we look
at that battery so that blue part up
front if we were to weigh that compared
to a diesel engine with all of its
emissions and cooling we weigh about the
same our tractors weighed 5050 a typical
tractor 6040 so we we put that weight
across the tractor more evenly than than
some of the others in in the industry
run time is up to 14 hours so that's on
a single charge we offer three different
Chargers we can charge that as quick as
5 hours up to you know 10 hours
overnight to be fully charged ready for
the next day and then the warranty piece
the tractor itself is a 4year 4,000 hour
warranty the battery is an 8year 8,000
hour warranty so when you look at
longevity warranty what the company's
going to stay behind nothing in the
industry today
gas diesel electric touches this
warrant how does run imp on
the great question it definitely affects
it um PTO takes a lot of horsepower
and our last demonstration is of that
male Baylor would you see up on the
hill well as you can tell not everything
goes to plan uh I got a very small
partial bail but if you look over here
you can see I just really jammed that
right side uh it's a jam I've not before
uh so this is new to me I'm going to
have to take some time to clear that out
um but you can see it only takes half a
second before you run into a problem
that might take you an afternoon to fix
um so it takes a lot of vigilance when
you're running this equipment only takes
6 in for 2 seconds too long and you got
a problem
so like like what everything we're doing
out here this is research we're learning
and we're going to continue to develop
our knowledge um I'll as an equipment
operator I'll continue to learn and
encounter this less and less but I can
assure you I will encounter this more
times in the future um so that's that's
what we're all here to do today is is
learn and now you can see some of the
things I deal with which can be
immediate problems um a little bit
more well you got to have tenacity if
you're going to give oh absolutely I
don't have many skills but I got
persistence
TV products but they're not a priority
for us um it's actually more ourv have
market and our
[Music]
and that's how you make a boun
[Applause]
smell yeah it has a yeah of a mulchy
smell to
it now
this this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu