This is a production of Cornell
University.
Okay, good morning everyone and thank
you Mora for that introduction. I'm very
excited to talk to you all today about
some of the work that my lab is doing
and turning to um tomato's genetic past
to improve traits for for its future.
So let's see now before we get started I
just want to um thank the grad students
for the opportunity to present here
today. It's it's really an honor. Um
when I was a grad student these symposia
were a highlight of my graduate career.
Um this is the first one that I attended
in 2016. The the theme that year was
breeding for the emerging global middle
class. That year I had the opportunity
to nominate and ultimately invite a
scientist whose work I really deeply
admired. That's Frank Mangan at the
University of Massachusetts Amherst who
devoted his career to reaching out to
immigrant populations in the northeast
United States uh developing market
opportunities for new vegetable crops
for for those communities. Um I I I
learned recently that that Frank passed
away last year. Um this symposium gave
me the chance to meet him in person,
hear a wonderful seminar. So, you know,
to be on the other side of that and
presenting today, it's really meaningful
to me. So, thank you all for the
opportunity and and thank you for for
sponsoring these these wonderful
programs. So, I was also excited as a
new tomato breeder to hear the theme of
of this year's symposium. Um, maybe I'm
biased because of what I work on, but I
think tomato is really a model for the
conservation, characterization, and
utilization of of wild relatives in in
plant breeding. Um, thanks to the
efforts of pioneering geneticists like
Charlie Rick who collected thousands of
excessions um, both wild and
domesticated of tomato. Um, we have
access to to excellent germplasm
resources in gene banks. Um, wild
relatives of tomato have been used to
answer fundamental questions about
evolutionary biology like the evolution
of self- incompatibility and
interpacific
incompatibility. And breeders have used
these genetic resources for at this
point almost 100 years to identify um
traits of agonomic importance in wild
relatives and bring them into
domesticated tomato.
So just to give a really high level
outline of my talk today. Um I want to
share a little bit about the genetic
history of tomato. Um before going into
kind of what the modern US tomato
industry looks like and where the
research that my lab is doing um where
we aim to kind of fit in there. I'm
going to talk about two different
projects that that we're working on. one
looking at uh you know a very um
diverged tomato wild relative and
looking at sources of abiotic stress
tolerance there and then also going you
know more recently into tomato's
evolutionary past and breeding modern
varieties for quality and beauty using
heirloom genetics and then finally I'll
talk about some of the challenges that
we're facing and what I think
possibilities are for the
future so they're generally considered
to be 16 spec species that are wild
relatives of tomato. These are found in
western South America where populations
of these grow from the western slopes of
the Andes to the coast. Um, two of these
species are also uh found exclusively on
the Galapagos Islands. These species
occupy a variety of different uh
ecological niches and grow in a variety
of different uh microclimates that
people have um characterized extensively
uh considering you know what that could
mean in terms of their potential impact
for tomato
breeding. So in terms of the
domestication of tomato for for a long
time it's been recognized that the most
closely related wild relative is senam
pipanelopolium which you can see on the
left here. This species produces small
maybe P-shaped fruit that ripen to a red
color. Um, but there's also been this
other uh botanical variety of tomato
called selenium like a persicum variety
sassif that grows either as a cultivated
plant through South America, Central
America, Mexico or it grows in wild
populations or as like a weedy species
in relation to to human habitats.
And um it's been proposed that this
botanical variety was kind of an
evolutionary intermediate in the
domestication of tomato from selenium
pibanelopolium. But the exact nature of
where and how that happened has been
under uh debate for a little
bit. One of the most recent theories
that's come out um proposes a pretty
complicated story of how tomato was
domesticated.
uh but it it the story that they present
is is most psimmonious with the genetic
data that we have. So what the authors
of this paper proposed is that um tens
of thousands of years ago before humans
arrived to South America, ancestral
populations of selenium pimpanelopolium
migrated to Mexico um acquired different
traits adaptations to a new climate
along the way um and diverged into this
new species like a persicum uh variety
Sarasa for. And then tens of thousands
of years later, it moved back to South
America, but this time in a much shorter
time span, probably carried by humans
who are also carrying other early
domesticated crops such as
mace. Back in South America, it
hybridized with wild populations of
selenium
pippinellopolium. Um the native people
of South America might have um selected
and um domesticated selenium like a
persum uh strassopform at that point. It
then moved back to Mexico where the
native people of Mexico domesticated the
large fruited tomato that we all
recognize
today. So there we don't really have um
records of what you know early tomatoes
selected in Mexico look like in terms of
herbarium specimens or images. Um what
we do have is what was characterized by
the Europeans in the middle of the 1500s
um shortly after the conquest of Mexico
and when when the tomato and other crops
were moved back to Europe and grown in
botanical gardens and characterized by
um
botonists. And what what we can see is
that there really was quite a bit of
morphological variety. You know,
tomatoes at this point were yellow, they
were red, they may have been purple,
they they were different shapes, they
were small, they were large. Um, it
seems like native Mexican farmers
probably selected and grew and preserved
a diversity of varieties with with with
different uh
morphologies. So, shortly after that,
the tomato began to spread outside of
botanical gardens and into local
cuisines and cultures across Europe,
starting in Spain and Italy and then
moving to other countries. And as this
new crop was integrated into new
cultures um we saw this radiation of
morphological diversity and development
of uh novel use types. So in Italy you
see the development of types that some
of you might be familiar with today like
the San Marzano paste tomato a type with
high soluble solids for processing into
sauces. In Spain, there was a
development of these um uh storage
tomatoes, these de penhar varieties that
traditionally were hung and stored for
the winter.
Um, and what's kind of interesting or uh
paradoxical is that despite all of this
morphological variation, genetic data
shows that actually these vintage or
traditional European land races of
tomato have a very narrow genetic basis.
uh much more narrow than the the wild
populations that that preceded
them. And it seems hard to believe, but
if if you um are familiar with some of
the effects of some of the mutations
that are used in tomato breeding, it
kind of starts to make sense. So, uh
this figure on the right here shows just
the effects of four different genes with
strong effects on tomato fruit shape
variation. And you can see how different
combinations of alals at these four
lossi result in this wide variation of
tomato shapes among modern market
classes of of tomato.
So thinking about genetic diversity in
tomatoes evolutionary history
um it appears that there were multiple
incidences of genetic bottlenecks
affecting the genetic diversity but also
a few cases where as a result of ad
mixture and crossing with wild relatives
the genetic diversity
increased. So first as pimpanellopolium
migrated to Mexico um there was a a
reduction in genetic diversity but then
as those populations moved back to South
America crossed with the wild population
the pipelium there was an increase in
genetic diversity after domestication in
Mexico to the large fruited domesticated
type that we're familiar with. there was
a further reduction in genetic diversity
that was made more extreme with the
bottleneck as those moved out of the
Americas and into Europe. But actually,
if you look at the genetic diversity in
modern varieties today, um there's
actually been an increase in genetic
diversity in modern tomato varieties,
which is, you know, kind of contradicts
something that a lot of us think when we
think about the results of of modern
plant
breeding. And the reason for that is
because um plantreeders have
intentionally introgressed
uh alals from wild species into modern
tomato varieties uh as sources of
important agonomic traits. So here I'm
showing the fogyny of tomato species
that I showed earlier. Those species
that I've circled here um have been used
to identify traits of interest, move
them into tomatoes, and those traits are
used commercially today in tomato
breeding. And it's not just the most
closely related relative to panelium.
It's some that are quite quite diverged
from domesticated tomato. The species
that I put an asterisk next to, there's
reports in the literature about um QTL
or genes being mapped and moved to
tomato, but I'm not sure if they're
they're used commercially or not.
So sequencing data shows that these wild
introgressions actually contribute
significantly to the genomes of modern
varieties. So if you look at these
images here, the the the light blue
represents hletypes from modern tomatoes
and these other colors show hletypes in
wild species and the traits that they're
associated with. So in some cases if you
look at chromosome 1 and you look at
these processing tomato hybrids here
denoted with P you can see that they're
small in progressions from selenium of
habricites that provide higher soluble
solids content associated with the AGPL1
gene. But if you look at chromosome six,
you can see among a variety of modern
varieties, both fresh market and
processing, you'll see that over half of
the chromosome seems to be represented
by these two different disease
resistance in regressions from selenium
chilenc and selenium peranum. And then
that's even more extreme on chromosome 9
with tomato where essentially all of the
fresh market hybrids that were sequenced
in the study um have a very large
introgression from senamanum conferring
resistance to tomato mosaic
virus. It's even more amazing to think
about this when you think about or see
in seed cataloges the extent of
introgressions that are present in
modern tomato varieties. So here's a
screenshot I took uh from the Harris
seed catalog. This is a tomato called
Maverick bred by um an an alumnist of
Cornell, Jason Cavort with earthwork
seed. And if you look at what I
highlighted in terms of its disease
resistance package, we can count one two
three four five six seven eight nine 10
11 resistance to 12 different disease
diseases or disease races. A few of
these might be represented by different
multiple genes and all of those are
independent integrations from wild
species that tomato breeders have have
used in
breeding. So before I go into the focus
of my lab and talk about a few examples
of how we're using genetic diversity in
tomato breeding, I thought it might be
useful to just give an overview of kind
of what the tomato industry looks like
in the United States and where the
tomatoes that we eat come from.
So in terms of acreage, the state with
the most significant acreage is
California with almost 300,000 acres of
tomato and this is predominantly um
processing tomatoes. So this is a very
highly specialized industry with
specialized varieties
um that are machine harvested and these
are processed into ketchup and tomato
sauces and all other products that that
we
eat. The state with the second highest
proport uh amount of tomato acreage is
Florida. There are about 30,000 acres of
tomato in Florida. Um historically
Florida is where um the tomatoes that we
were shipped across the country and
consumed in in the offseason when
tomatoes couldn't be grown elsewhere
were were produced. And historically the
way this happened was um these were
varieties that were picked when they
were uh what's called mature green. So
before they start turning red um off the
plant they were exposed to ethylene gas
to promote ripening and this way they
could maintain a very high level of
firmness and tolerate being shipped
around the country and that industry
still still continues
today. Increasingly though if you go to
the supermarket and look at tomatoes
that are there and look at the sticker
and see where they came from um you
might notice that a lot of them come
from Canada. Um, and these are varieties
coming from high-tech green houses. Um,
these green houses, there's a there's a
large number of them in in Ontario. Um,
also many in the northeast and
Midwestern United States. And this is
another very highly specialized
production system where uh these green
houses grow indeterminant or vining
types. They're plants that are grown for
for 10 or even more months. Um, by the
end of the season, these things are
dozens of feet long. And these are
producing, you know, high quality tomato
varieties that are sold often, you know,
retail in supermarkets in in
clamshells. Finally, the la the last
major kind of production zone I'll
mention is Mexico. We we import a lot of
tomatoes from Mexico. Um, unlike
Florida, these are typically harvested
viner ripe. Many of these varieties have
a gene that offers extended shelf life.
Um, so they have slow ripening and they
can tolerate being shipped um when
they're ripe and you'll see a lot of
these in the supermarket as
well. So the the I would say those are
the four major production regions and um
what I didn't mention was was New York
in the northeastern United States. Um
and that's that's obviously where we are
and that's where my work is based. So in
New York, we we have around 2,000 or
maybe a little, you know, a little bit
more acres of tomatoes grown in the open
field. There's probably similar acorage
in Pennsylvania and New England. Um so
compared to say Florida or California or
Mexico or high-tech green houses, the
total value of that seed market is is
more minor, right? So in terms of
private sector investment and breeding,
there's a uh you know fewer resources
devoted to breeding for for this region,
but it's still a significant amount of
acreage. And because farms on average in
the Northeast are smaller than many
other parts of the country, um
collectively, you know, this this is
representing thousands of individual
vegetable farms, uh for many of these
people, tomato might be a very
significant crop in terms of their
profit margins, and there's still many
needs that need to be addressed for this
area.
So, you know, what what are those
needs? Things that I would say would
would define tomato production where
where we are is, you know, we have a
pretty short growing season, May to
September. Uh we have warm, humid
summers that result in high fungal and
bacterial disease pressure. And those
diseases that we have in the Northeast
are um in many cases different than the
diseases that are of importance in the
Southeast. and in protected culture
environments. Um, in the Northeast, we
also have very high proximity to major
population centers. Um, people with very
high demand for for good quality
produce. And that results in farms
having a diversity of marketing
strategies, people selling wholesale and
people selling directly to consumers
through things like farmers markets and
community supported agriculture.
So in terms of my lab's research and
extension goals to to summarize it at a
really high level what we do is we try
to release cultivars and germ plasm
adapted to the northeastern United
States with high yield quality and
disease resistance. We discover the
genetic basis of traits of agonomic
or in many cases traits that are
important to the northeast but also to
other production regions. Another goal
we have is to model strategies for the
implementation of new technologies and
applied vegetable breeding. And then as
part of our extension mission, we we try
to generate and disseminate results on
variety performance in New York for our
stakeholders, which which are farmers,
gardeners, and members of the seed
industry. So I'm now going to get into
two different projects that we're
working on um leveraging genetic
diversity from tomatoes past at at kind
of different places in in its
evolutionary history. So for the first
project, we're accessing diversity that
diverged from tomato millions of years
ago. And this is from uh the species of
lambsidians where we're looking at
sources of abiotic stress
tolerance. And then you know instead of
millions of years ago, we're also
accessing diversity that diverged from
modern tomato maybe more like a hundred
years ago or 150 years ago. So this this
figure is definitely not to scale and
and that's quality that we're trying to
access from heirloom varieties for
modern tomato breeding.
So I'll talk a little bit first about
seleniums. Selenomsidians is a tomato
wild relative that grows in the Ottakama
desert of northern Chile. This the
Otakama desert is the most arid
non-polar desert on Earth. Um on average
it receives about half an inch of
rainfall a year and some weather
stations in the Otakama desert have
never recorded any precipitation as long
as they've been there. Um, but what's
remarkable is if you look at these
pretty desolate landscapes, there are
these wild tomatoes that are able to
grow there. So, it seems like pretty
remarkable source of of tolerance to
these very harsh
conditions. If if you look at the fogyny
that I showed earlier, you'll notice
that I didn't have a a circle around
seleniums.
That's because for a long time um
breeders weren't able to access genetic
diversity in salamsidians because of
reproductive barriers with like a
personum. You can't cross like a
persicum and salamsidians.
However, uh Roger Shadlay at the
University of California, Davis, um over
the course of many years, decades
actually, um completed a very complex
series of crosses using bridge species
in order to move genetic material from
cyians into like a persicum and
developed a population of introgression
lines. Uh these are 56 lines. Each of
them have a single introgression from
selenium cidians in the background of
domesticated fresh market tomato. Um
these inressions range in size but on
average they're about 20 megabases which
you know most of them probably have
several hundred genes. Um and this
population was developed and released
recently for um use by the tomato
breeding
community. So we were very interested in
this when I when I first started and we
still are. Um there are multiple traits
that you know we're interested in
looking at. One of them is salindy
stress.
Um and there's there's a there's a few
different reasons why. So cindy stress
can depress tomato yield in a few
different environments of commercial
relevance. So, in the central valley of
California, where, like I said earlier,
you know, there's almost 300,000 acres
of tomato, there are actually millions
of acres of crop land there that are
affected by pretty high groundwater
sali. Um, this this red area shows um
areas where the salia is so high that
there's a yield impact on
tomato. In New York, you know, we're a
much wetter climate. sal so soil
salinization is not really so much of an
issue. Um but actually in certain kind
of production systems it can be a
problem for farmers. So in in recent
years in the past maybe 10 20 years uh
the production of tomatoes in high
tunnels has really kind of exploded in
New York and and many other states. And
what happens when you put some sort of
covering over your plants and preclude
precipitation from from falling on the
soil is you prevent leeching of salts
that build up through application of
fertilizer and your irrigation water. Um
so this production system actually
results in in in creating something more
similar to like an arid climate as in as
in
California. This can be managed through
cultural practices. But still in recent
years we've seen you know many farmers
struggling with uh with high levels of
soluble salts in their high
tunnels. So there there have been
populations of salamsidians found
growing in in basically like salt basins
soils with an electric conductivity of
almost 100 desins per meter which is
around 40 times the level that tomato
can tolerate. Um the particular
accession that was used as the parent of
the inggression line population however
hasn't been characterized for its
salinity tolerance. So the first thing
that we wanted to do was verify that
it's tolerant to salt and also develop
some methods or protocols for evaluating
salinity tolerance. So this work has
been led by um our lab's uh field and
greenhouse manager Howard Rice who uh
has been very creative in designing the
irrigation systems that I'll be showing
and and leading these experiments.
In in the literature, there's many
different ways that salinity is
evaluated in tomato. Oftentimes, people
evaluate it um in terms of its impact on
vegetative biomass at the seedling
stage. We really wanted to look at fruit
yield, you know, the most like directly
relevant agonomic trait. Um so the way
that we did that was we grew plants with
drip irrigation and then in um with
these fertilizer injectors instead of
injecting just fertilizer into those
irrigation systems we injected table
salt as well at different concentrations
and grew the plants to maturity and
evaluated their yield. I'm just going to
pull my phone out to get a quick time
check. Okay, I think I'm good.
So in this first experiment we looked at
four different um genotypes of tomato
the two parents of this introgression
population. So this fresh market line
LA4354 theidians donor here we also as a
susceptible check we looked at a
processing tomato hybrid and as a
resistant check we looked at an
excession of selenopeli that's been
characterized by others for salinity
tolerance. Most of that work though has
been at the seedling level. Um in this
experiment we grew the plants under four
different treatments of fertilizer only
treatment and then three different
levels of um sodium chloride up to a
total electrical connectivity of 17.5
descendants per meter which is much
higher than what you would you know any
farmer would hope to find in their in
their soil.
So here I'm showing the effects on fruit
yield for the two tomato entries in this
experiment. Um if you look at the red
that's denoting the fresh market parent
of the integration line population. The
green is the processing tomato hybrid.
You can see on the left here pretty
steep decline in yield with increasing
salt
concentration. The under the highest
level of salt that we applied the yield
was maybe around 20% of what we saw
under the control. You can also see that
the most precipitous decline was from
the control to the first level of
salinity applied and after that it kind
of
plateaued. Um something that's
interesting that we haven't really
followed up on but um you know seemed to
be a curious result was although the
response with these two different
varieties was the same in their total
yield the way that that was realized was
different actually. So, Selenium uh the
the fresh market tomato variety showed a
decrease in fruit weight whereas the
processing tomato hybrid showed a
decrease in fruit number. Um but but
they that resulted in in the same
response in terms of total yield.
So for the two wild species we had in
this experiment, we we can't evaluate
their fruit yield because they devote a
really negligible portion of their
biomass to fruit. So the way that we
looked at this was we looked at their
vegetative
biomass. Um and the results of this were
kind of surprising to us. So if you look
at again at the at the domesticated
tomato genotypes in this experiment
represented in orange and green you can
see that there wasn't really a strong
response to celindia in terms of their
vegetative biomass. In fact under two of
the salt dosages the fresh market tomato
lime showed greater vegetative biomass
and under the control. Um the two
presumably resistant wild species
actually showed stronger declines in
vegetative biomass. Um if you look at
cyians which is this teal color here um
you can see the difference from the
control to the highest salt
concentration there. In terms of the
absolute difference it was fairly minor
but that's because salamines we found to
be a slow growing plant. There wasn't
really much biomass to to to decrease.
Um but as a relative difference actually
it had the steepest decline of all four
of the entries in this experiment. Um so
that that was kind of like a
disappointing result, right? You don't
want the the donor of the trait that
you're hoping to introgress to show a
poorer response than than the uh than
the pair you're hoping to introgress it
into. But after thinking about a little
bit more, you know, maybe we decided
maybe it's comparing apples to oranges,
right? We're comparing these species who
don't produce any fruit. They don't
devote any energy to fruit production
and comparing their vegetative biomass
to tomato varieties that do devote a lot
of energy to fruit production and we saw
that that fruit production was affected.
So we we move forward with screening the
integration lines thinking that uh maybe
in the background of domesticated tomato
we'd be able to see more of the effects
of the salamidians
genome. So we started by looking at 27
inression lines. Um not all of the
complete set um was available for
dissemination when we started this
experiment. We also avoided lines
carrying introgressions in a
hetererozygous condition. These are
introgressions where there's um a
recessive lethal mutation in the
background of domesticated tomato. And
to make our lives easier, we just
avoided working with
those. We evaluated these under both
control conditions and a fertilizer
treatment with about 75 uh millar um
sodium chloride. We completed the first
replicate of this um last fall and the
second replicate is is we're hoping to
wrap up in the next month or
so. And here, you know, as as opposed to
looking at the wild species itself, here
we were able to see an effect of
salinity tolerance when you look at at
the um gene effects in the background of
domesticated tomato. So in this plot
here on the left I'm showing the
distribution of fruit yield under the
control. On the right is the
salt treatment. There's lines connecting
the performance of individual genotypes
between those two treatments. The red
line is is the domesticated parent
recurrent parent of the population and
the black lines are all introgression
lines.
Um, we saw unsurprisingly that the
domesticated parent did pretty well for
yield. Under control conditions, it
ranked fifth, but under saline
conditions, it ranked 17th in terms of
its yield. And then in terms of the
severity of its percent decline in
yield, um, it ranked third. So out of
out of all the entries, um, it showed
the third steepest response in terms of
its its difference uh, in in sailing
versus control conditions.
The introgression lines ranged from a
response of about a decline similar to
the domesticated parent around 80%. Uh
and the best integration lines showed a
decline in yield around
45%. Um we also saw there were four
integration lines that out outy yielded
the domesticated parent under both
control and salt
conditions. So what what are our
immediate takeaways from this
experiment? Well, for one thing, you
know, by the fact that almost all the
introgression lines did better than the
recurrent parent, it seems like there
are multiple genes distributed across
the genome that provide partial effects
individually on salt tolerance. My
background is is in disease resistance
breeding and pathology, right? Where um
we can identify single genes, R genes
with major effects. And um I probably
should have done my homework and read
some more about plant physiology. This
this might not have been such a
surprising uh find in terms of abiotic
stress
resistance. So this leads to the
question are these genes
um do they have effects that are large
enough to be commercially relevant?
Right? We can look at the lines that did
the best. Right? They had a 45% decline
in yield compared to an 80% for the
domesticated tomato. And you you can
look at that two ways, right? One is 45%
is much better than 80%. But also a 45%
decline in yield is still a 45% decline
in yield, right? Is that is that enough
to to be relevant
commercially? So we need to do further
experiments to figure that out. One
thing that we're interested in doing is
combining different integrations that
each had pretty, you know, good effects
individually and seeing what they look
like in combination. We're currently
doing a crossing block to to try to
answer that. And then another question
that we need to answer is um can we
reduce the sizes of these introgressions
enough to get rid of linkage drag while
retain the effects on salt tolerance. Um
so there's a lot of work to do, but
we're excited about this project. Um I
mean just just looking at the fruit
yields from
um the control on the left to salt on
the right. Um except the the patterns
actually reversed this lower picture. I
don't want to mislead anybody.
um you can see the the variation in
response along these lines and visually
it's it's pretty observable the impact
that that these integrations
have. We're also moving on to look at
other traits that we're interested in.
Um one of these is freezing tolerance.
Um the accession of slamsidians that was
used as the parent of this population um
was characterized and discovered growing
at really high elevations where the
temperature goes below 0 degrees. Um
Pablo Benort is an intern in my lab
who's leading this work and we've been
really excited to see that when you
throw tomatoes in a growth chamber at
pretty cold temperatures um they come
out looking like this but when you throw
salamidians in there it comes out
looking like that. Um, it seems like
maybe a more far-fetched uh project than
even the the the salinity tolerance
project, but what we hope is that we can
develop tomato varieties that have
freezing tolerance as seedlings. farmers
can transplant them to their fields
maybe a few weeks earlier than they
typically would um get season extension,
maybe harvest tomatoes earlier in the
season when prices are are are prefer
are are better um and not have to worry
about late spring frosts. So Pablo just
this week I think wrapped up screening
the rest of the integration line
population. So if you're interested in
the results of this project, come talk
to him during this uh event today.
Okay. So I want to move on and talk
about another project that we're doing
uh focused on using heirloom tomato
varieties in breeding. Um so I I want to
give a little bit of a historical
perspective.
So in terms of modern tomato breeding,
so breeding trends in the 20th century,
um what those trends reflect are kind of
larger ongoing trends in society at the
time, right? um industrialization of
agriculture, the commodification of
produce, and that's reflected in the
traits that breeders were selecting on
things like
uniformity, firmness, fruit firmness,
and chipability, fruit size, shape, and
color, disease resistance, yield. Um, I
don't have on their flavor. It probably
was not a major trait under selection
for for a lot of this modern tomato
breeding.
Towards the end of of the 20th century,
so starting maybe in the late 1980s or
1990s,
um the heirloom tomato started kind of
growing in in popularity. If you look at
this figure on the left, this is showing
the mentions of of the term heirloom
tomato in two newspapers from 1989 to
2005. And you can see that, you know, it
at one point it was something that
didn't really exist in our popular
consciousness. and within a few decades
became something that was common to talk
about. Um, and that was the result of
maybe a few different larger movements
or trends happening in society that kind
of represented maybe a push back against
some of the industrialization of
agriculture that was happening at the
time. So, the seeds exchange was
established in 1975. That's a network of
individuals interested in preserving
seed that maybe was handed down to them
in their family or or uh in their
community. um saving those varieties and
distributing them among a network of
other seed
savers. Chefs like Alice Waters um
opened restaurants that were the first
to champion what we now refer to as
farm-totable cooking. They included
items on their menus like heirloom
tomatoes. And you know, pretty soon
heirloom tomatoes became ubiquitous at
farmers markets, upscale restaurants,
and today they're pretty common to find
in grocery stores at Wegmans here in
Ithaca. I can see them uh all year round
uh grown in in green houses in in
Canada. So what what what exactly is an
heirloom tomato? And the the answer is
you know we we don't really know. There
there's there's no scientific definition
for this term heirloom tomato. But there
are a few different definitions that are
thrown um around you know uh more
popularly. So here here are some of the
most common ones. They must be open
pollinated. They must have been
introduced more than 50 years ago.
That's kind of an arbitrary cutoff, but
you know what it means is that these
aren't the results of modern breeding,
right? These are uh heritage varieties
that that were selected in a previous
time. And then according to this book,
Taylor's Guide to Heirloom vegetables,
they must have a history of their own.
Um, and many of these varieties are
accompanied by stories like familiar
lore about where these came from, who
originally selected them, how many
generations they were passed down, um,
that make them kind of more more
interesting.
I think if you do ask most people what
an heirloom tomato is, uh maybe I'll,
you know, I'll pull all of you later. I
think they probably wouldn't refer to to
these things. Instead, they'd probably
be thinking of um visual traits, right?
Things that differentiate them from
round red tomatoes, differences in size,
shape, and color. maybe some defects
that have been selected against defects,
you know, depending on uh who who who's
deciding what a defect is. Things like
green shoulders or scarring on the
blossom end of the fruit that are all
associated with these
varieties. So the these are these are a
few of my personal favorite heirloom
varieties. These are also ones that are
among the most popular and most
wellknown. um Cherokee purple, uh brandy
wine, both pink brandy wine and yellow
brandy wine, striped German.
Um if you've grown these in in your
garden, maybe you'll agree with me that
these are very delicious varieties of
tomatoes. They're they're beautiful. Um
and their quality in terms of eating
them fresh in a salad is really
excellent. So I think you know part of
the popularity of heirloom tomatoes is
not only for their cultural associations
and and you know their repres what they
mean in terms of um self-sufficiency and
seed saving and a push back against
industrialization of agriculture but
also for their value in and of
themselves as as really excellent um
varieties.
So, in recent years, there's been kind
of a movement with some seed companies
to develop varieties combining some of
these qualities found in heirloom
tomatoes with traits more typical of
modern hybrids. So, things like disease
resistance, resistance to cracking, high
yield potential. This is a screenshot
from high mowing seed catalog. And one
of the terms that some of these
companies um is using is is high looms.
A combination of hybrid and heirlooms.
Uh we like that term a lot and that's a
term that we're using in our lab to
describe the the breeding efforts that
that we are
using. One thing that we started doing
in the lab was uh variety trials of
commercial high varieties. Here you you
can see uh the harvest from these
varieties uh in bins in preparation for
a field day we had last summer. You can
see the variation in in color, how
beautiful some of these varieties are.
In terms of the data that we collected,
we also saw that there have been, you
know, pretty significant improvements in
terms of many agonomic traits. So this
plot on the right is showing these
varieties in terms of their percent
grade one fruit. So the proportion of
fruit that can be marketed as USDA grade
one, meaning free of blemishes and other
defects. If you look at Brandy Wine
Pink, which is our heirloom check, the
percent grade one was about 25%. Which,
you know, if you think about that from a
commercial agriculture perspective,
that's that's pretty pretty pretty bad.
If a farmer has to uh discount or throw
away 75% of the harvest, but these
Highland varieties, you know, get get up
to uh 70 70%. So pretty big improvement.
We also trial just normal standard
slicer tomatoes. Uh we found in our
trials that the percent grade one on
those can get up to say like 95%. So
there's there's still probably our
trade-offs in terms of things like
resistance to fruit defects,
shipability, and traits relating to
eating quality, softness, texture, uh
thickness of fruit skin, etc.
So, another thing that we did when I
first started in in um 2023 was um
surveyed growers in New York about their
perceptions of both heirloom and highle
tomatoes. Uh this was in collaboration
with Teresa Rousnik um vegetable
specialist with Cornell Cooperative
Extension. And out of the 76 tomato
growers in New York who responded to our
questionnaire, uh we found that about
threequarters of them grew heirloom
varieties as a portion of their
production. So that kind of speaks to
the demand that that that's that's um
grown for for for this type of product.
Uh fewer grew high varieties. About 44%
grew high varieties. And when we asked
what the challenges that they found
associated with heirlooms, uh there were
things that we weren't surprised by. you
know disease susceptibility,
susceptibility to fruit defects and poor
storeability or shipability. Uh what I
found more interesting was when we asked
what are your desired attributes in
terms of future highland varieties. And
when they ranked these the top four were
number one uh resistance to diseases
common of the open field, number two
resistance to fruit defects, three
determinant growth habit and four uh
resistance to diseases more common in
the high tunnel. And the reason that
this is interesting to me is that most
of the seed companies currently are
breeding types that are indeterminate
and maybe more adapted to the high
tunnel or the greenhouse in terms of uh
their disease resistance package. So it
seemed like there were some needs that
that still um may be left um needing to
be
addressed. So we we started um crossing
modern varieties with with heirloom
varieties in 2023. Um, in terms of the
modern lines that we're using as
parents, we're we're making uh use of
lines developed at Cornell by my
predecessor Martha Mutler, who developed
lines with a really comprehensive
disease resistance package to diseases
uh of the in the open field in the
northeast. Um, including several novel
disease resistance genes and QTL that
her lab discovered. Um, and then we we
crossed these a few of these lines with
a number of heirloom varieties. I have
four listed here. These are the
populations that we carry forward in the
in the schema that I'll show you in a
few slides, but we made crosses with
with many more. And the objective of
this work is to develop attractive crack
resistant um high flavor lines with
strong open field disease resistance and
determinant
growth. We've been following a pretty
aggressive timeline to move this project
forward. So in the winter 2023 2024 we
we carried out two generations. We did
the crossing block. We did the F1
generation in the greenhouse. The F2 in
in in the field last year we we used
marker assisted selection to enrich
those seedlings for the disease
resistance alals for especially for the
diseases that were we were most
interested in. We then made visual
selections in the field for uh fruit
quality traits and for determinant
growth habit. So that's a determinant
growth habit is a concentrated flowering
type that sets flowers in a short window
and then kind of stops growing. Um the
selections from that field here a
picture of a couple that we're really
excited about. If we continue to see
fruit like this, we'll we'll be we'll be
very pleased. Um and we sent those to uh
Winter Nursery in Costa Rica for single
seed descent. So the F4
generation and this year we we plan to
get back around 320 F4 families from
this work. Um these are derived from 10
crosses. These 320 families not all of
them are part of this high breeding
project. Right. We also have crosses
that are I guess you would say modern
standard varieties by modern standard
varieties but six of them are from
heirloom by modern crosses. And one
thing that we're excited to do with this
population is use it as kind of a test
case for how we might be able to
implement genomic selection in our
tomato program. So this work is being
led by Jack Frizzio who's a postto in
the lab. And the specific strategy that
we're planning to use is what people
call a test and shelf strategy. Um, for
us, one of the biggest opportunities
that genomic selection poses to a
vegetable breeder is the opportunity to
have our phen phenotypic data stretched
further. Collecting data like yield or
fruit quality on a perishable crop that
has to be picked multiple times is
really labor intensive. It's very
difficult for us to do that on a large
number of entries. But if we can do it
on a certain number of entries, then
predict into a larger number, um, we
think that can have pretty big impact on
our breeding program.
So this year out of these 320 we're
going to put 80% of them in the field.
Um genotype those phenotype them as well
and then we're going to predict on the
entire population including the 20% that
were only genotyping and not
phenotyping. So here's a kind of a quick
schematic of of what that that would
look like. Um so those 80% will be used
to calculate genomic estimated breeding
values including on the hold out set. So
among that entire population of 320
we'll select the top 10% across the
entire population. We'll carry these
lines forward for further product
development you know further testing and
breeding maybe creating some test
hybrids. And then we'll also interate
intermate those um complete another
cycle of modified single seed descent.
And then we think that as we continue to
do this and generate more historical
data, we can change the proportions,
right? So maybe in two years when we
have another population of F4 lines,
instead of phenotyping 80%, maybe we can
phenype just 20%. We can include a
larger population and we can use some of
the historical data as well to make
predictions. There there are lots of
questions to answer on the practical
implementation of genomic selection. um
not just in my program but I think
personally in vegetables in general
there's there's literature answering
these questions in many agonomic crops
that haven't been addressed really in
many vegetables um so for us you know
we're really interested in how well can
we predict within families across
families across market classes are these
high crosses going to be predictive of
standard tomato by standard tomato
crosses how many markers do we need is
is a thousand enough a thousand is kind
of the number that that is financially
reasonable for us. So, we're we're we're
hoping that's
enough. What training population sizes
are needed to achieve reasonable
prediction accuracies? Right? Like I
said, it's a lot of work to collect this
training data. How much do we really
need to collect in order for this
strategy to to work? And then tomato is
a crop that's primarily marketed as F1
hybrids. um even if the inburning
depression is is is not as strong as in
a crop like corn, we're going to be
predicting the p per se value of these
lines. Is that the right strategy?
Should we instead be predicting general
combining abilities or specific
combining abilities? These are things
that we're hoping to to figure
out. So, I'm going to start wrapping up
my my presentation. Um I think you know
one thing that's kind of in uh in common
across these two projects that I
described is the fact that these traits
that we're interested in are are
quantitative traits. So the the history
of tomato breeding um there's been uh
tremendous progress in trait improvement
focusing on moving qualitative major
effect genes from wild relatives. in
terms of using similar approaches to
improve quantitative traits, it's
probably going to be a bigger challenge.
Um the way that we're doing that with
these high loom breeding uh
populations, um we think genomic
selection might help, right? Um we we're
using breeding methods that we think are
suitable for the improvement of
quantitative traits. We don't expect
necessarily to find amazing varieties in
that first cycle. We might need a few
generations of re combination to break
up linkages between um uh
alals. But we think that using this
approach we can we can develop high
quality lines. In terms of the work
we're doing with salamsidians where we
found that there are multiple genes
conferring resistance to the uh stress
tolerance that we're interested
in. the linkage drag is is probably so
extreme that you know there's only a
certain limitation in terms of how many
of the integrations we can practically
use in commercial breeding right maybe
there's a world in which we can use two
of them or even three of them uh if
we're able to reduce the size of those
integrations sufficiently but beyond
that it's probably um not feasible from
a practical point of view um so I think
you know there we probably need creative
solutions moving forward um I don't know
exactly what those are maybe I'll be
inspired by the rest of the talks today.
Um, you know, maybe there's a world in
which we can use these genetic
resources, these populations that have
been developed, the phenotyping
platforms that we're using to identify
the genetic basis of these traits, and
then perhaps instead of actually
introgressing them into tomato, we can
just make the edits in tomato through
genome editing um corresponding to those
genetic differences that lead to the
phenotypic
change. So, with that, I'll I'll wrap
up. Um I I talked about the work that
some of my lab members are doing. I
didn't have the chance to talk about the
work that my students Ivana Castillo and
Diana Moulder are doing. They're doing
really exciting projects in disease
resistance genetics in tomato and
eggplant. Um, I also want to thank the
work from former lab members who have
contributed especially to a lot of the
field work that we've done and then um
the funding sources that we've had for
the projects that I've described
including the California tomato research
institute who's funding some of the work
with seleniums and salt tolerance um
USDA federal capacity funds Cornell and
the vegetable breeding institute. So, if
we have time for any questions, I'll I'd
love to answer them and I also al also
be around the the rest of the day and I
look forward to talking with some of you
then. Thank you.
Yes. More about your process for voting
in on your breeding goals and focus for
this program.
Sure. That's a that's a that's a very
good
question. So, the question was, you
know, how what what the process was for
honing in on our our breeding branch.
Um, I think it's through it was through
a combination of things and I mean
there, you know, we're still working on
on them.
Um, the for me the most important thing
is to be out there and talk to people.
Um, learn what problems are, learn what
should needs to be addressed, learn what
solutions already are out there and
don't need to be reinvented from
scratch.
So, you know, my first year, um,
especially my first summer in my
position, I tried every week to to
visit, um, at least one different farm,
right? Travel to different parts of of
the state. Um, got in touch with
extension specialists in those regions,
got introduced to vegetable growers in
those areas. Uh, just learned about what
they did, asked what varieties they
liked, why they liked them. If, you
know, if you could have your ideal
variety, what would it look like? Um,
and you know, those conversations really
helped contribute to to a lot of the
work that we're doing and how we're
moving forward.
Uh, yes.
Hey, thank you. Really cool to see all
the work that you've been doing and I I
love this idea of highs. My question is,
so you're looking at a lot of the
agonomic traits, but I'm assuming a lot
of the motivation of using the heirlooms
is to introduce some of those more, you
know, unique flavor and taste profiles,
but that's of course a really hard thing
to quantify. Do you have any plans to
incorporate that into your selection?
That that's a really excellent question.
The question was, how do we plan to
select for flavor in this high program?
Um, and you're right that it's really
tough to select for flavor. In our early
generation nurseries, we we walk through
and we do a lot of tasting, but we get
very sick of tomatoes very quickly. And
I'm someone who loves tomatoes. I never
thought that would happen to me. Um, so
to to start, we're looking at some
things that are relatively easy to
quantify. Bricks,
acidity. Um, we're going to do some
taste testing, too. Not formally, but
informally, and see how well those
traits are associated with our informal
assessments of flavor. Um, and we're
going to go from there. I mean, tomato
flavor has been there's been a lot of
literature on what what controls our
perceptions of tomato flavor. And it's a
mixture
of sweetness, acidity, and then lots of
different volatile compounds. And
measuring those is obviously a lot more
work. So, we're we need to see um how we
can balance our resources and do that
efficiently moving
forward. Uh yes, Lance, I got two
questions. It it always strikes me that
we we've taken this perennial shrub and
we kind of impose this annual lifestyle
onto it, especially for the wild
relatives. Are we evaluating the the
traits of these things too early in that
first season? and and if we gave were
able to give them time to establish, do
you think they would be more resistant
to some of the stressors? The second
question is given those those big
integrations and how divergent like
citians is, Roger probably couldn't
break those those integressions up with
with crossover and stuff. So, how do you
plan to go about breaking these things
down?
Okay. Yeah, thanks. Those are those are
good questions. Yeah. So I think I think
the first question was you know how do
we evaluate phenotypes and camcidiums
when it's probably a perennial and its
growth habit is so different and I think
the answer is we didn't we probably
didn't really do a good job of of doing
that. We we grew it in you know almost
hydroponically in a greenhouse the way
we grow normal tomatoes. This is a thing
that's adapted to the desert, right? um
we we put in a very different kind of
artificial condition and probably not
the best way to assess the traits that
we were interested in assessing. Um
however, when you look at the effects of
portions of the genome of slam obsidians
in the background of domesticated
tomato, I think it's much more it's much
easier to kind of isolate and evaluate
those traits. And your second question
was how do we plan to break um apart
those recombinations? and and we don't
know how easy or difficult it's going to
be, right? The the the way that we are
planning to do it now is to just try it
and see what happens. Um maybe that's
magical thinking, but I guess I guess
the only way to to find out is by doing
it.
Uh yes. Uh thank you Greg for that great
talk. Um, I was just wondering, you
mentioned that heirloom varieties have
been maintained by seeds savers and that
kind of came out of a response to modern
agriculture, modern breeding. So, how do
they feel about highs? Is there
acceptance within the existing heirloom
community? Are they excited about
disease resist resistance or are they
kind of not liking this? That's a really
good question. Uh the question was you
know people who are really attracted to
heirloom varieties for for various
reasons how do they feel about hybrid
versions of those heirlooms and I think
there's a diversity of opinions um I
think people who are interested in
heirlooms primarily because of their
flavor and appearance um are are open to
to new varieties even if if they're
hybrids. There are other people who have
political opinions on on um F1 hybrids
and the control of seed um intellectual
property protection. Um those people
probably aren't as thrilled about the
development of of hybrid varieties.
Um but you know these these heirloom
varieties for the point of it only get
them by you know writing a letter to
somebody else who saved them. You know
that that was that was a long time ago.
These these varieties seed of them are
sold by all sorts of major seed
companies and and grown um commercially.
Now
that's all the time. So please
awesome. Okay. So I have the honor of
being I think the side of this symposium
that's more about conservation which you
might see or uh you might remember is in
the title itself conserving and
utilizing. So it feels like an honor and
also um a responsibility to bring the
other half of the equation to what seems
like a really strong and wonderful
community um mainly of plantreeders uh
genetics folks and such. And so a great
community to for me to connect with and
to um speak with. Thank you for the
invite to the the graduate student
organizers and to Cornell and to
Corteva. Really appreciate it and I do
not take for granted opportunities to
get together and collaborate um
especially in this day and age. And so
thank you.
Um my goal I think above all else with
this talk is to
um engage you enroll you even in how
important that side the conservation
side is to your work. And so let's see
how I do about that. This is a real
photo by the way not just a screen
saver. This is from the Great Sand Dunes
National Park in Colorado. And that's a
wild relative that I'll talk a little
bit about a little bit
later. Yeah. Yeah. So, I'm going to be
talking about things like this flower on
the left side and its relation to the
flower on the right side and
um how those two are still related after
so many millions of
years. I just as a reflection um when I
started in this work like 25 years ago,
I do feel like we were all the weirdos
that they didn't know what to do with at
the tri society's meetings. um we had
sort of our own little group that nobody
came to, you know, there's four people
in the audience and all of that thing.
That was the crop wild relative people.
And I it's not I mean it's not that the
plantreeders weren't using the wild
relatives. They certainly were and all
of that, but it was much lower on the
awareness screen there I think at the
societies and and also in the
conservation world. And that's not true
any longer. there has been this huge
sort of shift as I've seen it into
public awareness like all of these
articles around wild foods or wild
relatives or genetic resources even
terms like that that you never thought
might end up in the news and um you
might have seen that the world food
prize this year was given
to conservationists including of wild
relatives of crops and all kinds of
crazy things are happening in the world
with uh wild relatives and that's true
not just of uh public awareness. But
even in our very largest global or
international accords and agreements,
for instance, the sustainable
development goals and the new agreements
and the older agreements of the
convention on biological diversity.
These are really our largest
international instruments of countries
agreeing with each other about
biodiversity, about food and
agriculture. and they're all saying
things like wild species and wild
relatives in them, which is wild in and
of itself. That actually was not an
intentional
um so I have a couple of slides that are
a little bit simple for you all um in
this group, but I will put a few
definitions out and and a little bit of
the history. For me, I keep it really
simple. Wild relatives are wild plants
that are related to our domesticated
crops. As you saw from the tomato group
um and from the brassasica talk and
others, the exact definition or which
plants are in and which plants are out
for each crop varies um a lot. And the
wheat one, the wheat talk coming up
after me is um is another example of a
different way of defining the edges of
the wild relatives.
The the theory behind this goes back 50
years or 53 years now
um to to some science that was really
based mostly on crossing on on breeding
studies and seeing what could cross with
one another and the coming up with this
kind of onion concept of the center
being the crop and it's related spec
same species that's wild and then as you
go out from the onion it gets less
related and more difficult to cross. Uh
these days those boundaries have really
fallen through modern tech and so you
can um you can double chromosomes easier
and you can do these bridges with other
species as mentioned in Nebraska and all
these things. And so the edges of the
gene pool two and three and out from
there are getting fuzzier over time. If
you're interested in the the picture of
like who is a wild relative for what
crops you're interested in, there is a
wonderful database, probably the only
like truly global database run by USDA
Grin Global Taxonomy with the link
there. I hope these presentations um are
available to everyone after this. Uh I'm
happy to make mine, but there's a lot of
links in this presentation. If useful to
you, you can go there and you can put in
your crop of interest and it will start
to tell you based on literature who are
the wild species and what have they been
used for that has been published.
Um there's been a couple of reviews of
of the uses of wild relatives over the
last uh 50 years or 100 years in this
case and essentially the trends are
there's more and more publications folks
saying that they're using wild relatives
and again this is not the private sector
so much. This is this is what's being
published. And so it's even higher the
number of uses of course when you get
into the privates. And then as as you
might have seen already from the from
the talks we've had the major major uses
so far are primarily pest and disease
resistance also abiotic stress uh
tolerance and then many other things.
Um two final points as we just get into
it about wild relatives that I like to
make. Again, you all as a very educated
crowd um will not be surprised by this,
but the the complexities of their use
are wondrous and and it's there is of
course still just bringing
in single genes for important traits
like pest resistance, but then there
there's there's much more I'm not saying
any better or worse, but much more
complex versions like grape. And so what
grape is for those who don't know and I
know this is a big crop in in New York.
Um grape has a top the scion that can be
different than the bottom the root
stock. That top scion is still mostly in
most places in the world one species the
domesticated species venifera but that
is um that is not the only species
that's out there. And in fact there's
more and more coming along of hybrids
with venifa and other things. And there
is a case, this is a rather extreme case
of um of this chambers which is we don't
actually even know all the different
species in it, but you can see the list
of of six or actually seven different
species actually in this hybrid that's
that's u that's grown on the east coast
here. And then the rootstock there is
now um almost by standard or by
definition one of three or four
different wild species from North
America. That's how grapes are really
able to grow around the world for the
most part. And so this is the landscape
really of wild relatives and of how much
they're used. They're they're really
really integrated into some of our most
major crops. And I had to put this
picture up here um for several reasons.
One uh one is because this is a Cornell
work seinal work from 25 years ago that
was one of these papers that really did
start to raise the awareness and change
maybe people's minds uh even breeders
minds about using wild relatives. And um
so Dr. Makuch who's
um maybe listening in online. Uh
uh this is a kind of a synthesis paper
and it was making a several points and
one is that you don't always know what's
in these plants which is the wonder and
also the challenge of them. And so the
photo here that the A was the wild
relative um which was spoken about by
our first speaker here. What a wonderful
presentation. Thank you. I learned so
much. the B on the the the left side
there, that was the domesticated version
before the integration. The the right
side of that is actually after the cross
with this green tomato. Um you get a
darker red version of the of the tomato.
So that darker um trait came actually
from the wild green relative. And then
on the bottom side on the sea, this is a
smaller one. This is I believe
pimpanellopolium crossing with that
medium-sized tomato to get even a larger
tomato through you know kind of um
through that vigor effect and so you
don't always know what you're going to
get.
Um okay so the talk that I am going to
give today also as much as it's about
plants and about genes and conservation
it's really also about
people conservation really can't happen
by by an individual or an institution.
It's a it's a
collaborative effort. Um the bigger and
more collaborative it is the more it
works. Relationships matter to
conservation tremendously. And so there
was a big first step 15 years ago
through a mega global project called the
crop relatives project that was 50
million uh euros through um the
government of Norway and that enabled
giant steps forward in trying to
understand who are the wild relatives of
our major crops uh how well are they
conserved in seed banks or gene banks
around the world I'll talk a little bit
more about that in a minute and then um
to start to do more pre-breeding around
those this was an important project for
me because I got to do my PhD as part of
it and so I'm very thankful for that and
um and I think it it's still having its
major effects around the world many
institutions including Cornell were part
of this project
um a little bit as part of that project
on the far right side one of my chapters
of my PhD uh was starting to just try to
understand who are these resources in
different countries and so we published
an inventory for the United States of of
what what is this diversity? And I'm I'm
going to be talking mainly about North
America in this uh presentation. So I
wanted to list that Mexico came along
with their version also in crop science
a couple years later and then the
Canadians a couple years later. And so
we have wonderful now resources to just
understand lists basically of all these
species. And this is not it. There's
probably 15 or 20 other countries that
have now published national inventories
for their wild relatives. And so that's
a really neat baseline of um of
understanding what's out there. And so
to give you a short idea of of who's out
there, um we have this pie chart that
gives you a little sense
of big the pie how big the slice is that
are related to these major crops. And
this is the narrowed down like most
prioritized set of species that we
prioritize basically based on how
important the crop is. And so we've got
a lot of blackberry and blueberry
relatives and grapes and pecans and
peaches and plums and sunflowers and and
other things there. And so um I would
like to talk actually for a minute about
why we have diversity of crops in North
America, which I'm just going to talk
about the United States and Canada when
not that many crops were domesticated in
this area.
So, this is a map I worked on a while
back that it's certainly not every crop
in the world, but it's most of the crops
that we eat. It's about 80 or 100 crops
and let's just call it where they where
they came from, if you allow me that. I
know you're a very educated crowd, but
where where more or less they arose the
region part of the world and where their
where their genetic diversity is is
richest and where their wild relatives
tend to be richest. And you can see a
few things here. One is that plants were
domesticated in many parts of the world.
So were animals, not just one place. I
believe I was taught in high school, I'm
still angry about this, that uh that
that agriculture arose in the fertile
crescent and that was the whole
story. It's not the whole story.
Um uh
so actually many dozens or even hundreds
of places crops were domesticated by
hundreds or thousands of cultures. And
uh that's typically understood to be
maybe 28 to 32 kind of very rich centers
where a lot of innovation was going on
typically 4,000 to 12,000 years ago. You
can also see that North America is not
the biggest list. It's it's it's it's
kind of a smaller list. This is again
not the whole list of crops, but there's
blueberries there and um those currants
or rybees, grapes, some pumpkins,
sunflowers, strawberries, pecans, some
other things. So um I have four reasons
I'm going to try to argue for with you
of why we actually have this giant
inventory of 5,000 species that are
related to crops here in North America.
And the first one is because we do have
these native domesticates. That is
people that were here in this part of
the world were checking out the wild
plants and realized that some of them
were really awesome and started growing
them and domesticating them and they got
bigger and more useful and more edible
and and um and their wild relatives are
are still here. So that's number one. We
got that. Number two is that there is a
very rich diversity of crops that were
domesticated south of here. Meso America
and further south. That's corn and other
types of squash and chili peppers and
potatoes and tomatoes and and many other
things. And they have wild
relatives, cousins, northern cousins,
ones that live up here in more temperate
regions, but are related to those crops
to the south. And so, um, for instance,
typicum, which is a wild relative of
mae, and there's a a researcher of that
here, Dr. Denise Costich in the crowd.
And so that's a kind of let's call it a
there's versions that are more temperate
of maze that are up here. That's number
two. Uh number three is that as a
temperate region we also have cousins or
wild relatives that are cousins to crops
that were domesticated in other
temperate regions of the world in Europe
and in East Asia. And uh so there's a
lot of wild plums and apricots and
almonds and things like that that were
the domesticates were domesticated
elsewhere but the relatives are also
here. Um, and number four is that we
have weeds, invasives that come from
other places, and those are problematic
as weeds. Things like in in the west
where I'm from, wild oats or um or wild
beets, wild lettuce, but they are also
genetic resources and they are also crop
wild relatives and they can be used for
breeding as well. So those are the four
reasons, my major four reasons why this
is actually a very rich part of the
world even though other parts of the
world are just as rich in this
incredible flora that is useful for
people through plant breeding and um as
we'll talk about at the end of this
presentation for for other reasons
too. So um we have been using wild
relatives for a long time that are
native to this region. This is just four
examples of of real uses of our native
resources in wild relatives in in
sunflowers and in um in filberts or
hazelnuts in maze and in um uh walnut.
The other side of the story and and my
contractual obligation as a
conservationist to start really into
this conservation uh story here is that
unfortunately a lot of those species are
threatened or endangered and and these
are all four of these are listed under
endangered species act. Many of the
species are not listed but these are
lucky enough I suppose you could call it
to be uh to be listed and regulated
there. And so what do we do about these
species that are useful to us, that are
wild, that are threatened?
Um, one of the things that we do is we
put them in seed banks or, uh, gan banks
as we we like to call them. And, uh,
this is a picture from the National
Laboratory in Fort Collins located in
Colorado State University. It's a USDA
facility. uh the full term is national
laboratory for genetic resources
preservation. This is the national
backup repository for the United States
system and uh our previous speaker who
spoke about the use of the brassasica
collection from USDA. This would be
where the long-term collection that's
kept for decades or hundreds of years is
kept to make sure that it stays alive
and is around and um and can be
replenished out into the more active
sites. The active sites I'd like to talk
about this system just for a minute if
you will. The active sites in the USDA
system are all across the United States.
And that's that that makes sense because
crops grow different crops grow in
different parts of the United States and
and the desire is to to have these
active sites really working in in the
right ecologies. Um that system is the
largest probably national system in the
world in terms of how active it it is in
doing um doing the research to keep the
seeds alive but also developing useful
information like what color and what
size and all of that basic phenotyping
work and then distributing seeds to
plantreeders. And so what I really want
to make sure is understood is that this
is a this is one national system.
There's there's many around the world
which I'll get to in a minute. But that
national system which is supported by
the public then is one of the major
foundations for plant breeding through
universities through private industry
that then become the seeds that go out
to farmers around the world. And without
that system um it would be a much more
fragile or unstable system going forward
in terms of the future of new varieties
and food. And so um we even have backups
of backups. This is probably the most
famous seed bankank or team bank around
the world global seed vault which is um
which is our tertiary backup here in the
United States. that is we put seeds uh
we have our active sites and then we put
them in Colorado and then we also put
them in Spalbard which is a Norwegian
territory. For other countries they
don't have that Colorado version and so
their backup is at Spalbard. This is
like a safety deposit box. Um you don't
pay for it as a country but you put your
seats up there and nobody else has
access to them except you so you can get
them back when you need them.
This is a picture of all the gene banks
around the world more or less and the
size of the circle is the size of the
collections just in terms of number of
what are called excessions there. These
are both national seed banks or gene
banks but also international ones which
are held in trust kind of for the global
community not just for a country. Um but
I want to mention even with the national
ones like the USDA they're they're not
considered only for the country
themselves. In fact, the distributions
go out around the world. And so it
really is a it's a global network. And
that makes sense because of that earlier
map that you might remember that crops
came from places, but but we need them
everywhere. We grow them everywhere. The
major crops at least. Maize is vital in
Africa and rice is vital in South
America. For all of those reasons, we
need genetic resources to be able to
flow across the world.
So,
um, how do you figure out if your
collections are complete? Uh, if you
need to go collect more, how are we
doing in terms of, um, making sure that
the these plants that are threatened in
the wild because of habitat destruction
because of pollution, contamination, and
um, overh harvesting and all kinds of
things. How do we make sure that they're
in the seed bankanks? So there is there
are techniques that are geographic to
try to start to understand where the
species live and whether we've gone to
collect them. And that was a good part
of my PhD was starting to do research
like this. This is this is basically the
richness of beans of fasiololis the
whole group of 80 or so species. And
that darker color in the middle is where
the where they're richest in the world
which is central Mexico. And then the
picture on the right is um where they
are richest but we have not collected
them well enough yet. And so um that
also became a major paper during that
global project that was kind of all the
wild relatives uh of all the mo major
crops around the world over a thousand
wild relatives that we consider the most
important. And so this is this is an old
figure. It's It's actually a little bit
hard to see at this point, but the um
the dark red would be the richest places
to go for wild relatives um if you
wanted to find as many as you could in
one single 5 kilometer x 5 km grid. But
let me just get a little bit more into
the methodology that we use to try to
explain it um what we're trying to do
here on the conservation side or
planning side. So this is just one of
our wild grapes that occurs in Texas.
Um, sweet mountain grape. And what we do
is we bring in information that come
typically from plant museums called
herbaria
uh or other types of museums or
increasingly from
um from citizen science applications
like I naturalist where people have
marked I've seen this in the wild and
this is where I saw it which you can now
do on your phone very easily and um map
those. So, so this is where the species
has been seen, uh, those gray spots. So,
it occurs basically in central Texas.
And, um, there's one other dot that
you'll see there, which is the same kind
of thing, except this is actually where
it's been collected and put into a germ
plasm repository, a seedbank or or a
botanic gardenard. And so, you could
already get a sense that, okay, well,
it's been collected once from one spot
in the farthest north. Is that enough?
Do we have all the genetics that we need
in the future? Maybe, maybe not. Okay.
So now all this geog geographic stuff is
based on hypotheses that geography has a
relationship to genetic diversity. That
is if you go to somewhere different then
you'll get different genetic diversity.
And so we do some modeling. So this is a
guesstimate of where we think the
species occurs based on where we've seen
it plus climate and soil um attributes.
And so the green is where we think the
species might occur. And then we can
draw a buffer around where we've already
gone and collected and say, "Okay, we
maybe we don't need to go back there in
the purple, but all of the orange,
everything that's left of the
distribution we haven't been to is where
we might want to go back to and collect
more of." And that's what we call
conservation gap analysis. Um, and so
actually 12.5% of the distribution, the
the posited distribution of the species
has been collected from and the rest
hasn't yet in terms of this rather
simple methodology.
Um we have some other metrics that try
to collect from every different eco
region or different soil type and such
to try to get an idea of sort of the
ecological variation. And then the other
side of it is now not thinking so much
about gene banks or seed bankanks but
thinking about how well protected are
these species in the wild that is in
national parks, forests and such. And so
we have a similar methodology for
institu of um essentially how much of
that range is in national parks and
such.
So, this was put together a few years
ago into a national gap analysis that um
that tells us how we're doing in terms
of 600 of our native wild relatives here
in the United States. And this map is a
heat map, a richness map of all of them
together, 600 species. And um what I I'd
like hopefully to get two messages out
of this. One is no matter where you go,
there's a wild relative underneath you.
um even just these 600 most important to
us uh in terms of relation to very
important crops and such. The other
thing is up here in New York, maybe
you're slightly out of that red, but
you're in a hot spot pretty much here,
too. So, there's a lot going on all over
the place. The darker colors is more
species occurring in the in the same
areas there.
Congratulations. Um you got work to do.
So um these are the kind of metrics that
we came up with to try to understand how
we're doing and I mentioned a series of
metrics around XC2 conservation status
that's in seed bankanks ganks or botanic
gardens and then the other side is in
protected areas that's in C2
conservation and this each of these
black dots is one of the species one of
the 600. Um, we have this scale from
zero, which is we're doing very terrible
on our conservation, and 100 is you're
done. And that's why you can see green
over there versus red. And you can kind
of get a sense now. Um, XC2, we got a
lot of work to do. Most of the species
are in that high urgent priority
category for further collecting. In C2
is a little bit better. If you combine
them, we still got a lot of work to do.
This is just grouping the species in
slightly different ways into the types
of crops or their their um their
associated crop itself. And I'll just
take some water while you take a look at
this. All right. So, another contractual
obligation of being a conservation is
just, you know, to have the doom and
gloom story just a little bit. Um, so
there's my doom and gloom story. We got
a lot we got a lot to do to really
conserve these resources. But again, let
me just emphasize, if we don't have them
in the seed bankanks and gene banks,
they're really not that accessible for
the plantreeders, right? And so we got
to be doing that work.
Um, so how do we also make this
information useful so people can go out
and do that work? We've been building
websites and making the information
publicly available and all of that. So,
this is a really great website where you
can actually explore those 600 species
uh on a USDA RTIS basically site and um
try to get to know where they are and
how well they've been collected. If
you're a coder, we've developed an R
code called gap analysis.r where you can
do your own analyses. Um and we're
rebooting that because it's a little bit
outdated right now with its
packages. Um very excited that we're now
working on a project for the non-coders,
which are most gene bank people, by the
way. um where online you can uh bring in
data from some of these big global
database uh sites like GBIFF which is
the global biodiversity information
facility or I naturalist and then you
can bring in your own data as well. You
can figure out which of those points are
just sightings versus which ones are
actually in GMES or Botanic Gardens. You
can um make your own buffer size and you
can do your own gap analysis. This is
not quite yet ready for you can go play
with it already on that on that link uh
or there's a link on my last um on the
last slide but uh another year and
hopefully this will be really ready for
prime time. I will say unfortunately
this project uh was just canceled um due
to federal funding but we're hoping to
still move it forward.
Um I naturalist I just I I have fallen
in love with citizen science myself. Um
just mentioning I created this own group
project on I naturalist of just what are
these wild relatives in the United
States and there are 2.7 million
observations
uh of of observations of these species
around the country. And so what an
incredible resource even if 10% of them
are are misidentified. What an
incredible resource. It really doesn't
matter. The amount of information on
them is is just incredible. And I'm I'm
fully in on the citizen science thing.
It's
incredible. We've been working with our
Forest Service and other land management
partners to understand what's on their
lands and um and and to be able to
protect them better. This is kind of
this is a really incredible story of how
these collaborations started with land
managers in the United States some 2530
years ago. We actually had a designation
already of a um an area that was on
forest service land but hadn't been
designated yet for anything around
botanical interest and it was designated
as a wild chili botanical preserve. It's
south of Tucson. If you're ever in that
area, um you can go you can go see it.
And so it's still special. Essentially
uh the US only has one or two really
sites on public lands that are
explicitly to conserve a cropot relative
and this is one of them. Why is it
there? Well, this is the progenitor of
chili pepper capsmanuum and it just
barely creeps up into the United States
and a couple of places in Texas, Arizona
and this is conserving one of those
populations which is near
Tucson. Very cool.
So trying to expand that work by letting
the Forest Service know what's on their
lands. And so we're doing that kind of
modeling for them on all forest service
lands of which species might be there
and then um going out and a further
version of that that then starts to
integrate genetics which is really fun
is a wild cranberry project which is a
collaboration between USDA's a research
service and forest service in
identifying in this case actually across
most of the east coast um different
populations of wild cranberries and then
doing genetics to figure out how much
they differ genetically. to identify
kind of the most interestingly different
populations that might be specifically
designated in these in these categories.
And so you can see just by the
vegetation here how different the
ecologies are. This is everything from
um well actually there's some west coast
stuff here, but everything from kind of
um north all the way south to West
Virginia. And so pretty cool
stuff. This presentation is certainly
not just my research. It's also
colleagues around the around the the the
continent around the world that are
doing work. And so just a little bit on
the Canadian and Mexican efforts here.
Uh there has been as mentioned quite a
lot of just inventorying and then
mapping and trying to understand where
the species are. And so as thought and
as expected along the southern border of
of Canada is where you get the richest.
And that's also true um to some degree
in the United States. Although as you
saw there is this northern range because
of so many berries and things that are
more temperate there. But we have a lot
of richness also on our southern border
in Texas and Arizona, New Mexico,
Florida. A lot of berries up there in
Canada that are that are I think a lot
of the efforts of the people who are
most active right now doing work in
Canada on on the native wild relatives
are around their cranberries which are
culturally significant um also
significant for wildlife etc.
Mexico. Um, huge diversity also a lot of
studies of of who they are and what
their risks are in terms of
disappearance.
Um, I want to convey a message that I've
has been driven home to me by colleagues
from Mexico, which is somewhat of a
different way of framing and
understanding these species because
there is still a lot of in uh
integration with traditional agriculture
with the wild relatives. And so there
are systems still with beans and maize
and other cultivation systems where the
wild relatives are occurring in the same
area as the domesticated fields and
there is gene flow often both ways. And
so they're understood in less is just
sort of this kind of historic thing that
you can bring genes and take them and
put them in. um but also as part of this
dynamic system of traditional
agriculture where there is still gene
flow and uh and that is that is a
different way of seeing it and and an
important aspect
there. We've been doing work together uh
publishing books and such around what
what is this richness and what are we
doing about it a couple of volumes if
you're interested in over a thousand
pages of North American crop relatives
and then starting to really reach out to
a wider audience including the public
and um eaters uh diners if you will
around these wild relatives or wild
foods. And so this is an example of of
several different events that we've
done. This one was in Tucson where it's
a wonky I think it's a funny experiment
in of itself. Can you kind of do wonky
sciency stuff? Bring together scientists
and talk about these things. Can you
also throw parties for the public uh
with chefs that bring in um that bring
in the public that want to taste
alcohols made from wild relatives or um
interesting food? Can you go down to
preserves like the Wild Chili Preserve
and see them? And it's a it's a
interesting experiment. I think it's
been very fun uh to try to to try to
message this still kind
of middle land between wild wildness and
agriculture threats and food security
all together into a a message that kind
of combines all of our challenges in the
world and all of our our issues we got
to work on.
I've been working in the botanic garden
world for the last four years and so I
want to mention that because it's the
other side of the whole world of XC2
conservation. That is where we put
things into frozen storage or into live
plants and gardens. And just as you saw
that picture of all the gene banks
around the world, there is also these
thousands of botanic gardens around the
world who are also holding crops
actually and their wild relatives and
they do it for somewhat different
purposes. Um but we're we're making
efforts to come together to do
conservation alto together all of our
repositories. And so one of the ways for
arguing for that which is a little
simple but if you'll allow me this is
another map of the richness of wild
relatives in this area but those uh
buildings are the different USDA sites
that I mentioned the active research
active research and collection sites.
Colorado's there uh in the middle there.
Um, so you can imagine the number of
different people working there and what
they're able to do. But then you map all
the botanic gardens on top of that and
all their botanical expertise around
being able to identify species or go out
or collect and all of that. You might
imagine that you could do more working
together. And so um, I got to be part of
a really fun project almost 10 years ago
that Dr. Mark Zell also up there was
part of. And
um we had never met each other actually
before and it was really really cool. We
were both on the sort of the more a
side. There was all these botanic garden
people that had never met and it was all
about like could we work together and um
could we do something on crop relatives
and so we decided through that to come
up with a roadmap for North America on
what do we got to do? And we published
that in the crop journal. We published
it in a botanic garden journal. We
published it for land managers and it
has five tenants to it. This is kind of
the big picture of how do we deal with
this giant richness of diversity that is
threatened that is important for our
food security that plantreeders need.
And so the first one is we still got to
do science about who are these species
and where do they live and how well
collected they are. Uh the second one is
we got to protect them in their natural
habitats. Why? If they're not in still
evolving in their natural habitats, then
they're not evolving alongside pest and
diseases and changes in the weather and
climate and all of those things. Um, the
third is we got to put them in the seed
bankanks and gene banks so that they're
conserved for the long term, but they're
also available to plant breeders and
others. The fourth is we got to do the
value addition of phenotyping and all of
that stuff, pre-ereading to get them
ready. And then the fifth one is public
awareness and outreach, which the
Botanic Gardens are particularly posed
to do good work on.
Um, and so just a couple kind of last
slides that are about that that
networking or that that growing network
of people that are really working on it.
So as the botanic garden world then and
the gene bank world has come together,
we've tried to figure out what is the
lowhanging fruit for us to work on. And
it actually turns out that fruit um and
nuts is is a lowhanging fruit for us
because gardens have live trees. They
often have whole plants and have enough
space for them. Whereas the gene banks
struggle to have enough field space for
them. And so it makes a lot of sense to
work together in that way. There's
gardens that have giant apple
collections. For instance, the New York
Botanical Garden in the Bronx. And so
this is a network that's been happening
for a couple of years. It's working on
these 10 genera. If you're interested in
any of them, please uh get in touch with
me. And it's a very active network of
understanding who the species are. It's
got a little bit of money so that uh
folks can go out and do collecting and
then bring them into the botanic gardens
or gan banks. And this is three pictures
from um my own work at the San Diego
Botanic Garden uh uh bringing in these
collections. This is two wild plums from
native to California. One of which is
very very rare and endangered, the
desert one on the left and then uh a
wild walnut in the middle. It's really
fun. It's it's a great network of
people.
We also put on a symposium last year
that was quite an experiment I would say
as well. It's kind of a reboot after
that first um work 10 years ago of
getting together and it was um where are
we at and how do we go forward and what
I there's still some really good
resources on that website that you'll be
able to find um there. But um yeah,
before I get to that, let me just go
back here.
So one thing that I really hope to
express is that I think also in the last
20 years as our working in this field
has deepened in this region we've also
started to move
beyond
that that simpler understanding at first
that all we're doing really is just
grabbing jeans and bringing them over
which is wonderful and important. It's
not there's nothing at all wrong with
that. But the bigger picture of what are
these wild plants and how can they be
used and that has broken down all kinds
of terminological silos like wild or
even
crop. Uh let me just repeat that. So
like crop what is a first of all what is
a crop? Um does it have to be
cultivated? So, what about the plants
here in North America that aren't
particularly cultivated but are food
resources and very interesting like paw
paws or a plant I'm about to show you in
a minute. And then what the heck is wild
mean anyway as we start to realize that
people have been managing wild
populations forever anyway through
burning or or selecting or management.
And so our our our understanding is less
now that there's just wild stuff and you
bring it over into the domesticate, but
there's this giant spectrum of plants
that have been associated to more or
less of a degree with people for
thousands of years and we're still in
there somewhere. And what do we want to
do about that? Where do we want to go
forward from here? And um I'll get back
to that in a minute for a last point.
But on the networking side, I wanted to
mention something actually very
exciting. And that's that in the botanic
garden world, they've started to have
these global networks to do important
work on really important taxonomic
groups like oaks or psychids. There's a
psychid out in that nice little green
area out there. And these are often very
threatened plants. And and it's this
whole group of thousands of institutions
through a network like this getting
together to conserve all the species.
And I'm very um excited and proud to say
that uh
the 10th no sorry the 12th
um quick math there uh the the 12th
global conservation consortium has just
been uh just been agreed upon for the
world and it's going to be focused on
food plants including cropot relatives
and so that really brings the whole
botanic garden world of thousands of
institutions connected with gene banks
around the world to try to to do
something um about crop relatives but
also about all these wild food plants
that are increasingly threatened around
the world etc. And so okay so now
finally I get to this expansion. I have
three more slides and um I think I have
enough time to express them. I'm going
to take a deep breath for a minute and
try to give you one one last big
thought.
Um, this is such a great
institution and so many amazing brains
and creativity here, so much
productivity. I really agree with the
previous speakers that spoke about how
what an amazing place this is and I'm
really honored to be here.
um taking care of our major crops I
think in the title of the symposium as
well relatives of our major crops is of
utmost importance in terms of those
crops future we have to keep this
diversification process going on are
bringing in new new genetics that said
my own feeling is that that's just the
beginning of what agriculture can look
like with these wild plants or semi-
wild plants don't even use the word wild
these plants
uh and So, anybody know what this plant
is by
chance? Please. It is a ground nut.
American ground nut. So, this is aios
aios
americana. This is a plant that um that
was incredibly important in Native
American food systems. Could say
agriculture if you'd like. Um all the
way from St. Louis to Cape Cod at one
point and is kind of barely around
anymore, mostly by hobbyists. There is a
USDA collection in Iowa. Um, this is
known to be really associated with
people because it's a
triploid. It has a native distribution
as a diploid, a fertile diploid, but
these triploids are what are were
occurring all the way from St. Louis to
Cape Cod with bigger tubers. It's a
legume tuber, high protein, higher
protein. It's tasty. This is my own
actually um harvest in Colorado which is
kind of marginal to collect it there
which I fed during Thanksgiving to my
family. Um it was known to be probably
one of those foods eaten in the first
Thanksgivings and um of course my family
had you no idea what how there was like
teaspoon each that they got to eat. Um
but I thought it was pretty darn good.
It's an amazing plant and it's just one
of these plants that I want to I want to
express for those that have the
opportunity and privilege to think
outside the box uh about new crops. This
is one of these crops that really could
be something. And um there's an
association in the world with tuber
um people who are predominantly
dependent on tubers and protein
deficiency. And so a crop like this
could also be an incredible crop uh for
other regions in the world.
Just wanted to mention two other
examples that I think are really neat
that are coming along that are not so
much about bringing genes over but uh
thinking about bringing entire plants
into food systems or or or um our
agricultural systems. And this is work
by my colleague Dr. Nolan Kaine and and
colleagues in University of Colorado
also USDA and other places. And this is
a this is a native flax that you can see
in its native distribution in that that
map on that side widely distributed.
It's a perennial. And so this is work
that was also referred to a little bit
in an earlier presentation um around the
promise or opportunities of perennial
crops and um in in in more sustainable
agricultural systems. This is a pretty
neat one. it it it already has good oil
content like the domesticated flax that
is mostly grown and it's already in
wildflower mixes so we kind of know how
to grow it already. It's really just
figuring out the agonomic systems and
bumping up the quality and and um and
and yeah the quality essentially and so
there is some really great work like
this going on and I'm happy to talk more
about it to those who who want to talk
more about that stuff. And so as a last
slide, so here's a question that um my
mentor and my postto Dr. Allison Miller
from the Danforest Center in St. Louis
University in St. Lewis asks which are
the wild relatives of our future
crops and her argument which I agree is
they are certainly the wild relatives of
wheat and rice and maize and tomato and
brassica the canola and all of that but
if our future crops are also other
things then um then our wild relatives
are also other things too. they can go
much beyond. And so there is some really
excellent and interesting work about
trying to figure
out for instance if you want to go
perennial, how many herbaceous
perennials in this case um the land
institute type thinking on productive
perennial systems that you could mow and
things like that. How many are there out
there in the world? And so in terms of
grasses, in fact, there's almost 8,000
perennial or baceous grasses that could
be looked at. And then how do we whittle
that down to 20 or 30 or 50 or a couple
hundred that might really be promising
next step crops for the future? I'm so
inspired by this because this is the
kind of long-term, you know, big picture
thinking that maybe 500 years from now,
we end up with 20 or 30 or a couple
hundred different crops that we're
eating. and and how exciting and
interesting that would be. So, I hope
this was um interesting and uh and I
hope that it just drove home just a
little bit how important the
foundational bigger thinking and
conservation work is to plant breeding.
Lots of links to these websites and data
resources and and papers at the end over
the years. So, thank you so much. Happy
to answer questions.
Yes, thank you so much for the
presentation. Um, I was wondering if you
had any knowledge of our interest in
crops being domesticated by nonhuman
animals.
Um, so and and how if you don't mind me
asking, how do you define a crop in that
case then? Oh no,
that's a good question because I think I
probably
put in the definition. Yeah. Or say that
it's a plant that's been used widely by
humans and has diverged from a wild
relative, but I guess you could say the
same.
Yeah. Well, I'll try to answer your
question in some helpful or meaningful
way. In any case, what what I well I
don't have off the top of my head
something that um yeah, I do actually. I
have two answers.
one thing is um humans are incredibly
innovative. I mean obviously we're doing
all kinds of crazy things like cell
phones, right?
Um, I still think probably the biggest
most incredible innovation that's ever
happened is agriculture
itself, which is this huge process of
just of of noticing what's around and
then working with that diversity and
changing it in this co-evolutionary
process where everybody needs everybody,
humans need the plants or animals, etc.
But we didn't, it wasn't just us. And in
fact, we capitalized on other animals
quite a lot in some cases, particularly
with fruit. And so avocados, for
instance, didn't actually go from this
to that like maze did. Uh avocados
actually went from this to that because
they were already being eaten by and
selected by megapana in this case in the
past. And so I think maybe that's um
that's that's some something that gets
to your question. But the other thing I
want to say that's also really important
is as as many of you probably know, the
more we know about plant systems,
especially plant systems and and what
we're hoping is more sustainable
agricultural systems that have living
soils and such, the more we realize that
the cropping systems are actually very
complex with microbiota, um, with
pollinators, including things like bats
for agave and things like that. And if
if those things aren't all still
working, then you really don't have your
plant system. That in cases like agave
are sometimes a little bit
contentiously, I know, but not even
called plants anymore. But holions, that
means that that that that there's so
many organisms that have to work
together that if if you just have the
plant, it's really not the thing
anymore. It's not the crop. You need you
need all the microorganisms and you need
the pollinators, you need the people,
the whole shebang.
Cool. Thank you so much. You're welcome.
Yes. So, so in my mind, and I haven't
researched this rec so I could be wrong,
but I feel like a lot of the threats to
um conservation and natural diversity
are driven by capitalist market forces.
Um and I always thought that it's kind
of hard to quantify in the language
those forces are conversant in
economics. um like the value of
biodiversity that people are really like
deeply steeped in plants and agriculture
wilderness that value is kind of
inherent maybe in our perspective but
now that you like seem to have this very
high level picture of genetic diversity
in these crop oil species like across
America kind of across the world and
we're also developing a pretty like
clear understanding the impact that
diversity can have on our agricultural
system. Do you feel like there could be
kind of a quantification of the like
potential economic value of genetic
diversity in these crop wild species?
Um, and would that quantification be
like a useful argument for conservation
efforts if it could be made? Cool.
Great.
Um I I know that there have been for 30
years um economic valuations of genetic
resources including crop relatives and
um there's a there was a among research
groups there's a a person named Melinda
Smail who I think had some associations
with Cornell in fact and some other
places and she did some preliminary work
as well as a group in USDA the economic
research service. So you can look up
some of that early stuff. It's pretty
wild. In some cases, the valuations are
specific to um to genetic innovations
and they're always in the millions um if
not billions of dollars. And so if you
the economic arguments I think have have
been there um to do one for the whole
like what is the value of wild relatives
economically? I don't think anybody's
come up with the single number and of
course it's a crazy thing to even
attempt but if there are any economists
in the crowd that want to give it a try
it'd be incredible to to hear
that I don't know you know I'm not
placed to say as as a economist or
policy person or anything which none of
those how effective those arguments are
but I I I do think that money talks to
some degree and we should still be
speaking in those languages um to to
drive home the ever important message
that we need genetic resources.
Thank you.
Sorry. I think we need to move on to the
next speaker time wise, but yeah,
definitely fine. Thanks so much.
Thank you, Henry, for the kind
introduction. I want to thank the
symposium organizing committee for all
their hard work in putting this event
together, as well as to the to Corteva
for sponsoring the event. I'm really
excited to be here today to share some
pieces of my PhD research with you which
is focused on maintaining diversity
within the Kansas State University wheat
breeding
program. So when we think about wheat
performance over time, we have seen
sustained genetic gain in terms of wheat
yields. Specifically around the adoption
of green revolution varieties in the
1970s and 1980s, we see a significant
spike in our wheat yield increases.
However, this genetic gain for yield,
while is still increasing, is
decelerating to where this might suggest
a potential plateau and improvement in
wheat yields. And at any point when we
start to lose um improvement for a
certain trait, it can become very
prudent to go back and look at those
more diverse sources or wild relatives
to be used in
breeding. When thinking about what makes
up the overall wheat yield, we can think
of it as a trade-off between our source
traits and our sync traits. So our
source traits are going to be those
traits that are more important in the
early stage of the growing season. Um
development of adequate levels of
biomass will determine photosynthetic
efficiency and eventual um
transllocation to the sink filling
organs which are on the right side of
the triangle. The sink filling organs
are going to be more important um during
scinessence and grain filling period to
where these are the ones that have been
historically prioritized the most in
increasing wheat yields. Most of our
increases in wheat yield over time has
come because of increases to harvest
index which is shown in this bipot
analysis where grain yield and harvest
index have the highest amount of
co-variation compared to these other um
yield components.
So in thinking that all of our mo many
of our improvements yielded have come
because of harvest index. If we want to
keep making improvements, we may need to
start focusing more on this right side
of the triangle in those source traits
while keeping in the back of our minds
that we have to make sure to optimize
this trade-off. You have to have enough
biomass to photosynthesize early in the
season, but you also have to leave
enough time to fill grain later on in
the growing season.
So in thinking about how we can do this
in wheat specifically, wheat has a
complicated genetic history in terms of
its um evolution and domestication which
provides several opportunities for crop
wild wild relatives. I was very thankful
for to Colin for introducing the onion
concept of the primary, secondary, and
tertiary gene pools. When thinking about
wheat, the primary and secondary species
that are in the gene pool are going to
be those ones that have um genomes in
common. So those are going to be the
ones that are shown on this slide. So to
go over just in detail the steps that
occurred in generating our hexaploid
wheat or tric
acum. The first species that were
involved were the wild grass species
which donated the A and B genomes to
formed tetroploid tricum turgidum
subspecies daoidis which is also known
as wild emmer. Further
domestication rose made a cultivated
emmer or triticum turgidum subspecies
dicum come about. After the free
threshing character was conferred durham
wheat arose. This is what is used in our
pasta production. These free threshing
tetroploids were also the tetroploid
donor for um breadwheat which when
hybridized with the dgome donor
adelopsia formed hexaploid
trum. Some things to notice about uh the
evolutionary history of wheat is that
there were two hybridization events each
associated with their own genetic
bottleneck. Because of the um makeup of
the wheat genome, there have been many
opportunities to lose out on genetic
diversity coming from these wild
relatives. The other thing I want to
point out is that this species wild
emmer specifically is can be considered
the central conduit of gene flow between
the wild um diploid species and our
cultivated durham and
breadweeds. So there are several main
approaches to gene ingression. A very
straightforward approach approach would
just be through making direct crosses.
This will be limited to species within
the primary and secondary gene pools to
where myotic re combination will not be
very successful if the chromosomes can't
even pair in the first place. Synthetic
wheat is another approach that's taken
specifically in wheat breeding. This is
where a cross between a tetroploid
Durham or other tetroploid wheat is made
to that Dgome donor. This basically
regenerates that initial cross that
resulted in hexaploid wheat. However, a
drawback of using this approach is that
you're essentially discarding many
generations of breeding progress that
has made in hexaploid wheat. So, these
materials aren't generally very um
adopted
agonomically. Gene editing also has its
um place in gene in introgression
breeding. This this is really specific
for precise edits. Um when thinking
about just increasing overall
quantitative variation, it can be a
little more challenging. And it's also
important to think about any sort of
regulatory constraints that come along
with that process, especially in the US
and in um working with wheat germ
plasm. Amphiploid hybrids are a really
interesting approach that can be taken.
This allows for crossing between two
relatively unrelated species because
when that cross is done, artificial
chromosome doubling is performed. That
way the complete chromosomeal
constitution of each of the two species
that were used in that cross is
maintained.
So the amphopid hybrid approach was what
was used in development of my PhD
research population. So I know this is a
lot but just go step by step with me.
The first step was through crossing the
hexaploid recurrent parentred wheat
donor to the age lobst genome donor. A
cross between these two species does not
have much um match in terms of its
chromosomes which is why we had to
double the chromosomes with ultraine.
This resulted in development of a
synthetic octoploid where we have the
full genomic makeup of acce and the full
genomic makeup of
agelopia. In this way this synthetic
octoploid is used as an amphiploid
bridge to bring in the diversity coming
from wild emmer or triticum
dyquoides. So that second step was
through was using this um amphiploid
bridge with a cross to
dyoid. After that, the hexaploids are
able to be regained. Something that's
important to notice is that in this F1
generation, we still have a really high
contribution of theoretical um wild
alals in our background. So to regain
that background recurrent parent, two
back crosses were made to uh the same
hexapoid recurrent parent to where after
the first bat cross, the proportion the
theoretical proportion of wild alles
would be around 30%. After the second
that's reduced down to around 15%. So
essentially this population is developed
to have a very high proportion of that
recurrent parent background in it to
maintain adequate levels of um yield and
regional adaptation while still keeping
low-level uh contributions from those
wild relatives. But it's also important
that we keep those integrations at a
high enough frequency to where we can
actually pick up on any meaningful
variation.
So after these um F4 derived F5 lines
were increased, we were able to do a ton
of phenotypic triing across Kansas. We
used three years, three locations
distributed across the precipitation
gradient. However, it's um interesting
that in the three years that we did this
study in, all of Kansas was under a
pretty severe drought. So the
differences that we might observe
between these locations in a year with
adequate precipitation were not
necessarily observed in my data.
The largest piece of my project was
collecting this massive quantity of
phenotypic data. I'll go over each of
these components. In the next several
slides, but the goal was essentially to
look at the trait means and variances of
those wild integration lines compared to
common check varieties that are used as
benchmarks of regional performance.
So before I talk more about each of
those um trait groups, I wanted to
discuss my data processing. So this is
essentially a zoomed in view on two of
those 279 integression lines. What is
shown here are my raw observational data
Y for three traits in essence state,
plant height, and grain yield. What you
might notice is that these traits have
very different magnitudes of variance to
where making efficient comparisons
between them can be really challenging
um especially when considering deviation
between
them. So that's why I pursued a data
standardization approach. This is a
fairly straightforward methodology to
where within each location I took the
within environment trait mean subtracted
it from the raw data and divided by the
within environment standard
deviation. After doing this
standardization process, we are left
with an a data set that is quite more
easily interpretable to where the mean
is going to be at zero, which means
anything with a positive value is going
to be above the mean. Anything with a
negative value will be below the mean.
This just becomes really easy way to
view a lot of data at
once. These standardized data were used
as the input for two-stage analysis. The
first stage was uh modeling the within
location genotype genotypic values as
fixed effects and we did this by making
a AR1 row column spatial correction.
After running this model, we had our
blues or genotypic estimates and our
weights corresponding to each one of
those values which were used as the
input into the next model in a two-stage
analysis which is a bl. This is run
across locations using genotype as a
random effect to where we can extract
one single genotypic value for each
genotype across all locations. Doing
this enables u much more efficient
analysis because instead of doing single
within environment analyses and trying
to composite across them, this
essentially does that for me. And to
further verify that this approach um was
a reasonable one, I looked at the
genetic correlations of different traits
and traits uh within environments.
So the diagonal shown here or the matrix
shown here has genetic correlation of
grainy blues at the six locations tested
with genetic repeatability on the
diagonal. What can be noticed is that
the high degree of correlation between
these locations indicates that there
aren't very many rank changes in these
genotypes which allows me to make more
um efficient comparisons just using
those blops. I would expect my results
to apply regardless of my
location. Looking at my trait blups in
this matrix again with the genetic
repeatabilities plotted on the diagonal.
I specifically want to highlight the
fact that these repeatability values are
moderately high to high which is not
necessarily always expected for highly
quantitative traits which is what I'm
working with. Um, but the fact that
those had high repeatability values
indicates that using these blops is
going to be an effective way to still
capture that effective variation while
not having to necessarily do it within
each
environment. So going into some of these
um specific trait groups, one of the
first um things I measured were some of
my phenological characteristics. So
heading dates, essence date, grainfill
period and plant height. A pattern that
is interesting here to notice is
the divergence of the mean and standard
deviation of the checks versus
integration lines. So we have this
orange bar corresponding to the checks
and the purple corresponding to the
integration lines with the mean centered
at zero. And we see that these checks
are on average developing quite a bit
later compared to the ingression lines.
And this can be localized to a region on
chromosome 2B. And I apologize I didn't
have time to talk too much about my
marker data, but I did want to show some
of my G-W was results just so you guys
can see um that we are still able to
pick up variation coming from these wild
alals even though they're at very low
minor al frequencies which is shown in
this table here.
Moving on to yield components. Something
that is important when thinking about
working with wild material is the fact
that we're going to see pretty
significant yield drag. So these are
showing grain yield for the checks for
the integression lines. We see that
those checks are having a much higher
level of yield compared to those
integration lines. Although that pattern
doesn't necessarily follow off of um
throughout all of our different traits.
So focusing first on our traits that are
related to the source stage of the yield
triangle, we saw quite a bit of
variation to where I got some fairly
strong peaks across all these traits.
And a specific thing I want to point out
here is that for my green reflectance
values, I got that same um peak on
chromosome 2B. This is fairly intuitive
however because previously when I was
that peak was associated with um
maturity and development to where
something that is uh scessing is losing
its green chlorophyll content and so
when you average that green reflectance
throughout the growing season things
with lower values are probably going to
be the ones that matured faster anyway.
So, so far making sense
still. Moving on to the um sink related
traits. We see that there were was a
common association for several of these
grain size traits. So, thousand kernel
weight, test weight, and kernel width.
Specifically, that association for test
weight, which is essentially how um
effectively your grain can pack into a
certain volume. that has a fairly large
effect and fairly large percent variance
explained to where the fact that this
region came up for multiple uh grain
size traits indicates that this may have
a fairly large effect on the yield drag
that is observed in these
materials. While we see a drag for
yield, the opposite effect is generally
observed for our quality traits. One of
the reasons people use uh wild emmer
specifically in wheat breeding programs
is because of its quality. When thinking
about our grain protein content, we see
that these checks have an average of
much lower compared to the wild
integration
lines. However, grain protein and grain
yield and wheat have a very strongly
negative relationship to where it can be
challenging to select on both of these
things. And if you you're going to pick
one, then you're going to pick yield. So
this is where breeders use a metric
called grain protein deviation which is
essentially a regression of protein
content on grain yield using the
residuals from that um regression as the
protein deviation values. This can be
used in a way to where a cutoff
threshold for grain yield can be
established and then um lines with
higher than average grain protein can be
selected which is shown in this green
box. And so looking at the um
distribution of grain protein deviation
in my population which essentially
combines the protein and yield, we see
that those checks and the recurrent
parent all kind of cluster at the lower
end of that distribution. So these
integration lines have higher grain
protein deviation overall. But one thing
that is interesting to notice is that
for protein quality score and solvent
retention capacity which while grain
protein is more a measure of protein
content these are a measure of protein
quality those do not necessarily
increase. So while we've brought an
increase in protein content over from
this these wild relative integrations we
did not necessarily increase the
functional protein
quality. So, I also screened some of
these um through a full ionomics panel
of 19 elements. I didn't include these
on the previous correlation matrix just
because it would have been incredibly
massive to look at, but I showed these
here also including grain yield and
grain protein. Something to point out is
the generally negative correlations
between grain yield and these ionomics
traits. Meaning that selection for
increasing concentration of desirable
elements in the grain may very likely
reduce our grain yield levels. And
additionally, when looking at these
genetic
repeatabilities, those low genetic
repeatabilities indicate that there's a
lot of environmental variation that's
going to have an effect. And so the
efficiency of selection won't be that
high anyway. So these ionomics data are
a little bit messy in terms of how we
can use them for breeding but
nonetheless I was able to actually find
an interesting um pathway which can be
pursued to where for rubidium which is
shown here I got that same
um peak on the same region of chromosome
2b. So rubidium is generally used as a
proxy for potassium transport and which
is going to be water transport. So when
you see variations in your rubidium
concentrations that are localized to the
same regions as your um development that
can really be indicative of some sort of
a drought related effect especially
given the fact that these were these
data were all collected under drought
conditions. So, it's going to be
interesting to look more at this region
on chromosome 2b in greater detail under
more controlled drought environments
instead of just the randomly natural
drought that uh my experiment was
conducted
under. So, I've shown you guys a bunch
of data. Sometimes my ingression lines
did better. Sometimes my checks did
better. A question that comes up is how
on earth are we going to use all this
data? So, this is where index selection
becomes um really interesting. And
because I am in an applied breeding
program, I'm still going to always be
the most interested in grain yield,
which is why I developed this selection
index specifically to always pick the
highest yielding things. So, the way I
did this, and just a reminder that these
are standardized blops I'm working with,
I multiplied the um blop of grain yield
for a specific genotype by the blop of
another trait. So in this case,
grainfill period. I selected a subset of
traits that I thought captured um what
breeders are generally selecting on. So
grainfill period, high yielding but low
um short plants. That's why I divided by
plant height here. Um I I had my
protein, my solvent retention capacity,
some of my kernel traits. And after
doing these individual granular by trait
indices, I was able to average across
them to come up with an overall index
for all of these lines. This index
pulled out a couple integression lines
that outperformed absolutely everything
in the population, including the highest
performing check, which is bolded to
showdown. And I have this plotted next
to grain yield in bushels per acre for
comparison. And you can see that while
this selection index is pulling out the
things that are best across a wide range
of traits, it is specifically also
pulling out the things that are the
highest yielding, which is going to be
incredibly important when thinking about
developing breeding materials. We
weren't necessarily trying to develop um
germ plasm to release. We were more
thinking about developing parents for
our crossing block, which these
materials are already being recycled in
our crossing block um this year. And
additionally, these top three, so those
three are being pursued for germ plasm
release later this year. So this was a
really um positive result out of my
project because we weren't necessarily
expecting that yield and adaptation to
come through from that recurrent parent.
So overall, some of the most in
interesting things that I found out of
my project is that using that amphoploid
hybrid bridge approach was pretty
effective at bringing in diversity on
all three genomes at a level that was
able to be detected by my different
analyses while still maintaining that
recurrent parent background. These
things are still very well adapted to
Kansas um even in spite of the drought
conditions that that was experienced.
Additionally, there are several
interesting routes that can be pursued
further. I think that region on
chromosome 2B could be really studied in
a lot of detail. Also, the re the region
on 6B, I think that would be really
interesting to look at in terms of um
reducing that linkage drag that comes
from wild in
regressions. So, with that, I just want
to make sure that nobody thinks that I
did this all on my own. Um I have to
give the biggest of thanks to the K8
weep breeding program. They've supported
me through every single stage of my
research. Additionally, my graduate
committee for all their intellectual
contributions. I I was pretty stupid
when I started, so they've helped me uh
become slightly smarter. Also, my
mentors, they've been the people who
have gone out of their way to make sure
that I have had the one-on-one support
I've needed at any given point in my
research. And of course, my family and
my funding sources. So, with that, not
sure how much time we have left for
questions, but you can find me during
coffee. And thank
you. Yeah, you can go first. Um, so you
talked about how you're developing these
reccominant red lines
and you had a certain estimated
proportion from each of your species.
And that's been Yes. However, did you
see any
uh segregation distortion? That is a
good question. So I did check for one
annuploids did not find any um because
since these are DC2s that allows for um
a lot of that background to be brought
back in to where these were mostly the
recurrent parent. Um we are doing I just
got access to the deep sequencing data
from my parents. So that's the last big
piece of my project. And so I'll be
doing integression mapping to like more
finely delineate where those
intergression regions occur so I can
look more at that segregation
distortion. Um I also expect those
frequencies once I do that to not
necessarily match my mandelian
expectations. Mandelian expectations do
not necessarily apply when playing
around employee levels super well. So
these are approximate um estimations.
Additionally, the there was some
negative selection that we did against
things that didn't thresh or that
shattered before harvest. Um, so I might
expect those to have a higher proportion
of wild alals in them, which is why they
were not adapted, and removing those
would subsequently lower my overall al
frequencies from those integressions.
But if they can't run through the
combine, then there's no point in
evaluating them. Thank you.
Um I was just curious uh you mentioned
um the overall protein content and then
the protein quality and I was curious
what that meant like quality in terms of
nutrition or what were you Yeah. So the
question was about protein content
versus protein quality. So we have a
really breeders friendly low or high
throughput assay for early generation
materials because it only requires five
grams of seed and it's a lactic acid SDS
SRC. So we basically add lactic acid and
SDS and we can do the dry pellet weight,
wet pellet weight and adjust that for
moisture to look at our solvent
retention capacity which gets at your um
gluten strength. These are very well
correlated to some of our lower
throughput um bake analyses that are
done on our very late generation
materials. Um and then off the solvent
retention capacity, if you divide that
value by the protein content, that gives
you an estimate of protein quality
because something that has higher
solvent retention capacity but lower
protein has more functional protein.
That makes sense. So yeah, it's a
breeders assay that was specifically
developed for wheat breeders. Thanks.
Yes. Could you elaborate more on a
ionomic section and you said you're
using the rubium levels to infer drought
resistance is that
so rubidium is has a pretty high or
strong correlation to potassium which
when you look at a the potassium
concentration in the grain that's going
to indicate that's going to be an
indication of water movement throughout
the plant and rubidia is used as a proxy
for potassium transport u because the
way that they are seen in these assays
is relatively similar and I had to learn
that from some little deep dive in the
literature did not necessarily know that
um and so when we see things with
elevated rubidium levels that can
indicate that the plant is under more
higher levels of drought stress because
if there's more rubidium that means
there's going to be more water transport
and so that's kind of where we're going
with this association right now. This
will of course be better verified with
my deep sequencing data and my uh and
any other analyses that are done on this
region. I don't know if that answered
your question. Perfect. I think I saw a
hand over here. Oh yeah. So this is a
bit more anecdotal and like maybe far
out of the distribution of your
research, but I noticed um in some of my
work that the I look at chloroplast and
the chloroplast genome for a lot of
species and centrum is like drastically
shorter than others. So I was curious
when you're doing your crossing, did you
like observe anything weird happening
based on um cytoplasmic inheritance?
Like if you had atrolops as the maternal
the female parent they cross versus not.
Yeah. So that's a good point is that
when crossing with these wild relatives,
it can be really hard to use the wild
relative as the female parent. Um we
used the wild relative as the pollen
donor in all of our cases because
especially with like a tasti those are
some really small anthers. it's going to
be hard to pull those out. Um, so yeah,
we did use the recurrent whatever had
the recurrent parent in it. That was
always our female donor. So we didn't
specifically look at maternal versus
paternal inheritance, but that would
definitely be interesting to do. Yeah.
Um, I want to ask what has been your
greatest challenge in this research and
also what is the thing that you're most
excited or passionate about?
most excited about is this. Uh we were
really really not expecting these things
to look very good in the
field. They are not super drought
tolerant. I mentioned that drought
escape strategy. That's not necessarily
desirable because that's going to
shorten the uh grain filling period. So,
the fact that we were able to get
upwards of 80 bushels an acre grain
yield off of these materials was a
really encouraging um result, especially
because there's simultaneous research
that's going on alongside at our um at
the USDA in Manhattan, Kansas using
Emmer in direct crosses to where when
making comparisons between things using
the direct crossing approach and the
amphiploid bridge approach, there's a
significant difference to where we
really like the um integression strategy
we used and I would say the most
challenging
thing I think that there are not a wide
variety of resources to train um
graduate students in breeding analyses
if that makes sense. So the kind of some
of the technical aspects, it's hard to
get exposure to both the practical and
the theoretical. And so having being
able to bring those two things together
and kind of think at every stage of the
process, what might be going on and
thinking of a plant as a whole system
and not just puzzle pieces, but a whole
all together, but I could list a million
things. Cool. Thank you so much. Yeah,
we have time for one more question, but
if not, then we uh will come back here
at 3:25 for Samantha's talk. But enjoy
the coffee, everybody, and give it up
for potentially speciation. And so we're
thinking about um these processes
happening at an evolutionary time scale.
So we're thinking hundreds to millions
of generations.
And we have these kind of three main
processes, mutation, selection, and
drift that are really big shapers of
this genetic
diversity. Um, but sometimes there can
be these hybridization events between
two species where instead of getting
half of a genome's worth of DNA from
each parent, you get the full genome
from mom and the full genome from dad.
So instead of one and one making two,
you get two and two making four. Or a
tetroploid.
And uh over these evolutionary time
scales uh we can see this DNA sequences
are being lost. Um and this process is
called diploidization where that
polyloid species becomes something like
a diploid again. And this process of
sequence lost is called fractionation.
And while DNA sequence loss is a major
consequence of polyloy and basically the
response to this uh event, there can be
other changes including uh changes to
gene expression or changes to existing
gene functions to change slightly that
gene function or even develop novel
functions. And it's not just the genes
that are duplicating in these events. Um
these are affecting all the other
genomic elements including repeat space
uh like uh transposable elements and
also all of those regulators that are
affecting gene
expression. And so when we have these
whole genome duplication events, we are
generating this massive pool of genetic
diversity and thus a huge pool of
adaptive potential. And this process of
fractionation whittleles that pool down.
But during this process, we can also see
these bursts of diversification where
there are many more forms of species um
either forms of the same species or form
or even whole new species forming that
could be adapted to different
environments compared to that parental
species. And so in this way polyloy and
fractionation are major shapers of
genomic diversity and structure.
potentially leading to these novel
forms. Okay, but you're probably asking
yourself, well Sam, how common is this?
Actually, this seems like this would be
a pretty rare
occurrence. Um, but actually polyot is
very common, particularly in plants. Um,
and so here, this is a wonderful kind of
mini review about it. um where they made
a fogyny using all of the plant emojis
available to you on your emoji
keyboard and they put all of the whole
genome duplication events that we have
observed as red dots and all the whole
genome triplication. So instead of being
two, right, you have three
um on onto the spogyny and hopefully you
can see that there's quite a large
number of them.
Now if we have an estimate of what that
genome size was right here at the base
of this fogyny right either how many
chromosomes was in that original genome
or how much DNA as like in poggrams
there was we can then say okay if you've
been through so many rounds of
duplication we can multiply that
starting number of chromosomes and DNA
weight to get an estimate of how big
that genome should be now and And that's
what's indicated here in yellow with
being chromosome numbers and blue being
that genome size and just total DNA
mass. Um, and with the darker colors
being bigger
genomes. But what do we actually
see? We see much smaller genomes and
much fewer chromosome numbers than we
would expect here in those kind of inner
circles that are much lighter in color.
Now, personally, I find these color
scales really difficult to parse and
compare, and so I'd rather show you this
histogram
instead. Um, here we have uh genome
size, right, in poggrams on this x axis
for thousands of angioperms.
And the high edge of this histogram,
while there is a long tail at much
larger genome sizes, the edge of this
histogram is at 30 pogs, which is about
where the arrow is pointing to on the
original scale. So, as you can see,
we're not even getting into those darker
colors. It's all these um basically
gradations of bright bright
blue. Okay?
So all of these small genomes have to be
due to these um really large amounts of
DNA sequence lost over time given all of
these uh poly events. And since in this
talk I really want to focus in on this
process of fractionation I want to
reiterate this with a simplified
cartoon. And so here this cartoon is
really nice in that we have a red genome
and a blue genome that come together to
form a polyloid that has six
chromosomes. Three from blue, three from
red.
And over time we see sequence loss where
maybe those chromosomes start to shrink
in
size. And maybe over some more time some
of those chromosomes start to fuse
together. And so we see a reduction in
overall chromosome number. And maybe
over really really large time scales we
see something that looks like a diploid
or has been rediploidized and we're back
down to a chromosome number of three.
Now, this is a really nice simple
cartoon, but as a biologist, when I'm
coming up to this species at the kind of
end of this cycle, I don't see red and
blue. I just see something that looks
like a diploid with three chromosomes.
And so the only way we can see this
history of duplication to parse apart
those red and blue uh chromosome
segments is by aligning these quote
unquote purple chromosomes to uh either
the red or the blue genome or something
that's very similar to one of
those. Okay, but what do I mean by an
alignment? So here we have this
ancestral species. And now each of these
colored triangles represents a gene and
given some time we might see speciation
um giving us these two descendant
species. Genes that arise from that same
common ancestor. So the red triangles
here we call these orthologes.
And when we see all of these orthologes
kind of conserved in the same order and
orientation, we call that cintonyine,
right? This conserved gene
order. Now, over time, structural
variants such as inversions or um
insertion and deletion events can break
up this ciny, making it harder to to see
these conserved pieces of the
chromosome.
Um, so when you see in bow ties in um
some future slides, know that that's due
to these inversions,
right? Okay. But now let's add in some
polyability on top of this. Okay. Let's
say one of those species suddenly has a
whole genome duplication event and now
there's two of everything. Each copy of
that genome is called a subg genome.
Here we're using subg genome one and
two. And each one of those um genes
arising from that duplication event,
right? They're pairs from that same
orthologue. Those are called homeologs.
And when now we do these alignments with
this now polyloid species back to the
species that's remained diploloyid we
should see a
2:1 ratio of cintin where for each part
of that reference diploid we see two
pieces matching in that polyloid
genome. Okay.
Now I've been showing you a lot of
cartoons. So let's start adding in some
real data on top of
that. So I study the trips which is this
subtribe of grasses in the
anthropogan. Um it includes two uh genre
that is tpticum which is a wild grass
that grows kind of um more in the United
States and and in more northern regions.
And then we have the genus Zia which is
mostly centered in Mexico and central um
America. And that's made up of a number
of wild species mostly annual um as well
as our domesticate maze.
And since maize is a very important
cultural and economic crop, we have a
lot of genomic resources including 26
genome assemblies that are chromosome
level and cover a wide range of
diversity including tropical and
temperate material, sweet corns,
popcorns, field corns. It's a good
encompassing of maze
diversity. Okay. And we know that it had
a whole genome duplication event about 5
to 12 million years ago. And we know
this because sorghum which has remained
diploid over that time. We see a 2:1
relationship when we align these genomes
to sorghum. So I know this is a
complicated figure. Um we're going to
walk through it. So along that x axis we
have our sorghum chromosomes lined up 1
through 10. And on that Y-axis we have
the maze chromosomes lined up also 1
through 10. And each of those circles
are representing areas of cintin that
had been identified. And so when we look
at sorghum chromosome 1, we see that
there's a full copy of it essentially in
the maze chromosome 1. We also see a
second copy of that sorghum chromosome 1
split up across the maze chromosome 5
and the maze chromosome 9. And so we see
this expected 2:1 relationship that
tells us that uh this was an ancient
polyloid at some
point.
Okay. So because we have all of these uh
many chromosome level assemblies for
maze, we've been able to study what's
happened to these subg genomes over
time. And so for instance, we know that
one of those subg genomes, the maze one
subg genome has been preferentially
retained while the other one has been
preferentially lost. And this is likely
due to functionality differences. genes
on the uh M1 subg genome are more
strongly expressed, right? And are
likely contributing more to traits than
the M2 genome.
Uh we also know that fractionation is
ongoing meaning that if you were to take
two maze lines and you look at a
particular uh pair of
homeologies are deleted but you might
see a different outcome in that other
maze line.
um suggesting that fractionation is not
something that happened just long ago
but is happening also um
today.
Okay. And I'm uh telling you about all
of this because there was this recent
project called the panandroprian project
that did a lot of genome assembly not
just in this subtribe but across the
entire tribe of the androbaganier which
is kind of warm seasoned
grasses and uh among these uh genomes
that were assembling included a
androagon virginicus which is a sister
species to sorum. It's wild. Um but it
has also remained deployed during this
time frame and so can be used as a
reference out group along with sorghum.
Um we also have two uh new tricome
genomes that are chromosome level as
well as multiple wild zia genomes. So we
can combine all of these wild um genomes
with our maze genomes and thus get an
unprecedented number of assemblies
representing descendants from the same
whole genome duplication event. I want
to reiterate this point because all of
the information that we have kind of uh
come to conclude about polyloids we have
done through studying polyloids from
different whole genome duplication
events and comparing across them.
Whereas this one, it's the same event,
but uh all of these descendants um have
have experienced just this
one. So this is really really exciting
because it allows us to ask two big
questions. One, how repeatable is
fractionation across all of these
lineages? Right? It's the exact same
event. How similar are their responses
to it? And two, we can start to ask
questions about when does fractionation
really occur relative to these species
diverging from each
other. And so we're going to focus on
this first question
first. So I told you that these are
chromosome level assemblies, right? And
they're some of the first for trips. And
so we're curious about how conserved
that cintony is between sorghum and
tpticum. And so important to understand
trum has 18 chromosomes and that
ancestral polyloid probably had 20. So
there's not been a huge reduction in
chromosome number only losing two
chromosomes.
And so when we compare it to sorghum,
each of these um ribbons are colored to
each of the 10 sorghum chromosomes. And
each ribbon represents cintony between
sorghum and the tricum genome. And
hopefully what you can see is that for
each sorghum
genome you uh chromosome I should say
excuse me um you see two trips
chromosomes right only a couple where
those chromosomes have been mashed
together right to have that reduction to
18 chromosomes.
Okay, so we see this massive
conservation of chromosome structure
between tpsum and its ancestral uh
polyloid. What about zia? How is that
different?
Right? So when we look at zia, right,
we're looking at 10
chromosomes which is very different from
trips. So there's been this massive
reduction in chromosome number. And the
way we get that is because when we
compare to sorghum, each maze chromosome
is basically a mosaic of many sorghum
chromosomes that have been mashed
together, right? And so we see these
huge chromosomeal rearrangements
relative to
sorghum.
Okay, but you might be asking yourself,
Sam, you said you had over 30 genomes.
You're only showing me two. What about
all those other ones? How does cintiny
to sorghum compare within and across
these genre? So at the bottom are our
two reference genome sorghum and
andropagenicus. And they're strongly
cintenic to each other. And likewise our
two types genomes are strongly synthetic
to each other as they are to both of our
reference out groups. Um and at the top
is that maze uh reference genome B73.
So I'm going to start adding in some
genomes. Let's start with our wild zeus
species diploinus and
nicaraguensus. Um we see that they show
lots of chromosomal rearrangements
relative to sorghum but are strongly
centenic to each
other. And as we add in uh the wild
relatives that are subspecies of ZMAS
such as carbaglamus, Mexicana and weii
tenensus
um we can see that there are some
inversions which are those bow ties. Um
but we still see that cinty is strongly
conserved across the and we can add in
the rest of our domesticated maze
genomes and hopefully you can see it's a
pretty consistent band of color across
all of these genomes.
indicating that we have really strong
conservation of syony within genre but
very different between
genre.
Okay. Now I also told you that this was
part of a larger data set and I would be
remiss if I didn't talk a little bit
about that. Um and so this larger data
set is looking at the whole angonier and
Michelle Stitzer um who's here in the
front row um has been looking at what
kind of has happened
uh
tribewide and so we have been focusing
on this one all genome duplication event
but when we look across the andagan
there have been many other polylo events
and here I'm just highlighting and red
the whole genome duplication events. And
when we look at the syony to
there guys
um what you should be
seeing is
um there is huge ribbons of color coming
down between each of these chromosomes.
Sorry, there's been some file formatting
uh struggles, but what you should see is
this kind of very conserved chromosomeal
structure across all of these genomes.
Um, indicating that they look a lot like
what we see in TPS. Another way of
saying that is that Zia is an outlier.
Um, at least in an observational sense,
if not a statistical sense. And I know
this isn't particularly uh convincing
but of that point but you can absolutely
convince yourself by looking at that QR
code which is the preprint for the
panropagan
paper. So um please check out that
preprint and believe me when I tell you
uh that that's what it
shows. Okay. So, let's focus back down
into our whole genome duplication event
in Zia. Um, and here we're really
focusing on these potential outcomes for
pairs of genes, right? Either they are
completely retained as duplicates within
a genome or one or the other have been
lost or both are
lost. And we identify these
fractionation events by looking for
deletions within the exxons of genes. So
the first thing we have to do is align
our genomes to sorghum um to identify
where deletions have happened in our uh
zeia and tricum genomes versus
sorghum. We also know that one of those
homeologues should be in the M1 subg
genome and the other should be in the M2
subg genome. and we can figure out which
is which using orthology and syony. We
then need to combine this information so
we know which homeologues had which
deletions um across each
genome. Basically making sure that we're
comparing blues to blues and reds to
reds across all of these
genomes. And we're looking at about
12,000 genes because while all our zeia
and trips genomes have been undergoing
fractionation, sorghum's been evolving
too, right? It it's not necessarily
exactly what it was, you know, 12
million years
ago. And so, uh, we use that other
reference out group,
identicus to come up with these gene
models that have the same number of
exxons across both of our reference, um,
genomes. And those exxons have the same
length. Basically saying we think that
these gene models are probably highly
conserved and are more likely to be
representative of what we would have
seen in that polyloid 12 million years
ago. And so these represent about 69,000
dex. And so just across genomes, when
we're thinking about how much of M1 and
M2 have been retained versus lost, we
see that M1 is preferentially retained
almost 60% to 40%.
and M2 is preferentially uh lost in
about the same kind of the reverse
um
proportions um suggesting that M1 has
been um the preferentially retained
across all of these genomes. And that's
exactly what we see when we now look at
pairs of exxons across each of these
genomes where if one of those exxons is
lost in a genome, more often than not,
it's the M1 that sticks around and it's
the M2 that's
lost. But you might also be looking at
that section of where we see pairs of
exxons retained that both retained. And
you might notice that our pink dots
which represent our tpsum genomes have a
much higher percentage of exxons
observed in that both retained category.
Um this suggests that tpticum has
retained more pairs of exxons and thus
has had less fractionation um or or loss
of DNA than
zia.
Okay, we've been talking about exxons,
but a lot of people they really want to
know what's happening at the gene level.
And so we can think about on average how
many exxons from a home log have been
lost. And we can break this down to
percentages because not all genes have
the same number of exxons, right? Keep
it standard. And so here in black we
have this reference um gene model for
three exxons. And we can think about if
one, two, or all three have been lost,
right? You would see 33, 66, and and
100%.
And so across each of these genomes,
what we find in both M1 and M2, the
majority of these homeologues have been
completely lost. There's no exxons left.
Um there is a bump um where only maybe a
little bit of the home log has been
deleted in M1, but for the most part we
see that the entire gene has been
deleted. Which brings us to this perhaps
philosophical question of at what point
do we consider a gene to be
fractionated? How much do you have to
lose before you're no longer a gene?
Right?
And I I don't have a satisfactory answer
for you to that particular question, but
I did try some different cutoffs. And
I'm going to show you the most extreme,
right? Um and so at the most liberal
cutoff, we consider a gene to be
fractionated if even a single exxon in
that gene has been fractionated. Even if
all the other ones are retained, only
one is is lost, then the entire gene is
considered lost. And as you would expect
under this very liberal definition, the
majority of our
exxons are considered lost. But we do
see a handful of genes that are
completely retained, right? Meaning they
still have all of their exxons available
to them.
Um and then the kind of opposite extreme
where every exxon in that gene has to be
lost for that gene to be considered
fractionated. Um we see right there is
this bump in terms of the number of
genes that are considered retained under
this very strict definition. But we
still see a strong amount of genes um
that are completely lost, meaning
there's no exxons left um of them in
these
genomes. So kind of the big thing that
you should take away from this
particular slide about genes is that
whole gene loss is a heck of a lot more
common than whole gene retention.
And this got me
wondering if an exxon or gene starts off
on one particular ancestral chromosome
um instead of another
chromosome. How often is the outcome of
that fractionation different? Right? So,
are you more likely to be retained if
you're say on chromosome 1 than if
you're on a different original
chromosome from um here
sorghum? And so what I'm showing you
here is for exxons and we take the
percentage of exxons found on that
reference chromosome in sorghum and we
say how many of those exxons are
considered both retained across our
genomes.
And what you can see is that if you're
on sorghum chromosome 1, you are
actually much more likely to be observed
as being both retained than any other
chromosome, particularly chromos sorghum
chromosome 5. Um, and so there's
actually a difference in terms of how
often genes are fractionated based off
of it seems which chromosome they
originate from.
And so, uh, we can see that, um, this is
true across many other of our
fractionation categories. And so,
there's this large variation between
ancestral chromosomes. Um, which brings
us to the big question, why why do we
see a difference? And again, I don't
have a particularly satisfactory answer
to that, but I do have a hypothesis.
And my hypothesis has to do with what
happened to those ancestral chromosomes.
Right? So when we're looking at the
syony of sorghum chromosome 1 versus
sorghum chromosome 5, we can see that
across both subg genomes, chromosome 1
and sorghum has been retained in pretty
large chunks. It's not very broken up
even in zia where there's been a lot of
rearrangements.
But chromosome 5 from sorum is really
sliced and diced. It's in really small
little bits and pieces. When you make
those dot plots for cinty, it looks like
confetti. They're so broken. And so I
think there might be this connection
between rearrangement histories of these
ancestral chromosomes and the amount of
fractionation that we observe
today. Okay. So to summarize our answers
to this first question, um what we find
is that all lineages do show this biased
retention of the M1 subgenome and that
fractionation tends to affect all of the
exxons within a
gene and that tsicum retains many more
homeologs than zia and that this perhaps
might be due to different chromosomeal
rearrangement histories.
Okay, so this brings us to our second
question of when did when did these
differences start? Um and and when did
all of this start to happen? And we can
look at this in a number of ways. The
first way I want to talk about is
parsimony, which is this idea that the
simplest solution is likely the correct
one. So if we were to take the our obser
our observed states of retained versus
lost um if you could only put that
fractionation event in one spot on the
tree where would the spot be that gives
us this observed pattern. So in the blue
case, we only see fractionation of an
exxon in a single species and so it must
have happened much more recently after
that species diverged from the others.
Whereas with the red copy, we see that
that fractionation event is found in two
of our uh genomes and so must have
happened early earlier right before
those species diverged from each other.
That's all we're doing here.
And so, um, we're only using exxons here
that have a definitive fractionation or
retention call across every genome. So,
we're not using the full 69,000 exxons
for this analysis. Um, but those that we
do use about 80% across both M1 and M2
are completely retained or completely
lost across every genome.
This suggests that the majority of
fractionation must have happened earlier
um before the divergence of trips and
zia about a little over half a million
years
ago. And about 10% of those exxons can't
be mapped to a single point on the tree.
Meaning that um you'd have to put down
multiple fractionation events to get to
our that observed pattern. And so we're
grouping all of those instances under
this term
paraphily. Okay. But if you're doing
your math, you might be asking me,
what's about the other
10%. Um, and so as we look at those
exxons that are fractionated across all
of Zia but retained in both of our
tricom genomes, we see that uh about 4%
of exxons fit that description. Whereas
the reverse exxons that have been lost
across both of our trips genomes and
retained across all of the Zia genomes
is only about
1%.
Um this is more evidence that trips has
experienced less fractionation than zia
and that this is likely due to increased
fractionation in zia after they um start
to diverge from each other. So after
that speciations
event. But that leaves us with the the
last 5% of
exxons. And um that is divided into
smaller and smaller increments where the
exxon is fractionated in either a
handful of lines or even just a single
um individual genome. And while these
percentages are low, it does mean that
recent fractionation was detected across
all lineages. And thus fractionation at
these exxons could be different across
genomes.
which gets us to this question of how do
you even measure that? Um, and gets us
to this term of differential
fractionation, which is just a way to
capture how different is fractionation
for a given locus across these
genomes. So, when things aren't
different at all, where every single
genome has the exact same status for an
exxon, we can say it has one status,
right? No differential fractionation.
But perhaps maybe when we look across
all genomes, we see two of these
potential statuses. Um, and that is a
little bit of differential
fractionation. And we can add and add
until we see all four statuses across
our genomes would be the most
differential fractionation that you
could possibly
observe.
Um, and so this is this is what I mean
by one, two, three, and four statuses.
And so here we have those statuses going
from um no differential fractionation
there at one to the most differential
fractionation that you could observe at
four. And each black point is the
percentage of exxons that we see in or
that particular number of statuses
across all of our genomes. And so the
majority of our exxons, right, only show
one um fractionation pattern um
indicating that it's all shared, right,
which we had just seen in our previous
analyses. But about 35% of these exxon
pairs show some differential
fractionation across genomes, right?
Which is pretty stunning. We weren't
expecting that at all. We're expecting
things to be very similar across these
genomes. But again, we've been talking
about exxons and everyone wants to know
what's happening at the gene level. So
here I have an example of some real
data. We have this sorghum gene that has
13 exxons and I've made a representative
of the M1 home log across a few of our
genomes where you can see perhaps in the
trips we see many of these exxons are
retained but exxon one and 10 are lost.
And when we look across our zia, we see
a lot more exxons are gone. Um, and just
a few are retained, if any at
all. And
so, as you're looking at this, you might
be wondering, how do you even begin to
summarize comparisons um across um the
sharing and differences of fractionation
and retention across all these different
genomes? Remember, we've got about 30
plus genomes and 12,000 genes to
evaluate. And so I've come up with this
particular system where you can have
these three levels where fractionation
has occurred in two genomes that you're
comparing. Um, if that fractionation is
completely shared, right, the exact same
exxons are lost across both genomes. We
call that complete sharing. Whereas if
only some of those exxons have been
fractionated in both genomes, it's just
some. And if some exxons are
fractionated in each genome, but they're
completely different exxons that are
lost, right? There's no overlap in which
genes or which exxons are lost. Um
that's no sharing. We can then also add
in the layer of how closely related are
the two genomes that we're comparing.
Right? So if they're the most closely
related, they're excessions of the same
species,
right? Um and on the other end of the
spectrum, we would be comparing a genome
from tricum versus a genome in Zia. And
in the middle, we'd have some comparison
of um genomes that aren't the same
species, but are not um but are in the
same genus, right?
So these are comparisons within our Zia
subspecies and and
species. Okay, I go through this to help
us understand this particular box plot
because there's a lot of information
here. Um and so when we are looking at
home logs where there's fractionation
occurring in both, but that
fractionation is completely shared in
the light pink and and light green at
the top here. we see that there's the
greatest amount of sharing. And these
represent comparisons between genomes
that are closely related, excessions of
the same species. And when we look at
kind of more diverged genomes, right,
comparisons between a tricum and a zia
genome, we see less complete sharing.
And as we look at more uh differential
um um sharing of fractionation
um or less sharing we see that um those
more diverged genomes so our trips
versus zia genomes show um are much more
prevalent in these categories where
there's less and less
sharing. Also note that it's very very
rare that none of the fractionation is
shared at all. Right?
Um most often when we see fractionation
between these um two genomes uh that
we're comparing there's at least some
overlap in which exxons are
lost.
Okay. Whenever we see patterns that are
either shared or different across
lineages, we want to know why. Why is
there sharing and why might there be
differences? And so this naturally comes
to the question of selection.
And dnds is a way of measuring
selection. Um so on this scale we have
uh dnds of zero refers to purifying
selection which is the removal of bad
alals from a population and at uh one or
much greater than one uh dnds that would
be positive selection. So promotion or
or uh keeping around really good alals
in a population.
Now if
uh differences or or changes between two
genomes, right, if those have a DNDs of
one, that means that those changes are
neutral, right? They're not under
selection. They might not have a
functional or a fitness effect, right?
And so any changes that we see there is
likely due to
random changes, right? Random drift.
Um and so when we look at those genes
that show complete sharing um between a
focal genome and any other genome, we
see that the majority of the DNDS values
that we have for those genes are at uh
centered on zero, right? Um meaning that
they're under purifying selection. So
selection is acting to remove
um uh u delletterious variance. But as
we look at um genes where uh they have
um less and less sharing between
genomes, we see that that distribution
moves further further away from zero and
closer to one. Meaning that they are
more likely under weakened or relaxed
purifying selection or are becoming more
neutral and thus affected by more random
changes.
Okay. So what does all of this even mean
in terms of when fractionation occurs,
right? So big picture, the majority of
fractionation is shared, right, across
all of these genomes, suggesting that it
happened before these species began to
diverge. So long, long
ago. However, we do see a large
proportion of exxons that show
differential fractionation, meaning that
fractionation is indeed ongoing. and at
larger scales than perhaps we
expected. And that sharing of
fractionation on a gene bygene basis
seems to be correlated with relatedness
with more related genomes sharing more
of the fractionation
um patterns and that this is any
differences that we see are likely being
driven by relaxed purifying selection.
Okay, now I know that was a lot and so
some big takeaways from this study is
that fractionation is much more dynamic
as a process than we really expected to
see. Um while the majority of
fractionation which was shared across
all of these genomes including the bias
retention of M1 over M2 homeolog um and
the loss of entire
homeologicum genus and members of the
Zia genus which we did not expect at
all. I can't emphasize that enough. we
really expected that all of these
lineages that descended from the same
whole genome duplication event would be
very similar to each other. Um and so we
hypothesized that these strong
differences might be related to
different chromosomeal rearrangement
histories between these two. And finally
um differences in these fractionation
between genomes are probably likely
driven by drift right and are correlated
with
relatedness. And it's usually at about
this point in any talk I give on this
subject that somebody asks this
question. What about sub and
neofunctionalization? Um, and you might
be saying, Sam, those are some really
big new words. Did you did you use those
in your talk? And I did not. I did
not because we really focused on
retention versus fractionation as the
potential outcomes of this downsizing.
But actually there are many outcomes for
duplicate genes after a polyploia event.
Um they can um be subfunctionalized
which is where that original function of
that gene is split across these two
copies either by each copy taking part
of of the original job or by becoming
tissue specific. So one gene is used for
that job in specific tissues and the
other gene is used in different tissues.
They could also become neofunctionalized
which is where one copy retains that
original function and the other copy is
allowed to mutate and generate um new
sequence and basically create a new
novel function. And these are really
cool. They're also really really
difficult to prove and require a lot of
molecular work to validate them. And so
I chose not to investigate them in this
study. That's not to say that these
aren't necessarily happening in these
genomes. Um, just to say that they would
be really hard to study. And I do have a
really great example of
neopunctionalization where they did do
that kind of validating work. So, if
you're excited about that, uh, this was
an instance of sodium ion channels um
that were duplicated after a whole
genome duplication event in fish. and
one of those copies of that sodium ion
channel uh
neofunctionalized to basically become an
electric sensory organ in
fish. So if you're interested in that,
highly recommend reading that paper.
It's really
cool. Okay, but it's not just maze,
right? We're plant biologists. We like
to think about all of all of the other
many uh diverse species available to us.
Um, and so what we can take away from
this beyond just what it means for maze
and its wild relatives is that polyloy
and fractionation have shaped every
plant genome through these multiple
rounds of expansion and downsizing. And
so a fractionation is much more dynamic
between descendants of the same event
than we previously expected. What does
that mean for all of our other polylo
events um and all of the descendants
from from those?
How um do we see that this connection
between chromosome stability and
fractionation when we look at across all
of these other um polyloids? Um what
might make chromosomes more stable than
others? And how we haven't even touched
life history or some of these other kind
of biological factors that might
influence these processes occurring at
the genome level.
And so since this is a plant breeding
symposium, I wanted to have this one
takeaway slide of what does this study
add to plant breeding. And so um
hopefully through this talk you've
gained an appreciation for how
fundamental these processes are for
generating the diversity and structure
of modern plant genomes. Um, and that
while many outcomes of these processes
are shared across lineages, descendants
of the same whole genome duplication
event may have very different outcomes
in terms of what diversity is kept or
lost. And finally, that these processes
develop novel, potentially adaptive
variation beyond what was available in
those parental
species. With that, I would like to
thank all of my funding agencies, um,
mainly NSF who have supported this work.
all of my wonderful co-authors and
labmates, my PhD committee members and
um the practical hletype graph team for
their help and support in completing
this work. I'd also be remiss as a
postoc not to mention that I'm working
on a completely new project with my
adviserss Jeff Rossy Barara and Graham
Cooper at UC Davis looking at human
domestication of maze as a bioultural
co-evolution. Um I'd be happy to discuss
this project more with folks um during
the social hour later. Um, but I just
wanted to mention that that's what I'm
working on
currently. And so with that, thank you
so much for your time and attention. I'd
be happy to take any of your questions.
We are over time, but I'll take like one
question.
All right.
Um, I wanted to ask what your greatest
challenge is in this
research and what you're most excited or
passionate about with this research.
Yeah. So, I think the hardest part about
this was developing the methods, right?
Trying to come up with a way to
accurately identify fractionation and
that it be the same fractionation across
each of these genomes. that was really
challenging um to use these tools um
that might not have been built for that
particular purpose. Um but I I use them
for it. Um and what I'm really excited
about is just the amazing diversity um
that we can study uh given all these new
genomes and genome assemblies. There's
so much big data out there. There's so
many cool questions that this data
allows us to address and answer from
basic biology that we previously
couldn't really get at. And so I'm
really excited about the the
opportunities that big data give us.
Cool. Thank you so much. One last round
of applause.
So we are approaching the end of the
symposium. I would like to thank all the
speakers for taking their time to come
all over to Ithaca and give these
wonderful presentations. uh I'm really
grateful to to them and also for uh the
audience I'm grateful to you for giving
your presence here and making this
symposium a success. Uh lastly I would
also like again like to thank my uh
planning committee members who have been
a a source of support to the symposium
and to me. Um with this I would like to
say that we have a social hour uh
outside and with this we can end the
symposium. Thank you.
This has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu.