this is a production of Cornell
University hello this is a closer look
at hemp micropropagation my name is Adam
Ganon and my wonderful partner for this
project was UD
Patel for a little bit of history on
hemp micropropagation uh there wasn't
really any published research on have
Micro propagation before the late 1990s
due to the illegal status of the
cannabis plant the first published work
was done by rali and mandolino in the
late '90s that I could
find and then as regulations and
legislation have become more lenient
research efforts on H micropropagation
have increased and gained traction into
the late 2000s the first systems for H
micro propagation being published in
2009 So currently all kinds of different
aspects of hemp propagation are studied
including different media types photo
period anoint synthesis genetic
variation among other
things and some great work has even been
done by our excellent teachers Dr virin
and
Victor so who would like to Mich
propagate
hemp first place I thought of was
nurseries and professional propagators
so this is becoming more specialized I
would say as the hemp industry continues
to legalize in different states and
countries but probably not yet a lot of
professional hemp propag
ators another place would be commercial
cultivators in the Cannabis space so
commercial cannabis operations may want
to use
micropropagation as a way to preserve
clean genetics uh these genetics could
be of high value for
them and then so obviously researchers
places like the USDA Cornell and several
other universities micropropagated hemp
for various research
purposes and finally maybe
hobbyists I had a friend I met back when
I started growing cannabis who was
trying to micro propagate hemp I don't
know four or five years ago uh just at
home still something I've never tried to
do I was impressed by that always but uh
do you know anyone who has done hemp M
micropropagation as a
hobby why would someone micro propagate
hemp there are many reasons to micro
propagate hemp so a few of these include
rapid clonal propagation genetic
preservation sanitation of a mother
stock space preservation Canon
production as a solution to poor
germination
rates so of these genetic preservation
and sanitation of the mother plants are
of growing importance in the commercial
cannabis industry right
now the first and one of the most
important steps in micropropagation is
selection of the source or a stock plant
um as mentioned in the previous slide
there could be many reasons to micro
propagate so selecting Source material
based on the right reason is the first
step
the stock plant or Source material has
been selected good sterilization
Protocols are utilized and specific
selections of the stock plant are
selected as xplants for further
culture here we will go over some common
supplied used in the micropropagation
process starting with the laminer flood
this workbench uses a continuous stream
of air pass through a HEPA filter to
maintain an Airborne contaminant free
space following that we have a petery
dish for easy propagule
handling the micro bead sterilizer uses
very hot glass beads to sterilize tools
between
usages in arranging in this picture we
have four steps of varying lengths along
with a small razor blade for ease of
cutting and this is a closeup of a set
of forceps that have tooth tips um I
find this particularly useful when
handling delicate
stems finally 70% ethanol is a simple
and cost effective way to sterilize a
workspace
for the containers in media we've had
good success with both test tubes and
magenta boxes the test tubes are
particularly good for long-term growth
since they accommodate hemp's vertical
growth habit while the magenta box is
nice since it offers a larger space to
start multiple cuttings in without all
of the extra hassle of setting up
individual culturing
vessels for the growth media uh Mig and
skoo has worked well for us
setting up your workspace correctly
within the flo hood is important to
avoid creating turbulent air currents
that might bring in contaminants
pictured on the left is a cluttered
bench toop while on the right adequate
space and clearance has been made to
allow for good air flow to understand
good Flowood technique let's take a look
at some examples of what not to do in
the first image Adam's Body is too far
into the flood and is likely causing
turbulent air currents over his
workspace in the middle image another
container is open under Adam's right arm
and he runs the risk of it being
contaminated as he works over
it in the final image the culture vessel
is being worked on too close to the edge
of the flood where its Effectiveness is
being
reduced good flood technique can be
summed up in the single image here we
can see Adam's Body is out of the flood
with the material being worked on deeper
within the hood and Adam's arms are
extended to work on the plants at that
location the container here is closed so
now accidental contamination can occur
before it is ready to be worked
with the micropropagation workflow
begins with removing the xplant onto a
clean work surface in our case we used
an autoclave petri dish the two forceps
were particularly useful when trying to
manipulate tender stems at this
stage to subculture our xplant we needed
a small fragment of the current plant
typically a segment with two nodes is
sufficient and here is the result of one
cutting being prepared for
subculturing now to add the prople to
the culture vessel it isn't necessary to
insert a node into the media the only
requirement is enough stem tissue is
inserted to hold the cutting upright as
it develops
Roots a crucial final step in the
micropropagation process is sealing and
labeling your containers sealing can be
done by wrapping plastic wrap or paril
at the lid to vessel Junction Point
labeling can either be done directly on
the container or the tray holding or
culture vessels
hemp's preferred lighting at this growth
stage is 100 to 300 ppfs per square
meter lighting should be kept at the 18
hours on 6 hours off Mark to ensure the
plants remain in a vegetative state and
don't start
flowering warm attempts are preferred 76
to 80° Fahrenheit is a good range um but
while the conditions I described are the
optimal ones hemp in the
micropropagation environment will
tolerate lower lighting and varying
temperatures to an extent
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu