this is a production of Cornell
[Music]
[Applause]
University here in the garden of the
meavy educational center three
cornellians came to build a piece of
community-minded living sculpture with
students to start the planning process
they made a list of goals for the
project and everyone agreed creating a
private and quiet shaded space would
draw community members to the area to
create this contemplative space they
built this tunnel and Dome from Willow
and
Dogwood the design of these pieces is
very nice the Dome sits within the curve
of the twisting tunnel and the entire
space is designed to maximize people's
interactions with the
sculptures while the layout of this
piece is interesting this sculpture is
seen better days this tunnel was created
using cuting of Willow and Dogwood which
were planted in the ground in the hopes
that they would grow roots and survive
this is a difficult practice because
fresh cuttings require a lot of water
and Care in order to become established
the more successful parts of the tunnel
are made from Willows like this one
which has survived because of its
thicker diameter one of the strengths of
living sculpture is the adaptability of
its components while this project may
not have turned out as planned this
tunnel and Dome are still effective
because plants like this bean vine and
these sunflowers are growing to fill in
the gaps it can be frustrating to work
with living materials but every project
has the potential to grow into something
new
[Music]
[Applause]
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu