this is a production of Cornell
University mention what my lab is
interested in is the interaction between
bacterial pathogens and plants and today
I'm going to talk about two different
projects in the lab one is focused on
the role of plant kinases in regulating
plant immune responses and the second um
is work on bacterial canker of tomato uh
disease that's caused by Asylum limiting
uh bacterium and some our work
understanding what regulates bacterial
virulence in that
system so um plants have a variety of
different associations um with
microorganisms uh in nature and also in
agriculture and this significantly
shapes plant health and productivity uh
in these Landscapes and so uh I'm sure
we're all aware that there are positive
associations between different
microorganisms and plants like that of
nitrogen fixing bacteria um or micro
risal fungi that enable nutrient acqu
position but what we're interested in uh
in my group are these negative
associations um or pathogens that can
infect plants and decrease uh crop
yields and so we work on some Leaf uh
Leaf pathogens like pseudomona singi and
we are also working on vascular
pathogens that can infect um uh tomato
uh as well as
citrus and one of the reasons why I
became interested um as a a younger
scientist in Plant Pathology and decided
to pursue that was because plant
pathogens can really significantly
impact agricultural production and in
addition uh there's always a lot of very
interesting plant diseases um that are
are continuously emerging as well as
really important longstanding diseases
so I've just Illustrated a few here um
so Banana uh is particularly problematic
uh for plant disease and it's currently
being affected by a number of different
fungal pathogens including microser
fijiensis
and this is because all banana uh that
we eat is clonally propagated and
derived from a single clone called
cendes so that makes breeding for
resistance uh very difficult because
there's no genetic diversity there to
draw from uh and so because of that
there's lots of fungicide sprays that
are sprayed aerially over uh banana
plantations multiple times even within a
week uh in a growing season uh another
really important disease is Citrus
Greening or Juan long Bing uh this is a
long-standing disease but it's emerged
recently within the United States um
it's severely impacted Citrus production
in Florida there's been about5 billion
dollars worth of loss in the last um
five or six years and it's thought that
almost all trees in Florida are now
infected uh it's transmitted by a sid uh
and it's very hard to control a flying
insect um and we now know that the
disease is present in Texas the SIDS
established in California um and there
are um disease trees within the Los
Angeles area and now we know that that's
spreading within the LA County area of
California um and uh uh so this is an
important uh emerging disease within the
US um there are also long-standing
diseases that still retain importance
like late blight of potato and tomato uh
caused by the OM phyto feses and here
you can see the um importance of genetic
resistance where you have one row of
potato uh that possesses an immune
receptor that can recognize the pathogen
and another row that uh lacks the
corresponding immune receptor and is
decimated by the disease so genetic
resistance can be quite robust the issue
is is that some immune receptors can be
rapidly overcome uh by the pathogen
population and then there's also been
quite a bit of basic research on plant
microb interactions that have really
significantly enhanced our understanding
um of genome engineering and editing in
Plants also hormone perception and um
receptor perception as well
so we work on the plant andate immune
system so plants don't actually have um
uh adaptive immunity like you and I do
they don't have specialized immune cells
that can circulate but what they do have
is a large number of germline encoded
receptors that can specifically
recognize all classes of pathogens so
there are receptors that are present on
the cell surface called pattern
recognition receptors that can
specifically recognize conserved
microbial features called pamps or Ms
examples of this would be uh bacterial
fuelin or fungal kiten um and these
surface localized receptors recognize
these microbial signatures as nonself uh
commonly function in conjunction with a
co- uh receptor and then elicit pattern
triggered immune responses uh and
resistance so um uh pathogens need to be
able to be adapted to inhibit uh plant
immune responses if they want to be able
to cause disease and one way that
pathogens can do this is by delivery of
pathogen proteins called affectors into
plant cells and these affectors um uh or
characterized affectors can disrupt
plant immune signaling they can Target
The receptors themselves or Downstream
immune signaling components um and these
affectors can still be recognized um in
certain plant genotypes by the presence
of plant resistance genes um I'll call
them nlrs but basically resistance Gene
and nlr can be interchangeable um
they're called nlrs because they have a
nucleotide binding site and C terminal
Lucine Rich repeats and these nlrs can
recognize the presence of pathogen
affectors trigger robust defense
responses and affector triggered
immunity and uh historically it was
thought that these are two distinct
branches of plant immune signaling but
now we know that it's kind of more of a
complicated web uh and there are sign
ific overlap in immune signaling
networks between PTI and
ETI and then plants also have large
arsenals of immune receptors so if you
look in uh plant genomes and you're just
looking at these um R proteins or nlrs
that can recognize uh intracellular
effectors they range on the low end of
about 54 in papaya um to the high end of
around a th and domesticated Apple um
and the repertoire differs significantly
even among different genotypes of a
particular plant uh there's also large
numbers of receptor like kinases or
receptor like proteins these do control
a range of processes but at least a
subset are going to be involved in
pathogen perception and in the model
plant to rabit opsis there are 600 of
these um and the number is just
increasing for nlrs as well with the
Advent of AR Ren seek uh to identify
more nlr receptors and
plants so in my lab we work on three
different p pathogens um and I'll talk
about two of them today
uh one disease that we work on is called
bacterial Speck um it's caused by Pamona
sinki path of Our tomato and it can
infect both tomato and a rabbit opsis
and cause these necrotic specs during
later stages of disease and that's where
the disease got its name we're primarily
um I'll Focus today on our work with
pseudomona singi and a rabid opsis uh
the other uh pathogen that we work on is
clav actor Michigan ensus and this
causes bacterial canker of tomato you
can see some of the symptoms here um
it's called canker because during later
stages of disease uh the bacteria will
induce the stem to split open and this
is caused called a canker where then
bacteria can ooze out and serve as a
secondary source of inoculant uh and if
there's a lot of bacteria around during
um flowering you can get fruit symptoms
as well and so here we're interested in
we've performed some genome sequencing
of a variety of different clava Michigan
Andis isolates and use that for um diag
diagnostic testing as well as to gain
insight into conserved viance mechanisms
present in caor and then I won't talk
about this project but I'd be happy to
talk with anyone afterwards uh we're
also working on Citrus Greening or Juan
Lang Bing um here we're primarily
interested in investigating the role of
secreted bacterial proteins called
affectors and what their plant targets
uh are during
infection so first I'll talk about PUD
singi and our work with the Rabbid opsis
and uh if you look at camonis singi um
it can be divided into different pathar
and each path ofar can cause a distinct
disease uh and pseudomonads in general
are pretty good epifit so if you go out
and surf uh sample the surface of a
plant leaf you'll see that pseudomonads
are a core component of the phosphere
microbiome but pathogenic pseudomonads
need to gain entry into the plant
interior in order to cause disease and
they can do this by swimming through
open stamata or wounds where then they
multiply in the apoplast or the space
between mesophile cells and if it's a
susceptible genotype that lacks
corresponding immune receptors you can
get quite High bacterial titer and then
visible uh disease
symptoms so first I want to talk about
our our work focusing on how uh these
intracellular uh nlr immune receptors
are
activated so these nlr receptors have a
conserved domain architecture they would
have either a coil coil or tier domain
at their end Terminus uh a nucleotide
binding site that could bind and hydy um
ATP and C terminal Lucine Rich repeats
and it's hypothesized at a resting state
the receptor is tightly bound and it's
bound to ADP and so uh if a receptor
directly recognizes an affector in their
cases of this uh what happens is um you
get exchange of ADP for ATP um this is a
switch for the active bound uh form of
the receptor so now it's on an on State
and can signal Downstream can also get
ATP hydrolysis to potentially recycle it
back uh to an inactive state in indirect
recognition the model is similar except
the affector is not directly recognized
rather the uh nlr guards a host Protein
that's targeted by the affector or a
mimic of a host Protein that's targeted
by the affector um and when the affector
targets and modifies this guarded
protein this acts as a switch for
receptor
activation and other outputs of affector
triggered immune responses in Plants um
are kind of shown here uh and outputs of
ETI are really if you're looking at uh
resistance or susceptibility it's more
of a quantitative phenotype than a
qualitative phenotype so you can see
here these are tobacco plants that have
the enge that recognizes um the portion
of the tobacco mosaic virus and you can
see these resistant uh tobacco plants
there's basically no um viral
proliferation but compared to
susceptible plants where you're looking
at gfp this is the presence of the virus
there uh similarly in bacterial
infection this uh arabidopsis line has
the rpm1 resistance uh nlr uh you
basically see no symptoms after uh
inoculation whereas susceptible
genotypes um look uh very diseased and
at the at the cellular level a common
Hallmark of effector triggered immune
responses is programed cell death at the
sight of infection so this plant if you
look under the microscope will have
patches of programed cell death um and
what we can do in the laboratory is go
in with a higher dose of pathogen and
then you can see macroscopic cell death
symptoms as
well so work in my lab has focused on uh
one key plant protein called ren4 ren4
is conserved across land plants and it's
been shown to be important for mediating
immune responses in lettuce tomato
soybean uh and also a rabid opsis and so
uh what we know about rin4 and a rabid
opsis from work in my lab and Brian
stt's lab also Jeff dangle lab and Dave
Mackey's lab is that uh it can associate
with several immune receptors and it's
also targeted by a number of different
bacterial effectors so uh at a ing State
rfor can associate um with the nlr rpm1
and rps2 holds it in an inactive State
um to suppress effector triggered immune
responses um but upon um delivery of the
bacterial effector avrb Rin for gets
phosphorated and Rin for phosphorilation
was hypothesized to be a trigger to
activate the rpm1 receptor leading to
effector triggered immunity so this is
an example of indirect recognition um
now we tried and several other
Laboratories tried quite hard to see if
avrb was a kise that would be the most
simple explanation uh but we were never
able to detect kise activity for avrb so
we thought there had to be another hose
kyes that might uh be playing a role and
what we did is we used Mass spectrometry
uh and imuno precipitation to pull down
the rin4 and rpm1 complex upon um
activation uh and upon delivery of avrb
and what we found uh is a kise called
Rip K and rip K is a receptor like
cytoplasmic kise um and we could show in
vitro that rip K can phosphorate Ren for
at three sites uh and we map those sites
by mass spectrometry 3 21 Serene 160 and
3166 and 321 and uh
3166 uh were conserved across rin4
homologues and land
plants and we had some evidence to
indicate that 3 166 would be a critical
region based on where it was within the
rin4 protein so we generated a phosphos
specific antibody that would recognize
phosphorilation of 3 166 and we can show
that during natural infection with
pomonis expressing avrb you get Rin for
phosphorilation at 31 166 total levels
of R for at this time Point don't change
and the bacterial effector is also
expressed and delivered uh then we used
a genetic approach to um uh determine
the importance of Ren for
phosphorilation for Activation of rpm1
so we changed these phosph phosphorated
residues and mimicked phosphorilation by
changing them to um aspartic acid and
then uh if we looked at the resulting uh
lines when we tried to complement rin4
if we mimic rfor phosphorilation you see
the plants are small dwarf they're
lesion mimic so this is a Hallmark for
constitutive activation of immune
responses um whereas if uh we cross
these lines into a genotype that did no
no longer possess the rpm1 immune
receptor these plants looked
phenotypically
normal and then um using transient
expression in N kosana we also um
determined what the critical residue was
uh that's required for uh recognition by
rpm1 and so here if we coexpress rpm1
with various versions of Ren 4 we can
see that coexpressing with a
phosphomimic of 3in 166 induces uh this
macroscopic hypersensitive response
which is a Hallmark of a factor
triggered
responses and then uh if you look at Ren
4 it doesn't look like it's an enzyme of
any kind uh although it's conserved um
and it has a high predicted level of
intrinsic Disorder so um we tested the
hypothesis that potentially
phosphorilation might change uh uh uh
secondary structure or some aspect of
flexibility we didn't see any change in
Gross secondary structure and what we
did is we what we we phosphorated for in
the presence of rip K using recombinant
proteins um then got rid of uh rip K uh
using centrifugation and then subjected
either phosphorated here or un
phosphorated Rin 4 to CD spectroscopy
and you can see here for wild type rin4
you get a peak uh at low wavelength and
that's cons consistent with this being
uh uh intrinsically disordered or random
coil protein uh and it you see a
stronger negative elasy uh in the
presence of phosphorilated Rin
indicating that it's a more flexible
protein see similar things if we're
looking at wow type rin4 or a foso uh
mytic mutant here by CD spectroscopy
um and then we also searched for
potentially other players that could
play a role in early recognition of rpm1
and this is a collaboration between my
group uh and Jim s group at Chinese
Academy of Sciences and what they
identified was a point mutation in a
cyclophilin uh that had enhanced
enzymatic activity uh but compromised
rpm1 mediated recognition so
cyclophilins are cyrans isomerases uh
and they catalyze this uh for pepal pral
bonds and this is a rate limiting step
during protein folding and if we looked
at this particular point mutation uh
within Rock one and we perform disease
assays using virulent bacteria here on
the y axis you can see
bacterial growth um on a log scale and
then this is days post inoculation you
can see there's not a difference between
wild type Colombia and The Rock one
point mutation or any null mutations
within uh uh nlr immune receptors but if
we look we could see a specific effect
uh after uh activation of rpm1 in
resistant plants uh and so what you can
see here is that Colombia can can
recognize avrb through the presence of
rpm1 so has much lower bacterial growth
than here um and then the rock one point
mutation was compromised in rpm1
recognition this here is the rpm1 uh
null
mutant and then we did some mapping of
the importance of uh Proline residues
across Ren 4 for activating rpm1 um and
mutated every single Proline residue and
first the graduate student that was
doing it I said don't don't do that
because that's going to grossly mess up
the the structure and you're going to
get a lot of uh results that aren't
going to be easy to interpret but I was
wrong because there was only one mutant
uh that uh gave a phenotype and that was
proline at position 149 so sometimes
it's good the students don't listen to
you and just go and do the
experiment so here what we've done is
we've taken a peptide of ren4
surrounding pein 149 labeled it and then
subjected that to NMR spectroscopy and
we can see that this is the general
structure
and then if we add in unlabeled Rock one
you're still only looking at Ren 4 what
we can see is specific
isomerization um here and here uh
surrounding Proline 149 so that
indicates that in vro uh Rock one can
isomerize Ren for at position uh 149 and
then we tested to see what's the effect
of this uh on the ability to induce Rin
for phosphorilation so first if we look
in Plants uh at this rock one point
mutation that has higher isomerization
capability uh that uh after delivery of
avrb we see much lower ability to induce
rin4 phosphorilation and if we delete uh
Proline 149 from Ren 4 we can see that
at a basil level you much you have much
higher basil phosphorilation uh of Ren
4 so this is our current model of rpm1
activation we know that rpm1 is at the
membrane um it can associate at a
resting state with rip K Rin 4 and rock
one and ren 4 is isomerized by Rock one
we predict at a resting state upon
delivery of
avrb um avrb can dimerize with um rip K
Rock one disassociates
rin4 is now in a Cy confirmation at its
pran 149 residue this uh enables
stronger phosphorilation uh via rip K
and then subsequently we know that rip K
and avrb disassociate from the complex
but rin4 and rpm1 stay at the membrane
and you get activation of rpm1 uh and
induction of Defense responses so um
this association with rock one enforces
the inactive State prior to recognition
because you want really close control
over uh activation of plant immune
responses because there's a energetic
cost to inducing immunity and enforces
actually the active state after
recognition so you get robust immune
responses there and and we've also done
some work to try to figure out why
affectors would actually Target rin4 in
the absence um uh uh of rpm1 so I
mentioned that there's a large number of
nlr immune receptors that are present in
plant genomes but um the nlr complement
can vary significantly depending on the
plant genotype so our hypothesis was
that in the absence of rpm1 ren4
phosphorilation would enhance bacterial
virulence and this would be maybe one
reason why multiple effectors would
Target RN 4 because it's not going to be
beneficial to them if it's inducing
immunity uh and so we able to show that
uh rinor mediated phosphorilation inside
mesil cells suppresses pattern triggered
immune responses so you get lower
extracellular Ros burst um altered M
kyes kinetics and increased growth of
non-adapted pathogens uh we were also
able to show a number of years ago on
this PL biology paper that Ren for can
associ with a plasma membrane pump
called aha um and uh what we found was
is that phosphorated Rin could more
strongly associate with Aha and induces
enhanced um uh activity and if you look
at plants that are phosph mimics for
ren4 what we see is that they have wider
basil stodal apertures and we also know
that avrb when you inoculate ponus
stringy expressing avrb it can also
manipulate stodel apertures uh upon
surfaces
inoculation so now I want to switch
gears and talk about another kinas that
we've been working on uh and this is pbl
13 and uh pbl 13 and rip K are closely
related they're both members of these
receptor like cytoplasmic kineses so uh
here is just a um a diagram of the
receptor likee kinases and you can see
these receptor like cytoplasmic kinases
uh their kinase domain is similar to the
rlks but they lack uh an extracellular
domain and there's a a number of
different um uh subfamilies within the
RLC Cas and one particular sub family
called subam 7 uh has been demonstrated
to be important in immunity uh in a
Rabbid opsis and so here is just the
philogyny of um subfam 7 and why we
became interested initially in pbl 13 is
because it's closely related uh to ripk
um and other members that are uh have
been intensely studied in this area are
also um uh PBS 5 and bi one and they all
belong to the sub family
7 but pbl 13 actually looks uh different
than these other rlck and that's because
um it has a unique amino acid repeat uh
of 15 amino acids that are repeated five
times at its C Terminus uh the rest of
the rlck looks very similar to other RLC
it has all of the um catalytic
subdomains that would You' predict it
would be an active k
uh it has a pilation motif at its in
Terminus and we've shown that it can go
to the membrane as well so a graduate
student in the lab Dan Lynn was um
focused on the role of pbl 13 and so he
obtained two different tdna insertion
lines in pb13 one's called pbl
13-1 and the other one which has a tdna
insertion right before this amino acid
repeat and it's a truncated alal uh and
the other is pbl 13-2 that has a tdna
insertion closer to the beginning of the
um Gene and is a true knockout and what
we found is that both tdna insertions
had identical disease phenotypes uh
which indicates that this C Terminus uh
is important for pbl 13 function and so
here is just phenotype after dip
inoculation with virulent pomonis you
can see Colombia's diseased you see
yellowing here uh whereas the tdna
insertion uh looks much better and if we
look um either by dip or after pressure
in filtration syringe infiltration we
can see that um these tdna insertion
lines uh exhibit enhanced disease
resistance so here's bacterial growth on
the y- axis and you can see uh both of
these have at least a log uh decrease in
bacterial growth so it's pretty strong
phenotype and we can complement um this
enhanced resistance phenotype uh by
adding in Wild type pbl
13 so it looks like pbl 13 is an active
kise um and indeed when we performed in
vitrinas activity assays with radio
labeled p32 we can see that it is an
active chinise uh we already knew rip K
is a chinise so we use this as a
positive control pbl 13 can uh Auto
phosphorate and trans phosphorate a
common kyes substrate and then uh if we
have this lysine mutant it's no longer
an active chinise and what we also
noticed is this is recant protein from
ecoli here while typ pbl 13 U migrated
abnormally large based on SDs page gels
whereas the kyes dead variant uh ran at
its predicted molecular weight and we
know that uh by treatment with SIP that
this is due to um heavy Auto
phosphorilation and then we tested the
importance of kinas activity uh for its
resistance phenotype and we can see that
the pbl 13's kinas activity is actually
functionally required because you can't
complement the enhanced disease
resistance phenotype by adding in a kyes
dead variant of pbl 13
so we were interested in what uh
residues within pbl 13 are actually
phosphorated so we subjected the protein
to mass spectrometry and mapped phosphor
related sites and what we could see is
there are few residues within the kise
domain that are phosphorated and uh
there the serine serine and thine but if
you look at the percentage of the
phosphopeptide distribution we can see
that the vast these this correlates to
one Spectra and round three Spectra
respectively uh but the vast majority of
phosphorilated residues are present
within this repeat region um and since
it's a repeat region it was a little bit
difficult to actually nail down
unambiguously what particular residues
were phosphorated so we used a few
different enzymes and we could get um
some uh unambiguous Spectra uh
indicating that likely this repeat of
threein
serene is phosphorated on most of the
repeats so we're interested now and why
actually pbl 13 is more resistant um we
hypothesize it's a negative regulator if
we look at um uh the plants they don't
actually look um uh phenotypically
different uh than wild type of rabid
opsis they don't have much higher levels
of salicylic acid um but we do think
that it and so there we think it's
actually uh but we do think it's a
negative regulator because it has such a
strong enhanced disease resistance
phenotype and we know that immune
responses have to be uh tightly
regulated there is a trade-off between
plant growth uh and plant defense and so
the timing and also the amplitude uh of
immune responses are tightly controlled
within the plant so these are just some
common outputs of plant immunity uh and
we looked at a few of them for pbl 13 so
one is you get this uh uh reactive
oxygen uh Ross burst this extracellular
Ross burst upon pathogen perception um
this is by an nadph oxidase this uh
extracellular Ross then serves as an
antimicrobial it can also uh lead to
cell wall reinforcement um and then
Downstream of immune perception very
early events also are this calcium
influx which is an important secondary
messenger you also get activation of
specific map kyes Cascades that lead to
um transcriptional reprogramming in the
nucleus so we looked at a few of these
Ross uh and map Kines activation and
what we're able to show is that the pbl
13 knockout has enhanced M induced Ross
burst uh so here what we do to measure
the Ross burst is we use luminol based
acid and so here you can see the sum of
the relative light units on the Y AIS
and then the different genotypes on the
x-axis so uh when we add in uh a
bacterial mamp called um L8 uh what we
see is that you can get uh rapid Ross
production in Colombia the pbl 13
knockout has higher Ross burst and this
can be complemented by when of the pbl
13 complementation lines um also uh if
we apply bacterial immunogenic epitope
of bacterial fuelin we can see that uh
Colombia can respond to this um the pbl
13 knockout has an enhanced response and
this can be complemented uh in the
complementation lines the next thing we
looked at uh was map kinas
activation and here what we can see is
that um this occurs between typically 10
and 15 minutes uh after uh applying uh
recognized microbial pattern here we're
looking at bacterial uh flag 22 um
application so you can see a strong
expression of phosphorated map kinases
around 15 minutes um after treatment but
we see faster um expression at 5 minutes
in the pbl 13 knockout and then this is
just the felin receptor mutant uh as a
negative control and so both of these
are very early processes this is going
to occur around 10 minutes after
bacterial or or pathogen perception the
Ross burst occurs you know five to uh at
least by five minutes after perception
so we think that this is going to be an
early
response so we are interested in this
Ross uh phenotype and um previous work
out of Jim anda's lab as well as Cal
Zip's lab had shown that a related
chinise called Bick one is involved uh
in phosphor lating the nadph oxidase
rbohd and rbohd is responsible for
producing this extracellular Ross uh it
produces a super oxide uh which is then
rapidly dismutated into hydrogen
peroxide and can serve as an
antimicrobial and what they were able to
show with Bick one is um after felin
perception B one is able to associate
with rbohd phosphorate it and this act
to Prime subsequent phosphorilation by
calcium dependent protein kinases uh
leading to enhanced activity so because
pbl 13 had an opposite phenotype as Vic
one we are interested in its association
with
RBD so here we're using a split
luciferase assay where you can take um
one protein and fuse it to one half of
luciferase another protein fuse it to
another half of luciferase and then if
they uh associate you can see um uh
luminescence within the plant and this
is transient expression in Nana so here
we can see that um pbl 13 can associate
with rbohd at a resting state but um
opposite to B one it rapidly
disassociates upon felin perception and
this is a negative control on aquaporin
that's also membrane localized uh to
show that there's no signal there we
also looked for associations by split
luciferase or coip between primary
immune receptors uh and pbl 13 and we
didn't detect
that so this is our current model uh for
pbl 13 function and I should also
mention that we know that pbl 13 can
phosphorate rbohd uh C Terminus as well
and we're currently mapping those sites
by mass spectrometry so we see that pbl
13 has enhanced disease resistance it
has a higher Ross burst and faster map
kyes kinetics um and we hypothesize that
it acts to suppress defense responses in
the absence of pathogen
perception uh it's Unique among rlck
because it has an extended SE terminal
domain that's heavily phosphorated at
least in vitro we're interested in
determining the importance uh in Vivo of
P bl13 C terminal
phosphorilation um and um we think that
it could compete with bi one to regulate
the extracellular Ros first so we know
there's different pools of pd13 within
the plant cell uh potentially one pool
could be involved in suppressing uh map
kinas activation because we know rth
first and map kinas perception can be
genetically uncoupled uh but there's a
pool of pbl 13 that can also associate
with rbohd potentially phosphor relating
it at novel sites in order to suppress
activ in the absence of pathogen
perception uh but in the presence uh of
pathogen perception or elicitors pbl 13
disassociates enabling bit one to come
in and phosphorate which then primes for
subsequent phosphorilation by calcium
dependent protein kinases uh and an
enhanced Ross burst uh upon pathogen
perception okay so now I'm going to
switch years and talk uh about uh the
final project uh and this is uh looking
at the interaction between a gram
positive bacterial pathogen clava
michiganensis subspecies michiganensis
uh and
tomato so uh this pathogen causes
bacterial canker of tomato I've just
shown some disease symptoms here it
proliferates in the xylon vessels uh and
if you uh look at an infected tomato
stem you can see Browning of the xylem
here uh there's also Leaf symptoms where
you can this is called Leaf firing stage
where where you can get marginal leaflet
necrosis uh which is a Hallmark of the
disease as well and then if there's a
lot of bacteria around flowering uh
during flowering you can get fruit
symptoms these are called Bird's eyee
spots because there's a black spot
surrounded by a white margin or Halo and
you can also get infection of the
vasculature of the fruit uh by the
pathogen as
well um sources of inoculum are infected
seeds uh infected tool staks or
transplants um the bacteria can also
survive several years on crop debris in
the field um and uh when you have this
canker formation what happens is the
bacteria then will ooze out get
bacterial streaming and in the presence
of water uh they can then move from one
plant to another plant so that can serve
as a secondary source of an ulum as
well so um uh CMM has a high GC content
uh it's xylem limited it's subjected to
International quarantine because it's
particularly problematic uh within um
Glass House Greenhouse production uh and
there's no genetic resistance in
commercial cultivars uh there have been
a few sources of resistance that have
been identified uh in Wild tomato
species but they're primarily associated
with altered um vascular morphology and
so they have negative Horticultural
attributes that are associated with them
so uh they haven't been successful and
then transferring those into cultivated
germ plasm so right now the control stat
strategy is sea disinfestation copper
sprays don't really work very well um
and uh in the literature there's one
completely finished reference genome uh
that was published a number of years ago
so what we are interested in doing is
collecting a large number of CMM strains
uh to represent the worldwide diversity
and then using philogyny to sequence a
number of these strains and so here is
just a map that's highlighting the
geographical distribution of these
different uh CMM strains so we collected
from six continents over about six
decades uh and then used philogyny of
five core housekeeping genes to try to
figure out which strains we really
wanted to
sequence so we sequenced uh a number of
different uh CMM strains um 34 uh
pathogenic strains and then five
saprophytes so there are closely related
um clava strains that are non-pathogenic
that are saprophytic so they kind of
hang out they'll uh grow a little bit
within the Tomato uh but they won't
cause disease but this is problematic
because then if a grower wants to test
to see if they have bacterial canker um
they these will light up with any kind
of currently based Eliza techniques so
um this is problematic for for Disease
Control uh and also if they detect that
there's actually um clav aaor there they
have to get rid of all of their plants
when it could be just sapric clavor um
now I mentioned that CMM has a high GC
content it's at least 72% so we did
aluminous sequencing um but that became
and and it also has a number of
repetitive elements uh within the genome
but we couldn't get great assemblies
just based on aluminous sequencing so
for a subset of these um we went in and
did uh pack bio sequencing as well uh
and there that worked quite well we were
able to get completely finished
reference genomes uh and completely uh
uh complete plasmid uh sequences just in
a single shot um so what I'll talk about
uh from now is mainly our work on the
pack bio sequences um and we also
sequenced um in this number of 34 uh
some CMM strains that were collected uh
within California as well so in
2011 uh and also uh 2015 what we had in
California was this Vine decline disease
which uh basically what we've found
right now is that it's a combination of
fungal infection of the roots uh as well
well as uh clava uh infection um which
combines to have a decrease in
productivity during later stages uh of
the disease and so most of the tomatoes
that are grown in California are for
processing um and UC Davis is in Yolo
County that's where they grow a lot of
tomatoes uh so we've collected a number
of isolates just right around the
university in collaboration with Farm
advisers and also the sanwa valley grows
quite a bit of uh Tomatoes as well
so um what we first looked at were the
plasmid complements um and as I
mentioned there're saprophytic claba so
this is one of the saites we sequenced
you can inoculate but you don't see
disease symptoms uh plants look healthy
um this is one of the pathogenic uh
strains that we sequenced and this is
the reference genome that's been uh
studied the most so the reference genome
has two plasmas pcm1 and pcm2 um both
are required for uh disease symptoms so
you can delete these uh from The genome
or or cure them from the
bacteria bacteria can still replicate
but they don't cause wilting symptoms um
what we found was there's a variation in
plasmid complement uh among the strains
that we've sequenced which is really
similar to what uh has been found for uh
uh some of the strains that have come
out of Cornell as well um and around the
the Cornell area and in New York uh so
they have vary in their plasmid
complement all the strands that we
sequenced have pcm1 um um but there's
variation in the presence of pcm2 Andor
presence of other plasmas um and sapres
have neither pcm1 or pcm2 but they have
a novel uh plasmid uh that we call PCM
sap and if you look at this circos plot
of the reference strain in one of the
California strands for pcm1 it's similar
for others you can see that uh these
lines here indicate that U there's
homology and those genes are present uh
there's there's High homology between um
sap the other strains uh and the
reference strain with respect to pcm1
and if you look at bacterial growth um
PCM uh 2 is not necessary because this
California strain can grow quite well
just as well as the reference strain and
then like I mentioned the sapry will
grow a little bit but not to the same
extent so we looked at the The genome to
predict uh secreted affector proteins so
this is a gr positive bacteria so um it
can't deliver affectors directly into
host cells but it can secrete affectors
direct outside of its own cell uh and so
what we found when we were mining for
the serrone is that there's a set of
about 40 affectors uh that are conserved
across pathogens and sapres there is
also around 10 that are only found in
all the pathogens that we looked at and
then there's a variable number of
effectors as well if we look at these
conserved effectors most of them look
like uh that at least that that have
been have assigned potential fun
function would be degradative enzymes or
secreted
proteases then we also looked at the
presence of genomic islands and so
bacteria can acquire um uh uh DNA
horizontally either through conjugation
for plasmids viral infection or um uh
through the environment and this can be
detected uh based on their uh deviation
and GC content so if we look at the
genomic Islands present U between sapres
pathogens and Cal California and
pathogens in the reference drain we can
see that most there's only one large
genomic Island that's present um both uh
in the reference strain as well as all
the other strains that we um sequenced
and the other genomic islands are
variable and the genomic Island that's
uh conserved is called the CHP T
pathogenicity cluster so I've just
highlighted it here and you can see it's
quite conserved um uh across the
reference strain this is one of the
California strains and this is the sapry
where it's lacking so there's been some
work that's been done on CHP Tom uh on
in clav aactor we know if you delete the
entire genomic Island it abolishes
pathogenicity if you delete uh just chpc
which is shown here in yellow um this is
a Serene protease it's secreted um that
decreases virulence um and what we are
interested in is what about some
degradative enzymes because you do get
this canker formation there's mation of
the host tissue you get the stem
splitting open during later stages of
disease and we know that the genome
encodes several putative degradative
enzymes um and so we focused on the
importance of two um potential
degradative enzymes Pelle 1 and Pelle 2
that are conserved that are pectate
liases so if we look at Pelle 1 and
Pelle 2 they're predicted to be secreted
they have a a central and this is
cleaved then afterwards we have a
central pectate lias domain um if we
look at crystallized pectate liases we
can generate high confidence uh models
it really looks like a pectate lias the
uh catalytic sites are conserved between
Pelle 1 Pelle 2 and characterize pectate
liasis um and then if we perform
Knockouts uh of either Pelle one or
Pelle 2 what we can see is that the
Pelle one deletion um in clavor has
reduced symptom morphology we don't see
this Leaf firing stage whereas the Pelle
2 deletion doesn't really affect uh
bacterial virulence and we can see a
decrease in bacterial growth uh but it's
not very robust here so this may be
affecting symptom morphology and not
necessarily bacterial colonization but
we need to go back in and look over time
and potentially look at movement within
the plant as
well uh and then if we look at
expression of Pelle 1 and Pelle 2 uh if
we look in rich media both are expressed
to fairly low level but if we look uh
and grow the bacteria in xylm mimicking
media minimal media we can see that
Pelle 1 uh is much stronger expressed
than Pelle 2 uh and Pelle 1 the deletion
is the one that gives us a phenotype
after we inoculate on
tomato so we've also used um these
genome sequences to try to develop uh
diagnostic primers for Growers and
Industry to use um so what we did is we
looked at um our genome sequences of
pathogenic clav actor sapric clav aactor
we also sequence some genomes of a
related pathogen um subspecies
sepedonicus that causes potato ring rot
um and we designed about 10 different
PCR based primers uh that should
specifically detect uh pathogenic clava
but not saprophytes and then we found
two that very robustly amplify and
looked quite specific uh one is based on
a sugar ABC transporter the other is
based on a transcriptional regulator and
so uh We've provided these to Growers uh
to now use uh for Diagnostics where they
wouldn't detect uh these sapres or other
pathogens so uh just to summarize we've
completely finished genomes for about
seven um uh CMM strings using pack bio
uh use that to develop specific PCR
primers we know these strains are not
clonal there's variation in plasma
composition genomic Islands also uh in
secretome uh we can see there's about 10
core secreted uh proteins uh from uh
clav aactor and we' started to
investigate a subset of these secreted
proteins for their role in bacterial
virulence um the conserved uh Pelle one
pectate lias is important for bacterial
symptom morphology but deletion of a
clustered and closely related um pectate
lice Pelle 2 has no effect and that may
be because it's not robustly expressed
during
infection so I'd like to thank the
people in the lab that have done the
work um work on on Ren 4 was uh
initially started by Jun Lee AE previous
postdoc in the lab who's now faculty
member at Chinese Academy of Sciences um
and also uh dung hulley a graduate
student has worked on that project as
well work on pbl 13 was led by a former
graduate student Dan Lynn um as well as
D huley and then um work on uh clab of
actor has been performed uh by a post in
the lab sharit tapa and then Coast uh
Thomas and Jessica have also contributed
to the ren4 project um also I'd like to
thank my collaborators and then uh
funding uh for support so thank
[Applause]
you you know so the question wasc pbl 13
and ripk are closely related but it
seems like they have different functions
uh so the question was are they
functionally redundant um initially the
reason why we were interested in PD 13
is we thought that it could be um uh
functionally redundant with rip you
might be able to get more severe
phenotypes when we made uh higher order
mutants and we we tried that so we have
double mutants of PDL 13 and rip K but
we don't see that there uh is more of a
significant phenotype let's say with
respect to activation uh of rpm1 or loss
of rpm1 activation than just the rip ke
knockout so I think they're actually
doing uh different things uh if you just
look at the the central region it looks
very very similar to uh rip K so what
we're trying to do now is just take um
pbl 13 central region and if we and see
if we can complement The ripk Knockout
just with that as compared with fand um
but I think there's something that's
going on with the c Terminus that might
determine specificity um we're also
doing some kise assays with truncated
pbl 13 versus full length to see if that
changes um ability to uh phosphorate
particular residues uh within Target
do you know anything about their
expression Express tis yeah so rip K is
uh expressed in strongly in the root and
also within the uh the leaves but more
strongly in the root um and it has a
much higher expression than pd13 so pd13
is very lowly expressed um in the root
as well as in uh uh the leaf and in
cessing
tissues U but it's its expression level
is quite low
disase certainly has no commercial value
it oh okay so the question was for
citrus Greening is it edible after
infection
well um in the juicing industry for
Florida uh they can do certain things to
um uh the juice like add sugars Etc and
then that will uh still enable them to
sell uh the product you know during
later stages of disease it's going to
kill the Citrus plant so then obviously
yield will be reduced but um part of the
phenotypes for citrus Greening and why
they they called it Citrus Greening is
that you get this um inversion of uh rip
the ripening of the fruit so usually uh
it'll ripen at the bottom first and then
go up and then here when you have citrus
Greening you have green at the bottom
and then ripening at the top you get the
pathogen proliferates in the FL
and so you get more bitter fruit uh
because uh there's flow blockage uh by
uh Callos and so there's decreased uh
sugar accumulation within the fruit so
it's possible to do some things uh for
uh it's juicing industry for a fresh
market there's not much you can
do so the question is if the um pbl 13's
General function is to dampen Ross as
the mutant have phenotypes in addition
to defense responses um so that's a good
question we're looking at that right now
so some of these rboh mutants have
altered root morphology Etc we know that
pbl 13 is uh expressed in Roots and so I
don't have the answer uh now but we're
looking into it to see if they can
phenocopy uh some of those uh mutant
phenotypes yeah and if they do then that
would I think that would indicate that
there may be um additional functions for
p 13 outside of just depend responses
[Applause]
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu