this is a production of Cornell
University thank you so much I'm not
sure I know the guy that he was talking
about um it's a pleasure to be here um
and I thought maybe the way to start
this off would be to give you a sense of
my personal Journey uh I I got my
masters and PhD in astrophysics at a
university called University of
Pennsylvania
I I recognize him at
Cornell um and I was I was working in
planetary science for a little more than
a decade and a half and I decided to
make a switch to full-time National
Science Education um I I've always been
fond of both research and education I I
remember uh when I was in high school I
worked as an amenis for the New York
State Department of Vocational
Rehabilitation working with uh very
physically disabled students who were
brilliant trying to take them to the
next level up and um I felt that
education was just so vitally important
to what it meant to be me that when I
had a chance to uh after my my PhD I had
an opportunity to work as a NASA I'm
sorry a National Resources Council
postdoc at Goddard space flight center
or help establish a lab for astrophysics
at the National Air and Space Museum
which is the most visited Museum on the
planet and I gave up the NRC postto and
my my thesis adviser said nobody gives
up an NRC postto what are you doing but
to to be able to do research at the
Smithsonian and also be able to tell
kids about it and teachers about it and
families about what it's like to be a
researcher um was really really
important to me because research and
education went hand in hand and so maybe
what I I I should really start off by
telling you a little bit about the the
emotional experience behind uh what I
did as a researcher and I can tell you
that um my friends and I at Goddard
space flight center had to build a very
special machine called an infrared
heterodon spectrometer this was my
graduate work at Godard space flight
center and we would take this machine
which would fill a nice-sized classroom
it was a big machine um out into the
middle of the Pacific Basin and we would
take it to the top of Mona which is on
the big island of Hawaii we take it up
14,000 ft almost 3 miles into the sky
hook it to some of the most powerful
telescopes on planet Earth point it to
planets tens of millions of miles away
and we would uh measure temperature and
composition of the atmosphere and the
Very Special laser system that I built
which was my baby allowed us to measure
gentle breezes on these planets so we
were able to build um the a model of the
global circulation the global winds of
of these planets and so I was sort of
like an interplanetary weather guy and
and uh I could talk hours about why you
would want to do that why you would want
to look at weather across the family of
Worlds as a means of getting a better
understanding of what drives weather
here on Earth but I really wanted to
talk about the emotional context of what
it was like on Mona and in fact I have a
slide of
this this is the summit of Mona and you
you see some of the most powerful
telescopes on Earth um this is the kek 1
and 2 telescopes this is the telescope
that we used back in the mid 1980s
through the early 1990s it's the NASA
infrared telescope facility and um the
the summit of mon is really interesting
because let's see this is
Subaru this is the Japanese national
telescope does anybody know why it's
called
Subaru what do you see on the back of a
Subaru it wasn't named after the car
what do you see on the back of a Subaru
what's the symbol stars in Japanese
Subaru means the ple
and so this is the Japanese national
telescope and you go up to the summit of
Mona and uh you go up um towards the
afternoon um right after dinner which is
your first meal of the day and you work
all night and you come back down and you
go and have breakfast just before you go
to sleep and you have breakfast with
people working from all over planet
Earth I mean scientists from from every
corner of this planet and you you sit
down over breakfast and you talk about
what you're researching and somebody
might be looking at planetary
atmospheres or somebody might be looking
for planets around other stars and how
the universe was born or how stars form
and it's just a remarkable experience
because this place knows no this place
knows no National boundaries it's about
Humanity pushing the envelope and so a
few years back a teacher came to me at a
professional development she said what
does it feel like to work on the summit
of Mona what does it feel like to do
research up there and and so I I thought
about that and I came up with really
three levels of emotion that you feel on
the summit um the first thing that's
really remarkable is that when you go um
to the summit of mon and the puffy white
cumulus clouds roll in they roll in a
mile below your feet so you're like on a
rock floating in the middle of the sky
and when the sun sets and the sunsets
are absolutely
spectacular um countless Stars 10,000
Stars fill the heavens and if you've
been to a dark here on the surface of
the Earth and went oh wow looking up at
the at the heavens that's nothing
compared to what you see at 14,000 F
feet almost three miles into the sky and
so here you are on the highest point on
Earth looking out into the universe the
Milky Way galaxy are the is this double
band of white that just Arches from
Heaven to Heaven 10,000 Stars fill your
sky and the only word that I've ever
come up with that has some chance of
describing what you feel in that moment
is Majesty you are standing here looking
out at majesty and what's really
remarkable about that story is that
you're not looking at it from the
outside you're part of it and it's part
of you which means that you are the
universe contemplating
itself that's a remarkable statement but
it's absolutely true and the next level
of emotion that you feel is when you
shift your gaze down to the Horizon you
see all of these these instruments of
exploration this this this set of
powerful telescopes that peer to the
edge of the known universe and you get
this overwhelming sense of history that
standing on the shoulders of past
Generations this is what we are doing
that you are part of a legacy of human
exploration and the way that it works is
quite remarkable because every gen
generation adds to the body of knowledge
every generation grows frail and every
generation in that moment reaches down
to the children and says it's your turn
to take us where we've never been it's
it's your turn and be content in knowing
that all of the knowledge that was
passed to me by prior Generations I give
to you and all of the knowledge that
I've acquired in my my generation and my
time I give to you take us where we've
never been before and and after all of
that sweat and toil this is the state of
human exploration pushing back the
envelope of human understanding in terms
of Earth's place in a greater
space the the third level of motion is
is really personal and I guess it
happened when I the the laser system
that I I built is really pnic it's got
um a detector that has to have a it has
to be kept cold at liquid nitrogen
temperatures um the laser itself has
Mirrors On actuators where the actuators
have to have a certain high voltage
feedback on them and so you're
constantly babying this thing and so in
the middle of the night some something
like 300 or 4 in the morning while my
friend is controlling this massive
telescope with a joystick we were
looking at Venus at the time and there's
this big image of Venus on the TV
monitor with a Crosshair as to where
we're we're taking the data I'm I'm
sitting there playing on on my laser
getting it all you know all back to
normal and I realized hey this is really
cool look what you're doing you're
seeing the For the First Time The Winds
of Mars The Winds of Venus and you
started out in Little Red Train Nursery
School I remember that moment I said I
started out and I I when when kids when
I if I go to a classroom and they say
where do you go to school I say well I
started in little red tray nursery
school and they kind of Grimace because
they they're trying to figure out what
university you went to but the point is
I started out in little red tray nursery
school and I figured out those gifts
that I had and those things that I love
and I worked at them and I got to a
point where I I made decisions along the
way I got to the point where I was on
the frontier of human exploration and
every time I took a personal step to
places I've never been I took the entire
entire human race with me That's What
exploration is all about and it doesn't
matter if it's science or art or poetry
if you put brush to canvas in a way
nobody's ever done before or Pros to
paper in in a way that nobody's ever
done before or in in Athletics you you
do something that's quite remarkable
you're pushing the envelope for the
human race you're taking us all where
we've never been before and what I
realized was the power of one that one
person has the ability to set their
sights in a in a certain direction and
take the race where we've never been the
power of one and so those three levels
of emotion again are the sense that
you're part of this this universe this
Majesty
and and you have the ability to reveal
how she operates you've got this sense
that you're part of a lineage of human
explorers that we've been doing this for
countless generations and working
together we're doing remarkable things
and you get a sense that just one person
has the ability to do something quite
powerful and
extraordinary I'm describing
science and I think that you hear in my
voice a level of emotion which you know
goes contrary to the way you normally
picture scientists right look I don't
wear a pocket protector I don't have a
white lab coat um I I know a lot of my
friends do have white lab coats but I
don't associate with pocket protectors I
don't no that's not true I just don't
have one um but the the the point though
is that science is a very emotional
experience and in fact let me broaden
that to human exploration in general
because in a little while I'll talk
about about science and I think the
point that I really need to make is that
science the the scientific method which
by the way is taught badly often as a
rigid recipe for success as opposed to
an art form the scientific method is a
misnomer because science doesn't own it
it's the way we learn it's the way we
explore and that's discipline
independent
so let me just say and let me ask if if
you have the definitions down because I
want to tell you a little story very
fast is the Sun a
star how many folks are are science
Majors uh I was going to say education
well education
undergrads maybe sort of you're kind of
you're on the fence okay what who else
is
here this is an audience participation
situation education gra education grad
students anybody else science grad
students science grad students okay so
good good mix so I have to ask this qu
these questions because it's a good mix
is the sun a
star like the stars in the sky yes
sure okay why does the sun look so
different why does it look so big and
bright because it's really really really
really close right what's a Galaxy if
you're all stars what do you call it
when stars like to hold together Galaxy
and our galaxy is the Milky Way okay
good so here's the story you all live in
Ithaca New York and a in an apartment or
a dorm or a house in the state of of of
New York in the United States of America
on a continent called North America on a
planet called Earth in a planetary
system called the solar system which is
the family of a tiny little dwarf star
we call the sun in the local solar
neighborhood in the Orion spur of the
Milky Way galaxy
a Galaxy by the way which has enough
stars to give 50 stars to every human
being on earth and the Milky Way galaxy
is in the local group of galaxies next
to the Virgo cluster of 1,500 galaxies
part of the Virgo super cluster of
50,000 galaxies which makes up the tiny
little sliver of the universe that
nature allows us to see called the
observable universe and that is your
address that's your
address and I by the way think it's high
time that every child on this planet is
given the opportunity to learn that
address because the human race needs
quite a bit of
humility um a good way to say it is we
all walk around like ships on the
ocean at the
center of a horizon a personal Horizon
and we have the hubris to say that
that's the center of the universe let me
say that again we all walk around dayto
day at just like ships on the ocean at
the center of a personal Horizon we
could see out in all directions
uniformly and we have the hubris to
think that that's the center of the
universe it's the center of your
universe and I think it's important for
us to have a better understanding of
Earth in a greater space um so let me
let me now just quickly did you like
that story so far okay let me just
quickly show that to you in photographs
this
is this is the nature of our existence
and if you go above Earth's atmosphere
you get to see the The Starry Sky this
uh and one star looks big and bright
that's the sun in a natural context the
sun is just another star it only looks
so big and bright because it's really
close and it's a small star a million
Earths can fit inside the Sun a million
Earths can fit inside the sun does
anybody know the name of that star in
the shoulder of
Orion Beetlejuice 800 million ion Suns
fit in the star Beetle
Juice 800 million if you put Beetle
Juice where the sun is now we'd be
inside it it would swallow the orbits of
Mercury Venus Earth Mars and Jupiter
pretty
cool okay here
is a picture of the Earth from space
this this spaceship with all known life
aboard where water air and land conspire
to give rise to life whether it's a
bacterium that calls a drop of water
home or a blue whale that calls an ocean
ocean a home this spaceship is teeming
with life and here is a photograph of
the continental United States and and
what you see is is California is in
daylight and there's the Pacific
Nightfall sweeps Westward at about 700
mph at this latitude and in its wake we
can see ourselves the entire Eastern
Seaboard lit up with
Humanity that's us at
night and here is a photograph taken not
too long ago a few months ago by the
Solar Dynamics of Observatory of the sun
burping and that's the actual size of
us and here's a photograph taken by the
messenger spacecraft in January of 2008
as it rounded the side of mercury the
human race had never seen and this craft
came from the earth it came from a tiny
little blue World which is right there
that's you from
Mercury and here is uh a photo uh this
is a digital image uh of what the vo let
me say it differently in February of
1990 the Voyager spacecraft was just
beyond the orbit of Pluto and a
Gentleman who you may recognize Carl
San suggested that the Voyager
spacecraft turn its camera platform back
and image the solar system from the
outside or at least outside of the
planetary domain for the first time in
history he actually got push back for
that but he was successful
and so these are the photos that the
these are these are the orbits of the
planets from Voyager vantage point in
February of 1990 here are the photos it
was going to take to to look at Neptune
and Uranus and Saturn and Mars um and
and Earth is in here um and here are the
actual
photographs and there is Neptune and
Uranus and Saturn and Venus Mars was
actually not in the photo um uh Jupiter
and ladies and gentlemen that's
you Voyager is traveling at 40,000 miles
an hour that's twice as fast as the
International Space Station or the space
shuttle it could orbit the earth it
could go around the earth at that speed
in 45 minutes and at this incredible
speed to get to a nearby star will take
80,000 years 880,000 years and that's
just two stars us and a nearby star
there are enough stars in the Milky Way
galaxy to give 50 to every human being
on planet Earth and we now know that the
vast majority of those stars have
planets of them of their own and so this
is
you from from near Earth from from near
space and if you go out into the Milky
Way galaxy you see these clouds of gas
and dust from which stars are born
called nebula and here are a few Milky
Way stars that get in the photograph and
this is known as the Eagle Nebula and
here's a picture up close by the Hubble
Space Telescope of this region here and
these little pink things are solar
systems that have just been born we're
seeing where we came from this is an
entire solar system planets and star
being born and what I'm about to show
you is a photograph in the direction of
Sagittarius of the closest star to us
proximus inor it's in the very center of
the photo and if you take a picture of
proximus centor a few Milky Way stars
get in the
way and you know this is like 50 stars
and this is like 50 stars and 50 stars
and 50 stars so how many blocks of 50
maybe 15 and 15 across 225 blocks of 50
stars this is Enough stars to give 225
people 50 of their very own that's all
this is nothing this is less than
nothing and you see that star right
there I think somebody's looking back NE
next time you look up at the night sky
think about this I firmly believe
somebody's looking back
and this is what we think we would see
if we left our home Galaxy looking in
from the outside this is what 300
billion Suns looks like from The Edge
and if you look from above we'd see
something like this it's a spiral galaxy
where the spiral arms are the sights of
star formation and
this is a really cool photograph because
there's a star because I can see the the
the the the the the the the the spikes
over here the crossed spikes
and here's a
star
and I'm losing sight of any others maybe
this one looks like a star over here
what are
these These are
galaxies these are all galaxies every
one of these galaxies on average has
enough stars to give 50 to every person
on
Earth and you know how many galaxies we
think are in the observable
universe enough galaxies to give 50
galaxies to every person on are you
feeling small
yet and here is is another photograph of
galaxies and and so has anybody ever
read Horton her a who by Dr Seuss my
favorite book by
far I say murmured hor Horton I've never
heard tell of a small Speck of dust that
is able to yell so you know what I think
why I think that there must be someone
on top of that small Speck of dust some
sort of a creature of very small size
too small to be seen by an elephant's
eyes we are the who's in hooville and if
you read that book you know that the
who's were calling out from a speck of
dust and Horton was listening with his
with his incredible hearing and he was
having this conversation with The Who
and hille the mayor of houille and he
spent the rest of the book trying to
convince the jungle creatures he wasn't
a crazy elephant where are the who's in
Whoville and we're calling out to the
rest of the universe not only with
spacecraft but ever since Marone turned
on the radio in 1896 radio and then
television have been moving out at the
speed of light and thousands of stars
are now bathed in human signal we're
calling out just like the who's and
Whoville and I think
that the real question that that you
have to ask in all of this how did how
did we re reveal all this from this tiny
little world the story that I told you
that I started off by saying hey I'm on
the summit of Mona I'm looking out into
majesty and then I Tred to convince you
by telling you your address and walking
through those images yes it is a a
majestic Universe how did we reveal all
that let me say it a little differently
how did we reveal all that with
something the size of this
something the size of this gave rise to
that story where did it come
from what process did we use
exploration
exploration what is
exploration what is human exploration
what are the fundamentals of how we
approach pulling back the veil of nature
on any facet of the universe and seeing
how she operates sort of a rhetorical
question not completely
yes asking
questions
observation anything else Discovery
Discovery curiosity curiosity inqu
inquiry we're just I'm just
Fielding words here okay listen to all
these words they're all very powerful
anything
else all right let me go on to the next
next chapter
why do we go to
school I'm I'm I'm now going to walk you
through my view of how we revealed the
Majesty of the universe that story why
do we go to school why do you go to
school think
about kindergarten Elementary School
think about college your your college
career here at Cornell why do you go to
school I'm not going to bite I swear I'm
not going to
bite there's no wrong answer what to
learn how to learn to learn how to learn
I would argue you already know how to
learn it just takes a little bit of
coaxing anybody else why do you go to
school okay here let let me let me
switch roles puff I know you're not
going to want want to do this but you're
all
parents what are we going to do with the
kids during the
day I
know
what do your K what do you expect your
kids to say in answer to a question why
do you go to
school
parents I'm
sorry to make the world a better place
that's a great answer I suspect there
are a lot of parents that will not say
that yeah I think parents are going to
think about if from the perspective of
what they consider to be success for
their kids okay what is that what is
that so that they can
essentially make make living get a job
to support themselves and their family
who in a sense reproduce the family and
keep
itable so when I go to yeah yes you want
your kids to do better than
you okay that's that's
a that's a profound statement because
it's so far-reaching um but let me tell
you what I hear when I ask elementary
and middle school kids that question
okay and and try to see whether or not
that extrapolates to your reason for
being here at Cornell kids will say um I
want to go to school I need to go to
school because Mommy and Daddy say so
that's the first thing you hear I need
to go to school because I have to get
good grades and get a good job because I
have to make
money right and if you get the higher
grades well I need money because I want
a car and then you you say well you
you're going to eventually want a family
and you're gonna want to have a mortgage
uh you're going to or or rent and you're
you're going to have to put food on the
table and that's the reason we go to
school do you buy
that
sure that has absolutely nothing to do
in my mind with why we go to school it's
all wrong and let me start off by saying
something maybe profound when we explore
we fulfill a commitment of our to our
own
Humanity
um I don't know you should ask your
parents this I don't I don't know if
you've ever had this conversation with
them but if I were to ask
parents do you remember that magical
time when your children were first
starting to express themselves with
sentences and as a parent I know what
that magical time was like I lived
through it with my son you've lived
through it with with your daughter I
live through it with my daughter that
magical time when they're first able to
communicate with you and express
themselves and all parents will remember
that time and then you ask what did your
kids do when they first were able to
express themselves somebody said it in
one of the words
before what why which is
a question kids will start asking this
unending stream of questions so many
questions so overwhelming are the
questions that adults tend to try to
squash it because they they can't handle
all the questions so as soon as we're
capable of expressing
ourselves we ask lots and lots of
questions and I had to change the way I
said this when my son was born because I
remember I was in a family room with my
son who uh and this was before he was
able to to speak he just knew a couple
of words that's it but he was an Avid
Reader and the reason I say that is we
had this incredible library of picture
books do you remember those big format
picture books where like every tree
imaginable was on these pages in the
tree book and then there was the car
book and the truck book and I remember
this this moment in time when we were
sitting on the family room couch and I
think it was I think it was um a the
fish book and he I turned the page and
he pulled the page back and he looked at
me he went da and I didn't know what he
was saying so I turned the page again
and he pulled the P the page back hard
and he went da da and then I again I
didn't know what he was saying so I
turned the page and he pulled the page
back really hard and he pointed to a
particular picture I can't remember what
the fish was let's let's say it was a
tuna I don't know and he said da da and
I looked down and I said a tuna and he
turned the
page and so what he was saying is Daddy
what is this before he even had the
ability to express that to say what is
this he was asking
questions we're born to explore we're
born curious we've got to do it because
what it it's what it means to be human
and we're also born with something else
so we're born curious we're born to ask
those questions we're born
evidence-based
Learners what does that mean well we are
born to poke the universe and see what
happens we love to poke the universe and
see what happens and a great example of
a class of humans that poke the universe
really really well are
babies a baby will poke the universe in
every way it can it will explore near
versus far and up versus down texture
and color and sound a baby will try to
figure out how to to bring that glass of
juice in a way so that the surface
remains horizontal until the the the
child can get the glass to their mouth
and then drink it think about the
articulation in in in the fingers and
the wrist and the elbow and the shoulder
to make all that happen and the act of
poking the universe and seeing what
happens gives rise to two things first
of all it tells us how the universe
works and the second thing does is it
tells us how to interact with the
universe we learn how to interact with
it because of the evidence it presents
to us so that's really really important
we are born curious and we are born
evidence-based
Learners
so let me start back with
that first part let me let me let me not
say that give the answer away not
knowing something is a
gift
why can explore it for ourselves and
have fun doing it and how do you start
that
exploration by asking what it is we
don't know asking uh question question
right not knowing something is really a
remarkable gift because if you don't
know something you can ask a question
and have a journey that's what it's all
about and I guess the the only caveat is
that you want to know it by the time the
exam rolls
around so the act of Journey the start
of
Journey is is is brought about by asking
a question and so let me give you some
examples of the Majesty in a question
there are common themes here I Ed the
word majesty a few few times sparingly
there is Majesty in a question and I was
doing a professional development with
Zoo staff
at the National Zoo in Washington DC and
we were talking about this and Roger
Rosco who is a curator in the reptile
house said Jeff I know what you're
talking about because there was one
question that drove drove everything I
did as as a as a kid when I wanted to go
out and explore and I said well Roger
what was that question he said I wonder
what's under that
rock and so this was the question that
drove him I wonder what's under that
rock and he would go and he would he
would Empower himself as a learner to
lift up a rock and see creatures that he
never would have seen if he didn't ask
the question this Brave New World of
creatures that live under the Rock and
don't want to come out in daylight and
so with a smile breaking across his face
you know what he did next Rock he said I
wonder what's under that rock and this
rock and that rock and after he he' done
he done had done that with all the rocks
in his backyard he moved over to the
park I mean this is what he told me and
that that love of of exploring the the
world translated professionally into he
became a curator at the reptile house at
the national Zoological Park and I said
to Roger at the time well that's really
cool because when I was in elementary
school there was a question like that
that I used to ask I wonder what's in
that rock and I took my dad's hammer and
I would whack away at rocks and it was
like on the outside they would be brown
or gray and inside hey this is really
cool there's Quartz in here and I'd go
to the museum and I would see geodes do
you have you ever seen geod and it's
like I would just whack rocks all over
the place and I had this this rock
collection which I probably still have
it's somewhere in a box somewhere and
and I know I've told that story stories
to that story to a number of geologist
who said that's how I got involved in
geology whacking Rocks open think about
another question and and some of the
most powerful questions are are the most
elegant how far can I see so on a clear
day if you're out in an open field how
far can you see what do you
think few miles a few
miles yes you agree with that well wait
can you see the
Moon that's 240,000 miles away can you
see the
sun that's 93 million miles away that
star Beetlejuice in the in the
constellation of Orion which you could
see from any urban area because it's so
bright that's 500 light years away one
lightyear is six trillion miles that's
500 time 6 trillion is 3,000 trillion
miles and that's a nearby
star if you're in the southern
hemisphere you can see the large and and
the the large and small magelan clouds
two neighboring galaxies and if you know
where to look you can see the center of
the Andromeda galaxy the nearest large
galaxy to the Milky Way and you're
looking 2 million light years away that
light started traveling to us two
million years ago and is only getting to
us now you can see really
far and so that one question how far can
I see provides this pathway for a
journey of Discovery that's stunning
it's absolutely
stunning
so a question is really really powerful
and here's something that I think ought
to be an appropriate reminder to any
adult okay next time a child comes at
you with question after question
consider it a gift
because they chose
you you're helping the next generation
of Explorer fulfill their commitment to
their own
Humanity people are taking
notes follow me on
Twitter you can see many of these are
short enough for 140 characters there's
a reason for
that how do you answer a
question
question well will that give you an
answer if you answer a question with a
question well okay how would you answer
sophisticated audience a
question you'd go
to Google or Bing right but wait a
second is that how you answer the
question or is that evees dropping on in
on somebody else's answer to that
question how do you answer the
question you poke the universe you've
got to find a creative way to interact
with the universe and in the case of my
field astronomy it's really cool because
light from all of those things that we
were talking about before is streaming
to the Earth and the Earth gets in the
way and that light falls without any
importance on the surface of the Earth
and it's gone but if you poke the univer
if you interact with the universe by
putting large light buckets in in in
front of the light streaming in we call
them telescopes and you collect the
light and you're smart enough to
understand the information contained in
the light you can find out how far and
how bright and how big and whether the
winds are circulating on the atmosphere
of a planet far far
away so how do you answer answer a
question you've got to interact with the
universe now I think what I'm trying to
say here is that
what we know standing on the shoulders
of past Generations have has come to us
because we have found creative ways to
explore and what we're doing when we're
just
children is naturally exploring we're
not we're not learning how to learn we
already know how to learn babies know
how to learn what we really need is is
is a little guidance it's sort of like
it's the students classroom and the
teacher lights the
way okay it's not the teachers's
classroom it never was never me was
never meant to be the teacher classroom
it's the students classroom and the
teacher lights the way the idea is that
we know how to learn we know how to poke
the universe we know how to ask
questions we know how to frame a pathway
to an answer but sometimes you need to
heard heard the cats a little bit to to
provide the tools that will allow to be
a very efficient
exploration
so what is science because you know I've
talked about what what it's what it
means to be human in terms of
exploration what is science because
formally science is what revealed the
Majesty of the universe what is
science if you ask scientists and
Engineers what do you do what would they
say
the art of generating new questions from
old questions
or way of
knowing how is that different than what
we've just been talking about in terms
of human nature in terms of
exploration it's
not
I like that can we use that on
Twitter um you know what science is it's
organized
curiosity it's organized curiosity and
you know what science is it's
evidence-based learning for the entire
human
race it's evidence-based learning for
the entire human race
science grows organically from what it
means to be human we're born
curious organize it you get science
we're evidence-based Learners organize
that into a process by which you can can
really put evidence to the test you get
science think about it I'm a scientist I
go and I find out something new I'm
really excited about this new thing I
found I tell all of my colleagues
through scholarly Publications and at
conferences I tell all my colleagues
about what I found they say I don't
believe you Jeff you know what I
say well you poke the universe the same
way and see what you
find that's what science is it's a
torture test you you you make your
evidence you know you're an
evidence-based learner you've you've
figured out what the evidence is you've
presented it in scholarly Publications
and now you you invite the entire C
scientific Community to throw darts at
it and and you know what happens
sometimes you find out you were wrong
and you know what happens sometimes
everybody finds out the same thing and
it's it's it's like the whole world goes
to a whole new
place
so science as I said is a natural
outgrowth of what it means to be human
so the next logical question in this
story is what should Science Education
be there's a pathway I'm I'm I'm getting
to a point here and and let go back to
something I said earlier which is
that the process by which we ask a
question and the art by which we frame a
pathway through the noise of the
universe around us in quest of an
answer and the act of pulling back the
veil of Nature and seeing something
wholly new and the joy that breaks over
your your you know breaks across your
face when you see something holy new is
science where was I going with this ah
Science Education well that process you
know in an organized way or you know is
is the scientific you know well let me
say it a little differently that process
is the scientific method and it's an art
form it is not a rigid recipe for do
this do this do this do this I could
tell you that two scientists approaching
the same problem okay may go at it
completely different ways and one
scientist approaching two different
problems well they may go at it too
different ways because the problem
demands it and I can tell you there are
scientist that will not hypothesize to
begin with because they don't want to
bias the results lots of science is done
by poking it and just seeing what
happens so the scientific method I think
we do a very bad job in teaching in in
classrooms but the the more important
thing is that process of exploration and
learning that I described is that
science
specific what about history if you want
to learn about the Civil War okay
instead of paring facts and information
here memorize all of this stuff okay or
or let's say Truman okay the decision to
drop the bomb okay instead of of a bunch
of facts and figures to memorize for the
exam exam your Truman and his Joint
Chiefs of Staff and his cabinet that's
who you are you're making the decision
to drop the bomb what is it that you
would need to consider in other words
you can put students in the moment
provide them a problem in history
and history becomes alive it becomes
something that is more organic and so I
think what I'm saying is that process
that I'm describing here is the way
humans like to learn it's the way we're
born to learn and it's discipline
independent and so therefore my question
becomes how then should education be
conducted so that it's Effective
Education you know what should and I'll
give you the example of Science
Education what should Science Education
be what are the what is the nature of
Science Education if it's going to be
effective and so let me um let me take
you through a couple of other things my
thoughts on education some some of my
thoughts on educ uh education a question
we should be asking but don't what is
the role of Education you tell me what's
education all about what's the point of
Education what's the point of going to
Cornell what what is the the set of of
objectives that you're trying to meet
and I'm not talking about you know
Downstream the job the diploma the
education what's the point I I'll give
you a hint here's a here's a tweet I put
out that went viral student why do I
have to learn all this stuff system
because we want you to get a good job as
a search
engine what do what do I mean by
that did did I'm
sorry you can find all that stuff online
you find that all so so it's important
for you to know all of the state
capitals by the time say you're 10
because that information is hard to come
by how many of you in your you know
you've gone through a a a k through 12
education system how many of you
remember subjects where the educational
experience was memorizing
information how do you feel in the age
of
Google you know it's like 10 minutes
okay um I I actually saw that that's
good that's good you didn't have to
throw anything okay um you know what's
interesting is I used to tell students
uh years ago I I'd go into a classroom
and they wanted me to talk about um
careers and you know how I made my
decisions and what I did and I used to
say something that I now kind of sort of
regret I used to say to students you
know knowledge is power the more you
know the more capable you are to decide
what you want to do with your life so
school is really really important you
got to know you know as much as you can
that's really not right that's not
correct what what happens if all of a
sudden somebody finds this humongous
deposit of gold what will happen to the
value of
gold go down it'll plummet because
there's a lot of
it well look at Google look at the
information age look at look at the
knowledge base of the human race online
and you know in the not too distant
future I'm sure a couple of generations
from now you're going to be able to plug
your brain into the human knowledge base
and what then of
Education
um knowledge and and let me say this for
effect I don't believe it to the depth
of what I'm about to say but I'm I'll
say it for effect just to make the point
knowledge is virtually
useless it's
everywhere you know we were we were
driving in the car and we were talking
about William Penn in Philadelphia and
we were having this debate well William
Penn must be like you know 5 10 stories
high and I pulled out my iPhone 5 and
it's like 547 feet high William Penn is
54 stories up in Philadelphia that's
like incredible it's like I have the
power at my fingertips to probe the the
the knowledge base of the human race and
so the power doesn't lie in how much you
know the power lies in your ability to
do something with the
knowledge what's power is your ability
to use the knowledge to do something
with the
knowledge and actually that's true in in
virtually every field um a bold
statement when it comes to education we
must stop telling our children that
knowledge is power and we just talked
about that and and so it's not about the
information knowled education is not
should not be about the information
and over here education must not be
about dictating to our children what
they should be curious
about you you know what's really
reprehensible forcing a child to sit in
a classroom for 6 hours and telling them
what they should be curious about that
denies them I think I said it on the
next slide here it is okay education
that denies our children their curiosity
and their need to poke the universe is
not education worthy of our
children it's the it's the students
classroom not the teachers the teacher
lights the way and if we take away
ownership and learning from the child
what we are doing is denying them their
need to be
explorers and there are ways the ways to
do this what I'm asking what I'm what
I'm suggesting here is not difficult to
do so going back to what is innately
human the journey is written in our
genes The Book of Knowledge is not what
should that tell us about the role of
Education okay let's go by go back to
biology the journey is written in our
genes do we have to teach our children
those those CH those those those babies
for instance how to explore their
Universe the journey the process of
inquiry and exploration is written into
our genes The Book of Knowledge is not
so what should that tell you about
education how education should proceed
shouldn't it be nurturing what is
already in
US shouldn't it be about nurturing the
gift of a question and and inquiry based
exploration shouldn't it be about
recognizing that there is core knowledge
to let me say it this way when you ask a
question if you understand how to play
the game the art of of of learning you
recognize that there is core knowledge
that you need to bring to the problem at
hand and there is core knowledge that we
ought to be teaching our children basic
conceptual underpinnings across the
board and then you find a pathway to
address that question and the answer is
the creation of new knowledge the
objective ought to be the a student's
ability to go through that process and
create new knowledge at least new
knowledge to
them um
so education and the title of the talk
was a teacher's gift uh nurturing
education in our children what education
ought to be about is that nurturing of
exploration in our children nurturing
exploration in our children now let me
give you some some examples okay and
maybe this is on the next slide
um what do I I want to say uh let's go
to the next slide it's been a long day
already okay okay well I didn't get to
the other slide but yeah education needs
to be about
Journey it needs to be about
process and what are the skills required
ownership and learning critical thinking
problem solving navigation of an
interdisciplinary landscape teamwork
ownership and learning is so important
it's like you know here's an example for
you know Elementary pres school
generalists um you know it's like are
you telling me that you want me to to
allow unfettered exploration of my my
science class letting all of the the
students go and do whatever they want
and I I understand that problem um and I
can tell you when I was building the the
the uh carbon monoxide uh carbon dioxide
laser system for the heterodon
spectrometer no Divine hand gave me the
procedures on how to build it nor would
I have taken it as soon as a science
teacher say gives procedures for an
experiment to their class they're
ensuring that no science is going to be
done that day
why because who owns the
procedures the teacher you've taken all
of the ownership away from the students
you're asking them to be technicians
follow these
procedures but a creative compromise is
for you to with the class explore the
problem at hand so your class comes up
with the experiment you happen to have
written
up did you hear what I just said okay a
good teacher an Artful teacher will be
able to to facilitate conversation in
the class so that the class moves in
some direction and if you can get your
students to come up with the experiment
you happen to have written up why is
that a difference between night and day
who owns it
then they do and that's really really
important so ownership and learning is
important critical thinking
understanding logic you know I think
that there should be a bar that has to
be passed for people who want to go into
public office they have to pass a
critical thinking test you know I I I
just I don't understand I was saying
this to a couple of people um Akin you
know the the famous uh the the famous
congressman who said that uh in case of
um in case of legitimate rape a woman
has the ability to shut down a pregnancy
and Brawn from Georgia who said that um
uh Evolution and the Big Bang are the
biggest lies of the devil and and and
here's the insanity both of these
gentlemen sit on the US House science
space and Technology
committee okay so you know we have a
problem ladies and gentlemen okay
problem solving that art form by which
you take a question and find a pathway
to An Answer navigation of an
interdisciplinary landscape you know how
many of you took you know trigonometry
and calculus remember that okay do you
know how many students that take
trigonometry and calculus ask this
question why do I need to know this
stuff because because the math is taught
in full isolation from actual
use math is the language of nature if
you want to understand her and
understand how she operates you have to
speak her language it's a language and
if I were to teach French and and you
were never going to use that French to
talk to other people who speak French or
go and read the the the the literature
the um and newspapers in French and
understand the French culture if you
were never to do that why would you want
to take French just to memorize
vocabulary why would we subject our
students to these stove pipe math
courses with no connection to why math
provides the ability for the human race
to see so interdisciplinary Landscapes
you got to navigate it's not like
opening a physics book and closing it
and opening a chemistry book and closing
it and opening an art book book life is
an interdisciplinary tapestry and
education ought to mirror that maybe I'm
asking too much for the education system
but what I'm simply saying is that
education ought to be nurturing what is
natural to human
learning
so and as an example as a working
example that I'm familiar with in terms
of Science Education which is now called
stem okay if you if you've been doing
good Science Education it had to be stem
because science technology engineering
and math cannot be done in isolation
from from each other but my view is if
if exploration is something that our CH
our children are born to be able to do
and science is nothing but organized
curiosity and evidence-based learning
for the human human race our children
are capable right now of being immersed
in real science and doing science which
means that Science Education could be
about modeling real science immersing
kids in science letting them be
scientists and Engineers right now not
talking about the science knowledge base
The Book of Knowledge is not science
that's what you get from science or
talking at science let them do science
and the program that we did to really
put that to the test which has been very
successful is the student space flight
experiments program where we can say to
a school district we're going to give
you your own space program we're going
to give you a real microgravity mini
laboratory and all launch services to
get it to the International Space
Station have an astronaut assigned as a
technician to operate the single
experiment it contains return it safely
to Earth and just like NASA that school
district at the local level says to at
least 300 students you're all scientists
and break into research teams and each
team design your own microgravity
research program and each team Des write
your own research proposal which will go
through a formal two-step Proposal
review process just like professional
researchers and one of those teams will
have their experiments selected for
flight and we're doing this with fifth
graders grades 5 through 12 and it is
stunning what we're seeing we we've had
21,7 00 students fully immersed in
experiment design and proposal writing
over 4,000 proposals all this since
2010 students are saying I never knew
this was science teachers are saying wow
this is a completely different way to
teach science a project-based approach
immersing students in every facet of
real research and they even get their
own research conference at the
Smithsonian National Air and Space
Museum so I I have obviously oh we're
out of time I got to stop we I obviously
have some very strong opinions about
human exploration science and Science
Education and more generally human
exploration and um you know professional
exploration and how we teach uh in an
interdisciplinary way subjects in the
classroom but I also have a track record
for putting that into
practice and I think that what we are in
right now as a um as a test based
educational system that stifles
creativity that denies many Learners the
ability to be curious that forces
testing um uh education to serve testing
and not testing serve education is a
recipe for success is not a is a re it's
a recipe for success for
China oh I pulled that out at the last
minute okay so um I think I'll stop here
um I'm certainly able to answer any
questions if people want to m
rounder this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu