this is a production of Cornell
University my name is Jacob Johnson I'm
with the project yard map at the Cornell
lab of ornithology a citizen Science
Program aimed at creating habitat in
your yard show you the yard map
application online and the website and
how we use that yard Maps essentially
allows scientists to better understand
how landscape use and gardening choices
affect birds and wildlife populations in
a residential or Urban
settings in terms of coexistence we're
realizing also that a greater diversity
of birds and a greater diversity of
plants and Wildlife around a
neighborhood or around a group of people
improves their well-being and this is
true in almost any demographic and
almost any society and so what yard map
seeks to do
is um collaborate with groups of people
to join people together and to create a
community of yard mappers a community of
people making connections or connecting
points connectivity is a very big
Concept in ecology that connects large
expanses of wild areas through small
expanses of wild areas like
yards one
yard that's yard mapped and is being
managed for wildlife is great two yards
is even better
because that provides stepping stones
from say a national forest to you know
lake sarac or something then you have
you have these Stepping Stones of
habitat and when you have Stepping
Stones connected you have corridors so
you have corridors and stepping stones
and all of this you know when a
community works together to provide all
the necess necessary or essential parts
of a habitat across the landscape that's
when we can all make a really big
difference so what I want to do is show
you some of yard
map and some of the uh some of the best
practices that we suggest and some of
the tools that we have for um for
planning it yourself and this is our
website this is our new page our new
homepage and it sort of demonstrates
what I was just referring
to the actions of you and your
community and
create you know a larger
more uh efficient
and useful habitat so a anatomy of a
yard map a yard map takes a Google image
of your house you outline
it and then you fill in the habitats and
then you place objects like trees and
bushes and bird feeders on that habitat
and it creates a yard map like this I'll
show you that in a second
here's our active
participants
adding habitats or objects to their
yards and then when you do when you add
say um you know a native flower bed or
native flower garden to your yard you uh
you document that and you it tells the
scientist here at yard map so let's see
up here on this top bar we have a lot of
resources the explore resource will show
you will take you um if you put in your
ZIP code
here this will show you your uh plant
hardiness Zone and your Eco region and
give you the list of um bird reports
local experts States native plants this
is a really nice uh link here that gives
you uh
suggestions of available plants that you
can buy and then here's places where you
can buy them and here's places where you
can get together with Community um Comm
community events that are around you and
that's all based on your zip code and
plant hardiness zone so that's one of
the things that yard map allows or um
you know provides a resource for and
then we have the top learn we have the
learn articles which are constantly
updated articles referring to um best
practices basically um Native Lawns
replacing na or non-native plants with
native plants Zer escaping you know what
I mean anything you can think of rain
barrels cats and so there's um just a
lot to learn from that section
there but what are what we the citizen
science part of it here is the
mapping and here's our this is an
example here of a map that's been
created and we can take a look at some
other maps that have been recently
created there right now there is a
project going on up in
Canada where they um are encouraging
elementary schools to map their schools
so here's a map what each of these
sections has been outlined with a
tool and then each of these trees
replaced I'll just take a quick
second and show you a little bit of
mapping so first you find
oops first you would find your house say
this is my house here
here you use a site outline
tool you pick whether you're using a a a
home or it's a school or a community
garden you can map Farms Parks preserves
and if you have something else that's
unique like we have a couple of yard
mappers that map their balcony you know
they live in a giant apartment building
but they have a wonderful B Garden on
their balcony so they use this other to
just map the balcony so I'm going to
pick a a home and I'm going
to assume that I know the boundaries of
this house this property and so that's
what it takes
there it saves
it and then you use a habitat
tool outline the
lawn I'm going to be really rough about
this but you can I'll show you some
intricate examples that are really well
done and there's some Forest
here all of the dots are movable you can
either expand the range or you can move
the whole piece around like this
and there's
also
buildings so this
gives this gives us
area and type of habitat but it doesn't
give us everything but you want what
happens next once these things are
mapped you go into
the you go into the characteristics
page and you can put in information I'm
going to call my
house my home the characteristics does
it have a
garage or is it a home this is a home so
then like we want to know about the roof
does it have a green roof or does it
have a white roof because white roofs
help with
uh albo effect with CLE warming of the
climate around you and things like that
you can put in some comments and you can
upload
photos and that's for almost every
object every object has and every
habitat is going to have um these
characteristics that you can
include information for like the lawn do
you use an electric lawn mower or gas
powered lawn mower or push re lawn mower
that sort of thing everything is going
to have a different collection of
characteristics once you get the entire
area filled I'm not going to fill it
right now but once this area is filled
that's when you go back through
you find you go to the object tool and
then you can start adding
trees and say this
tree not sure what happened there Pard
par me just give me one second here
doesn't seem to want to save for
me oh there's the tree
okay so when you open the
tree you can type in the type of what
you want to call it say it's you know
it's my uh I have a big swing in the
tree or something and then this is an
interesting part here you can put in
this and say it's a red maple I'm going
to put in
Acer and as I start to type species
lists will come up this is where the
citizen science data comes in really
handy because then we have
species and abundance on the in each of
these
properties so that's one of the one of
the things that you can do with yard map
and then
also we are starting to really integrate
the yard map with all of the other
citizen scientist uh programs so if I
open this site
again I can I keep getting that error
message I can list all the birds that I
have seen on this site and this uses the
eBird
this uses the eird citizen science
program and so what you do here is you
add data to the
eird program through the yard map
program and then that ties them together
and eventually what we'd like to be able
to do
is U connect Nest watch and feeder watch
with these so that when you put a bird
feeder let's see let me find a bird
feeder there's a lot of objects down
here on the bottom if you look there's
Planters cactuses everything
from um wild flowers to bat houses and
be nests here's a birdhouse I'll put a
birdh house in the lawn
here so then it won't be long before you
can um connect your nest watch data with
bird houses that you put on your land or
on your yard
map so like if you notice here yard map
is in beta we are constantly growing and
expanding but right now it is is very
usable and um very very fun to use we
have a lot of people that enjoy it and
we're really glad that um folks like you
are interested in learning about it so
that you can take it to your
communities and put it to use and get
get feedback for us here at the coral
lab of orthology and um provide um much
better habitat more
efficient more efficient habitat
for I'm sorry I seem to be losing
this okay well if anybody would like to
see anything else let me know this is a
just a quick demonstration of this but
ites definitely takes a little bit of
learning curve to learn to use first you
you know here's a and some exploring to
use the uh website here
but once you get the hang of it it's
fast and a lot of fun so uh we do have a
lot
of
um
um extension members um using this with
their communities um to create groups
and things like that and so what we've
been focusing on recently is let me see
if I can give you all a sneak
peek this is behind the scenes this is
not a live site here but what we are
working on now is this groups function
and this is what we'd like uh people
that work with the communities people
that work U with uh other like Community
gardeners or Planters to uh
collaborate together and to work
together in a group so this is the new
function that we're starting
here and these groups um you can find a
group to join you can start your own
group and you can
create let's see you can uh let me see
if I can pull one up here yeah and then
you can compare your group to other
groups and you can compare yourselves
within the group so if you're in a group
that say native lawn see you know native
lawn group and you're all trying to get
the least amount of lawn on your yard
and the most amount of native plants or
something then you know you can you can
compare each other's efforts through
this group function here and that will
probably be live in a few
weeks so that's something to look
forward to
there through uh the the learn and the
explore
tabs but eventually after the group
functionality that we're working on now
the next part the next tool that we're
going to add to the yard map U network
is called a planning tool and that will
be a second math that you sort of lay
over the math that you have so that you
first will assess what you have and then
after that you can plan what you want
and yard map will make the connections
for you so if you want you know to put
in a Native Garden
yard map May pop up and say Here's
native plants for your area that will
work to attract the birds that you
listed you want to attract you know what
I mean something like that right now
it's sort of uh using the resources to
explore on your own but very soon it
will be one that is a planning tool that
gives you the resources and
suggestions what you would do is go to
the explore Tab and put
in um your ZIP code here
and one of the best resources that I
found that we've found for plant
suggestions is this uh your States
native plants it takes you to the um
Lady Bird Johnson Wildflower
Center and it will give you a suggestion
of of
uh native plants and you can filter that
suggestion too if you want trees or if
you want bushes or if you want them to
flower in June or if you want them to be
you know dry dry sight type flowers you
know what I mean there's a number of
ways you can
filter um the selection to get kind of
what you have in your yard if you have a
dry site that gets lots of sun with
acidic soils and you want something that
gets about four feet high you can enter
all that into that uh so there's 16 uh,
almost 177,000 sites across the country
um we do have some sites in Mexico lots
of sites in Canada we've got a couple in
like Costa Rica a couple in Europe we're
really trying to work together with the
the Google Earth or the Google Maps to
make that more accurate right now the
the the software isn't as accurate as it
needs to be you know lining up a Google
Earth picture with our with our our
mapping tools doesn't quite work very
well so people have some difficulties
outside of the Country Canada and Mexico
seem to be fine but any further outside
of that and it's um has to do with
ejections with map projections and
things like that that we're working on
um but the engagement is always going up
this number was 200,000 Acres mapped
just a few weeks ago so we've almost had
40,000 Acres mapped in a couple of weeks
um so people are always um coming back
to it there's no commitment to come back
to your map although we do try to
encourage people to always be adding and
changing and updating um what what
they've done to their yards you know if
any changes you make to your yard we
want to know about it you know and then
know any any differences that uh may
have come about from that so there's no
like I said there's no commitment but as
often as you want or as few as you want
we try to keep people coming back at
least once a year with any changes that
have made if a tree fell over or you
know they changed their gardening
techniques or something like that yard
map.org
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu