this is a production of Cornell
University so well thank you for this uh
invitation um I have to give a a bit of
an uh uh disclaimer that it so I'm going
to give really a it's kind of a public
uh relations event um so I'm going to
give it a talk that and is a version of
a talk that I gave at the
bti I'm very well Amplified it feels
um and um that it's Magdalene Lindberg
who invited me to uh come and give it
again uh here and uh so I'm going to
point to um One Vision of the
opportunities and uh try to illustrate
it with uh projects that I know of
around campus um around uh heavily the
College of Engineering um but also
physical sciences and I'll put in a few
um uh projects that from published work
from uh other places in the world um and
but I'll start out with a a naive um
Outsiders perspective on why why uh
plant scientists might look more to
these uh emerging and future physical
science tools uh if I'm offensive it'd
be it'd be good if you told me because
so I won't continue to be offensive
about my uh assumptions about the state
of plant science and uh important
questions uh so uh I come to this having
um interacted with plant scientists here
and elsewhere but also having um been
part of a a big uh growth area at
Cornell in uh looking at engineering
questions in biology and uh I was very
naive early on to in in thinking that uh
but not completely wrong in thinking
that there are a lot of similarities
between the organism scale uh as well as
the cellular and molecular scale of U
Mamon systems and uh plant systems um
now that's of course a very coarse view
but uh in terms of Technology
development there's reason to believe
that the the analogies can be powerful
and there maybe translation from one to
the other now why bring up mammals in a
plant science department well it's
because they the Maman biologists in
particular in the biomedical field have
heavily engaged engineers in technology
development at to a level that I I think
is you know uh well maybe scales with
the size of human biology relative to
plant science but there's been a lot of
Technology development in these past uh
decades and so uh one way to say is why
not bring bio nanot technology and other
Technologies to plant science well one
is that they they' they've gone to human
biology they've gone from uh being
molecular tools through cellular tools
through being uh clinical tools that our
interfaces with the living organism so
it doesn't have to be dissected uh and
I'll point to some of these examples
that ought to be able to be uh and uh
translated in some form to um plant
biology and uh agriculture now working
in attempts to bring technology to
plants I understand also that there are
important differences that in in some
ways it's harder plants don't let you in
as easily um they don't have soft skin
often um and disrupting them can have
dire consequences that uh and in some
ways mamalian systems are more uh
agreeable to some of these interventions
okay I I I highlight the hypmic needle
because this is one of the absolute
workhorses of human of of biom medical
intervention and I would argue that
essentially we don't have a hypmic
needle uh for plants um and there are
important reasons why we don't but we
it'd be awful nice if we did
um so agriculture uh I think a lot of
people think of Engineering in uh in
plant Sciences being things you stick to
a tractor um and I think that's been the
definition of uh for many decades um and
it still is an an an important uh Target
um and one way to see it is one one
thing that has surprised me I was first
surprised to know how heavily uh
agriculture has invested in smart uh
irrigation strategies 10 million
hectares is a re reasonably uh uh recent
estimate for globally um and yet almost
never is that on a closed loop feedback
because they don't ask the plants how
much water they want or ask even the
soil and so here you have what is an
Advanced approach uh Running Free
Running on somebody's intuition about
what um what should be going on in terms
of uh irrigation uh and it's uh and it
for example and this these are topics
that I'm interested in it's uninformed
by uh parameters that are relatively
coarse but have been shown to be
crucially important like water potential
stem water potential that it's been
shown that you know uh crop uh
productivity quality uh correlate with
uh this one uh simple seeming uh
parameter in the plant and yet we have
no uh uh practical way to go and ask uh
even a sampling of plants in the field
what their water stress levels are uh
today you you the techniques of are now
mostly 60 years old um and course and uh
uh manual and hard to use not giving you
real-time data um uh I think there's uh
important advances have been going on in
uh remote senting um I think that and
they can give a beautiful uh information
uh I think there I'd like to see is
bringing into the plant getting local
physiological data uh into that um uh
potential feedback
loop uh the other another place that
I've been learning more recently what
the realities today are are about uh
breeding programs and selection of of
better crops and um here's it seems to
me a a a beautiful challenge for the
engineering community that most
Engineers have no idea about and it took
me uh uh a number of years working with
plant scientists but for truly learning
the the realities of what it is to
select a a better plant um and so here
I'm showing science fiction a patch on
that you could a a few Cent patch that
you could go along and put on uh many
many uh um um uh crosses for example and
get something uh local physiological uh
back uh during a growing season outside
um and it was actually uh partly um
meeting with Ed buckler that
crystallized this uh challenge for me uh
he he and this is a paraphrase but he
basically told me if you can measure a
trait 10,000 times I'll find you the
Gene and I may you know better than I
whether he's correct about that it it it
looks from his publication record like
could well be true um and again uh this
uh this challenge uh thousands of um
reproducible uh quantitative
measurements on Plants that's a great
Challenge and it's one that uh Engineers
should know about should be going after
um because I think it's possible not for
every um uh uh definition of a trait
every phenotype every protein but for
some crucial ones and this I got to say
I saw a talk by Pioneer and they and
they it was maybe he was retired from
Pioneer and he admitted that in his
opinion Leaf angle had been the biggest
change in phenotype that had defined
increases in yields in their breeding
program and that may be an
oversimplification but I I was shocked
that that what the that these
extraordinarily sophisticated molecular
biologists uh deal with extremely coarse
physiological information extremely
coarse definitions of what a trait is
and I can understand why because you
have to measure it thousands of times
you have to measure it uh in complicated
environments but again it's a it's it's
it's in some sense it's the engineer end
of the problem that's failed in this
project because I know that the
molecular tools are incredible but if
you're applying molecular tools the the
the absolute state-of-the-art and
genetic analysis to Leaf angle that
seems
unfortunate so I know so I have very
naive again perspective on what uh the
molecular and cellular questions in
plant biology are and so I'm I'm just
giving one example here where I see
opportunity and again I was surprised to
learn about the state of knowledge in
plants is here's an example of it's a
review saying that um direct evidence of
the motion of the movement of a peptide
uh has yet been to not been uh achieved
in the lab um and that uh this
particular flowering Locust te uh is the
in in 2013 was said to be the only
example of long range signaling bio
protein in the plant in a plant and uh
this seems like again this is uh a
challenge across uh biological Fields
but to uh integrate information
extremely sophisticated information
about individual cells and molecular
processes with organism scale processes
this is a place where in bi in
biomedical engineering there's been a
lot of it's been a rich area for making
progress uh to get to the tissue scale
get to the organism scale with
hypothesis about uh with molecular
hypothesis and so it's another um
opportunity so I'm going to uh talk
about three uh perspectives on how and
I'm going to again I'm going to
illustrate them with lots of people's uh
work um I'm going to talk about what I
call devices and uh this is where
Cornell has U Been a leader in uh
developing smallscale devices and a lot
of that energy over in the time I've
been at Cornell has been pointed towards
human health um not much of it pointed
towards plant science and I think that's
a a a missed opportunity to date uh
Cornell is also extremely uh good and uh
in imaging and I know many of you uh
probably use Advanced Imaging techniques
uh but I think this is a this is been
continued to uh uh be leaders in the
world in um in Advanced Imaging
techniques um and then also uh models um
they there uh models that I'm going to
focus on not bioinformatic like models
but more um what we call systems biology
models which again look to integrate
information from the molecular across to
the uh uh uh the cellular and to the
physial the full animal uh full organism
physiology so I'm going to start with uh
devices and I'll just point out that
there's a Cornell has a uh tradition in
this uh one of the uh workhorses of soil
science and um agriculture still today
uh was invented here there's some
argument about uh precedent but uh the
the Richard soil tensiometer is still
the the only uh tool to measure
precisely across uh the plant
physiological range of drought stress um
uh the the few bars of tension that are
relevant to most agriculturally relevant
plants um this is it versions of this
technology
um I think many most of you know uh the
Gan gun and and of course both of these
came from CS they didn't come from the
engineering College um so that's uh uh I
I I'll C admit that um but I think these
are these are uh two technologies uh
historic technologies that came out of
Cornell um that uh are precedent for
what should be being done here still
today um so I'm going to turn to a
number of technologies that I I don't
know of being used in Plants but I think
could be interesting and so this Irwin
uh devalck is a new faculty member in U
biomedical engineering and this is
something he he's working on today and
this is a publication he published just
before he came here uh and this is an
example of using a microfluidic system
which is a a miniaturized lab that can
handle extremely small scale samples uh
to collect um uh single stranded DNA out
of the blood um and turns out that is
has an importance in the context of
transplant uh biology of transplants um
but this is one of many examples of
doing um molecular biological analysis
on what would have previously been
thought of as being uh unusable samples
the contents of a single cell you can do
analysis on the contents of a single
cell today it's still that's still a
challenge but uh it's the uh it's the
kind of advance that is represented by
uh
nanobiotechnology this is an example
from uh Harold Craigs Harold Craig
head's group in Applied Physics he is uh
I think maybe the person who coined the
the name nanobiotechnology when he
started the nanot biotechnology Center
here at uh Cornell um and one of the big
themes has been manipulation of um
biomicro molecules in a particular DNA
that has led to uh the beginnings of uh
or the what is now becoming a reality of
of of uh uh single molecule sequencing
um and this is an example I believe this
is an example of mapping epigenetic
change at the single molecular scale and
so what you see here is what Nano this
is a truly this here are the features
that were created in Cornell's nanofab
are of a molecular Dimension and forcing
this DNA to take on a confirmation that
allows it to be literally read uh with
microscopy
this is another example from uh Applied
Physics of creating uh a cell culture uh
that uh has uh that that allows uh
electrophysiology to be done with
subcellular resolution so this involves
both the traditional patch clamp type
approach but also the cell that is
living on a circuit that allows uh the
group to interface with it and uh watch
for events that occur
uh uh to triangulate to where these
events occurring on a sub a subcellular
uh
scale moving up a little bit and a
number of these ideas are about uh
cultured tissues and cells and I know
this is there's a a difference in how
important that is in uh plant biology uh
than uh in Maman biology but I think uh
I I uh I hope that some of these
examples trigger some ideas of about um
where uh the translation could occur so
this is an example from Mike Schuler's
group who I I I still claim him for my
department he's actually uh shared with
biomedical engineering um and this is an
example of in fact uh building
um a a mimic a replica of the
connectivity of tissues in a Maman
system and so you see here uh liver fat
kidney um and coupling them with a very
primitive vascular system but one that
allows um the metabolic environment and
the signaling to interact with these
different tissues in a manner that
simulates uh time scales and
Transformations um that occur in the
different tissues uh in the in the body
um and so uh this this type of uh
replication of uh of tissue properties
of the tissue environment um is
something that there's a lot of there's
a lot of knoow now both from the M the
material side the fabrication side and
uh in some cases uh the biological side
about what are the influences of uh the
the tissue environment and the
communication between tissues within a
full
organism this is an example again that
is called uh uh of tissue engineering
effort from my lab of f focus on the the
um U microvascular structure of uh uh of
uh humans which is um like the FL in a
plant is built of living cells okay um
the the vessels on the smallest scale
are really formed of a of a single layer
of endothal cells that have a huge
amount of biology associated with them
and of course it's a bottleneck for
forming any um big tissue is to
simultaneously form its vascular system
if you're going to do an Engineering
Process to form a tissue um
I generally and I've spoken to very few
people about this but it I wonder uh it
would seem AR in naively that uh tissue
engineering um might be a whole lot more
fun and easy in plants in some ways um
that uh creating uh and because plants
might just go with it um and there may
not be there's not the clinical vision
of bringing somebody a a lab grown heart
but actually today much of tissue
engineering is done to recreate a
multicellular structure to study it
study its biology at that multicellular
scale without there are very few
examples uh today of translation truly
to the clinic and so in that same spirit
I could uh imagine uh uh that it could
be interesting for uh in uh uh plant
biology
um here's a effort that I thought was uh
exciting um from uh from Northwestern
for Northeastern um not from uh Cornell
but it's an example another example of
creating a a micro environment and in
this case uh so again what we call a
microfluidic uh system that has
microscale features that um inside this
cartridge and this is they by creating
that environment and EMB burying in the
soil they were able to ex uh
uh grow up a huge number of uncultivable
microbes and from that um they managed
to isolate um antibio promising
antibiotics that had been un unseen
previously because if you just took the
soil you had to too little too little of
any one species to produce that uh small
molecule um and so uh this is uh uh I
wish I wish it had been an idea here uh
but it's it's an example um that I think
it's worth noting that one one place and
in fact Harvey Hulk um as a plant
pathologist was one of the early uh
people that interact with the
nanobiotechnology center one of the most
active biologists at the
nanobiotechnology center and the one
reason to recreate these uh mimics or
replicas uh these engineered tissues may
it may be more about uh pathology than
it is about uh the plant biology on its
own okay
um here is uh one of the the first
efforts that first targets that my group
went after was to uh build synthetic
xylm and because plants do something
that Engineers don't that humans
basically don't which is use liquids
under tension and so uh we made very
very simple uh replicas and it was
really more about a materials question
of how how to build a network that
coupled to the outside in a way that
allow the the uh the the fluid in these
tiny vessels to go under tension in the
manner that's proposed by CT Co cohesion
tension Theory and um uh it turns out
that it's we we from a in a synthetic
system validated uh cohesion tension
Theory um which has nice consequences
physically there it brings us into a new
regime physically um but I think it it
also gives us an opportunity to for
example understand uh the the design
ideas from the purely physical point of
view of the the here for example the
segmented xylm structure seeing these
events of embolization occurring uh
independently as has all long been
proposed uh for the Redundant segmented
structure of xylm I've also uh thought
that and I've spoke to Harvey about this
before he uh retired that that this
creates uh an unusual environment the
environment of uh the xylm in the for
example where important pathogens live
that is unlike any other environment uh
in the world so what is it like to be a
a microbe that uh lives with uh the the
fluid pressure around it going from uh
zero to minus 20 bars uh up and down and
up and down and so it's also potentially
a bioreactor environment to study um the
biology of uh plant pathogen
interactions one of the things we've
done with this and this was um uh Alan
and laxo uh we were building a device
that ex that extrapolated from our
synthetic tree to put to have a cavity
of liquid uh with and this is it's a
strange geometry but this gray area
around is is a a nanoporous membrane
that allows the liquid in this cavity to
go to tension when the when it's exposed
to a dry environment and here we were uh
uh building it to have direct mechanical
sensing so that we'd have a direct
measure of that stress and Allan came uh
to find out what what this synthetic
tree was and so on and when we showed
him this that we were building as a
laboratory to study liquids under
tension he said oh well that's a
tensiometer and we hadn't known about
Richard in the whole challenge of
tensiometry until that point and uh we
realized that this was in fact a
miniature Richard's tensiometer and
again like I told you we've come to
appreciate that that tensiometry
measuring drought stress as a stress as
a tension is the most sensitive way to
to uh measure that thermodynamic state
of water and so uh having here a a
strain gauge on a diaphragm over this
cavity allows us to have quantitative
measures of the water potential in the
environment around this device uh and in
this case this is an this is our
champion of this generation of of these
devices uh we measured uh it went to an
embolization event um at uh 300 Bars of
uh of tension or uh water potential of
minus 300 Bars and just to this is U I
don't know if this will yeah
maybe uh to actually see
um uh I don't know which of these work
uh but to actually see embolization is
fun that this is the release this is the
click that acoustic measurements here uh
this uh atic release of uh of the
tension um upon uh
embolization and so it turns out we
we've been continued with Allan and
Taran uh uh to uh pursue this so that
it's a truly practical for uh plant
science measurements and so uh here is
our current generation of this device um
which is uh as you can see here uh down
to a a relatively small package
um I'm failing to get a pointer here um
and uh this in this format it's just
it's like a pinky a pinky uh fingernail
um and it turns out one of the nice
things is uh that I like is that to make
it uh respond fast enough to be able to
catch all of the changes in water
potential that might be occurring in a
plant uh which is where we we'd like to
take Richard tensometer and move it into
the stem instead of being Pur for the
soil um is we had to give it a vascular
system we had to uh connect this cavity
uh to the outside world uh with vessels
that would as in uh um plants as in the
xylm tissue uh transmit the stress uh
maintain the stress so be uh they're
divided from the outside world by
membranes um by nanoporous membranes but
once inside this device fluid moves
extremely rapidly along these uh vessels
and so the idea of segmented xylem
allowed us to take from our first
prototypes the our first generation of
these devices very long transients it
would have meant we wouldn't capture
things that occurred in less than an
hour to having just few just tens of
second transients that allow us we think
to C capture all dial and so on uh
behavior of of a plant and to do it
across a bring the Richard tensiometry
idea out towards 100 bars so all across
all the way to really desert stresses uh
in
plants and we actually have just moved
this into uh into plant tissue and and
uh we have uh uh trees growing in the uh
Greenhouse uh that so here working in
Branch segments these are actually just
in the last week to actually measure
here we apply drying stresses onto uh
this Branch segment um uh and uh can
watch what we've been calling in the lab
dials uh although they're not uh they're
just tens of minutes long and they're
associated with not with true
transpiration but with imposed
transpiration um but we are hoping that
this will uh allow us and in a process
in an embedding process here designed
for a woody species that just takes a
few minutes uh to get uh real time
long-term uh stress information on uh
plants and as part of uh water relations
research and eventually as part of
irrigation scheduling to close that
feedback loop with what is uh a very
relevant uh way to do it the plant's
actual stress and this is just a zoom to
see we we're getting we able to resolve
on 10 tens of bar scale we can resolve
uh small fractions of one bar changes in
water potential which of course for
annual species may be the more relevant
scale just a few bars instead of tens of
bars
so that's
uh that's an example of actually
bringing one of these Technologies to a
plant here's uh coming to a a leader in
the world of uh making Electronics
sophisticated Electronics compatible
with Life uh John Rogers Group which is
now moved to Northwestern and this is an
example of what I think I pointed to the
idea of an RFID chip or or patch on
every leaf of uh a field of uh plants
and this is this is an example on human
of human application of a a real
integrated circuitry on a flexible
adhesive uh patch uh that gives you in
this case
electrophysiological data through the
skin uh of this of the wearer and so I
don't know of anybody moving this uh in
Plants but if again with the right
inspiration from from you uh it I'm sure
it could
happen um moving towards the field
bringing these things from research
questions to the field is is certainly a
place where there's lots of expertise on
campus you may have seen this this is a
work from the Ericson group in
mechanical engineering uh where they
have uh turned us turned a iPhone into a
a relatively
sophisticated um uh sensor diagnostic
system for metabolic uh uh uh diseases
and uh uh
symptoms and so this is an example of
engineering all the way towards uh
something that you can hand off to a
non-expert user and uh bring to the
field and do uh Diagnostics and again
there's this this type of idea from an
once you have the idea of a lab on an
iPod or I lab on an iPhone you you can
um there's no reason not to bring it to
a question about a biochemical question
in Plants we have a a very large very
strong electrical engineering department
uh this is an example Edwin Khan who uh
is is very much focused on this question
of uh completely wireless power free
sensing so all those patches may not
even need a battery as with the checkout
counter RFID an RFID is just an antenna
it picks up the energy it needs to
respond to you just from the radiation
you send at it and so uh this again is
uh he is someone who be if you have
sensors already and what you need is to
have 10,000 of them that all talk to you
uh there's that expertise uh on
campus so that was my longest section
I'll just give a few examples of um uh
Imaging capabilities we have one of our
Imaging experts here Becky Williams um
there there is a very good shared
facility in while and in across in a
biotech building um I'm going to
highlight one of the things I very
exciting recently which is a
collaboration of uh Matt Patrick and
Warren zipel they're developing Advanced
versions of the mic of the microscopy
that I'm showing here and this is a
Maman example but uh it's a super
resolution technique and what they're
able what we're seeing here it's hard to
maybe read this scale bar what we're
seeing in the Z direction deformations
of the cell's plasma membrane of tens of
nanometers okay and so this cartoon the
the the bumps in this micrograph are
associated with individual or small
clusters of transmembrane uh binding
proteins interacting with the substrate
um and so uh this is one of the things
this is going from Pure structure to um
to Dynamics in the uh current efforts
and it's uh a huge
uh possibility to uh watch interactions
at the plasma membrane uh one molecule
one one transmembrane pro protein at a
time this is an example uh that you may
have heard about recently ulie visner
got a very large National Institute of
Health grant for this effort um uh it's
in this case he's the the star of this
picture is this uh little sphere here
which can be just a few nanometers
across and carries with it uh the
ability can carry with it uh uh
fluorescent and chemistry that allow it
to be a detector okay in this case
they're using it uh to carry contrast
agent for an Imaging but they've worked
on this in many different directions uh
these little lab on a particle um is an
opportunity to have a truly dispersible
sensor that could be go to the tissue in
an intact plant go to the tissue uh
where you want it and then be read out
Spectre scopically for example or by
fluorescence an example not from Cornell
but from this field of uh so-called
nanom materials uh here uh from uh
Michael sto's group at MIT of uh
disrupting a chloroplast with a a nanot
tube and what he finds with a simple my
simple understanding is essentially by
putting this carbon Nano tube which is
just a few nanometers in diameter and
has tunable electrical properties he's
essentially putting an antenna into this
organel uh within the cell and changing
and this is him
piercing uh a single chloroplast and
getting a diff getting an infrared
signal from that chloroplast that was
invisible before he put it in they go on
in this paper to claim that this is
improved photosynthetic efficiency in
these leaves that were treated with uh I
have some worry about that claim but uh
the the idea again of having uh almost
molecular scale engineered material that
can uh be part of transducing
information from the cellular scale or
even influencing the behavior at this uh
cell and subcellular scale I think is uh
interesting so uh models uh again I'm
going to I'm looking towards models that
uh I know there's a lot of a lot of
expertise uh in Cals and U uh in plant
science in um bioinformatic modeling I'm
less familiar with um uh modeling of uh
gene expression coupled the kinetics of
gene expression coupled to signaling
coupled to uh cellular Behavior coupled
to transport processes on the organism
scale and that's a that's one definition
of
systems systems biology that I think is
very relevant to plants and so we uh
Mike Schuler again here I gave him both
his uh
departments biomedical engineering and
and chemical engineering is actually
famous in this community as a very early
uh a developer of uh complete um
treatments of uh uh cell Behavior here
starting with uh uh microbes uh bacteria
but what I mean by complete in this case
the definition of complete is that he
has a set of differential equations that
are self-
sustaining
alive and respond to metabolic stimuli
and so on in a way that is reasonable
including Gene regulation okay and so
going from Gene regulation gene
expression through to uh metabolism um
those are tractable there are a large
number of tractable Mo models for uh
procaryotes and UK carots uh to be
worked with uh uh to to ask questions um
Jeff Varner in uh my department is uh
somebody who uh is uh one of the people
who push this to uh e extremes of of
completeness in terms of the number of
molecular players they're willing to put
into such a model of the cell um again
going from uh going from gene expression
uh signaling uh uh internally and uh
with the external environment um and in
this case uh moving to a multiscale
consideration of how a cell uh evolves
in its tissue context and so with
signals coming from other parts of the
tissue and through vasculature for
example other other parts of the
organism highlight an uh effort with uh
Bob Turon that I've been involved in uh
on uh the questions of flow and loading
and here's an example of uh where
focused on the uh the biochemistry
associated with um flam loading and
transport
questions uh very detailed questions
about plasma desmal the physics of
plasma desm desata and how they uh
regulate what goes what gets loaded um
and we do this we we claim uh and I
believe that we understanding the
implications uh the design ideas that
are represented by plasma desata
uh requires some accounting for the full
organism scale uh uh coupling that this
is what the the the concentrations water
potentials that Define transport very
locally in the uh at the uh mesil flum
interface in the leaf are coupled to
throughout the entire plant and so that
again is an example of uh where
different levels of what could be
defined as a systems biolog approach can
lead to hypotheses that then lead to
experiments and it's a it's it's a a
useful C iterative process that I think
is uh not done
enough so I just there here I can share
these slides there are a number of other
people across uh the university um that
uh uh most of whom have not thought to
apply their skills to plant science but
um I think a number of them would be
happy to um
uh and uh there are again lots of
resources I this talk was originally a
co- talk with um uh the the center for
Nano scale physics uh nanoscale Science
and Technology the CNF but I'd also
point to the and I believe they're
represented here uh the um Center for
Material Science um which is like the
CNF uh an extremely uh robust long
longterm effort which in particular for
example has some of the best
microscopists in the world and the
absolute best uh uh tem facilities that
can be had in Academia and uh uh this is
actually Lena uh is uh recently arrived
and recently acquired a34 million
transmission electron microscope and is
very interested in biological uh
questions uh so to summarize I there I
there are opportunities that go from uh
the the very most basic molecular
biology through to uh something that
will be coupled to something strapped to
an a tractor um I think uh that and
there's it be it'd be very nice to see
um the kind of uh interactions vigorous
interactions that have been going on
between engineers and human health
biologists going on between engineers
and uh plant biologist um for if there
are any decision makers in the audience
one of the things that helped a whole
lot early on were seed
grants uh that uh we had no
collaborations with wild Cornell Medical
School and then they started to just
sprinkle on these 50k seed grants uh
once a year and it was amazing how
quickly that um changed um now of course
biomedical Engineering also grew a whole
uh program um but I think there's uh
there there's reason for this kind of
interaction um I think could lead to a
lot of activity so that I'd like to uh
thank my group um a number of people a
number of collaborators including those
here I think uh Bob I have not gotten
you on my collaborator list yet we got
to get those papers out but that wasn't
because of that but uh so thank you very
much for your attention and I'll be
happy to take any
questions
well there are few sensors in for rux
[Music]
potential encodable encodable sens
yeah well that's that's great but it's
not always that easy to read them and so
I think uh Becky and Warren over uh
Warren zipfel over in uh are working on
ways to read those sensors which are
finicky um and of course always the more
folks can get for sensor the better and
working out tricks to uh um calibrate
them and so on so that's a good them
that I agree if you can if you can grow
your censor into your plant express it
in the
[Music]
small um I I do think there are uh
physical uh size exclusion steps that um
uh animal cells that Lind the vessels uh
actively uh and po uh components at
least in the context of Z will not make
it into the you know not make it into
any all they would be size excluded by
border pits for example and challenging
they would be size excluded from
entering the
roof and so that but what that Dimension
is is uh not I think is somewhat species
dependent and and not always well
characterized but I think some of
Nan materials are small enough to be
taken
up um somebody in the a may know better
about uptake of
particulate U but but it's it is it is a
trick and that's again and you can't
just use a hyp to go into the
is or
the it'll stop working that's a that's a
frustration so you mentioned kind of the
differing scales of plant versus
mamalian trials I mean like a small corn
breeding trial might be 10,000 plants
which would be an absolutely massive Tri
on rats much less humans I guess what
are kind of in terms of these
Technologies and meleon systems for
tissue sensing what are the largest
scales that people work on and how could
that be modified for the scales that you
know someone we eating like the cereals
might be working well so there are two
two uh so if you uh given the budgets I
hear of breeding programs you could get
people interested enough to make enough
sensors that their cost would go very
low so if I can make enough of myyl
sensors to satisfy readers if they they
if they have a way to use them uh I can
bring the cost in that sensor down to to
to be very inexpensive because it
benefits from the the scaling of price
that micro benefits from um so that's
one if if if there is a if there is a a
real investment um the you know you
carry a supercomputer in your pocket for
a few hundred dollars um so that is impr
the other perspective is that some of
these approaches around So-Cal nanom
materials these are can be synthesized
by the many on the many gr scale and so
that they can be uh if if the delivery
can be worked out that um can
uh and there's one reader stractor one
tractor might be able to read all plants
and you you have to paint every leaf but
you must be doing something like some
such human interaction with every one of
those 10,000 uh species right now so
it's not today I don't if I had it I I
doing something with it but the 10,000
replicas of an experiment out the field
is is a challenge but is a good one is
what I'm saying and I'm hoping I'm
trying to articulate that to to this
community and to the engineering
community and hopefully to the funding
community that there'll be an investment
because I don't think it's there's no
reason it's impossible but but what what
do the engineer really need from uh the
plan biologist is what to
measure and it's not just your dream of
what to measure but what is it to come a
compromise between what would be the
perfect piece of information and what
would be scalable to, because of a
reasonable price and so and my feeling
is that the the Breeders uh are quite
they don't they don't think about it
they don't and this is the the the the
gene to trait Gap uh they they're so
focused on the the gene identific a that
they're not worrying much
about what traits might be um good if
they could get
Beyond it seems like being able to tap
into the flow and
sense
small signal through the would be game
Cher understanding happening certainly
in plant miction there a lot happen
and you know there are curious things
that could potentially build for example
some
ins but are there any ideas you have
well so so I once we we've explored some
of these in the CNF for example of
trying to so the the proasus the prascus
of uh FL feeding insect can go through
without
inducing uh
CL that's the right word um and so this
ought to be replicatable um and there's
been a huge effort on micr needle drug
delivery for human isssues and so it's
extremely fine so it's like with p pipet
uh but replicated uh many times over
with tunable chemistry on the surface so
I that yeah yes I think there is a
possibility there um uh to and I think
the looking to the bi biology so I think
also um uh species like the mistl toe
that grows itself into tissue without
disrupting uh tissue the biochemistry
that allows to do that gracefully um the
suppressors of plant response those are
those are part of I think of what's
going to have to be um allowed for a
graceful interface
Yeah question yeah okay question yeah um
so you I mean you focus a lot on on
mechanical properties of course plants
are engaging a lot of exotic chemistry
as well if you thought about sort of
technologies that might be used to of
make sense of of of you know discovering
a compound or something like that that
that uh yeah absolutely and so I and so
for example and and and in the examples
I've shown much of the focus has been
about so is is on uh biomes macro bi
macro molecules and small molecules uh
in terms of uh uh analysis on small
samples on small scales and cheap
devices that is a big part of what um
the so-called lab on a chip effort has
been and so whether it's uh
the volatiles around the plant or small
molecule signaling within tissues uh
it's a good Target it's not one that my
own group has been um uh focusing on but
there's a lot of expertise on campus in
that uh in that analytical chemistry um
scale
down so I like to say that I think that
uh a given us a number of really
excellent illustration examples of what
can be done as well as some really
stimulating ideas of opportunities where
I think our community has to uh you know
maybe do some more thinking about how we
can uh address some real breakthrough uh
new advancements by bringing together
our problems with uh you st a toools and
before thanking you don't forget that
we'll have a session out in the hall
where we can continue discussion with a
and also with others from these you
other facilities it' be great to have a
volunteer to come do the reciprocal talk
in
engineering uh or volunteer somebody you
know but uh I think you could to to
because again they they they you talk to
students and all they've heard about the
biomedical challenges they've heard
about tissue engineering they've heard
about cancer uh and they know less about
um problems from Agriculture and plant
science and so it it' be great to be
talk and we could find a good form for
okay thank you so
[Applause]
much this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu