this is a production of Cornell
University Bill thanks a lot for the
introduction uh I remember interviewing
for my position back in 1981 and I was
in this room now it's been remodled a
few times since then but uh this takes
me way back and I'm not going to try to
give a history of what I've done you
know I was thinking of a title like 43
years and 43 minut but I said no so I
thought maybe some of the more recent
projects and trying to what we're
calling Under the topic of modern seed
technology uh there's many many people
as all of us go through Cornell
especially for such a long period that
you run across and how they've affected
you that they're Cooperators there have
been grad students in your program
visiting scientists a number of people
way way too many to to list here but I I
want to mention just
one was Dr Carl Leopold who was at the
Boyce Thompson Institute is probably one
of our most famous seed biologist the
past several years ago uh he was I would
say this you know good teachers teach
Next Level motivate he was actually
pretty inspirational in some of the
things that he was doing and it kind of
rubbed off in some of the early work
that we did in more the applied area
relations in water relations of seeds
uh Carl was also Thomas bjorkman's PhD
advisor so that kind of connects him a
little bit with some of the things so I
just want to start with that I said
there's just so so many people but give
you
that okay so obviously my life is
seeds and this is what you're going to
be hearing but hopefully there may be
some of the little nuggets that uh some
little ahas I had thought about that
maybe that would work in sep things that
you're doing in in your own program so
first of all we're going to start off
what is the kind of looking at the I'll
call it the agronomic life cycle of
seeds from production of seeds all the
way through to crop
production now here and focusing on
vegetable crops most of the seed
production harvesting this is we are not
here in the Northeast in an area where
there is that much seed production most
of that would be in the western part of
the United States where the climates
much better or much of it now is is more
of a global business in different
countries based on environmental
parameters that are in that which are
optimal for those particular crops
conditioning is really kind of the
physical sizing of the seed grading
seeds try to improve the seed quality
this is all when they're in the dry
condition after the Harvest storage of
the seed preser really the key there is
Preservation of the seed quality the
germination the Vigor of the seed lant
this is what we're trying to preserve
until the time of sewing now we come
into the area that we're going to be
talking about is Under the Umbrella of
seed enhancements and there's different
examples of that I'm going to go through
a few examples of some of our work in
seed treatments and Seed Coatings but
those of you familiar may have worked
with seed priming techniques priming
would also be listed as one of these
type of enhancements we're not going to
be talking about that though this
morning or this
afternoon seed quality assurance with
germination seed quality testing is is
really important to make sure that the
grower has high quality seeds and has
some parameter by looking at the label
of the seeds so they know what that that
quality is now we move into more of what
is happening in the north east and this
part is the planting of seeds in the
crop production and most faculty
programs are
focus on that area but just realize that
there's there's many steps to this
agronomic life cycle what I've done is
since we're not in a seed producing area
is really try to Target my research
program in this post Harvest area of
working with seeds what can we do to
treat them to enhance uh their
performance
potential this is kind of breakdown
there's a lot of subtopics under the sea
treatments and codings we'll talk about
kind of the the the cookbook part of the
composition the processes that are
involved and then go through a few case
studies uh using organic seed treatment
insecticides on onion onion being
obviously major crop here in in in New
York State uh with the work with hemp
that we've done uh and development of
organic seed treatment fungicides some
of the experimental materials that we
tested at the time we'll go through that
kind of quickly then we'll kind of break
away from the seed treatments and try to
better understand the biology the
science part and the seed coat
permeability and that then Segways into
a more recent work and using some of the
systemic seed treatments this is not now
for plant uh protection per se but
actually visualization of where the
seedlings are and that'll become obvious
as we go through them the last one is is
kind of where our last topic kind of my
what I consider kind of my last topic
working with with different faculty and
crop and soil science with Tony D Tomaso
John Losi and entomology on this mscp
multiple seed Zia pellet and here we're
looking at to enhance the biodiversity
with establishing various pollinator
plants
so member of a of a multi-state project
when I think it's it's been very good
that there are a group of us seed
scientists uh that that work together
collaborate together at least exchange
knowledge together and so there is a
review of this seed enhancements you can
see it's kind of dated 1998 that I was
the senior author that so I came up with
this definition that we're looking at
post Harvest methods that improve the
germination or seedling
growth or facilitate the delivery of
seeds and then finally application of
other materials required at time of
sewing the examples that I'm going to be
talking about really fall into number
two and three if you're doing the seed
priming or we've done work on bio
stimulants that would kind of fall into
the number one so so he seed
enhancements is not just a method per se
it's really kind of an umbrella
terminology for a number of Technologies
under that
umbrella we're going to talk about the
different seed Coatings we'll use onions
here as an example uh onions are small
seeds irregular shape we you see about
3.5 millimeters the size of the raw
onion seeds in the upper right hand
corner and then there's different
coating technology
the blue are film coating the film
coating is originally adapted from the
pharmaceutical in The Confectionary area
of the colorants and the plasticizers
the materials that are used uh in those
areas are then been adopted for
application of seed treatments pelleted
seeds that is used on onions still used
commercially there with so much filler
material that this kind of changes the
whole ballistics and improves the plab
ility for the singulation of those seeds
the encrusting is somewhat of a hybrid
between the two of the film coding and
the encrusting where there's certain
amount of materials that are use part of
the buildup of
those all right
so M who H from my laboratory uh we have
a a review article came out a few years
ago trying to take a a broad view of the
whole seed treatments and the first is
is kind of is is kind of the cookbook
part of all the different potential
ingredients that can go into a seed
treatment and coating on the left hand
side are the different Active Components
so what are you trying to apply our
examples today are mostly focused around
the plant protectants insecticides
fungicides and that's where the largest
part of the the market share
is I'm seeing El Taylor but not the
slides I'm not sure how to remedy that
uh okay um
anyway getting back to the Active
Components there are the bio stimulants
like I said there's different materials
that are used and then we can see the
smaller the S YN means it's synthetic
material can be organic the O
parentheses so it kind of just
classifies
materials the next part is what do you
need to put on with the materials are
the liquids and water is the key water
we're not using any organic solvents I
did this project uh started with boy
Thompson many years ago and they said
we're going to put DMSO on tomato seeds
and I said don't do that so when you
look commercially water is the universal
carrier water is the universal solvent
when it comes to applying materials and
there's different binders which are the
adhesives hopefully Bruce is seeing this
now
I will text BL
okay so there's a different constituents
so we need the adhes adhesives which are
the binder materials which hold
materials onto the seed and then the
last column the solid particulates those
can be these binders so in the case of a
solid particulate binder with a filler
you're only applying powers and then you
only have to spray water so so a lot of
the streamlining has incurred most of
the fillers are just materials that have
been mined such as the Limestone gyps
and the only only thing that's been done
to those is just Milling those to
problem solve says Bruce rice yay okay
I'm glad everybody out there can see the
slides at this point so anyway this is
kind of like going into a kitchen and
then having all the ingredients there
but you need to decide what you want to
apply what is the purpose for that what
type of coding technology and we'll talk
about that
next if for example just just because
many people are interested in organic
production you need to use an
organically approved seed treatment to
do this but along with that organically
approved seed treatment such as a
biological you also need to use the
liquid components and the solid
particulates also have to be
organically approved so you have to
consider the whole system everything
that's going onto that seed must be
organically approved
uh again from that same review article
methodology we have a dry powder
application this would be an unarm
operation where the seeds would be
treated right prior to sewing and
probably the most common is say using
some of the inoculant materials rium
which are tend to be short-lived those
could be treated uh right on and right
prior to the sewing operation the rotary
coder which is probably one of the kind
of the key workhorses where the liquid
material is being atomized onto an
atomization disc and then is treating
the seeds and then you can adjust by
those fillers how much of the buildup so
you can see the seed dressing it's kind
of a European term the seed dressing
which is just what we would call a seed
treatment but it gets a little confusing
on on the process wise so it' be seed
dressing the film coating like I showed
you the encrust m so we're seeing more
and more of the buildup of the material
so finally the the seed pting operation
okay mentioned this dry powder so at
Geneva Kyle wickings is our turf
entomologist and he has a project where
they have certain biological seed
treatments and the
Biologicals uh cannot withstand kind of
a wedding and drying so they really are
very sensitive to these hydration
dehydration events and then I said
earlier that we have to use
water in our seed treatment and Seed
coating process so if we can't use water
then we go take a step back and use this
seed powder technique so everything your
biological is already as a dry powdered
formulation we're mixing this in this
case with a t graphite mixture and
that's being applied we're we're okay
now oh did they email back yeah I just
Bruce just sent a chck text we're okay
now uh so the upper pictures we're
looking at some field crops we use we
generally use a large seated crop as
kind of as a model system and then you
can see the tall fescue and the Kentucky
Blue there so that's an autof
fluoresence that bluish green color of
the seeds under just a black light long
long 365 nanometer long
wavelength then with our Coatings we are
applying a fluorescent Tracer material
that's where you see that bright red
we're doing this one is it's pretty to
see these but we really want to make
sure that we have uniformity application
over the seed surface and uniformity
from seed to seed so this gives us a
visual assessment for that delivery
system of just applying a dry powder
powder that adheres onto the seed
surface this is kind of the Workhorse in
our laboratory it's a small laboratory
scale we call it R6 which is means for a
6 inch diameter or 15 cm uh coating pan
this slide there on the right the
picture on the right shows an
atomization disc which goes down into
the unit so the liquids are applied
atomized into very small droplets and
the seeds are being treated and then
you're you're done so it's a rather
rapid process we have a even little
YouTube it hasn't gone viral yet but you
can actually see the process of actually
coating uh seeds and delivery
that um I was again with this
multi-state group out at Oregon State
and then we did a little field trip so
this company I
iny Oregon is in the wamit valley so
very large seed production and so that
little rotary pan that we have the
principles involved of a rotary is
scaled up in here so you going from 50
grams of seeds to hundreds and hundreds
of pounds of seeds so the technology is
nice is what we can do at the laboratory
scale is directly amendable to the
scaleup so it's not a toal total
separate consideration as part of the of
the research okay I'm going to digress
here a little bit U so we have these
pelleted seeds and this is a lettuce
seed which is inside of an
pellet take a res and cut through that
so now the question is is we know for
seed storage that the moisture content
of the seed is very important now how do
you measure the moisture content how do
you access that seed how do you
understand what that moisture is which
is important for the storage so the
figure with the broccoli and the snap
Bean is showing what we call a moisture
isotherm moisture isotherm is how water
is held onto the seeds and you can see
differences the broccoli which I say is
similar to soybean that would be an oil
or lipid storing seed the snap Bean is a
starch storing seed so you can see the
curves are roughly the same shape just
shifted because of the oil content
uh I just want to plug this too that
that this is published um Chris W's
second book and is a vegetable crop
physiology he also had the first edition
and I also had the first chapter in that
so very very proud that Lung Association
that I've had with Chris but that's
where this uh Mo moisture isotherm shows
which is really kind of our
understanding of water relations and
seeds in storage and under the dry
conditions
okay with that
background now you can kind of
extrapolate the line there of if you
hold seeds of 50% relative humidity that
will give us a corresponding moisture
content and we have laboratory
instrumentation uh at Geneva to actually
measure what we call water activity
which is the decimal equivalent of the
relative humidity so and I give this
talk to a lot of different organizations
different companies say well we don't
have a water activity instrument so I
tried to to try to make this more
simplified as well so this is just a
handheld relative humidity meter put
that inside of the Ziploc baggie or any
some sort of enclosed container so by
measuring that relative humidity you
then have the essence of what the water
activity is of the sample also we use
this uh nut is is clean cut because of
the gradations there but taking a small
piece of this paper putting it in with
the Ziploc baggie it'll just change
colors and so you again have an idea
especially if if the moisture of the
seeds is too high let's say say 60% or
higher than you'd have a quick diagnosis
of what the the water activity is or
equilibrium relative
humidity all right now we're going to
get back to our seed treatment
theme kind of two major groups are the
chemical seed treatments then the
biological seed treatments on the
chemicals which is the the probably
two-thirds of the market share is in
those areas uh insecticides and
fungicides and so we'll have some
examples of of the type of work that
I've done in collaboration with
entomologist and
pathologist mostly mostly at G Geneva
but also outside of the agretech
so I tell the onion story in very
quickly so when I came on the scene in
the 80s this is what Planting onions
look
like onion seeds for Dre seed onions to
produce bulbing onions planted early in
the season in April don't Harvest until
the end of the year the onions are grown
on organic soils we call Muk soils so
you can see in the tractor in the front
there's a large tank and so that's where
there's big volume gallonage with the
insecticide fungicides these some of
these insecticides were pretty nasty
materials in fact they've been banned in
the last few years we are seeing the use
of farmers are using pelleted seeds for
singulation with a planter type called a
belt seeder you can see those the Stan
hay type of a planter so you could have
the Precision placement so there's some
parts of the technology that we could
kind of build on through our
research so what I kind of prophesized
uh back when I was younger and I still
had red hair is I said you know we're
going to get away from all these tanks
we're going to get away from all this
hauling these pesticides over the land
have to go back and refill again
everything's going to go on the seed the
seed treatment is going to go right on
with the coating so that was kind of
what my prophecy was I I got a little
bit of push back by some of the
Pathologists but that was you know we're
going back to a previous light if on on
that so let's just stick with with what
we did to to to achieve that goal first
of all you needed a seed coating
technology you needed a delivery system
of getting these seed treatments on the
seeds and especially looking at pretty
high loading rates we couldn't use the
little seed dressing Technique we needed
so that's where the pellet came in where
part of the pellet during the formation
of that pellet there could be a band
called pellet loading of the materials
and this is done by the the seed
treatment industry the seed pellin
industry much of it out in the west
coast the second part is you need some
different materials new chemistry
materials that are one going to be very
effective have downside very minimal
phytotoxicity but also which is very
challenging with specialty crops low
acreage high value crops is the
registrant must support that
label so I mentioned about these
different pellings uh when I started
this project with just comparing
different pellets there was probably
about 10 15 different companies now we
we have five companies that do pting now
they don't just do vegetables they'll
they'll do flower seeds and things so so
they're not restricted to vegetables but
that's probably their their
largest part of their their business but
the pting technology is well worked out
within these
industries and I just want to call
attention the type of pellets we have we
call a hybrid and then a split coat so
let's look at the the picture and the
lower left hand corner the tan ones are
what we have a split coat so in other
words the p are planted they're in a
moist substrate and there's like a
cleavage that the seed actually the
pallet opens up that allows oxygen to
get to the germinating seed and there's
no restriction for the germination the
hybrid is a hybrid between the split
coat and what we call a melt coat in
other words it kind of dissolves away
and so that you're seeing cleavage in
different areas it achieves the same and
as far as Pest Management with putting
seed treatments they're both effective
as Delivery Systems for the insecticides
fungicides this is what some of the
newer Planters look like moving away
from the old Bell Planters to vacuum
seeders and so now you can plant the
palleted seed but you can also go to the
encrusted seed the yellow ones and the
upper right hand corner the advantage
there is there's a lot less physical
material the shipping costs are reduced
the production costs by the seed
companies that are making these is also
reduced so it's become a little bit more
economical to go that way
again combining that with the vacuum
Cedar
technology I'm going to bring in now
getting to the chemistry materials and
as a challenge which is a very large
overarching problem is the use of
neonicotinoids and neonicotinoid Seed
treatments there are three seed
treatments we have just showing you the
chemical name the moper the trade name
GAO and then the company that is selling
those so some of these are also used in
the onions they're used widely and other
mostly in field crops as a seed
treatment
insecticide environmental concerns with
colony collapse disorder some of the
dust off problems from those seeds that
have been treated with these new
nicotinoids in New York state we are
going to have a ban of the neonicotinoid
seed treatments on field crops in
2029 so the our IPM group and others are
working how we going to see some
substitutes how we dealing with this
challenge with the loss of these kind of
this major class of seed treatment
incde at Geneva we've kind of handled
this in the vegetables where we were
aware of this well before there was any
bans or restrictions just because of the
environmental concerns so we really need
alternate chemistries for this efficient
early season pest manag
management um this some early work when
Brian N is a vegetable entomologist and
he and I worked collaborated really
since he first started at Geneva as
assistant professor now full professor
and department chair whatever they call
them now at Geneva
administrators so the material that we
latched on to is called spinoid now if
you're familiar with Pest Management and
foler material spinoid is used as a
foler
insecticide it is the entrust
formulation is organically approved so
with that organic approval we said aha
that that is very good to have something
that's already omry approved but now is
it going to work so we did the work way
back at the time and it is quite
effective as far as controlling onion
maggots applied as a seed
treatment so if you want to try to put
this more on yeah a time frame because
working on specialty crops working on
pesticides it's a long time of work to
get something to see the light of day so
again going back to the time I started
we did have one SE treatment fungicide
this carboxin thym which also had some
phytotoxicity uh the first insecticide
was Brian n's predecessor his name is
Chuck eckenroad and so in the mid 90s we
had that cyromazine uh which is as an
insecticide still used to this day then
we see the spinoid and some of the other
the farm more packaging that senta had
done um at the time one I didn't talk
about is is a more recent uh seed
treatment fungicide for onion smut
called pen fluin but you can see a lot
of years a lot of time is involved and
again is having making sure that that
you have the registr the company that's
going to stand behind that especially
when they're going to label that for
commercial use and Brian nton and I had
several really good materials looked
really great excellent at Pest
Management but the compan for one reason
or another said no we're not going to
pursue that
so it died right there so where is that
now we're still working on this we're
working with companies that are doing
the pelting Brian is uh leading that
Leo's a PhD student in his laboratory
and then we have a number of faculty in
different areas maruth McDonald's up at
GF in Ontario she's doing trials with
some of the pellets that are being
produced Tim Waters in Washington
Stewart in Oregon uh California so so
we're so we're now kind of broadened out
with some of the the field testing in
cooperation with field entomologist
Christy hoping is with CCE she's out in
the bavia area uh where we're working
with her on some of the seed treatment
fungicides as well so there's kind of a
continuation it's not just our work and
done there is a continuation that I want
to talk about in several of these topic
areas uh next Case Case Study is going
to be with
hemp when Larry smart first kind of
formed the Cornell team we were
fortunate to be a part of part of that
team and dealing with some of the seed
science and techn techology issues the
first one he says well we're going to
treat the seeds and some of our standard
coating materials we are
using you can see there's Green in that
middle seeds but it's very
splotchy uh some were well treated some
w't treated at all so we I said we
really need a much better film coating
polymer to give us uniformity of
application so I have good contacts with
the with the seed industry with uh
companies this happen to be in
I said we have this new seed it has kind
of a waxy seed covering to it is there
any film forming materials that you have
that might work and they knew nothing
about hemp at the time and so they said
we've developed this that we've used
this on sorghum as another waxy seed we
have good relations they provide they
didn't tell me all the leev herbs and
spices that are in it but they provided
my
laboratory with this material and I've
had these long-term relationships with
these seed andan M companies that
they're willing to collaborate with us
maybe not give us all the Le herbs and
spices but very fortunate that we don't
have to do every inch of the way on the
development because we'd never be able
to do the things accomplish what we need
to if we had to do
that so now we're looking for control of
damping off much of that caused by
pythium but there's other pathogens
involved it could be uh biochemical
materials organic copper and phosphate
materials be examples in different
microbials so I'm going to kind of cut
if if you are interested in this I can
send you the PDF of the paper we
published a few years ago but just think
up in the green are all the Biologicals
the trod deras the Basils some of the
major materials that have been used for
a number of years for controlling of
damping off and other cropping systems
those in the middle in red is our
organic copper or phosphate so we'd call
these biochemical material the group in
blue as our chemical fungicides our
apron XL Maxum type of materials which
are widely labeled on on most crop seeds
so this these are the seed treatment
lists that we went into with this
project a lot of the screening we do is
in the laboratory is is how can we make
sure that some of these have efficacy or
not so we we went to taking a field soil
actually just not too far from here in
East itha that had natural levels of of
pythium present in that soil it's
damping off like see a lot of damping
off in that from that field so we got
the field soil then we're using that
mixed with sand over our roll time you
see the brown paper is from our
germination
test uh we're looking at a time course
with the hemp hemp germinate very
rapidly so after four days we're already
seeing a nice rout and shoot on that
after seven days there's quite a bit of
damping off and death of the seed lanes
and then we get to 10 days uh pretty
much everything is wiped out so so that
was kind of our screening
uh assay that we were using uh in my
laboratory this is some of the the data
from that on the far left the black is
the non-treated control the interesting
thing is we tested all these Biologicals
all the hopes of Biologicals none of
them are worth of darn none of them
really gave any level of protection the
phosphite material gave some level of
protection in particular the Alum which
is the organic copper with the letter A
on the top was just as good as many of
the the apron
Maxum some of the chemical fungicide C
treatments we also through the ir4 did
two years of testing Cornell Virginia
Tech North Dakota state where we had
field testing under multiple
locations and uh just kind of go through
this really quickly but just and this is
just from one of the sites East actually
East itha where we knew we had the the
pythium they were generally seen some of
the the materials now these are the
trade names but there organic materials
the organic biochemical materials
looking quite well in
that so again the biochemical materials
looking quite promising with this also
is organic it's already been organically
approved for other applications the
chemicals worked very well but senta
owns those materials and they basically
said we're not interested in supporting
anything on hemp at the time so that
stopped none of our Biologicals really
worth worth a d so after we finished
this uh Chris smart and her PhD student
Patrick McMullen uh have done some
additional work we're just kind of
summarizing some of that that work up
now so so there's been continuation and
further uh field testing at Geneva with
some of the the key the kind of our
optimal treatments from this
project okay I'm kind of use this from
the Geneva colleagues are going to
remember some of the people uh
when this was taken I was Department
shair of what we called Horticultural
Sciences at the time so Lan Rego in the
upper leftand corner was the
administrative assistant uh there some
of the people from my laboratory Joe
Shale worked for many many years in the
upper right worked with dick Robinson in
the plant breeding program worked with
Thomas borkman and I towards the end of
his career uh but the the lower right is
Julia Salena and she's done a lot she
had kind of the good SE
physiology training from Bose came to my
laboratory and we're going to kind of
talk into some of the work that she did
not a seed treatment work per se but I
thought I'd throw this in just just as I
I like to see uh what people look like
way back back in the in the
time all right so seed treatments can
have two different kind of a modes of
movement they can either work as a
contact material some of the older
materials the fungus Ides capan thym
have that type of contact
activity some of the newer many of the
newer ones have systemic activity the
systemic activity allows uptake by The
Roots into the transpiration stream all
the way up to the leaves so this when
some of our seed treatments some of the
neonicotinoids but others were coming
along we were asking questions we knew
that they're taking up here we're we're
killing cucumber
beetles uh with a systemic sea treatment
but our question was is how are these
materials moving into the are they
moving through the seed coat into the
seed and taken up how how are they
actually moving so that was kind of our
our curiosity at the time first thing is
what and and and this applies if you're
applying herbicides or any other
material and you're looking at systemic
uptake what are the physical chemical
properties that that compound has to
have a compound must have a balance
between the hydrophilic and the
hydrophobic char character to enter into
root system some of the classic work was
done on this in the early 80s with
herbicide
moving we have what's called a partition
coefficient where You' put the material
in with water and octanol octol is an
eight carbon alcohol and how does it
partition into those two and that gives
you an idea of that relationship with
the hydrophilic hydrophobic you come up
with kind of this gaussian distribution
or you call it a bell-shaped curve and
number of our treatments are are shown
here the thyoxin Meto these are all the
neonic ramine B we'll talk about is not
a pesticide but a fluorescent Tracer and
we'll be talking about this in the next
section and then some of the other
materials so all the materials have
their own particular log of K also
called the log of P the partition
coefficient so that tells us the
relative water solubility and lipid
solubility but at the top of that
gussian distribution is where there'd be
the greatest amount of systemic uptake
for a particular
compound so again we're we're not
interested in herbicide uptakes we're
really interested in seed coat
permeability how do these materials do
they actually enter into the
seed or are they blocked by the seat
coat so we can have a visual so we
decided early on we were doing this work
if we had to get c14 labeled or other
ways of try trying to trace these
materials one it'd be very difficult to
get it it'd be even more difficult to
dispose of this and so we decide at the
time we need a better system that we can
do in a laboratory so we adopted the use
of these fluorescent tracers that had we
could get the particular log of K we
could get a lot of their particular uh
characteristics along with the
fluorescence and mo make sure their
movement why is this important let's say
you have this case was tomato we had a
project a few years ago and then say if
you have an
internal seedborn pathogen a bacterial
pathogen in the embryo and you say well
we're we'll just soak the seeds and the
chemical is going to get to that does it
get the question is does it really get
there so this is what kind of our
inquiry was is is are these materials
that yes you're soaking the seed and yes
they take up water but is the active
material getting to the seed getting to
the embryo more
specifically so we end up with three
classifications based on their seed coat
permeability a soybeans same as our our
Bean family
physis if we have compounds that are
nonionic or ionic in nature both of
those will move through the seed coat so
in other words we're playing these as as
a seed treatment we put them in a moist
soil and as the seeds take up water it
would basically allow the materials to
migrate into the the embryo so it's a
visualization
of the
movement the next group is in many crops
switch grass we found hemp is going to
be in this onion Tomatoes just a number
of these this is what we call Selective
permal seed coat selective meaning that
only the nonionic compounds which is the
the cumerin which are this light blue
fluoresence that you're seeing is
actually moving into the seed the
rodamine is an ionic material charged
molecule it is being blocked you can see
the tomatoes very Vivid in the Tomato
hairs is that ionic material being
dropped there and not getting into the
embryo and then there's a last group
which we're calling the
nonpermeable and this is with the
cucurbits so cucurbits have particular
morphology with the perisperm endosperm
envelope acts like a little cellophane
around there is blocking both compounds
now when I say non permal people think
is well these seeds take up water
they're not hard seeds no don't be
confused this is not a hard seed in this
this is actually the layers that
surround the embryo are actually
barriers and then this just from some of
our reviews and again hemp we added uh
through some of our our earlier work
onto this would be an example of the
selective
permability okay we're going to kind of
take with that basis that we're using FL
ENT tracers and how can we kind of
exploit this into kind of in we'll talk
about into a a a weed management and so
when Yu Jing was hired at Geneva as an
engineer uh he had a lot of knowledge
and being able to do work with imaging
systems so here we're treating this case
we're just showing some bean seeds with
a rodamine which to us visually be read
but it's also has a strong fluoresence
to it the setup that was built with
using particular wavelength lights LED
lights and we'll see in the green re
where we're exciting uh the ramine and
looking at the fluoresence from that
some of the lights that were set up some
of the the physical Hardware that he
developed that we used in our
laboratory so we have non-treated so
we're treating the seed okay we're
treating the seed we're planting the
seed the seed grows into a Seedling and
then we're looking at does the material
translocate up into the plant so we're
using the white light so we're looking
at reflection of light under the
non-rated and you can see well there's a
green leaf and then we're taking little
leaf disc punch so we can quantify from
a certain surface area and the ramine
treated seed looks about the same way
but now if we look at that the ramine
fluoresence under the fluorescence
detection system the Imaging system I'm
just we're just showing the silhouette
where you can't even see the fluoresence
because there's really yeah there's
nothing to be taken up in the
non-treated where you can see exactly
the leaf and particularly the veins of
the leaves why these compounds have
apoplastic movement they're coming up
through the translocation stream and
then they get deposited in into the
leaves but you can see the these
materials quite
vividly we we've uh taken that and then
with our h project that we had going
concurrently we're looking at and it's
maybe difficult to see but we're looking
at pelleted hemp seeds so our pelleting
technology we talked about we actually
had a company do that for us then we're
adding ramine those on the upper right
have that purplish color so we actually
treated those with ramine then so that's
how we did the seed treatment is by
treating the pellet again doing the same
type of of work that we did with the
sampling and so let's just look at the
graphical part on the right where you're
seeing just a trace amount of background
of fluoresence from the he the pellet
only we're also growing these with a
Velvet Leaf as a weed as our model weed
in this but then where you had the hemp
pallet with RB which stands for the
ramine B then we see extremely over
tenfold increase in in the signal so
where are we going with this is bringing
Linn into the the program with this is
then this could actually go to the field
where you actually treat the seeds your
crop
seeds it You' be able to identify those
seedlings out in the field and then the
weeds that are around that are not
having the ramine be so they're not
taking it up so then you have a way to
to differentiate based on the
fluorescence profile of the crop the
treated crop versus the the weed
and that's just kind of a graphical
abstract from this from the same um just
kind of as as a landmark for us massis
here we in eug Jing and Lynn we spent a
lot of time we just finished a paper and
just got it accepted so this is our big
yay to to get this stuff to see the the
light of day and and special issue of
exploring application of artificial
intelligence and image processing and AG
culture so I thought this is pretty neat
that we made it with the AI papers as
well with doing this project with Eugene
and the
Imaging all right we're going to the
last section
now
so nothing about Pest Management here
we're taking a different
angle we're looking at the law of
biodiversity which was attributed to the
use of GMO field crops when we have all
these herbicide resistance jeans we can
see soybeans before round up a lot of
weeds and the farmers hate those weeds
so when we had the GMO technology then
we said how clean the fields like
Farmers love no
weeds the problem is is when we do that
then we start losing the
biodiversity the insects some of the
other
pollinating and one that we're
interested is particular in is in come
on in the Monarch the monarch butterfly
the decline of the monarch butterfly the
Monarch requires milkweed to complete
its life
cycle so if we lose the milkweed we
don't have place for the monarchs to go
ahead
into multiply so this is kind of the the
problem again John Losi from entomology
is a project leader on our current Grant
with this Tony damaso in weed science in
soil and crop soil so this is just from
data from the literature of looking at
this decline in the milkweed so we're
kind of defining what the problem is
we're also seeing this Con commitment
loss in the Monarch population so to a
critical
situation so this this is our kind of
our our challenge that we took on kind
of as our Cornell team we already know
the monic butterfy is now listed as
endangered by this committee it's just
came out dangered
2023 our challenge is how do you restore
the milkweed population if we could
restore the milkweed we're hoping that
we can reestablish the
monarchs now we have to go to the
milkweed seed and we look in the lower
right hand corner the milked seeds we
have the dimensions there but they're
very flat
seeds kind of pearshaped seeds so you
can't use you can't go and use your
conventional planter to plant the seeds
they're just not handle that there are
specialized Planters native seed drills
that have been dealt very expensive most
Farmers aren't going to have something
like this so our paradigm shift is let's
develop the new seed technology where we
can plant the milkweed seeds but use the
farmers existing corn planter or
existing uh crop
planter so this kind of is a nutshell of
what we developed together and actually
have a patent application on this
starting off with the
milkweed where then considering this to
go say into a field corn so we're using
field corn to make 3D molds that shape
of the flat don't if you know corn and
you do large flat corn seeds is our
model that we're making here that is
we're making a mold and then we're
putting a dough with the seeds inside of
that so this is where we get the
mszp multiple seed ZF for corn
pellets so we're having
these seeds the milkweed seeds embedded
into that we can then go ahead and use a
conventional planter just shows a vacuum
seeder there on the right hand side that
we have is a model system in in Geneva
so we can go ahead and plant those so
this is this is kind of where our our
first ideas and kind of the conception
of this where we could try to take these
wild these these pollinator species that
do not lend themselves to our planting
technology and then put them in a
conventional
planner so where are we now we've done
the research Innovation now is how you
going to scale up we're making 40 of
these mzps at one time well it's going
to take
46,000 to plan an acre well how are we
going to do that huge multiplication so
the scale of now becomes very critical
we're working with a company they're
based outside of Atlanta Georgia called
canar collaborating with them in the
scale up so that's kind of where we are
right now but there's already other cor
cortiva on the lower right hand corner
cortiva you may not know the the name
but CA owns Pioneer Seed Company the
largest field crop companies in the
United States they are going to be our
conduit to connect this to our rad crop
Growers so so that is our scheme and
that's what we're work working towards
right now is to get from the the patent
application all the way to agriculture
so I know I'm probably running over time
a little bit but I want to thank
everybody msi's here from my laboratory
and how we've taken and used different
aspects our tools and Seed Science and
Technology to address particular
problems in vegetable crops and Beyond
thank you so much
questions for
Alan uh Alan thank you that was a a
really good seminar uh so 43 years ago
you called it you said 44 okay going on
to the seed and and and you're
absolutely right so 43 or 44 years from
now what does seed technology look
like boy Justin so so kind of for
everybody
just oh so so Justine asked that was a
nice review of some of the things that
we've done in modern seed technology
what is the next 40 years look like in
modern seed
technology so first of all much of the
what work that is going on is going on
within industry we don't always know
that until it's actually developed so we
we have a very small University base
kind of besides in the US kind of on a
global basis working in this
area what we're doing right now in
horiculture is we've had the approval to
go ahead and to kind of fill my position
but basically is to continue in the seed
biology seed technology area and Larry
smart is chairing that search committee
so we're we're hoping to hire a person
kind of in this General vein well we
don't know exactly how they're going to
uh what projects they would do but kind
of in this general
area but there's there's going to be a
need because of seed technology of the
importance of high quality seeds we're
dealing mostly of veg crops and
ornamental seeds that are direct seed
field crops it has implications with
others like the weed seeds with our
pollinators so there's a lot of use of
seeds both in agriculture and what's
goes on in nature so there's a lot of
opportunities a lot of challenges in
there so that's where I think where the
challenges are going to be
is you know I was never thinking about
the monarch butterfly when Tony and John
approached me with this but there it is
and now what are we going to do with it
so I I think there's going to be a lot
of those aha type of things where we can
see with with the with the background
and the knowledge that we've kind of
started and then others can continue can
continue in this in this path again
there's a lot of work that's going on
with industry so that is going to have
to be kind of integrated or at least be
able to be tested before we can even
hand it over to our Growers and say yeah
you're this is ready to go go ahead and
do something when it's a pretty new
technology so so I think there's there's
definitely the research component but
also the extension Outreach component
about what is coming along now and then
what what may be available for New York
agriculture in particular vegetable and
other Growers good question and anything
from Geneva question
wise um
I'll jump in here I'm not seeing
anything on
chat can you can you hear me Steve
reiners oh yes Steve reiners okay Alan
Taylor not so much a question but um
sort of just wanted to thank you for the
work that you've done over the years
because you have been extremely helpful
to me and I know to many other people as
we always talked about you always shared
your toys quite nicely and uh and you
shared your expertise said for that I
just really wanted to to thank you for
all the work that we've done together
over the years too so thank
you Dave thank you I mean I think that's
you you know while I'm still makes me
excited to go to work every day is the
people that I get to work with you know
it's it's in horiculture it's outside of
horiculture it could be somebody at the
University of GF or it could be somebody
in in in in the in Washington State
University so there's always a challenge
and and that really makes it fun for me
uh so so yeah thank thank you for that
that Steve and yes I I do like to share
our toys
here uh anything else yeah yeah um do
these treatments today exist for tree
seeds and
um do you not in studies that looked at
um in ulating seeds with
beneficial micro such as micro of
Fung for
example okay the the the question was is
on tree seeds and where is Seed
technology on tree
seeds I'm not aware of any say
registered materials like a fungicide
even though it would be very effective
for that I think there would be an
opportunity and again since I can't
really answer it is some of the
biological that would be effective first
for some of the damping off
organisms um there is some of the The
Beneficial uh uh fungi some of it comes
into the delivery system how big are the
spores that you have to apply what is
the size of the seed so so some of it is
is kind of is how do you how do you
develop the coding technology for that
particular biological and things like
that so I'm not as definitely not as
knowledgeful what's going on in that
area but kind of as I look at kind of
looking backwards is the vegetable seeds
because of the value of the seeds and
you have high value small seated crops
lower value large seated crops there's a
lot of different challenges and I think
a lot of that that's developed then will
spin off and so the the trees not that
they're not important but there's a lot
they can they can kind of adopt from
some of the work that's already being
done with some of the these other crop
seeds good now I have to do some HK work
to better answer that question
right thank you very much all
right this has been a production of
Corell University on the web at
cornell.edu