this is a production of Cornell
University so thank you so much Dan for
that introduction and thank you everyone
for coming out to the seminar today I'm
really excited to talk with you about my
work looking at the influence of
microbial Community Dynamics on the
cycling and stabilization of soil carbon
um so the first piece of this story kind
of comes
why are we interested
so so where that comes in is looking out
how soy carbon or soil organic matter
relates to this concept of soil health
and so soil health is this idea that we
have our soils maintaining this
continued ability to be a leing living
ecosystem that can sustain our plants
animals and humans so in agriculture
looking at means sustainable and
productive soil system and where soil
organic comes into this equation is that
we see that it contributes to better
soil structure it can modulate soil
water availability it's an important
store of soil nutrients and then also
looking at the global scale it's a
globally important part so especially
understanding climate change so of
organic matter is being po that so if we
have this goal of increasing soil health
we also see that increasing soil organic
matter can help us achieve that
particularly in our agricultural soils
and so if we want to have this and
achieve this goal we need to understand
how soil organic matter is accumulating
and also how it's rain and so some re uh
some of the questions we're asking
ourselves when try to approach this are
what compounds make up S organic matter
and where are those compounds coming
from so last week we actually heard a
talk from love which was looking at this
first question so what compounds they're
making up with
Sol so my work is where they getting
into the second question of where are
these compounds coming from who is Mak
these compounds
that so Recent research into this has
looked at how microbial necas can be
contributing to so oranic PN also called
soil organic so what the study did is
they got metadata from a bunch of
different studies that measure microbial
nephros markers the extract sing organic
carbon and then estimated how much we
how much of a contribution neas was
making to the overall soil organic
carbon and so they looked at this across
the range of soil deps and then actually
see all of the deps kind together and
they looked at different types of soils
so C soil vaselin soils and then also
Forest soils and across all these
systems microbial necromass was measured
and estimated to make up around 50% of
the soil carbon and so particularly
focusing on this term of
necromass it's showing the importance of
understanding the microbial
contributions to this the import
microbial death cyes understand so
understanding how they're making their
ne how much they're
Mak so now the question becomes this is
the piece that we need to understand how
are we going to
measure it's not a trivial thing to so
typically if you think about a micro and
you think about typical microbiological
methods in order to measure do
cultivation so you would get an isolate
of the micro and grow it up in a lab
culture and use that to measure
death the problem comes in the soils we
are notoriously bad at cultivating soil
organisms and in fact there was recent
study where they took a soil sample and
they sequencing to see how many
different types of were there they did
that they found 31 p with
pres and then from 2019 they had this
new cultivation method they wanted to
use for soil microbes and they
cultivated the microbes and sequence the
ones they were able to
cultivate and when they did that they
found they cultivated representatives
for so cultivation is not a method that
we're able to use to accurately
represent the diversity of those be Happ
of
this and so because of this problem with
cultivation field is largely moved
towards sequencing processes so instead
of relying on cultivating these microbes
we can extract their DNA and sequen
particular recently do met genome
sequen but coming back to this idea of
one understand and death The genome
isn't enough for us to be able to
tell so you can imagine perhaps didn't
know what a
dandelion a dandelion grod death cycle
was we wanted to understand how it might
be different and its grow death from the
O but all you have is the Gen you're not
able to measure it death there's no
particular Gene and the genome that
controls the grow
dep in fact what creers have found is
there's a variety of gen Ro death is
something that arises from the entire
genome B together to create an
organism
specific so from the micro soil that
we're able to we know that there's
differ so this is sh the abundance of
microbes over time a grow Cur for
so as you can see the and yellow
really so similar to dandelion and tree
there are big differences in how these
anes are growing in the soil and appear
to have different patterns them but if
all we have from them is their
metagenome sequence or genome sequence
we can't tell from that what growth
death might Happ so we can't really
understand the necrom they might be
making and contributing to the carbon
and the
soil and so again we just run into these
problems we can't at microbes so we
can't measure both death that way even
if we have the genome sequence so we
understand the phy of the microb we
can't really use that to tell us how the
micr is going and Di what is the Cy so
we come back to this issue of how do we
make sense and
measure so the way that the field
recently has been trying to get around
this it's using something known as life
history strategies so this is a term
that's largely borrowed from
pinology which at one point bring into a
similar problem and it's based on this
idea that an organism can't be the best
at everything you have to make tradeoffs
in your general approach to life and
then spe specifically tradeoffs and
things such as your growth your resource
acquisition and your survival so there's
different Specialties that you can feed
into or you can be a generalist some of
these Specialties and that's how you
function and survive in your ecosystem
so a classic example of this is Brian's
competitor stress tolerator
andal so this is a way that he used to
categorize the life history strategies
of different plants um so for example a
competitor you can think of an organism
like an oak tree so this is an organism
that grows slower has more investment
into the ecosystem around it it's really
good at competing
resources whereas you think of a lunal
or be species something like a dandelion
it grows quickly and dies quickly its
goal is to produce a lot of Offspring
and it's not
investing and then finally you have a
sun or something that's stress or
scarcity tolerant and the goal of these
organisms is not to die they can live
stressful environments that other
organisms may not be able to live on and
they're not trying to grow really
quickly or anything they're just trying
not to die and so when we look and come
back and think about applying this to
microbes again we have this observation
that growth and death Cycles are
differing in different microbial
communities so we have this kind of
sense that there might be a difference
in life history strategy between
different microbes that could help us
understand what function they're having
in the soil and so so the question
becomes is there a way similar to what's
been done in plants that we're able to
find tradeoff traits in
microorganisms that we can use to define
what specialty they might be have having
in the soil so their investment into
things such as growth resource
acquisition and survival and so that's
really where the first question and
first part of the project comes in is
can we build a life history framework
that explains microbial growth and death
behaviors and explains the different
special TOs and Life Strategies that
microbes might be having in soil and so
previous work in this area has largely
um started trying to apply like historys
to microorganisms and one of the first
questions that you have to ask yourself
is well what traits are we trying to
look at inps to be able to measure this
so in Plants the way again these
Concepts is far far from plant ecology
people have found things such as Leaf
area Leaf dry matter content and
specific Leaf area be related to life
history strategy so measuring these
traits tells you something about how
plant is investing in energy to be a
specialist in surviving in its work in
its environment so from this you were
able to understand the life history
strategy and comes to microbes though
there's no beles that we can measure in
fact going through and looking at
microbes even through a microscope is
really an impossible task when you're
looking at a soil that can have billions
and billions of microbes in it so as I
mentioned before our way of kind of
looking
at
is
sequences and but again with grow of
depth you can't look at just a single
gene or a single set of gen so instead
what we're interested in looking at is
what I'm calling
GS so in this case um kind of explaining
what I'm mean by General genomic
features and looking at zooming out a
bit on your goo and understanding what
general tools you have to accomplish
different tasks in life um so an example
could be a membrane transporter how much
of your genome is made up of transported
so how much are you able to pull stuff
in across your cell wall push stuff out
across your cell wall and how might that
be related then to what you're doing in
the ecosystem your overall approach to
life another example could be
transcription factors so in the genome
transcription factors help you turn off
and turn on gen they help you control
your gene expression so if you can
imagine the environments that perhaps is
not good for microbi it's nutrient
deficient and if we have two micro one
that has many transcription factors and
one that only
has living in and then suddenly there's
a washing Nutri in the environment you
have very
good imagine that perhaps the with many
transcription fact is able to respond
more quickly to this change environment
and change its gene expression to turn
on its quote
and so it's quickly able to respond and
begin replicating in this
the of my a few transcription factors
can't change as quickly so it's not able
to start replicating it as quickly and
so these perhaps General features such
as transcri factors have an influence on
the growth and death and responsive
responsiveness of a microorganism in
soil environment it's overall
like so current work in this field has
really looked at making an overall life
his first going in and defining what we
think the different life history grou
things objects would be so using
understand Theology and trying to come
up with on the firsthand what they think
could be and then they go and look for
genomic features that are interesting
and potentially related to these
categories that so what I'm proposing is
do the opposite of that and start by
looking into the genomic features
particularly ones that seem interesting
and they would be training off to define
your general approach so instead of
applying to the genomic data I'm using
the genomic data to inform my
cre and then once I am finding an
analyzing those genomic features using
those to tell me what Specialties do I
think my soil environment by might be
trading off against and using that to
Define my things and again so we have
evidence shown this figure quite a few
times microbes are growing differently
in the soil they have different go deps
like we also have evidence that General
genomic features like I mentioned so
this case membrane transport qu the
prescription factors are associated with
each other so in this case have an organ
these two factors are positively
correlated with each other have high
membrane transmits who also appear to
have transcription factors so we can
imagine an organism that occupies this
side of the gra might be having a very
different life history strategy with
organism that occupies a point where
they have low transcription factors and
low membrane
transs so that really defines the first
what the first part of my work things to
build on is examining genomes and
metagenomes from the soil and looking
for Gen these General genomic features
that appear to be showing a trade-off
indicative of specializing into a
certain life history strategy or have
interesting relationships to the
potential growth in death or life
history of
N and then from that I would use those
features I've identified to understand
what those different Specialties could
be and how those could be related again
to how the organism overall is
approaching its life history and what
it's doing in a soil
environment and so at the conclusion of
this my hope would be that we could take
the genomes of or organisms and the
metagenomes of organisms and use that
along plot this to understand what sort
of Niche and what sort of ecological
nich the organ
from that get a sense of its dep as well
as other factors related to how it's
functioning and so when we're thinking
back to this growth and depth it's we
want to also understand why would this
be important for the soil carbon and so
we have some initial hypothesis about
how some of these potential Mings could
relate to soil carbon so if we had a
growth adapted organism you think about
a Lal or a Dand
perhaps that's an organism that's
producing large amounts of it's growing
and dying rapidly in the environment so
it's producing a lot of and then if we
go to a competition adapted organism you
think about like an oak tree perhaps
it's producing an intermediate amount of
necromass it's not growing as much it's
not dying as much um we're still trying
to understand how that relate this
production but then if you think about a
scarcity adopted organism organism
that's goal is just don't die it's not
producing a lot of NE mass and you can
imagine how being uh occupying these
different spectrums of specialty that
then go on and influence how the
microbial Community is contributing to
soil Caron and the accumulation of soil
again matter so that is the first part
of my work is kind of nailing down and
defining what these different life
hisory strategies could be and how we
can achieve them and the subsequent
questions I would have is maybe going
back into the field and getting closer
and closer back to that question of the
influence on so of the get matter so one
of the questions would be do our
management practices influence what life
history groups are present in the soil
or what the diff the relative
composition of those different life
history groups are so for example I
would look at hillage because we know
tillage Alters the composition of the
mobial but we don't know how it might
impact what ecological nich these
different soil organisms are occupi or
what their specific Specialties might be
and that could be what's important for
understanding and the final question
which is really related to that as I do
these different life history groupings
actually matter for Sol car so we have
some hypo IES again about how they could
be related to necromass production but
actually going out in field and using
soils to study if these life history
strategies differences in that
composition have consequences for um the
eventual carbon fuel syst so that really
is a summary of what I'm going be doing
focused heavily on the beginning work
and alluding
to um thank you all so much for
listening and I'm happy to
talk right well that's honestly is a
problem I think
that strategy so
allows
theying
change
set so I think the swapping really an
issue of trying to focus specifically on
biologically and understand
this one
changes so what's going on right now
my
file
change I get it thank you
yeah that's a very naive question how do
you measure a necromass I can see a dead
animal or a dead plant how do I know
that that thing in the soil is a dead
micro
see so what they used is a marker of
microbial cell wall composition so in
that study specifically they broke it up
into bacterial fungal so they extracted
the carbon measured the amount ofic acid
which is a bacterial cell comp and then
glucos is
fos and then they had an equation for
converting that into an estimate of
necromass based on how much of the cell
that cell while showing came from
mic yeah those are unique signatures
to
yeah I think there lot of debate on that
yes yeah so it it is
um but as you may have learned from the
presentation last week as many people in
thisi really hard to tell what's going
into sort
of so those are signatures that we're
trying I have about I'm kind of very
curious about
stud mention about how
the
and yes yes we do so it Al this is
coming largely from conceptology so
plantology um we think about like hist
strategy something that encourages PLS
that are able
to kind of
come soil up and K all the plants that
are there first
one so our initial hypothesis going into
this is that a similar thing
occur think especially you
have a lot
go
that destroy
perhaps
that
inth thank you for the wonderful
introduction and good afternoon everyone
as he said my name is Alex yor and I'll
be giving my M exam seminar presentation
entitled Dynamic crop growth data for
predicting nitrogen status Ma so as most
or probably all of you know nitrogen is
very critical fertilizer for any
agronomic system very particularly maze
um so what happens is it's often
overapplied in heals and this this is
the simple reason is this is sort of a
cheap insurance policy to protect
against uncertainties in the season a
lot of things can happen from the time
you plant and the time you fertilize
till the time you actually Harvest so
applying a little extra nitrogen is
typically thought of as a as a
reasonable practice um but there's a
fine line between sort of managing yield
loss and then offloading nitrogen into
the
environment because again as most of you
probably know nitrogen is very reactive
in the environment it's very mobile move
around a lot um so this can cause a lot
of ecological harm when it's overapplied
you know so you get a big Rin after you
apply now you're washing into water ways
you're doing a lot of lot of harm to S
ecosystem there's potential human health
effects and then we also have you know
nitrous oxide emissions this is a major
greenhouse gas so this can be very
problematic um typically what's done
what's very common is uniform
application nitrogen field so you pick a
rate maybe you add 20% or something like
that but you apply that same amount
across the field irrespective of where
it's needed or where it's not needed as
much even in Precision system Sy where
they have a little more control over
rates and have a little more spatial
control um typically this is done with
like a static piece of information like
last year's yield map and so you'll use
some algorithm to to derive a rate for
particular areas of your field but again
you're using this sort of single point
data whether it's ndvi map or a field
map so this sort of led me to this
question of can we use some kind of
dynamic model to inform our nitrogen
application rates um at at a spatial
scale and so what I what I mean by a
dynamic by a dynamic model
is instead of taking a single point like
a single ndvi image take more of a Time
series can we get some additional
information from this time series
leading up to the time when you would
fertilize to give us a better sense of
what the nitrogen status actually
can so to do this we measured crop
height two to three times a week in our
fields we performed spectral
measurements about once or twice a week
and then we did nitrogen status
measurement of the actual plants then we
fit a model to the whole thing to kind
of try to tie it all together and one
thing I really want to point out is we
do not use yield data in this because I
imagine somebody would ask because any
agronomic Pursuit sort of the pair
amount becomes yield you know you want
to know how's this going to affect my
yield is it going to hurt my yield is it
going to help my yield is it going to
maximize it and so I want I just want to
point out now that're we didn't look at
yield in this part of the study and this
is actually part of a broader body of
work that we actually do have the entire
growth ratees the entire season will
have field data um but for the purposes
of this project not looking at that so
this took place over a few different
sites so here in Ithaca we had three
different sites across three years 2021
through
2023 and we what we did is we had two
separate planting dates per Fields we're
calling those different site year
because you essentially have created a
different environment if you plant two
weeks later you're you're sort of
changing the environment a little bit at
least in terms of weather pattern things
like that so we have three sites three
years here in itha we also partnered
with our colleagues at Agriculture and
AG Canada which if you're not aware is
essentially the the Canadian version of
the
USDA they provided us with one year of
data this past year 2023 same protocol
where they did two different plant dates
um and they had three different fields
they're calling them blocks but there're
three separate Fields within this within
this area so this is this is a map of
theirs at L um which is just south of
Montreal so there's their three
different fields again two planting
dates as I mentioned the little squares
we'll talk about in a moment these are
our three sites so 2021 we were at the
gallon Woods 2022 we were at calwell
field which you probably know is over by
the um by green houses and then 2023
we're a couple miles away in Bara most
of the rest of the talk will focus
primarily on 2023 data um with a little
bit of
2021 primarily on our on last year's
data so what we did is we mapped out the
field as you can see professional
longshan here with his backpack with
this funny little antenna on it so what
this is is it's an rtk GPS what this
does is it allows us to have sort of
centimeter level resolution
within the field so we can walk around
the field and know where we arein a
couple cim accuracy about ctim accuracy
and what we did is so as promised the
little squares so what these little
squares are they're they're 3 meter
pixels within the field and so we
flagged out the corners of these and
again that's why we needed this high
resolution uh GPS so that we could map
this out precisely the reason we chose
the size and the orientation is because
this is based on planet satellites which
is if you're not aware is sort of a it's
a daily pass high resolution satellite
product um basically they've sent a an
entire swarm of little satellites up
into the sky and so it allows them to
give us daily entry so we we match that
to their grid so that we can use this
for further work with with the satellite
data and as I mentioned we have two
different planting dates so the southern
half of the field was planted around L
May second half of fields about two
weeks
later for the height measurement pretty
straightforward um you can see up there
there's sort of a zip tie encircling the
plant so we did this with all the plants
we actually went back and measured the
same plants every time we measured and
there are 10 of them within each field
with a specific colored zip tie so we
could actually track the growth of
individual plants this doesn't play as
much into this particular project but we
did want to have that granularity for
later ultimately what we did is we
average pixel the the height so we have
sort
of average height for the for the
individual 3x3 meter pixel this
corresponded well with what they did in
Canada which is where they just averaged
the averaged value didn't didn't have
this sort of granularity of data uh we
measured from the soil surface to the
highest lead and I want to point out
that we did unmanipulated that is we
didn't move the leaf in any way or we
didn't stretch it out so there's a
pretty standard protocol a lot of times
you will you know hold the leaf up to
its highest point and measure that way
the reason we chose not to do that and
to do it this way is we wanted to
correspond this more closely to what you
would see would say a lar image where
you're not actually touching the plant
you can't affect it it's just how the
plant sits where it is what is the
height that way so we we wanted to
measure that way and as I said there
were 10 plants per pixel that we're
measuring Al average looks for average
height over that three that 9 square
meter
area go so for the spectral measurement
we used the ASD field spec handheld
although we didn't use it handheld we
used it on the boom and on a ladder so
we did this to get about four meters
above the above the soil surface the
reason we did this is because the spot
size of the actual device comes out to
about three and a half meters at that
height so it worked out perfectly nearly
perfectly with our with our pixel size
so we would we would stand up on a
ladder and measure straight down that
was how we got our spectral data um one
of the one of the challenges with this
is it requires a lot of calibration so
you can see on the right um my colleague
here holding up this device called
spectralon essentially just like a pure
white reflective surface that we were
able to get sort of a white balance for
our device but we had to do this every
10 to 15 minutes field so as we're going
along we're constantly recalibrating to
make sure we have the most accurate data
now our wise Canadian friends used a
drone to give their special data and
having walked through the field of the
ladder a lot I'm a little jealous
so again because we were trying to tie
this to this sort of Planet satellite
data what we did is we took this um so
this this figure on the right is sort of
a typical days measurement from the ASD
and it's it's a hyperspectral instrument
so we're actually getting single
nanometer resolution from 325 to 375 to
1025 and what we did is we broke this
down into individual bands and these
bands correspond to the planet super
Dove which is the current instruments
that are up right now so we wanted to
match up that band structure so that we
could ultimately use this data use this
protocol with the satellite data
later so for nitrogen status measurement
we did in 2021 and two we did a nitrate
sa test so this is taking fresh plants
and actually measure the amount of
nitrate within that um again since we're
not focusing as much on the 2021 and two
data don't don't worry too much about
that so for 2023 what we did is nitrogen
n index what this is is essentially a
measure of the nitrogen in the field or
the nitrogen in your plants relative to
a sort of critical nitrogen
concentration this critical nitrogen
concentration is a sufficient level for
growth at least theoretically and it
tends to be a pretty good standard
pretty good Hallmark for this for this
kind of work so for this we actually
took dyy plant so we did destructive
sampling in and around the pixels in
question and then deriv with n values
from that this protocol is also followed
we have consistent measurements of
nitrogen so this is a typical plot of
our height so the individual points are
the actual measurements where we
measured the height and what we did is
we fit this exponential curve and so if
you know a little bit about sort of corn
growth or plant growth in general if you
look throughout the if you sort of
project this out through the whole
season you're going to see sort of a
logistic curve and fit really well
because we're not looking at the entire
season we're just looking at this early
stage growth the exponential model
actually fits really well and if you've
seen a logistic model essentially the
first half of it is an exponential so
this actually fit really well from this
curve we gen we generated a growth rate
which essentially how fast is it growing
at that last
measur in centimeters per day so our
exponential fits were really good our
mean r squar was 997 exponential F I
mean you can see that there's pretty
strong pretty strong relationship there
it fit really well so we so we went with
this calculated the growth rate from
that this is for 113 pixels so this is
including the Canadian as well as the
itha locations for all three
years we did a similar process for ndvi
again the points are the actual measured
ndvi or calculated ndvi in this case we
calculated sort of an ndvi growth rate
or the ndvi increase rate so how fast
the ndbi increasing at that last
measurement day right before side
dress the fit was not quite as strong
for exponential and you can just see you
know this is just a typical plot and the
points were a little bit off um but our
our mean r squar was about
86 the N is a little bit lower so we had
only 95 points here because the 2021
data would not have spectral data so
that that's not included
this now looking at our static model and
again by Static model I'm saying a
single data point so if you're just
looking at this one point just the
height if you measure one time right
before side you measure the height how
good of an indicator is that of the
nitrogen status not bad I mean we're
looking at about a 68 R squar for this
um this this is nni versus height but
what we wanted to see is okay we're
we're looking specifically at this one
day right before side dress what about
all the other days before that are there
other days that might be better
predictor and so as we sort of move down
along this curve looking towards
planting date um we see the R square
drop off pretty prly there's no real
Improvement here with the static model
we looking backwards in time we're
trying to predict it a week earlier now
if we look at our Dynamic model again
this is height so we're looking at nni
but now we're looking at growth rate so
this is that the slope of that curve
essentially at that last point so this
is our growth rate the dynamic model
which we've derived from the actual IAL
curve so for this our R squ was about 64
still not bad for predicting nitrogen
and again we wanted to look and see okay
what if we move back through time and
sort of move our way through here how
good of a bit do we get and you see
there's a there's a little bump so the
red line indicates the r squar of our
leftand lot which is measuring just at
the last date but now if you measure
about a week earlier you get a pretty
significant bump in accuracy so we
actually just a little bit higher than
the static model in this case about a
week earlier so this is actually good
news because typically you want a little
bit of lead time to be able to plan this
thing out if you if you're going to use
this sort of tool to indicate how much
to fertilize it'd be nice to know that a
few days earlier also sort of projecting
forward into using satellite data this
would be really important because as we
all know here Clow is going to be a big
issue with satellite data um so having
that of time where you actually have a
still a decent decent accuracy is really
important so now again looking at the
static model this is for ndvi now same
thing if we just take the ndvi value at
that last Point what do we get uh the R
square is not great about3
33 again if we look and project this out
and look back in time how early can we
get a better measurement well we really
can't any anytime you go back through
it's going to just drop one thing I do
want to point out though is for our
height model the actual measured height
and the projected height for for our
last day were spoton they were the same
the modeled and the measured were almost
identical you saw that from
099 um r s in this case there was a
little bit of a discrepancy between the
modeled value so the red line here is
the actual measurement R squ so
corresponding to the figure on the left
but now this is looking at the point the
actual measurement but if you take the
the point on the curve as opposed to the
measured point we actually get a little
bit better accuracy that way but again
moving down going back through time our
accuracy just dropped if you go earlier
earlier in the season now with our
Dynamic model for ndvi and again this is
looking at that increase rate of ndvi
how fast is the nvi increasing at that
last date uh in this case we got an R
square about 049 so this is pretty
significant improvement over the static
model and so this sort of underlies this
sense of you know using a single point
ndvi to trying to predict nitrogen
status is maybe not the best and a
dynamic model may actually have some
improvement over this and similarly as
we go back in time about five days we
get a little bit of a bump and a little
bit of an increase in the overall
accuracy of the
model now comparing the static and
dynamic models as we just mentioned the
the overall R squar was actually just a
little bit higher for the static model
but this is only for the date right
before side dress if we actually look
across all days again we have this
little bit of room for improvement which
which takes the dynamic model just kind
of eats out the the static model in this
case but again because now we're a week
earlier that we can make this prediction
that's really important one for planning
purposes and also giving us a window as
we sort of this process into satellite
data similarly for the ndvi except in
this case we did see a pretty big
increase between the static and dynamic
model directly in the last day but then
we also have this little bump of
improvement about five days L again this
is really helpful for planning and also
sort of mitigating issues they trying to
get satellite right
on so to sort of wrap this all up and
bring it together so we looked at these
Dynamic model fits so our height model
model there was not really any
improvement with the dynamic model over
the static model at the final
measurement date but we did see a slight
Improvement about a week earlier so
we're predicting a week for side dress
we actually have a slightly better
chance of predicting that nitrogen
status with the ndvi we saw about a 50%
Improvement in the accuracy of the
dynamic model versus static model um we
didn't get quite as much of a benefit
from going earlier but there was still a
benefit and the overall fit is
better some of the limitations of how we
how this study went one of the ones is
just the noisy spectral data it's it's
just inherently noisy I mean you saw how
we're doing it I'm up here on a boom you
know we were pretty accurate about our
Heights and things like that and aiming
but there's just inherent challenges
with that um a tiny Cloud passing in
front of the sun when you're taking the
measurement could really affect that
spectral reading we did a it over
multiple measurements to sort of take
care of that as best we could but
there's still a lot of noise in there
one thing that we didn't look at that I
think would be really helpful is looking
at the differences between sight ears
and this is sight ears from one half of
the field to the other with the
different planting dates but also
between the different sites that is itha
versus versus Canada even looking at our
previous years and see the differences
there there there inherently going to be
differences in precipitation GD that
they're starting with in the first
couple weeks and make a really big
difference on the growth so that's
something that that needs to be looked
at a little more
deeply and again as I mentioned in the
beginning we are not looking at yield
and again because this is sort of a
Paramount issue for any agronomic
experiment ultimately somebody wants to
know a farmer wants to know how does
this affect my bottom line how does this
affect my heal it's G to hurt my heel
you know is this going to be a waste of
time so you know as as we use the the
broader body of work that we have the
broader body of data that we gathered
from this project which actually looks
the entire season then we can start
teasing out the yield impact things like
that uh so the implications for future
work as I mentioned we want to look at
using satellite data to do this um as
fun as it was hauling a ladder through
seven foot tall corn I would love it if
I didn't have to do that and I can tell
you I don't know many farmers who would
be really willing or even have the time
to do that so you know drones are great
if you have access to one that could be
a really great way to sort of gather
some of this data but ultimately it
would be you know having this public
access uh satellite data would be really
powerful to sort of making this
predictive ultimately what we like to do
is make these high high resolution
prescriptive end Maps so you could map
out your field at 3 meter resolution and
know where needs less nitrogen where is
going to need more just based on this s
icted nitrogen status using NN as
mentioned before so with that I'd like
to thank you all for being here a big
thanks to my uh my advisers professor
longan professor Vans um as well as Bill
Philpot help a lot with spectral data
the entire team at Agriculture and Agri
Canada uh the entire long Shams lab past
and present they've all been a part of
this project and have been tremendously
helpful as well as the Cornell Institute
for digital agriculture for providing
some funding for this project
and then Corell farm services for all
their awesome help getting our field to
prep and and helping with all the all
the management of the actual Agronomy of
the thing and of course I'd like to
thank all of you for being here and
thanks for
listening um you mentioned Harold at the
very end and so I was already thinking
to ask you how this might integrate with
the adapt end approach which for that
side rest date he'll give um because of
having followed the weather the initial
applications and so forth is going to
give some estimate of the nitrogen
status in the soil at that point you you
see a complimentarity to this
to I mean you're being more spatially
resolved obviously that's one aspect but
have you thought of some integration
with adap yeah yeah this is something we
we talked about a little bit um this
could essentially be another piece of
that another another way to enhance the
sort of reliability of that or enhance
accuracy of the C conditions that that's
I think I think this could be a really
important piece that taking some that
Dynamic data as opposed
to thanks great presentation uh so as
far as I grasp the idea is basically
that we use growth rate uh as an
indicator of nitrogen status because
nitrogen status is probably what uh
determines our growth
uh so have you thought about other
factors that can be growth rate at that
point like moisture
status some that can affect your
measurements of yourens absolutely there
are because like I said especially
between the different site years we're
going to have differences in the amount
of GDP that's accumulated early in the
season moisture differences soil
differences weeds can be a big factor so
yeah there are a number of other factors
that I think should be explored to
really make this a more a
[Music]
model that's actually a really
interesting question so we used the only
difference between varieties was between
Canada and us all three of our years
used the same variety of corn so I think
that' actually be a really great thing
to look at and see you know does a
variety that typically is going to be
shorter um do we see the same thing I
think that' be
a maybe like we didn't see much
difference between the last height and
the growth rate for the measurement but
in this case maybe the growth rate more
stable across varieties than the actual
height which you have some
shoulder all right thank you very
much this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at Cornell
EDU