this is a production of Cornell
University um okay so my name is Alyssa
dilers I'm a thirdy Year Ms PhD student
in the lab of Dr Carmen aned Martinez
and I'm really excited to share my
research with you today I'm going to try
using this clicky thing and oh here we
go so first I'd like to acknowledge my
committee members Dr Nicole benedek Dr
Natalie capiro and our collaborators Dr
Dr Christy Goodale and her amazing lab
group in ecology and evolutionary
biology and also Dr Taran bowly in
horiculture and then of course um the
lab group I'm in all the great members
of it and particularly aned thank you so
much um I've been lucky to receive
funding through the USDA for the first
two years of my program that has been
really wonderful and I'm uh recently
funded through the Cornell ainson Center
for sustainability graduate research
Grant
so to give you a general idea of how I
anticipate my degree going the first two
chapters will be based on my Master's
project this involves acidification and
nitrogen addition in Forest soils and
looking at the effects on the water
extractable fraction and then the next
two chapters that I'm proposing for my
dissertation will shift to look at
cellulose decomposition and trying to
link enzymatic breakdown with this
technique that an need mentioned of
density functional Theory
so diving right in to the Master's
project as I said this is looking at
acidification and nitrogen addition in
Forest soils and while our uh
collaborators in the good lab group are
looking at ecosystem fluxes of carbon
and nitrogen and the bowly group is
looking at below ground carbon
allocation and root exodites we're
focused on the soil solution or what
comes off of the soil into water in the
soil and our hypothesis was that
dissolved organic matter composition and
then absorption to soil minerals to form
mineral Associated organic matter would
be altered by nitrogen addition and
acidification this is an important issue
because as probably many of you know uh
we've had acidification and nitrogen
addition going on for quite a long time
in um our soils so uh what we see on the
right here is global sulfur emissions
and through the combustion of fossil
fuels and particularly coal uh we had
started having an increase in the 1900s
and then what you see I think I can here
we go so what you here see here is
around 1950 we have a sharp
acceleration and down here this is
nitrogen and in black is atmospheric
nitrogen so this is nitrogen sources in
the Chesapeake Bay and you see that same
pattern so in the 1950s we have a big
acceleration of atmospheric nitrogen and
then we see it uh peaking around 1980
and so what happened then was uh
essentially the Clean Air Act started
regulating um sulfur and nitrogen
emissions so on this picture what we see
is that uh through the combustion fossil
fuel sulfur dioxide nitrogen oxides are
released to the atmosphere they can
travel and then through dri or wet
deposition they get distributed across
the landscape and that can cause
acidification it can cause nitrogen
addition which itself can cause
acidification um and then also we might
have other sources of nitrogen addition
like ammonia volatization or runoff
so as you can see in that graph uh we've
actually already peaked on those things
those regulations worked and they helped
to bring it down and this only is
showing until 2000 in that top graph but
those numbers continue to fall so
actually what we're seeing now that's
more important than the effects of
acidification is really what's going to
happen as we recover from acidification
and recover from nitrogen addition um so
we want to see what effects we have on
the soil from that and one of them that
can be happening is that more dissolved
organic matter can leave the soil and
that can cause Lake Browning where the
water is getting more organic matter and
more color in it and then that in turn
affects the Aquatic uh life in in
streams and lakes um also we are
thinking about soil Health in terms of
losing nutrients or retaining nutrients
and carbon in the soil and climate
change if we have more carbon combing
off into the soils it's possible that
microbes would be able to respire that
out as CO2 and we might lose that from
the system so that's sort of of frames
uh what we're thinking about in this
project the setup we used to look at
this was actually pretty exciting
because it's been happening for over a
decade so before I was involved with the
project these were already treatment
conditions that were set up in sites
around Ithaca there's a control
treatment with no Amendment an acidified
treatment where Elemental sulfur was
added a nitrogen addition treatment
where uh nitrate has been added and an
acidify plus nitrogen addition treatment
where ammonium sulfate has been added so
the idea there is that some effects
might be from both acidification and
nitrogen but some might be from just
acidification or just nitrogen
addition um so we're going to call each
of those uh treatments a plot the plot
was 40 meters by 40 meters with a 10
meter buffer and the important thing to
know here is that those uh treatments
were each replicated six times so we
have 24 total plots distributed at three
sites around Ithaca and in general these
are forested hillsides that are silt LOM
and septisol but there is uh you know
there are some pretty big variations in
organic matter and pH at these different
sites so we do take that into account
when we're doing the statistical
analyses
um at each of these plots soils were
sampled in five locations and composited
to the PO plot level and then cved and
four depths were taken so we have the
forest floor which I'm going to call the
O Horizon and then pretty pretty shallow
depth so 0 to 3 cenm just the first top
inch of soil 3 to 10 cenm and 10 to 20
cm which all fall into the a horizon
mineral soil and down here um in this
graphs this is just to show that we did
have acidification in
um you know in the treatments we
expected to acidify so acidify only
brought the pH of the forest floor down
to an average of three and a half so
this is really quite acidic um at this
point in the study these soils that I'm
looking at are from 2022 we only saw a
small effect of pH in the um acidify
plus n condition so that's also
important to note and then once we look
at the 0 to 3 cmers top inches soil both
acidify plus nitrogen addition and
acidify are bringing the pH um to around
4.6 so I just want to ground everybody
in what kind of phes we're talking about
because some of them are really quite
acidic okay
so uh I was not involved in the soil
sample collection and then these samples
as I said were composited cved they make
it to me so here's where I come into the
story I receive that soil and I shake it
with water and then filter it to less
than two microns so now what we have is
this water soluble fraction so
everything that's going to come off the
soil into the water um sometimes we
might think of this as the dissolved
organic matter and our first objective
is to find out what's in that and as
many of you will know it can be very
hard to find out like the exact
compounds are in there there's thousands
of compounds but we're going to pick
some uh analyses to give us an idea of
what's in there and that's that
characterization step then if you think
about that uh water moving through the
soil and now it's picked up various
different things into it now it's going
to start interacting with the soil
around it so the next part to simulate
that is a batch experiment where we take
that dissolved organic matter and shake
it with minerals that are found in the
soil and see what sticks so the
Assumption here is that you have some
amount of say carbon or nitrogen in
solution you shake it with a mineral you
remeasure the solution and whatever
amount that's decreased that has been
zorbed or stuck to those soil minerals
so that's uh part two and then I I've
completed the experiment but not this
variable importance which is going to be
the next aspect and the idea there is to
say what factors are controlling how
much carbon specifically is sticking to
these different soil minerals and then
finally objective three is uh ATR FTI
flowthrough experiment and the important
thing to know here is we're going to
take a a soil mineral we're going to add
some organic matter on top of it that's
going to create uh what we call Ma or
mineral Associated organic matter and
then we're going to run root exodites
off of that and see what happens so root
exodites can push off organic matter
possibly off minerals or maybe they'll
get stuck themselves so uh those are the
objectives and one really important
thing to remember the whole time I'm
talking I think U probably people in
this room mostly already know this but
I'm not talking about bulk soil or the
carbon and nitrogen in the soil I'm
talking about the carbon and nitrogen in
the water that comes into contact with
the soil and so I might call this the
water soluble fraction I could call it
the soil solution or the aquous phase or
I might talk about soluble carbon and
water extractable nutrients but just
remember that it's all in the water and
why we care about this fraction is
because it's highly mobile it's
responsive to environmental changes and
it's available to plants and microbes
without a lot of additional effort on
their part and why I have all these
arrows is not to say oh I've gotten
every single input or output of the
system is just to illustrate that if we
find that we have more or less of
something in that water soluble fraction
it could be for a number of reasons
maybe it's because we have more inputs
but equally it could be because we have
fewer outputs so it kind of as usual
with soil is a mess for trying to
determine exactly why something's
happening uh but just keep that in mind
for when we see uh an
effect so jumping right into the results
I'm going to start in the O Horizon and
talk about dissolved organic carbon so
here on the left uh we see that all of
our treatments reduced the carbon coming
off the soil at this point which is 10
years you know de into the
study so um then we want to see what can
we say about that carbon so just saying
the amount of carbon is pretty General
and one measurement type we can get is
aromaticity and
aromaticity uh you can think of as
sometimes people think of these Benzene
rings so it's where you have bonds where
electrons are shared and it tends to
make the molecules more stable um and
also if it is a complex system then it
can add more color to those molecules so
what we see here is that the only
treatment that had an effect was our
acidification treatment and that lowered
aromaticity of the dissolved organic
carbon now moving to this graph uh this
is sort of a proxy measurement for size
or molecular weight of molecules in
solution and what we find is
acidification alone is the only
condition that had an effect and its
effect is if we follow this Arrow up to
make molecules smaller so we start to
get this picture as we can see down here
if we imagine these little brown balls
as dissolved organic carbon that when we
acidify what's coming off the soil is
less in amount of carbon it's smaller
it's lesser aromatic and I'm not showing
the uh box plot here but it also has a
trend of less color at the same time
when we add
nitrogen we still see less dissolved
organic carbon but no change in size
aromaticity and at first I thought oh
the nitrogen's having a modifying effect
in the acidification but remember that
in this o Horizon that acidify plus n
treatment actually wasn't that acidified
so I think uh based on the fact that
size aromaticity and color in the O
Horizon have a linear correlation to pH
what we're actually seeing is just an
acidification
effect so why might this be happening
and this is where we get into to u i
this is not I'm just giving you some
ideas on this and everybody else is
welcome to add their ideas in at the end
um so there could be biotic and abiotic
reasons why might we have less input of
docc into our water soluble fraction
well with nitrogen addition it's been
shown that there's fewer root exits
coming into the system essentially the
trees are getting enough on their own of
their requirements met that maybe they
don't need to be sort of uh enhancing
the system to to their benefit in that
way um alternatively maybe we're
retaining more of the
on the soil so when you have
acidification uh that is going to take
oxygens with negative charges that are
in solution and add a proton to them so
now they're not going to be negatively
charged and that tends to reduce
repulsive interactions uh between
organic organic interactions we'd be
talking about in the O Horizon and then
that could mean that more is retained
and less is coming off into
solution um okay so then in terms of the
smaller size in the acidification
treatment a biotic reason might be that
at that really low pH of 3 3.5 we could
be inhibiting microbial decomposition so
maybe a little bit is happening but just
they're just knocking off a few number
that are just small small sort of small
bits off the end um and then an opposite
idea would be that in fact larger
molecules are coming into solution but
because of that acidic pH they're broken
down into smaller molecules rapidly a
biotically so this is the type of
thought process we're going through when
we're doing this but overall the
implications and and this is really uh
something that other Studies have found
also and is really important is that as
we Rec recover from acidification the
opposite effect can happen so that means
that we would have more docc coming off
soils but also that it's made up of
larger and more aromatic molecules with
more color and so why that matters is
that idea of Lake Browning that I
mentioned earlier so if we have more doc
coming off and also it's more aromatic
per gr uh you know per unit of carbon
that can impart more color to waterways
and they do actually that is something
that other people are finding and
researching actively um but because we
see that nitrogen addition also reduced
the total amount of dissolved organic
carbon it seems like that the recovery
from nitrogen addition could add to the
effects of the recovery from
acidification
okay straight from carbon to nitrogen
all the important uh players here so in
this top left box plot we see total
dissolve nitrogen and acidification plus
nitrogen is reducing total nitrogen and
acidification has a trend of reduction
all right so then we want to think well
what kind of nitrogen are we talking
about so first we're looking at
inorganic nitrogen nitrate and ammonium
and we see something pretty interesting
although not wholly unexpected uh here
and purple is the acidification only
treatment and what you see is that there
this is for nitrate in that graph so
what you see is in the O Horizon there
is no water extractable nitrate at all
coming off of these soils under
acidification and when you go down into
the top inch of soil there's still
almost none um and then we don't see an
effect for the other
treatments and then on this graph this
is ammonium and what we see is that
there's a little increase in ammonium
under ification and a decrease in
ammonium in acidification plus nitrogen
addition and that's kind of interesting
if we're adding nitrogen in that
condition as ammonium you might think
okay we're adding ammonium to the soil
ammonium might go up that's not what we
see um so here uh pictorially you can
see that the ammonium in acidify it's
mostly ammonium 0% nitrate and here in
the acidification plus nitrogen uh we
have a little reduction in ammonium and
increase in nitrate
so why might that be
happening I think uh one of the
major
uh bacteria that we need to think about
when we talk about ammonium and nitrate
is nitri fires um and probably there's
at least some role going on here for why
we're seeing that so there could be a
number of reasons that we're losing that
nitrate in acidify uh but a microbial
reason would be that even though
nitrifiers can operate at some acidic
phes again we're really acidic uh and
it's possible that we're seeing
inhibition of nitrification and so the
ammonium is accumulating and not being
converted to nitrate but uh we also
could have more output and in fact I'm
sure these two are working together so
from abiotically speaking nitrate is an
annion it's not going to stick to
negatively charge soil particles so
you're just going to have loss from the
system and as acidification pushes out
base cations and those lead to the soil
nitrate is a good uh kind of companion
to exit with them um also we could have
more output due to chemodenitrification
or self decomposition of
nitrate and then I'm actually going to
uh talk about this one at the same time
because this is still in the
acidification treatment so as we add
protons or hydrogen ions to the solution
uh that might also push off zorbed
ammonium so that those are some reasons
that would explain what we see in
acidification uh how about in the
acidify plus n why would we have that
decrease in ammonium currently my idea
is that maybe uh we have an in increase
in nitr fires and they're able to
process that ammonium we're saying
here's your substrate and we're adding
it every single year here you go and
maybe they're pretty good at at
processing that and continually putting
out nitrate into the system and you
really need that kind of continuous um
input of nitrate because again it's not
going to be retained in the soil it's
either going to be taken up by plants or
leech leech
out um and what we've seen is that water
extractable nitrate was completely
absent after a decade of acidification
and it's not the nitrogen addition but
the acidity that is the major factor
influencing uh nitrogen
speciation okay so now we're going to
move out of the O Horizon and into the
mineral soil and uh we have a new a new
player in the game and that's aluminum
so what this first graph is showing is
the relationship between aluminum and
dissolved organic carbon and this is a
known relationship
uh so again not wildly surprising but I
think the important thing to emphasize
here is we don't see a relationship in
the O Horizon so aluminum's really not
playing a role even though we have those
really acidic soils in the O Horizon
then when we get down even an inch down
all of the side and we see that
correlation so moving to this graph on
the upper right um this is showing size
or parent molecular weight on the y-
axis to aluminum on the x-axis and again
what we're seeing is that aluminum is
really not affecting the O Horizon and
very you know essentially not in the
first in soil but once we get down a
little deeper to 3 to 10 centimeters as
we increase in aluminum molecules are
getting larger in size and so a lot of
times people talk about cation bridging
which is the idea that a positively
charged particle with more than one
positive charge could essentially
mediate between two negatively charged
uh carb containing molecules so if you
have two carboxilic acids with negative
charges and you have say a calcium with
a charge of plus two in the middle it's
kind of making everyone play nice right
it's making it so that you can have a
little more um a little less space
between those negative charges and
aluminum is a plus three uh ion and we
could expect that the same thing might
be happening so this could be evidence
of that then on this bottom graph uh
this is showing a romatic again and
there is a relationship in between
aromatic aromaticity and size in the O
Horizon and the top inch of soil but
it's pretty flat you can see that here
but then once we get to 3 to 10
centimeters uh we see a a steeper slope
and that's saying as we have more
aromatic molecules they're larger so we
start to get this picture where there's
more aluminum in solution more carbon in
solution they're larger molecules with
more aluminum and we have these larger
arom when there's more
aromaticity and so uh why we better
click along here um so why would we care
about that so the next part is leading
into the batch experiments so once we
have an idea of what's maybe making
larger molecules which tend to sit down
on Mineral surfaces uh more and we get
the sense that aluminum is playing a
role in that and we get a sense of how
much carbon we have in solution now we
want to know how is it going to stick to
the other uh the rest of the
soil and so for this we're we move to
objective two which is the batch
experiments and so I extracted dissolved
organic matter from the 0 to3 cimer
layer and then shook it with gerti an
iron oxide hydroxide cholite a one:1
alumino silicate clay gibbsite an
aluminum hydroxide and the 3 to 10 cm
soil which I'm not going to show the
results of uh right now but uh this
graph which is um again I'm only going
to show one result from this we're still
processing the data but this graph I
think is kind of cool uh this is
aluminum zorbed on the xais and organic
carbon zorbed on the y- axis so if we
just look at the amount of organic
carbon zorbed to the soil we see as
expected kite is really not absorbing
very much carbon and then uh gibbsite
and gerti are absorbing you know at
least in the same order of
magnitude and the interesting part is we
saw that aluminum associ with carbon in
the solution but now we're still seeing
it on what's been zorbed so what's left
the solution once we shake it with those
minerals
um and there could be a couple reasons
we might be seeing this so This bottom
one um is saying here's aluminum
associating with organic molecules in
solution just like we saw maybe on that
previous slide and then uh it's this is
a chem aborption to the iron and gerti
and it's sort of all helping it come
together kind of coor together or
alternatively maybe aluminum first zorbs
to the gerti and then allows for um more
organic compounds to pile on so either
way we're going to be investigating
what's going on there and seeing whether
we can see particularly we can look for
this Bond here of iron oxygen aluminum
so that's something we'll be continuing
to
do all right uh for now that's going to
wrap up the Master's project disc
session and I'll move on to what I'm
proposing for my dissertation proposal
um while this is still relevant in
Forest soils I'm actually uh mentally
shifting more to agricultural soils um I
think that we talk about soil health and
nutrient cycling and how to build soil
Health which is something really
important to me as a small farmer and
one thing we notice is one way is to add
plant matter and nutrients so what does
all that plant matter have it has
cellulose and so how that cell cose
breaks down and how it interacts how
quickly it breaks down is going to
affect that nutrient cycling through the
system so I'd like to look at five
factors on cellulose decomposition pH
enzyme and cellulose concentration the
presence of three soil minerals probably
the ones um I just showed the presence
of low molecular weight organic
molecules like amino acids and then the
presence of a divalent cation and an
agricultural systems calcium is probably
the one we'd want to look at because uh
obviously when you're liming you're
adding calcium to soils so the question
is uh could could these different
factors affect how quickly celluloses
cycling and the sort of inspiration for
this comes from the way cellulose
enzymes work so here this is cellulose
it's made up of chains of glucose
monomers called fibral that are then
hydrogen bonded together and this
actually rigid crystallin structure then
to break it down you need three
different types of enzymes endo
glucanases exoglucanases and beta
glycosidases um and this is an example
of exoglucanase cell 7A and I just think
this is so cool this is a molecular
Dynamics simulation of the
oh hold
on
whoa so that's a a simulation molecular
simulation of that enzyme at work and
what we see is that here it's picking up
a fibral off the cellul surface and it's
going to be knocking off two and three
chunks of cellulose at a time off uh the
back end here out of the catalytic
domain and then it has this flexible
Linker and in the front it has a
carbohydrate binding module which they
sometimes call foot and that's that's
anchoring that enzyme to the surface so
that's a really important part of the
whole thing and in this foot uh we can
see it zoomed in over here it's got
three amino acid residues that are
helping it bind and those are tyrosine
so the question is this is going to be
processing along the cellulose surface
breaking down these little units as it
goes what happens if it hits an obstacle
and so when we think of uh aborption and
protective absorption some ways that we
might see that for uh the cellulose
enzyme would be the enzyme could bind to
a mineral and then not be able to get to
cellulose and break it down in the soil
or maybe the cellulose could bind to a
mineral and then not be available for
the enzyme but another type that I want
to inv investigate is what if something
binds to the cellulose like what if a
couple tyrosines come in here could they
bind and would that then block the
process of of this enzyme moving down
the surface so to test that um I have
these eight different treatment
conditions and I'm going to shake each
of them with cellulose to allow any
interactions that are going to happen to
happen uh and then we'll add an enzyme
mix from a fungus called trod damari
that has the ability to break down the
cellulose all the the way to glucose so
then we can measure glucose as a
function of time and see how much uh
cellulose is being broken down and the
idea would be uh we assume that some
some in some of these conditions you'll
find protective absorption of different
types and then we can investigate what
we see
there okay and then finally for
objective two I'd like to link this
technique called density functional
Theory um and see if we can get it to be
predictive in a slightly more macro
scale of enzymatic breakdown so what
that might look like is in density
functional Theory which is based on
quantum mechanics and models electron
configurations we can model a surface
like a mineral surface or the cellulose
surface and then we can Model A molecule
like an amino acid and then we can put
them together and see how they bind and
so the question is and I don't don't
know the answer but can we um if we can
accurately by collaborating it with
laboratory experiments if we can
accurately predict which molecules are
going to bind more strongly can we use
that to predict whether or not say an
enzyme is going to have uh trouble
breaking something down and so that's
the idea with this and why why it's
exciting is um partly because it's high
throughput so once you model your
surface you can Model A lot of different
molecules although again you have to
corroborate the results with your
laboratory results um and then there's
this question could it be predictive
that be pretty exciting if we could
measure a cellulo surface measure how
tightly something bound to it and that
correlated to how efficient the enzyme
was uh I'm not sure that'll be possible
but that'd be exciting I
think um so that's everything I wanted
to share with you today and I really
appreciate everybody coming and I'd like
to open it up for
questions johannas yeah thank you very
much Alysa great data and wonderfully
presented congratulations I just some
Nitty Gritty questions I wanted to learn
you you said you're you're filtering
your doc at
0.22 why that soil scientists usually do
0.45 aquatic scientist 0.7 why 0.2 well
I I think that the goal with all the
filtering is to make sure you're not
getting like mic I mean like microb
sterile so not getting microbial biomass
U but also not getting like fine soil
particles uh so I think that we just
chose point two to make sure we weren't
getting anything in that range I think
there's a I think there are some things
between 0.2 and 04 um particularly like
colloidal yeah lcms we doing Z point two
yeah um so I was just wondering whether
there was a some other reason that I I
was no it's just that reason and I'm
trying to remember the chart of the
different sizes but I remember at some
point looking at it and that's what we
chose yeah it's always interesting how
the different fields are are using
different cut offs right so you might
lose a little bit that's in that range
of 02 to point4 yeah yeah yeah um did
you have another one yeah few ones so
did you look at do you think sulfur
plays a role in in in all of that I mean
you you H it on the nitrogen and acidity
but then there's sulfur as well and I
know that you fundamentally change when
you add sulfur yes and also with the
historic emissions uh that it changes
organic sulfur forms um yeah I think
play a ro I'm sure it plays a role yeah
and and sulfur can be involved you know
there's redo reactions going on there
and in fact when we add the elemental
sulfur it's primarily acidifying by
microbial oxidation um so yeah it's a
lot of sulfur cycling going on and
unfortunately we were not well set up to
measure um The sulfur in solution so I
don't have a lot to say about it but
that's definitely an important role and
I do know some other papers are looking
at like sulfate concentrations also that
be the counter iion for your yeah it
could in fact what could be a counter
ion primarily nitrate and sulfate it's a
really good point yeah yeah thank you
yeah of
course yeah Jonathan I got a question if
the aluminum component since you're
reifying yes that the going from the SKB
site into these ionic state aluminums
but with the pH you're you're increasing
you're as you decrease the pH you're
increasing accelerating aluminum
concentrations I'm
wondering certainly from a concept of
recovery from acidification what's the
what's the tag there that this is what
we're going to see is recovery rather
than this is just more we're not mean
it's no no more acid brain in a sense of
the EPA but still I actually think um
that's something I'm really interested
in thinking about and I don't know if
other people have this problem but I
find my mind can go round and round in
these sort of different Circles of oh
may maybe it'd be this way or maybe it
would happen this way but um it it
depends what role aluminum's playing in
the aborption so we're not seeing it in
the oh Horizon and a lot of the research
out there that's similar that's looking
at that runoff into streams and Lake
Browning is talking about what's coming
from the O Horizon so but the O Horizon
is not GNA be shch of aluminum exactly
right exactly so so that's interesting
so so it depends is that going to be
going into the soil and then interacting
with aluminum uh or is it just running
off the surface but if it's in the soil
I would expect that what I mean what
we're seeing is more aluminum is
actually helping it stick around so I
would expect that as the pH goes up that
it would reduce aluminum and that that
could also exacerbate uh losing you know
more carbon that that's the way I was
looking at it anyway you're thinking
that's more like a Spoto than the
incepto that we have around here I mean
there's that experiment that's up on
Turkey Hill or game farm well not game
farm up to Mount Pleasant that they
actually put the trees in place okay to
see if the I mean because it's the O
Horizon proding the acids y if the if
the organic material that's coming from
these trees are actually creating the
spodic horizons which would then be
these BHS and bhs's farther down and
when you when I looked at those numbers
that you were saying this is the a
horizon those those aren't a Horizons
you got an A Horizon that's may be this
thick and yeah they like the soil series
they consider it AP I don't know you
know I don't know depends how you want
to think about it maybe yeah I I mean I
think it's all effectively been
Disturbed soil at some point so um but
but I do think that that thinking about
how the recovery acidification will
affect the aluminum is important and
whether something like calcium or a
different uh Dent you know cat could
sort of take over some of that uh
bridging role would be interesting but
um not something we're at yet I guess
yeah thank you yeah of
course any other
questions no okay so then Applause and
I'll will see you next
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu