This is a production of Cornell
University. So the title of my work is
evaluation and development of ecosystem
models to understand carbon and
hydraological processes.
So as we all know uh soil it is the
largest reservoir in the terrestrial
ecosystem which is more than the
vegetation and atmosphere. Carbon
dioxide combined and even a small change
in soil carbon stock can influence a big
impact on uh climate or ecosystem. So
what is really happening in soil? Um we
want to understand to understand uh it
we use process based models and there
are several process based models being
developed to explain what is really
happening in the soil for like
decomposition u soil organic carbon
decomposition but still um lots of
uncertainties still exist as we can see
here in the graph um no earth system
models are able to accurately estimate
or predict um solar organic carbon in
the uh terrestrial
ecosystem. So uh to explain um to
address these uncertainty I studied
couple of u uh processes in the
terrestrial ecosystem like microbial
models and hydraulic redistribution. My
first project uh chapter was a review
work which I reviewed more than 70
microbial models and the next two
chapters I studied hydraulic
redistribution which um I'm very excited
to present
today. So first uh microbial
models. So what is a microbial model? uh
when we compare it with conventional
model conventional model they don't have
microbial biomass pool here as we can
see but in microbial model they are
explain representation of microbial
model microbial
biomass and uh in the recent uh uh
decades because of the advancement of
microbiology we can see uh there is a
recent a very high number of development
of microbial models um yeah in latest
20th century we have more than 60
microbial models developed. So it was
very important to review what is
happening uh in the microbial models uh
scenario. So to put forward I developed
these ident
objectives that is to identify and
characterize the major microbial
processes incorporated in microbial
models to elucidate the environmental
factors influencing microbial processes
and to identify the challenges
associated with microbial
models. So after reviewing more than 70
models, I found that there are four
micro major microbial processes that has
been incorporated in microbial models
that is microbial biome microbial
mediated decomposition, mineral
interaction, microbial necroass
recycling and active and dormant
microbial
dynamics. One by one I would like to
explain all these microbial processes.
Uh the first major process is microbial
mediated decomposition of solonic
carbon. uh there are several
mathematical equations how these
microbial uh mediated decompositions
have been represented in microbial
models
like so I I am trying to explain here u
like zero order the first one is zero
order microbial model as the name
suggest even there is a representation
of microbial biomass in the model this
biomass does not actively participate in
the decomposition equation so the
decomposition rate uh does not depend on
microbial biomass. So I named it zero
order microbial uh model. Then um then
the next one first order microbial
model. Here the microbial
biomass was directly related with the
decompositions as a linear fashion. So
uh the decomposition was linearly
related. So I named it as first order
microbial bio model. Then there are
several nonlinear microbial model. um
that are represented by forward mikles
mainten. Uh in the forward mucus
mainten the decomposition is u limited
by substrate s here represents uh the
amount of solonic carbon present in the
soil. So the decomposition rate it um it
is limited rate limited by substrate
whereas in reverse makement the
decomposition is um rate limited by
enzyme microbial
enzyme. Then uh combining all together
most of the microbial models they are
represented by
nonlinear equation. So like here we can
see most of them are represented by
nonlinear and only few models were
represented by linear models either
first order or zero order model.
So what um in the conventional model
again conventional model assumes that
the Z the decomposition of any solar
carbon it is not limited by microbial
biomass and uh they implicitly assume
that the decomposition of carbon
substrate um is different than like
active soil carbon pool slow carbon soil
carbon carbon pool and passive soil
carbon pool. So these uh these are
conceptual biomass soil biomass uh yeah
soil carbon pool in the soil
um those have different decomposition
rate. But in microbial biomass uh the
soil organic carbon they have different
decomposition rate because some solici
carbon are attached to microbial
attached to mineral component and they
are not actively available for
decomposition that's why they have they
are not taking part in the
decomposition. Then um if there is a
microbial biomass in the model what is
happening with the microbial
biomass in some microbial model they
pushed forward um they added sorry
uh they added one more carbon pool that
is microbial necroass that that contains
dead organic dead microbial biomass and
also enzyme secreted by microbial
biomass because these dead microbial
necroass they have different
decomposition rate than uh plant residue
or other sologic carbon pool uh because
of different carbon nitrogen
ratio. Then uh some models also assume
that some microbes they are smart. uh
when the environment is not favorable
they can go into dormant uh phase and
the these dormant microbial biomass they
will not actively participate in
decomposition and when we have favorable
environmental condition they again
switch to active microbial biomass and
start to decompose so organic carbon
uh in microbial model um these processes
are also influenced and affected by
environmental controls. Most of the
models they uh use three main
environmental controls soil temperature,
moisture and pH uh with varying u
functions um to represent in the model.
But uh even these cons uh these are very
like um microbiology based microbial
model development still there are
several challenges associated with
microbial models like first one uh
microbial model core biggest assumption
is that uh the decomposition of soil
organic carbon it is limited by
microbial biomass. But some studies they
suggest that micro that some organic
carbon they are limited by abiotic
factors like mineral in the soil. So we
need some experiment to prove that the
decomposition of sol organic carbon is
limited by microbial biomass and more
observation data is needed to constrain
more microbial models parameter. And the
third incorporation of more processes
makes the model too complex to constrain
parameters. So in conclusion u I found
these four processes microbial mediated
decomposition mineral uh interaction
microbial necrom active and dormant
physiological states and um like even
these four processes they are
represented by several mathematical
equations. It means same uh processes uh
we have very difficulty and they are
uncertainty in translating these
knowledge into model and the highest
biggest recommendation is we need
datadriven model development and
parameterization for highly recommended
to improve uh prediction of microbial
models. So uh now next two chapters I'm
very excited to present my modeling work
that is uh hydraulic grid distribution
chapter 2 and chapter 3. Uh in the
chapter two I will discuss about
hydraulic red distribution um decreases
with precipitation magnitude and
frequency in a dryland ecosystem. It is
a uh data model fusion approach. So
first what is hydraulic redistribution?
Um it is a vertical movement of water um
among soil layers u by root from wet to
dry soil layers at night time mostly
diven by water potential gradient water
can move from deep soil layer where we
have more water to shallow soil layers
at night time preferably mostly at night
time when we don't have transpiration
and downward hydraulic redistribution
can happen when there's a rainfall and
top soil layer have more water water
than the deep soil layers. So downward
hydraulic red distribution can
happen. So it is not a conceptual based
uh process. Uh we it is really
identified in the field. It can be seen
by using root slux uh measurement where
we install some sensors in the uh in the
lateral roots and we detect water is
moving from away from root uh to the
soil. So these
negative these negative lines um below
zero they represents that water is
moving away from the root that we found
um the presence of hydraulic
redistribution in our study site but uh
this is one tree location. Uh the
magnitude of hydraulic redistribution is
still uncertain and there has been
several studies conducted and still
magnitude uh is a debatable
topic. So uh to improve hydraulic red
distribution representation in model um
I use uh one classic uh hydraulic red
distribution model to my to uh process
based ecosystem model that is chico
which I will explain. Uh the main
purpose of this study was to uh
realistic uh implementation of hydraulic
redistribution in a model. So for the
objectives of this study was to
incorporate hydraulic redistribution
process into an ecosystem model
constrained by observational data
through data estimation technique and
then to identify the key mechanisms uh
determining the presence and magnitude
of hydraulic redistribution then to
quantify the dynamics and hydro of
hydraulic redistribution across multiple
soil depth.
So this is uh some uh information about
the study site. Uh the mean annual
temperature was uh 10.5° C. Annual
precipitation 170 to 400 mm. The soil
type is uh sandy
loom and the vegetation mostly 60 to 80%
is juniper pinion in our study side. So
to implement a realistic process in a
model, we need uh these three steps to
fulfill that is first structure uh we
should have a correct representation of
equation in our model that I added
hydraulic redistribution process in our
ecosystem model. Then parameterization I
use data simulation technique u to
optimize parameters to represent our
study site and external forcing uh like
precipitation temperature uh for the
realistic
projection. So this is the toco model uh
that is terrestrial ecosystem model uh
it presents an ecosystem for a field
fail study site. uh it has all the uh
components like canopy model
photosynthesis where is happening
photosynthesis transferring to leaf stem
and roots then um these biomass going
into the
soil liter formation and then we also
have soil water dynamics. So I added
hydraulic redistribution uh in our soil
water dynamics module. The soil water
module was balanced by unsaturated water
flow, evapor evaporation, transpiration
and hydraulic
redistribution. This is a very important
uh uh unsaturated water flow. How water
usually flow in the soil. uh this is
represented by Darcy equation or also
known as U Richard's equation where
water moves because of this u water
potential gradient and plus one here
represents the gravity. So water is
moving among the soil layers uh like
deep in the soil layer through two uh
two processes u based on water potential
difference it can move upward and
downward and plus one uh it will al
always go downward through gravity. So
uh and this uh this K represents
hydraulic conductivity which was
represented again by uh Brooks and Corey
model. Um uh the Z colorcoded parameters
I used data simulation to optimize these
parameters using soil water content data
I had uh from the yeah from the field.
Then the this process uh all about this
process hydraulic distribution
model it is represented by CRT that is
maximum radial soil how much uh plant
root is allocated in the soil layers.
Then u it is difference between water
potential gradient between the soil
layers. Maximum u yeah the ci represents
relative soil root conductance how much
soil and root they are connected with
each other and RI they are the root
fractions available in each soil layers.
DAN it control it is a switch because
hydraulic rate distribution it happens
only night time. So
uh this dan has two values zero or one.
At night time it will become one. At day
time uh it will be zero. And this is
controlled by solar
radiation. So if there is a solar
radiation it will assume the model will
assume it is a daytime. If not then
nighttime. So uh this is the model
lizard. Uh the black line it represents
observation. blue it is to plus
hydraulic red distribution that is
modified model and default TCO means
without adding hydraulic red
distribution. Here we don't see the much
improvement but if we see more closely
we can see the blue line that is
modified model it is aligning well with
the observation
um and also hydraulic redistribution
model does not is not active all the
time. we need to find out what time
period at what environmental condition
it is active. So if we see RMSSE error
here the first column is it represents
the RMSSE for whole time period. Um not
much improvement, little bit improvement
but not much. Mostly at dry period we
see a major improvement in model uh
performance for soil for volumetric
water content and again wet
period not much improvement because this
dry land does not have very high amount
high volume of rainfall. So water is not
moving uh like hydraulic redistribution
is not contributing much moving water
from top soil to deep soil layer. But uh
because of dryland ecosystem water is
moving from deep soil layer to top soil
layers that what we expected here. We
can see here in dry period we have
improved model
prediction. This is total model
simulation. Here we can see dal
um uh dial HR simul hydraulic
redistribution
simulation. Uh one note I would like to
say TCO model it has 10 soil layers. So
here it represents 10 soil layers from 5
cm to 180 cm and this is the
representation how water is moving how
this is how hydraulic redistribution is
moving water from deep soil layer to top
soil layer. So when we don't have
precipitation, water is moving from deep
soil layer to top soil layer. These
these lines they are the top soil layers
of 5, 15 and 30
cm. And at the same time we are seeing
the deeper soil layers they are losing
water. So it also represents the water
mass balance. Similarly here u yeah when
we have precipitation u very little
amount of precipitation still hydraulic
redistribution is moving water from top
soil layer to deeper soil layer that is
shown in negative direction and the deep
like 30 cm soil layer it shows some
increase in water content uh in
hydraulic distribution which represents
deep soil layer means top soil layer is
moving to a deeper soil layer because of
precipitation
Here we see
daily hydraulic redistribution
simulation at different soil depth
mostly at 55 30 60 cm which I had data
to compare with. So here we can
see when we have precipitation hydraulic
red distribution is coming close to zero
and when we have dry water is like
hydraulic redistribution getting in the
very positive side. water is being moved
from deep top soil
layers. So uh again uh we wanted to know
h how this which mechan how how
hydraulic redistribution is working in
the ecosystem. So we found a uh
significant correlation between
precipitation and hydraulic
redistribution magnitude in the top soil
layers. we see um there's a decrease um
there's a negative relationship between
hydraulic redistribution and
precipitation. uh but in the deep soil
layer when we have uh much uh
precipitation high volume of
precipitation deep soil layer hydraulic
redistribution is getting positive which
means at high precipitation it is
gaining water from the top soil layers
and not only precipitation the drought
period at the in the environment also
controls um how controls the magnitude
of hydraulic redistribution so the
x-axis uh represents dry dry spell
length. How long the dry period was in
that uh between two precipitation
events. So if we have longer dry spell
between two precipitation events, we
have high hydraulic redistribution. What
means more water is moving from deep
soil layer to top soil
layers. Then uh because this water is
moving so we want we wanted to see how
it is influencing overall soil moisture.
So when we have dry condition persistent
dry condition water is getting so top
soil layer is gaining more water. This
is a heat map graph. So at persistent uh
dry condition we see increase in soil
moisture up to 30 cm in top soil layers.
But if we go deeper in the soil this
volume is decreasing.
So uh the conclusion of this uh chapter
was hydraulic redistribution improved
soil moisture prediction especially in
the top 30 cm with greatest impact
during dry periods. Surface soil
moisture increased by up to 30% during
dry periods. Hydraulic red distribution
decreased with increasing precipitation
magnitude and frequency but was also
influenced by length of dry spells
between rainfall events. Uh in this
ecosystem because of dry land ecosystem
we have upward hydraulic red
distribution in top 60 cm soil profile
became more pronounced as dry condition
progressed with rates ranging from 03
to2 mm per
day. Uh then the third and final chapter
that is investigating the influence uh
the uh influence of hydraulic
redistribution on carbon and water
dynamics. The overall objective of this
project was to quantify how much
hydraulic redistribution is influencing
on carbon and water dynamics of
ecosystem. So to conduct this study I
used data from two study sites. One is
from US MPJ New Mexico site. It is a
flux site where we had data for soil
water content at 5 10 30 cm and NE net
ecosystem exchange data to compare and
validate our model. Again this ecosystem
also similar pinion and juniper sandy
soil 385 mm average precipitation and
10.5 average temperature. Whereas the
second side alpine meadow it is a
grassland ecosystem having mean annual
temperature 1.5 annual precipitation
760 different type of soil lom soil
vegetation yeah against
grassland we have soil water content at
5 10 20 and 40 cm. So the model was
calibrated using soil water content and
net ecosystem uh using data
simulation. So u this is very
interesting finding uh from the both if
we compare both sides. The first one is
uh still dryland ecosystem but we have
very frequent precipitation u not very
seasonal throughout the year we have a
small amount volume of precipitation
throughout the year. So we did not see
much hydraulic redistribution in this
area.
So hydraulic um mostly it was still
upward hydraulic redistribution because
it is positive but very minimal 0 to 0.5
mm water per day moving from deep to top
soil layer whereas this alpine
meadow here we can see we have seasonal
precipitation only mostly at the growing
uh period. So um we see a significant
negative hydraulic redistribution means
water is moving from top soil layers to
deep soil layers that is downward
hydraulic redistribution.
So uh again uh if we see if we compare a
model result with observation at US MPJ
site we don't see much u effect in ne
data uh ne simulation model simulation
with and without hydraulic red
distribution red color line is uh
modified model with hydraulic red
distribution blue is without uh we see
little bit change um but not much
substantial so
u we also see some improvement in model
simulation when we added hydraulic
redistribution but again not much
hydraulic redistribution decreased
carbon dioxide uptake from atmosphere
during April to June by 0.03 to 0.2 2 g
carbon per meter squared per day in
average.1 g u. Yeah. So at this site
because of uh very frequent
precipitation we did not see much effect
of hydraulic redistribution happening in
this site. But uh if we see u second
site alpine meadow uh we see some
difference in with and without hydraulic
redistribution.
Um after adding hydraulic distribution
in the model we saw a little bit
improvement overall improvement in hydro
model simulation R square value 044 to
A48 but uh if we see at particular time
period because hydraulic redistribution
does not work all the time throughout
the year we need some particular time
when it is most prominent in the uh
ecosystem. So I found these two time
periods.
Um so this uh here we see hydraulic
redistribution decreased carbon dioxide
uptake from atmosphere during April to
June that is early growing season by
0.07 to 0.53 g carbon per meter squared
per day. Uh if we compare with the
hydraulic redistribution because water
is moving from top soil to deep soil
layers. So hydraulic redistribution is
reducing water content in the top soil
layers. That's uh that is the reason we
see reduced carbon dioxide
uptake. But if we see here there was a
gap um even in this growing period if we
have a gap of precipitation we see model
um during late growing season hydraulic
redistribution increased uh carbon
dioxide uptake by 0.4 4 to 0.31 g per
meter squared um per day because we can
see there is reduced in downward
hydraulic
redistribution water there is not much
change in
water. Yeah. So again we wanted to see
how how hydraulic redistribution is
affecting water dynamics of the
ecosystem. At US MPJ site we did not see
much um influence of hydraulic
redistribution but at alpine meadow we
see at early growing season there is a
reduce in available soil moisture
because of downward hydraulic
redistribution and then hydraulic
redistribution reduced ET that is evapo
transpiration here red line represents
um modified model that is TCO plus HR um
yeah it is matching with the data and uh
hydraulic redistribution reduced ET by
0.7 mm uh water per per day.
So the conclusion of this chapter was to
um no significant hydraulic
redistribution and its influence on
ecosystem functions was detected at US
MPJ site likely due to two main reasons
because of frequent precipitation
there's no prolonged dry period. So
hydraulic red distributor did not get
activated much and also because of sandy
soil uh sandy soils the water moves very
fast uh through the through the soil
profile. So there was not much retention
of water in the sandy soil. But at the
alpine meter due to seasonal
precipitation model pred prediction
suggest downward hydraulic
redistribution of magnitude of up to
0.22 22 mm water per day and decrease in
carbon dioxide uptake ranging from 03
to.32 g carbon and it also reduced at
some time period of ET up to 7 mm water
per
day. Uh and the take-home message from
all of my three chapters like first
chapter it is microbial models. uh the
biggest
uh recommendation or suggestion was to
datadriven model development and
parameterization are highly recommended
to improve the prediction of microbial
models. from uh second and third
chapters. Uh precipitation pattern and
soil texture are the stronger drivers of
hydraulic redistribution than biome
itself because we saw a two uh same kind
of biome precipitation is influencing
hydraulic redistribution. And then the
incorporation of hydraulic
redistribution could
improve
somewhat little prediction of uh
ecosystem functions at extreme
environmental condition.
Yeah, I would like to thank uh my
adviser and committee uh Dr. Lu, Dr.
Santosu and Dr. Scott Stein Snider, Dr.
Leen Jang and all uh my collaborators
and
friends. Yeah, if we have time, yeah,
I'm happy to take question. Thank
you. Yeah, thank you Anish. Um, I was
wondering mostly regarding your second
chapter. So, how would you say if we
think about the potential for climate
change to have longer dry periods and
and um, you know, potentially having
those, you know, droughts that are are
are for longer? So how would you say
that would I guess it would increase the
importance of including um the hydraulic
bre distribution in models but how do
you think that would be likely to affect
uh anything? So your question is how it
will affect uh when we have climate
change longer drought period. Yeah,
besides that we should maybe include it
more in models like it seems like more
important then to include
means if uh yeah if we have more drought
period I think uh that is beneficial to
add hydraulic redistribution because as
we have more uh drought period as we go
further in the dry condition the
hydraulic redistribution is more
activated so it is adding more water
from deep soil layer to soil layers So
it is only beneficial we have really
longer dry period and also if we have
short dry period adding it is it not
also harmful uh it is also matching well
without adding hydraulic redistribution.
So adding is not harm yeah harmful and
yeah but it could help when it's drier.
Yeah thank you. Yeah.
Yeah. Anisha probably ask you before um
do you have soil moisture data do does
top layer so moisture increase at night
time in the observational data if
hydraulic retribution is a has a big
impact we should see that
signal. So in uh in the soil moisture as
other literature says there should be
increase in soil moisture exactly at
night time. Uh we do see amplitude uh
like increase uh in the like 24 time
period we see increase and then decrease
of moisture but not exactly at night
time. our data there is some lag time
lag which shows um yeah but in the in
the hydraulic distri we assume it
happens mostly at night time but there
is some
lag soil moisture is getting highest at
11:00 a.m. like that but we do see there
is a amplitude fluctuation of soil
moisture. Yeah. Without without rainfall
in dry condition.
Yeah.
I just had a question about your
perspective on chapter one. So uh the
McKelis Menon style models when they're
looking at microbial biomass they're
usually substrate driven. So the
activity is sort of dependent on the
substrate concentration. From an
ecological point of view, we describe
that as as bottom up. So you're limited
by the substrate. But there's another
model where you could be top down where
the growth of the activity is driven by
consumption by like a predator or a
virus, ciliates, neatodes. So in a top
down system, you sort of uncoupled from
aisment kinetics because now it's the
rate of consumption and the microbes
grow to keep up. So it could change the
efficiency and then change basically the
amount of necroass that you get. Did you
encounter any models or were there any
sort of recognition of this top down
versus bottom up issue in the models
that you explored?
Uh u uh unfortunately no I did not see
uh this u maybe it is more
bio microbiology side paper I have to
review. uh this was more uh ecological
side pure modeling works so I think more
time we will need a modeling side they
need more time to incorporate those
understanding u my my sense is that
they're mostly based on Michaelis meton
but you've read many more papers on this
topic than I have so value your opinion
thank you yeah thank you right thank you
so much and thank you all
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu.