this is a production of Cornell
University um so like Lori said um my
lab works on these thermally dimorphic
fungi so these are all pathogens of
people and unlike many fungi that cause
disease in people they're all primary
pathogens which means that they can
infect um healthy individuals as well as
imuno compromised individuals and what
Drew me to these organisms is that they
all have the very interesting capacity
to sense temperature and that's how they
distinguish whether they're growing in
the soil which is kind of their natural
habitat or whether they're inside a
Maman host and on this slide you can see
um these two images so these are both um
histoplasma capsulatum so uh this is one
of the organisms that we study and when
it grows in the soil it grows in a um
one second I'm going to see if I can
make the pointer not go away okay so it
grows in a filamentous form so long
chains of cells or hyy um for those
familiar with the fungal lexicon and
this form also produces vegetative
spores and so then when the soil is
disrupted fragments of these filaments
um and the spores get aerosolized and
they can get inhaled by mammals
including humans um and then inside the
host these cells will transition to a
budding yeast form so a more unicellular
form of growth and um that form in the
case of histoplasma goes on to colonize
inate immune cells so specifically
macrofagos um and so in my lab we study
um so since temperature is a major
signal that triggers this switch between
the soil form and the host form we study
how the cells sense temperature um and
then and that's something we can we can
recapitulate this transition in the
laboratory simply by switching the temp
tempure so that makes it um a little bit
uh easier to study alth the although
these are uh somewhat challenging
organisms um but then we also look at in
addition to temperature sensing we look
at the interaction between uh these
fungi um and innate immune cells and
today I'm going to focus mostly on the
um temperature regulation of morphology
um but I will tell you a little bit
about um veillance as well all right so
these are the these are the main
organisms the thermally dimorphic fungi
that are primary pathogens so
histoplasma is up there at the top um
and uh I'm going to tell you today some
histoplasma biology and then also covid
coides um the third one down um which is
uh one of the sorry um which is one of
the thermal dimorphs that we more
recently started studying so when we
embarked on this field for all of these
organisms it was clear clear that they
sense temperature and that that affects
their development either in the soil
form on the left or the host form on the
right um but for none of them did we
understand what the pathways are that
allow the cells to sense temperature and
then um adopt the appropriate um
morphology um and I'll just tell you
within the the US these are the areas
where these fungi are endemic so
histoplasma is mostly in the Ohio and
Mississippi river valleys down into
Texas and coides is a uh Southwestern us
pathogen so um uh California Arizona um
it's spreading northwards into Oregon
and Washington State and then it's also
um Mexico Central America South
America
okay so um I really love this slide
because it's um it's an old one but it
kind of encapsulates um some of this
really interesting temperature dependent
biology so um on the top you can see uh
what happens to histoplasma spores at
37° so here we're starting with um
asexual spores that histoplasma has
generated that we've generated in the
lab then we're allowing them to
germinate at two different temperatures
so along the top you can see that if you
germinate them at poost temperature or
37 degrees Celsius they'll um happily
divide uh in the yeast form so they'll
generate these unicellular yeast cells
but if you germinate them at lower
temperatures they'll make hyi and so we
think that there must be some molecule
or set of molecules in the Spore that as
it germinates allow it to sense what
temperature it's at and then allow it to
figure out whether to grow as generate
cells that grow as yeast or grow as hyy
um and then these yeast cells when
they're generated in the host they are a
pathogen of um macras so this is just
this is a movie um of histoplasma yeast
cells that are growing inside bone
marrow derived macras so um what's
happening is that and I know it's maybe
it's easier to see um over there um
because of the lighting um but the
histoplasma cells are producing a
secreted M Cherry protein and so when
the histoplasma gets phagocytosed by the
maccrage it gets taken up it stays
within a membrane bound compartment and
so all of those red rings you see that's
because the histoplasma as it divides
the membrane also continues to surround
it and then the secreted M Cherry
protein is is kind of ringing the
membrane that's the host membrane that's
um around each fungal cell and so you
can see there's a pretty dramatic cell
death event so histoplasma replicates
within a human a human or Mouse in this
case immune cell the maccrage and then
it will trigger host cell liis and one
of the things we study in the lab which
I'm not going to really talk about today
is that the fungus produces secreted
virulence factors or ectors that Transit
out of the out of the fungus out of the
phagosome into the host cytool where
they stimulate um host cell death
Pathways um and that's an area of
interest for
us okay so getting back then to the
temperature question how do cells sense
temperature to turn on both this change
in morphology and veilance factor
expression that's coupled with growth in
the yeast form um and so we've been
studying this for for a while um and
over the years you know just comparing
the soil form and the host form we see
that you know there are robust gene
expression changes so about a quarter of
the genome uh the transcriptome sorry is
remodeled um uh during this temperature
transition we can see that some
transcripts about 1% of the transcripts
have an alternative transcript start
site depending on whether the cells are
growing in the hyle form or the yeast
form and we have some evidence for
translational regulation again um in
these two different forms so temperature
then results in this change in cell
shape and gene expression and that
allows the fungus to be um Prime to then
colonize the host and cause
disease okay so we imagine that there
are some molecules in the fungus we call
them molecular thermometers just
borrowing a term from the field of
temperature sensing um in general um and
so we think that for example a molecular
thermometer is a molecule that changes
its confirmation in response to
temperature and that could be a protein
it could be an RNA um there are even
some examples of DNA um sensing uh
temperature changes changing the
topology of the DNA um but that that
that confirmational change which could
be intrinsic uh to the temperature would
then um prompt the cells to turn on
signaling Pathways that determine growth
in either the yeast or the hyle form and
it looks like I guess the bottom of my
slides are going to get cut off a little
bit so hopefully there's not too much
information that we're going to lose
okay so the holy grail for us has been
trying to identify what these
temperature sensors could be and I'm
going to tell you in this first part of
the talk how we are approaching um that
problem so a number of years ago now we
did a screen for uh genes that are
required for yeast phase growth so just
simply re reasoning there's some pathway
Downstream temperature that's going to
result in the ability for histoplasma
cells to grow in the yeast form and if
we um have mutants that are deficient in
that pathway we will then get meant that
are unable to grow as yeast and instead
they will be constitutively um
filamentous and so in that mutant screen
we identified a number of genes that are
required for yeast phase growth or we
call them rip um and you can see here
the phenotype so wild type cells will
grow in the yeast form at 37° uh the
filament is form at room temperature um
just as I've told you but these mutants
are constitutively filamentous so
independent of temperature they always
grow um as hyy and each of these mutants
turns out to be deficient in a different
transcription Factor so all four of
these transcription factors are required
um for yeast phase
growth and uh they are all conserved
fungal transcription factors and these
transcription factors are each
upregulated in response to 37° or high
temperature either at the transcript
level or the protein level or both and
each is required for the normal
transcriptional program which you can
see here so um while type cells uh as I
told you uh grow as yeast at 37 degrees
I'm going to try the pointer here um and
then uh filaments at room temperature
and if you just look at this First
Column so here this is just a heat map
of transcriptional data where each row
is a different Gene and if you compare
wild type cells growing um at 37 degrees
to room temperature you can see that
there's a set of transcripts that's
normally upregulated at 37 degrees and
normally upregulated at room temperature
when the cells are growing as filaments
and then in each of these rip mutants if
you compare their gene expression
profile at 37° to while type cells
growing growing at 37° you can see that
they fail to upregulate that set of
transcripts that's normally associated
with high temperature growth and instead
they inappropriately accumulate
transcripts that are normally expressed
in the hyle form um at room temperature
so there each of them is a master
regulator of um yeast phase growth and
that program um and interestingly to us
when we started you know when we first
defined them sorry and uh we looked at
their transcriptional targets we could
see that they regulate genes that are
required for both cell shape as well as
veilance and so they were the first or
they are the first molecular handle
between temperature and these Downstream
phenotypes of you know changing the cell
shape and turning on bance genes um so
this work is all published um uh we
basically defined the network of these
rip transcription factors we can see
that they all regulate
well rip one two and four regulate them
regulate themselves um they all regulate
each other either directly as indicated
by the solid lines or indirectly as
regulated by the dash lines so I think
one of the reasons each of these four
transcription factors is required is
that when you take out any one of the
four you're basically taking out all
four because they regulate each other um
we defined a motif uh for rip one um
that we call um here Motif a and we and
we just we biochemically found the rip
two and rip three which are part of the
same um transcription Factor family um
make a heterodimer and together bind a
separate Motif Motif B and then in terms
of the genes that are required for cells
to become a yeast cell so yeast phase
specific genes or yps genes there are
all kinds of combinations of different
motifs um that stimulate the expression
of those genes in response to
temperature so having defined these
networks um what was really useful for
us was that some of the downstream genes
were important candidates for virence
these are all you know sort of effectors
of unknown function and we've been
exploring that but what I'm going to
focus on more today is this question of
what turns on this pathway in response
to temperature thinking up stre of the
rip genes and um how that might work so
um just to then quickly summarize that
and set up the the next question so I've
told you that these four transcription
factors form a complex circuit they
regulate each other they regulate
themselves and they're required for the
normal morphologic response and
molecular response to temperature but
we'd like to understand then what is it
about the higher temperature that
regulates um these important
transcription factors
um and so to set that up I'll just tell
you uh one of the things we've looked at
in the past is um comparing um steady
state um yeast cells grown at 37 degrees
to steady state hyy I didn't tell you
this but it it actually this is not a
fast transition for these cells
morphologically they're slow growing
cells it actually takes if you start out
with yeast cells growing at 37 degrees
and you shift the temperature down to
room temp temperature it takes several
days to make highi um so if you look at
the steady state populations and you
look by Western at the rip proteins what
you see is that the rip proteins are
much more highly they accumulate to much
higher levels in um steady state yeast
as opposed to hyy so they're just not
around in steady state hyy at Rim
temperature to very high levels um and
interestingly one of the things that we
continue to explore is that the
translational efficiency of the rip 1
and two transcripts seems to be
temperature responsive so it seems like
at 37 degrees you facilitate the
translation of rip one transcript and at
Rim temperature you you um you uh
whatever the opposite of facilitate is
the you sort of downregulate the ability
of that rip 2 transcript to be made to
be translated at um rim temperature and
so that's a very interesting um area of
potential temperature regulation that
we're investigating I I also told you
that there's differential transcript
start sites for some um subset of
transcripts including rip 2 actually at
the two temperatures um and now one
thing that uh morat um oh you can't see
his name at the bottom of the slide that
um Marat uh a post talk in the lab
is exploring is just looking globally
um in genome wide at RNA shape at the
two temperatures and so this is
something we are continuing to
investigate how different RNA molecules
might serve as molecular
thermosensors but um the next so that's
all well and good but the next set of
experiments I want to tell you is based
on the reasoning that if there's
something intrinsic about temperature
that is um that is causing a change in
the cells then we ought to be able to
see that not just by looking at these
steady state very different cells yeast
and hyy but after acute temperature
shift if it's intrinsic then it
shouldn't take days to um to cause a
change and so we wanted to understand
two things one is what happens at
intermediate temperatures and this has
never been looked at in the literature
and then what happens short term after
you change the temperature from
37° so um and I'll just say one of the
reasons this very simple question of
what happens at intermediate
temperatures hasn't been looked at is
because these organisms require
biosafety level three containment to
work on because they can infect healthy
people in the lab and so um that means
that a lot of the fundamentals um we we
don't understand um and so uh this is
one of one example of that so we wanted
to understand whether 37 degree that
temperature was required to m maintain
um rip transcription Factor activ
activity and if you shift the
temperature down acutely uh what happens
um and so we so Anna Morrison who's a
current graduate student in the lab
finishing up her PhD um looked at what
happens early on when you shift um the
temperature down both to room
temperature and some of these
intermediate temperatures so first
morphologically um so starting out with
yeast cells at Day Zero
um Anna maintain them at 37 degrees and
then you maintain the yeast morphology
as you would expect but if you shift
them to room temperature then you start
to generate High full cells um and then
at intermediate temperatures it turns
out that you don't maintain the yeast
form at 29 degrees Celsius or even at 33
degrees Celsius a four a 4 degree
temperature shift down from
37 um and so uh we need maintenance at
37 Dees to keep um uh the yeast form and
so Anna wanted to look at what happened
um transcriptionally to cells um and she
decided to look um two hours after the
temperature shift so I'll just remind
you at two hours after the temperature
shift all the cells look morphologically
like yeast it takes a number of days for
them to shift into the hyle form but
even though they look morphologically
like yeast the question was what are
they doing transcriptionally after this
2hour shift and it turns out uh to be
the case that about a quarter of the
transcriptome changes significantly in
expression level after a 2hour shift to
lower temperatures um and you can see uh
what I'm showing you uh in terms of what
the yellow indicates so these different
columns are um what happens when you uh
compare the um gene expression profile
of cells grown at 37° with a 2hour shift
to a lower temperature either 33 29 or
room temperature so the yellow these are
the genes that are normally um expressed
in the yeast form at 37 degrees but
change in expression when you shift um
when you shift the cells down and the
blue are the ones that are normally hyul
in their expression um and they turn on
when you shift the cells from 37 degrees
to a lower temperature and so just
looking at these genes so so um this was
this was very interesting because it
told us okay even at an early stage when
the cells still look morphologically
like yeast transcriptionally they're
very different and the cells already
know they're no longer maintained at 37
degrees and so um some of these genes
make sense to us so for example and this
will be uh relevant in a few slides
hsp90 which is a well-known heat shock
protein chaperone um in UK carotic cells
so hsp90 is one of the genes that when
you when you shift the cells down from
37 degrees they start to turn off hsp90
expression and I'll just say here that
you know that's sort of very appealing
because the heat shock pathway you know
if you just think about the question of
how do cells sense temperature you know
heat shock response is a highly
conserved um response from you know you
know across you know different King
and so um it it's it's appealing to tie
in the heat shock response to um how
these organisms sense temperature and so
um this kind of goes along with old data
in the lab where Cam ban a former postto
um showed that if you take yeast cells
grown at 37 degrees and you treat them
with a chemical inhibitor of hsp70 you
see filamentation of the cells telling
us that the a sorry I said HSP p70 I me
hsp90 so the that hsp90 pathway is
required for yeast phase growth and the
cells will turn down expression of H
hsp90 when you shift um them below 37
degrees similarly some of the other
genes um in this cluster um include
other transcription factors that we know
contribute to morphology because if in
this case cph1 if we knock it down the
cells can't maintain yeast phase
morphology
um and additionally some of the
veillance factors that are required for
yeast phase biology are also regulated
acutely by temperature so this um
affector in histoplasma is required for
maccrage Lis so I showed you that movie
early on of histoplasma yeast cells
licing host macras and you can see here
that wild type cells um wild type
histoplasma cells if you infect
macrofagos they'll trigger hostel Lis
which we can measure by release of a um
a maccrage molecule into the supernat
lactate dehydrogenase if you don't
infect the macrofagos you don't see Lis
and if you mutate the sperance factor
you also don't see Lis so again these um
effectors their expression is exquisitly
tied to growth at 37
degrees okay and similarly some of the
genes that um turn on when you shift the
cells down down from 37° include um
genes that we've shown are um sufficient
to trigger filamentation of cells if we
inappropriately Express them at 37
degrees so these temperature dependent
regulons um make sense to us so just
thinking about then what I've told you
um we know that transitioning
histoplasma from 37 degrees to lower
temperatures is sufficient to disrupt
yeast phase growth and transcriptional
changes occur very fast after transition
to lower temperatures um probably uh
within 30 minutes to an hour though I've
shown you the data for um two hours
after the transition um and just notably
for the next part of the talk these heat
chock pathway genes are some of the
genes that are very sensitive to Temp
the temperature of the environment so I
showed you a western blot of ripped
protein levels in steady state East and
hyy and I told you that there aren't um
there isn't much rip protein around at
room temperature in steady state growth
but how about two hours or a day after
the shift well it turns out that rip
protein levels are rip proteins are
still quite abundant these transcription
factors um when you shift um down from
37 degrees at these short time points so
this change in transcription suggests
that even though the proteins are there
something is happening about their
activity um when you shift down from 30
7° so um Anna did some uh chromatin IP
experiments where she's essentially
imuno precipitating um the DNA targets
that are bound by the rip proteins
either at 37 degrees or two hours after
shift um concomitant with also probing
the transcriptome by RNA seek and I'm
not going to show you all the data but
what she's observed is that many um
chromatin IP events or Association
events of these rip transcriptions
factors are 37 degre at 37 degrees are
reduced or absent after shift to 25
degrees so this is telling us that rip
activity is actually regulated by
temperature not just rip abundance and
in that data which we're still analyzing
Anna found a really interesting heat
shock pathway signature so I had told
you before that um normally rip one uh
from our previous published data
associated with a particular
Motif um and then rip two and three form
a heterodimer and associate with the DNA
at a different Motif so from these data
what what Anna found was the surprising
result that rip two um shown here in
green so this is Rip 2 chromatin IP at
37 degrees in in green versus two hours
after a shift down to 25 degrees in
Black that there were a set of
associations for rip 2 that were
actually not at its Norm normal DNA
binding Motif but instead we're at hses
or heat shock Elements which are um
which are the DNA binding um motifs that
regulate expression of the heat shock
pathway so um we were able to discover
that at 37 degrees rip 2 is associating
at this different Motif a heat shock
element and that that is dependent on on
temperature um and so