this is a production of Cornell
University so we're going to tell you
about the study we've been doing um on
behalf of USDA uh we have a Cooperative
agreement with the EG marketing service
and they were really interested in
exploring what is the role for USDA in
supporting Urban
Agriculture and um they recognize within
that that there is
there it is um that there is this sort
of uh emerging interest well it's
actually a huge interest right now all
over the country in how do we support
and cultivate Urban Farms carry Urban
Farms there's a lot of people doing this
so what does it take for USDA to support
the growth um and there's also um uh
also the challenge of trying to
understand is it different or similar to
how we're trying to support farms in
rural areas um what are the unique
policy um and sort of political issues
that are facing these types of producers
and and how do we help them sort of
frame and redesign themselves to be
commercial and so that was where they
came to the small farm program and they
asked could you help us do this study
because the interest was around
commercializing Urban agriculture they
fully recognize and embrace the the fact
that there's a tremendous amount of
urban agriculture happening to Community
Gardens and other types of structures uh
in school Gardens and all of those are
valued but what about the idea of trying
to make a living farming in an urban
area what would that look like where is
it working where isn't it and um so uh
that what was interesting for us is that
you know we've been doing a lot of work
in the small farm program uh focused on
Commercial uh on Commercial Rural Farms
but uh for us too it's like how would we
extend our reach and support the
development of these types of farms in
urban areas so that's kind of how we
came into it
um so we had several things that we
wanted to be able to U look at first of
all is um what are some of the different
factors that have helped uh contribute
to the success or this sort of challenge
in an urban egg
environment um and what were policy
Investments or community actions that
supported the growth of these types of
farms when they were commercially viable
and then what would be sort of future
needs and ways that USDA could position
and support Urban agriculture so uh one
of the interesting pieces here is that
in urban agriculture you have the sort
of convergence of urban planners and um
activists really interested in uh issues
of food security issues of food deserts
that are all sort of clamoring to try to
figure out is there a place and a role
for urban farming in the system and so
um this is all part of the context for
why we set out to do this so uh it was a
one-year project and it's been a
whirlwind
We There was over 150 interviews and
then we focus in on 14 Case Farms and so
um what we really want to do is sort of
help USDA think about the next Farm B
with these results and so um we're going
to tell you the kinds of things that we
found in the work and then I'm sort of
tell you about the next
steps uh so one of the issues around
trying to Define commercial Urban
agriculture it's not any different than
trying to Define commercial farming in
general we used the cut off of having
people earn at least
$110,000 a year from the sale of
agricultural products that was sort of
our Baseline that's what your tax
exemption is based on we had no real
good way of doing that um but most of
these Farms you'll see have diverse
sources of uh diverse product mix they
go into diverse Market channels um so
they and and their income from the sales
of act products is pretty sizable Port
portion of their overall Farm
budget um and uh in order to do this um
the first job we faced was trying to
identify these farms and um we were
confident we would find commercial Urban
Farms but it was actually really
hard it was harder than you would think
primarily because we wanted to have
Farms that had uh had a few years of
experience at least under their belt
three years and with recently there's
just more and more people getting into
this space so we wanted them to be
established um they had to be willing to
sort of talk with us and share with us
and we had some challenges getting
people to trust us so we'll talk a
little bit about why and how that
happened um but then uh we wanted also
them to be able to share with us some of
their financials so that we could really
look at a little bit more about what
does it look like to be farming and how
to people put together their full
package and we also want a geographic
diversity so uh the dark greens do
represent the 14 cases that we actually
did the 14 farms and so they go from
east to west and south we're not very
well represented in parts of the sort of
Southeast the Deep South but we did our
best the lighter green um uh dots are
farms that are profiled in our study but
they don't represent commercial Farms
that's novel approaches to Urban farming
um or really interesting new models of
farming that are emerging uh and then
there's in the study it a couple of
cities that are highlighted La Baltimore
and Boston based on really unique
policiy and so one thing that that Molly
has done an amazing job and Molly has an
urban planning background and so it
comes from this in a from that
perspective and then I come at it from
the agricultural perspective and um so
uh one of the things that we've wanted
very much to do with each of these cases
is to really really analyze the policy
framework that supports the development
of that so included in our study is and
there's actually other uh resources
available but have help we helped
uncover and sort of create uh what we
hope is a more robust database of
policies that can help communities
support Urban
agriculture so I'm going to give you a
little bit of a background and then um
on the types of farms that we have in
the collection there's 14 as I mentioned
um uh split in the uh gender of the farm
manager um so male and female uh one of
our important components in our work is
having racial diversity represented in
who we talk to and who were the farm
managers um and we also wanted to try to
capture new Americans who are farming in
urban spaces and so one of our Farms is
actually burmeses was a new
American um the uh years in businesses
from 3 to 23 years some of these folks
have been at this for a long time really
well
established um on average six years in
terms of thinking about farm development
we would consider all of these people
beginning Farmers because uh USDA and uh
generally recognizes individuals who
have farmed for more than 10 years as
actually being stable Farm businesses so
and several of these businesses are at
risk and in fact one of the cases and
maybe Molly will tell us more about that
uh we just found out lost their land so
we'll talk a bit about what that means
for you know a commercial Urban
Farm uh the acreages of these Farms
range from .1 acre to
3.25 very
small um and uh the the year and their
ownership or access to that land um is
at times very tenuous but many lease
some own and some have some combination
of
that uh a mix of structures and we're
going to talk a little bit more about
business structure primarily because it
has real implications on income sources
and the actual business strategy so we
have uh some of these are llc's and sort
of similar to many of the Farms that we
have in rural areas but we have some
nonprofits and some Farms have split
their activities into for-profit and
nonprofit
entities uh the range of Revenue on
these Farms ranged from uh 11,000 to
it's actually wrong I mean that's wrong
yeah I'm just going to say 12,000 to 1.5
million yeah 12 to 1.5 million is the
total um uh total revenue from these
Farms so quite a range of income and and
what we'll do is sort of share with you
sort of their farming strategies and how
that plays
out so I at
that um I might not use both microphones
I think I only one you don't have to as
long as you're at the podium all right
be good I won't move um so I want to
walk you guys through three example
Farms just to kind of show you the breth
and diversity of the types of farms that
we um were interviewing so Karen Fresh
Garden is the farm that Anu mentioned um
um Le Leu who is the farmer is a Burmese
Refugee she's been in the country for
about 8 years now um and she was farming
when she was back in Burma um and when
she came to the states she enrolled in a
program called new roots for refugees
it's run by a group called um cultivate
Kansas City and they do a lot to um
increase the amount of local food in the
Kansas City the area but they do help
with this farmer training program that
assists new Americans in refining their
skills building markets and becoming
commercial farms in order to have their
own businesses and their own income to
increase their opportunity upon arriving
the states so Leu founds um she Farms on
her own land where her house is too it's
just a half acre in her backyard um and
she grows a little bit of everything she
grows what she calls American crops and
burmes crops and she sells them to
different markets but her primary
markets are at farmers markets she's a
two in Kansas City um and she is kind of
Lucky in Kansas City Kansas because
there aren't any policies restricting
Urban farming at the moment or improving
it for that matter but she's able to
operate as she needs to um but she did
get an nrcs equi grant that helped her
get a high tunnel she put up at the end
of last year uh which she said has
improved her her production of spin
immensely so um the important thing to
know about Leu and a few other people
like her is that not only is their Farm
important for having a commercial
business but it's also very important
for food security for the household um
and she says the best thing about
farming in the city is that we have our
own vegetables and do not have to buy
them unlike the people that she serves
at Market so that's one example very
small small business second one I think
a lot of folks in the room know is
Brooklyn Range um they're in Brooklyn
and Queens New York they were founded in
2008 by a group of five people who
wanted to experiment with growing food
on rooftops um they have managed to get
two sites like I said one in Queens one
in Brooklyn and they have a 10-year and
a 20-year lease which Ben planner who's
um the head farmer one of the
co-founders said is extremely important
because he would not think about farming
um on a rooftop or anywhere if he had
less than a 10e lease because the amount
of work and resources that need to go
into it um they are specializing in
salad greens and other things that are
quick succession crops that um can be
sold for a high value they're growing
micro greens all year round um and have
sales all year round as a result and um
not only are they doing restaurant sales
but they're doing a lot of other
additional activities they're hosting
weddings they're hosting big farm
dinners um and they've gotten a a lot of
support too not just from doing those
other activities but from other grants
and City programs that have helped them
get the resources to farm on the roof
because as you can imagine it's not
cheap to blow all that soil up onto a
roof but they really know um they would
like more help with distribution and to
find increasingly more favorable lease
terms to keep these businesses alive um
and they are cognizant of the fact that
they are not feeding the city they're
specializing in um high value crops that
are only going to white tablecloth
restaurants but that they say does not
mean that there isn't an impact because
they're doing all these other things
that they hope are improving the food
landscape of the city and are they also
using High tunnels they do yep and we're
going to talk a little bit about how
that season extension has impacted these
Farms the third one um on the total um
flip side from Karen fresh Gardens is
green City growers in Cleveland Ohio uh
it's a
3.25 Greenhouse that uses hydroponic
floating uh rafts to grow
about I forget how many pounds they said
last year a
lot um but they um they own the land
that they're on they got help owning the
land that they're on through the city of
Cleveland kayoga County
uh they got new market tax credits which
most Farms can't get but if you and if
you want to talk about New Market tax
credits let's have a different seminar
probably won't be any of these people in
the room because it's not that
interesting but they are it is a way
that controlled environment agriculture
Farms have been able to build out in
cities and it's not available to
soil-based Farms because Farms are
excluded from New Market tax credits but
it's a way that people who want to
develop
buildings can can actually um get
financing so that helped them to build
out their $17 million facility they're
employing 36 people um and they are a
Cooperative while Evergreen cooperatives
who founded Green City Growers is a
nonprofit kind of umbrella organization
they have three separate Cooperative
businesses that they've started in a
lowincome area of Cleveland in order to
Pro provide a suite of resources to
employees who come from those
neighborhoods to kind of lift them up
out of the poverty that surrounds these
facilities so there is a program that
helps them secure housing and own a home
in the neighborhood there's a program
that helps them own a car so they can
get to work trying to make all the
things possible to get these people to
work while growing a lot of butterhead
lettuce I think one thing that's very
interesting about that business is uh um
I don't know they identify as a social
Enterprise but they are and the people
that are working there after one year
can be voted in as a
co-owner and there's no actual return
yet as a
co-owner um but the aspiration is within
10 years they will actually be able to
they would be able to sell their share
of the business and have something they
walk
away so obviously these are all really
different and it was a challenge for us
to figure out how to present them how to
part this very small data set that has a
lot of diversity but these are just some
of the examples of how diverse it is per
square foot they are earning Farm sales
between 14 cents per square foot and
$12. 63 so that's a huge range um and
there are those that are focusing on
specialty crops like I said micro greens
Sprouts mushrooms um and there's also a
diversity of farming experience and that
have an effect on how much they're able
to yield um and we're going to talk
through um on just going talk through a
little bit of how this plays out in
terms of their finances in a couple of
slides um but the farm product sales for
these organizations these Farms some of
them our organizations are anywhere
between 9 and 100% of their total
revenue
so we'll see where that other those
other parts of the revenue come from but
it's worth noting
that there's a lot of diversity and a
lot of them aren't relying solely on
what they're selling in order to keep
themselves in business um and 10 of the
14 Farms earned a profit three are
nonprofit Farms but we included them in
this study of commercial Urban
agriculture for reasons that we explain
a couple of
slides um I'm going to just to give you
an overview of what this looks like we
separated the farm into three categories
just to kind of wrap our heads around
the data so like I said there's some
nonprofits there's some for-profits
there people are doing all different
types of things so to kind of make it
simple we separate them into program
focused Farms which are those Farms kind
of like green City Growers where they're
trying to provide more than just food
there is some sort of social component
of their work some sort of programming
component of their work and often they
are nonprofit or they have a non profit
arm that enables them to get grant money
and individual giving in order to
support the programmatic work and as you
can see that makes up over half of what
they earn on average um there's
Diversified Farms so Farms kind of like
Brookland Grange that are growing food
for people to eat but they're also doing
a lot of other things like workshops and
events um and that ends up making a
significant portion on average of their
total earned revenue and then there's
production focused Farms which as the
name suggest focus on production um and
they might have a few activities that
happen but those are more kind of oneoff
events that occur and so just looking at
this these program Focus Diversified and
production focused Farms you don't
really get a sense of what that means in
terms of scale in terms of how much
they're earning and so we try to break
it down in different ways looking at the
ranges of income
and Anna is going to walk you through a
little bit of that information so you
can see what this looks like in
practice so we're going to focus
primarily in on income and sales and
profit and um we have aggregated the
data to sort of protect the information
from these Farms um so what I want to be
able to share with you just sort of a
breakdown of a total income and this is
a little bit of what Molly had shared on
that previous
slide where um we have a income anywhere
um uh from I think
around 43,000 at the bottom all the way
up to 1 uh 3.3 million for total income
but we cut off the chart at 100,000 or 1
million there at the top and so uh the
total income of our largest operation
was 3.3 when you combine both what
they're making from agriculture as well
as what they're getting from grip scin
gifts grants and other
activities um so uh what's really
important to note is of course what's
really obvious the production Focus
Farms very small total uh income to the
farm very little done with um additional
activities but also um uh for the
majority of that earnings coming from
agricultural when we look at the uh
Diversified farms and the Farms that are
um program focused the ones that are
using a lot of um educational activities
to supplement what they're doing uh our
differences in the actual earnings by a
sales is not that different but what
this does allow that uh those Farms to
do is actually to supplement income to
provide I think longer term employment
uh for many of the individuals that are
working on the
operations um so when we uh take it then
and we add to
this um and so these are ranges so these
These Bars are just representing ranges
to give you a sense we're still trying
to figure out how you actually want to
represent this for USDA so so these bars
are basically the top and the bottom of
a range for a group of farms that are
included here and so in this business
strategy What's um interesting here is
at the very bottom when you actually
look at the orange bars which represent
the um agriculture based sales the
income from sales um and then the actual
profit that they declared after you
remove
expenses um when you look at those
yellow the yellow bars at the bottom you
can find there's very very low
profitability in those ones that are
program based these Farms are doing a
lot of things they may have really huge
incomes but at the end of the day the
total profits from those operations are
not that much different from the very
small production
ones so this was a bit counterintuitive
for us and so we're still sitting with
this because it is actually kind of a
surprising to think about that and what
you're not seeing in here is um that you
know these are all Farms of different
sizes with different production capacity
and one of the other challenges in
working with small farms whether they're
rural or Urban or any kind of small
business especially if it's a sole
proprietor is how does the actual owner
operator uh take a draw from the
business and so some of our Farms
actually do have pay the owner operator
the primary manager from the actual
sales of products and others don't they
just take what's profitable what's left
over and so that is a really difficult
place in as far as trying to manage and
analyze this type of information so we
recognize that um uh and again there's
also the additional draw of food that's
supporting food security of the
household how do you actually account
for that impact on a household income so
those are um sort of future research
questions additional types of inquiry
that have to happen but we're beyond our
scope but trying to think about um the
strategy that the business strategy that
these different operations did uh what's
really evident is that um even though
they had really high operating budget
these program based ones were not
actually that much more profitable in
very small farms that were primarily
earning from the sale of egg
products so uh one thing that we tried
to do is because again there's a range
of sites we tried to sort of represent
this in a way to help us sort of get our
heads around uh some of this information
of um uh earnings and profit and cost
and so we use a small area 0.1 acre and
it's a funny thing to use that because
when you scale up if you want to
represent things on an acreage basis U
that's really common in our work in
rural agriculture but that scale up is
fraught with so many errors and doesn't
really represent sort of the intensity
of production in these Farm systems so
we actually scaled everything to a tenth
of an acre because that is sort of the
that is a unit that it really I think
represents the intensity of the way
these people are doing and managing
their business
so um and it provides sort of a way of
uh comparing across these different
categories and we're going to use this
same metric of a tenth of an acre to
look at a bunch of different things
about these
Farms so um when you look at just a
tenth of an acre and you look at the
sort of um a sales all of a sudden we're
looking at a really different framework
between these different types of
approaches where our one of our Farms
that's farming a very small scale is
making U $55,000
as far as their top and from a tenth of
an
acre um and uh and if you look at that
production Focus the first set of bars
at the far end um in fact the um the
total profit for that 10 fo acre is
higher than those other Farms that had
much higher operating
budgets so um with embedded within this
is the controlled environment farm and
so that has um uh you know the the
ability to farm year round uh and it has
a much higher earning so that's kind of
lost in this and so we want to we
recognize that but if you really just
look at a tenth of an acre over a whole
year annual sales um the very small
farms don't look that
bad one of the key factors in affecting
this um that is actually quite dramatic
is the use of season extension and so
many of these farms and I think Molly
probably share more about this um use
high tunnels and they benefited from an
nrcs program in which uh producer can
get um the cost of a high tunnel paid as
long as they report yield data from that
tunnel and um many of these Farms that
are growing outdoors with season
extension are using High tunnels and if
you actually focus in on that middle
section um you can see that their
earnings and their overall um profit per
tenth of an acre is higher than those
that are using controlled environment
agriculture so the ability to farm
really intensively using the soil based
media here based on this our um study
and the sort of information that we have
uh um for those particular Farms when
they had that season extension it really
did a lot to enhance the security of the
farm and manage risk for the farm by
increasing the months of production but
also then the total um output and the
value of that production
um Yes again these are ranges so on the
left CA it's the range of the Farms are
um as far as the 10th of an acre that's
like the the oranges um uh anywhere from
uh 47 to 7 is their total sales but then
the profitability is much lower on the
10th of an
acre so um one of the again it's
difficult again we're trying to sort of
give you a couple of different lenses to
look at this it doesn't show you the
scale um the months Outdoors that people
are producing are varies based on the
region you saw the sort of range of
farms we have from the east coast to the
West Coast and the South so some people
just out they can grow outdoors and it's
just easier to do it um uh even our
farms in the South are using um a the
high tunnels it's a really tremendous
program that probably has had more
impact on those operations and any other
intervention um that's coming from
USDA um and then uh another issue that
this does mask a bit is the diversity of
the crops that are being grown on these
farms and so that is actually sort of
the next lens that we want to sort of
give you a sense of um and so one of the
things that we've found is that those
Farms um that were actually grow um uh
and there's a new care uh a new um
category here and we're calling it
specialized um those are the Farms that
are earning more than half of their
total income from the sale of one high
value product most of the times these
Farms are growing things like micro
greens or salad
greens uh and the Farms that were able
to specialize actually had higher
profitability and this is actually kind
of important especially in terms of
thinking about the overall food security
um and the sort of impact on community
that these Farms could have because if
they're having to to be profitable they
are narrowing the number of crops they
grow um a salad does not a full belly
make and it's a challenge it's the
challenge of building a profitable
business what do you make on a square
foot basis what can you earn where do
you have a consistent marketplace where
do you take advantage of your resources
those Farms that were uh intensively
producing fewer crops um and those
specialty high value crops for specialty
markets were the ones that were actually
able to demonstrate a more profitable
business so um uh the ones that were
non-specialized those Farms were growing
A diversity of crops often using a CSA
or some other type of a marketing
channel or farmers markets but um again
they were having to sort of balance a
broad number of crops that they were
able to provide to their
customers in contrast to those that were
specializing
um and then so we can sort of talk about
what is those Market channels that these
different Farms are using and they are
the same ones that we would see Urban
farmers use or rural Farmers using
farmers markets csas uh does everyone
know the term CSA is anyone not a
community supported
agriculture I see shakes yes okay um so
uh very common um in uh from many small
farms in rural areas and these firms as
well but um gr for a CSA frankly is a is
a lot to ask for a small SC for a very
small footprint because you have to
offer uh a diverse number of crops and
so you're moving away from that
specialization and your ability to plan
and use your space most efficiently
there's always crops that don't make you
any money when you're going for a
CSA and so those Farms were not earning
or profiting as much as the other farms
and the farmers market you're capturing
all of that direct retail funds
um but those folks who are using um uh
direct wholesale to restaurants and
other types of uh purveyors so directly
selling at a wholesale they were um they
were okay of course they were probably
more specialized in what they were
growing um but they uh didn't do too bad
as far as being um more profitable than
certainly the CSA Farms um but it's
still um uh challenging to them because
they have to specialize and the
profitability is not necessary neily
always
there but so um but the markets and
again U uh I always want to sort of add
the caveat that for many of these Farms
they're not paying owner the owner has
not paid a salary so that makes it
really challenging and if you look at
sort of over comparing just about if an
owner is taking a draw versus not um uh
the on the other side the owners are
actually paid as part of the uh expenses
of the farm and then closer to me
they're not being paid um but they're
taking basically the profit from the
farm or other things from the farm to
support the household and the family
they often have other jobs off of the um
farm so there's a complement of income
coming into a family um so there's a
wide range and there's a it's a wide
there's a basically a fairly wide range
of uh total incomes per month in on a a
0.1 acre basis uh but you can see that
the sort of bars right now as far as uh
the upper earnings um for those that
aren't being paid that's that money is
really going to the um owner
alator but it's there's just not a good
way to separate it out we do have
information in our collection of based
on labor hours and total labor hours so
that's one of the things we're trying to
analyze is paid labor almost all these
firms use unpaid labor through
volunteers and we know that's fraught
with a lot of challenge because uh it's
not actually a legal label labor
category in most cases and so we are
really trying to work on these issues
related to uh volunteer labor on in
farms whether Urban or
rural so um that just gives you an
overview and a sense of the sort of
types of farms that we're seeing um I
think the real take-home message is that
these highly specialized Farms that are
growing in soil can be quite profitable
and competitive in their areas if they
have season extension technologies that
they're using um and that the word in
some ways is still out about controlled
environment agriculture firms relative
to the final sort of profitability but
with the caveat we you know we are not
completely comparing Apples to Apples
here because of the way people are
representing their own salary draw this
is the challenge across small farms
everywhere so that's a lot of different
ways to look at data and I figured it'd
be helpful if we actually applied those
lenses toce you guys to so uh Karen
Fresh Garden remember the um the refugee
farmer um she is production focused she
does very few other activities um and
she had received that equi Grant um that
allowed her to get the high tunnel that
she implemented at the end of last year
um but that did not actually figure into
her sales for 2015 she really didn't get
up and running until January um so she
doesn't actually fit in that season
extension category um and like I said
she's non-specialized she's growing a
wide variety of things and she's proud
of that
um and her income for those I think that
there were seven I know that there were
seven production Focus Farms was around
the middle um in terms of her uh yield
per 10th acre um she sells for eight
months of the year at the two farmers
markets that she sells through and those
are her primary uh those were her only
actually um Market channels in
2015 and um she has no paid labor does
not pay herself a salary but her family
helps out and her um her family members
also have off- farm jobs so together
they are um supporting the household as
is some of the yield from the farm but
she and every other farmer that I've had
an opportunity to speak to over the past
year did not figure how much she was
taking from the farm so hard to be able
to put in dollar value on that uh she
pays herself in the profits like Anu
suggested and um she is an excellent
Record Keeper when it comes comes to her
production but not when it comes to her
finances and she gets a lot of
assistance actually through uh the
training program that she worked with
for four years um and then graduated
onto her own Farm the new RIS for
refugees program so she wants to improve
her ability to manage her own finances
but that's predicated on her English
language acquisition which she is not
totally on board with the T herself too
for a lot of reasons including the
amount of time that she has including
the fact that she wants to diversify her
markets and start selling to restaurants
because she sees that there's more
potential for her to be earning more
money potentially if she works or with
restaurants book and range uh is it one
of those Diversified Farms we talked
about like I said they have a lot of
other things that they do about half of
their income comes from nonproduction
related activities um they have high
sales because they're specializing in uh
micro greens and salad greens and edible
flowers um and they have two high
tunnels on their Farm in Brooklyn one
high TL Farm Queens and they are heating
them throughout the winter to grow those
micro greens so they do have 12 months
of sales a year um and they pay all
their employees they used to have
volunteers as kind of a community
outreach uh opportunity but they
realized that it was costing them too
much money to have volunteers and they
were better off paying people who were
skilled in their labor to do their work
so they have 12 full-time year round
employees and another 12 part-time
seasonal employees and they are
continuing to refine their crops they do
very intensive recordkeeping uh to
figure out what's making money what's
making money and what's not per square
foot um and they're also scaling up
their events they're aiming to do 10
weddings in
and I haven't checked in to see how many
wasn't mine um
so Green City Growers um is controlled
environment agriculture obviously but
they are program focused like I covered
before and the way that they are
supporting their employees um and half
of their total income is coming from
their sales in 2015 and they're
continuing to scale that up but the
other half is coming from Grants um and
they also have significant loans that
are not operating loans but just as kind
of to keep in the back of your head this
wasn't a cheap thing to start
up um they're doing all direct wholesale
they're selling to Major grocery store
chains uh in
the near Midwest region want to call
Ohio the Midwest but the near Midwest um
and everyone is getting paid they the
starting salary or the starting wage for
a a worker at uh Green City Growers is
$10 an hour and they become members of
The Cooperative their pay increases from
there about a dollar a year um and their
big problem right now is building out
more markets they built this facility
and they say this themselves they they
built this facility and thought they
will come they will buy our lettuce they
are near to about 14 major institutions
hospitals colleges museums and they
figured this would be easy sell but what
they didn't realize is that a lot of
those institutional customers don't use
head lettuce they want pre-cut lettuce
and they're recognizing now that that
probably would have been something that
they should have investigated um but
they're very open with that it's just
worth noting too this is the only major
large scale uh indoor growing operation
either with um in green houses or in a
totally closed system um uh with no
lights and only using LED lighting that
was willing to be a part of our study a
lot of those types of larger businesses
have great front-facing um public
relations but they're not really willing
at this point to share information about
their sales because and about their
technology because they are trade
secrets in this very Nation uh
industry so that's just what those
financial findings look like when we
look at the farms and I want to talk you
through a couple of other findings uh as
well so the farmers are largely
self-taught um it's surprising how many
farmers say you know four years ago I
didn't know anything about farming and
people don't usually pick their dentists
that way but they but Farmers I guess
there's a little bit more leeway um but
they're working on small scale so maybe
there's a better opportunity to learn
more on small scale um and they really
want help building out their skills they
recognize that they don't have a lot and
um there is a call for having extension
agents in urban areas there aren't uh in
a lot of the places that we visited um
and they're lucky because overall their
support from the community is high
they're is sometimes tension when these
uh when these Farmers come in and we're
going to talk a little bit about that
tension um but overall the community
support is high even if the zoning and
legal support is not High um because
agriculture is not not an accepted use
in most cities only in one of the cities
that we uh profiled a farm in was
agriculture already on the books and
that was in Kansas um and the farmers if
they had a policy recommendation I think
it would probably be similar to most
farmers and it is ways to reduce their
costs um and they have high costs High
utility costs High land costs um and
they've benefited like we said from
programs like the nrcs equip program
that helps them get high tunnels and
they want to see more like
that so just to walk you through a few
of our preliminary findings and I'm
going to do this quickly um land access
is an issue as you can imagine it's hard
to find land in a city to do farming um
especially land that does not have a
toxic history or that you can even find
the history on I'm going to add that
this is also the primary issue for
people trying to start farms in
and as Anu covered before and as I said
a little bit about um they are using or
they are finding they are profitable
when they focus on Niche produce um and
not the whole CSA calorie crop uh
production uh
strategy uh the costs of social
entrepreneurship are high that's all of
the things that you do that aren't
farming when you're in City taking kids
on tours and having a workshop on
beekeeping those those are things that
people are often doing for free and
they're great community outreach tool
especially if they're trying to build
knowledge of where food comes from for
people who don't have access to Farmers
but that means that they're not farming
and when they're not farming they're not
making money um water costs in
particular are still very high for
Farmers when they really need uh that
water and they're often paying sewage
fees and storm water fees which are
extra on top of just the irrigation
water cost
and then finally commercial Urban Farms
are primarily owned by white people who
are who are farming regardless of where
they are whether they're in a community
of color or they're in a white Community
those are usually the people who are
doing the commercial farming there are
other sorts of farming that happen in
the city but for commercial purposes
it's one of the reasons why we had a lot
of difficulty getting into diversity in
terms of ethnic background and racial
diversity and socioeconomic University
because it requires we finding certain
things in order to get your on the land
so I'm going to skip over the land
access piece because we're running out
of time but um I'm happy to talk more
about how zoning has been affected the
one thing I will mention is little city
Gardens which is up here is the one farm
that we profile that has lost their land
since we started this process um and
they are out at the end of the year and
is going to be developed it is one of
the last significant green spaces over a
half acre in San Francisco um and it is
now going to be a
school um I want to head over to Anna to
talk a little bit about the racial
question so one thing that's um really
apparent in the urban egg space is the
um real tension around racial inequity
um and the structural racism that played
out in every single one of the cities
and places we were and it's not the kind
of thing that we talk about very often
in rural places because everyone there
is primarily
white um but what has played out in many
of these cities and I is
that um particularly the
African-American Community is not only
trying to farm they're also trying to
affect the health and well-being of
their communities often uh lower
resource and impoverished communities
and they are systematically and
systemically not able to access land
it's actually uh really deeply
disturbing and one of the issues that um
we confronted ourselves in trying to
visit and talk to some of these Farms
that have built you know viable Farm
businesses but they're like what
difference is this going to make us to
talk to you and I think it's U one of
those places of sensitivity everybody
has a social mission in mind but um uh
one of the far one of the one of our
Advocates here in the New York City
itself here in Washington she is just
she just said you know if you really
want to help us just ask us what we want
don't tell tell us what we want ask us
come into the community ask us what we
need to support the development of our
farms and I think it's something that um
is actually the center of the next step
of this project is really how do we
create honest conversation around this
stuff and work with planners policy
makers and developers who don't have a
language in order to communicate about
this type of use for
land um and I think what we're going to
do is just uh we this other piece that
ties to this is social entrepreneurship
and I just want to take a moment to talk
about this with you because um we h a
lot of the Farms six of the 14 have
specific educational activities that
they're doing and they are they really
recognize you know the that here you
have this Farm in this urban area and
all of these people have no idea where
their food comes from it is part of our
mission to sort of change that and
actively um sort of help bring schools
and get kids familiar with how you grow
stuff and parents so they understand the
value of Agriculture um and so it's a
service that they're providing and it is
an unpaid service for the most part all
of Agriculture benefits from this
activity but yet it's Urban Farms on
their own they're sort of soldiering it
and and and whether it's a community
garden or an actual commercial operation
that's doing it so what does that mean
for all of Agriculture this is a a
question how and where are Partnerships
with Urban Farms like this actually able
to facil itate greater awareness that
benefits all of Agriculture not just
those few little farms in those small
communities so it is a contextual thing
how do we build this
out um and so uh we know that these
cases um uh the whole point of the study
has been to really try to elevate
examples where people are making livings
or trying to be commercial on a very
small space well it's just challenging
by the footprint but it's challenged by
all of these other so economic and
cultural things going on around them uh
but I feel like we have found some
really exciting stories and what's
really interesting to me is that the
story that these Farms are telling when
they're really focused on growing food
and growing it in a good way um is not
that different than what we see in a
rural place but we haven't connected
this very actively in different ways and
so many of these Farms are really hungry
to interact with their rural colleagues
to be learning the best strategies to be
participating in those types of training
programs to be uh doing the hard work of
capturing their costs in a more active
way um and they recognize that you know
here I'm growing lettuce or I'm growing
micro greens none of this is dealing
with the real food insecurity issues
that my community faces but if I'm going
to do a business this is how I have to
approach
it so um but in the end it's being there
and being in that place in doing
agriculture that has a huge impact on
their communities and what's um we need
are some ways in which we can actually
quantify that how do you actually
quantify a change in the land values of
a community because of a farm that's
come in there and taking place and
actually affected all sorts of things
Neighborhood Activity how do you put a
price t on that um there's people trying
right now to sort of understand what is
what how do you measure social impact
how do you turn it into a number that we
can use to sort of assess uh the actual
broader impact of these types of
activities so um uh I think that's as
far as future research one of the things
that we're recommending to USDA is to
sort of think about how they're
investing in these types of metrics and
coming up with other ways to complement
the classic economic basis for which we
evaluate uh business
impact so uh we're going to be taking
the study um USDA once we're finished
with our work we've been working with a
group of 14 advisers from around the
country people that are real experts and
deeply vested in or um Urban agriculture
who've been working with us to sort of
think about how do we tell this story um
because it has sort of Fairly
broad-reaching possibly impact
particularly for planners and
individuals that are sitting in that
role in city and urban government uh so
uh what we want to do is once we're done
with this part of it and this and and
this work is published is that we will
be doing Regional uh presentations of
this and cultivating sort of more
Regional dialogue and conversations with
planners as well as those activists lead
leing to a national uh community of
practice that's really focused on the
farm bill so that's the activities for
the next year is to sort of bring
together those people that are either
farming themselves are are currently
committed to trying to figure out how do
we make Urban Farms more successful and
then how do we connect that to other
individuals that are trying to really
think about um those broader social
impacts of the farm bill and think about
what what particular changes in USDA
legislation how do we recraft or change
the authority of the rural development
arm of USDA so it could be rural and
urban AG development um sometimes it's
just changing a word or dropping a word
that allows uh grants and funds to be
used and deployed in urban areas so
that's one of our intentions uh because
of what Molly said that there's very few
um uh U controlled environment a
operations that are fully contained and
no vertical Farms were included in this
completely contained LED based farms uh
we are working right now with
Association of vertical farming and Neil
and a couple of others to try to
actually add more cases based on that
type of farming system to flush this out
and then ultimately we want to be able
to um build a deeper egg fent egg
resource library to help planners as
well as Farmers find good resources and
connections often these folks um you
know they are hunting and pecking just
like everybody else on the internet and
it's not that easy so how do you
actually distill Urban um egg policy if
you want to write an urban egg policy
for having a livestock who's done the
best job of considering the issues so we
want to be able to take all of that and
distill it into a place that can serve
as a resource um and be maintained and
work with our colleagues to do that
going
forward
so that was
it I was wondering in terms of
addressing
I it seems that the traditionals model
may not be
effective that for urban
agriculture pH I I these Farms have such
a small fo they're never going to make a
very big impact
on and I think not that is not the S of
goal and and yet there's so much that
happens just with individual awareness
and individual agency and self around
food access to production I think that's
the venue in the space where Urban egg
really works um but it is kind of um it
it's it it creates a split personality
for an urban farm because there're
supposed to be walking forth with this
Banner we're addressing food security
and some would quite passionately with
me right now saying that's all we are
about but they the bottom line is
they're not producing anything that
makes any real for communi if they
really want to farm so can we talk about
it what it really is and then think
about the complimentary activities to
amplify what it and just for an example
there's one Farm in Philadelphia that
has a CSA not really CSA Farm box
program that they're a farm but none of
the food that they is going through that
farm box program is coming from them
it's coming from the big farms in New
Jersey and Lancaster and everywhere else
so they can take a regional approach and
introduce people to the concept of
regional agriculture through an urban
farm and that actually is a way they're
increasing the calorie crops that are
coming into uh Philadelphia I have a
real impact on food security there
there's interesting programs in New York
City through working with senior centers
now which they're doing CSA box type
models they're farming on rooftops
they're getting exercise they're having
those activities there's complimentary
Farms that are making money that are
actually trying to make a living but
we're not asking one operation to we
don't ask Rural Farms to sort of meet
all of these social goals why can we
allow Urban Farms to function without
that I mean furthermore it's it's like
it's how why should we treat an urban
farm different than we treat any
business opening up in a farm in an
urban area I mean what you're saying is
they're primarily profit M motivated
like we'd like to think every farmer
should be right um why should they get
any subsidies why should we be
developing any educational resources if
they were coming in to build Refugee
communities or ways of bringing people
up then that's something we would all
invest in I think as a way to sort of
grow our next Generation population so
yeah I feel like there has to
be so there should be a really clear a
very clear social mission that can be
funded and supported with outcomes that
are related to education training or
other things that's one certain type of
operation and so Brooklyn grain for
example they split that off they
recognize that that takes so much energy
and a staff onto its own and we can't do
that and
F and by splitting up it allows them
actually to get back to the business of
the business but not lose sight of the
opportunity presented by being a farm
innoc City and that's the elegant design
that you know we want to be able to it's
examples like that there's some there's
all sorts of examp like that that we
don't think about and I think it's
really easy for us to consider and and
really focus in on um uh we we confound
think of an urban farm as an in a
community garden they're really
different these are farms that are not
Community Gardens um there is some of
them that feel like they are that they
lose vegetables to two-legged Predators
but not that much so they really are
about people trying to make a living in
these spes so we're running way over
time I'm going to suggest that for
anyone who would like to chat with Anu
and Molly they will presumably stay in
front for a few minutes and and you can
come talk to them thank you both so much
thank you thank
you this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu