this is a production of Cornell
University it's March 11th
2014 and we have had a very cold winter
I'm at the Lancing research Farm we hit
minus 10 here on January 22nd and then
had several other instances where we
went below zero so Adam and I are out
here cutting buds to see what's alive
and what's dead and so I wanted to show
you how this process works and so what
we do is we use a razor blade and cut a
way up Buds and look at what's alive
inside and so we're going to zoom up on
a bud here and you need to remember that
great buds are what we call compound
Buds and So within each Bud that we cut
there's actually a primary a secondary
and a tertiary bud and I found a great
example here for what's alive so what
I've done is come in here and that's
what the bud looked like I sliced it
with the razor blade opened it up and
you can actually see the three buds here
this Center one is the primary and
there's the secondary and then there's a
little Green Dot over here and that's
the tertiary bud so this is great we can
look at the other side of the bud here
too and you can see those green dots
those are buds that are still alive
after this winter they all have the
potential to produce shoots so what will
happen is the primary will grow first
and as long as it grows well it's
unlikely the secondary or the tertiary
will ever grow if we move up the cane
here is another bud that I cut uh and in
this you can see that the center of that
is actually Brown and so that's our
primary Bud the primary bud is dead it's
been damaged by the cold but you can see
a little bit of green on either side of
that that's the secondary and the
tertiary and those are both
alive so this is what we do pre pruning
if we've had some cold damage is that we
go through we actually cut these buds
with a razor blade and look at What
proportion are alive and What proportion
are dead because that will tell us how
many buds we want to leave on the vine
because I'll know for example that to
balance this Vine I want to have in this
example maybe about 30 live choots but
if I cut these and I know that only
about half of them are alive that means
I actually need to leave six0 nodes
rather than 30 to get my 30 shoots
through the growing season so in many
years if we haven't had cold damage we
don't bother doing this but in a year
like this where we're seeing a lot of
damage in the finger legs we go through
and cut some buds first so we get a
sample and figure out what's alive and
what's dead so we know how many more
buds we need to leave when we do our
pruning so it's it's March 11th
2014 and I'm in the Lancing Vineyard
we've had a very cold winter and we've
had some bud damage that I wanted to
show you so I've cut some buds here and
this is something that we frequently do
before pruning if we've had cold events
because we want to see how many of our
buds are alive and how many of our buds
are dead because the number of buds
we're going to leave on a vine uh we'll
know the number we need to be have a
balanced Vine for example it might be 30
in this situation and so if I know half
the buds are dead I've got to leave 60
buds so that I have 30 shoots so I've
cut some buds here and I wanted to show
you uh you need to remember that great
buds are actually compound Buds and So
within every bud there's actually three
smaller Buds and this is one where
everything's dead but you can see a
bigger set of circles here that's the
primary bud this is the secondary bud
and this little one over here this
little wedge is called the tertiary bud
and on this one when we cut it open all
three are dead so the primary the
secondary and the tertiary are all brown
nothing is growing from that bud this
year the second one here it's a little
harder to see uh because the primary
secondary and tertiary are actually
alive here so this little middle Green
Point here this is our primary bud it's
alive and well if I had not cut it it
would grow into a chute there is our
secondary bud and there is our tertiary
over here which is alive too so normally
it's the primary that will die first so
it's easy to find buds here where the
primary is dead but the secondary is
alive and in that case the secondary Bud
would actually grow and be a chute in
many cases it's not as fruitful as a
primary Chute uh the fruit will come out
a couple of weeks later and so it has
less time to mature through the growing
season sometimes it won't be a fruitful
shoot but at least there'll be a shoot
there if the secondary is alive and the
primary is not but in this case we're
hoping to find lots of buds like this
because we want to see an alive primary
secondary and tertiary
bud this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu