this is a production of Cornell
University so as my title shows I'm
going to use this opportunity to sort of
look back over the last few years of
different research projects I've been
involved in in which we particularly
looked at how arod communities respond
to different act management practices
environmental factors and so the common
theme will be Community level response
uh where the factors differ will be the
focal arthropod tax that we're looking
at the crop man the cropping system and
then the landscape context of the area
so I'm going to try to cover three
different topics here and so I might
move quickly feel free to interject if
you have any
questions so just about myself real
quick as Don said in the introduction
the main goal if I could reduce it down
to one idea is that my work tries to
identify management practices or other
environmental factors that maximize the
abundance and diversity of beneficial
arthopods in Agro ecosystems and if
possible concurrently measure ecosystem
Services as
well so before I get into the three
topics we're going to look at I just uh
want to point out again everything I'll
talk about today is at the community
level or at least multiple species
systems and so when I think of these you
sort of have different analytical
toolboxes you can pull from to assess
communities that differ than say working
at the population level and so one
objective maybe to look at diversity and
so some of the things I'll present today
might relate to species richness where
will present rare faction curves which
is sort of a standardized way to compare
species accumulation as it rises with
sampling intensity among locations or
habitats uh we may look at evenness the
relative abundance of different species
within a system or we may combine these
two things with richness and evenness
into a single diversity indic which
you've probably all heard of or we may
use similarity indices if I'm interested
in comparing the amount of overlap of
species among different habitats or
treatments the other sort of toolbox
I'll pull from is this idea of community
structure because when you work with
diversity measures you sort of lose that
species level resolution you're reducing
everything to a number per se and you
don't know how different species are
responding in different ways and so here
I'm going to present results from
different ordination techniques where we
can look at how species and treatments
associate with one another by
identifying sort of dominant gradients
in the community and then looking at
groups of species and how they're
responding and So within that I'm
looking Prim using primarily redundancy
anal is which is a form of constrained
ordination where we're looking at actual
how the environmental factors in our
experimental design relate to these
subsets of the community and then
another one I'll introduce is this idea
of principal response curve which is
similar but it has an added layer of
complexity and that you also have a Time
component so the principal response
curve would be something like a
multivariant repeated measures so how
these species respond to treatment
factors at multiple points in
time so I'm a little Ambi ious I'm going
to try to get through all three of these
but uh I just feel it's interesting to
sort of take a broad look at three
different studies so the first one I'm
going to talk about are ground beetles
which are in the family carabid uh in a
maze cropping system and the landscape
context would be then these Ridge and
Valley physiographic profits in Central
PA uh the second one we look at a
broader beneficial group of taxa we have
the pollinators predators and
parasitoids and how they're responding
to practices in Mid-Atlantic tree fruit
specifically south central Pennsylvania
and then the third one is a much
different system I'm looking at how wild
bees respond to different conditions in
Community Gardens throughout New York
city so an urban landscape
context so let's begin with the ground
beetles so for each one I'm going to
sort of talk about those three factors
so as far as the landscape uh you have
this rigon Valley region here where you
sort of have these long parallel
forested slopes and in The Valleys there
are these AG dominated valleys and so
depending on where your farm may be you
could be in the center part of the
valley in an agricultural Matrix or it's
not uncommon to be on the edge of the
valley bordering directly adjacent to
forested areas so that comes into play
in part of our research as
well and the focal taxa for this group
will be members of the family carabid
which are a very diverse group of
beetles if you haven't heard of them
before there's about 40,000 species
worldwide maybe 2,000 in North America
and they're very popular with
entomologists because they seem to be
good bioindicators and so we can use
them to test the effects of different
management practices and what have you
they also provide us with many great
ecosystem services so many people go
throughout their whole lives never
looking at these small little beetles
near their feet yet they're providing us
with wonderful services such as pest
predation uh they're becoming more
widely known for their predation of weed
seeds and some estimates are that for
all the seed removal from a system 40%
can be attributed to just these these
beetles
alone and then the cropping system or
the Contex of the study uh is going to
deal with this introduction of trans
genes into agar ecosystems in this
region and so we've done several studies
here I'm going to focus on one that's
looking at uh transgenic maze that is
corn root worm protected which is a
beetle Pest and this BT maze expresses a
cry3 toxin that's supposed to be
directly targeting this Beetle Pest and
so our basic question coming into it was
introducing this new Pest Management
technique could it potentially affect
non-target beetle that are beneficial
and live in the same area uh a lot of
studies work on these non-target effects
and often they try to isolate the effect
of the trans Gene and its product we use
a slightly different approach what I
like to refer to as a systems approach a
real world approach uh for example this
Cry 3 BT maze comes coupled with other
seed management Technologies including
neonicotinoid SE treatments which could
potentially also negatively affect these
communities so we designed a set of
tiered studies assessing the effects of
BT maze our field work was preceded by
laboratory toxicology work uh where we
tested the effect of the cry proteins
for example and long story short they
seem to have no effect on the Beetles we
fed many different species of crabbed
beetles large amounts of BT corn pollen
for hundreds of days in a Petri dish in
a drawer and they survived just fine
different story with a seed treatment so
one presented with seed things with the
neonicotinoid SE treatment we had nearly
100% mortality of these beetles in the
lab setting however there did seem to be
a slight anti-feedant effect so we
wondered would we pick up these effects
in the field or not so then we moved to
sort of an ecotoxicological approach so
how are populations communities
responding in a field
setting and so here's an example of one
of the studies we worked on that we
called the ecotoxicology of transgenic
Maze and we would have these randomized
complete block designs in which we would
pitfall trap for beetles it's the most
commonly used trapping technique for
these epigeal or soil surface dwelling
arthopods it's basically a sunken Cup on
the ground anything that crawls calls
along Falls in and we collect
it uh the treatment factorial we used
was based on genetics and then on
conventional management practices so the
first part of the factorial would be
whether it was the BT corn or its
nearest genetic isoline keep in mind
though the BT is inherently coupled with
the neonicotinoid SE treatment so it's a
coupled technology we're not trying to
differentiate among them however any
effects we see in the field we were
tributing then to the neonicotinoid
based on the laboratory toxicological
work the second part of the factorial
then is whether there is a soil incde
applied at planting a pyoid that's a
conventional management for corn
rootworm and non-rotated field corn
versus n so we get these four different
designs for example isce line un manage
would be our control There's No Pest
manage practice at all there isoline
manage would be sort of a conventional
management with that soil
insecticide BT unmanaged would simulate
a grower who decide to adopt the BT
technology with a neonicotinoid to
control corn rootworm and then this one
I call the double Amy the BT with uh the
neony treatment and the pyoid soil
application just to round out the
factorial and so I like to put these
slides in I don't want you to be able to
read that but this is just to impress on
you when you decide to do community
level work the amount of tax taxonomic
investment and sampling effort that goes
in we collected over 7,000 beetles every
single one pinned and identified as
species uh with the help of Robert
Davidson from the carnegi Museum of
Natural History in Pittsburgh and you
can see here we found quite a diverse
range of Beatles too in a cropping
monoculture 50 different species of just
one family of Beatles right there's a
lot going on out there
and so since The Pest Management inputs
occurred at the beginning part of the
field season at planting uh we were
interested in how these communities
responded to treatments over time as
well so here's a case where we decided
to use this principal response curve
ordination technique and basically what
you're plotting are what we call the
temporal trajectories of community
composition and in order to do a
principal response curve it has to be in
relation to a control and so I have this
little in case you haven't seen a
principal response curve before I have
this little training slide as what it
looks like so the output the visual
output would be a control shown as a
horizontal line with time going left to
right and then the temporal trajectories
would be the communities in your
different treatments so the
interpretation for this would be that
treatment a as a community in that
treatment overall responds in a negative
Fashion on average to the control
treatment B the community is responding
in a in a positive fashion meaning
you're finding the individual species at
higher abundances
keep in mind that these lines are entire
communities those aren't populations and
so in order to look at species specific
data the principal response curve comes
coupled with what are called species
weights and so if you have species with
a positive species weight they tend to
follow the principal response if they
have a negative species weight they act
in the opposite fashion because
inherently when you study communities
there's a lot of fuzziness and you get
different ential reactions to the
different conditions right so you have
different species responding differently
the line represents the overall trend at
the community
level and so now what did we find from
our eoto study it was two years that's
why you sort of see the two groups from
left to right again the horizontal line
where you see those darkened circles
that's our control the iso unmanaged and
then the other three you can see pretty
closely follow one another and that you
see where those large dark arrows are
those are our Pest Management inputs you
see a decline in all three communities
for the three treatments over time
followed by a rebound later in the
season that may be due to immigrants
coming in or later emerging species or
what have you and so we're concluding
from this it seems to be that even with
the transgenic technology that neon
neonicotinoid C treatment also has a
deleterious effect on the community and
so you get this same response no matter
which treatment we were looking
at um keep in mind that not all of these
uh transgenic crops come coupled though
with these seed treatments so we did do
another study that I'll just say what we
did and it was a more of a diversified
Farm setting where we had sweet corn
potato squash and we compared transgenic
systems versus conventional no control
plot but just using grower standards we
managed the two and we documented
pesticide inputs and looked at Community
level response and in that case like
this Diversified Farm setting
what we found is
that the
isoline the non-transgenic clots
actually required more insecticide
inputs due to lack of control of the
focal pest taxa that the trans Gene
controlled for in the transgenic plot so
in that case these little blue squares
you see here these are species
accumulation curves and so as you
increase the number of individuals
you've collected you increase the number
of species in almost all instances we
had slightly higher species richness
actually in the transgenic systems due
to what we believe were fewer
insecticide inputs just due to effective
control because these did not contain
that that seed treatment that could be
affecting these epigeal
pootra so in general though we found
that we really just weren't finding any
differences between transgenic systems
versus conventional and so uh we wanted
to do an additional study to consider
well what about position in the
landscape does that affect the ground
beetle community so again we're in this
rig Valley region all of our work so far
had been done and sort of surrounded by
an agricultural Matrix yet there were
all these Farms that were directly
adjacent to the forested area so we
performed one more study uh where we
looked at the effect of these field
margins where you're growing maze next
to this continuous forested habitat and
we did more Pitfall trapping and so we
set up this transect design at multiple
locations throughout the valley where
you had traps extending from interior
forest from left to right going through
a grassy margin typical for Farm
vehicles and then the whole way into the
interior part of the maze field and so
this experimental design allowed us to
approach approach the data from two
different ways we could sort of group
the traps and just compare between
discrete habitats Forest versus grass
versus maze what type of beetles are we
finding or we could use the transect
design to look at how the community
shifts from one location on the transit
to the next and we were trying to
categorize how are these Beatles
responding to these ecotones in these
agricultural
Landscapes and so first at the discreet
habitat level we just looked at
biodiversity how it differs and these
turned out really nice I even thought
about submitting this to like an ecology
textbook or something because it really
shows why you should use rare faction to
compare species richness uh because
there was a sampling bias we had Pitfall
traps in the corn and the grass and the
forest but if you think of the
vegetation the forest very dense the
activity Den The Beetles is much lower
and so just on average we caught many
more beetles in the corn just because
it's a much more open environment which
can bias than the number of total
species we think are there so if you
would just look at the end points as far
as species richness they're all very
similar however rare faction allows you
to go back to a standardized number of
individuals collected let's say around
300 and we found significant differences
between the forest and the corn
Community as far as species richness so
the forest was much more diverse than
the the Corn based on species
accumulation
rates likewise with dominance
distribution or evenness you can see the
forest on the bottom here the most
abundant species just represented maybe
12% of the total number of beetles
collected whereas the corn and the grass
you get these highly skewed dominant
structures our Palace
pennsylvanicus a good species a weed
seed Predator however you can see nearly
60% of all the Beetles caught were one
species so you get these really skewed
down in the structure uh same with the
grass here so overall we're concluding
that the forest represents a much more
diverse and stable community embedded in
these agricultural
Landscapes so now what about using the
transect to look do a spatial type
analysis from one trap location to the
next so we decided we really like that
principal response curve but if you
remember that that's supposed to be used
for temporal trajectories we thought can
we sort of trick the program and just do
it in a spatial context so each of these
dots from left to right represents a
position on the transit and so we said
our interior Forest one is sort of the
Baseline community of cbids what would
be there if we didn't impose
agricultural fields on the landscape and
so we considered that our control and we
really took the species by sample Matrix
from that location and just replicated
it multiple times in our data set and
then we compared the cabic communities
found at each location of the transect
back to the interior Forest one so each
of these represents the relative
dissimilarity with the interior Forest
community and so we get we put it in a
principal response curve we get this
nice you see as you approach the Forest
Grass ecotone the crabbit community is
inevitably being influenced by the
neighboring habitat and it starts to
become more dissimilar to the interior
Forest Community then as soon as you
cross into a new habitat you get this
drastic Decline and again here as you
approach this next ecotone so we found
obviously a significant difference in
the cabbit Community between forest and
corn and so that was one of our
objectives going in do the cabbits
perceive this eone as a hard Edge or is
it highly permeable and so from this we
would conclude that it was a a hard Edge
right you get this very quick rapid
turnover in community
composition remember the species weights
the positives follow the principal
response so these we could identify then
as Forest Specialists because they
follow they become less abundant As you
move from left to right AC Ross the
transect these we would identify as corn
Specialists because they would actually
increase abundance as you come into this
area here into the
corn however that's not the whole story
because when we plotted population
distributions despite that quick
turnover we were able to identify
several species that seem to be ecotone
Specialists and just anecdotally we
noted from collecting in other maze
fields in the agricultural Matrix that
we seem to be getting some different
beetles at this Forest adjacent recent
location in particular terus digus
psychot trus
feris pus Luca blandis all of these were
at much higher abundances or weren't
even present at the AG Matrix location
and so when we plotted their
distribution they seem to be going
readily from forest to cornfield and so
our last question was can we document
that there's a significant difference in
the communities in maze adjacent to
Forest than those embedded in
agricultural Matrix
and so we sort of pulled data from all
kinds of different studies all over for
example the blue circles might represent
locations that are in the agricultural
Matrix yellow are locations we sampled
from forest adjacent and we basically
did pairwise similarity calculations
which are rooted in the number of shared
species versus the number of unique
species in each and so when we looked
for similarity between a matrix and
Forest adjacent locations we found that
similarity was 17 to 53% lower than
similarity between just different mag
Matrix locations so what we were
concluding is
that the kabic community in these Forest
adjacent locations were distinctly
different than those within the
agricultural
Matrix so for the first study what are
some key findings at the local level we
were again looking at the introduction
of these transgenic systems we found
that both conventional and seed-based
Pest Management tactics seem to
similarly influence cabbits on these
Northeastern small farms and we
attributed that to the the effect of
that seed treatment which may have
deleterious effects on these ground
dwelling beetles and we could detect
this in the field setting just as we
detected it in the lab setting as well
neonix obviously being more in the news
now with potential effects to bees as
well at the landscape level we found
that crabon communities and forested
areas are more diverse exhibit high
levels of complimentarity meaning
dissimilarity with neighboring Agland
and so this is evidence that you should
try to retain these Forest fragments in
agricultural Landscapes because the the
beta diversity will be much higher you
have a lot of species turnover however
there are some species that readily move
across that ecotone and they seem to
influence communities in adjacent Maze
and so the next question would be
interesting to see is if this affects
say ecosystem Services if based on your
position in the landscape and proximity
to
Forest all right second
study this one we look at a much wider
range of beneficial taxa because we're
including pollinators Predators
parasitoids uh in tree fruit growing
systems so I've been I've been lucky to
get involved in a lot of different
systems uh with a lot of great
collaborators and so I'm partial to this
one because it's where I'm from I'm
actually from Gettysburg Pennsylvania
which is in South Central PA in Adams
County which is a huge fruit growing
region and so you have these nice sort
of Rolling Hills or mountains and it's
very conducive to fruit tree production
because you put the Orchards on these
slopes and the cold air is able to sink
down in the valley to prevent a frost
damage on on the tree so it's very good
growing conditions for apples peaches
cherries what have
you and fruit trees are notorious for
having a very complex arthropod uh tax I
mean you have a wider range of
beneficials a wider range of pests and
so it's a very interesting system from a
management standpoint
and so uh we were looking at again
Predators like you see on the left here
everybody knows ladybird beetles they're
larv are also very effective
Predators we looked at lacewing larv
they look like little alligators they're
great Predators minute pirate bugs
anority spiders and even the larv of
surfit flies those little hover flies
that mimic bees very good
Predators we looked at the community of
of parasitoids uh members of the family
ikumon
Bron chalid wasps and then we also
looked at bees so anything from
bumblebees to Green metallic bees all
kinds of different bees which we found
many of in these
systems and so this is part of a
collaboration that's ongoing uh that I
work with people from Penn State from
the fruit research Extension Center
especially Dave bidinger um who does a
lot of work down there and a lot of what
we do again is in that ecotoxicology
realm where we're looking at how
orthopod community ities respond to P
management practices in tree fruit and
the work I'm going to present today came
out of this program within the USDA ramp
uh funding program the risk avoidance
and mitigation program and so
essentially we're comparing conventional
Pest management practices to these newer
reduced risk tactics that Growers are
starting to adopt as a result of the
food quality protection act so the food
quality protection act suggested phasing
out these Organo phosphates and
carbamates which can be toxic to hum and
and workers in the field and the reduced
risk are supposed to be to be safer uh
and so we're comparing does that
translate into elevated numbers of
beneficial arthropod taex as you switch
to these new
programs and so in this system uh
throughout Adams County we relied on
working with local Growers they allowed
us to establish research plots which
were sort of paired blocks of under
standard management or reduced risk
programs so reduced risk might include
clude uh the use of pheromones to
disrupt mating uh could be anti could be
microbials it could also be
neonicotinoids because they're
considered lower mamalian
toxicity uh a wide range of different
products whereas the standard plots were
mainly managed with the Organo
phosphates carbamates and
pyrethroids and so we wanted to look at
the response of the beneficial community
so for predators and
parasitoids uh we used a bug Vac
entomologists get to use these cool
things things like this it's a leaf
blower with an inverted fun function and
we just basically got all the insects
off the tree as we would we walk around
and then the bees we use pant traps
which you may be familiar with are
basically colored bowls blue and yellow
and white highly attractive to bees that
have a little soapy water breaks the
surface tension and it's able to catch
bees that way so two different sampling
methods and we're looking at uh the
beneficial Community
here so what about differences in Pest
Management again we use the systems
based sort of real world approach uh
Dave
bidinger uh acted as the Scout and the
guide as far as pesticide inputs and so
we kept track of what the different
Growers use for the different needs in
the different locations and really what
I want to point out here is the DraStic
reduction from 95 to 50% in Organo
phosphates and carbamates when you
compare the standard versus the reduced
risk uh here are some of the reduced
risk inputs and then another thing I
want to highlight just total pounds of
active ingredient per acre by adopting
reduced risk Technologies you reduce per
acre 5 and a half pounds of active
ingredient and so a real drastic change
we used the environmental impact
quotient uh for the different
insecticides provided by Cornell uh New
York IPM program where you can sort of
get this general idea of environmental
impact because it includes the idea of
persistence in the environment effects
of mammals fish
arthropods pollinators all kinds of
things and we had an 83% reduction in
this idea of environmental
impact so did this translate into more
beneficial arthopods in our tree fruit
systems uh we got a different story
depending on which group we looked at so
here's one of those redundancy analyses
where we could look at uh do the
communities respond to different
treatment variables and what I want to
draw your attention to are these darken
squ the ramp would be the reduced risk
and the the standard is obviously the
conventional management and you can see
all these vectors represent all the
different beneficial groups within
predators and parasitoids and the
general Trend here is very Stark right
you can see they're all trending towards
the reduced risk
plots found a significant effect of
treatment such that the vast majority of
the beneficial Community were found in
higher abundances in the reduced risk
Fields as opposed to Conventional Fields
some of these oddballs over here are
actually species which seem to be
uncorrelated so equal abundance is
regardless of system so this you have
branid wasps ID wasps green lacewing
Predators minute pirate bugs ladybird
beetles assassin bugs great names for
these spiders all much higher in the
reduced
risk so as far as the pollinators or the
wild bees we looked at we actually got a
different story so here you can see you
look at these axis you have standard
versus ramp they're both clustered right
near the center of the bip plot which
means they have a very low effect size
and we found no effect of Pest
Management program on wild bees however
these triangles you see all around the
perimeter here those are the different
locations those are just the grower
names and you can see we got widely
Divergent communities depending on
location in the landscape as shown by
the different Growers so for example so
again no effective treatment however for
example peponapis prosa you may
recognize as the squash B so we
collected that near this Harner Farm
there he must have been near some
agricultural Fields with a lot of cbits
it's the only reason I can think of to
catch that you have other things like
Catina osmia which require sort of a
structurally complex environment because
they're cavity nesters in wood and so
the diely may have been located next to
a forest edge or something like that so
this is something we're actually
pursuing right now is looking at
landscape predictors for wild be
diversity within um Orchard systems and
so this is sort of anecdotal evidence or
suggests that the landscape is what's
driving be diversity in our our
Orchards and just to drive home the
difference between treatment and sight
location again these are those rare
faction curves species accumulation
comparing B diversity between reduced
risk and standard they overlap
completely no difference in diversity
however when you look across site
locations you get widely different
things as far as the number of bees
collected to the number of species found
even at standardized level so
something's going on at the at the
landscape
level so some conclusions from the ramp
reduced risk study so Trends associated
with adoption of reduced risk tactics
were established in this agnolo paper
from which researchers at Cornell were
also involved this was a multi-state
study up the Eastern seab board looking
at how what it means to adopt to reduce
risk pesticides or Pest Management
Programs overall they lower the
insecticide loow load they an
environmental impact however they are
more expensive on average to implement
so our study was sort of a followup
what's going on with the beneficial
arthropod community and it does seem
that reduced risk tactics support
beneficial arthropods especially those
providing biological control not
necessarily the pollinators and so to
address this idea of being more
expensive one question we have is
possibly over time with the
establishment of these biological
control services you might be able to
offset some of those added costs of the
dck those Technologies we build up a
real strong biological control
community and we actually uh if you're
interested in this it looks cut off but
we just published a paper in Journal of
economic entomology that describes this
this ramp
study and then since the theme of my
talk is sort of this local versus
landscape just to summarize that
predators and parasitoids responded
strongly to local Pest management
practices we believe that because they
have limited mobility and they also have
strong associations with what they're
feeding on or what their hosts are for
the parasitoids that are found in the
orchard right so they have incentive to
stay local the bees are operating on a
different scale uh evidence of this was
a recent paper showing that you can
actually predict be diversity in
Orchards based on the percent of
forested area at a th meter radius bees
obviously have greater dispersal
capabilities and throughout their
lifetime they're relying on multiple
feeding resources their nesting
resources are often going to be outside
the orchard as well they might just be
coming into the orchard during uh Bloom
Peri right for
resources and then the last one I'll
transition to an urban setting and here
uh when I came to Liu I knew I wanted to
do something maybe in the community
garden setting and I was starting to get
interested in in bees and be diversity
so here we were looking at Community
Gardens and how they support wild be
communities in a heavily urbanized
setting the urban is sort of used
Loosely in the literature New York is a
very you know Metropolis
with heavily urbanized sitting so the
New York City
Gardens you see a lot of raised bed
although not all some have some row
cropping and communal sort of gardening
but in general you get situations like
this um there are over 700 Community
Gardens in New York city so and it's
growing the number so put together that
represents a large portion of the
landscape and if you look at the
surrounding landscape almost 70% of it
is impervious surface right so as far as
resources for for bees they could be
limited and people growing food in the
city just like anybody else can benefit
from insect derived ecosystem Services
whether it be biological control or
pollination in this case so I focused on
bees and a study by Kevin Madison and
Gail leleto found that of the commonly
grown crops there over 90% benefit from
be pollination Services maybe not
totally rely on but at least benefit
from so the group studied were wild bees
like a bumblebee here although there
five different families you might
collect uh we used again different
trapping methods to see what was out
there so here's a a bumblebee visiting a
bud
lasia and so the the study was
relatively straightforward so we had
these three basic research questions and
I worked with some undergraduate
students at Liu on this project uh the
first one was what bees are found in
Brooklyn New York Community Gardens
because thing that I try to include in
all these studies is species level
identification to establish Baseline
information you know sometimes we want
to answer these bigger questions and we
put the right the cart before the horse
right when we don't even know what's out
there and in fact to some of these very
common systems we're finding new species
still to this day and so the first thing
I try to always do is work with
taxonomist get everything identified
this Baseline information could be used
in the future to see how communities
change for example in response to
climate change and so these historical
data are very important the second
question was does be diversity differ
among Community Gardens throughout
Brooklyn New York so it seems like a
simple question but we thought it could
be possible that due to the severeness
of the landscape the severity of the
landscape that you just have a small
group of generalist species and you no
matter what you do in your garden you
get the same small group of these but
assuming we did find a difference our
third question was then can we build a
model a simple model just describing
what environmental factors best explain
variation of diversity among Gardens and
we included both local variables and
Landscape variables and sort of had them
uh both
included so we established research
sites uh throughout Brooklyn this is a
sing this makes me a little sad because
it's just a single slide but as Megan
can attest this is a huge project
because you have to procure Keys you
have to get there right you can't carry
all your nets and Equipment always on
the subway so you're driving and trying
to find parking and it can be a huge
headache
so we uh compared to Megan's work which
you may be familiar with this was a
smaller scale again because I I was
typically working with just one other
student so we had a sites that were
spatially distinct and we tried to
include sites that approached land use
in different ways so typically your
community garden may be the size of a
single home plot maybe it burned down 50
years ago and they put in a community
garden others like East New York Farms
here is about the size of a half a city
block so size land use plant divers we
try to include a wide range of different
variables B sampling right the best part
why you become an entomologist uh we did
for two years we sampled the bees
bi-weekly we used the pant traps again
which is a passive technique so they're
just attracted to those bowls and then
we also wanted to use net sampling where
we actively scouted for bees and we
tried to cover the whole extent of the
card and again everything identified as
species we received a lot help from John
Asher at the Museum of Natural History
although he's not there anymore but he
identified a lot of Beast for us and
verified them all the species
level and then while we're doing the
collecting while we're in the gardens we
concurrently also measured environmental
factors that can be used as predictors
in the model and uh we kept it
relatively simple so at the local level
we looked at the size of the garden we
looked at percent area and the different
land uses cropping areas non-rop areas
we also used plant diversity which was
just measured as total species
richness so I had people say from the
Brooklyn Botanical Garden come with me
would walk around and just identify as
many plants as we could at each location
and then light availability which was uh
we use this hemispheric photography
which was introduced to me Thea Megan uh
but this is a great way light
availability isn't something you maybe
consider that much in other settings but
in an urban setting especially New York
which is so such a vertical City it can
have huge effects on the community right
if you have a tall building right next
to your garden it could be cast in shade
for half the day so this hemispheric
photography allowed you to get a picture
from Horizon to Horizon and there is
certain software that you import the
pictures and it calculates the amount of
light intensity over the course of the
whole growing
season and at the landscape level uh
again we kept it relatively simple we
had our garden like you have here in the
middle and we looked at two different
radi 200 M 500 M and we just calculated
total amount of Green Space we broke it
up into two canopy this would be like
Street trees and then open green areas
which we we simply called grassy
areas so I'm going to go through the
results just based on the three research
questions so the first one was what bees
are found in Brooklyn Gardens uh so
through our two years of sampling we
collected over, 1600 bees found 50
different species including one that had
never been found in Brooklyn before uh
18% of the 50 species were exotic is
that a lot yes it's a lot that's
basically nine species there are I think
around 20 to 22 nonnative species of
bees catalogued in North America so we
found nearly half of them in our New
York City
Gardens um this trend was documented by
also by Kevin Madison who did a similar
be study in the Bronx but this is just
such an interesting example of how human
modified Landscapes affect community
structure because there are a lot of
bees out there if you're not familiar
there are almost 20,000 species of bees
globally more than species of fish and
most of them are not social like honey
bees which most people think of but
they're solitary and most of them nest
in the soil for example so if you go
outside the city the majority of species
you find would tend to be the solitary
soil nesters you get an inverse
community structure in the city in that
most are cavity nesters just because
there's not a lot of available soil as I
said about 70% of New York is impervious
surface and then here are the different
be is a wide range from bbus andati is
your eastern
bumblebee peponapis prosa is a squash B
so you have a a range of generalist some
EG Specialists and just a wide range of
diversity
here the second question does be
diversity vary among Gardens this is
something we were a little unsure of and
the resounding answer is that yes it
does greatly so uh if you look at the
top part of this table abundance this is
two years worth of data so we had a
garden that we collected for two years
bi-weekly UL we collected 18 bees
another one we collected nearly 300
right so drastic differences species
richness one one Garden only seven
different species of bees another 37 and
so if you look at the Garden
characteristics we felt pretty confident
that we could build some type of model
to explain this because the gardens also
varied widely from very small to very
large uh plant diversity range from
about 50 to over 150 species some of
these places I would call like hyper
diverse just the gardeners pled many
many different
ples light availability widely Divergent
and then even landscape context had some
variability as
well so for question three are there
environmental predictors of B diversity
we we used a multiple regression
approach with Ford selection just to get
the smallest number of variables that
best explain the different be diversity
measures and so we looked at abundance
species richness and then we used a
diversity index for the bees as our
response and so for be abundance
that's just total number of bees
regardless of species uh you could
accurately predict that using light
availability and plant species
richness I include the coefficients here
so you can sort of think about what that
relationship would be so for you know
for every additional plant species you
gain a b you have a coefficient of one
and then as the diversity measures get
more complex so do the models a bit you
see if you want to know about B richness
the total number of different species
again plant species richness and light
availability are important but you also
get this factor in with the uh landscape
context as well which makes sense if you
think about it if you have a food Rich
very a lot of light availability you
might get a lot of activity of bees but
you may not get a wide diversity whereas
bringing in the surrounding landscape
context if you have a lot of Green Space
you have many different nesting
resources alternative food resources and
you just might catch a larger number of
these and then the diversity index again
those same three and also Garden area
seem to be a predictor for diversity
which includes both richness and
evenness so maybe more ecological niche
space for the bees allows them to be a
bit more even in that
context so what were some of the
conclusions uh the diversity and
community structure of the community was
definitely influenced by the urban
setting in that we found lower species
richness than you might Elsewhere for
example our research in tree fruit again
you have a a pretty standardized
cropping system we found well over 100
species of bees there so this Urban
setting really lowers the species
richness and you get the fewer number of
soil nesting species and a high number
of
Exotics the gardens vary greatly in be
diversity and land use patterns so that
maybe there's the opportunity there for
Gardens to augment more bees by changing
some
practices and we found that be diversity
could be strongly predicted by local
factors such as floral diversity and
light availability and to some extent
landscape context plays a role as those
were included in the models for B
richness and diversity and one result I
didn't share but again we employed those
similarity indices there's a lot of data
out there on bees in the city parks like
Central Park and Prospect Park from John
Asher at the Museum Natural History so
we did some similarity indices to
compare what we were finding in
Community Gardens to city parks and we
found substantial amounts of
dissimilarity you think that's driven
because the plant diversity is different
you get these a species and there are
several bees that are Specialists of C
certain egg species such as the squash
bee peponapis pinosa the sunflower bee
melodis agilis and so with these new
resources without those Community
Gardens there those bees species would
probably not be present in New York City
at all so uh reason to support Community
Gardens and put more of them in the
city and then I wanted to use the
opportunity since I did go through three
different completely different systems
just some overall closing thoughts from
doing these Community level work so one
is despite the fact that I mentioned
that there's lower species richness in
these settings it was still surprising
the amount of diversity we did find when
we first started the work in the Maze
ecosystems on the transgenic maze
somebody commented that why would you
want to study diversity out there it's
it's a baren landscape you know we found
over 50 species of beetles so we should
view these managed Landscapes as a place
to conserve biodiversity and there's
increasing evidence that cities can even
host a large amount of
biodiversity and then we also Community
level Works important and that
investment into taxonomy is important to
establish Baseline data as we have a
rapidly and changing environments again
due to climate change or urbanization's
going to expand agricultural production
is going to expand with the growing
human population so there's so much out
there we just don't even know about
insect diversity it's important to get
these Baseline data the problem is we're
in the middle of a taxonomic bottleneck
where we have fewer and fewer taxonomist
that can actually identify these little
critters uh the second broader
Point uh these ecotoxicological studies
reveal that sometimes species respond
differently than other species in the
community to these treatment factors and
so we believe especially I've had this
conversation with Dave bidinger that
there needs to be a role for these
realistic systems-based Community level
studies field studies in risk assessment
uh for example in registering pesticides
or things like that the EPA might use
honeybee as a surrogate for all
pollinators
and we see that we get widely different
responses to different things among
different species and so we know that
you have to have a realistic approach
because you can't test everything
however we believe these Community level
studies if you can invest the time and
resources could serve to augment those
normal practices and there's also
increasing evidence coming out with bees
of synergisms between pesticides and
fungicides even adant like oils or
adhesives that can affect toxicity and
you really don't pick that up unless
right because you can't do every single
combination in the lab you pick that up
though in the field what's really going
on these different
tpan and then the last one is that the
relative influence of the surrounding
landscape in any given system uh varies
based on the ecological needs and
dispersal of whatever taxonomic group
you're working with or or Guild you're
working with U for example the bees were
responding at a much larger scale than
the Predators and parasitoids and our
tree fruit systems so uh in the tree
fruit again we're working with funding
from the specialty crop research
initiative us SDA on looking at those
landscape factors also getting from nrcs
some seed mixes of pollinator Habitat to
establish next to Orchards and see if
you can get things food resources for
before and after Apple Bloom per se to
support pollinators in these
Landscapes and
acknowledgements so again I'm I'm
visiting from Long Island University my
appointment is primarily teaching there
so everything I presented here really
wouldn't be possible without working
with really wonderful collaborators
allows me to stay active in the research
realm and so at Long Island University
I've worked with uh several great
students who I've sort of converted into
ecologists uh Penn State University
Shelby fler was my uh Mentor David
Biddinger I work a lot with on this tree
fruit C collaborations and just his
practical knowledge of those systems is
is is really amazing uh Chris Mullen
toxicologist at Penn State and neandra
josi was a postdoc
uh the reason I'm here is from working
with Megan Gregory who I met in the
gardens in Brooklyn who's also doing
research there I obviously want to thank
all the Growers and Community gardeners
and then the taxonomists all this can't
be done without them I really relied
heavily on John Asher and then Bob
Davidson and then this work was funded
by several different resources so I hope
you found that interesting entomologist
in the horiculture department here but
uh I can try to answer any questions if
you have any also if there are any
students that are soon to graduate and
considering different job opportunities
sometimes when I've given past seminars
they like to talk about that working at
a place like Liu or something like that
so thank
you this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu