this is a production of Cornell
University uh thank you so much for
inviting me up to New York love love New
York love Etha um before we get started
I know we've got some at least one
retailer right um how many Growers are
in the audience okay
landscapers couple Educators Master
Gardeners wow okay really good
okay well I'm very pleased to talk to
you about pollinators because it's an
extremely important topic um and we can
all we can definitely all help listening
to Carol was very helpful um to see you
know where is our gardening public going
and who do we need to reach out to just
coming um about three weeks ago from the
international pollinator conference at
Penn State I can tell you that the
pollinator crisis is very real
and it's something that we have to
address worldwide I think the good news
is that all of us here working in the
screen industry can be part of the
solution and again listening to Carol I
was thinking about the connection with
kids I mean what's a more wonderful
connection than plants butterflies bees
you know things that move because kids
love this kind of thing and food
gardening um it it's a perfect match so
what I want to do I'm going to kind of
take you through a quick introduction
for those of you who might not be
terribly familiar with pollinators uh
we're going to talk about who they are
going to talk about the stressors on
them and then the important part um what
can we do to help them with our floral
resources okay so most of you guys know
this why are pollinators important well
we like to eat we like to eat watermelon
we like to eat squash we like to eat
blueberries and apples and these are all
things that are insect pollinated so
without these our diets become very
Bland um we also have an economic value
going on here uh without pollinators we
have definitely have some economic
problems and then there's the ecosystem
without pollination of plants we have no
seeds we Have No Berries which means we
have no food web and everything really
does collapse um which is why we call
pollinators keystone species we cannot
pull these guys out and still have all
of us survive okay so I think when
you're gardening for pollinators and
you're thinking about plants for them
it's important to know who our
pollinators are um because it's not just
honey bees it's a very very wide range
of diversity and each of these guys use
something just a little bit
different so flies I know flies aren't a
big S cell to the public but some of
them are actually quite beautiful the
surfed fly over over here on the left
some sometimes also called hoverfly very
frequent flower visitors and they do
their share of pollination and as a
bonus their larvae are wonderful aphid
eaters so we've got beneficial insects
going on here too this Tac nid fly not
quite as pretty over on the left um or
excuse me on your right um this tacn fly
is actually very important because it's
the parasitoid of the brown marmorated
stink bug lays its eggs on on them so
these pollinators that are visiting
these plants have more benefit than just
moving pollen and nectar or moving
pollen beetles very frequent flower
visitors I can't tell you how many
people bring these into the office after
they've killed them because they've said
they're on my flowers and must be doing
something bad um but this soldier beetle
is actually another beneficial and you
know it actually does eat some aphids um
and as a flower visitor it's moving some
pollen butterflies and moths easy cell
maybe poster child for pollinators not
as efficient because their legs hold
them above the flower so they're not
moving around as much pollen but they're
absolutely beautiful they have they
definitely have another role in the
environment and that's their
caterpillars feeding Birds which is is
supporting the whole food web um but
when we're talking to people about
pollinators sometimes this is the way to
get them into pollinator gardening
because who doesn't love
butterflies and of course Birds another
very beloved pollinator I I would think
that Cardinal flower and this B bomb
menarda would be very very very easy to
sell uh we find that in our in our
Master Gardener plant sales um because
people want to support these beautiful
birds and then we get into the hopter
the wasps and the bees and yes if you
have pollinator friendly plants you are
going to have a lot of wasps most of
them are solitary um they're not the
Yellow Jacket type social wasp they're
solitary the the female is doing all of
her work she's far too busy to even even
think about stinging a lot of these are
ground nesters this is actually uh one
we've been doing some work on at our
pator plot this is by certies um she is
a ground Nester and during her lifetime
which is very short she can kill 40 or
kill and take back to the nest 40 Brown
marmorated stink bugs so you know very
the they're flower visitors but they're
also um performing other functions for
us and then there's the bees these are
our main pollinators there's no doubt
about that all the bees are um very
effective at pollination because they
are collecting pollen these other
visitors are strictly getting nectar and
kind of accidentally moving things with
them these guys have to collect pollen
to take back to the nest to feed their
larvae to feed the young um and they're
very well adapted for it with their
bodies and pollen collectors everybody's
familiar with honeybees but not
everybody knows that honeybees are
actually a farm to be they're not
considered wild they were brought over
from Europe with the Jamestown settlers
and it's been an economic Farm product
ever since what folks aren't too
familiar with is the native feas and we
have a lot of them before these honey
bees were brought over pollination was
happening here we had a great ecosystem
going and there are over 20,000 species
worldwide right here in the Mid-Atlantic
region we figured in Pennsylvania we
have about
450 we're discovering new species every
day because until we had the problem
with pollinators nobody was doing a
whole lot of studying and so now with
everything being geared up we are
learning a
lot and these species are very very
varied um there's all kinds of bees out
there bumblebees most people are
familiar with they are a social bee the
queen actually has workers in a small
colony in the ground maybe 250 of them
um and then these other bees are
solitary again the queen is doing all of
her own work she might only be laying 10
12 eggs she might be laying them in the
ground um in hollow hollow stems she
might be using dead wood so all of these
nesting sites become extremely important
and these bees vary from the pretty
large carpenter bee down to the tiny
little sweat bee that is really
difficult to identify when they're on
the flowers but there are a lot of them
out
there we have bees that are Specialists
and this is important when we're
thinking about what we're planting um
the squash be on the on your left over
here actually nests underneath squash
plants and you don't need honey bees if
you're growing squash because you if you
plant it they will come if your farming
practices are not disturbing their nest
they will be there for you the males
fall asleep in the flowers very very
sweet um and they take care of your your
crop for you it's a native Fe um the
mining bee on the right I put in here
because there is a particular mining bee
that is a specialist on Golden Rod that
the way it collects pollen and its
collectors only fit one size of pollen
grain and that's from Golden Rod or
asure and so with without Golden Rod or
Aster those bees are gone so these
specialist bees are not as common but
they have a very important Niche and we
need to keep the diversity so they're
very
important um other bees have a really
wide floral range can bumblebees are
this way this wonderful little leaf
cutter bee can go from one species to
another um and and actually visit many
many different Ames of flowers and we
need we need both of these
groups the bad news is pollinators are
declining um and it's a rather steep
decline it's happening quickly we have
about 34 animals identified as
pollinators that are endangered or
threatened and then look at the number
of flowering species that are also
endangered or threatened and the the
relationship ship between the flowers
and their pollinators is very tight so
sometimes if you lose a flower floral
resource you're going to lose a
pollinator and and vice versa um so this
is a concerning
issue this last winter um honey bees
declined again these are our farmed bees
they lost
45% um 15% loss is what they normally
would expect and this has been going on
now for quite a few years ever since
we've heard about the colony collapse
disorder our wild bees are also in
trouble we might never have known this
if colony collapse hadn't happened with
the honey bees we may never have
actually started to study these other
bees but we've got at least five species
of our North American bumblebees um that
are are shrinking and range and part of
this is due to climate change there's a
lot lot of other reasons as well 13 out
of 46 species of our Bumblebees are now
threatened or near-threatened this is
not good news because the Bumblebee
globally is our second most important
pollinator of crops second only to that
that farmed honeybee that's being taken
around and then
butterflies wow um 141 different species
at risk of course the latest one that
everybody knows about is is the monarch
right so what in the world is going on
with our pollinators what is stressing
them out so much well there's no one
Smoking Gun to this it's hard to do
research on these wonderful um you know
wonderful creatures because there's so
many factors coming in we know that
habitat nutrition is one pesticide
exposure we've got diseases viruses of f
fungus out there um pth genetics we know
that climate change is is playing a role
and when these all come together
somewhat of a recipe for
disaster I'm going to talk about these
two of the pesticides and the nutrition
because these are things we can do
something about the rest of this we have
to kind of leave to the
researchers and habitat loss is huge
both of nesting habitat you know they
can't nest in mulch they can't Nest um
in thick Turf so our gardening practices
are kind of against them and we've
fragmented our landscape so much that
some of these insects can't fly across
some of the um the more urban areas that
we've
created and uh noted ecologist down in
Arizona has determined over 95% of the
land in the lower 48 states is either in
agriculture or development that doesn't
leave a whole lot lot for our pollinator
friends and our farming practices in the
midwest have changed drastically and we
know this is this is a definite problem
for pollinators um these vast fields of
monocultures no hedge r no pollinator
ships you know uh there's just nothing
there for the
pollinators here in the Northeast we're
a little better off um because our Farms
are smaller we still do have HED tros
we've got you know Forest land in
between and so we're definitely we're
definitely better here than in the
midwest our Suburban areas are the other
part of this um as natural fields and
forests are plowed down or taken down
for development for homes and businesses
what we put back in our yards does not
begin to um to satisfy the needs of the
pollinators our our turf our our plants
which we're importing mostly from other
countries um just not a lot there and
even our campuses as beautiful as as our
own Penn State campus is when I walk
around I see a lot of places where you
know we could we could do better and we
could be putting in more floral
resources we could be filling this up
with flowers wouldn't that be wonderful
we filled everything with
flowers a lot of the natural lands that
are left um have been overrun with inv
IES and I know you have a a talk on that
a little bit later this is a n a state
state forest in Pennsylvania which is
being overrun by Japanese silk grass and
Japanese Barberry that has escaped from
our yards um and once you get that kind
of monoculture in the forest crowding
out a lot of the the wild flowers our
pollinators have
trouble pesticides are a tough issue and
um I'm not an expert on pesticides so
I'll kind of relay to you what our
Center for pollinator research has found
so far um we know that pesticides are
part of this whole problem we also know
that whatever we put down pollinators
pick up and in a study um back around
2007 we of pollen samples we found out
that there were 121 different pesticides
identified
in wax and pollen samples from honeybees
so if we if we put it
out they're picking it up okay so what
are those um there's a lot there were
very few samples that didn't have
anything in
them and of the 121 different ones here
is a list of some of the categories you
you see some very familiar pesticides
there very
s% that's a good question um I'm not
100% sure what percentage but um we can
find that
out oh yes I'm sorry she asked what
percentage of the samples did not have
any detections it says very few but I
don't have that actual percentage okay
we have systemics out there that are are
getting into pollen into nectar and
they're getting them the pollinators are
getting them that way and per pollen
sample each one had an average of six
different pesticides um so it's it's
really it was very eye openening for our
researchers um to see
this what is your
s oh of the of the
entire I don't know how many samples
they looked at again the center for
pollinator research we can get that from
them how many samples they sampled
yeah oh per well whether whether they
were yeah whether they were looking at
pollen and wax they were looking at them
both together
yeah the pesticides
toed and
wax would be applied have been applied
to the plant prior to
presence of the PO there in other words
perhaps PRI even
theen for the
systemics yeah and yeah um really good
go ahead
words
right would would be present
right it's a very a very good question
and I apologize I don't have all of
those answers um but Maryann Frasier who
was our researcher at Penn State that
did this um she has since retired but
these this is all available at Penn
State and if you guys want that I can
try to get I can try to get more of the
total study for you so you'd have an
idea of what all the parameters were
okay okay that sounds good
okay the other thing I just wanted to
bring to your attention is um there are
different there are different modes of
action of these pesticides um with the
pollinators lethal means well carburo is
a good example seven you spray it they
die so that's lethal they immediately
die but there are sublethal effects as
well so of the four that are listed here
reduced immune function reduced lifespan
impaired foraging Behavior rep reduced
reproduction which one do you think
would be a sublethal
effect all of them you're right um and
this is a difficult thing to study but
there are many many studies out there on
this
and so often times when they're exposed
to these pesticides you don't get an
outright kill but they are impaired in
such a way that the colony eventually
you know is affected or the individuals
may die okay so all of the
above um just a quick word about neonix
and again I'm I my ex my expertise is in
the plants not so much in the pesticides
um but they have found sublethal effects
from the
neony and impaired foraging behavior um
you know the decreased
reproduction and so the the
recommendation that is coming out is
don't use neonx
prophylactically and if you're growing a
lot of the plants that we're going to be
talking about in a few minutes there's
no need to be using anything in them
because these plants are tough and um so
wherever you can especially with Ator
plants try to stay away from from any
kind of
systemic they also discovered that
fungicides play a role here which really
complicates things especially for the
orchard folks um and the fungicides can
actually synergize with some of the
insecticides particularly the three
listed here and become stronger we also
don't know what the inert ingredients of
the pesticides do and there are some
researchers looking at that what is in
those inner ingredients we need to find
that out and how can they affect
pollinators so with the pesticides it's
complicated it's very complicated um
herbicides play a role too in that by
spraying our roadsides or median strips
you know we killing off a lot of our
floral resources reducing habitat in our
Lawns um violets are a good early season
source of nectar for bees host plant for
the frary
butterfly Clover which used to be a
Mainstay in our Lawns back you know my
grandfather always seeded Clover into
his lawn um but today in this generation
Clover is a weed we've kind of made it
that way but Clover is a wonderful
source for for bees um you know so the
herbicides can can do some damage to us
too so just in general these are some of
the recommendations that the center came
out with for protecting pollinators um
from pesticides you know know know what
you're using know how toxic it is
sometimes sometimes that's not so easy
because what's toxic to a honeybee might
not be toxic to a bumblebee vice versa
um it's it's complicated um but never
use pesticides on blooming
crops and then pre- Bloom don't use the
systemics because some of these can link
ER in the plant for a long
time so that's bad news but there's good
news and at this International
Conference this last uh this last month
the one theme that came through of so
many of the papers was that even in the
presence of diseases and in the presence
of
pesticides if these pollinators were
wellfed if they had good good
nutrition they could fight off some of
this some of these effects and it's no
different from us you know if we're run
down we don't have a good diet we don't
have a diverse diet yeah we're we we can
easily get pick pick up a cold pick up a
flu uh pick up anything and they're no
different and so we can really make a
difference even in the face of the other
things they're facing by giving them a
diverse diet by giving them what they
really need um the best possible nectar
the best possible pollen we can dilute
some of these these compounds um and
dilute the effects of some of the
diseases so to me I kind of came away
from the from that conference feeling
like yes what we do and how the green
industry responds to this really can
make a huge
difference the other good news is the
gardeners that I talk to are
aware they you know they're kind of tied
into this and those new gardeners that
Carol was talking about they want their
kids they want their kids to be tied in
they know that we have some
environmental problems going on here and
they're anxious for the kids to learn
and what a wonderful learning
opportunity that could be paired with
you know with our our garden centers um
because these guys are hungry and
providing food is also a very feel-good
thing for all of
us it can also be
lucrative um Michigan State just did a
study of on this was
actually on the labeling of plants
treated with
pesticides and the study found that
plants that were labeled be friendly as
being grown in a bee friendly way were
much preferred by the consumers so
people are responding to this they want
to
help they also found out that people are
willing to pay a little more for a plant
that was grown in a beef friendly way
fact up to a dollar more so there's an
opportunity there as well
and I'm I'm assuming because of how
consumers are reacting that they would
react the same way to not just plants
that were grown in a pollinator friendly
way but growing plants that are truly
really nutritious and good for
pollinators um I think the labeling of
these plants would would definitely be
helpful and there's all kinds of things
you could do in a garden center to you
know to make that
attractive um but the big question is
what are the best pollinator plants and
we are still trying to answer that
question um we're getting
closer we know that some of our modern
hybrids that are being developed
especially in the annual world and they
being developed for color or size or um
you know just appeal may or may not have
poer nectar um sometimes the nectaries
are bred out of the plant so the pollen
is bred out of it sometimes the plant
can become so complicated in structure
that the pollinator has no idea how to
get to the pollen that's there um if you
look at our Aro native plants they are
they have been they've been co-evolved
to actually attract pollinators mean
some have I I show you some here some
have guidelines I mean some are just
saying hey guys you pollinators may not
be too smart here this is where you come
and a plant like this it's a little
confusing um
so down at our Penn State research
station um near where I live in
Landisville where we have our flower
trials the center for pollinator
research has set up a row for pollinator
insect study and they've taken some of
the most common SE good sellers at
Garden Centers and the uh researchers
from the center are coming down and
evaluating them for po pollinator
visitation which I'm really glad they're
doing this because we need to know and
it's it's not nothing wrong with having
a plant in your garden that doesn't
attract pollinators but we also need to
be including plants that do attract
pollinators we need to know what they
are um we do know from our studies that
most native perennials are good
pollinator plants yeah Car checking
question are you doing uh like existing
varieties that are at garden centers in
this test that's kind of what they chose
um you know when availability was part
of was part of the issue too when when
they did that but um and as they go
forward they're going to Target you know
specific plants a little bit more and
and try to see what what are the best
sellers out there what are people buying
and how can we label these things um
most native perennial plants we know are
good for pollinators because they
co-evolve together without their
pollinators these plants wouldn't have
made it through but when we change them
and we we create cautivar from them what
happens on the left is a straight
species of of eonia or cone flower um
and boy you know pollinator Heaven on
the right is another one in our trials
and I haven't spent much time over there
looking but the few times that I've been
over I haven't seen any pollinators on
that guy and it's because we've we've
changed
it is is anything still there these are
things we need to find
out Mount Cuba is doing some great
studies down at the University of um
with with the University of
Delaware and uh Dr Delaney and one of
her grad students Zen Cass have been
looking at monardas in
copsis and trying to determine which
ones of these are attracting pollinators
they're even looking at the nectar
they're analyzing the nectar you know
what does it have does it have the
proteins and the lipids does it have
what pollinators really need and they're
looking at a lot of cultivars so if you
ever get down there um it's a really
neat place to visit and they do have
some reports out they were also just
looking at the plants themselves no
which ones are the most attractive which
ones hold up the best so this pollinator
study is now a little addition to all of
this and these reports are online U this
is their coreopsis report um Owen should
be putting his Monarda um report out
pretty soon okay and then lastly um we
did a a trial study at our research
station 2012 to
2014 where we looked at 84 different
species of native plants and they're
cultivars and these were replicated in
5x5 plots three times um and we had
Master Gardeners helping us with this as
well as as well as our
researchers so before I go into the
results of that study which is what your
handout is all about um for those of you
that are
landscapers just wanted to mention a few
things um about how we can make some
changes in our Landscaping to help out
the
pollinators here are three
properties very different in size the
one on the top is about 35 Acres um got
Meadow um it's all been landscaped in
native plants done professionally done
and even the pool area I mean this is a
wonderful floral resource for
pollinators but down on the bottom left
is a small garden in the city of York
postage stamp size but look what she's
done um she has put a lot of wonderful
Floral resources in there um still has a
little bit of lawn but she has Beauty
year round well three seasons um and
then on the right this is a nursing home
also in New York County where they have
taken grass and they've turned it into a
therapeutic place for their um their
residents a place of beauty a place
alive with pollinators that the
residents are lining up to get into this
nursing home because they want to be
able to look out on this this wonderful
Courtyard so Size Doesn't Matter every
space that we have can be
utilized but what all three of these
places had in have in common is they
have put Plants closer together we have
plants touching each other uh reduced
use of mulch and landscape fabric
because the nesting they can't nest with
landscape fabric
um and so by by packing in our plants
letting them touch letting them be a
little bit more natural um weed-free
there's no space there for weeds to grow
um so that's a really big help as well
there's still maintenance obviously but
it's a different different kind of
Maintenance so think about
that in really large areas landscape
plugs can be very helpful yeah in the
previous Slide
whated the landscap fabric
and a
negative um couple things one is if if
you're PL spacing plants you know 2
three feet apart have a need for mulch
you don't have many floral resources you
have weeds you're going to have weeds
growing down through that that mulch
nesting sites become limited because
bees can't the ground nesters can't
can't go down through the mulch or the
landscape fabric yeah so and it's also a
costs saver um I talked to a group that
said they had spent
$15,000 for their homeowners association
on March last year and I'm thinking but
they were wondering how they could get
more flowers and I said well you know
take that $15,000 and maybe maybe move
it over so so yeah uh those two things
are kind of a negative when we're
talking about about pollinators this is
actually the front of my house
um so landscape plugs are a really
costeffective way to do this if you're
Landscaping they can be a dollar a piece
there are native plant wholesalers that
are growing these guys they're
struggling to keep up because there's a
demand so anybody looking for a niche
market um maybe might be a place to go
these plugs can also be purchased and
potted up into quartz and sold at Garden
Centers so there is a source for these
plants um there're also seed sources out
there a lot of people are collecting
local
eloyes and also when you're placing
these diversity is really key I told you
that plants um pollinators and their
plants are closely related look at this
penamon I mean this penin isn't letting
anything to chance
here's a landing pad for the
Bumblebee guidelines hey guys that's the
way to go right um and each of these
plants is going to attract a different
kind of pollinator because they all have
different Siz tongues and um different
needs so diversity is
great planting we're trying to get
people to planting groups and drifts
because one single plant isn't going to
help a pollinator too much and you know
they'll see them Mass much better and
have plants to move
between succession of Bloom plants from
Spring through fall there are different
kinds of bees emerging in March and the
whole way through the season until the
first really hard Frost they all need
food so picking a succession of Bloom it
also means hey we're getting more plants
out there we're selling more plants um
we're we're enjoying more plants we're
seeing more color in the
landscape so here are the results of the
84 species that we did you have the full
results on your on your papers I'm only
going to touch on a few of these plants
for the sake of
time in general we discovered that
plants with large compound
inflorescences of tiny flowers attracted
more different kinds of pollinators than
other flowers this is where we got our
diversity so think swamp milked over
here on the left um bone set in the
middle which is one of the
eupatorium The Joe pies there are many
many flowers out there that have these
kind of flower heads they're not the
only thing you should plant but you know
if you're trying to to get a plant to a
new Gardener see biggest bang for their
Buck these are the way to
go and then I'm going to start with our
number one winner right off the top pnan
muticum the clustered mountain men is
anybody growing this you are okay lots
of
pollinators yeah yeah apple mint Apple
mint the mint family in general um the
mint family the asra family um are both
huge families for pollinators and this
is a native mint but yes other mints you
know will will do well too if you let
them flower and this clustered Mountain
Min was was a plant that we felt could
be a gorgeous plant for the garden um as
well as valuable for pollinators smells
wonderful we had 21 different kinds of
pollinators visited from butterflies to
flies to beetles to to bees to wasps um
it seemed as though if you you could
tell where it was in the child plot
because there was this
over the top of it and I actually had
one educator come visit our plot and we
we talked about the plot before we went
in he told me later if you hadn't told
me that that was a good thing I would
have made a big birth around that plant
he said because there was so much stuff
on it but but he said now I know it's
it's a good thing it's a good thing so
we need some education
too um it only grows about 3 to four
feet tall does like some soil moisture
it's not not a plant for real dry soils
it had an advantage over the other
plants because it bloomed for 10 weeks
and so you know we were counting
pollinators for a lot longer one of the
best juices I've seen for this plant was
at Irvine Nature Center this is a
parking lot divider the only downside to
having that was when people were getting
in their cars with their
purchases they no they would get they
would get their cameras out and they'd
be taking pictures of buck guys and all
kinds of you take them 20 minutes to get
out of the parking lot and I have to say
in the three years well five years now
that Master Gardeners about 20 of them
have been working in this trial plot
there's been not a single sting these
guys are too busy only the females can
sting of the wasp and the bees because
it's the osor that's the Stinger the
males can't sting guess who has time on
their hands
the males the females are doing all the
work they've they they've got to get the
nectar they have a short period of time
they've got to get the Palm they've got
to feed the kids they could care less
about you the males are kind of hanging
around and being a little aggressive um
but they can't hurt you okay golden rods
I would like to I okay on time five
minutes okay I would love to see anybody
here growing golden
rods yes
not
wild golden rods are an extremely
important plant it really tied for
number one with that mountain mint this
is this is stiff Golden Rod butterflies
loved it we're doing a project with the
xeri society right now to find out what
nectar plants the Monarch is using on
its trk from Canada to Mexico and
they're strongly suspecting that Golden
Rod has historically always been in one
of the fuels to help them get down to
their wintering grounds um so they're
extremely important and we had so many
butterflies on this plant it really
stands up very tall and will withstand
some some medium to dry soils it's
blooming as we speak um and just
attracts so many different pollinators
would be great for back of the
Border it does seat around after 5 years
where were learning which plants stayed
in place and which ones didn't um and in
some places seaing around would be great
in the case of of a homeowner they might
not like it so much so hey got another
Golden Rod for you fireworks this one
just kind of grows out from a Center
patch and forms a larger patch easy to
take care of you divide it and you can
keep it in check it all the golden rods
were very good for pollinators
and I would love to dispel the fact that
people think that Golden Rod is is an
allergen I hear that all the time it's
insect pollinated pollen's heavy it does
not get carried by wind insects move it
it is not an allergen Ragweed is the is
the the corpit and when I went to
England last fall I saw more Golden Rod
and garden over there than I ever see
here they have a love affair with it
they shouldn't because it's become
invasive for them um because they don't
have you know they don't have the
ecosystem built around it but this is
Shakespeare's birthplace I mean just
amazing use of Golden Rod they love it
they're selling it back to us by the
way and here's their award another
wonderful wonderful pollinator plant
attracted a lot of those those uh
parasitoids or the brown marmorated
stink bug very easy to grow plant likes
likes dry soil and full sun none of
these native plants ever need fertilizer
ever in fact fertilizer is
counterproductive to them they are
adapted for nutrient po
soils the jie I can't say enough about
these and they all of them were
wonderful plants even all the cultivars
all the straight species did very very
well I singled out dubium because it was
our number one plant for attracting
butterflies we over three years we had
17 different butterflies and Skippers on
it it was the last one to bloom it's
actually it is actually a plant of the
coastal plane it's the shortest shortest
of all the Joe pies which is always
popular with homeowners um like all the
ji's average to moist soil and it is
just beginning to bloom now okay swamp
milked if you have a garden center
milkweeds are so popular at our plant
sale
um at our office we we can hardly get
them The Growers are having trouble
keeping them in stock because everybody
knows about the Monarch and everybody
wants to help even common milked is
flying off the shelves um the swamp
milked is a great plant for all kinds of
pollinators including a good nectar
plant for the Monarch and they love to
lay their eggs on this plant um so but
it does need moist soil um there are
other milked s that can be grown that
need other other conditions it's a
milked for
everybody rattlesnake Master pretty cool
Plant um this is an is anybody growing
this one I know this one this was a bit
of a surprise to us I was a little
surprised to see how good it was as a
pollinator plant but all those tiny
little flowers um were attracting a lot
of different uh diversity and it's a
very cool Plant the kids love
it and I was interested to see that at
the new formal Garden by The Mansion at
Mount cubba Center they have
Incorporated rattlesnake Master into
their Garden as a structural element so
it's really very
cool and then a few comparisons do we
have time for this or do sure okay um
there a lot of comparisons and you have
the cultivar sheet there for for all of
them here are just a few examples
we looked at the straight species of
menarda filosa against CLA
Grace and what we discovered is that the
straight
species was very much preferred don't
know what it is about CLA Grace that the
butterflies or the the bees didn't um
didn't prefer it but and maybe it was
just just the fact that we had so much
food available okay but this this you'll
see on your sheets is a terrific plant
for pollinators six different kinds of
bumblebees on here hummingbird moths and
you plant it with other plants so that
if it does get pwy mildew you don't
notice it you put it with its
friends here's another cultivar
comparison between the aromatic asers
three different kinds and in this case
you'll see that the ca of our October
Skies was preferred we were we were
surprised to see that
um but it it actually did better and
it's a shorter
variety um than the straight species and
did not seem to seed around very much um
which was kind of a plus to and then we
looked at copsis um three different
types of copsis including the straight
species and after three years
Zagreb had done better possibly because
it was it was had had more flowers on it
than the straight species um but what
was interesting we're 5 years into this
we're not counting cators on these
plants any longer but the plants are
still in the in the trial and after five
years Zagreb is starting to fade under
the weed pressure at the farm because we
can you know I only have 20 Master
Gardeners and trying to get all these
weeds out of there is interesting so
we've kind of left Moon Bean go it it
just isn't it's still there but it
doesn't have the Vigor Zagreb is fading
a little bit but the straight species we
don't have to do much to so it's it's
just interesting watching what happens
over time with these plants and I wanted
to give a shout out to this particular
plant um Monarda Peters fancy fuchsia
we're not 100% sure of the parentage of
this plant if somebody knows I I'd like
to know what it is um but in our trials
it was a favorite of bumblebees and they
would hang on to it to the very last you
know last flower till it just about was
ready to fall off and in our trials has
really held up under all this weed
pressure so I just feel it's a really
good Garden plant the other thing that
came out of this trial is a phology
chart we kept track of the bloom for a
couple of years um this is not in your
handout or on the website but if you
wanted I can send it to you it's you
know it prints large because it's 84
different species but it's a really
handy thing to have if you want to to
think about planting that succession of
Bloom and there were really I mean all
the pl all the plants in our plot did
pretty well if you want to see the full
report you can go to the Center for
pollinator research website just Google
it go to the pollinator Garden
certification this is a Master Gardener
program and under step one provide food
for pollinators there will be a link to
bees bugs and blooms and I have a card
up here with the website on it if if
you're
interested okay so hopefully together I
mean what it's this is a feel-good thing
because getting plants out there and and
getting plants in the hands of people
and kids is great wow helping
pollinators at the same time is even
better so you know collectively I think
we can make a real difference thank
[Applause]
you this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu