this is a production of Cornell
University thank you for the detail
introduction amazing and first of all I
need to say that thank you for attending
that's it's great to have you as
audiences and I'm excited to present my
board my book is about life and I'm
seeing I'm looking at G interaction
right organ
Association and focusing on kinetics and
mechanisms this is what we know about
herbici application in United States
glyos is most heavily
applied between all those herbicides to
kill
bits and over years it's a more popular
became more popular and farmer loves
this heresite and Dally if you look this
map
here so this is the Mississippi Basin
it's Al and Central Valley Columbia
River and Washington State those are
planes which heavily farmed and heavily
used for
herbicide herbicide or you can know as a
this trademark round up it's
so became a little bit uh
controversial in terms of environmental
toxicity and occurence we can find
everywhere in soil water even air and
also can be accummulated in
Plants however it's not cionic it's
defined by
EPA in terms of like a usage that's a
thing we are thinking we should more pay
attention about that I'm showing here
the most uh like a the main processes of
like in envir compartment how it moves
around after spray it can be by
accumul or it can be degradated by U
light or it can enter into water sorry
into soil or water and interact with
minerals specifically organ organ
mineral
associations excuse
me I'm interested to
learn about how it retain and be
released or transforms and those
are mineral and organ Association a
biotically and
also this really important to know how
this byproducts can be generated after
transformation because we seea Amal
phosphoric acid which is one of this by
product it can be uptaken by plant much
more than
glyphosate and also it's has the same
toxicity impact on
cells this is a general understanding or
general figure of my
visitation orgam Association
concentration diminishes as you go down
profile and after spray obviously it's
going to interact with organ Association
on top
in terms of interaction and type of
organ Association it can go into the
retention process or it can be
transformed so mag oxide is very well
known for transformation or oxidation of
glyphosate so this is a candidate for
doing that study and iron oxide is
selectively they selectively absorb
organ Organics and form organ
Association so it's a good
representative to pick as organ
Association to see glyphosate
retention at
one in act one or section
one is a kind of in section for my
dissertation and that's about theability
of particles in soil organ Association
forms and obviously can change
theability of that in the other like
language we call them how it can be more
hydrophobic or
hydrophilic if we can measure it is
measuring Water contact angle if the
contact angle is about 90 de it's going
to be more hydrophobic and below that is
hydrophilic
surface so
gote has a hydrophilic surface and
I I picked Diamond because we have
diamond plate and that's a hydrophobic
surface and can be used as a model to
study how organ Association formation
can change this hydrophobicity of the
philicity on both
surfaces so for organic or dissolve
organic matter I picked polysaccharide
polysaccharide can be find in soil and
it comes from plant cell wall and also
microbial
necromass and they accumulate at the
surface of minerals specifically a metal
oxides I this
interesting uh so now I have a model
system I can see that more
fundamentally instead of using like a
the extraction of
D on this graph
here uh first of all I use Inc ATR
spectroscopy is a technique to see
absorption at the surface of mineral if
you have mineral you can introduce your
organic your uh your target sorbent they
going to absorb and you're going to see
some
PS they come different frequency and
those frequency is related to different
bondings in in each
molecule at the surface of theide we see
absorption of poy is much more than
Diamond that because po itself is
hydrophilic and hydrophilic loves
hydrophilic it ter kinetic with
increasing surface loading or pide we
notice it's gets
slower and we have more
absorption and subsequently when we have
dsorption
phase some of those absorbed can be
disorb if it's much we have more
absorption there's more chance for
dsorption but in lower is a lower
absorption rate we have less absorption
the other way to translate that looking
at isoterm is absorption dsorption is
also shows this uh loading at different
St like a phase absorption and so
dsorption
this is a a similar set data set for
Diamond so we have less absorption
compared to goite kinetically much much
faster
and during
absorption I can say most of them are
disorb and some of them are still at
surface and this is you can see an ISO
as
well this is really important to know
first how much stuff you have how does
it look like the loading uh rate and
capacity what I did next I was
interested to see the hydrophobicity and
ficity I use water contact angle
measurement uh
met to measure what what angle we
increasing surface loading here we
notice on both surface idop phobicity
idop phobicity increases since we have
higher contact
angle that was interesting but it
doesn't matter what surface you start
but you load more more more surface
become more
hydrophobe and this this picture here
it's not obvious actually maybe that
that screen is much better the outline
here this space is loaded by po this a
Tage of poy
Association that's giving you a little B
visual result how Z look like in
summary and also more data we have here
in terms of functional interaction of
functionality on P private
surface what you learned
in interfacial sequence for those
functional groups you can see functional
groups here this is po structure par
groups Mi groups and M groups and this
is
backbone if if it's the surface Diamond
hydrophobic
surface backbone which is a more
hydrophobic surface hydrophobic
component it start to show up at the
surface but loading more and
more we we started to see am and
carboxilic functionalities those are
more
hydrophilic and but at the end it's
wrapped up by a metaler functional group
which is
hydrophobic more hydrophobic than other
functionalities the same we have we have
the same Trend like in terms of how this
hydropic hydrophilic functional
accumulated surface and go side at the
end of the the loading ultimate loading
we saw again luster and the surface
again became hydrop the top here at the
most surfaces this is really important
to know how much organic
matter can change the hydrophobicity
ority and how this going to impact a
contam the transfer of contaminants when
they going to
interact act two
in act two so I introduced lios in the
system and I
found that was a question actually the
question was how this organ complexation
now can change glyos retention or if
there's any potential for release with
they abor or
not this is a bad uh study dat I'm
showing here the first look at this uh
plot at the left
typ with think this red line showing
absorption during showing absorption of
glyphosate with increasing absor loading
we found with loading more poy absor
lessly absorb less and after but we had
aborption this is the Blue Line we had
some disorb but the same trend
with the same
Trend if you look after specific point
with loading with loading more poy here
and here for absortion absorption we had
a little bit increase for glyos
absorption uh it's more feable it looks
to have more glyphosate even we have a
lot of polysaccharide at the
surface what I did I said maybe it's
about like a charge we can look at the
charge of the surface because
electrostatically we are interacting
each other I measured the potential of
those uh samples I found with increasing
this uh red sorry this green line here
with increasing loading we have are
generating more negative charge
glycosite itself is z ion but in total
one one negative one so that means we
should have less absorption and that's
which is about this part so what about
this part when we have more loading when
we have more loading it looks when we
have we add glyphosate in this are the
red dots does it the potential became a
little bit more positive still negative
but less u in terms of the pulsive Force
it's less the
pulsive sorry repulsive and we can have
more more interaction attractive
interaction fundamentally I have one
more question what's happening like what
do we see this increase for charge so I
looked a little bit in detail using STD
NMR uh technique STD NMR technique is a
very good technique to study H gas
complexation between protein and small
legans
this is the combination of glyphosate
and polysaccharide we had a com we had a
stample this is just glyphosate only we
found when we have pick of glyphosate in
this sample when we have Spectra that
actually shows we have noncovalent
interaction via hydr bonding between
polysaccharides and glyphosate they can
attract each other through hydrob
bonding and hydrob bonding is very good
sort of interaction to stabilize a to
stabilize the complex so the complex can
immobilize easily at the surface so we
have this increase
now
oh
sorry that was a bch of study now I want
to see more about glyos it itself and
its bonding how the molecule interact at
the
surface and how how those
functionalities in glyos we have glyos
here it has phosphinate group group and
carboxilic acid group I want to see how
it interacting at the surface of Po poy
go Association and also
go so at the right hand side we are
looking at P band which is related to
this interaction chemisorption of
glyphosate and at the right hand side
you have carox
AL C this peak that shows this part the
green part of the
glyos and I looked at Peak area versus
time this is a thing you can figure out
how much stuff you have and how change
it as a function of
time so this is for po band and this is
for Caro I mean car coo band so third
thing we can find so this is faster
carox Ian functionality is interacting
faster and but this this phosphonate is
not interacting at the same rate in
another thing with increasing PS loading
this way I'm loading
more we we decrease both functionalities
and that's equivalent to less
absorption there the reason to have two
different rates for one molecule is
actually about interfacial species we
don't have only one type of Kos at the
surface we have multiple different types
and those are in different locations and
in total in general we see different
rates oh one thing I to mention that
okay and if you look the uh the type of
binding this is by dented binding we
have two oxygen
and connected to two
iron atom and here only we have one hand
which is a or one bonding we call the
monodendate so when when we have
polysaccharide mon monate bonding is
moreable and that's really important
because bented is much stronger than b
monodentate and that means there's a
chance that glyphosate can be released
from po Association versus uh goti be
goti again I like to think more in
detail and I looked the carox I mean
versus carox Acid versus
aming so I did I deconstructed the Peaks
and this is the deconvolution analysis I
found if I look the
retained if I look the contribution of
this function
ities I can find how much they are
important in the interaction during
absorption and absorption what we found
during absorption with increasing poy
loading ammonium this functionality here
this functional
group have more getting more
contribution in the interaction the
retention of
glyphosate and that's a really uh
interesting for me and it makes sense
actually actually am mean is positively
charged so electrostatically they can
interact more with the negative charge
uh components in
polysaccharide and it makes a tertiary
complex polysaccharide
glyphosate uh iron
oxide and this is we have a
chemisorption from the one side and we
have a hydrogen bonding from the other
side so this wayos can be stabilized at
the surface and then maybe it can have
delayed release when there's uh when you
have more precipitation in offseason
during fall or
winter in
summary did you know sorry I know now
you know
whyos dances on J floor it's more
mobile looks so glyphosate retained to
less sent uh we can find I'm just
counting so just comparing those
Peaks and po go to Association that
means we're going to have greater
transport of g into water and po
Association promotes more monent dat
bind dat and Which is less strong and
the retain lifeo that's the kind of uh
interpretation from those data that says
that could be possible to have a delayed
Ling act
three in act
three I have a different
question in this question I'm looking
at how low molecular weight this time
poy is high molecular weight compound in
soil but I wanted to know how low
molecular weight disol organic matter
can interact with glyphosate
and how it changes their absorption and
retention so I made a binary system this
time I mix them together and let them to
absorb so for low modly weight do I'm
using
this peptide it has 19 Amin acids as a
model
PTI so before starting study absorption
on go type I was interested to know is
there any interaction in solution itself
this low moleular we and GL can interact
so I use two different techniques ir and
NMR so in ir and at the right the left
hand side this spectrum showing
glyphosate plus peptide
sample if you compare the lines the dash
Lin
which is from blos pepti you can see
this is the summation of those Spectrum
with no shifts no shifts for frequencies
and no shifts actually for brening or
shortening of the sh of bands and that
means there's no interaction we test it
again with a different technique and we
look at those amino acids this
time this is the NMR
toxy for P sample which is a do of black
regene and pepti plus gly sample are
showing the showed by Red regines if you
look those regines from peptide and
peptide plus glyphosine they're over lay
completely covering each other and
there's no differences they're not
moving around that means there's no
interaction what about surface what
about the
surface I looked at glyphosate peptide
absorption
spectra and to know how peptide can
change the absorption rate and capacity
and also how it changes its complexation
of the data shows here I looked at this
bonding here which is a f POF
bonding or can aborption of
glyphosate glyphosate itself is the sign
the this is the curve for lios so plus
peptide you can see dramatically dropped
it they have less absorption for peptide
they competing for surface and peptide
is winning this game peptide can sit
accy the surface
and
didn't I
didn't allow glyphosate to the
sorb another thing is about kinetic also
the kinetically
glyphosate absorption is
slower during the in a in a Solo System
but when we have peptide it's became
faster the reason is
chemisorption kinetically is a slow slow
reaction but alter complexation without
chemisorption is faster so that me
peptide is changing binding top not only
absorption capacity
also we found if there is any type of
chemisorption for glyphosate with
peptide it's more monen take form which
is a less strong
one the summary for that I can say
peptide glyos in the presence of
peptide decreases the absorption for
glyphosate and that means we going to
have more transport then you have low
moleular weight comp kind of sub and
plus glyphosate lios are not able to sit
and find someplace for it sit for itself
so it goes away and stay in water and
another things as I mentioned don't way
do like peptide promotes more more
dented and outer sphere complexation
those type of bonding are are very weak
bonding and also less
strong and in
general we found there's no
interaction in solution and at the
surface between glyphosate and peptide
that was another which is opposite
poyares P way they interact with each
other then you have high M weight
compound but low M weight and glyphosate
P tract
the last
Act is about transformation of
glyos so I looked at absorption and
dsorption
now the question is how organ Min
Association impact transformation of
glyos blosic transformation I think I
mentioned this create a Amal phosphoric
acid which is toxic as same as
glyphosate or earli stage kind of celf
development in animals and plants and so
we should look we should
study fic acid more and look at that so
the Orin and this compound originates
from transformation so I wanted to know
how organ Association can uh change
generation of this product or
transformation of
glyos so the model mineral is magese
oxide we have two magese oxide in this
system sorry uh berite and
Hite Mages oxide the differences is
they're having different catalytic
capability and the reason is having
different content of Manganese 34 or
different manganes uh different
oxidation States for
manganese bite have more
manganese 3 and four but Hite has more
manganese 2 and
three that means lower average oxidation
state lower Catal catalytic capability
or
oxidative transformation for
glyphosate on this is slide I'm showing
uh two interesting Pathways in terms of
my
study the pathway that create I'm
phosphoric acid or ampa and
glycine Glycine paway and the reason
there are we have two different molecule
because this cage a c and cage can be
happen in two different position and
then then can create two different
molecule and two different
Pathways either is it ampa or
glycine two steps are really important
step for transformation the first step
is
complexation Gite absorbs and then we
have a single electron transfer reaction
electron jumps into the surface and then
we have a radical species and this
radical species start to
degradate gly is okay if you have G only
this
halfway we should be fine g g is safe
it's om acid
but the empa is not safe and also it
accumulates more imp plants so this
pathway is a bad pathway and this
pathway is a good
pathway again is there any interaction
between protean and glyphosate before
starting to see the interaction at the
surface protean is high moleular we
dissolve matter in soil
so I was expecting to see interaction
and I saw it SDR showed this interaction
and this time the interaction was much
uh Stronger the now now calent bonding
between glyos protein it looks shows
better signal for SDR the bigger signal
means a stronger non coent bonding
so let's talk about absorption first and
then we're going to talk about
transformation so the first step I said
is surface
complexation for this I use in2 ATR FD
spectroscopy since I have a very limited
surface on
ATR I'm able to see only detect glyos
absorption you have a lot of glyphosate
and Lim the surface the signal from
byproduct mole
is not is negligible and it's not uh
overlapping or interfering with the
glyphosate signal so I
can TRW some data based on what I'm see
and referring that to p and bonding this
bonding here is a bed bonding between
Mages oxide and
glyphosine on top we have bur side this
panel and this panel has KN so I'm going
to talk about side first first two line
from top side top are showing P
experiment at pH 4.6 with up and with
BSA protein and the the next two which
are lower showing lower absorption they
are pH 7.2 so this is the first on first
result increasing pH decrease absorption
that makes sense glyos became more
negatively charged and surface also gets
more negatively charged because those
magnes oxide
having lower Z PC zero point of charge
and then the the pH is above that
surface became more negative and we have
more repulsive
Force what about
BSA BSA adding and comp to the
system decrease
absorption you have less absorption now
when we have the set surface it doesn't
matter which uh what
pH is that or even the surface we see
the same ter even for Hite and hus also
show this uh absor list absorption
capacity when we add BSA
in and also the same turn for
pH so BSA Association reduce the extent
and absorption rate for glyphosate on
both coated Mages oxides at higher pH I
said less capacity at soing capacity
that means so we going to have more into
the
water for
transformation I needed to extend the
surface so I wanted to measure
byproducts my Surface needed to be
bigger so I designed a new system a new
kind of experimental design so actually
I'm mimicking the the transport in po
water these are SW particles and also so
particles coated with manganese oxide or
iron oxide
Plus organic matter so this is what I
did I
made BSA magnes oxide chips protein is
loaded onto the magnes oxide here and
this this glass SL glass glass SL goes
into the a microf reactor then we ince
use glyos in as a function of time we
collect influence and we analyze for uh
for byproducts using lcms or other
photometric photometric
approach this is a closer view to the
bite and light chips so here on Top This
is a cross-section of that it shows how
thick is uh film The magn oxide and for
Hite for Brite is around 2 micrometer
and for Hite is 4.5
micrometer so they have different amount
of mang oxide at the surface
but the thing is very important is the
surface area internal surface area or
total catalic surface area we have
almost similar surface area now so
they're going to be
they're going to have fair condition in
terms of surface
area and these two are T images of those
cryst kind of
particles now we are looking at work
through curves from those uh from that
uh microfic
reactors when we have bide and then in
the next slide we're going to look at
Hite so I
or sort the result based on ph here at
the left hand side we have pH 4.6 at the
right hand side we have P
7.2 on the bottom and on bottom of the
panel we have bur side with BSA and on
top bur side alone no BSA it's is very
obvious like with increasing with uh at
greater pH transformation became less
you have less by products and so if you
compare at either either like a pH 4.6
or P ph7.2 when we have glyphosate sorry
when we have protean at the surface so
it diminishes the deration we have less
transformation for
glyphosate in terms of path phas I
calculated how much of transformation
related to a and how much is related to
glycine I measured since I have data
for ampa and
glycine at pH 4.6 it looks they are
going equally we have both Pathways and
they are almost equal rate increasing
pH it changes again now bline pathway
gets more dominated dominated now this
primly we can say goes this way around
70% and 30% that we have two numbers
here because of the with BSA and without
BSA uh with BSA port at the surface we
see more ampa uh as a
pathway that's a littleit change if it's
40 without BSA it became 46 here at p7
7.2 if it was 28 now became 32 so BSA
Association
Ina kind of change the pathway toward
amp but it still Li is
more exactly same Trend not exactly same
similar Trend observe the surface of
Hite with without DSA at to
pH and then here but the the ratio
between ample pathway and glum pathway
is not the same it looks
aite uh mediate more gling paths way 80%
at 4.6 and 86% at 7.2 and there's no
difference with with having or not
having a BSA they have exactly the same
ratio and one thing I didn't mention
that is about if there's any chance for
to go forther transformation for
byproducts the way you can say that
measuring ammonium and I detected
ammonium at the surface of asite but
burze shows couple per like a 2 to 5%
ammonium that means still B is more
catalytically active
to
serate one more step to get ammonium
phosphate carbon dioxide and
water so here I'm summarizing the
protein Association in bags
so it looks active site occupied by ber
by by BSA
protein then what's happening so it
limits the adsorption and subsequently
limits transformation
rates another thing we found from STD
andmr study there is organic organic
interaction so how it changes the system
we have organic organ interaction so
glyphosate has less chance to interact
with the surface and to be degradated so
it protects glyphosate from
fire so another thing this is
interesting this is studied by many
people and they found protein can
immobilize and reduce manganes when we
have reduced surface and that's another
another way to have less transformation
because catalic capity capability drops
then we have video surface instead of
having oxid
surface here I have
time this is the thing I'm proposing for
surface passivation of manganes
oxide so I measured pH and also
dissolved manganese soluble manganese in
influence to learn how it changes like
because when we have glyphosate
transformation we have a electron uh
transfer from glyphosate to surface and
surface became
reduced that means magnes oxide became
transformed so we have not the same
surface the surface changes when we have
more
transformation and the transformation
causes higher pH that means we going to
have high pH in solution that diminishes
the
transformation we have more soluble
magang in solution that means Ru surface
again it decreases
transformation another thing we have
glyphosate glyphosate can complex with
manganes reduce manganes and make a
dissociation a dissociation for surface
that we call liant promoted
dissociation and Li promoted
dissociation decrease the catalic
capability for magaz oxide and another
way to passivate surface so this is a
negative feedback loop in long term if
you run this
experiment the gradation of G Posite
going to become less less and
less so I'm going to summarize entire
four
acts to what I learned and I want to
give you
this when we had load surface like a
minerals in soil say like this when we
add more organic matter into soil and
before more organal
Association the surface going to be more
hydrophobic and less
reable and in terms of absorption and
transformation for glyphosate we going
to have less
retention and also slower
absorption and slower dsorption
all of this means more transport into
the groundwater or as a or runoff into
the
streams for
transformation when you have higher
loading at the
surface again less transformation become
because absorption is a first step for
transformation when we have so this is a
kind of crucial step less absorption
less
transformation and so we found the trans
transformation became less
slower and when we have
transformation ampa pronounce more this
time compared to a surface without any
any orent
matter and that's not good and yeah
that's my conclusion somehow uh uh it's
going to be problematic High organ
matter and then so environment this way
in terms of contaminant transport and
contaminant fate but the problem is a
contaminant first but this is a
subsequent kind of
interactions another bonus uh thing I
want to share is about organic organic
interaction
order between glyphosate and those High
molecular way and low molecular Way D So
based on NMR studies so high high
protein strongly is much stronger to
make a CO calent or hydogen bonding to
glyos compared to paride and also
there's no interaction between low
moleular way uh molecule like peptide
and
glyphosate this already suggests that we
need to pay particular attention to the
type of do in
evaluating the behavior of
contaminants at the environmental
interfaces it could be water it could or
to be soil
system uh here I want to
acknowledge uh thank
you past eight years
yeah you supported me
and and you led me to uh to learn more
about soci science and
also to developing skills any skills you
let me to try
anything and also my lab labmates so my
previous labmates Michael Taylor Ariel
and my current labmates
Amy Luna and Alysa they are
awesome I know this is a teamw
workk and
it's not possible to do in a something
like this in a lonely and know so not
supporting
environments my special commente they
had good uh advice
uh and also I minored environmental
processes and environmental assessment
in environmental engineering school and
I had a time to learn about those things
with Damian and Matthew and I want to
thank uh Y and Hugh for helping me with
measuring
Toc uh
manganese phosph
glyphosate not glyphosate sorry auto
phosphate because they have
IC by
chromatography
uh I use ccmr facilities and different
facilities at Cornel lcms at bti and
measuring a surface area Z the size Z
the potential in
energy
Institute and I was I worked with the
Robert Page to make that micr
director sorry
uh some some of those researchers and
also some of those scientists they are
really uh supporting and inspiring for
me Linda nichelson for supporting me to
do NMR studies and uh Mary MCB is
a you say his research and his attitude
is
inspiring what I'm doing here he started
I don't know maybe 30 years ago to study
this I'm just adding 11 keys to what he
found in the past like a
Years also there people from different
loc places that they help me to do
modeling for some stuff are not shown
here that the thing
like Eugene Elton helped me to do pck
modeling for manganese
fractions and also my friend neria help
me to do a 1D transport in hydras
and at the end my
family my lovely wife R and adorable
kids a and
Lena they made a positive environment
and safe environment for me to do this
research and also my friend s
Teddy Sonam you know I think you know
son uh Richard is my business uh friend
U he's my founder I'm running a sub
company is my founder and his co-
founded and Michael Schmid Michael
Schmid
twice thank you so much um it's over but
if you have any question I G take those
questions question yes I have the sarite
was fining the ability of the gly to and
the idea there is that it's going to
then perhaps reduce the chemical
transformation the first this first
second act is about absorption an iron
oxide so an iron oxide there is no
transformation for glyphosate so what we
see is a pure impact on absorption of
so it diminishes absorption of
glyphosate but so I needed to work with
another molecule actually it's a fair
question and I picked protean because I
had a batch study before starting the
transformation study I picked different
Organics liin polysaccharide polyalc
acid protean and other stuff that are
people can detect in soil mix them with
Mages oxide and and started to see the
transformation of Organics itself before
add glyphosate I found proteins more
stable at surface that means less
problematic for me if want to detect the
bipu or I'm going to have more stable
surface to see a transformation for
glyphosate so that was the reason I
changed from Pacar to protean on
manes I guess my followup question there
is
in terms of in terms of what the
behavior is since
Sol um it seems like you know to get
chemical transformation you need to get
interaction with the surface yeah um but
in terms of like entic or microbial
degradation that's going to be maximized
in solution and so potentially you have
one form of transformation is when
you're on the surface but then processes
that are inhibiting that form of trans
that form of transformation might
actually enhance microbial trans
Teri
system yeah that's that's
a fair and valid uh fact so it's not in
the at surface more available for
bacteria also more available for ex
enzymes can be degradated but those
are biotically instead of
atically thank
you yeah it's good to to follow up like
the now system needs to be have a micro
how it's going to
be organ
Association and
micro that's could be something to yeah
interesting all right so for the
interest of time I think great thank you
very much
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu