this is a production of Cornell
University well welcome I'm so glad this
is a lot more people than I expected I
think the last time I did a talk here it
was like two people like during that the
peak Zoom time but um this again this
talk does work so much better if we're
standing in the Orchard and I can like
do the Willy Wonka like look at Paradise
like look at this beautiful diversity
collection so you're so close
you're like so close to Paradise
Geneva's not far like we do tours Public
tours um Marvin like we do lots of Tours
for Horticultural groups from Cornell
like take a chance to come up and see
and taste fruit and that that's really
how like germplasm is meant to be
interacted with and discovered um so I
am the the curator for the apple and
tart cherry collection I'm going to talk
about the grape collection that's up
there a little bit but I am I'm really
grateful for this opportunity let's see
here we go and of course like I'm the
only one talking today but this is all
like a a team effort really so we have
you know a a core of three scientists on
the team and and also Ganan zong who's
the research leader up there but like we
have tremendous expertise in in grafting
in chemistry in pathology um entomology
now with the new edition Michaela
Robertson and who can forget interns
right like this is kind of the highlight
of the job and I really like Advocate
strongly for anyone who's in the science
like Mentor as many as you can like find
your replacement right like we can't do
this job forever like you need to get
the the Next Generation motivated and
trained to kind of step in and take the
Reigns um so yeah we've done yeah maybe
23 interns now at my time starting in
2018 um and again this is like I think I
always give this quote and from Aldo
Leopold is like kind of my like the
philosophy that I try to like frame
frame all of that all of our discussions
in horiculture agriculture and when
we're talking to Broad audiences maybe
this isn't the audience for this quote
but I think this is useful in connecting
to the Next Generation to connecting
people who who don't think that they're
part of Agriculture but really there are
two spiritual dangers in not owning a
farm one is the danger of supposing that
breakfast comes from the grocery and the
other that heat comes from the furnace
and I do think that this part of New
York does a little bit better job at
that than than most of the country but
still there's a lot of work to do and
really like when you consider about 2%
of the US population is directly
involved in agriculture or ranching like
it's pretty it's there's a lot writing
on on the few that are are contributing
to this and this is this is how I feel
this is how maybe it feels to all of you
working in in your respective Fields
like we're Copus pushing this boulder up
the hill and like you know other fields
I don't feel like have this challenge
that we do right like if they never made
another smartphone I think we' we'd
adapt like we'd be fine it's not like
once they stop making smartphones we've
roll back to like the rotary phone right
but if we stop the research and the the
progress in agriculture there really is
a threat that we roll back production we
roll back that sustainability as new
pests new challenges emerge and like
really there's no end to what we need to
do right so really like passing that
Boulder off to the Next Generation so
that food security is like yeah not the
the pressing concern for our society
right like we can solve other societal
issues rather than just trying to feed
ourselves but not all doom and gloom
right like this is the other this is the
flip side getting to work in horiculture
is that there's a joy and there's like a
childlike you know wonderment at the the
diversity that's out there and the the
exciting Discovery so hopefully um so
this is not the original Willy Wonka
this is Tory mum who's our molecular
biologist and a talented um intern of
our did some nice Photoshop but um
actually I I do need to update this
because I mentioned that to an NPR inter
um in an NPR interview with Susan Brown
that Susan's kind of the Willy Wonka for
apples and they picked up on that and
published it now Susan Brown kind of
gets yeah teased a little bit for her
Willy Wonka but there's just there's a
joy and like there's mystery and some I
don't know impishness to like coming to
visit the the Jean Banks and tasting
weird flavors and yeah not not
everything will pass to you is is is
desirable and hopefully this group is is
well vered in in germplasm and I don't
know that there's like maybe a a course
or thing that like really hammers this
home but like what is germplasm and just
simply like bearers of heredity right
like these living resources that can
contribute to plant Improvement and it
can be any number of things modern
cultivars heirlooms land races crop wild
relatives like we do a lot of work with
those and I I think I highlight here the
the value of these prop wild relatives
cuz all like of the really exciting
traits that like you know I lose sleep
at night thinking about like how cool
some of these these traits are you know
the the disease resistance is huge for
sustainability but flavor like conquer
the the kind of the classic grape flavor
comes from a Wild Grape and what we
associate you know with the candy flavor
of grape really is like a wild trait
that is introgressed um strawberries
right like the production of
strawberries like that everbearing trait
comes from a wild um strawberry species
from Utah where I'm a native too so
really like getting excited about you
know bringing in the crop wild relatives
like the land races have a tremendous
history and story like this is the story
of uh of civilization told through
Agriculture and it's so important that
like not just speaking of them as tools
that we can use to to to make new Cult
of ours but really like preserving our
history and our culture um and really
it's this it's this balance right like
so the breeding pipeline is to like come
up with amazing cultivar but there's the
selection process really does narrow
down that and like really this is
showing the breeding I don't know if you
can see my
pointer is that coming through yeah so
like the breeding is leading upwards but
really like that's poor that's just poor
design like because the breeding cycle
is going back through each layer and
trying to bring in new traits and new
you know new what to maintain this broad
diversity because again no breeder worth
is his salt or his or her salt is going
to like breed themselves into a corner
especially for Apple breeding which
again the generation time like to be
able to Ingress new new traits and new
new germ plasm is going to set you back
quite quite a bit of time so always be
thinking like how can I maintain this
while trying to achieve you know a
broader and more you know broad
diversity and targeted releases for for
new cultivars um so yeah avoid the
bottlenecks um because that's really
kind of evident here when we do genetic
studies of our apple collection each
line represents the first degree
relationship and so in our diversity
collection of about 2,000 Apple
accessions you can see how everything's
kind of already intermixed and and
somehow related to one another um but
Apple because of its uh biology really
retains a lot of diversity but modern
cultivars really only have about eight
like progenitors that is like the found
like the effective population for Apple
that's kind of kind of
scary so I am part of the national plant
germ plasm system which is a USDA
program that has about 20 sites
throughout the US dedicated to crop
conservation Geneva is unique because we
are one of the original four that
started in the 1940s um so here's Geneva
here I'll highlight um again here's like
the overall Holdings of the the entire
program about 621,000
accessions and is again this isn't just
like a cool collection like an arc that
no one has access to this is like
broadly accessible for research and for
breeding and for commercial de
development so about 20 you know quarter
of a million samples go out every year
from ourg Banks and that's pretty
amazing and with our simple mission of
acquire preserve characterize and
distribute these genetic resources um I
do love this quote by the geneticist of
Francois Jacob uh diversity is a way of
coping with the possible it acts as a
kind of insurance for the future and
when people get excited about talking
sustainability and how do we like
preserve you know agriculture for the
future that genetic diversity is a part
of that
solution so our Gene Bank does look a
lot different than maybe what you've
seen like I know Denise like has a lot
of experience working in like in like
the classic G bank but here is our G
bank and it's really like not preserved
at like not protected at all like so we
have deer issues isues we have disease
management problems just because these
are field-based
Collections and you can see we do have
you know a substantial diversity of
apple and uh 56 species with about 4,400
um accessions in there making at one of
like the world's largest and most
diverse genetically in the world which
is really exciting the grape collection
has about 30 species with 1400
accessions and the tart cherry which
again is like it's small but it's one of
my favorite things things ever to talk
about um so here's just kind of our
numbers we mentioned like the quarter of
a million distributed um Geneva mostly
was Distributing Apple for a long time
like reaching about you know 6,000 to
8,000 accessions a year or samples a
year that we were Distributing um postco
we've had some like pullback just
because we want to like focus our energy
and to making sure that that germplasm
is targeted for breeding and for for
legitimate
research so here's kind of the class
view of like this is a jean Bank this
anyone recognize the one on the left
where is it spart spart yeah so like the
Doomsday Vault right and so we have a
vault like this for our vegetable and
Seed collection um hemp I should mention
as well is in a vault like this um and
this is what I mean by we need to
balance vulnerability and accessibility
so apples are are easily like the most
the simplest way that people have
propagated and and traded apples over
time and preserved them is through Al
propagation so you can keep seeds all
you want but if you want a clonally
maintained line like a pure honey crisp
it's only through uh clonal propagation
that you can do so and so if you want it
accessible for pollen and you want to do
crosses you need a tree a mature tree
living in the field and so in 2020 we
had an outbreak of fire blight that
really just devastated each um each
Square here in the grid of our field map
represents an accession and the color
indicates disease severity and purple
being the most severe and it's kind of
there's a lot of purple in there so at a
time that like we were reduced Workforce
because of covid policies we had this
outbreak of fire blight which really was
a challenge for us but hey we got on the
cover of agronomy with one of our
picture so we did an evaluation just
let's go through the collection and just
evaluate like let's do a quantitative
score of how infected these trees are
just by counting number of fresh and new
growth and then taking account of how
many infected shoots and just giving
kind of the rough percentage of those
and you see quite a bit of of broad
variation you know from zero% which
could be just a lucky Escape or I like
this one it's like 64% here and about
0.9% so they're right there we're you
know a high probability of tree you know
see here getting some disease pressure
but not showing any signs of resistance
and then when we map like our the
results by species you see like a lot of
the domestic ated apples have you know
kind of interesting broad range of no
infection to heavy infection Mal saveri
is the wild progenitor so it kind of
makes sense for that one as well to have
a similar pattern that was June July you
see a lot of those healthy trees
disappear as disease progresses and we
start to capture more infection but a
lot of the wild species retain their
resistance to the
disease and again the challenge for us
is maintaining these collections is
there are
amazing Horticultural practices a lot of
them developed at Cornell to manage
apples but not diverse collections of
apples where everything might Bloom at
the same time or at a different time
which is critical for managing a disease
like fire blight or the the response to
a certain pesticide and you might be
sometimes we were doing more damage than
good by putting on certain applications
of um copper right for example or proex
apogee doesn't not each accession
doesn't respond to the the effects of
apigy to reduce growth to kind of limit
the disease so it really is a tight a
tight rope walk of Orchard management to
like hold the all these diversity
collections keep them all together while
managing all these different you know
challenges and requirements and so a lot
of pruning and regeneration happened
during that time and I think our total
was close to 3,000 individual trees were
propagated and replanted in Geneva and
we're doing so much better now with a
diverse um Management program chemically
that is but there's still an impact on
on on fruit quality again this is where
we don't rely on uh commercial practices
we can do things that like will
sacrifice fruit quality to main maintain
tree Health um but this is one of the
consequences is like we'll see Heavy
rusting heavy splitting which makes the
fruit kind of not useful for
characterization which is a critical
part of our our mission so we have these
healthy trees right like or we have a
wonderful diversity collection that no
one's interested in using because they
don't know what we have right and but
during this kind of heavy fire blight
time we couldn't do a lot of
characterization to take representative
images or get good fruit quality data
from those um the other kind of safety
net that we utilize heavily is
cryopreservation and Apple's one of the
easiest to cryopreserve it's simple
collecting dormant signwood like you
would right now for grafting and you can
dehydrate it and put it in liquid
nitrogen and almost the recovery is you
know 80 to 90% viability and it's
tremendous um really easy to to manage
and get your diversity collections
backed up this way grape is a lot more
challenging it doesn't direct cryle
there's like a shoot tip and a droplet
vitrification so going into tissue
culture getting droplets freezing those
and then bringing those out right so you
can imagine that the the labor intensive
part is like kind of the bottleneck
there
again clonal propagation this is one of
the the coolest and most ancient tools
that we have right like dating back
maybe 10,000 years of people
demonstrating that this um capacity so
this is likely how apples were taken out
of original forests and traded and and
brought to your backyard right like no
more foraging now we have cultivars we
like we can put them right where we want
and so um again just kind of a an
example of how we do grafting and
propagation to maintain our Collections
and so these are these are examples from
cryo preservation which you can see
here's the root stock and then here's
the the bued the chip buted accession
and then yeah you'll get some growth and
then you can trim back the root stock
and have a a brand new accession and
what's so cool about this is now you
have a timelessness to the diversity and
so things that were are hundreds of
years old or sometimes thousands of
years old they report some grapes back
to Roman periods um Roxberry russet is a
cool Apple in our excession because it
represents the first true American Apple
um it's this kind of wild triploid thing
that's not that tasty but it's again
it's part of American History Mont Mory
dates back to the the pre 17th century
and represents the largest um cultivar
grown for tart cherry production in the
us and our buddy conquer right like we
love this grape and its distinctiveness
but this is an old one as well and so
what's amazing is that you walk into
these Collections and you can see things
that were developed you know with within
the last 10 years or like the last
several hundred years in our collection
and they're intermixed with the wild
species as well so you kind of get this
the snapshot of all the diversity in one
time so now I'll just walk through some
of the exciting like I think they're
exciting characterization um efforts
that we're going through right now
because again like it's not enough to
just have these things be secure we want
people to use them and one of the
limitations to people having access is
just they don't know what we have or
what would be interesting to them so
collecting phenotypic genetic data like
getting that information out like maybe
it's got an interesting pedigree or
history and that makes it more
accessible um so the tarte Cherry is
kind of a nightmare though genetically
so it's a tetrol hybrid of a sweet
cherry and a wild European Cherry but
it's got this really interesting um
anthocyanin profile that it's like so
here's anthocyanin again it's not just
red right like it's it's a different
profile which gives it different
chemical properties and distinguishable
through chromatography kind of
interesting that you can tell a suite
from a tart just by it its chemical
fingerprint um melatonin is reported
high and this is one of my white whales
um for characterization because it's
just such a fascinating compound to
study um thank heavens that Tik Tok was
saved right like I don't know if you
guys were nervous about that but how
else would we have known about the
sleepy girl mocktail from tart cherry
juice right so here's a great use of
social media to promote a crop um go and
look this up again there's there's a lot
of
interesting um I don't know anecdotal
things that like we do with with our
crops um but sleepy girl mocktail
highlights kind of the the the Sleepy
benefits of of tart cherry juice which
might be related to melatonin or might
be nothing at all but we'll we'll
investigate more what's cool about tarte
cherries is that they're kind of having
a moment right now um so I guess I would
say like Grandma drinks prune juice
right and like your ultramarathon Runner
is chugging down tart cherry juice and
so like they have like this is one brand
like they've got the pit crew who
doesn't want to be part of the pit crew
right that's great that's great branding
and it's like a great promotion of a
product and it gets it into diverse
markets and applications and it's not
just uh a $3 bottle of cherry juice now
it's a $15 bottle of elite you know um
endurance juice right like drink this if
you want to to gear up for I don't know
Marvin's seminar or like maybe he's got
a tough exam coming up chug some tart
cherry juice maybe it'll help but the
problem with the tart cherry industry in
the US is it's narrowly it's like
precariously dependent on a single
cultivar um which again we if you take
any agriculture class you know that this
is bad news and you shouldn't do that um
so we wrote a fruit quarterly on like
let's move Beyond Mont morenzi
highlighting some of the the interest
ing diversity within the usdaa
collection and I highlight this again
because you can see the red is our tarte
cherry and it gets very little attention
compared again we're it's maybe a
hundred million dollar um industry in
the US on a good year compared to like
the billions that gra grape and apple
bring in so it's it's nothing it's not
the smallest crop but it yeah it could
benefit from some diversity so we've
looked at phenological traits so phen
like Bloom time alone sets back the
industry um every couple of years years
just by a frost bite or Frost um damage
and ruining your your crop um fruit
chemistry I mentioned like interesting
phenolic profiles that like might be
related to some of the nutritional
benefits of the the juice and then fruit
just generic fruit descriptores and
images um pit weights you know looking
at pit to fruit ratios you can like kind
of maximize um fruit size and not waste
yeah waste energy and and a market on a
heavy pit this large excessively large
pits
um looking at tart cherry Bloom
phenology we do see some like some
significant variation so this might be
this maybe represents a month-long span
with the the vertical line here
representing Mont Morenci so you can see
there's some extreme light blooming
Beyond Mont Morenci and then actually we
could do a lot worse for New York State
and so where the most of the production
is is in Michigan State which they have
maybe an even more volatile Springtime
than we do some years um so again here's
an article from 2012 when I started at
Cornell and I wondered where we talk
about tart cherries where are all the
tart cherries well there was a frost
that year that killed um Michigan and
Geneva's tart
cherries um so beyond just like looking
at Bloom phology we can ask um assay
using differential thermal analysis that
um Jason Londo now at Cornell is a
specialist in and so we did um a
three-year evaluation of 64 tart cherry
accessions looking at its cold hearty
adaptation um acclamation and de
acclamation over time and we're excited
to like um finally summarize these
results and get them out but just some
initial graphs you can see that each
species and then within the species
there's variation for this trade which
again is going to hopefully help us
Target climate specific cultivars or if
there's a yeah a new region that wants
to expand their cherry production how it
could be
done um I I do like this image of tart
cherries because other crops have these
beautiful diversity displays is like
cherries kind of all really do look
pretty similar like there's not a whole
lot of like morphological or size
variation that exists currently so it's
maybe a gap for us to fill um but each
one of these like box plots represents a
different trait you can see total total
total soluble solids the sweetness right
or its acidity or its acid R acid sugar
um ratio and each one like Mont Moren is
kind of on the low end so low end for
sweetness but not bad for its um it's
sugar acid ratio which is actually more
important than the total content to
begin with it's just our perception of
how sweet or how acidic something is I
think this is what sets back our whole
industry is the weight of Mont Moren is
pretty good and it's like it's on the
late blooming so conversion of an
orchard or like adoption of a new
cultivar is going to be kind of hingent
like can we get the same fruit size the
same dependen like I don't know the same
quality from a new cultivar even though
if you look at the anthym profiles which
again is the new market for tart cherry
juice is like high Den High nutrient
density like it tends to be on the low
end for almost every
trait um so here's just an example um
we're kind of chromatography nerds in
our group so again sorry apologize for
the excessive use of chromatograms but
here's again the specific tart cherry
anthocyanin and then the Sweet Cherry
anoc in and again here's a sweet cherry
it's missing mostly this glucos Altin
aide compound and then you do see this
kind of interesting hybrid like ratio
split between the two um but again Mont
Mory kind of on the low end for the
content variability Aroma and so I get
really excited about flavor and Aroma uh
diversity within the collection so Ben's
alahh is the classic Cherry compound
that we associate with C candy it's also
can fool us to thinking something's
almond as well it's the same chemical
but here's like some Benz alahh results
and you can see Mt morenzi kind of on
the lowend you could really drive that
cherry flavor by using different um
diversity or for breeding purposes um
this one was an interesting hybrid
accession with another wild species and
it's it has this more common grape um
aromatic linol which kind of is more
Floral in flavor and almost missing Benz
alahh so you can kind of see as you
start to profile like where you could
push flavor in um in a breeding program
or even just using these as um direct to
market for yeah for an heirloom
production or for something else but so
LOL content really is exciting to me so
we have seed friends in Geneva that do a
lot of seed analysis so we can use their
equipment so here's a Marv um Marvin
seed analyzer you can throw Pits on and
a whole fruit because chairs are small
enough and get you know circularity so
we're not spending a a tremendous amount
of time kind of with calipers and doing
these individual measurements so it's
kind of a nice higher throughput genetic
markers are um invaluable but
challenging to like used for breeding
just because of the tetrol nature but
you can see a clear split between the
sweet cherries in red the tart cherries
in black and the the um progenitor
ficosa in greed here and some kind of
like interesting things that yeah are
happening in there I won't go too much
into that um kind of the Highlight
though of of my career I think so far
has been this discovery of Mount Vernon
the the home of George Washington right
um for the history Buffs in the room
right like this is
like one one of our founding fathers the
first president of the United States U
they found Cherry preserves during an
excavation of the basement there and
they found you know initially one bottle
we got a phone call because like they
thought they knew it was cherries from
the pit specimens and how do you ignore
that phone call right like we went down
immediately while they were discovering
bottles in the ground this is Tori and I
like there at the Dig the dig site and
they were like everyone was screaming
out oh we found a bottle of 27 it was
like kind of a thrilling Indiana Jones
moment right are we going to unleash
some curse or like I don't know some
interesting Horticultural artifact but
so Tori and I actually have the the
privilege and honor now to be sifting
through the contents of those bottles
pulling out pit samples which we can
compare to Modern pits and look at like
because again the pit seam and the pit
shape all kind of is indicative of a
cultivar here's some stem fragments
which like that's amazing preservation
for about 250 year years old here's kind
of like a bottom like or a top down view
of one of the bottles which again it's
like some of the fruit is still intact
and exciting um we've isolated DNA from
them to compare to a reference library
and it's yeah super exciting um to to be
able to kind of bring to light again one
of like this is a a huge American story
that we get to be part of the
telling so here is moving on to Grape
and grape is interesting because it's
split between two sites so we have a
tale of two collections one in Davis
California one in Geneva I don't know
where you'd rather be today but I don't
know California seems pretty nice minus
the horrible fires but um so primarily
um Vena or the historic European wine
grapes table grapes in California and we
specialize in cold hearty hybrids which
again it's like we we call it the cold
hearty grape collection but it's so much
more than that like um disease
resistance and flavor is what um we
really should be promoting um so we're
doing a a large profiling of about 350
vanifer accessions and about a 100 plus
um hybrid accessions from Geneva to look
at like anthocyan profiles which are
huge for again nutritional content but
now wine and table grape Industries um
these are just a few of the like
interesting profiles that come out like
so these are all run with the same
analysis you can see some anthos in Rich
some really anthos in poor accessions in
um in melon versus royalty and the
classic Mero right kind of like you know
in Middle Ground there this is Papa
Smurf um so this is yeah it's our our
Workhorse um lcms in the lab
there um so again when we look at total
um karic acid which is important acid in
in wine we see again some extreme with
Mero being on the the really low end and
some really um interesting cultivars or
accessions on the highend which some
studies are showing karic acid
associated with other um physiological
traits like maybe drought tolerance and
some other things which will be kind of
interesting to compare this is with
fruit but how do you what does what do
leaves look like as well um again
anthocyanins the color of of your wine
is so important not just for like antoin
but for the marketing we Low's kind of
again on the middle to low end not of
the box plot but we do have some really
extreme high antoin cultivars and and
again these are just some interesting
stats from some uh from our diversity
evaluation so one one cultiv our royalty
had 30 individual antoin any we talk
about like how do we diversify the human
diet right like so anthos in rich foods
but anthos in diverse Foods as well are
play a major role in
that um we do solidphase micro
extraction or spey which um we're using
a method developed by Gavin saxs the
famous um wine food scientist here in
Cornell itha and it's super yeah super
low input platform that gives us a lot
of really powerful results so again
here's our conquer our foxy Aroma um so
we're able to all these purple compounds
are ones that are heavily associated
with the foxy um Aroma and grape and so
we can profile that and Muscat I
mentioned the linol so muskat grapes
have just such a distinctive and lovely
Aroma um like a French perfume I don't
know how else to describe them but but
better but sweeter you don't want to
drink French perfume maybe but these
grapes really like have such a
fascinating flavor um mostly from linol
and other monot turpins so again I
that's why I'm really excited about our
tart cherry that has more of a a Muscat
grape
profile and and here if we're looking at
linol diversity this one accession is
really on the high end um July muskat
for this narl compound another similar
or musat Associated compound um one of
the challenges is like the name so we
have the cold heart grape collection
which is more than cold hearty full of
hybrid grapes which could be anything it
could be um domestic to a wild or wild
to Wild inter specific but it's kind of
it's just this non-descript term that
really makes it hard to to Leverage The
Power of the collection so here we have
um Stout seedless which is 90% Vena and
Napa which is 10% Vena and grin in our
database they're both called hybrid so
pulling out that information really
limits right like if you're searching
just by taxonomy alone so um we did
ancestry estimations using PCA principal
component analysis and you can give a
percentage to how much of one particular
ancestor um contributed to one or
another so we have now um kind of a
continuous variation of from 0% hybrid
to or 0% Vena to 100% benifer in the
collection so at least that like
classification helps bring to light some
of the cultivars that we can use
um and these are just I always have to
highlight this because um Peter cousins
who was a longtime breeder for the usca
now at Gallow um has developed these
cultivars from hybrid grapes in Geneva
so like high disease resistance really
interesting environmental adaptation but
also amazing fruit quality as well so it
kind of proof that you can take
something hybrid with a wild background
and bring it into a more cultivated and
not just serving New York industry but
California Industries as well well um
kind of the heart of the collection this
is what I spent my PhD studying is the
apple collection and working with Susan
Brown um the Apple breeder here at
Cornell um but we've got you know
several thousand accessions and we talk
about an apple a day this is almost you
know 15 years of apples a day if you
were to try one accession every day so
kind of endless Joy right if you're
looking for that Wonka Everlasting
Gobstopper like you can just spend years
searching the collection looking for
that um this is kind of showing our
fingerprint of or footprint of
distribution like we've really touched a
lot of the major Apple production World
um in the world which is kind of cool
like so these are accessions that landed
somewhere internationally or not and
Apple has an interesting domestication
because we talk through grafting this
instant domestication but um Apple
itself is a hybrid between two species
and the story has been retold and told
so many times every time I want to gloss
over it though someone maybe Marvin in a
tour like oh no you got to tell the
story and have to go back and and and
highlight that but so really trading
apples out of Kazakhstan through Europe
where at hybridized with a different
Apple so we get this interspecific
nature to Apple which makes it
interesting any guesses on which is the
domesticated which is the wild
row top middle bottom what do you guys
thinkle no middle yeah you're actually
right so that's the malice sarii
Representatives that we have in the
collection To Go
Hannah and so this story really was was
famous here's jaro fio I love this
picture of him and the the first curator
for Apple Phil forsland so they got the
helicopter in to Kazakhstan how cool is
this right like like I'm talking Indiana
Jones level like just going into a
basement and looking at Old bottles and
stuff like they actually got a
helicopter in and collect fruit from the
wild which is really cool and was
popularized by Michael pollen the
botania of Desire um so this is showing
over time the growth the apple
collection you can see starting with a
large donation from Cornell um the
breeding program a lot of wild material
and then huge amounts of malice of ACI
the wild progenitor of Apple coming in
in the 90s and over time it kind of has
like slowed down to like being more
targeted for wild
species um but the story really wasn't
done being told until we had strong
genetic background and genetic data um
because what we thought was pure malice
to verci so we brought back maybe 383
sessions into the collection 151 only
were pure what we considered pure
species pure malice um cersi 215 were
admix we have a hybrid um population and
then 17 were pure domestica in the
forest of kha'zix stand and again
explain how that can happen it's kind of
amazing right so apples get around and
they're they're welld designed even
through propagation to to propagate
themselves and just be planted where
maybe they shouldn't be planted but this
is kind of highlighting the the really I
don't know the stress and strain of like
collecting wild Apple today and not
waiting right because if there's an
apple orchard down the road that pollen
is going to add mix into a wild
population and over the course of you
know a few decades who knows what will
be left of that so the genetics are
secure with apple the the purity of a
species if that's a a high a primary
concern is is yeah it's kind of a
nightmare um what's so cool about our
story s i those all of this came out
that it was still a mystery of who was
the wild progenitor of apple and it was
germplasm found by the USDA and brought
here that has been now distributed to
Europe back to Kazakhstan for
repatriation and it was like really that
initial effort to conserve malari that
gave us so much scientific information
so it's kind of yeah it's a it's a huge
win for our our our unit and the the
legacy of Phil forsland and those um BB
aldwin you have to mention him as well
um so again when we look at genetic
diversity though within the collection
we see a lot of clones because a lot of
things have names and the names Chang
and so we bring it in not knowing that
it's actually identical sometimes the
Clones are like take up space but
sometimes they're really useful because
you might have um just single mutation
sports that like maybe it's Golden
Delicious with a new novel trait added
and that kind of is exciting for
breeding because otherwise these These
cultivars are stuck without any kind of
mutation just because they're yeah
they're they're fixed in time through
through colonal
propagation of course I have to show
more chromatograms you thought I was
done um but this is licorice flavor
estral and so apples most people don't
have this familiarity with apples but if
you go to an or Orchard late in the
season and harvest even a a Golden
Delicious you'll get a a bright licorice
flavor or maybe it's dark depending on
if you hate dark or if you hate licorice
but it's it's it's a fascinating flavor
and I think it adds to the diversity and
what what consumers want in that novelty
I think the red flesh apples maybe had
their moment and it's not that exciting
anymore because it didn't really bring a
lot of interesting um flavor or
interesting I don't know we love that
element of surprise and just red flesh
wears off pretty easily um but flavor I
think is kind of an I think a powerful
Target for for modern Apple breeding
alha Farine um is kind of associated
with some um some disorders in post
Harvest and you can talk to Chris
Watkins about all of those but um honey
crisp is one of the the major I don't
know the troublemakers with some post
Harvest disorders like um scald and
Alpha Farine is associated but I don't
know if it's really clearly um
demonstrate how it is but this
particular R is really high um it's got
some estral but you know low in this
particular
sample I have to leave with some life
advice so wherever you go maybe you
don't care maybe you've tuned out Apple
grape and tart cherry this whole time
maybe your thing is carrots I don't know
or berries if Mar um but like just
whatever trait whatever crop you're
working on just consider the germplasm
like so many studies that I read from a
curatorial or Gene Bank perspective like
fall short of what they could be had the
authors more carefully considered what
diversity that they were including in a
study and again you can make huge
progress and just the scientific
discoveries like Limitless when you're
like really working with a strong um
genetic Foundation but please like don't
forget like the silliness and the joy of
what we do like there's a reason we're
not in agriculture and maybe growing
wheat right like there's a reason we
picked horiculture as opposed to I don't
know running a combine 247 like there's
a joy in what we can bring in new fruit
flavors and diversity to the world um
please come see us like the Apple T
apple and grape tour is in the fall
usually associated with the plant
breeding tour if you're um within that
group um and then the tarte Cherry tour
is maybe mid July we picked a firm date
and then all the cherries ripened before
that date and so stay tuned for maybe a
more updated like tour date for the the
tarte cherries have to acknowledge yeah
wonderful colleagues at Cornell
fantastic team with the USDA and I will
leave the some time for
questions I have a question yeah so you
said M Mor has been around like 400
years and so the industry's really
locked into that R so if you did come up
with something was even better maybe
they already have would the industry
adopt it or are they so stuck on moity
that they're just not going to change
yeah talk to amyone who was
the yeah so Marvin's question was like
okay Mont moren's old news there's may
be something interesting what's the the
likelihood for an industry to adopt that
and I think Amy aone at Michigan State
University along time breeder for root
stocks and advocate for new tarte
cherries like had some success in in
getting Balaton and other kind of
heirloom land race cultivars into
production um but yeah just strong
resistance and I I don't know again if
if there's just the risk of it's already
such a small industry and like the the
extra effort to go to a new cultivar is
just is not worth that to them I think
it just needs maybe a few more crop
failures through Frost damage right and
because that's that that's an easy one
to overcome with with some of the
diversity that we have already and just
Bloom late just bloom a week later and
you you've saved yourself an entire loss
so yeah I I don't know I don't know what
holds back industry from that
Chris uh just out of curiosity a little
while ago we were had an email exchange
about the apples of New York volume one
volume two uh how many of those apples
have been saved or has the majority of
them they lost the history yeah so how
many so Chris is referencing that and
maybe you shouldn't broadcast this that
you have the apples of New York books
volume one and two which again careful
there are no break-ins but these are
yeah so these are Hedrick um so in the
early 1900s published these apples of
New York's book and I don't even know
I've never seen one I've never like look
through it to see like how many are in
there and how many like would CR
reference back to the collection but
it's been reported that there are you
know tens of thousands of Apple
cultivars that have been named that were
at one time in the world right and
whether those were synonyms pseudonyms
right like same name but yeah or like
how many yeah how many of those actually
exist today in the collection is that's
kind of hard to to figure out yeah and
we don't necessarily want all of them so
right now we're like we had that hit
that acquisition phase and we filled the
the acreage pretty quickly and now it's
really targeted like we want proof that
it's something really interesting
genetically or culturally important or a
wild accession that deserves that spot
otherwise yeah we're happy to work with
Partners like Seed Savers or other
Heritage groups to conserve those
because there is a quite an heirloom
hobby Enthusiast group for Apple that's
out there chasing them and you'll read
about it in the news the Lost Apple
groups
and yeah
like for especially for something like
apple where the center of origin is
overseas like the sort of you can't just
like for germ plasm you can't like shove
seeds in your pocket not that you should
do that anyways but like you obviously
is it sort of like a like a uh through
University like researchers you exchange
things do are there similar germ plasm
collections yeah overseas is there like
a diplomacy thing yeah so there there
are international treaties that we're a
part of that like allow for that
exchange through um a shared material
transfer agreement so everything's again
above board we're not going in and and
taking anything that doesn't belong to
us right like making sure that countries
that have the germ plasa maintain that
that ownership of it with apple and with
grape and tart cherry it's it's
challenging because of viruses to import
and so we do have like aphis the animal
plant health inspection service like has
a quarantine site that specializes as in
in Palm fruits and stone fruits and so
it can go through there we actually from
those 90s Explorations there's still a
malice sersi in quarantine that still
has viruses that like just will not get
cleaned up right so this is like 30
years now in quarantine um the pipeline
now with like genetic tools and like
screening for viruses can can streamline
that a little bit so you can get it
quicker but yeah so the pro process for
importation is a
challenge yeah well I was going to say
when you get a chance to check with Gen
see if
Geneva let's see oh so Ira who's a new
um postto with the grape genetics
Research Unit asks about PCA ancestry
for grape and I'm not sure if it works
for different Ploy I mean I assume that
it would like we're able to capture that
and intelligibly like I know just
looking at the principal component
analysis say that like these results
match what we know about these
accessions but maybe there's some flaw
in doing the quantification well chat
Ira that's a good
question I may have interrupted question
that was felt to be
asked bill can I ask a question
hello yes yeah this very smart uh great
great talk Ben just a very quick
question I saw you have a 20K snip chip
I'm just curious all the genotyping that
you've done on Apple for example was is
that based on a snip array or what what
are your favorite genotyping
methods yeah so um the snip aray is
phasing out and it was um developed for
commercial apples or domesticated apples
so it falls short for us and when you
start looking at hybrids or wild we've
used a lot so my um experience has been
more with genotyping by sequencing which
again is a is a every platform is flawed
but this one at least can account for
different genomes and it's um it's
updatable so as new genome references
come out or you have a new wild
accession that you don't know where it
fits that's been really helpful in kind
of elucidating relationships um
collaborators now are just going for
full genome sequencing and so that'll
probably be the future but I think um
disentangling the pedigrees of Apple the
snip array and just its reliability for
the domesticated has been really helpful
for that that data set
I'm supposing what you distribute from
the center varies right in some cases it
might be seeds in other cases it could
be
wood yeah so um what do we distribute
it's primarily Canan wood because people
want to propagate an accession but
pollen as well or fruit samples for um
yeah different studies seeds not so much
unless they're for wild just because
yeah people want to to maintain that
genetic Integrity of their accession
seeds are nice because well in theory we
can trade them more easily because of
virus issues but I know some recent
research at Cornell agretech has kind of
made us questioned that whether it's
truly virus free through
seed anything
else this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu