hello and welcome to the final webinar
in a series of
13 on Berry crop nutrition and soil
management these webinars were developed
for training egg Educators and
Commercial Berry Growers the webinars
were recorded as part of a 2 Northeast s
professional development project led by
Dr Marvin pritz small fruit
horticulturist and Berry crop nutrition
specialist at Cornell
University the speakers for this week's
webinar are Mr Jeff Miller Association
issue leader from Cornell Cooperative
Extension in Ida County Laura mcdermit
extension associate with the capitol
District vegetable and small fruit
program from Cornell
University and uh your host myself Kathy
henrike I'm extension specialist with
Cornell University in the department of
horiculture the agenda for this week's
webinar apart from the introduction of
speakers which we've already done is the
presentation and the topics of the
presentation will include an
introduction to Berry soil and nutrient
management discussion of the basic soil
test pH modification and testing uh the
Cornell soil Health test and tissue
analysis if you'd like to listen to the
other recorded webinars in the series
you may do so by going to the link
below Down Below in the files box you
will see uh there are several files that
you can download the berry soil and
nutrient management revision two is a um
PDF of this presentation there's a
grower pre and post test you can take to
test your knowledge before and after the
presentation there's uh a chart that
gives you the uh desired ranges for
foler analysis for strawberries
blueberries and raspberries and then the
submission forms for the standard
Cornell soil Health test form I'm sorry
the standard tissue test form P or the
Cornell soil Health test down below also
listed over in the web links box is
again the link for the recorded Berry
soil and nutrient management webinars
and the Cornell fruit resources Berry
pages and without further Ado we will
move to the present ation screen and
Jeff we're ready for you
now thanks
Kathy I'm going to take a couple minutes
in the beginning part of this
presentation to talk to you a little bit
about soil testing uh soil
sampling and we'll start off
uh talking to you a little bit about
soil and tissue testing it's it's pretty
hard to manage a crop unless you have
some pieces of information to help you
manage that crop and that's really where
soil sampling soil testing and tissue
testing come in
um there's definitely two main time
frames that uh we talk about when we
talk about uh sampling and that's
pre-plant so if you're planting an exp
expensive crop like raspberries or
blueberries and you want to prepare uh
the soil beforehand so that you have the
least amount of obstacles and the most
Optimum conditions for those expensive
crops is a great opportunity to take
soil
tests um and get analyses back and have
time to actually make some adjustments
and for these crops one of the major
things that you have to think about is
uh things like soil drainage as a
possibility getting irrigation to the
site as a second possibility but really
what we're talking about today is uh the
fertility management and one of the
things that you can change is pH if you
plan on doing a blueberry planting you
know that you want to get the PH down
into the uh fours at least mid fours and
if you do not do a soil pH test in
advance of the planting then you're
probably not going to have enough time
to modify that pH
and have it down in the range that's
optimal for that crop and the same would
be true in acid soils and bringing them
up to six or 65 depending on whether
you're going to go with raspberries or
strawberries so it's a real opportune
time to take those
samples uh another time to think about
soil sampling is after the planting is
already in and this is the case where
you're talking about maintaining a
viable stand at Optimal Performance and
taking samples of soil uh running them
through a lab and getting an analysis
back and and then making sure that
there's no um maor major shortages of
any important nutrients and if there are
uh making sure that you're applying
those nutrients in adequate quantities
to optimize both crop yield and
quality a last thing that Growers should
consider is protecting the
environment so if you look at it and you
say to the average grower how much do
you play how much do you apply and do
you do soil testing there's often enough
times where you hear the answer I I
don't really do an awful lot of soil
sampling but I make sure uh that I never
short the crop so that means that
there's a possibility that there's over
fertilization going on and that can be
very costly and depending on the
nutrient that could have some
environmental ramifications as
well now just talking you about the the
basic uh types of testing uh the
standard soil test which is a chemical
analysis uh the cornal soil heal Health
test and tissue analysis if you look at
a standard soil test um it's it's
something that's conducted at many Labs
across the states and the attempt is to
measure the availability of of essential
nutrients for
plants so each lab has their own setup
um their own
procedures um their own uh materials
used to leech out nutrients and and
measurements taken on the quantity of
those nutrients that are then reported
back to the
Growers um in in New York State uh
Cornell has done an awful lot of field
research and done some tests to look at
what is in the soil and application
rates and the response application rates
given
uh different soil levels of those
nutrients uh so that's the basic
chemical analysis that people would get
reports back interpret them and and
adjust their fertility and pH
accordingly the Cornell soil Health test
is a unique test looking at some of the
other attributes of the soil and that's
the biological aspects and the physical
aspects of the soil and how they impact
plant growth and development and Laura
is going to be talking to you about that
a little bit later in this presentation
and then finally tissue
analysis uh this is a great uh way to
measure what actually the plant is
seeing in the way of nutrients if you do
soil tests you can see oh well this is
what we have in the soil but the tissue
analysis tells you what the plant is
taking up from the soil and Kathy is
going to talk to you a little bit more
about that
later there's two basic times that you
would look at testing one
is the routine measurements you know if
you have an established planting you
take samples every 3 years you look at
the results you make some minor
modifications uh adding phosphorus when
it's needed or uh modifying the pH if
it's needed either down or up depending
upon the crop Andor if you have a
situation where you have no history of a
site at all and you plan on putting a
planting of uh perennial Berry like
blueberry into an area it's great
opportunity to do that soil test at that
time that's more of the routine types of
tests that are
conducted uh there's definitely um a
chance to use soil testing and fer
analysis to do diagnostic work when
plants are not doing as well as you
think they should uh and it's just one
piece of the in of of information that
you can use to help come up with answers
uh for local Growers to actually
identify what the problem is on the site
and usually this is done with doing some
paired sampling so taking a series of
samples in an area that is just not
performing up to par and then comparing
them with at least the results of those
chemical analyses with an area of the
field where you have reasonable
performance um in these situations
adding soluble salts as an analysis is
probably an important thing to do and
using plant tissue analysis just gives
you that additional piece of information
that you can use in in a answering a
battery of questions and narrowing down
the field to the the
problem now it's important to to look at
how you'd want to obtain a
sample uh in the case of
uh the
identification you can see that in by
the Green Arrow there's an area of uh
sweet corn in this case that's not
performing very well and yet uh a
majority of the rest of the planting is
doing very well this is an opportunity
to take some samples to identify what
the problem might be so in sampling
these areas you'd want to take a series
of samples from the area that's not
performing well and you should take a
minimum of eight uh
subsamples that are then mixed together
as a single sample from both the problem
area as well as the area that's more
representative of good performance so
that's one sampling strategy another
important uh thing to consider when
you're uh sampling is actually to sample
by management unit so you can picture
your farm and you can picture block
planting of that farm over time you
would want to First Look at the soil
types that are underneath these
plantings and if there are major changes
in soil type to actually sample within
those soil types because there can be
very big differences in their ability to
hold on to nutrients the amount of lime
or sulfur that's needed to change the pH
depending on the texture differences
between those soil types so that's the
starting point but beyond that you may
have a planting of strawberries that's
newly planted and that should be sampled
uh separately than plantings that are
two and three years old and even within
those plantings maybe have different
varieties planted you should be
considering them as management units and
doing sampling separately for those
management units and then using it as a
diagnostic tool is is yet the other
method
so talking about a a sampling of soils
for chemical
analysis um there are different labs
they use various extractants to estimate
how much plant available nutrients are
in that
sample um and yes the values that you
can get from the same sample can be very
different from different
labs and the important thing to take
home out of that is not to take values
from one lab results and try to uh make
recommendations using another lab's
information so in in New York state the
recommendation is to go with Cornell
soil sample analysis and that is being
conducted by a private firm Dair
1 uh because then you get the power of
the university and all the trials that
are conducted and the information
gleaned from those trials and the
recommendations that come from those
trials so Agra one is the place to go in
New York
State uh mainly because you get the
benefit of the Cornell recommendations
which are based on Research
results there are a certain set of
sampling tools that can be used in a
obtaining soil samples uh in the upper
right you can see series of those tools
um you have an
orur uh soil probe head um and you can
see that they're made from stainless
steel one of the one of the important
things to avoid is contamination of the
sample so if you use you know steel
shovels um Spades to obtain the sample
and they haven't been cared for and
there's some rust on them that can
actually contaminate the sample another
thing to think about when you're taking
a sample is you're trying to be as
representative of the situation as
possible it is just a sample from the
field so getting to the same depth
consistently making sure you have have
the same volume of soil that's obtained
at each site and then mixing each one of
the subsamples to come up with a
composite for an entire area all those
things uh give you good information if
you got too much sample from one site
and uh Not Enough From Another now
you're actually weighing the sample
results and if you don't have sufficient
numbers of samples you can definitely
have some errors in the information that
you're going to get from the sample
results uh another thing to consider is
to make sure that you're using a plastic
bucket you know some buckets are made
from zinc and zinc can contaminate the
sample as well and the third thing is
make sure that you're using the
appropriate forms and appropriate
procedures in uh putting together the
sample uh to send it off to the
lab now looking a little more closely at
the soil probe this is a favorite among
a lot of people and the reason why it's
a favorite is you have this tube uh
that's attached to a t you can press
this into a soil get a nice core sample
to the depth that you're uh that you
want to go to clear this tube and then
move on to your next site so under good
conditions so that's not too wet not too
dry and definitely not Rocky or grally
um you can do this uh very
quickly uh and so a lot of people use
this particular device to uptain samples
I will say one of the things that I do
is whatever depth uh I'm going to
for a specific crop I'll measure it
right on the probe and then I'll put a
piece of electrical tape around the tube
at that height so that I consistently go
to that same
level looking at the orur the orur is a
great tool under Rocky and wet
conditions if it's too wet and you use
the soil probe anybody that's done this
you press it in the ground you pull it
back up and only half the tube is
actually filled because you actually
compressed the soil when it was wet and
and you didn't get a full tube worth of
sample uh so under wetter conditions the
soil actually adheres to the augur and
you just run your hand down the augur to
clear that and you've got a reasonable
sample the same thing can be done with
the augur where you measure uh let's say
8 in from the
tip uh to the top and make sure and put
your electrical tape there and then you
know that you're going to that depth
consistently another benefit of the ogre
is that you can actually set them up so
that you can put them on a power drill
if you're doing a lot of samples and
some
uh thought has gone into this where
people have cut a hole inside a
container like a bucket a plastic bucket
and actually run the orar right through
the bucket through the hole into the
soil and bring it back up and they clear
it right there and the samples trapped
in the
bucket so pretty efficient way of
sampling as was mentioned before you
definitely want to uh take at least a
minimum number of samples to get a good
representation of Any Given area another
thing that you should consider is never
do uh sampling in let's say straight
lines why is that because a lot of times
we are uh running in straight lines up
and down Fields with our equipment with
fertilizer uh and planting maybe doing
drainage work and if you sample over
that same uh area consistently across
the field you actually are not
representing all the rest of the area
and you may actually be tainting the
results so usually the recommendation is
to Zig and zag across an area to obtain
a sample so that you're getting a good
representation of the entire area
to start sampling you always remove uh
the organic debris that's at the surface
because that will uh change the
results uh you make sure that you know
the depth at which you should be
sampling for the crop that you're
actually sampling for and it would
definitely be different depths for tree
fruits versus small fruits versus things
like field crops um and turf grass so
make sure that you know the depth for
the crop that you're actually sampling
for um you should definitely take 8 to
10 sub samples at a minimum in an area
anything less than two acres and
anything greater than two acres you
should have 10 to 20 subsamples as a
minimum uh in larger acreages you want
at least a minimum of three subsamples
per
acre uh
for uh sampling for berries uh both
pre-plant and uh established plantings
you want to go down to 8 in depth
um and then in established plantings you
want to pair up the soil sample results
with tissue analysis and Cathy will talk
to you a little bit more about that
later uh additional guidelines remember
to remove that organic mat uh to go to
the depth that's uh
recommended uh taking each subsample
putting it into the plastic bucket uh at
the end of sampling a particular area
mix well uh because now that uh is going
to represent that area and then you
subsample from it to get your sample to
send off to the lab if the sample is uh
too wet then put it on something like a
plastic plate uh put a fan on it to air
dry it avoid using any kind of heat
Source because that can definitely skew
the results especially
nitrogen uh and then make sure that you
put it in the appropriate container for
the lab that you're sending it to and
make sure that you're forms are
completely filled out because they use
that information in making the
recommendations uh in New York state
they have mapped the soils out they've
actually done it in the whole us but
they use the soil
names uh in New York state um to provide
information about uh yield capacity of
the site and some of the physical
attributes of the soil and its ability
to hold on to nutrients so it's
important to to put the soil series name
on the
form uh indicating for the area that
you're sampling for your crop because
that is a valuable piece of information
that adds into the recommendation in
fact you won't get a recommendation
without having that information on the
form um uh so you can go online and use
web soil survey. nrcs uh. usda.gov
and uh get the soil survey uh for your
farm and then specifically get down to
the field level and indicate what soil
series name is most predominant in the
field or the area that you're intending
to
sample uh there's actually an iPhone app
um and you can uh get this from this
presentation and actually use that to
find the soil name for your particular
location uh Andor if if you don't want
to go either of those routes you can go
to corporative Extension Office often
they have copies of uh the same
materials and can help you to identify
the soil name for your
field uh interpreting the results uh can
be challenging um if you go to an outof
State lab they might send you results
back uh just indicating the pounds of
particular nutrients that are tested in
the sample and no recommendation s um
and that's why it's important to really
use the the lab that's in your state
that uh is associated with um a local
land grant institution and can provide
recommendations just a simple thing like
checking your soil PH uh you definitely
have to have the information ahead of
time that if you're growing strawberries
or raspberries that the pH that is
recommended that's optimal for those
crops is between 6.2 and 6.5 versus
blueberries uh much lower at 4.2 to
4.5 you look at the results and say okay
are my macronutrients uh do they fall
into the medium range or above and if
not then I need to make some adjustments
in that here's the recommendation on the
soil sample results uh what's your soil
organic matter content uh for most Berry
crops it's recommended to have 3% or
higher and again this is one of those
things if you test the site beforehand
you have a chance to build up organic
matter levels if you need to uh the
calcium levels are very important for
blueberry production and the
recommendation is when you're looking at
a Cornell soil test results through Agro
one that uh calcium be below 2,000
lounds per acre and aluminum can be
toxic at higher levels so if you see a
reading of 300 lbs of aluminum in your
sample per acre uh then this is a
situation that you're going to have to
correct very quickly uh and that can
occur more and will occur more under
acid soils and definitely there's a
recommendation not to use any kind of
aluminum based
fertilizers so just a a quick word about
soil PH if you look at this graph it's
it's one that probably you've seen
before that indicates the availability
of uh some major uh necessary nutrients
for your plant growth and development um
and it just shows the The Wider the band
The more available those nutrients are
so you can see that in the PH range of
let's say six to 7 you find that most
nutrients have a high availability as
you go towards strongly acid the
availability of many nutrients falls off
and that can affect the performance of
your plants or if the pH gets driven way
up you can have that same situation at
least for a series of these nutrients
that are necessary for crop growth and
development so it's very important for
you to understand that relationship and
how important it is to have the pH um in
the soil at an optimal level for the
crop that you're growing
uh when you're modifying uh soil soil PH
one of the things that you should be
aware of is that it isn't instantaneous
you can't just apply lime to increase
the pH or sulfur to decrease the pH one
day and have the pH Changed by the next
day in fact it's a long-term process and
takes from six months to nine months to
occur um so this is better that you
pre-plan uh do the testing
beforehand uh make adjustments in the in
PH through these
applications and do that nine months or
more in advance of actually planting the
intended
crop and if you want more information on
this you can go to the production guide
for Berry crops put out by n rce
this is what you might expect this is
what you would get from dairy 1
uh as far as uh a results form and you
can see that they have a nice graphic in
the upper right which shows you very low
low medium high and very high levels of
some of your major
macronutrients and you can see for
instance that phosphorus is uh in the
low medium level and probably would need
to be built up with additional
applications uh potassium is already
high so pretty
reasonable calcium we talked about that
2,000 lounds of calcium uh per acre
being an indicator of uh uh at least
above that being a problem for Blu Ray
production um pH uh 6.1 and looking at
strawberries as the intended crop we're
you know close to the range that's
recommended and then organic matter we
talked about the fact that you wanted 3%
or more and in this case you have
4.6% aluminum we said that you had to
have 300 lb per acre or more to have
problems with toxicity from aluminum and
it looks like we're okay in this
case uh nitrogen recommendations from
this
sample uh 100 pounds of nitrogen total
to be split 80 lbs in July 20 lbs in the
following September and then 25 lbs of
phosphorus fertilizer at
planting and when it comes to uh
bringing those nutrient levels up to
recommended levels it's it's really the
same the the soil test results will tell
you okay you need so many pounds of uh
p25 or k2o poach or phosphorus nitrogen
and really it's when you talk about
organic versus conventional it's just
the source that you're changing so the
percentage of nutrients found in organic
fertilizers is usually lower than those
found in uh conventional
fertilizers but if you're told to put on
30 lbs of
nitrogen uh then you just have to put on
more material uh the organic uh type of
fertilizer to achieve the same 30 pounds
of nitrogen contribution to that crop
and you have two really really really
good guides the organic strawberry and
organic blueberry production guides to
help you uh find sources of
fertilizers and you know bring those uh
uh soils up to spec for uh optimal
production of those crops and with that
I think I'm going to be turning this
over to
Laura uh for further discussion about
the Cornell soil Health
test all right thank you Jeff um so we
talked a little bit about one aspect of
the cornal soil Health test which was
the chemical evaluation of the soil but
a higher level of testing involves
evaluation of biological and physical
properties of the soil in addition to
the chemical ones that Jeff um explained
and those are measured in the S standard
soil nutrient test um all three of the
components biological physical and
chemical um are interact to provide
conditions that could lead to Optimal
plant
performance chemical properties are the
most understood and they're the easiest
to modify of those three but we can also
influence soil physical and biological
properties to in to enance plant
performance and that's why um the soil
Health test is so valuable because it
gives us some idea of what some of those
constraints might be so this is um a
slide that explains a little bit the
Cornell soil Health test was developed
by the Cornell nutrient analysis lab and
there's um a whole team of folks that
work on uh soil Health at Cornell uh not
just erronous but um
uh
horticulturists uh soil scientists Etc
and they came up with um the Cornell uh
soil Health assessment training manual
which is right here you can order this
online it's
downloadable um and it's very helpful
for folks that are just beginning to
understand what soil Health could mean
uh this is the address and the website
uh that you can get more information
about this process and and there's basic
packages and standard packages and the
basic is really for uh grain and forage
crops um and other non-agricultural
applications uh especially used for
landscaping and site remediation but for
us with specialty crops um the standard
package is what we are recommending that
you get and um this is used a lot in
vegetable production organic producers
uh are very interested in this um
information some problem diagnosis again
in landscaping and urban
applications and for for Berry crop
Growers and tree Fruit Growers uh any
especially perennial um plant Growers
the best time for us to take advantage
of what the soil Health test can offer
is for first time soil Health
assessment so soil health is the
capacity of the soil to function
chemically biologically and physically
and that's what we're going to explore a
little bit and that's what the soil
Health test will um make sure that that
folks understand so characteristics of
healthy soils include good tilth
sufficient but not excessive amounts of
nutrients um a sufficient rooting
depth a healthy soil has good water
storage and also excellent drainage
those are very important in Berry Crop
Production
um it is free of chemicals that might
harm plants and has relatively low
populations of plant disease and
parasitic organisms but High populations
of beneficial
organisms healthy soil has um lower weed
pressure um and it is has some
resistance to being
degraded and all of these um help it
become more resilient so it's actually
quick it has a capacity to recover
quickly from Adverse Events and those
are characteristics of healthy
soil some characteristics or signs of
poor soil Health include um when you
plow up clot soil and you have poor seed
beds those are signs that you might have
uh poor soil you might have hard soil at
planting uh it it tends to um kind of
get that uh surface soil
hardness on it which is a real
problem um there could be rapid onset or
of stress or stunted growth during dry
or wet periods that's a sign of
unhealthy and poor soil and it can also
have poor growth the Vigor on the plants
is just not great at all you might see
in poor soil declining yields that
actually is one of the biggest tip offs
to Growers that there's something
happening their yield just keep keep
going down regardless of how much
fertilizer or uh organic matter they
might be
adding and that this also can exacerbate
High disease pressure when you get uh
poor Vigor a lot of times diseases take
advantage of that and then that you
might see signs of runoff and erosion so
those are are pretty obvious poor soil
signs um so some of the interactions and
this is what um the soil Health test
will help delineate or help make obvious
is some of the things that they will
indicate to you will have
interaction and so uh hard soil reduces
rooting but why why is that happen it
could be compacted dense soil layers
restrict rooting volume um and then it's
not the plants are not able to exploit
water and nutrients the way they should
be compacted soil can also supress
beneficial biological processes and so
you see in blue um is the physical
attribute and then in green nutrients
and root diseases and denitrification
all are chemical aspects and and the
yellow is the biological so Poe drainage
reduces rooting and aerobic biological
processes and then the compaction which
a hard soil um often you you have
compaction that will increase root
diseases and denitrification losses so
that's an example of all three of the
characteristics the soil characteristics
having an interaction um around hard
soil so some of the things that the
Cornell soil Health test will do is that
there's a battery of tests that uh are
employed and um some of these are done
in the soil Health the photos of The
Suite of
analyses um the soil physical tests in
are in the blue across the top these are
all laborator laboratory tests except
the field penetration test and we'll
talk about using that soil
penetrometer um a little bit later and
then the biological tests are in green
across the bottom the soil Health uh lab
uses a modified Morgan
extraction um solution to determine soil
nutrient levels and then the soil
texture determination is also used to
cat categorize test
results Cornell soil heal Health test
guidelines and this is just some things
that you'll need in in the field
basically I find that it's easier for me
to take this test if I have an assistant
somebody to help carry some of the gear
but if you're alone you'll definitely
need two um 5 gallon buckets and one of
them would be for soil We Gather much
more soil in this particular test than
you do for a chemical soil analysis you
want a large 1gallon Ziploc bag to uh
put all of the soil sample in at the end
of the uh Gathering it you'll want a 600
mil or plastic Beaker a 3 cup capacity
you'll want a permanent marker and
Pen I use a trow or a spade and I
actually use a larger kind of a tree
spade type thing and uh that helps a lot
to gather that soil you want a a soil
penetrometer um a grower and field
information sheet and a clipboard uh to
hold that information on and so this um
right here uh is an example of that um
soil Health uh field information sheet
that you'll be filling out
so these are rather important guidelines
and the sampling will be done roughly in
the same manner for the standard
chemical soil like the nutrient soil
test with some of these
exceptions you want to sample the soil
in the spring when the soil is at Field
capacity so that means that it needs to
have enough soil moisture to be um
tillable but it can't be
saturated and that is a that was a
difficult thing this spring um we had
such a dry April it was difficult to get
uh any kind of fi capacity in most soils
so and then it started raining like
crazy so it makes it it hard the soil
Health test should ideally be done
before tillage
occurs um and sometimes that's not an
issue in a perennial crop because we
don't do a lot of tillage but uh you do
want to be aware of that also you want
to have these soil Health test um
samples gathered
before uh the end of June because the
lab stops analyzing um the samples
sometime in July so try to make the end
of June uh being your kind of cut off
date if
possible you want to use a troll or a
spay to sample soil as a larger volume
of soil is required for this test again
I use kind of a tree spade um so that's
uh allows me to gather kind of a nice
sample on that you're going to be making
five stops across the field and you're
going to be again zigzagging kind of in
that uh W type of um random pattern you
want to collect two sub samples samples
at each stop and you're going to mix
those subsamples thoroughly and then put
that into the bucket at each of those
stops you want to make um two
penetrometer readings one um from 0 to 6
in and then 6 to 18in depths at each
subsample location and actually if we go
back to that form right down here is
this um area where you're going to have
push one and push two for the surface
and then the sub soil samples and um
you're going to be doing that for each
of those two locations so you end up
with quite a few readings there
um then you're going to record that on
the F uh form after you've done this
you'll have at least one and a half or
six full cups and then that's what the
three cup measurement is you want to
take that make sure that you have enough
mix that soil into a Ziploc bag label it
with the field name the ID and the date
on that Ziploc bag now next you want to
make sure to keep that sample out of
direct sunlight um putting it
immediately into a cooler and then if
you cannot get this shipped um right
away you want to put it in a cold room
or a refrigerator the entire time that
you're shipping so I will bring a cal
pack in my cooler put that soil sample
in there and um not let it warm up the
reason being that you don't want any
degradation of organic matter um to
happen so just be aware of that it also
makes shipping somewhat difficult
because this is a rather large sample
it's quite heavy and it still needs to
be cool cool during shipping so you're
going to have to be aware that you'll
need some kind of a styrofoam container
probably put a coal pack in if possible
so that the sample can remain cold
during shipping and let your grower
clients also know that um you you're
going to need to have some you know
they're going to need to pay for the
shipping it's it it is something to
consider especially if you're doing
multiple
samplings so interpreted interpreting
soil Health test results um make sure to
understand and this is something that I
it took me a while to understand that
the report is a management guide there
is no real hard and fast prescription
but what it does give you um are those
kind of readable data so that you can
try to um figure out your management
around the data different management
approaches can be used to mitigate the
same
problem um so that that's something that
you and the grower would disc discuss
quite a lot uh it while you try to
understand what's the easiest and most
um efficient and also um economical
approach for the grower in addressing
some of the soil constraints management
practices can affect multiple indicators
so some of your things that you might do
like using cover crops might actually
mitigate many different things and soil
Health changes slowly over time um one
thing though to be aware of is that we
use this in a vegetable
situation uh we actually were looking at
um uh things back to back and we
actually did see some improvement even
in one year so it is a long-term process
oftentimes they won't see changes but
it's wonderful that we now we have a
tool that we can kind of track these
changes when they happen um
so here is some here's an example of two
soil Health tests this is what they look
like uh we get this kind of uh we can
learn the effects of long-term mold
board plowing and that's what we're
looking at here 14 years of fall
plowing this is a corn for grain um
study and a clay LOM LOM soil the soil
physical properties have been affected
as have the biological properties a
steady diet of corn Stover has
maintained soil organic matter but it's
impaired active carbon levels in the no
till this field started out as an alala
hay and we see that no tilling
maintained a healthy soil which gives it
the high score while the continuous till
tillage had measurable effects and
results in the low score and um let me
just see if I can get my so you can see
that this um test on the on the left
left is the corn this is the um we get
aggregate stability which is in a danger
thing that's the red indicates of danger
available water capaity is also in that
red danger zone um surface hardness it
has a very excellent rating probably
because of all the tillage that's
happening but the subsurface hardness
still you have a a subsurface pan deep
compaction resulting organic matter the
yellow indicates kind of a warning sign
um it's at 3.9 which uh is the
percentage it still seems like it should
be good but for some reason it does not
rate that high active carbon uh is is
very um poor there's soil biological
activity is low and potentially
mineralizable nitrogen is also in that
area but the Ral Health rating is still
quite good um so sometimes some of these
things you wonder what there there
doesn't seem to be clear um picture
across the board in one um biological
area soil pH is a little bit you know
from a nutrient or a chemical aspect 6.1
isn't bad but they put it in the yellow
range extractable phosphorus um is a
little bit uh High probably so that puts
that into a a yellow area a caution
extractable potassium is fine and all
your minor elements are fine but that
that rating gives it a low reading
whereas on the right the same kind of
situation but they've done no till you
can see that all of the aggregate
stability the subsurface hardness
um the organic matter and the
potentially mineralizable nitrogen
things that were in the red areas um now
are green giving it a much higher uh
rating so the soil Health then is deemed
better and we aren't as lucky we a lot
of times we have a no till situation
just because Berry crops are primarily
no till so approach for a successful
soil management strategy you want to
assess your soil's health to identify
constraints and that's what we're
recommending doing with the Cornell soil
Health test you want to be able to make
changes in management strategies that
work for your farm and that address the
specific constraints identified in the
soil Health test you want to be able to
experiment on your farm to see what
works in your situation starting small
is helpful and um you should be able to
adapt the many resources of information
that you gan from the soil Health test
to your farm and build healthy soils to
increase resiliency to extremes and
that's one of the overall um
goals and now um Kathy's going to talk
about uh the cornal tissue analysis or
the or excuse me just tissue anal
analysis in
general thanks
Laura we want to take a look now at the
above ground aspect of uh small fruit
production and we're going to look at
tissue analysis or Leaf analysis and
this kind of testing directly measures
the amount of nutrients in the leaves
and in some instances as incredible as
it may seem there may be sufficient
nutrients in soil and yet leaves can
show a deficiency and we'll talk about
the reasons why that may happen so these
sufficiency ranges uh have been
determined or estimated for small fruits
um sometimes from other crops sometimes
directly and so we'll be looking at
those shortly um and these ranges when
you fall into the lower or deficient uh
levels alert you to nut ENT uh issues
that are are approaching are coming and
often those can be caught before they
become critical and effect yield and
plant
performance um these tests are also used
to fine-tune annual nitrogen application
rates typically there's a suggested
application based on the crop age but
you may need to adjust in your
particular situation uh either higher or
lower depending on the test results and
then these can also be used
diagnostically as Jeff discussed earlier
to rule out nutritional causes for poor
Plant
performance oop sorry wrong
way so these tests can also be done at
the Agro one uh lab and the information
for the lab is here um these tests
previously were done at Cornell at the
nutrient analysis lab and they've been
shifted to aggro one so that uh the
nutrient analysis lab can continue to do
the research needed to to uh fine-tune
the recommendations and in this instance
you're looking for uh the tree fruit in
small fruit form form
p and the report that you will get will
give you uh the Cornell nutrient
guidelines uh inter and the
interpretation thereof and the same run
roughly uh
$24
each so when would you need to collect
leaves for the analysis typically
strawberry leaves are
collected uh after renovation and we're
looking for the first
regrowth the youngest full-sized leaves
and those are usually collected uh
toward the middle to the end of July for
blueberries these leaves are collected
just before or during Harvest and you're
sampling
from uh fully expanded mature leaves
from the middle of this year's Chute
growth and those that are exposed to
full sun typically these are collected
in Late July and early August for
raspberries and blackberries you're
collecting leaves from the Prima canes
and you're looking for the youngest
fully expanded leaves typically they're
collected in early
August one of the things that you want
to remember though is that it's best to
avoid collecting leaves when the plant
resources are all being directed fully
to fruit because in a lot of instances
those levels can fluctuate there may be
sufficient uh nutrients in the soil for
example um but the leaves may show a
deficiency this is particularly true of
um
potassium so you want to be sure to try
to collect
um when their plants aren't under a
heavy fruit load that's not always
possible but try to avoid that whenever
you
can so how do we collect the
leaves again we want healthy leaves that
are well exposed to light they should be
representative for the average condition
of the planting uh try not to select
leaves that are damaged by disease
insects WEA for example hail damaged or
mechanical
injury um don't mix leaves from
different calars remember Jeff talked
about Management areas you want to try
to keep your man Management areas
uniform um plantings of different ages
leaves from those should not be mixed
those should be sep separately sampled
and you want a minimum of uh 2 ounces of
fresh weight leaves typically 30 leaves
for each sample if possible try to
collect each Leaf from a different plant
within the sample area and then try to
process your leaves for analysis as soon
as
possible okay when you prepare your
leaves for
analysis um one of the things you want
to do is use distilled water for washing
and rinsing the samples washing leaves
removes dirt and residues that can
affect the test results so it's
important to do so before they're dried
for
shipment so gently and lightly scrub the
leaves together in distilled water
change the water if it becomes dirty or
after 8 to 10 samples whichever occurs
first shake the leaves gently to remove
excess water and then rinse the sample
in clean distilled water water again
shake off the uh liquid and rinse with
another clean uh water
sample you can lay these out on paper
towels and let them dry slightly before
you put them in a paper bag and then you
want to leave the top of that bag open
and dry the leaves at room temperature
until they're brittle it's important not
to let the leaves stand in water you
want to try to wash and rinse them in a
minute or less if
possible don't put them in plastic bags
to ship them or ship fresh leaves
without drying because these they often
can deteriorate really rapidly under
those conditions and it'll result in
very poor test
results so here's the chart that I was
telling you about where we have the
standard folar nutrient
ranges and I want you to notice that
when you look for example at
strawberries you have a range where the
nutrients are suff deficient and then a
range where they are deficient below a
particular point and you'll notice
across the top the nitrogen is expressed
in percentages that's true all the way
down to Boron and then the P the uh
ranges are expressed in parts per
million or PPM and so when we look at
strawberries you'll see that the ranges
if you compare those to raspberries
you'll see that for the most part the
ranges are are pretty much the same for
these two crops you see there's not a
lot of difference between um for example
Zinc at uh 20 to 50 PPM and the same for
raspberries in the sufficient range 20
to 50 PPM but when we
compare say for example strawberries or
raspberries with blueberries you will
see that blueberries have significantly
lower
levels the critical values for
blueberries are quite a bit lower they
have muchow lower nutrient requirements
than strawberries and raspberries one
exception to this however is
manganese higher manganese levels with
blueberries is not a problem as it might
be with other crops because manganese
becomes less available as the pH drops
so you can see here blueberries are able
to tolerate manganese even at the 350
PPM range whereas uh strawberries and
rasberries prefer a range of 200 or less
okay it's important to note that not all
Labs will compensate for the differences
between say for example strawberries and
raspberries and blueberries in terms of
the blueberries having lower nutrient
requirements and they will often use the
same recommendations that they are using
for strawberries and raspberries with
blueberries because these
recommendations are common across a wide
range of crops and so they may be
recommending addition of nutrients in
blueberries where really they aren't
necessary and so that's of the things
you really need to watch
for okay here's a typical uh plant
tissue analysis report uh from Farmer in
the Dell at HiHo Dario Road um these are
blueberries they're 1 to 3 years old
they're non-bearing and the variety is
liberty and you can see here there's a
knif nice graphic that gives you the
macro and micro
nutrients EX the bar graph shows when
they're in range or when they're low
typically you get the most benefit when
you address um nutrient issues that are
falling in the low to deficient range
that's when you really need to uh make
corrective action when they're in range
or in the high range that's when
typically um you won't get a lot of
um Change in Plant performance if you
make those uh Corrections
and so when we look at this report we
can see that both copper and iron are
deficient zinc is also low however if we
look at the soil levels over here the
levels for those nutrients are adquate
so what would the problem be here if we
go back and look at the soil test
results which is why you want to really
have a paired sample you'll notice that
the pH here is 5.2 which is uh higher
than you really would like for a
blueberry planting for blueberries you
really would prefer 4.2 to
4.5 when the pH reaches that level the
available nutrients in the soil will
become available and those
deficiencies should correct themselves
without even having to make an
application so when you're interpreting
your results be sure that the soil pH is
within the correct range
assess the status of the planting to
determine if some something other than
nutrients could be limiting growth for
example disease insect pressure drought
other environmental conditions be sure
to check the status of boron because
that has an effect on other
nutrients look for specific nutrients
that may be deficient check for inter
interactions or imbalances that EXA
exacerbate low nutrient levels and then
um come up with your
recommendations when Boron levels are
low that affects root growth root growth
and development limiting the uptake of
other nutrients such as calcium and
potassium soil levels of these nutrients
may be adequate while Leaf levels appear
deficient when you correct the Boron
levels it will often correct the issues
with the other nutrients without the
need for addition of supplemental
calcium or
potassium another thing to note as we
discussed earlier is that fruiting takes
a lot of potassium so a levels of this
nutrient may be adequate while Leaf
levels appear low this is especially
true as Leaf sampling often occurs not
long after Fring allowing time for
uptake and adequate irrigation will rep
replenish Leaf levels of potassium
without the need of
supplementing sometimes high levels of
soil nutrients may also cause problems
for example if phosphorus is too high it
may restrict uptake of micronutrients
such as zinc copper or
iron or magnesium by tying them up in
the soil this frequently occurs in the
case of strawberries another interaction
involves high calcium levels in
blueberry soils this nutrient often ties
up iron in the soil causing a folar
deficiency so when you're interpreting
uh tissue analysis test results there
are some things to to remember first of
all um the test results are not
meaningful for fertility fertility
guidelines unless the soil pH is within
the correct
range and remember that soil test
results do not always correlate with
folar test results for a variety of
reasons so you may have adequate
nutrition in the soil while there
appears not to be adequate nutrition in
the leaves or the reverse may also be
true you may appear to have adequate
nutrition in leaves but not in
soil tissue analysis tests are useful
for diagnosis but not for detailed
guidance unless you consider all of the
factors involved including growth and
yield
and applying nutrients may result in a
decrease in folar concentration under
certain
circumstances correcting deficiencies or
imbalances in established plantings is
more difficult than amending soils prior
to planting so really that pre-plant
soil test and soil amendment prior to
planting is critical and often provides
enough nutrients especially P&amp;K and the
micros for the life of the planting
nitrogen is something that we need to
add annually and I mentioned that it's
often determined by the crop the plant
age the irrigation and mulching status
and the leaf analysis results so often
Growers will say okay my strawberry crop
is 2 years old and so I'm applying um 25
pounds per acre of actual nitrogen and
if you actually used your Leaf analysis
results in comparison
to the crop age you might find that you
had sufficient nitrogen and you might be
able to apply less or you might find
that your nitrogen is actually lacking
in leaves and you might need to apply
more and for more information on this
topic you should check the Corell Pest
Management guidelines for Berry crops to
find the annual rates of nitrogen for
your crop or the NRA production guides
for more in-depth information on
adjusting
these to get the proper results
so again in many cases no additional
pkmg or CA will be required if the soil
test recommendations were followed at
planting you may need to supplement uh K
and um potassium and Boron especially on
sandier soils because those have a
tendency to leech more quickly and small
amounts of sulfur may be required to
maintain a low PH in some soils where
blueberries are grown especially if
calcium levels are approaching
2,000 Leaf analyses provides uh guidance
on supplemental fertilizers after the
planning established and don't rely on a
soil test for postplant
recommendations that do not involve soil
PH remember the pH has to be at the
correct
range so in review don't rely on visual
symptoms of what you've always done in
the past in terms of berry soil nutrient
management if you want to maximize your
yield and plant Health before you plant
consider doing the Cornell soil Health
test which includes the standard um
chemical soil test and more the physical
and biological properties that Laura
discussed and then after plants are
established use annual tissue analysis
and soil testing every 2 to three years
to fine-tune your nutrient
plan that's the end of our presentation
today and we'd like to acknowledge Dr
Marvin pritz who's the project leader of
our project he's professor and chair of
uh the department of horticulture at
Cornell
University um you've already met uh
Laura Jeff and myself we'd also like to
thank Mario Miranda sazo one of our team
members who's uh with the tree Fruit and
Berry fruit extension he's tree Fruit
and Berry extension specialist with
Cornell extension Lake Ontario fruit
team Mr Dan Welch who's extension
resource educator with kuga County
Cooperative Extension Dr Harold vess
who's
professor in at Cornell University in
the department of crop and soil Sciences
who works very extensively with the
Cornell soil health program and Mr
Robert schindelbeck who extension
associate also in the same department
and is the coordinator of the cor soil
Health testing and we have special
thanks to Mrs Miss Janet Fallon with
aggro one she's the certified crop
adviser and was very helpful in
providing information for this
presentation thank you