and I think we're going to move into the
meat of the
presentation and I'd like to introduce
our first Speaker Sonia schloman is the
um extension small fruit specialist at
the University of Massachusetts and she
specializes on all Berry crops um and I
have found her to be a real great
resource because I'm in Eastern New York
right around the Albany area so it's
wonderful to have somebody of her
expertise um that close to us and I uh
really thank her for being she's been an
active part of The Advisory Group for
this program and I'm very happy to have
her talk about pollination issues in
blueberry production and Sonia hopefully
that um audio is going to work just fine
I'm going to actually get off and that
way I won't interfere with your
audio okay Laura thank you so
much can everybody hear me I hope so um
I guess there's a thumbs up button that
can be used um down on the lower left
hand of your screen or thumbs down I
guess would be the other thing you could
do um but with that I'm just going to go
ahead and get started and hopefully
everybody can hear me um I was asked to
uh present some information today on
pollination issues
in commercial blueberry production and
I'm going to be talking primarily about
high Bush blueberries although a lot of
what I'm uh the concepts that I'm going
to cover are going to be useful in low
busher wild blueberry production as well
um I wanted to start by just going over
uh a little bit of information about the
structure of blueberry flowers because
it helps explain some of the issues that
come up with uh blueberry uh
pollination so uh the blueberry flower
is considered uh to be a flower that's
both perfect and complete which means
that it has all of the necessary Parts
um for pollination has a cix Corolla
Stam and Pistol uh all together in one
flower structure um interestingly with
the blueberry flowers the uh the the
Corola uh which is um essentially the
flower petals that you would find uh on
other kinds of flowers are fused so it's
kind of a tubular structure and out
outside sticking outside of that tubular
structure is a um the stigma which has
the pollen tube in it and the pollen
needs to land on the end of that stigma
and travel down the tube in order to
fertilize the uh the ovules that become
seeds um the nect is also very deep
within that tubular flower and because
the flower petals are fused it makes it
a little bit challeng chenging for
insects to gain access to the nect and
come in contact with the pollen that's
on the
anthers so we can see in this picture
here um let's see if I can find my
little
arrow the uh you can see the the um
pollen tubes here sticking out outside
of the flower and um the uh the the
blueberries themselves each each flower
each y uh can potentially have 65 ovales
in it um so there's a lot of pollinating
that needs to happen on each individual
flower um and also each individual bush
has many many flowers you can see from
just this one picture here one branch on
a blueberry bush has quite a few flowers
and over the entire Bush um there may be
as many as 2,000 or sometimes more
flowers so that's uh that's a
significant challenge for pollination um
and when uh pollination is going on if
uh an individual flower is not fully
pollinated in other words not all of the
ovules are fertilized and and become
viable seeds then that fruit does not
develop as fully as a uh a fruit a
flower that's completely pollinated so
complete pollination is important for
generating a uh a marketable yield
one of the things that um Growers can do
in order to determine whether or not
they're getting adequate
pollination um is to evaluate the uh the
pollinating activity during Bloom and
also do an assessment after bloom um if
you're the weather conditions and other
environmental conditions during Bloon
are making you suspect that perhaps uh
inadequate pollination is taking place
you can actually do some visual
observations uh um for a span of time
assessing the number of pollinators that
are actually entering flowers not just
the number of pollinators that are
flying around but ones that are landing
on flowers and spending time visiting uh
individual flowers so the
uh picture up on the right here sort of
indicates what that would look like here
so it doesn't have to be any specific
species of bee but or pollinator but any
type of pollinator that's visiting um FL
flers and you want to have a minimum of
or an average I'm sorry of 20
pollinators in a 10-minute period uh
visiting flowers and that will give you
an indication that enough activity is
happening during the bloom period after
bloom um there's also another um
assessment that can be done which
involves taking a look at the color of
the Corollas that fall to the ground
after pollination or after bloom is
complete and you can see in this picture
here um many of these individual flowers
have fallen off uh there are a few still
remaining and the ones that land on the
ground need to be a bright white in
color not brown or um gray or
translucent uh if they're not uh fully
white in color for that first 24 hours
or so after they land on the ground uh
it's an indication that they were not
fully
pollinated and finally uh at the end of
pollination after all of the flowers
have fallen off the ovaries the
pollinated uh fruit should swell rapidly
stay kind of a green color and swell
rapidly and this picture here is a nice
one because it shows um the sizing up of
the the the nicely pollinated fruit but
there's one here that didn't get
pollinated so that would be an
indication uh of a a failure to
pollinate and if you have a high
percentage of those in uh the the
clusters of fruit on your blueberry bush
you may find that you have inadequate
pollination so what do most commercial
blueberry operations do for pollination
well most of them rely at least in New
England I'm not sure if this is true
across the country but in New England
still most of our commercial blueberry
oper operations will rely on honeybees
for pollination and they might be um
hives that they maintain themselves on
the farm um or they might be hired in uh
as a pollination service although we're
finding now that many uh Growers are
considering some alternatives to honey
bees and we we're going to talk about
that in a little more detail uh in just
a little
bit um so while honeybees are uh the
primary source of pollination uh or what
Growers rely on in blueberries uh it's
important to have an idea of how many
honey bees are needed um generally
speaking uh we recommend anywhere from
one to three hives per acre and the
range um is defined by by a couple of
things one of the characteristics is
going to be the varieties of blueberries
that you're growing uh some of some
blueberry varieties are more attractive
to honeybees than others um although in
New England at least most of our
blueberry operations have a pretty wide
range of varieties so fine-tuning the
number of hives based on varieties that
are grown is is somewhat difficult so
you need to sort of get a ballpark idea
of what's going to be enough another
element that's going to Define how many
hives you need is going to be the
population of wild pollinators that you
might have in your area so
um I'm just noticing here some comments
about sound I'm I guess I hope that
everybody can hear me I can hear you
perfectly I'm hoping that everyone else
can hear as well um okay it looks like
it was it is a little tiny bit crackly
but basically I would just keep going
and I'll let you know if there's a big
problem all right well I can turn my
microphone up a little bit if necessary
or the volume you just let me know
volume is
fine okay all right um all right so the
the population of wild uh pollinators is
going to have a an influence on how many
hives need to be um used to supplement
um natural pollination that's happening
in a particular uh blueberry planting uh
if you are using honeybees um whether or
not their hives that you're um
maintaining yourself or bringing in um
when you place them you want to make
sure that they're placed in a somewhat
sheltered location away from driving
wind and rain and so forth um another
important concept is to make sure that
you place them in your Blueberry field
or blueberry planting once Bloom has
actually already started if they're
placed in the field too
soon um blueberries blueberries are not
terribly attractive to honeybees because
uh they're a little bit difficult for
honey bees to pollinate compared to some
other flowers so if they find another
nectar source nearby whether it's other
flowering fruiting crops or dandelions
or something else and they Orient to
those flowers uh by the time that
blueberries begin to bloom they may
Overlook them they may bypass them
entirely because they're already
oriented to another flower source so you
want to make sure that when you bring
your bees into the blueberry uh planting
there's
an adequate and abundant source of
flowers for them to visit and Orient to
so that they'll stay in that planting
and not go somewhere else you also want
to make sure that you place the hives uh
if possible in such a location where the
entrance can be Facing East which will
allow the sun light to hit it early
enough in the day and and uh encourage
early activity of
honeybees um this is a chart that you'll
find uh in one form or another in a lot
of different Publications this is from
uh Gary's wonderful
newsletter and it just gives you an idea
of the different varieties and their
relative attractiveness to
honeybees um and uh again if you have a
an abundance of a certain variety or or
varieties that tend more to the
attractive or to the less attractive
side it may help you decide how many
hives are needed but um it's a useful
tool although I haven't found one
recently that has a lot of the newer
varieties on it and perhaps um Gary can
help us with that information if he
knows where to find a chart that
includes uh newer
varieties honey bees do have some
limitations um the main limitation uh in
recent years has been the fact that that
b colonies have suffered from a number
of different diseases and parasites
probably the most notable currently is
what's called colony collapse disorder
which isn't very well understood yet but
it's certainly um quite pervasive and is
uh really reducing the U the
availability of a lot of uh commercial
honeybee uh hives veroom mites and
tramites have also been a problem um in
recent years there are a number of
management strategies that can be used
to help with those fou brood has been
known for quite a long time and most uh
commercial beekeepers are are familiar
with how to deal with that but the net
result is that there really are fewer
commercial hives available currently um
and it's harder to obtain them or
contract to have them brought in to uh
pollinate fruit crops there are also
fewer wild colonies available so that we
really need to start thinking about some
alternative strategies to help um
achieve pollination in
blueberries one of the things that we
can do and this would be true both for
uh wild and domestic pollinators
honeybees as well as other uh
pollinating insects is to be mindful of
certain specific recommendations that we
make that have to do with um insecticide
applications most spray guides and Pest
Management recommendations will very
prominently uh recommend to avoid
spraying insecticides during Bloom and
this is of course a very important
practice in the event though that you
find yourself in a situation where you
feel that you need to to apply something
um for a specific pest that is
threatening your crop there are certain
um considerations to keep in mind most
of our manuals uh will
include charts and tables that will list
um various materials mostly it's
insecticides but it also includes some
fungicides and
herbicides that um and they're rated in
terms of their toxicity to pollinators
so so that for the the particular pest
that you need to control you want to
make sure to consult this list and among
your options choose the least toxic to
pollinators if you feel that you have to
apply something during Bloom um
sometimes there's not a lot of choices a
lot of good choices available to you um
but to the extent possible it's
important to choose the least toxic
material the other thing is to make sure
to spray as late in the day as you can
um and this is important because um many
times pollinating insects will return to
their nests at the end of the day
especially
honeybees um and so you want to try to
make your applications at a time when
they are not outworking uh any flowers
so as late in the day as you can this
also allows the spray material to dry
and be absorbed into the plant tissue
overnight and um be less accessible to
pollinators when they resume working in
the morning and also to try to use uh um
liquid formulations of materials as
opposed to dusts or any kind of powdered
formulation that's likely to leave some
kind of residue that the uh the bees can
pick up when they begin working the
following
day um this is just an example of one of
the lists and again they're um found in
in many different uh guides and
recommendation Publications some includ
more materials than others um more
expanded list um this is just one that
comes out of the New England small fruit
Pest Management guide but again it gives
you an idea of what category um
different materials fall in including
the slightly toxic or not considered
non-toxic
materials okay now the other strategy
that people can employ when uh wanting
to get uh full pollination in their
commercial blueberries is the use of
native pollinators uh and there's a lot
of literature out there a lot of
different studies uh being done
currently on this topic and some very
good Publications one of the best that I
came across was a study uh that was done
in at Michigan State uh that was
published this year uh it was a
three-year study U very comprehensive
study at 15 blueberry farms and rather
than give you lots of different charts
and graphs and everything
um I I'll just kind of cut to the Chase
and let you know that what they found
was about 112 species of uh Native
pollinators that were active during
blueberry Bloom they found 166 alog
together spanning a time period longer
than just the blueberry Bloom period but
at least 50% of those 112 species were
contributing significantly to
pollination so that just tells us that
we have a very potent resource out there
in our native pollinators that we can be
taking advantage
of what are these
species well um probably the one that we
hear the most about are bumblebees um
there are many Native species of
bumblebees across the country they're
very effective at pollinating uh
blueberries partly because of their size
um honeybees because are they're sort of
an in between size they're a little bit
too big to crawl inside that Corolla and
really get a lot of contact with the uh
the pollen um but they're also a little
bit too small to reach very effectively
all the way in with their mouth Parts
Bumblebees are large enough that they
can reach right in and make a lot of
good contact with the interior of the
flower they also do something called
sonicating which is
essentially uh where they engage their
flight muscles without spreading their
wings and they kind of vibrate when
they're um working a particular flower
and it shakes some of the PO poen off of
the anthers uh Falls onto their bodies
and then they can transport that pollen
from one flower to another they're also
known for working um a lot more hours in
a day than honeybees so that's a real
Advantage um they'll work for example in
cool cloudy conditions where oftentimes
we won't see honeybees leaving their
hives and they're also commercially
available which is very
useful um the next sort of big category
or the osmia species there's a lot of
different osmia bees Orchard Mason bees
HornFans are a couple um that that are
commonly referred to Horn face bees for
example have been used for a long time
in Japan for pollinating apples and
interestingly what they found is that it
only requires somewhere from 3 to 800
individual horn face bees to pollinate
an acre of apples and this is compared
to 60 to
120,000 honey
so you can see that they're very
efficient
pollinators uh they nest in reads and
tubes and and holes in wood woodpecker
holes and uh insect tunnels that are in
uh decaying um wood and the forest
surrounding um a blueberry planting but
they're also commercially available so
this is a good resource for
us uh another category is the leaf
cutter bees there's a lot of different
species in this um genus as well Al
alfafa leaf cutter bees have been used
actually pretty extensively in Maine for
pollinating wild blueberries so there's
a lot of good literature on those and
again they're also um commercially
available one of my personal favorites
is the Shaggy fuzzy foot bee um I I'm
not sure that I've actually seen one of
these but I like their name um and they
are also identified as being significant
pollinators
um of a lot of different uh flowers uh
I'm not I don't believe that they're
commercially available at least not at
this point but um but they're definitely
an important uh constituent of the
pollinating
population then there's carpenter bees
now carpenter bees can be found um
pollinating or trying to to work
blueberry flowers they look a lot like
bumblebees except that um they don't
have that fuzzy appearance they lack the
fine ears on their bodies so that they
have a a more shiny appearance but
otherwise they're similar in size and
shape uh to uh
bumblebees but
um they don't do a good job of
pollinating because what they will do is
chew holes in the side of blueberry
blossoms bypassing the anthers and um
the pollen tubes so that they cannot um
actually achieve any kind of pollination
so they are not what's considered a a
good pollinator but but it's good to
know the difference because if you're
making observations in your field you
want to know whether what you're
counting are carpenter bees or
bumblebees this is just excuse me a uh a
little
diagram
um you can see here is a a carpenter bee
that's working on uh blueberries and you
can see rather than trying to enter the
flowers that are open it's just chewing
into the side it'll create these little
slits on the side and uh go right into
the nectar and get some nectar out this
picture here is showing us a number of
different species of
bumblebees um here across in sort of an
arc in the picture um and in the middle
is an example of a carpenter bee and you
can see that it looks rather similar but
there's this very shiny black abdomen
that makes it distinctively different
from the other um than the than the
bumblebees
I can see that there's a question here
about the number of quads of bumblebees
per acre I don't remember off the top of
my head and I I know that that
information is pretty readily available
from the commercial
suppliers um and so I would sort of
hesitate to make a suggestion um right
off the top of my head but I know that
it's a that's an piece of information
that's pretty easy to find
out um and I'm going to talk just a
little bit more about Bumblebee in a
second um all right so here we are so
again with the Bumblebees um there's a
wide range of species um out there uh
there's a couple different pictures of
uh a couple of different species here
both working on blueberries um they work
on a wide range of conditions um they're
more effective at reaching into the
flowers and actually achieving
pollination plus they do that
sonicating um
ction commercial bumblebee hives are
pretty readily available they're the
most widely used pollinator for
Greenhouse Tomatoes which are uh
becoming more and more popular uh so
they're um the uh the hives that are
available for interior uh locations like
in a greenhouse are usually cardboard
boxes um I suppose these could be used
outside if they're placed inside a
shelter of some sort but I don't think
they would hold up for um as long as the
ones that are actually designed to be
outside um and they are both of those
types are available and I'm sorry I
don't have a specific number of of quads
there's different styles there's
different sizes of boxes that are
designed for different uses um and as I
said they're pretty readily
available um just again a little review
of the osmia um species there a lot of
different ones the main blueberry bee
horn face bees blue Orchard bees um
there's a whole publication dedicated uh
to Blue Orchard bees that their acronym
is Bob so they refer to how to raise Bob
uh in a in a fruit
planting many of these will nest in
these types of tubes in nature it would
be a bamboo or Reed section of some sort
that would be their n one of their
natural sites but you can construct one
uh that's equally appealing to them uh
simply by using cardboard tubes
similar to a straw um and these are uh
again commercially available there's a
number of different sites that sell them
a lot of the um work on on different
designs of nests was done by Dr batra
from beltzville Maryland I I believe she
has left Beltsville now um and there's
another person that has kind of taken
over her position there but there's some
good information um this is uh here what
one of the
uh tubes might look like inside with the
larv that are packed in you can see this
is must be a leaf cutter uh be of some
sort you can see the little sections of
leaves that are packed in
there if you want to construct or
purchase a uh a box full of these types
of tubes you can create a shelter for uh
housing them pretty simply just
basically a a trash barrel laid on its
side and the tubes inside you want to
put some kind of a screen or wire mesh
around the front of it because U various
Predators like skunks and and other
kinds of animals would be attracted to
that food source that uh the larv
present to them you want to also make
sure you have some ventilation in there
and a nice clear area in front of it
where the grass doesn't grow up and
obscure the
entrance another option is to uh use a
wooden block and drill um holes in the
wooden block 5/16 or so uh in size not
too thick and you also don't want them
drill all the way through they they need
to have only one opening uh in one end
of the block and um these
are um the types of um nesting sites
that we actually see somewhat commonly
now in in a lot of different fruit
plantings this picture here was taken I
believe in uh IP switch haal area in
Massachusetts a fairly sizable blueberry
operation there um and I've seen them in
other locations as well pretty
inexpensive not a big commitment there
to uh increasing the nesting sites for
uh wild
pollinators in addition to nesting sites
you also want to try to
encourage um yearr round residents of
these uh insects in your location by
making sure that you have some um
suitable flower uh food sources for them
throughout the year now Birch Maple Oak
uh popler Willow those are trees that
are pretty common at least in New
England as food sources um but you can
also encourage some sort of wild areas
uh with asers and some other kinds of
wild um flowering plants rather than
mowing everything just keeping a a few
areas where uh they might find nectar
sources uh in other times of the year
besides when the blueberries are
blooming so just to summarize the the
things that you can do to enhance the
suitability of your farm for these
beneficial insects pollinating insects
is to provide a habitat suitable for
nesting encourage or plant flowering
plants that provide uh Bloom through the
growing season they need to have some
clean water so they need access to clean
water um nest building materials again
you know keeping a few areas that are
somewhat wild um and allow them to uh
have access to materials that they need
to to build the nests with and then to
minimize your insecticide use during uh
Bloom as much as as you possibly
can I did want to add um just a one
slide and again this is something that
Gary may have a lot more information
about if we have time for some questions
and that is what you can do if even when
you've done all the other things that
we've talked about you still have um
poor pollination uh in a given year such
as this year for example we had um very
cold windy rainy conditions in many
areas during Bloom and as a result the
flowers either set don't set fruit at
all or the fruit that they set is is
poorly
pollinated um one of the things that
people have talked about doing in
conditions like this is using uh a
supplemental uh plant growth hormone
application something uh like
gibberellin um there are a couple of
gibberellin products that are labeled
for use in blueberries prb and Gib grow
are a couple that I'm aware of uh there
may be others and these are materials
that can be applied to your blueberries
to help retain some of those um
unpollinated or what we call
parthenocarpic fruit that have no viable
seeds in
uh or no um pollinated seeds um and or
for those fruit that have incomplete
pollination um it can help size up those
fruit as well um this these materials
can be applied either in one spray or in
a split application um usually on the
order of 80 grams of active ingredient
per acre um towards the end of Bloom um
in a single application or towards the
end of Bloom and then again um and 14
days after that in a split application
uh it's important to have high spray
volume in order to get a lot of material
um good coverage of the the plants with
um a high spray Val volume it's good if
you can to try to apply this when the
drying conditions are slow so that you
can increase absorption and as with is
true with a number of different
materials to try to use materials uh to
to make sure that your spray water is um
the the correct pH in order for these
materials to work so
um I I'm going to try to read some of
these questions
here uh the development of wild
pollinators um such as wild bumblebees I
think is primarily a matter of making
sure that we have um good nesting sites
for them and uh maintaining some uh good
wild areas in the periphery around the
planting uh in order to allow them to um
develop some nests and also to get a
good food
source uh the next question is do the
parthenocarpic fruit have the same
quality I don't think that they do I
think that they're um inherently smaller
and I think the flavor is somewhat less
but again we don't have many Growers or
really any that I'm aware of that have
tried using gibberellin in Massachusetts
at least and uh I'm Pro pretty sure we
haven't seen much of it in New England
but it's possible that in areas where
there's more um significant large scale
production of blueberries such as New
Jersey or possibly Michigan that um that
may be a more common practice so uh it
may be true that Gary has something to
say about
it um and then the last question oh if
admire is used for Grobe control in June
it could yes it could hurt bumblebees um
and it that's going to be
um it's going to be important to use
that very carefully um and not allow
drift into areas outside of the
blueberry planting because most likely
the Bumblebees are nesting and other
natural pollinators are nesting in areas
outside of the blueberry planting itself
so we need to be very very careful about
drift um with spray materials such as
admire um that have a systemic um
component um so that we protect the the
pollinators and other beneficial insects
in the area around the uh the planting
and then I guess the last question is if
Bumblebees are brought in will they they
later colonized the area for next year I
don't have a lot of direct information
about that and I haven't found it in the
studies um but my impression from a
couple of Growers that I have that I
know who've recently kind of adopted
bumblebees in favor of uh over the use
of honeybees and are very happy with
them have found that the uh the there is
a certain percentage of a bumblebee
Colony that's brought in that will um
stick around that will become a resident
population U over time it may be
necessary to bring bumblebees in for a
few years before you have an adequate
population that's established that will
be reliable for an extended period of
time but I do think that they stick
around um for you know from year to year
is impression
so I guess with that I think that's all
I've got um and I'm going to stay on the
line and and um can take questions or
comments from people if uh if there are
any anybody um else have any questions
did you see the question about how long
is The Blossom viable for pollination
and if you just answered that forgive me
because I had someone here talking to me
did you see that last question
I think there's a little bit of I think
that there's a little bit of VI of
variation with different varieties um
but I would say that there's probably a
span of a week to 10 days depending on
the the weather conditions you know
certain weather conditions are going to
push the bloom period faster uh than
than other weather so in other words
when it's when it's sort of cold um
things it slows things down a bit uh as
opposed to if we get a spell where
things are is the weather's very hot and
um the whole Bloom period becomes kind
of compressed and goes through uh the
stages more quickly but I think on
average we're looking at uh something
like a week for uh the availability of
pollination for for flowers all right
Sonia that was great and um if anybody
has any questions that come to them uh
while uh Dr pavs is speaking Sonia will
be here at the end and I really
appreciate that thank you um give me a
few moments here folks and I'm going to
switch things around and introduce our
next um
speaker and our next speaker is um Dr
Gary pavas um he is a professor and EG
agent at rers University and his areas
of expertise are blueberry and grape and
wine production his blueberry newsletter
the blueberry bulletin has an
international following and he has done
a lot of research um transformative
research on blueberry
fertilization um and he's been in
instrumental in the expansion of the New
Jersey wine industry so if you um have
any wine questions after the blueberry
presentation now you know who to ask
them to but I'm so pleased to have Dr
Gary pavas uh here to talk to us about
blueberry site preparation and fertility
considerations all right
Gary thank you Laura thank you very much
uh and uh welcome everybody um we're
going to do a little bit about uh site
selection and I always put this slide on
anybody who seen me give a talk um has
seen this uh slide typical harvest in
New Jersey um
and what I always say is well you know
if you don't have a harvest like this
where you are then I guess you need to
listen up because this is what we do in
Jersey but in reality I'm sitting in the
research station in New Jersey and
looking out my window uh it's the pine
Barons and um what reality is is that if
you're going to grow blueberries you and
this is where blueberries High Bush
blueberries evolved um this is where uh
and what you have to basically produce
reproduce if you want to grow
blueberries um you know you have to
recreate our our climate here um you
know we have soils that are very
specific for blueberries we have the the
pH organic matter water table all of
this kind of thing is very specific for
high Bush blueberries and that's why
they do well so if you're going to grow
High Bush blueberries this is what you
are trying to
recreate um of course I always put this
in front of any anyone that's going to
start um you know this is a perennial
crop and as such um there's a there's a
lot of eyes that need to be dotted and
tees that need to be crossed and I I
often tell people that with something
like a perenial crop uh this crop is
sort of like children and that is that
any mistake you make today you will pay
for
tomorrow and so when you're getting
started um you have to look at what it's
going to cost for from an establishment
standpoint you really can't cut out
certain things well I don't I really
don't have the money to put in the
irrigation so I'm not going to do that
um you can't do things like that um and
we'll talk a little bit about um the
cost a little later um and we we'll
mention some things about site selection
um uh and the things that go along with
that a little bit about varieties um
irrigation labor and marketing um so
we'll get into some of this these things
um I mentioned the cost um see that one
pass the cost um the latest figures are
uh somewhere around
$8500 um that I have um and you know
they they if you look at this list
you'll see that it's it's uh you know
you probably could think of other things
that you could put in there but um but
certainly um uh things like irrigation
and sawdust Mulch and of course the
plants land prep or all of these things
um add up to this figure and and I've
heard figures anywhere from you know
well it's only about $3,000 to set it up
but but all of this comes into it and
this should be taken into account if you
if you're going to set up two acres or
five acres or 10 acres well 10 acres is
you know $880,000
to set this up so I think um it's
imperative that um you know what you're
getting into before you um go ahead and
do this um
s selection is uh is certainly has a lot
to do with uh taking a soil test and
finding out what you're starting off
with what are you have um as I said the
soils here in New Jersey where we are uh
right outside my window they are from
native standpoint 4.5 to
4.8 um organic matter can be as high as
9% um the water table is 18 in down and
um so as a result um
what do you have um you know in New
Jersey um when they try to plant
blueberries in northern Jersey you have
a pH of of 72 in some places so um that
has to be all taken care of before you
ever ever uh get into planting
plants um this is what the pine Barons
looks like um I just thought I'd show
you um in fact I was with some Growers
yesterday and uh they had told me they
were down here and they were amazed at
the soil type um
um and you know this is this is the
typical this is actually an old picture
from 1940s showing uh getting the
getting the uh the land uh site level
and uh being able to work it and know
actually where your water flow is going
Etc um and here's another actually very
old shot from the' 40s um this one
actually um as I understand it was was
taken while we were setting up the
research station um in the ' 60s um uh
that I'm sitting at right
now oops uh let's see I want to go
forward
there um but this is this is the typical
um planting um and uh you know if you're
not used to this kind of thing you
notice the soil looks so white um but if
you just uh kick away the the top
surface you will actually see that um
the it's black underneath and and that
reveals to you that yes it's Sandy it's
well- drained but it's also um high in
organic matter as I mentioned um it can
be uh you know 6 7 8 9% organic matter
and you can also tell from that ditch
there where where the water table is um
blueberries uh 90 95% of the uh roots of
a blueberry plant are on the top 18 to
24 in um they cannot be in standing
water actually the research shows that
within 24 hours actually 27 hours of
standing water um The Roots actually
start to die so um they can't be you
know there's sort of a myth that people
think that blueberri is uh like to be in
swampy areas they they can't be in uh
wet areas um it has to be well drained
and The Roots can't be in uh standing
water but it does show you in New Jersey
what this um uh water table looks like
um in the pine baronss
here um this is a situation of course
you don't want um this is uh this is a
very wet situation uh we had a uh a few
years ago we had a hurricane that came
through and uh this is on on one of the
biggest farms uh in the area uh this
water is actually uh in excess of 3 ft
deep and at that time um and this this
unfortunately this water was only here
like this for probably a day a day and a
half I did have my reservations as to if
these plants were actually going to make
it but um this planting actually made it
quite well um it was set back and yield
that ye that next year but um but it
came back fine but um but it's
imperative to understand the need of
water and blueberries um the use of
irrigation but at the same time um you
can't have blueberries in a wet
site um and this is a situation where it
was a wet site um you notice that
there's a whole whole area let's see if
I can um uh use my pointer
here um this whole area here um is uh
all the plants have died out and the
reason is phop for root rot um and we
confirmed this in the lab and as a
result
um uh you know this this was the
irrigation uh not the irrigation the uh
the drainage was just not adequate here
and this is very tough to come back from
um so it's it's an important thing that
this should have been uh really
addressed early before um before this
planning was even ever put
in um you know the question I often get
is uh about soil type well you I don't
have Sandy Sandy LOM soils can I grow
blueberries um yes you can uh my
actually first uh exposure to
blueberries was when I was getting my
masters at the University of Arkansas
and those soils were heavy clay um silty
clay soils and um so my first 5 years of
growing and dealing with blueberries was
in an area that was not uh New Jersey
Pine Barons and so we spent a lot of
time and a lot of work uh working on
exactly what uh what does it take to
grow blueberries in non-traditional
soils and uh it can it definitely can be
done and and done very well um but as I
said you need to dot the eyes and cross
all the
teas one of the things that has to be
done is as I mentioned the pine Baron is
high organic matter um the organic
matter here is is high and the
blueberries uh really um need that and
so um uh if you're not in the Jersey
Pine Bar with that kind of organic
matter you need to mulch um and uh we we
did a lot of work in arkans to find out
what was the best mulch actually I I
usually tell people the best mulch is
whatever mulch you can get for cheap
that's the best mulch um and you know
all you're trying to do is is uh get um
uh build up your organic matter um and
we actually did a study years ago um in
Arkansas uh testing these mulches and
this particular study was in Arkansas
and you're looking at a plant here and
um and if you if you notice the um
there's there's markings on this stick
and um after 4 years this plant had
grown to 2 feet and had no mulch the
Wheats were kept down by um just um
hoing
and um and a plant that was planted at
the same time with mulch you notice that
um this is 4T High um there's no
difference whatsoever except for the use
of mulch um The Mulch does a lot of good
things the mulch um uh increases of
course your organic matter um it lowers
the temperature the of the root Zone
which is which is a good thing um it
does suppress weeds to a degree um it
can run into troubles uh um mice and um
different different uh uh animals you
know like the mulch as a as a um Haven
and actually we found that grubs also um
like uh Japanese beetle grubs um Asiatic
Beetle grubs love mulch so um there's a
positive a negative but in the long run
um mulch is is a definite positive from
a blueberry standpoint and it's
interesting to note that um blueberries
in New Jersey were never
mulched um because we had the native
organic matter already High um but after
Decades of growing blueberries um with
no um um with with the use of herbicides
and with we rot a till in the mid middle
of the Rose um we have slowly uh burnt
up our organic matter
and um the soil test coming back uh five
and six years ago the organic matter was
often around
1% um and as a result uh we decided Well
um you know a lot of the guys is
starting to mulch again and um uh I see
there's a question about uh
incorporating mulch um no I don't like
incorporating mulch um uh what you're
trying to do is let it break down but um
um uh the problem with mulch uh any any
uncomposted mulch in the uh rooting Zone
at all is um that it basically robs the
plant of nutrients uh the microorganisms
spend their time trying to break the
mulch down instead of the fertilizer
going to the plant so the only thing I
put in a hole um planting hole is
something like Pete Moss um Pete Moss is
excellent uh and that is what I really
would call the Cadillac of materials as
far as putting in the in the planting
Hall um and I would never put anything
that is uh especially not composted in
the in the planting hole in New Jersey
we either use Pete Moss
or um we uh here we have also a
cranberry industry and we can get
cranberry leaves if you compost them um
uh usually at least 2 years um then that
can be put in the planting Hall but um
it's not a good idea to uh put anything
raw into um into the root Zone at
all um anyone who's ever seen one of my
um uh talks any place knows that I often
say the three most important factors for
successful blueberry growing are pH pH
and pH um pH is critical um and uh I I I
believe that from I work that the uh the
the optimum pH for high bush blares is
about 45 to
48 um and so if you have a soil um that
you're starting with that is not within
that range um it needs to be changed um
to lower pH you add sulfur um to
increase pH you add lime um the amount
depends on how uh what your pH is and um
what your soil type is and that that
those recommendations you can get from
um your soil test but um but the the
bottom line is is that uh you have to
change uh the ph and it it is not an
overnight process um for instance if we
were sitting here right now and and a
grower calls me up and says well I want
to plant in the spring my pH is is uh
6.4 um you're not planting in the spring
um and you possibly may be able to plant
in the fall but in my mind you probably
should wait till the following season um
research shows that um it takes about uh
2 to four months to change the pH but
the organisms that do this need 70 they
work best at around 70 so um it's if
you put on sulfur or right now uh
nothing's going to happen to it until um
late spring so as a result uh you put
the plants in the ground and uh you may
indeed lose them because they're not
going to go anywhere um so changing pH
is a slow process and uh I wouldn't rush
into planting if the pH is not correct I
also tell people that if they are going
to grow blueberries they really need to
go out and get a pH meter that's how
critical it is because um if your native
pH is not 4.5 to 4.8 then you should be
checking your pH Every Spring and every
fall and um and you know that be
cumbersome if uh you're you're having to
run to some lab or something all the
time but if you actually go out there
and take a test and I don't I don't mean
a pH meter from Home Depot um I you need
to actually get a good a good pH
meter
um we as I mentioned we use Pete Moss um
and probably about a 50/50 mix of um
Pete Moss uh and your planting hole it's
best to use people have asked me well
you bring in the top soil no it's really
not good to put other top soil in there
it's actually best to use your soil um
because then you have actually a barrier
between your soil and the top soil if
you if you've brought it in so uh that's
not a good thing um so 50/50 mix is Good
Pete Moss usually runs as I understand
um uh it usually runs of a pH of 3.8 to
around 4.2 4.3 depending on where you're
getting it so um and that's about the
best way to go um Pete m is very good
um well what would be a good pH meter um
there's a question here um actually I
get one I use one from um uh Spectrum
Electronics spectrum and it's called the
pH Pro it runs about
$150 uh I think it's s p c t r u m
spectrum and electronics and uh I often
put um mention this in in the blueberry
newsletter and
um it's about 150 it you can take it out
the field it's you know about the size
of a a large pen and that's that makes
it pretty easy um so uh they they make a
nice one actually we we did some tests
trying to find one that is accurate and
and um reasonably priced and that's the
one we came up with so pH Pro from
Spectrum um and then another question is
if banding sulfur acid in two bands how
much in per acre um
well I mean actually you you you really
shouldn't ban sulfur
um and I'm not sure exactly what the
intent of this question was except you
know they were thinking maybe uh putting
bands down where the plants are if
you're growing blueberries the entire
area needs to be decreased to um that
area of 4.5 to 4.8 um people have this
idea well you you know under the plants
it could be 4.5 and out in the row it'll
be 6.5 no um there's water that moves
back and forth um there's interaction if
if your middles are 6.5 and and the
under the plant is 4.5 at the beginning
of the spring by August um under your
plants are going to be
58 and so um the entire area needs to be
taken down so that means Vicon um you
know you can in fact use pel peliz
sulfur if you like but um the entire
area that you're growing blueberries
needs to be brought into that optimal
range of pH um and that's that really is
critical um varieties I usually mention
uh a lot about varieties um and you know
it's it's not I don't want to make a
knock on New Jersey but um the number
one criteria for varieties in New Jersey
is yield um and season okay that would
be number two so we have we only grow
three varieties in New Jersey we grow
grow an early we grow a mid and we grow
a late our early is Duke our um Mid is
blue crop and our late is Elliot um and
uh yield is unquestionably the uh the
top criteria
um that is uh we really don't care what
they taste like to tell you the truth um
and Duke is certainly not a great
flavored blueberry and Elliott is not
either um so uh you really have to ask
yourself what is your top priority um
the nice thing about uh Elliott it
doesn't get a whole lot of diseases it's
very productive uh Duke is is very
productive um but um if if
uh if you are going to run a picky own
operation it it seems to me that one of
the uh most important things um is
Flavor um you know people can go into
the supermarket and buy uh berries from
all over the world now and often they
are not that that great flavor um but
there are wonderful varieties that are
um available um that are what I would
call actually Gourmet berries um and
Gourmet varieties um and they are seldom
grown but if I had a pick your own
operation that's the way I would go uh
what varieties well um one of my
favorites is Elizabeth Elizabeth is um
easily better than anything on the
market from a flavor standpoint um is it
um is it uh I going to um crop as high
as blue crop no it isn't but um it's
it's certainly much better flavored uh
Elizabeth is named after Elizabeth white
um Elizabeth white basically started the
blueberry industry here in New Jersey uh
it's later than blue crop um one of the
main reasons why we don't grow it is
because it is sort of a a growing um uh
plant that is uh a weeping kind of plant
it's not very upright well in New Jersey
we do a lot of mechanical harvesting and
and a plant that leans over is not not
really good for mechanical harvesting so
uh no one grows it here but um it is
available in fact it's available through
a a um one of the nurseries in New
Jersey here Ammons and um and it's
fantastic um a very old variety that's
early that's wonderful flavored is
ivanho um excellent that's going to be
tougher to find but it's uh I I've
tasted it a few different places now
it's incredible um some of the new ones
Legacy Darrow um uh D's an older one but
Legacy uh is an actual flavor this is
later than blue crop um those are all
good flavor varieties but all I'm saying
is is that you you really need to kind
of ask yourself what you're trying to
put out there and I would I would go for
varieties if I was do pick your own that
um everybody's going to Rave about and
uh and you can find them they are out
there um this is a a young planting um
uh in New Jersey here this is what what
it looks like it might be a little dark
um but again you notice the soils look
very white but again it's it's very
really high organic matter um uh this is
an old shot and um I don't see actually
irrigation um you rarely will find any
no one New Jersey would put in uh
planting now without irrigation um uh
all the new plannings are using trickle
irrigation actually
um and um uh the nice thing is is
because you can put fertilizer through
the uh through your um trickle um here's
a question about Draper and bonus
Liberty and Aurora um we haven't tested
them too much they are in our
trial um and so we're not using them um
I've heard I've heard good things about
Liberty um Aurora is very late uh it may
be too late for anyone north of New
Jersey um draer is not quite as late as
I understand it um I think what uh I
would do is um if I want to look into
these is actually talk to um uh or come
we have a Twilight meeting here at the
research station in New Jersey and that
is in um late May um early June and
actually the main focus of that will be
to walk through those varieties and uh
look at the plants and taste The Taste
the uh uh the fruit so that that would
be available to you also um Draper um
Aurora were developed in um Michigan um
you certainly could get information from
them uh more up-to-date information on
those varieties uh if you'd like to know
more about
them um this is the how we this is what
we call solid City
irrigation um and um uh this is the the
typical irrigation that we use um it was
one of the reasons why it was popular
and uh is still popular in certain
plantings is that it's also good for
frost control um there are places in uh
the pine Barons here that are subject to
frost
and uh so we we often uh um in those
areas uh need this kind of irrigation uh
for frost control um I haven't seen
anybody put this kind of irrigation in
in a long time um I just think uh
trickle is is is more efficient uh as
far as use of water and the whole idea
that you can use uh put fertilizer
through it is is something that that um
has been found very efficient
um this is a shot of a blueberry farm up
in Burlington County um Counting north
of where I am and um and you notice all
the dead leaves on the plants um
blueberries are not good at all at
competing for water um and in a drought
situation they can get into big trouble
without uh irrigation um for some reason
often the the Burlington County um
fields did not have irrigation
or um didn't use it as much as they
should have and as a result uh they ran
into a lot of troubles and this was a
drought um this is back and I believe I
took this in
1988 um and this had lots of
problems and this is what um leaves look
like when they are uh when you're in the
drought situation um you can see the
dieback of the leaves and certainly this
will hurt uh the the future uh yields of
of these plants um you can really hurt
production um and flower production
initiation Etc so um you know I would
never put in a blueberry planning
without irrigation I just uh it's just
um uh fool hearted to do
that um this is an interesting shot here
and um I wanted to put this in I often
show this shot uh
because um it uh it shows you that this
was in Burlington County also and this
was in also in 19 1988 um during a a
drought and the farmer had uh did not
have irrigation and he had used
herbicides and the herbicides went down
this row and then he ran out of
herbicides about
here and you notice the weeds um along
here on both sides and you notice right
where the weeds uh start the plants are
dying um once again showing blueberries
cannot out compete uh anything for um
water and nutrients um and as a result
um that is also why you have to have a
very good herbicide program or some kind
of weed control program in blueberries
because they're just not able to out
compete other crops um they they're one
of the only crops that I know of that
have do not have root hairs um they are
shallow rooted and um and as a result uh
you know they they if you don't have
irrigation you and you have weeds there
um most of what is out there water and
nutrient it's going to be picked up by
um by the weeds not the blueberry plants
so again it's critical um there's a
question here about landscape fabric um
we um we had a grower that has have has
uh tried that um they ran into problems
with it um it seems like a a good match
but um they they ran into problems they
the growth was not there
uh with it and it's something that I
think we I need to look into a little
more but um uh he was very hot on the
idea for a while um it was he came from
a vegetable background and um and he
basically ran into so many problems with
with growth uh of the plants that he uh
tore up the uh landscape praic so um
there are areas other areas of the world
that are using that I know um
uh I was just down in Chile and uh in
Chile they they do use it um pretty
extensively um but um I think that the
you know it's the the jury is out on
that one yet um from a high Bush
blueberry standpoint I think there more
work needs to be really done on that
one we don't use it at all in
Jersey um I wanted to move to a little
bit uh more into
fertilization um and uh we have done an
awful lot of with fertilization uh over
the last 10 years um we've increased
yields dramatically and um you notice on
this on this list here
um jump jump the slide here um and that
is that um as I mentioned we we monitor
um uh we monitor
pH um all the time um we do an annual
Leaf analysis uh we Monitor and correct
any nutrient deficiencies so we really
are trying to get it to grow uh the
plant as efficient as possible uh we
apply fertilizer at the most efficient
time for uptake I'll mention that a
little bit later and we prune correctly
all of these things have uh greatly
increased yields here um you notice in '
94 um we went from 4,000 lb to 22,000 lb
in many fields um so that is a dramatic
increase um and people flat out have
said that they've gotten two and three
time uh increases in yield so how have
we done this um well uh years ago in '
94 uh we took samples of the best fields
and uh 39 samples and what we found was
that um we had deficiencies of all kinds
and and all these fields and uh and we
realized well we've got a problem here
we really do have a problem um and and
what we also found was that if you take
a soil test uh which is this above above
test and you take a leaf analysis that
um there is actually no correlation
between these two tests and these two
tests were taken from the same plant
you'll notice for instance in phosphorus
on the leaf analysis this phosphorus
level here is extremely high yet the
phosphorus down here is just fine um and
soil analysis of the up here of
potassium is low in the soil but the
potassium um down here is actually in
the excessive level so what we realize
now is is that there no there is no
correlation between the soil analysis
and the leaf analysis and
blueberries um so as a result we have
changed how we make recommendations we
do not use soil analysis anymore um we
totally uh base our um fertilizer
recommendations um uh with a uh uh Leaf
analysis the only thing we really look
at a soil analysis for is a um pH I'd
like to see the organic matter content
if that's possible but um that's the
only thing I really want to get from it
um otherwise all of it is based on uh
Leaf analysis and we have these the
chart in front of you is nutrient
concentration and blueberry leaves we
have we do know the levels of uh
sufficient levels of these nutrients so
we can make
recommendations um this slide effect on
nitrogen uptake um and this is what we
do get from the soil test this is the
exact same field oh let me put that back
um this is the exact same field um but
this field on top the pH is at uh 3.5
and the field down here is at 4.5 and
all we did was change the pH put the
exact same bit of nitrogen on and you
notice this top line here is nit nren is
deficient in this 3.5 but in 4.5 it is
in the normal range so um again the the
nutrients are there but the pH because
of pH the blueberry plant is just not
able to pick up um the nutrients and
that's something to understand now of
course you could put more nitrogen on it
to make that to make up for that but the
problem is is that that cost you more
money and PH does affect the
availability of all nutrients here's the
range here of for 3.5 to 6.5 and you
notice that a lower pH these nutrients
are more available malum isn't but it is
uh these are all more available um and
the main thing to know is is though that
pH affects um nutrient
availability um this is iron chlorosis
in blueberries um if you have
blueberries you've probably seen this um
this is actually a good thing because
iron chlorosis is 99% of the time due to
high pH not a lack of iron um so it's
almost an indicator plant that you you
are not monitoring your field right um
that you you're you have no pH meter or
you're just not using it um and so this
is very good okay um so it's very
important to to
notice um this is a blueberry plant in
the wrong pH um these are the roots when
it was planted you notice they did
didn't grow and the only reason why this
plant grew at all was because the the um
the field was mulched and The Roots grew
but again you could see that because the
pH was off these roots did nothing and
again showing you that how important pH
is um the pH uh sorry the fertilization
used to be done when when blueberries
were dormant um we have done research
now and we know that that is not the
right time to do uh
uh fertilization of blueberries the old
method uh was dormant and petal fall we
now realize that the new method should
be Bud break and 6 weeks later um the
blueberry plant almost works like uh
when you're drinking a soda and you put
a straw in the soda when you suck on the
straw the soda comes up from the bottom
when the when the buds break on a
blueberry plant it pulls the nutrients
in up from the root um so if you're
putting fertilizer out there when the
blueberry is dormant um it's a waste of
money and so uh you need to wait wait
till Bud break to put fertilizer out
there and well these are the treatments
that we did um this was dormant uh the
first one was dormant and the new was
when we had Bud bre but we also did a
trickle appar uh um trickle treatment
where we also the trickle was used uh
when the plants were Bud break also just
to see if how that would affect um
blueberry yields
and um suffice it to say that this is
the data from it and the difference
between the old and the new uh was a 21%
increase in yield um and we got a 10%
increase even more than that with the
use of trickle so we didn't spend any
more money um putting in um uh the
fertilizer later we just said okay um
we're going to put it in later and as a
result we greatly increased um the the
uh use of um uh the yields that we got
and um I mean this was dramatic and
actually many Growers have told me that
they have doubled yield um with uh this
kind of fertilizer regime and then
moving to trickle that they have
actually doubled yields and even more
than doubled in many cases um I see a
couple questions here but I'm going to
see if I can get through this and I'll
get back to you if that's okay
uh because we're back um near the
conclusion so um as a result all
fertilizer recommendations are based on
Leaf analysis um you have to get a leaf
of analysis if you're going to um make
some decisions as far as um
fertilization the pH is modeled
monitored annually um the optimum is 4.5
which 4.8 fero application is later uh
it's more efficient and you get higher
yields and in in in uh in effect you get
firmer fruit it's data that I didn't
show you but um it's uh you do get
firmer fruit and if you can fertilize
through your trickle irrigation you
actually can get even higher yields and
uh which which uh you know which is what
you're trying to
do um um Sonia mentioned our blueberry
bulletin um we do not send this out as
an email but this is the uh address of
the blueberry bulletin it's free it
comes out weekly from March through uh
September
um if uh you go on you can just uh
download it and pull it up and it's free
of charge the other thing is I put my
email on here and if you have any
questions after this is over um I
certainly will answer uh your emails um
uh there's a couple questions I don't
know I I'll try to to do
those um Laura do I have time for
questions okay um let's see uh how do
you fix nutrient deficiencies well um if
you do a leaf analysis um then you know
uh what what you uh are deficient in um
and an NPK is classically um uh a
granular fertilizer that you put down um
uh that's one way to do it uh we
actually can also put it through the
trickle as I mentioned um micronutrient
deficiencies are usually um done from a
foler standpoint and they they certainly
can do that um and so they pretty easy
to actually fix a nutrient deficiency
it's just that you got to know they're
there the other thing is is that
micronutrients are critical but the only
time you add um micronutrients is when
you know that you are deficient in them
so um you know you can get into trouble
just as much trouble with too much as
too little
um let's see
um treatments of those of others growing
organically um well um certainly you
still try to time uh there's so many
different sources of uh fertilizer from
an organic standpoint but timing is
still something that is critical um and
we have some grows in New Jersey that
are organic uh the thing is is that you
still want to time it so that the
fertilizer release is
um is uh time for when you have Bud
break and the other thing that you don't
want to do is to have such a slow
release of fertilizer which is the
bigger problem from an organic
standpoint that you are still releasing
fertilizer late in the summer and the
fall um so you're trying to time that
fertilizer for that especially for that
6 we period from
um uh Bud break till in New Jersey it
would be till uh late June so it really
depends on the fertilizer that you're
using from an organic standpoint but
keep that in mind when you're applying
it or getting a source of organic
fertilizer um from organic standpoint
that you're trying to still time it for
that that uh critical time
um right
um when we um when we put mulch down on
now I'm talking specifically on top of
the ground um no it really doesn't have
to be um aged um it will do it will do
better for your planting if it's aged um
and in fact if it if you actually have
composted your mulch um it will be
easier to uh deal with fertilization of
your plants because one of the things
about raw Mulch on top is that people
ask me well do you have to increase your
fertilization rate yes you do uh then
they next question invariably is well
how much there's no way to know that um
depending on the
composting uh stage and the kind of
compost that you have or mols that you
have it's it's impossible to tell you
how much it can be up to twice as much
um and but if that if that mulch is
actually composted already um and and
broken down then um the increase is is
minimal um and you will get the best
benefit from an organic standpoint um
for your planning um and as far as wood
chips or Hardwoods um no I don't believe
there's a difference uh a big um uh a
benefit of one over the other like I
said the best benefit is just finding
one you can get for the least amount of
price if you're near a sawmill and you
know they use specifically Pine and uh
they'll give you the chips that's the
one you want um I've never seen any work
showing one one or the other TI truth um
it's just that uh Hardwoods will usually
break down slower um if you're going to
compost them they'll break down slower
um Pine will usually break down faster
so you know those are those are kind of
the um uh things that you have to think
about um let's see
um well the the one that we use in New
Jersey as far as going through the
trickle irrigation is um one called
plant food ink plant food ink and that
is somebody that uh we use pretty
effectively uh they were actually part
of our research um they're uh they have
actually fertilizers specifically for
blueberries and specifically for trickle
irrigation so they've done a great job
of that kind of thing um the ratio of
NPK um really depends on um on the uh on
your soil test uh and your Leaf analysis
that you get back um you know uh the the
standard thing used to be a 10 101 uh
600 lb of the acre um and uh which would
give you 60 lbs actual nitrogen but uh
that's only a place to start until you
um get up and running from a leaf
analysis standpoint um from then on it's
it's uh the the tweaking of how much the
ratio would be between NPK is totally
dependent on your Leaf analysis okay um
there's a question about sawdust versus
wood ships um uh again if that's what
you can get great I have no problem with
sawdust um uh it will break down faster
um which can be a good thing for the
plants but you'll have to replace it um
more often
um um Walnut yeah I've heard walnuts can
be dangerous because they could they
could uh Supply um toxins um somehow I
doubt you'd ever be able to get walnut
because of the price of that would but
um but I but I've I would steer away
from them I think um from a walnut
standpoint have this are there any more
questions weinar up on there so you can
go back through and listen to it and
you'll be able to pause it on that slide
um I also want to let folks know that a
lot of lot of lot of information is also
available in the hi highbush blueberry
production guide by enr some of that uh
nutritional information is there
and uh if you get onto um Dr Pav's
blueberry bulletin you can get some of
this information and all of that um
those links and everything will be on
this webinar when it's
archived so uh be
um La I might make a comment about um
there was a comment about the pro drib
use by uh Sonia was asking me um and New
Jersey does use prib in bad
years um and but I think the most
important and it is effective but I
would all just uh mention that it you
have to be sure that your pollination is
um not doing well before using Pro drip
because once you put the pro drip on you
you cannot pollinate naturally anymore
so proj does uh result in smaller
berries and later berries but so I
wouldn't use it unless I'm sure that you
know your pollination is not doing as
well as it could have does anybody else
have any other question um there's a
question about uh when to when do I
recommend leaf and El in New Jersey we
basically say when blue crop has
finished which is basically the the end
of July Tom or wh that one particular
end of July slide but uh oh wait a
minute there's one more question here if
you have a rain and can't fertig gate
what method can you fertilize
overhead scary
if you have a rain and can't ferate well
ferate is through your trickle so you
can do that in rain or no
rain um I'm not sure what that what
method can you fertilize
overhead oh
um I'm not sure what that what that
question means tell you the truth um
what method can you fertilize over cuz
we don't we we don't fertilize through
the through our um solid City
irrigation um you know it's either it's
either a ped App application or it's um
for the rest of you thank you so much
for see what he means in
Rain topic today great and um just
trying to see if we got more information
about pration question before I let you
go but that's pretty much the end I want
to remind everybody next next week we
don't have two weeks between these
webinars next week will be the last um
blueberry uh webinar it's on Wednesday
December 9th at 1 p.m. we're going to uh
learn a little bit about um some
Innovations in Japanese beetle control
and also um a new pest in New England
winter moth so I hope that uh you will
join us and Robert sure oh
Laura if I can butt in here um there's a
there's a couple questions one is
someone asked about ammonium nitrate
should it be applied over the mulch or
should it be incorporated the answer is
no no in that you never use aluminum
ammonium nitrate in blueberries never
because nitrate is is not a form of
nitrogen that blueberries can uptake so
you use Ammon forms of nitrogen and you
use ammonium sulfate if your pH is high
but you never use ammonium nitrate in
blueberries okay because the nitrate pot
is actually toxic to blueberries and and
you're paying for that nitrogen sauce
and uh and you don't use it you can't
need it you don't need it and it's not
being used so never use ammonium nitrate
and um and then the other question is
how do you distributed the pelleted
fertilizer the fertilizer is put
underneath the plants not in the row um
and and um what the blueberry guys here
have is a Vicon that is directed in
other words rather than going all over
the back uh there's a there's a guard on
there that makes it just go underneath
the plant that's how that works so I
apprciate
it okay I think I'm done with the
questions sorry
laor okay
byebye thank you thank you everybody for
all the great questions and uh maybe
we'll do this again
sometime bye-bye
now okay I guess I can get
any um for those of you who remain I
think Tom Stevenson you wanted to take a
look at this chart again and there it is
I'll leave it up so that you can take a
peek at it right now now and um the rest
of you you might want to copy down some
of that information but there you go
thank
you e
[Music]
e
e e
hi folks
um
Lyn
uh L let me
just for