all right um I'm going to introduce our
first speaker and his name is Dr Frank C
Caruso he is a professor of Plant
Pathology at the University of
Massachusetts cranberry station in East
weham ma
Massachusetts he has researched goals in
a wide variety of cranberry dis these
systems and we are very pleased to have
him today to talk to us and um Dr Caruso
I hope that you are there and uh are
ready to
begin are we having some audio problems
Frank uh remember that little there we
go got me
I think I can hear gotcha you're there
great okay so I can get
started yes you can it's cutting out yes
you can all
right but it's cutting
out I don't hear anything in my
earphones right now Frank we can hear
you
beautifully okay now it
appears so I don't have to hear any
background I can just go ahead it should
actually be quiet in the back
okay I do I
do okay uh where's my
presentation no I have the welcome
okay it's loading I hope this takes
longer I mean I hope it doesn't take as
long as it did the other day Okay this
seems to be going
better I'm at 50%
now I don't usually get nervous for
talks like this anymore but there's so
much stuff that can happen for this not
to happen in its full fruition I just
hope I have a a better day today than
Bill bich had on Sunday
night so I'm waiting for the
presentation to pop up in front of me
here and then I can get started when I
see
it huh that's weird because on my
computer
but okay
all right Frank you want might want to
check your toggle button and make sure
that that's that little thing stays on
because apparently we're getting a
little bit of cutting
out
yep yeah I remember this was happening
to Anam the other day when we did our
practice okay I have talk in front of me
now I'm G let you go
okay off and i'mna let you
yeah okay Tom well we you have your time
on Sunday with us don't
you all right I did not see any
cranberry Growers but uh even if you
grow something else never assume that
you're not going to grow cranberries so
listen intently here I'm going to talk
today about cranberry diseases
particularly the East Coast version
and of all of our diseases the most
important one that we have to deal with
is fruit rot now fruit rot consists of
two things field
rot before the berries are harvested and
storage rot after the berries go into
storage which doesn't impact you unless
you are a fresh fruit grower which for
us in Massachusetts is about 10% of our
harvested material
yeah I remember this uh had issues
advancing the other day in a timely
fashion
so we have to be patient this is a big
file and
uh
H it's going to be hard to get through
my talk in 30 minutes if this is what
it's going to take to advance each one
of these
slides come on here Frank hopefully it
might be getting better as it uh kind of
gets warmed up here and hopefully it'll
improve yeah of course I've pushed the
button four times which means it's
probably going to jump ahead to the
fourth slide when it finally comes on
so this is very
frustrating field rot is an issue every
year for cranberry Growers and it's a Hu
okay you guys are getting it before I
am and it sounds like it's it's
advancing to probably ahead of where
it's supposed to be early or but I still
have
uh yeah see this is this is strange
because I'm still on the first Slide the
fruit rot slide you guys are ahead of me
and it's hard for me talk until I have
the slide in front of me here all right
earli right well now I got to back
up but maybe I'll say the heck with
backing up because it's going to take
forever I just backed up
one so now we have to wait for me to go
back one so I'm never going to back up
and I'm never going to push this Arrow
more than once I'm just going to have to
be very patient
okay well at any rate I had a couple
slides that you're not going to see but
uh at any
rate the fruit rot that you get in the
field that goes to the Handler does not
include the berries that you can see
right here which is the are the ones
that are left behind on the bog that we
see as trash these are very small and
they never make it onto the truck these
are all fruit rot however although there
may be some fruit worm mixed in
there some of our rots can be readily
identifiable by symptoms this one that
you can see here is the one we call
Early rot and and typically what you'll
see for this one is concentric circles
on the barrier this is our first rot
that shows up in the field this is
caused by the fungus fos sticta these
are all fungal induced fruit rots end
rot you can see the symptoms on the KX
end of the the berry here I'm even
having issues with the pointer here but
there's the pointer you can see the rot
that's developing there on the Kix end
this is caused by the fungus fusic
these berries on the right here
these are ones caused by um rip rot
chopa I'm also having issues with the
pointer which doesn't seem to be working
here either uh healthy berries on the
left chopa is the causal agent here and
now I have to wait for the next slide
can up
here so again I have to be very patient
I'm sorry for interrupting but go here's
yeah okay if you um want to I'll raise
to pre uh host and you can um then we
can watch your cursor but you just have
to promise that you won't push any
buttons that uh change everything on me
and that way we can watch your cursor if
you would
like so why don't I do that I'll just
quick change your
status okay
and now we should be able to watch your
cursor okay well this one you
see this one you see is uh black rot
which turns the berries totally jet
black and the causal agent of this one
is a lantop
opsis again nothing is coming up in a
very timely fashion here
so again patience is a virtue
I should have printed out these things
so I knew it was coming ahead of
time yeah I know you guys all seem to be
getting these before I do here which is
very frustrating I'm still looking at
black Rod
here and I know we had issues with
this okay now I have it this is
miscellaneous rot which means these are
berries that you can't readily identify
by a particular fungus these ones here
so in order to isolate and determine
what the causal agent is these berries
have to be in my hand so that I can
culture out
fungi
again waiting for gdau here I'm still
looking at miscellaneous
rot there's
obviously many issues that uh have to be
dealt with here I apologize Frank in the
future
what's going on because this is
not well this is F this has followed me
my whole life creation of new
problems at any
rate just because you have berries that
look like
here this is not a a fruit rot situation
these are berries that were scalded by
very quick Heat temperature changes
these are rotted berries on the left
here and you can tell they're rotted
berries because you can see all the
anthos essence around the area of rot so
this is how you can tell that you have
fruit rot because those scalded berries
will eventually look like this and if I
don't see them in the field right after
they've been scaled I can't tell the
difference between rot and
scal we have cultered as many as nine
different fungi out of one rotted Berry
and in some instances you'll have a
berry like this one here that has
absolutely no rod on it at all the one
on the
right we have a real disease complex for
fruit Rod as you can see there are 12
listed organisms here the ones that have
two
asterisks a fix to them are the ones
that are the most important for us in
Massachusetts and pretty much in New
Jersey
as well if you go to the Midwest in
Wisconsin and the Pacific Northwest in
Oregon Washington and British Columbia
they're very different situations out
there the fungus fos sticta can also
cause a a disease symptom we call
Blossom blast you can actually see some
of the uh fruiting bodies of the
pathogen right here and right here as
well fruit rot management includes a
true integrated approach of many things
from the application of fungicides to
the using of flood waters uh keeping
good air circulations by pruning the
vines or sanding The Vines uh removal of
trash After the flood irrigating them
properly and using cultivars that are
less susceptible to fruit rot this is a
list of our fungicides that were
registered in this past growing season
you can see we have a wide range of
active ingredients that we can choose
from uh the best one of these by far is
the
chlorothalonil group Bravo chloranil
Echo Equis although some of these other
ones are very good as
well our fungicides go on when the
cranberry blossoms go into bloom usually
our first application going on a 10%
Bloom followed in Massachusetts by two
subsequent applications they will use
one or two more in New Jersey because
they have a bigger issue of fruit rot in
New
Jersey in a conventional situation which
is one where they don't use a spring
reflood that I'll be talking about
shortly again the fungicides go on early
during Bloom to apply those fungicides
you must use the phenological plant
development don't go by just because you
applied your first application June 15th
last year that you should do the same
this year so some years were're two
weeks ahead some years we're two weeks
behind we have mostly protectant
fungicides but now we have some new
materials that do have Kickback activity
or systemic activity indor and
abound uh you need to determine whether
your fate of your fruit are going to be
processed or uh for fresh fruit your
Cult of ours will
determine what you do Stevens being the
most resistant Ben leer being the most
susceptible you should never use any
Fungicide and this goes for you
blueberry Growers dealing with blueberry
diseases you should never use a
fungicide at less the registered rate
there's a good reason why that high rate
and low rate are there because we've
done the testing ahead of time if you
have a material like a Bravo that has
very good sticking agents you should not
add something to it to add presumably
better sticking ability because you'll
end up with
phytotoxicity for us slate water is a
particular management of water that we
use by floting from mid April until
miday by using this you can reduce your
number of applications to as few as one
applications during the current growing
season and subsequent years as well you
can use later
applications and uh the tricky thing is
when you use light water is that bloom
will be compressed into a a shorter time
period and your plants will be very
susceptible to frost coming out of that
flood trash piles you'll see bog side
and these trash piles are a tremendous
source of
inoculum as you can see the fruiting
bodies on this one leaf and the fuing
bodies on this one Berry that are
sitting right in that trash pile these
are pathogenic fungi that are
overwintering here as far as the
irrigation goes you should never water
at night going into the long evening
where the water film will sit on the
plants for 12 to 14 hours water in the
early morning this goes if you have uh
any kind of plants you should irrigate
in the early morning to minimize the
optimal conditions for
infection we do have some cultivars that
do have some field rot resistance as you
can see
here we also have ones that have good
storage rot resistance
we have some new cultivars available to
Growers coming out of the Rutter
breeding program and the Wisconsin
breeding Pro program and we're still
trying to assess the susceptibility and
resistance of these particular cultiv
ours to fruit rot and we're getting a
pretty good idea so far what their
situation
is now some of these fruit rot pathogens
can also cause leaf spot in newly
planted beds this seems to be an
increasing problem and you can see the
the fungus that's probably the most
important is the one at the top there
fos sticta altho katrum seems to be a a
big problem issue causing organism as
well here is a situation where we have a
leaf spot and you can see the Fring
bodies on this particular
Leaf right
there these are simp symptoms of the
fungus fos sticta again you can see the
Fring bodies on the leaves and how it
can sign significantly defoliate the
plants if the infection is severe in
fact with this fungus we're now even
seeing stem caners on some of the stems
because some of our new cultivars are
particularly susceptible to fos
sticta all right leaving fruit rot
behind and what I'd like to do is is
leave questions to the end so can keep
moving
here our next disease of importance for
us is phy root rot it's the same phyo
that affects
blueberries this is what it does in a
cranberry bed and you can see how much
death of the vines are occurring you can
also see how poor the drainage is in
this particular area here's an aerial
shot showing you the significant areas
of this disease that can occur in a
particular bed it's nothing to scoff
at using my pointer I will show you
where
the
new areas of the disease are
occurring get it early is the key again
you can see the areas of poor drainage
and the areas of dieback in this
particular
bog these are some artificially
inoculated plants that we did years
years ago here's a a healthy plant and
here's a phyo infected plant you can see
what it does to the root systems and
that's why the the top of the plants
turn red and will eventually
die here's healthy Roots you can see
they're typically yellow here's phyto
infected plants which are typically an
olivaceous color very rly identifiable
if you take these roots here and you put
them on culture media within 48 to 72
hours we have the fungus phyto camomi we
can do a very quick diagnosis and we can
do this with blueberries as well we did
some earlier this
summer this is the
sporangium filled with sporangia spores
that will spread the fungus around it
can readily spread in
water these are the causal agents phyto
camomi is the most important one but we
will find these two other species of
phyo present
manag and fight tother root rot is again
a truly integrated disease you can see a
lot of things need to be done the low
spots need to be improved drainage wise
you can assist this by sanding those
areas fertilizing the peripheral
plants um using some resistant cultivars
fungicides are very important and
preventing the spread of these this is
the one that you need to do first and
foremost most and in many cases if you
do this one you don't need to do any of
the
rest here are some means of improving
the drainage you can see the area of
phyo there and how they improve the
drainage digging the ditches out
maintaining good drainage is another
important means of controlling this
disease sanding applying sand to the
affected area as you can see here it's
nice when these things advance on a
timely fashion uh these are peripheral
plants that were originally red and with
careful fertilizing they have greened up
nicely and are now moving back into the
area of dead
Vines rimil and alet are our two most
utilized fungicides they're the same
ones that you can use for blueberry
phyto upright dieback boy it really
helps if you get into a nice Rhythm here
I'm just clicking now upright dieback is
a disease that we will see every every
year in Massachusetts they also see in
New Jersey in Wisconsin and the Pacific
Northwest this is typically what you
will see and we will see some infections
that will affect 25 to 30% of the
uprights depending on the individual bed
you may have only vegetative uprights
affected on a 500 to1 basis versus the
fruiting uprights or you may see a one
to one situation where fruiting uprights
are getting clobbered just as badly as
the vegetative ones are here your
symptom right here going from the tip
downward on this one you can see every
single one of your uprights are
affected these are the causal agents of
upright dieback we've proven phomopsis
we've proven synchrono blastia we've
proven fusicoccum we think katrum is
also involved but phomopsis no question
this is the most important fungus
management of upright dieback includes
several things avoiding stress on the
plants managing fruit rot because those
organisms that were listed there not
only can they cause upright dieback they
can also cause fruit frot so they're
multer multifaceted
pathogens in Massachusetts and New
Jersey we're allowed to use a pre-bloom
application of Bravo or champ Bravo is
the better one and as any diseases avoid
excessive Vine growth because this
allows
for perfect conditions for fungal
infection to occur here's the stage that
you need to have of your Vines when you
apply the fungicide for upright dieback
management fairy ring is a disease that
we have in Massachusetts and New Jersey
only it's an East Coast disease and
here's your typical Rings right here in
fact this bog has rings all over the
place it's Stevens which is the most
susceptible cult
ofar here's a closeup of of another ring
that you can see right
here rings are typically found right on
the
ditches now we may actually change the
name of this disease to another disease
based on the finding that we we have a a
very unique
pathogen this one here we may end up
calling the disease viol root Rod
instead and we are still working out all
the details on the life cycle of this
thing it's very complicated life cycle
where it consists of a haid mop
parasitic stage and a diotic
phytoparasitic stage this is the one you
need to control right here on
Cranberries the phytoparasitic stage it
involves a lot of different organism
structures that the the fungus will
produce uh management of this uh we're
still still working out the details on
this but again avoiding stress applying
a bound indar or fur bam but ferbam
comes later you can't apply ferbam until
after June 1st you can use these after
May 1st and watering these things these
uh indor and aound applications in
before and after application seem to
work the
best now we have some minor diseases
that we really don't have to deal with
and
so I listed them here and I'm going to
show you some pictures just to show you
what they look like and and that will
essentially wrap up the presentation
here so let's look at some typical
symptoms of these this is prot venturia
leaf spot we see this one every year in
Massachusetts your typically diagnostic
symptoms on the upper surface of the
leaves this is parabot leaf spot
another Leaf spotting fungus very
similar to Proto
venturia this is rose bloom which is one
of the three exobasidium caused diseases
that we have uh in the east coast we've
only seen this on Nantucket Island so
far this is more of a West Coast disease
but this is the typical flowery type of
overgrowth that you have on the second
year uh buds this is red leaf spot
caused by another species of exobasidium
we had quite a lot of this this year
year because the weather was so wet and
so cool and this is Red Chute disease a
typical Chute infected by this
particular species of exobasidium three
different species of exobasidium
involved uh know it is not the same
fungus that causes fairy ring and
turf this is cotton ball
disease you can see the the melium on
the inside of these berries I've seen
cotton ball one Berry in Massachusetts
in 25 growing Seasons so the fungus and
the disease are here but it's not an
issue for us like it is in Wisconsin and
in Washington and Oregon Wisconsin this
is their number one disease problem that
they usually have to deal with the
fungus is very closely related to The
Mummy Berry fungus and blueberry it has
a shotlight phase that you can see here
so the fungus will sporulate on this
material producing canidia and those
canidia infect the blossoms and result
in those berries that show the the
typical cotton ball symptoms in the
berries boy I wish these were advancing
like this early on and I hadn't lost my
patience so
much this is false Blossom disease which
is caused by a
phytoplasma which is vectored by the
bluntnose leaf Hopper it's a disease
that was rampant in the industry back in
the 20s and the
30s and consequently almost destroyed
the industry in New Jersey um it was
managed particularly well by eliminating
the the bluntnose leaf Hopper but the
fact of the matter is is this this
disease is still present in Wild
cranberry beds in both Massachusetts and
New Jersey and so it has not gone away
it is still around and you can see what
it does to the blossoms no fruit
produced this is one of our virus
diseases our few virus diseases this is
ring spot Red Ring spot probably the
same as we have in blueberries symptoms
on the
fruit it does not impact the yield from
everything that we've been able to
see these are the symptoms on the
leaves this is funky flow condition that
we again just have on the East Coast you
can see the symptom here we have an A
type and a b type and this is the uh
typical symptom of the a type in Mass to
chusetts here we can see normal blossoms
here funky a funky B and this is false
Blossom so we do have some virus
conditions to deal with uh these are
caused by a virus very similar to
cucumber mosaic
virus stem caner Gall is something that
we will see in Massachusetts some years
it uh is caused by the uh very closely
related bacterium to what causes Crown
Gall and we we hardly ever do see it and
it's Associated supposedly with winter
injury this symptom here is very typical
it looks like upright dieback in the
field and this seems to be more of a
problem in Wisconsin than it is in the
east
coast I must mention parasitic nematodes
because we do sometimes have very high
levels of this one in particular
hemicycle offer the sheath NE
nematode uh we don't have anybody doing
work on nematodes in cranberries except
for some spotty work on the west coast
at Oregon State and in British Columbia
they may be more of a problem than we
realize they are and may impact yields
in certain situations we have some
valuable sources of information that you
can learn more this is our cranberry
chart book that we put out of UMass here
every year we renew
it we are currently working on the
second edition of the compendium of
blueberry cranberry and lanberry disease
and we'll have it available to you
sometime next year it is going currently
going through the editor editorial
process we also have this book that
talks about cranberry production as it
is in Massachusetts but cranberry
production here is the same as it is
anywhere they grow cranberries in many
ways and now I have time for questions
any questions does anybody have any
questions for for Frank that was a great
job um we got through that
beautifully and uh certainly cranberries
are really fascinating I had the Good
Fortune to go on a tour this summer of a
cranberry bug and it was just really
really
interesting um I think we might have a
question
coming wellow was kind
of was kind of like uh Tom Brady the
beginning of the Season he couldn't hit
Randy mosson once he got a good Rhythm
he started hitting him time and time
again out of the question for cranberry
Growers Tom uh organic cranberry
production in the east in Massachusetts
and New Jersey is about as challenging
as you can find anywhere we do have
people doing it we do have people that
are doing it
successfully but it's a constant battle
especially with insects and weeds and
with fruit rot so I won't say that you
can't do it but it has about every
challenge you could expect in the world
thrown at you all right do we um have
any additional comments before we move
to our next
presenter yeah believe me there's lots
of discussion on that one in New England
this week very very much for that um I'm
sorry we got off to a rocky
start so I should turn my turn your mic
off and I'm going to I should turn my
mic off now anim shoulder and change the
presentations here
um Dr schelder I should have asked you I
just turned on the shortened version and
perhaps that is not the one you wanted
and I I you had two versions The
shortened and the regular
one anim
make hi I think we can
the shortened version um Laura that is
the one I just cut it back a little bit
because of the let introduce you to the
group um Dr Anna milder is a professor
of Plant Pathology with Michigan State
University in East blancing Michigan
where she works to develop
environmentally and economically
sustainable methods of Disease Control
in small fruit crops and today she's
going to be talking about to us
specifically about blueberry
viruses and anim you can go ahead um it
looks like some people might think
you're a little bit
loud um so I don't know if we should
change
here put it to medium volume
okay can you adjust to where it's
comfortable volume level yes that is
something that they could do
I think I think I would go ahead with
the volume that they're at and hopefully
they can adjust their own on their um
headsets or their own uh audio levels on
their
computer that sounds great well I put
myself to medium volume now that sounds
wonderful and I hope it's not too loud
then perfect
okay so I'll get
started okay well thank you so much
Laura and Frank thanks for being the
guinea pig on this one I hope
mine afternoon
everyone uh do if you have any comments
yeah try to put them in the chat box so
I can see I will try to check that uh I
did notice that my presentation changed
a little bit so if the slides look well
to me they might look different from
what I put together and I'm not sure
what that that is about but I think
everything is there so today um I will
be talking about blueberry viruses um as
you know they have been more uh of a
problem lately and our Michigan
situation has been in the uh in the news
so that has been an interesting summer
and what I want to do is to give you an
overview of the viruses that affect
blueberries um some of these are mostly
prevalent in Michigan and not in many
other places but I thought that you
should be aware of the symptoms just in
case um the symptoms show
up so uh let's see
aha first question is what is a virus a
virus is really quite different from
fungi and bacteria which is what you've
probably realize as people were talking
about the flu virus and how antibiotics
don't work against flu virus
so a virus is is really a very simple
pathogen it consists of DNA or RNA which
is genetic material surrounded by a
protective protein
code um I'll try to get the um the arrow
going
here
H the
pointer there we go so that's the
protein code and this would be the
genetic
material uh they are dependent on their
host whether it's an animal or a a plant
for their
reproduction and the question sometimes
comes up is are they really alive or or
not but they are able to reproduce and
infect with the help of um their host
plants viruses are extremely small they
can only be viewed by an electr
microscope and if you look at this um
this picture next here these are virus
particles uh these would be magnified
100,000 times for you to see them and
they are present in plant sap and as
small as they are it's uh interesting
how much damage they can
cause so what happens when a virus gets
in it plants and so a virus and I've
drawn it as a little
vampire but um in reality of course it's
a it's a boring little particle but if
it gets into the plant cell uh what
happens is it takes off its protein coat
and it hijacks the cell the cell
Machinery to make copies of itself so
the
cell uh will make copies of the virus
particle and of the protein code it
reassembles um and then it gets out from
that cell and starts to spread
throughout the
plant so once it is in the plant uh it
has to redistribute to every cell of
that plant and that could take a while
from several months maybe to a year but
the virus can also end up in the
roots viruses um do not have legs even
though that's what I drew but they don't
have a way to spread except for
vegetative propagation which is one of
the main ways in which viruses spread in
plants and that's a big big problem some
viruses will spread through seed as well
as
pollen uh some viruses need a FS or
other insects to spread them uh
basically the insect will suck up the
the sap of the plant virus particles are
in that and then it will spit it back
out into a healthy
plant um even mites and some nematodes
are involved in the spread of certain
viruses in general viruses have very
specific um relationships with their
vectors so it's not like any insect can
spread any virus it's it's quite
specific
situation so viruses can be hard to
control because once the plant is
infected it's infected for life and
there is no
cure uh they can be present in Woody
plants in a symptomless state for
several years before you know that
there's something wrong with that plant
and they can even spread when the plants
are symptomless and it's further
Complicated by the fact that some um
viruses remain symptomless in certain
plants but they still spread and then
when they get to a cultivar for instance
that's highly susceptible or will show
the symptoms then you get a problem so
they're pretty tricky in that
sense some important points about
viruses uh like I mentioned they most
commonly spread through vegetative
propagation so it's really important to
start with virus-free planting material
and I think a lot of people uh either do
not know this or they well it's
expensive maybe it's not worth it but um
I think it's a very good investment
especially when you're working with a
crop that could live you know 30 to 50
years maybe
longer uh each type of virus has a
specific vector or way that uh in which
it moves from plant to plant and so if
there's insect vectors uh if you control
the vector you control the spread of the
virus uh unfortunately a virus cannot be
positively identified by symptoms alone
uh even though some viruses are so
characteristic that um you know you
could say well that's probably that
virus to be absolutely sure you need to
do a laboratory analysis and the test
that is performed um is akin to a
pregnancy test where you see a colar
reaction and then you know the virus is
present there are also some more
advanced uh DNA based methods uh some
Nursery sell virus tested Nursery stock
and the way they do that is that the
mother blocks from which the cuting are
taken are laboratory tested for viruses
every year uh that's also based on
visual inspection and then uh sorry
visual inspection and tissue culture
alone do not guarantee freedom from
viruses because because some viruses are
symptomless okay so I'll I'll go through
the most common virus symptoms in
blueberries uh the one that I think is
most striking and actually could be
called beautiful especially for plant
Pathologists looking at those uh is
blueberry Sho string virus and this one
has really characteristic symptoms that
almost cannot be mistaken for anything
else but you'll see uh the Oakleaf
pattern so there rening you can see red
blotches on the stems this is usually
what you see the
first and then there's the shoes string
leaves which are very thin strapped
likee leaves so if you see that that is
very likely to be blueberry Sho string
virus this virus uh in addition to being
spread by propagation material is spread
by apids uh it tends to spread down the
road because if it's either walk from
plant to plant it's more easier it's
easier for them to walk down the road
and to Crossroads and also because uh if
there's mechanical harvesting the
mechanical Harvesters could pick up
infective aphids and carry them down the
row uh Transmissions usually start in
spring when aphids emerge and can
continue until fall leaf drop but most
of the spread will occur when aphid
populations explode so one of the the
things uh that you could do to control
blueberry shoestring virus is to monitor
Aid populations and to use insecticides
well timed
insecticides uh including and washing
Harvesters after harvesting an infected
Fields um now when I talk about control
measures for specific viruses I um
emphasize you know additional control
methods to virus-free or virus tested
materials I think the virus tested plant
material um goes for all virus
problems tomato ringspot virus um is
actually a virus that infects a lot of
other hosts in addition to
Blueberry um you can tell that there's
something wrong and we find that this
virus is pretty common in Michigan uh
probably in other areas too New York
where you see Leaf spots sort of
spotting in the plants necrotic spots
and the leaves are distorted along those
spots you can see a decline a dieback of
plants uh usually it's uh one or a few
plants in the area that are showing this
dieback and slow
decline tobacco rings spot virus is
another very similar virus um and it
also looks quite similar it has these
spotting on the leaves
and the leaves are deformed or curled
and infected bushes will Decline and
eventually
die now here we have a little problem
with the formatting of the slide but
hopefully you can still read it um both
of these viruses have a wide hose range
which in includes many weeds d line
chickweed and they can be carried from
um you know from crop to crop by these
weeds uh also they infect tree fruits
apples Etc so if you plant it after an
orchard you might have a problem with
this virus because uh it's transmitted
by dagger nematodes zanima
americanum and this nematode which is a
small roundworm that lives in the soil
and feeds on plant roots can transmit
the virus and even for a year after um
the crop has been
removed so this is a bit of a problem um
so if you do have this virus and again I
would recommend testing or diagnosis
first to be sure that's what's going on
uh if you do remove infected bushes you
should test the soil for the presence of
the dagger nematodes and if they are
present there's a good chance that they
will then transmit the virus uh to the
next planting or if you replant in those
same areas so fumigation with fumigant
or uh rotating out of blueberries for
several years planting uh for instance
Rye that will not um have the the
nematode survive beyond the you know
that year would be ways to control that
and maintaining good wheed control uh
there are some resistant or tolerant
cultivar that can be
planted a blueberry leaf model for virus
is another virus that um as far as we
know only is found in Michigan uh so
I'll talk about it briefly but um just
in case people start seeing these
symptoms uh typically you see uh uh
yellowing or modeling modeling means
sort of a light and dark uh green areas
on leaves
stunting can occur um the leaves are
very small and rosetted and more more or
less
pointy and this virus disease does uh
cause some problems it causes slow
decline in blueberries uh the variety
Rubble especially declines more
rapidly the um control of this disease
sorry this disease or this virus
interestingly is transmitted by pollen
which are carried by bees so you
inadvertently get uh problems or the
bees will be carrying the pollen and the
virus around and as I mentioned is only
known in Michigan so far and the control
would be to remove and Destroy infected
bushes uh and not moving beehives from
infected Fields this just brings another
aspect of certain virus diseases where
uh bees are involved in a transmission
of
pollen you place the hives and what you
do with the hives after pollination of
the
blueberries okay
another virus that is a common or not
very common but it occurs in Michigan
and it's also uh appears to become more
problematic in States like North
Carolina is blueberry red ringspot virus
and just looking at the symptoms um I
think it's quite striking you could see
red blotches on the
stems they sometimes have a beautiful
ring- like shape but most of the time
it's more like a blotch and then you see
a red spotting on the leaves that is
only visible from the top of the leaves
and it's the older leaves that start to
have this problem there may even be Flex
on the fruit and delayed
ripening and let's
see I'm having a little bit of a problem
CU I don't aist or something screen
anymore I don't know what just happened
but this thing is doing things without
me touching
anything so are we back on
track no I don't know what's going on oh
okay I thought I was doing something my
fear was I was doing something
wrong okay well I'll
continue
um okay I hope there's I'm not running
out of time or
anything uh okay so uh the the
formatting has changed here but anyway
blueberry red ringspot virus does not
reduce yield significantly but delays
ripening it does not seem to spread in
Michigan but in New Jersey it's uh it
appears to be transmitted by Mele bugs
so um in the rare event that you start
to see this you know you would have to
monitor infected plants for spread and
watch for MOG in infected
Fields okay blueberry Mosaic uh this is
something thing that we don't actually
know is caused by a virus but we suspect
it's a virus and they have found virus
like particles in these plants but um
it's still being studied and so we know
don't know for sure what virus we we
have there but it's pretty common I
think in many growing areas where you
see this Mosaic pattern uh where there's
yellow and green area sometimes they're
reddish
um sometimes the whole leaves could be
yellowish and so uh it's it's not really
very harmful we don't think that there
it's it's a big deal um it sometimes
looks like it's spreading but it could
be that in cool years you just have more
plant showing
symptoms and the only known source is
infected plant material we don't really
recommend control but if people were
concerned you know the uh the uh recipe
would be the recommendation would be to
pull out that
bush all right
let me see if it's
advancing so let's switch to the viruses
that have really made my summer very
very busy and uh people I know are
concerned about these and you should be
because especially this blueberry Scorch
virus is a very uh potentially damaging
virus is been around in New Jersey for a
long time and it's called Sheep pen Hill
virus in the
area um the characteristic symptoms are
sudden bliding of the flowers and leaves
during Bloom so if you start to see a
lot of uh flowers Al together
simultaneously bliding uh right before
they open that is potentially a
problem also the leaves and the young
shoots will will blight
back
um this disease is common in Oregon
Washington British Columbia also in New
Jersey it has been found in
Massachusetts Connecticut and Europe uh
in 2009 so this year we discovered it in
Michigan at several
locations um and these locations or
these fields were destroyed to try and
contain it because since we don't know
that this disease exists anywhere else
in Michigan and we want to protect our
industry we had to go to this this
process of destroying the bushes uh in
this case we could trace the infection
to uh a specific or two nurseries that
um had plants that were infected but
those had been imported you know 14
years ago from actually from New Jersey
and I'll show you later but they were
not showing typical symptoms so that we
didn't know they were
infected uh other symptoms of the
blueberry Scorch virus are a yellowing
or marginal Leaf necrosis as you can see
here
uh and sometimes some cultivar show Red
Line patterns in the fall so if you see
patterns like these this is really quite
unusual and uh I would be
concerned uh there are multiple strains
of the virus and the symptoms are strain
dependent there is what they call an
east coast train and a west coast train
and with the west coast train there are
some um cultivars which are symptomless
so that is a bit of a problem they can
still serve as a reservoir of the virus
uh so if you planted a symptomless
cultivar you might start to see symptoms
in varieties that show symptoms with
that particular
strain now since then uh they've
discovered that there are many more
strains um that you know really need to
be studied because we don't know all the
reactions of these
strains uh the mild symptoms that could
easily be overlooked and also could be
confused with say nitrogen deficiency uh
are for instance in blue crop a pale
pale greens uh leaves in blue crop uh
the problem we had in Michigan was with
a variety Legacy and the only symptom
that I could tell uh was a yellowing of
the leaves and sometimes some kind of
strange Red Leaf you know stripe
patterns um or line patterns on the
leaves so I think you know the Growers
just thought the plants weren't growing
very well and um and they just thought
they need to fertilize them more
here you can see uh I hope you can tell
that The Scorch infected Legacy row and
it was still a very young planting um is
much paler than this row next to it and
that's the only indication that you
would have had that it was infected uh
the only other way was of course to do
the laboratory diagnosis and it came
through that almost 100% of these plants
were infected with the
virus blueberry shock virus um is very
similar in its
symptoms
um you can see here that you have also a
very uh simultaneous dback of shoots as
well as blossoms same thing as with
Scorch however it is a very a different
virus and interestingly there's a second
flush of leaves that occurs um after
these shock symptoms have shown up you
can see that there's some live leaves on
these on these canes and that
distinguishes it for instance from from
msis um however it is possible to
sometimes confuse the symptoms with say
mummy Berry or with
phomopsis uh this virus is common in
Oregon Washington and British Colombia
and unfortunately in 2009 we found one
site that had this disease it was at our
research station uh we still don't know
where it came from but it is possible
that it came in with some uh variet it
was a variety T trial that was planned
or some some breeding lines we're not
sure we're currently trying to eradicate
this uh
virus now in British Colombia or Pacific
Northwest they find that the uh the
plants after several years of showing
symptoms will come back to full
production and that may be possible in
Michigan as well but we don't know
whether the virus would make the plants
less winner hearty and therefore perhaps
more susceptible to winner injury
uh but over there they are not so
concerned about blueberry shock Scorch
is the way more dangerous one and so um
they're just suggesting to Growers that
they let the disease run its course and
uh but I don't think we can do that
because we don't know what it would do
in our regions and um you know if you
still have it in a small contained area
the best approach is to try and
eradicate it so that it doesn't spread
and this disease can spread very rapidly
because it also spreads via
pollen carried by
bees uh here you can see an infected
plant um and one of the things I want to
point out is that distinguishes a virus
disease uh from other diseases is that
you can see this this plant is showing a
lot of necrosis a lot of dieback of the
ches but the neighboring plants look
perfectly healthy so if you see this
very random pattern of a plant here and
there that has a sudden bliding of of
leaves I think that is what is very
indicative of a virus disease you might
see maybe two next to each other but
generally this uh uh if it was a fungal
disease you would see symptoms on other
bushes
nearby and Laura that is a good uh sign
I'm almost done with my talk here uh so
if you suspect shock or
Scorch um
I would say suggest that you contact
your local Extension agent you can mark
the plants and take Leaf samples from
several branches because the viruses may
not be distributed very well throughout
the plants and you can send them for
diagnosis either to a university
laboratory or to uh agdia which is a
private lab or AC diagnostics is another
private lab that will test samples and
uh the sample should be as fresh as
possible there's more information on the
on our blueberry
website uh plus the fact sheets or pest
alerts that I produced um are available
uh through the webinar for you to
download and hopefully that will help
you recognize the symptoms I think
there's you know no need to panic I
think in many cases we have seen uh you
know just a very small area of infection
that could be traced back um to certain
you know uh
sources and I don't think we have any
widespread occurrence but we have to be
alert or
Vigilant so with that uh I do have this
table here that would just show you or
the different viruses and their symptoms
and their vectors and I apologize for
the uh the formatting change that
happened when I uploaded this um and
also I didn't mention stunt because
that's not actually caused by a virus
but by a bacterial like uh a agent but
there's more information on stunt in on
the website as well as in our virus fact
sheet and with that I'll stop and if
there's any time I'll entertain some
questions one from onid
County can injury from herbicides give
similar
appearance yeah I see
can um I think it can and I think one of
the reasons why we did not recognize
that we had shock at our research
station is because we had a lot of uh
Roundup and so maybe some paraquat
injury in our bushes so uh the only
difference would be that if you have
herbicide injury it tends to be more
widespread you know it wouldn't be a
single Bush here or there and I think
that's that's probably the main way to
try to distinguish
them chance I know
there has been a lot of interest and
Frank has a question there oh it's a
statement wonderful um more information
about um viruses uh at the New England
vegetable and Berry conference in
Manchester New Hampshire and that date
is on the 15th 15th of
December and Google that you'll get
right to their website for registration
inform thank you Frank
oh and I would like to add to that that
uh for anyone attending the Great Lakes
Expo in Michigan uh Bob Martin from
Oregon who is sort of the virus expert
in blueberries and other small fruits
will be attending and we'll be talking
about shock and Scorch as well at that
meeting right that's uh 8th to 10th the
8th to the 10th in Grand Rapids Michigan
okay so there's a question what if you
don't remove all of the roots would the
virus remain in the roots in the ground
yes there's a possibility that while the
roots remain alive that the virus
remains alive so it's very important to
uh if you had infected plants to kill
them uh apply an herbicide first before
you pull them out so that the roots are
killed um let's see
how this is going real fast here is the
Michigan C ification process working
well for nursery plants or is it
possible that infected plants have
slipped through um I think our Nursery
certification process is working however
uh the the one Scorch case slipped
through because uh there are several
reasons one is that it was symptomless
so it didn't initially give uh any
indication that there was something
wrong um and we didn't know that we had
shock or Scorch in the state so we
didn't test for it until several years
ago and when we started testing for it
uh because we had also simultaneously
had plump box virus uh the blueberry
testing was uh relegated to the the
latter part of the season in the fall
and uh we didn't because the virus
concentration lower gets lower the later
you get into the season they had some
suspect samples but they weren't sure
that they were infected so only this
year did they confirm that uh it really
was infected so and those plants were
imported by the nursery uh 14 years ago
so they didn't sell any because they
weren't growing well but um you know
they did slip through uh because you
know we just didn't test through variety
of circumstances but I think we you know
all the nursery plants are tested for
these both of these viruses now so uh we
should be it should be working um okay
let's see sorry
yeah I can read them to you anim um how
trying to catch up all the the questions
here oh no I I think I let's
see how soon after removing can you
replant um I think you can replant if
you're sure that the roots are
dead uh you can replant you know within
even several
months um but I think it'd be good to
plow up
and if depending on the virus if you
have a nematode born virus you might
have to wait longer at least a year uh
if it's one of those viruses like Scorch
or shock you have to make sure that the
insects are all killed if there's any um
um call it transmission by aphids and
such and I should mention that for The
Scorch virus we don't know that it's
transmitted transmitted by the aphid
that we have which is Illinois at
peppery uh but it's transmitted by
ericus species so we're we're looking
into
that uh for the fields infected did you
test for both Scorch and shock Sy since
the symptoms look alike yes we tested
for both because we didn't know uh which
one was
which um do you know if they plan to
record Bob Martin's talk for later Vie
uh that's a good question I will look
into that uh for the Great Lakes
Expo I don't think they have actually
record talks in the past they have just
put the presentation on um online or
they have put some kind of summary
online uh I'll check into that to see if
that's possible and Frank's comment if
you have a positive detection of
squatcher shock in a New England S I
would like to know
okay I I think we should all be um you
know I guest talking to each other to
know where these viruses occur because I
can uh guarantee that once you start
looking there will be some places where
it will show up I think there was a lot
of plant
movement before uh you know we were
really aware of these viruses and some
of it could have been just moved you or
moved years ago and is uh infected maybe
it hasn't spread hopefully but once we
start looking I think we'll find
more um let's see are nurseries required
to test and certify their stock as
disease free no it's a voluntary
program and if you buy plants you have
to ask or be sure that it's virus tested
there are some nurseries that have
visual inspections and they might say
that you know it has been inspected for
diseases but that doesn't mean it's
virus tested it has to undergo a
Laboratory test so you have to confirm
that with your
Nursery do you or Frank have an opinion
about usda's National clean plant networ
very good question I am right now at the
berry clean plant Network meeting in St
Louis um and uh we are working on having
I guess more virus testing done and
cleanup of planting material um and also
perhaps support certification programs
for more nurseries or States through
this
network and I can you know it's still
developing so but they're working on on
it Kathy uh Growers with blueberry virus
concerned in yor should contact Dr carot
Cox is there any way we can find out
which nurseries carried the infected
plants okay is
there
um uh no I well I I guess I'm not at
Liberty to divulge which Nursery that
was um which carried the infected plant
I think they've worked on removing the
materials um and contacting all the
people that might have purchased those
plants um so I think Frank said I think
that's the best I can
do so if you are
contacted the the one thing I can
mention is that for the scor in our area
it was the variety Legacy so if you have
any concerns about you have legac see
and not many people are growing it but
some people are using it for as a
pollinizer
for um Liberty some of the late
varieties uh if you're finding that it's
not growing well I would be uh you know
looking into that and have it test
questions or comments things that they'd
like to share are there any other I want
to apologize to you folks I don't know
exactly what happened today we had some
unusual um
things happened during the presentation
that I am not totally sure why or if
they'll ever happen again but I really
appreciate uh Dr Caruso and Dr scher's
uh willingness to use this technology
and the presentations were wonderful and
I encourage you folks to um I'm going to
leave the website up so if you want to
continue to upload some of the fact
sheets about the
presentations and if you
um if you want to go uh back and listen
to the archived version that might be
helpful as well these are big uh issues
um right now so I just
appreciate help and then we have one
other question from Tom Stevenson about
what about vectors to be concerned about
while maybe
yes um should I answer
that um I think the same
vectors um would be an issue if you're
growing organically or conventionally
maybe there would be less control in the
organic
situation um I wouldn't be concerned
about vectors unless you had a a virus
problem or maybe if your neighbor had a
virus problem uh I would say that really
in most cases viruses get transmitted by
taking
cuting and I know we have several
growers in Michigan who have you know
said oh yeah I just got cuttings from my
neighbor and yes you know that seems to
be the the problem uh because the
neighbor also had a virus problem and
some cases some Growers have noticed
that people have been taking cuting from
their planting at night and uh anyway
that could be a problem if you have had
a virus be a problem for the thieves any
additional questions for Dr schilder or
Dr
Caruso and if not um I'm going to
officially end this and stop the
recording of it but I'll leave it up
here in case you want to continue to D
the fact sheets I really appreciate
everyone's
patience and I want to draw your
attention to the next webinar which is
on December 2nd again a Wednesday at
1:00 and we will be talking about um
site preparation for blueberries and
fertility and pollination man so thanks
thanks again very
much thank you Lara