okay
we're going to shift now to the
presentation for our first speaker
Dr Tracy Lasky reserved her PhD in
entomology from the University of
Massachusetts at Amherst
has been employed as a research
entomologist for USDA ARS at the
Appalachian fruit research station in
Kearneysville West Virginia since 2010.
her research focuses on behavioral and
chemical Ecology of economically
important tree fruit pests and
specifically on developing behaviorally
based monitoring tools and management
strategies for the brown marmorated
stink bug Plum croculio apple maggot fly
and Dogwood bore
Tracy
yes can you hear me Kathy
yes okay okay I'll go ahead then yes so
today I am going to talk about Brown
marmorated stink bug and its emergence
as a serious Pest of Agriculture here in
the Mid-Atlantic
uh to begin with brown marmorated stink
bug is considered an invasive species
and it is native to China Japan Korea
and Taiwan it's defined as an invasive
species because it has been introduced
into an area for which it naturally does
not occur in this case North America and
also because it threatens both
environmental and economic resources due
to the damage it causes in this case to
agricultural crops
now a little bit about the
identification of brown marmorated stink
bug if you haven't seen these insects
yet the adults you'll see on the right
hand side of the screen the lower right
with the male and the female they have
very prominent white stripes on their
antennae you can see the small Arrow
that's pointing at the left antenna of
the male Plum or male uh stink bug on
the outer edges of the abdomen there are
alternating patterns of white and dark
markings and this is actually why it is
referred to as the marmorated stink bug
it's another terminal term for
describing that appearance the underside
is generally pale with some gray or
black markings and of course they emit a
very pungent odor when Disturbed hence
they're called stink bugs and I can tell
you if you haven't smelled it previously
it smells very different than our native
species and some people often detect an
odor of cilantro when they when they
handle this bug although it it is much
more pungent than just the odor of
cilantro now the eggs in the upper right
hand corner are Barrel straight and when
they're first laid they're kind of
bright green but they turn white in
general they're laid on the undersides
of leaves in masses and there are
typically 28 eggs per mask the female
lays eggs in
intervals of seven typically the nymphs
you see the first instar nymphs there
just below the eggs the nymphs typically
the first in Stars will be near the
hatch tags and they will remain there
the seconds through the fifths are very
mobile and in fact they've been
described as sort of tick-like when
they're climbing around on foliage but
you can see that they typically also
have that those white stripes on the
antennae and again that's a good way to
define if these are brown marmorated
stink bug nymphs
now a little bit about the history of
brown marmorated stink bug and these
comments are related uh principally to
tree fruit because this is where we've
seen the most injury at least that we're
most familiar with this insect is
thought to have been introduced into the
United States somewhere between the mid
to late 1990s it showed up in Allentown
Pennsylvania in 1998 but the first
properly identified specimen didn't
occur until 2001 when specimens were
sent by Karen Bernhard who was this who
is with Penn State Cooperative Extension
she sent those to Cornell to Rick hoback
who confirmed they were indeed Brown
marmorated the following year in 2002
they were confirmed in New Jersey and
then we confirmed their presence in
Maryland and Hagerstown in 2003 we found
them in West Virginia in 2004 and they
continued to spread now there was a bit
of a lag period between those
introductions and and detections and
serious injury and in the Eastern
panhandle of West Virginia we actually
did not see injury until 2008 when the
first reports of late season injury
appeared
uh then in 2009 we began to see both
nymphs and adults in Orchards uh
throughout the middle of the season and
there was very serious injury in 2009
and then of course in 2010 this was
really a watershed year where we saw
injury in tree fruit small fruit
vegetables row crops and in Vineyards
and throughout the Mid-Atlantic States
including West Virginia Maryland New
Jersey Delaware Virginia and
Pennsylvania
now this is a distribution map of brown
marmorated stink bug throughout the 48
continental United States so the red
indicates states where we have seen both
severe agricultural problems as well as
nuisance problems from the fall
immigration of bugs from host plants to
potential overwintering sites the yellow
states are highlighted in that they have
had reports of nuisance problems in the
fall with homeowners but no agricultural
injury reported yet however when you see
these yellow States what that is
indicative of indicative of is
establishing populations where the
populations are beginning to increase
and then of course the green States mean
that we've had specimens detected but no
injury reported and no nuisance problems
reported and so at this point Brown
marmorated stink bug has been detected
officially in 33 States and the District
of Columbia
now the reason we were very interested
in brown marmorated and when I found the
first specimen back in 2003 we began
tracking it was because we were seeing
increasing injury from our native
species and in the Mid-Atlantic we have
three the brown and Dusky stink bug you
just disservice and tristigmas and the
great green stink bug Acro sternum
Hilary and in tree fruit this is the
typical injury that we find from native
stink bugs where on peaches we see the
cat facing and gamosas early in the
season and then on Apple which was
typically late season injury we see
these quirky indented depressions again
this is with our native species
and really the reason for that injury
has to do with the changes in our
Management Programs over the years after
the Advent of fqpa where we began to
shift from our broader Spectrum
materials to more specific chemistries
that were softer on beneficials and that
sort of thing so we were really removing
those broad spectrum materials from the
system and what this did was really
allowed increased injury from secondary
pests like native stink bugs
so during that time we were developing
monitoring tools for Native stink bugs
to determine the need for and timing of
insecticide applications and here you
can see the yellow ground deployed
pyramid trap that we had developed over
a number of years we also were working
on attract and kill strategies for
Native stink bugs as well and so for a
number of years we weren't seeing any
injury as I mentioned from Brown
marmorated however in late 2008 and 2009
this is what we began to observe in
commercial Orchards you see on the upper
part of the slide a mature peach with
adult Brown marmorated stink bugs
feeding and if you peel that skin away
this is the typical injury we would see
this Corky dry tissue beneath and blow
us an apple with the large indented
depressions again from Brown marmorated
stink bug feeding
so in 2009 we were actually having quite
a bit of economic injury here in the
Eastern Panhandle this is just one
example of a commercial apple orchard a
family run operation they have about
1100 Acres they produce about a half
million bushels annually and by 2009
Brown marmorated stink bug was their
number one Pest and nearly 10 percent of
all the fruit they harvested in this
case 45 000 bushels of apples had to be
redirected from Fresh Market to
processing due to Brown marmorated stink
bug injury and certainly for commercial
Growers the loss of value are somewhere
between 80 and 90 percent so again
already a tremendous pest
in 2009 the other thing that we observed
was a tremendously large overwintering
population these photographs were taken
on the our building here at the lab at
the Appalachian fruit research station
so you can see the adults aggregating on
the sides of the building on the lower
left you can see the um the bumper of
someone's vehicle with brown marmorated
stink bugs and this really highlights
the fact that they are excellent
hitchhikers and can be taken to new
areas just because of this this Behavior
we see in the fall where they aggregate
in uh in tight quarters including
vehicles and then we also had problems
with them actually uh clogging our air
intake vent which you see in the upper
right
so what I'm going to do now is sort of
take you through what we learned in
terms of 2010 and the field season in
terms of the different hosts that were
attacked and the types of injury that we
observed in the winter of 2010 we had a
tremendous snowfall here in the
Mid-Atlantic something we are not very
familiar with but
um so there was a lot of snow cover and
the question is did that snow cover in
some way help Brown marmorated stink bug
over winter more effectively in other
words we had higher survivorship the
answer is we don't know at this point
but certainly it's a question we have to
address and so what we learned next was
by April 2010 much earlier than we had
ever observed before we began to spot
Brown marmorated stink bugs in some of
our experimental Orchards here on the
farm but also out in commercial Orchards
as well and so we began photographing
them just to sort of document that early
season activity but we presumed because
many Orchard covers sprays are going on
at this time this would protect the
fruit from any injury from Brown
marmorated so here you can see it's May
5th and they're feeding on Montmorency
cherry
here they are on May 10th feeding on a
lowering Peach it's about 20 millimeters
in diameter
Granny Smith apple on June 10th
and second pair also on June 10th and so
you're starting to get an idea of the
number of different hosts this insect
will feed upon and so again we were
hoping the cover sprays would be
controlling this insect but indeed that
was not the case so by late June we were
starting to see the first evidence of
this early season activity in commercial
Orchards and in this case it was very
specific to stone fruit
um
this is a a peach that is immature and
what you're seeing on the surface is a
bit of gamosis on the left but when you
cut that open this is something that's
very unique to Brown marmorated stink
bug we saw these pockets of dead and
sort of gummy dry tissue internally in
the fruit because of that early season
feeding and and it appears to us as the
fruit expanded these Pockets also
expanded as well
we also began to observe something that
was very different from our native
species which is not only was it adult
feeding but also nymphal feeding
typically from our native species we
really only worried about the adults and
then the final major difference was that
we were learning that in fact Brown
marmorated stink bug could reproduce in
commercial Orchards with our native
species they typically would reproduce
on broadleaf weeds and then move into
Orchards but this was not the case with
brown marmorated
so here we are on July 21st and you can
see both adults and nymphs feeding on
peaches immature peaches in commercial
Orchards and you can see the gamosas in
injury
then by The Late July we began to really
see the devastation from this insect
these are some photographs taken from
commercial Orchards that had total
losses of their early season Peach
varieties in this case the grower made
the decision to strip those trees and
allow the fruit to rot on the ground
because it was essentially a hundred
percent loss and you can look up through
this Orchard and just every fruit that's
on the ground had just extensive Brown
marmorated stink bug injury from that
early season feeding
then we began to see the other hosts
that this insect would attack in this
case this is field corn and so you can
see both adults and nymphs feeding
through the husk on the kernels and what
happens is the kernels do not develop
properly they also feed on sweet corn
and when they do the kernels turn brown
because of brown marmorated stink bug
feeding on silk they were inter they
were implicated in interfering with
pollination and then we had a number of
farmers as they were cutting the corn
for silage the brown marmorated stink
bugs in the
fields were so thick at that time
literally they had to turn on their
windshield wipers and so from that then
the question is that silage that was
created would this deter a cattle from
feeding on it because of the presence of
the brown marmorated stink bugs and if
it did not could it in fact taint the
milk because of those defensive
compounds from the insect so this is an
open question as well
now we also saw extensive injury on
raspberries where they were feeding on
the fruit and this was both again nymphs
and adults and severe feeding leads to
the fruit not coming free of the
receptacle and also we started to see
sort of die back at the tips of the
shoots which again we think may have
something to do either with their
salivary enzymes or perhaps they're
introducing something into the plant
that could again be causing this die
back at the tips that we're seeing
they also attack a number of vegetable
crops including Tomatoes you can see the
injury on the surface on that ripe
tomato and you can see the numbers they
really do like tomatoes as well as well
as bell peppers we saw a lot of injury
on bell peppers and you can see the
injury the dry Corky tissue beneath the
surface
it wasn't limited to
vegetables in this case this is row
crops and so in the center where you see
the part of the field that is referred
to as unaffected where the the soybean
plants are starting to dry and finesse
this is typically what we would see but
around the edges of fields where you see
that green area that is from Brown
marmorated stink bug feeding and the
plants do not Nest properly there's sort
of a vegetative response they remain
green and so the pods do not develop
properly the beans do not develop
properly and this was a major issue for
soy green soybean Growers here in the
Mid-Atlantic and so the the soybeans
could not be developed or sorry
harvested correctly and of course there
was losses as well
they also at late August we see this
intense late season Fury feeding period
just prior to them entering
overwintering and so on Apple what we
began to see was really serious injury
and so this is a Pink Lady apple just
about six to eight weeks before Harvest
you see the fruit is quite deep in the
the injury is quite deep in the fruits
flesh and so obviously this is
unacceptable for Fresh Market and again
if it's redirected to processing the
loss of value can be up to 90 percent we
have a number of Growers that were in
this position and so now the question is
what are the processors going to be
doing in 2011 because this injury is
very deep it's very difficult for them
to peel out and so there may be new
requirements also due to the extensive
feeding there may have been questions of
premature drop of the fruit
now we also saw them feeding an
ornamental Nursery crops here they are
feeding on Norway maple on the left and
a newly planted Peach Tree on the right
and we don't really know what impact
that feeding may have but certainly with
the numbers that were out there we were
concerned
we also saw them feeding on Grape late
in the season this became an issue for a
number of Vineyards who had to get them
out of the Clusters or the lugs because
of issues potentially with taint to the
wine of course the feeding themselves
causes collapse of the berries and there
were also a presence of increased rots
despite the fact it was a very dry year
um so those are the those are the issues
in grape we also saw them in nut crops
these are pictures of hazelnuts with
feeding injury as well so you can see
The Host range is extremely broad so
that took us to harvest but in fact the
injury did not end there because in
throughout the Mid-Atlantic Growers have
put fruit into storage at Harvest
seemingly clean
um four to five weeks later we're
starting to see injury emerge from this
late season feeding that occurred during
that pre-harvest interval late in the
season just prior to harvest and so it's
not visible when the injury first occurs
but several weeks later it it appears
and so in the Mid-Atlantic we've had
there's been some surveys done by U.S
apple with Growers reporting or some of
these storage facilities reporting up to
60 percent of the fruit coming out of
Cold Storage having injury so serious
serious problems
so what's been going on well at the
national level one of the issues was
just getting the word out and so back in
September we held a meeting at two
commercial orchards in Maryland Catoctin
mountain and garden hour and this really
brought together both the leadership
from USDA as well as other government
agencies State Departments of Ag and the
research and extension Community to look
at this problem and really get people
talking about the issues and so this was
one of the events that really has been
useful another has been uh the press and
interestingly the Press really started
to pick up on the crop injury at the
same time when the homeowner issues
begin in the fall when the brown
marmorated stink bugs moved to homeowner
sites and probably one of the best
issues or best photographs that appeared
was in the New York Times and so you can
see the headline of the article move
over bed bugs stink bugs have landed and
certainly if you're competing with bed
bugs for press you know it's a serious
problem but you can see these folks this
is about a half an hour from our lab
they are lit literally sweeping up brown
marmorated stink bugs into five gallon
bucket so tremendous numbers of insects
out there
the other group that's been very useful
is the brown marmorated stink bug group
working group that's led by myself and
George Hamilton and this group is
designed to bring the research and
extension Community together and so what
we have been able to do is to develop
priorities for research and extension
and Regulatory and in looking at this
list you'll probably be able to see that
really are um we are at the beginning in
terms of understanding this insect
so this really leads into the research
that we've been conducting and so one of
the things we've been working on is
developing a monitoring tool for Growers
that essentially will allow them to
detect the presence abundance and
seasonal activity of brown marmorated
stink bug and then ultimately to design
behaviorally based strategies like
attract and kill or mass trapping so let
me quickly take you through some of the
work that we've done toward a monitoring
tool looking for visual cues that can be
incorporated into a track a trap design
or factory cues the lures we use a
capture mechanism that is compatible
with their um
uh movement patterns and then a
deployment strategy where and when do we
deploy these traps and so what we have
done so far is look at visual cues
associated with a pyramid trap one that
we had used for our native stink bugs
and we evaluated these five different
visual stimuli sources with baited and
unbated traps over a two-year period and
so we were able to capture a lot of
stink bugs obviously and what we found
was that for both nymphs and adults a
darker pyramid that has baited with a
known attractant is by far superior so
here you see adult captures in 2009
abated Black Pyramid trap 2010 there was
no difference between our dark green and
black but with the nymphs as well we're
seeing a baited Black Pyramid trap being
Superior so that's the first piece the
second is what we're doing right now is
the fact that brown marmorated stink bug
interestingly respond to wavelengths and
intensities of light and so in this case
what we've been doing is trying to
discern what are those wavelengths and
intensity so we can incorporate it into
a trap design this picture by the way
was taken at a bank in Spring Mills West
Virginia and the size of the aggregation
around this light was estimated to be
about a million individuals so we have a
light bioassay right now that's trying
to capture that information and so you
can see where we're releasing insects
into this Arena and tracking their
movement and determining those
wavelengths and intensities
we also are trying to identify the true
pheromone these are headspace collection
chambers that allow us to identify uh
the headspace volatiles being released
by in this case adult male bugs and so
we hope in collaboration with Dr ijin
Zhang who's leading this part of the
project will have a better attractant
that we can use with our traps to really
lure these insects in so that's another
piece of this puzzle
in terms of capture mechanisms and
deployment strategies interestingly
there are a few commercially available
traps from Asia that we were able to get
our hands on and compare with our
prototype Black Pyramid trap which you
see on the right so in this case the
pier the traps that were available from
Japan
they were different in that on the left
you see this clear sort of pyramid trap
you deploy in the canopy of trees
compared with the ground the center is
this yellow water trap that considered
to be visually stimulating to the insect
and again deployed in the tree so we
were able to compare these at our farm
and what we saw was in this case that
our Black Pyramid trap was Superior in
terms of capturing both adults and
nymphs and so compared with these
commercially available traps so again
this is where we are right now in terms
of being able to monitor adult popular
and nymphal populations
so just to wrap up this portion we are
using this dark visual stimulus as our
part of our trap design it's a ground
deployed pyramid because both adults and
nymphs have a tendency to walk up
surfaces that's their natural behavior
we have a known attractant it is
particularly good for the nymph season
long but the adults really don't respond
strongly until later in the season so
identification of a pheromone is really
critical and then we hope to augment
these trap designs with light based on
optimal wavelengths and intensities
now the last piece I want to talk about
with you today before I wrap up is just
the challenges we've observed in
managing Brown marmorated stink bug in
commercial plantings because one of the
issues is that brown marmorated stink
bug has an incredibly broad Host range
they feed on over 300 different plants
and what this means is tremendous
season-long pressure from populations
moving from Wild hosts into cultivated
crops like our commercial Orchards in
terms of managing them we've seen
greatest efficacy when adults have
direct contact with finished Wet Spray
material however because they're
constantly immigrating into plot only a
small population have contact with that
material and so that's a problem also
they have incredible avoidance behaviors
that allow them to potentially Escape
treatments and finally insecticides that
are labeled as excellent against native
species have not shown the same efficacy
against Brown marm rated in fact we have
seen knockdown in recovery from a number
of compounds and other compounds being
completely ineffective so let me show
you this knockdown and Recovery
phenomenon so what we did was to treat
one acre plots with Tombstone which is a
pyrethroid or vidate a carbamate we
recover these bugs from these um
plots and followed their mortality over
time and the reason we did this is
because in grower Orchards where we saw
them spraying pyrethroids particularly
like Warrior and Asana literally 80
percent of the bugs recovered within 24
to 48 hours and we were climbing back up
into the trees as incredible as that
sounds that's what happened so in this
case from this small bioassay that we
did what you can see is we tracked
mortality over
five days and so at the time of
collection all of the bugs were more
abund meaning they were unable to move
but they were still alive their antenna
or leg might be twitching but they could
not climb vertical surfaces or move on
horizontal surfaces so red is dead and
alive means they are capable of moving
once again and so you can see that with
Tombstone by uh by the end of the the
trial about a third of them had
recovered from that exposure and so this
was the issue so what we did was to
think about that in designing an
insecticide evaluation that we conducted
over the winter months where we really
needed to deal with what we consider to
be the primary threat those insects that
come in after the spray residue is dry
so
um
in this case what we believe is control
will depend on residual Effectiveness
and likelihood of uptake so our
laboratory bioassay was designed to be
biologically relevant based on that
primary threat and so all of the
compounds that we evaluate evaluated
through this three-part trial required
about 24 person hours
so this is the list of materials we have
evaluated we evaluated both carbamates
organophosphates pyrethroids
neonicotinoids we looked at the
organochlorine material thiodin or
endosoften as well as other classes in
newer chemistries and this three-part
bioassay included first of all using
ethovision which is a software package
that allows us to track their movements
on insecticide treated dishes in a
horizontal plane so it tracks horizontal
mobility and we would conduct these
trials over a four and a half hour
period where they were exposed to these
dry residues that had been cured for 18
hours then we would remove them from
these dishes and then look at their
capacity for vertical movements to sort
of mimic what may happen if they were
climbing back up into the trees and then
we were tracked mortality for seven days
so I can't go into all of these results
but what I want to show you is the type
of tracks that emerged from first of all
the horizontal mobility
where you can see on the top with water
as a control the bugs kind of behandered
around the dishes there wasn't really
any impact but with Warrior a pyrethroid
you can see at zero hours they appear to
be very stimulated within one hour you
can see the track becomes more irregular
they're succumbing and within two hours
you can see it looks like the bug's just
about dead and that's what we would have
interpreted but in fact because of that
knock down in recovery the all of those
bugs 100 of those tested recovered in
fact they could even reproduce
so we tracked bug mortality for seven
days and this provided us with this
lethality index and I know this is a
long list of materials but what I wanted
to point out is that we basically
we ranked each of these materials based
on how quickly they succumbed to the
material and also the overall rate of
mortality and so you can see that a lot
of the materials are older broad
spectrum materials that were most
effective so to wrap this part up in
terms of the insecticide work broad
spectrum materials including dimethylate
malathione bifenthrin methadathione and
a sulf and a methanol provided the
greatest levels of contact lethality now
certainly within each class the patterns
of lethality are similar but there's a
substantial amount of variation between
active ingredients in terms of the
intensity of effects on mobility and
mortality
based on the activity of registered and
unregistered compounds um a section 18
for dinotaphiran also known as Safari or
Venom is being pursued for tree fruit
with Virginia as the lead State this is
a Mid-Atlantic Regional application and
in terms of tree fruit and other crops
recommendations are being put together
based on what we have in the
Mid-Atlantic which is a season-long
threat now I know in other areas it'll
probably still be more of a late season
threat and in other areas obviously it
isn't well established
so in terms of where we are right now we
have formed a nationwide team of 50
research and extension Personnel
throughout the US representing 14
institutions in 10 states we've put in a
very large specialty crop research
initiative proposal entitled biology
ecology and management of brown
marmorated stink bug and Orchard crops
small fruit grapes vegetables and
ornamentals and in terms of my lab's
work we're going to continue to work on
the monitoring tools and behaviorally
based management strategies but the
bottom line for brown marmorated is that
it's going to require a sustained
Cooperative collaborative and integrated
approach for research and extension on a
national scale and I will tell you that
certainly within the strawberry industry
folks are going to be looking for brown
marmorated in 2011 and trying to
document any problems so far none have
been reported but with the broad Host
range we have to be extremely cautious
and and certainly document the host that
this insect May attack so this is my lab
group that worked with me on all of the
projects that we're conducting and
they're a great bunch of folks and then
finally my colleagues and Growers and
others throughout the Mid-Atlantic and
the US who have worked with me on this
project so I would be happy to get any
questions Kathy if there are any
thanks a lot Tracy are there any
questions
okay we'll give you a chance to think
about that and Tracy will be back with
us after Stephen does his presentation
foreign
Steven joined the Monterey County Office
of the University of California
Cooperative Extension in 1989
as a Plant Pathology Farm advisor Steve
is involved in the educational programs
and applied research and vegetable fruit
and ornamental crop diseases
his research emphasizes diseases of
vegetables epidemiology of disease
systems fungicide evaluations
identification of new diseases in
Ecology of fungi
exploration of alternative Disease
Control methods such as alternative
fungicides biological agents organic
agricultural disease management Steve
has also involved in applied research of
foodborne pathogens primarily E coli as
they occur in agricultural field
settings educational efforts consist of
informing clientele of research results
tailoring results to commercial
operations and diagnosing problems found
in field and Greenhouse
Steve operates the University of
California Cooperative Extension Plant
Pathology Diagnostic lab located in
Salinas and in 2007 he published his
first book a color Handbook of diseases
and vegetables
Steve
great thank you Kathy and I see there's
some questions about the stink but did
you want to take those or should I just
go ahead oh okay I didn't see those uh
let me see
I'd be glad to wait if you want to do
this yeah we could do that for just a
second
okay Laura McDermott would like to know
Tracy if Brown marmorated stink bug is a
pest of blueberries
so um
Rutgers did document them feeding on the
late season variety Elliott in 2010
other than that there hasn't been I mean
they're going to be doing season long
monitoring this year so that's what I
can tell you at this point
okay Pam Fisher would like to know how
it moves to new areas
generally we think that first of all
they are spread in some cases by their
um their fall overwintering behaviors in
that they end up in people's belongings
and they move them to a new location but
certainly we've also seen as they
established here in the Mid-Atlantic
that they move themselves you know that
Leading Edge of the population has
continued to move through our region and
head south so both of those are sort of
providing the spread I would say
foreign
would like to know if your pyramid traps
or patterns thereof are available for
other collaborators
they are we have a blueprint that's
available and also we there is a
commercial provider that is making them
this year uh AG bio which I can provide
that to you Kathy if you want to pass
both the blueprint and that information
on
yes that would be great Bob Martin is
wondering where they overwinter and can
they be targeted at the overwintering
site
we know that they at least some portion
portions up in structures and homes and
things like that but in nature it's a
it's a big question what are the
preferred overwintering sites we've done
scouting and found them under sort of uh
bark on trees as well as sort of in
Rocky crevices and things like that and
that's where they've been reported in
Asia as overwintering but again we we
don't know and so we have some
experiments designed this year to sort
of set up both understanding where they
overwinter most effectively in in in
terms of survivorship but also trying to
trying to track their movements to
potential overwintering sites
Carla is wondering if there's any
influence of temperature or weather on
insect movement
what those thresholds are but at lower
temperatures we see them more than
likely just walking around you know so
definitely I don't know what that
threshold is and even at higher
temperatures on some of our hotter days
these bugs would hunker down and sort of
just rest but again we have to Define
what those are
okay and and the last one for now Bob is
wondering if they have parasitoids for
these insects in Asia uh yes they do
there is a species of uh wasp in the in
the Family seleniana Day genus trisulcus
that has been reported to parasitize up
to 80 percent of the eggs and in fact
those have been collected and are in
quarantine at our sister facility in
Newark Delaware Dr Kim Homer has been
screening these potentially four release
within the U.S but again we're still
very early in that um uh in that process
laughs
Pam Fisher commented Bob would probably
like to go on a collecting trip okay
they'll be trying to ask more questions
of Tracy at the end Steve
okay thank you uh well first I want to
thank Kathy and the organizers of the
webinar for inviting me to participate
and I appreciate the chance to share
some things that are happening out here
West in California but first of all I
want to say I really enjoyed Tracy's
presentation I learned a lot and it
makes me glad I'm a plant pathologist
because some of those pictures are
creeping me out I don't think I would
like to see all those bugs around my
house or my vents either so a very
interesting Tracy and I think my talk is
a very consistent and very appropriate
to put with Tracy because I'll be
talking about uh some recent uh
challenges to Strawberry out west here
which also involved new problems and
perhaps recent introductions so some of
the principles and things might uh you
know really mesh well with what Tracy
talked about
so first I I think the audience here is
probably very experienced but just to
pull us all together I'm going to be
talking about some soil born issues some
new starborn issues on strawberry and so
here's a picture just showing us to
remind us that solving problems by
definition are plant pathogens that are
in the soil so at the top left you can
see uh what's called lettuce dieback
disease on lettuce it's a actually a
very strange pathogen this is a
soil-borne virus the viruses in the soil
it's spread in the soil on the water and
it is very aggressive and causes
significant problems on certain types of
lettuce like this Romaine picture here
and the bottom left here's a sole one
problem on onion this is a white rot a
very destructive disease on that group
of plants and then to the right vertic
sodium weld on strawberry probably very
familiar disease to many of you and
again a soil worm problem so we're just
going to be talking about these new
issues that are soil borne issues in
California and on strong sorry
and just to pull together the basics of
this type of issue again I think a lot
of you in the audience already know this
but there are some very distinctive
features of these challenges that are in
the soil first of all they often survive
for a very long time these pathogens in
the soil sometimes can actually survive
for decades without a host plant there
and as you might guess that is a
tremendous headache for a producer for a
grower or farmer because even if you're
not growing the crop the fungus or the
pathogen is still there so the very
long-term survivors in the soil and
they're often difficult to detect that's
not always the case we have some good
tools for some of these but in terms of
trying to know whether your field has
one or more of these problems it's not
always that easy to find out before you
plant the crop and before you see the
problem occur so sometimes difficult to
detect and find them and I probably
would add to the slide they're also
difficult to diagnose I'll touch on that
later in the presentation but sometimes
knowing which one you have is often not
easy
as I mentioned these would be very
damaging uh you're talking about plant
death or on the on the brighter side
just crop loss in terms of yields these
problems again a very significant
economic factors in agriculture
and part of the reason why they're so
important and damaging is that they're
easily spread
um not quite like stink bugs but we
spread these ourselves meaning we as
farmers and Growers and people for the
most part these are primarily spread as
contaminants in dirt or mud and on
equipment on tractors on trucks so uh
probably The Growers and the pest
control advisors and field Walkers and
our all these people who are moving
equipment and vehicles around that's how
we spread a lot of these we can also
spread them in propagation material so
that's another Factor but most of the
time we're spreading them in the dirt in
which they're found
one problem in terms of managing
Sovereign problems or pathogens for the
most part fungicides are not very
effective we could probably find
exceptions if we look around but for the
most part your fusariums your
verticilliums all these uh many soil and
problems don't respond well and are not
really controlled well by fungicides
and then often these pathogens have a
white Host range so you may be growing
strawberry or crop X you'll say well I
have too much of a problem the sobering
problem on strawberry I'll plant
something else often that other crop can
also be a host and will prolong that
problem so it's a complicated set of
factors here but this one slide kind of
summarizes these features of silver and
pathogens
so the issue that's happening out in
Californians are fairly recent one and
uh I'd like to walk you through what's
happening out here West regarding this
but I would say that even if you're not
out west here and you uh are strawberry
Growers somewhere else in the country or
you grow some other crop and you don't
have these issues I still would argue
this might be of interest to you because
it kind of possibly mirrors or acts as a
model for what happens when new
pathogens are introduced to an area and
when new problems occur and how you
approach it how you diagnose these
things so I think again even if you're
not sharing our issue particularly at
the moment with Californians the
information and the history that I'll
show here certainly can reproduce in
your area with a different crop or a
different pathogen
and by recent what I mean is the die
back and collapse issues on strawberry
that are new we first began to see in
2005 and unfortunately from 2005 through
the present we've seen an increasing
incidence meaning we've seen these
problems spread throughout the state of
California if in one County we had two
fields that had the problem in 2005 by
2010 there were 12 Fields so we're
seeing more and more Growers and more
and more ranches affected by that
very important to point out these new
die back and collapse problems which
I'll show you are not associated with
and have never been associated with the
other well-known pathogens that already
occur in Strawberry so if you're a
strawberry person you know that there's
phytophthora issues and there's
verticillium and there's rhizoctonia you
know there are some well-documented uh
historical soil when pathogens on
strawberries
these new problems I'm showing you today
have never been associated with these
other problems
and the other important Association here
almost without exception these are
occurring in fields that no longer
receive the traditional fumigation
treatments so in California of course
you know our industry has really relied
on methyl bromide and chlorpicrin flat
fumigation meaning we're applying that
fumigation to the entire field not just
to the beds and that practice has really
made it successful in terms of yields
and and dollar value these new problems
are occurring in these fields that no
longer receive that traditional fat
fumigation either because of cost or of
course the change in the regulations and
with methyl bromide leaving on its way
out so those factors not associated with
previous pathogens that are known to
occur and occurring where we no longer
fumigate in the same traditional way
these are really Hallmarks of these new
problems
now today we know that there are two
major pathogens associated with these
problems macrophobina phaseolina which
causes a disease called charcoal rot and
a strain a fusarium oxysprum which
causes fusarium Wilt on strawberry
neither of these were known to occur on
strawberry in California prior to 2005.
in terms of the the history again what's
happening initially I'll show you some
maps but initially we only saw these
problems in Southern California where we
have our Southern crop and now it's
occurring in other parts of California
and I'll illustrate that for you and
then in a second here I'm going to show
you what it looks like if you're not
familiar with these diseases but the
symptoms are very much characterized
here by this list you see the wilting of
plants there's overall poor growth and
performance
and then as the disease progresses and
as you go into the season eventually the
plants will actually collapse and die
and then when you examine these plants
it's very important to dig them up out
of the ground and cut them up and look
inside the plant you'll see a very
distinctive discoloration of the inner
tissues primarily the crown
so let's take a look at these problems
this is the first one this is charcoal
rot caused by the fungus macrophobia and
this is a soil-borne fungus that's known
to occur in soil and I believe you would
share in my opinion that this is a
significant problem if you see this type
of photograph or if this is your field
we have distinct areas where a large
percentage of the plants collapse and
die as pictured here
just a little closer up look to show you
again macro famina or charcoal rot
occurring on strawberry and uh plants
especially the one in the bottom center
photo showing advanced cases where
they're collapsing
the photo in the upper right and let me
try
Kathy's train me on this Arrow here
hopefully you can see that the photo on
the upper right this is a collapsed plan
and I pointed out to you now because
later I'll talk about diagnosing and
trying to identify these problems and
here I would argue and debate with you
the fact that this type of symptom looks
very much like it could be infected with
verticillium so again if you're looking
to say identify this just based on the
picture or on a visual of the plant I
think that's a dangerous assumption
because this is macro femina and not
verticillium
as I mentioned to you to diagnosis or to
assist in diagnosing it you need to dig
up these plants and cut them open and
the macro Familia always shows a very
distinctive discoloration in the crown
here you know already that the healthy
plant tissue will be cream colored or
light colored like this but the infected
plant with macro firmino will have these
very distinctly dark
discolored sections of the crown and
here are three examples of that
now what we do here in California of
course in all states we have plant
Pathologists like myself you give these
plants to a plant pathologist and
they'll take out through sterile
procedures they'll take out small bits
of that Crown tissue and put it in a
Petri plate with appropriate media and
that's what you see in the upper left
here and that black speckly Colony
growing off from those strawberry pieces
that is the macro famina and this is the
way you confirm the presence of this
pathogen in Strawberry crowns
and then I mentioned earlier one reason
why these pathogens like Mac or femina
are so dangerous and bothersome they
last in the soil for a long time and
here in the large photo in the front you
could see why
every one of these little black specks
is one survival structure this is called
a micro sclerosium and every single one
of these little black specks is a it's
like a seed for the fungus it is uh very
hard it's black which means it's able to
resist ultraviolet light and it's able
to survive and persist in the soil for a
prolonged period of time and this is
what the fungus makes to enable it to
survive to the next crop to the next
strawberry crop
this particular photograph shows the
size too there's my trusty penny at the
bottom and uh this is grown in a sand
and cornmeal medium so here you can see
these little crystalline pieces here
these are little grains of sand so this
gives you an idea of the size of the
micro sclerosis how they're very small
and how if the fungus is making these
These are easily transported in
contaminated soil these can be in the
soil in just a clot of mud on a tractor
or disk and when you move that disc to a
clean field you've moved these micro
sclerosis so this shows again why that's
a problem for our Growers and people in
ag
okay so that's the first problem the
second one is fusarium Wilt and it's
basically following the same uh pattern
here recently introduced to California
not seen before in California soil born
problem spreading the soil and we began
by seeing it in small patches the
photograph at the top shows what we
began to see in I think 2006 actually
where uh these small areas in our
Strawberry Fields began to collapse and
die and over time these patches got
larger the photograph in the bottom on
the front shows a couple years later
where these patch these patches gotten
much larger more plants are affected and
we're beginning to be very concerned
about spread to new areas
here's a close-up of that this is
fusarium Wilt on strawberry again it's
our second new development in fields
that are no longer receiving the
traditional flat fume treatment and in a
second I'll talk about diagnosing these
but again I would argue that you and I
we cannot separate this photograph from
the macro formida ones the plant
symptoms are identical and also resemble
verticillium wilt
again you need to dig up these plants
and look at them and cut them open and
again just like the macro femina the
fusarium wilt causes a very distinctive
dark discoloration in the inner Crown
tissue and so again
one cannot diagnosis strictly by looking
at the outer collapse you have to dig up
the plant cut open the crown and look
for this type of symptom inside now as
I've just shown you with macro famina
I'm telling you this is fusarium so how
you say well how can you separate these
well you cannot separate again based on
the symptoms so you take these plants to
your friendly neighborhood neighborhood
plant pathologist and we will again
plate pieces of that strawberry tissue
on the appropriate medium and look for
what grows out and in this case this is
the fusarium which has a different look
to it it's has a very pinkish color in
this medium and we can diagnose it based
on this recovery
the photograph in the lower left shows
you the survival structures for this
fungus these are called chlamidospores
it functions very much the same as those
black specks of the macrophilamina it
survives in the soil for a prolonged
period of time it resists weathering and
this is how the fungus survives between
crops and from year to year
so to show you um our dilemma or our
issue and concern uh here are two
snapshots in time as you will for our
state regarding macro femina in 2005 we
began to see detect and confirm the
macrophomina on strawberry in California
and it was only in two counties we have
a significant strawberry industry in
Ventura County and Orange County so
those are the two orange I'm sorry those
are the two pink stars there so 2005 we
began to get concern for our Southern
California Growers because of this
problem
unfortunately when we fast forward now
to 2010
2010 we have a number of other counties
that also report and have confirmed this
same macro for me on strawberry
as you probably know our major area of
strawberry production California is is
the central part of the state all the
way down through the South so this is
Monterey County actually where I'm
located here in Salinas this is Monterey
County from Monterey County South we
have the majority of the state's
strawberries and you can see that four
out of the major five counties
for strawberry in this area have the
macrophobina
the four counties to the north have
smaller more limited strawberry
Industries so the acreage is limited but
they also have the problem so you could
see why we're concerned about the future
when you have this spread and increasing
incidents throughout our state
so that's macro formida
and then here I want to show you a
similar pattern although at this point
fewer Stars thankfully for fusarium Wilt
on strawberry 2006 was the first year we
confirmed fusarium on strawberry in
California and you could see that the
only place we found it was in Ventura
and then we fast forward to 2010 we have
two sites two counties with the fusarium
that's good news bad news the good news
is it has not spread to say 10 or 8
counties the bad news is however the
fusion has been found in one of our
major strawberry producing areas and
that's my home base in Monterey County
here in the Central Coast of California
so even though there are only two
counties affected these two counties
probably account for I would estimate 65
to 70 percent of our state's strawberry
production so even though it's not
Statewide yet the fusarium has touched
down in our two major producing counties
in terms of the distribution as of last
year just for background information
macro flaming is not a new disease uh in
California only it's also occurring in
other parts of the world and I might add
it's very interesting to note that for
all these other parts of the world
reporting macro femina it's primarily
showing up again in locations where they
no longer use methyl bromide so Egypt
France India Israel and Spain these
places are reporting macro femina on
strawberry and these are places where
they are not using the traditional
fumigation practice anymore for
macrophobia we need to add Australia
Australia is another country that has
macro femina on its strawberry
in the USA maybe some of you know about
this I don't know where you all are from
but right now in Strawberry it's been
confirmed I've reported in California
Florida and Illinois
and then I talked to you earlier about
the counties in my own state with that
map
for the distribution of fusarium if you
zoom slightly different than macro
formula macro forming is a new worldwide
development and what I mean by new is
you know in the year 2000 and Counting
that's when macro femina began to be
reported on strawberry Fusion is a
little bit different fusarium is not a
brand new disease because the beliefs
the Japanese and maybe the Koreans
reported fusarium back in the 1960s and
19 early 1970s and I think Australia
also has had it a long time so a few
zero mode on strawberry has been in the
world a longer time and unfortunately
now we in the USA are just added to that
list of infested countries
but for us it's brand new in California
for whatever reason the fusarium wilt
disease on strawberry has been reported
in California and South Carolina in
terms of USA states
so let's talk a minute here about
something that I think is extremely
practical for almost all of you probably
uh participating and listening in today
and that is uh diagnosing you know if
you're a grower or a pest control
advisor or you walk fields and make a
recommendations or you're a sales person
selling products to Farmers and people
in ag
you know that it's extremely important
and critical actually to identify and
know what the problems are I mean if you
see a stink bug on your crop you better
call Tracy to find out which one it is
right you need to know what what the
problem is and have a precise
identification of the problem and for
pathogens that originate in the soil
that's very much a challenge and as this
Photograph here illustrates I'd be glad
to bet with you your lunch money about
which pathogen or pathogens might be
responsible for these symptoms the point
is you can't tell and I as a
professional who work with these 12
months of the year I cannot tell which
pathogens are responsible for these
dieback problems because it could be one
of our new issues that macro famina or
fusarium or it could be one of the old
time favorites verticillium phytophthora
we do not know and I want to use just a
couple minutes here to illustrate why
this is a very big Challenge and why
it's important to recognize the issue so
the first challenge is with our new
issues here our new problems the macro
for a minute and fusarium in my mind are
virtually identical in terms of the
symptoms poor growth stunting die back
plant collapse discardation of that
Crown which I showed you and also I
haven't talked about this too much but
very much stress related both of these
pathogens can really cause the most
severe damage when the crop is stressed
and that is either through environmental
extremes when it's very hot and dry or
there's a little bit of water stress if
you're a grower and you're half a day or
a day late watering and the plant's a
little bit under stress because of that
water shortage the these pathogens are
very aggressive and cause much more
damage and much more rapid development
of problems under stress so for macro
ferment and fusarium both of these act
the same they look the same you and I
cannot separate them readily without a
Laboratory test so diagnosing these are
going to be a problem for you they're a
problem for me
and then to expand this a little bit I
mentioned the old-time favorites
vertical and phytophthora for the most
part these symptoms and features are
shared by all four of these problems the
two new ones macro femina infuserium and
the old one spiritual and phytophthora
so if you have these types of symptoms
in general it's going to be very
difficult for you to know what's going
on without the support and help of a
laboratory or an extension pathologist
or someone who can actually have things
tested
um the one exception here is phytophthus
are really not considered a stress
organism you can have
um if I talk through issues on
strawberries that are growing quite well
and in fact as you know being a water
mold it likes lots of moisture in the
soil so the stress thing is it's not
quite relevant here
there's some good questions here if it's
I think it would be a good chance to
take these right now
are these problems worse under plastic
culture uh maybe Teresa can send me a
follow-up question
I'm wondering if you need plastic
culture meaning large hoop houses that
cover the whole planted area or plastic
covered beds that the plastic is just
covering the beds and the plants are
planted into that so I need that
um have these diseases ever been
observed in fumigated Fields
um we have seen them in fumigated Fields
again we need to qualify this here in
California our experience is primarily
with the production Fields these
production Fields have been fumigated
with Alternatives not the methyl bromide
chloropicarine they have been um
fumigated with these new replacement
materials we are seeing these diseases
in those situations if it's fumigated
with methyl brolic chloropicarine at the
appropriate rate and that's the
traditional treatment we do not see and
have not seen those problems so yes we
are seeing them in fumigated fields and
these are ones that again are in the New
World being treated with alternative
materials
uh okay and then finally the question
about Nursery stock as of right now and
uh I think we need more information from
the nursery producers in our state we
have not heard of significant problems
of these two new pathogens in the
nursery production uh Counties have not
seen that and we do receive materials
from them for testing for other things
and so far I've never isolated
macrophobia or fusarium from transplants
coming from those areas we do get those
standards the vertices
but no we have not seen these new ones
from transplants yet
okay Teresa got back to me see
the question is
um
uh okay so I think she's asking do we
see these problems or are they worse in
fields where the beds are covered with
plastic and then the plants are planted
into the plastic as opposed to the use
of straw or mulch as a covering of the
bed for us in California you may know
this we do not use anything except
plastic we don't use straw or mulch
covers for strawberry production so we
only see it in in the beds with the
plastic but that's because all
strawberries are planted into plastic
covered beds so as of right now I don't
know the how that might how that Dynamic
might play out for other types of bed
covering
and then the last question then I move
on for a second here
the question is has Macro for me to
let's see
question is can macro Familia be a
problem in temperate in a temperate
climate zone
um
and I I'm only a mere plant pathologist
so I you need to Define for me exactly
what temperate climate means does
temperate mean me here in central
California
um
Mediterranean type climates uh I'll look
for the reply on that I'll go ahead here
and get to that question in a second
okay so we in California have these
problems uh hopefully you won't but the
way things move in the world and with
these new developments perhaps you will
so uh what are we collectively going to
do about dealing with these problems
again I think an audience like uh this
today you're probably very experienced
so uh you could do this slide you could
put this together you would approach the
macro formula or fusarium issues the
same as you would any other cyborg issue
that's nothing novel about that when
it's novel is the fact we have new
pathogens on strawberry in California
and what's novel is we're in an era
where we're losing the main tool methyl
bromide that has been used in years past
to to defeat these these challenges so
that's what's novel what is not novel is
how you deal with it it's going to be
the same as with other sobern issues so
first of all
um select the appropriate site I mean if
you have the flexibility and the ability
to just move off site don't plant in an
area that reports a history of this
problem if you know that this field over
here down the road has macro femina then
you would not be well advised to lease
that ground and plant strawberry next
year stay away from known infested sites
very important is crop rotation if
you're a diversified grower and you grow
things more than strawberry just don't
plan something that's a host don't plant
strawberry don't have time to go into
this today but we know or feel that this
fungus will affect other crops that are
known to be hosts of macrofreaminas so
example is pepper so if you have a
disease strawberry in a field don't
plant pepper there either and don't
plant strawberry anymore try rotate
crops you know plant lettuce plant
broccoli plant petunias plant things
that are not a host rotate away from
that problem rotate away from Strawberry
for conventional Growers fumigation
remains a tool a management tool but the
question is which materials I'll show
you a slide near the end here that shows
our work in California that indicates
some of the Alternatives do control the
macrophobia and fusarium but it's not
100 and we are getting uh escapes and
we're getting a reinfestation of these
problems so that's not the answer in
itself we do have fumigation that will
help but it will not eradicate the
problem because it's not as good as
methyl bromide chlorpicrine
if you have access to resistant
strawberry cultivars that is obviously a
good management tool for for solvent
problems I'll again show you at the end
some of our work we show that there are
differences in the varieties and so
um we have the ability to maybe in the
future breed for some resistant
varieties as of right now we don't have
true resistance but we have varieties
that are more tolerant plant those if
those are available if they fit your um
your your situation
as I mentioned to you both the new
problems uh are definitely stress
related plants that are stressed from
environmental extremes and I think I
forgot to mention fruit load plants are
distressed with a very very heavy fruit
load that's good for you the grower
that's bad for a strawberry plant that's
already infected with Mac or famina a
heavy fruit load puts a physiological
stress on plants and that will
definitely create the onset of very
severe and fast developing symptoms for
these problems and finally of course we
talked about soil if you are moving
dirty soil infested soil from place to
place between Fields you are going to
move these pathogens so stop that don't
do that we're having more and more
Growers actually wash off equipment it's
a big pain in the neck but it's
something that is extremely important if
you want a safeguard clean fields in the
long run
okay let me uh quickly take a couple
more questions here
um
okay oh great question uh there's a
question about whether you can have uh
this problem show up in cooler climates
like northern Europe uh Poland Germany
um very good question and um I would say
of course uh we never want to say never
so we can't say that but we can say that
macrophobia entries area are both well
known as warmer temperature pathogens so
both of these pathogens prefer warmer
soils and I think I won't go back here
but you can see from the slides in
general a lot of those countries that
report the problem tend to have areas
where the climate's very warm so as of
right now we haven't had any of these
reports from say Norway so I would think
that the equivalent climates would
either not have an issue with these on
strawberry or if you eventually have the
issue the severity of the problem may be
lessened because of the cooler climate
both these pathogens like warmer
temperatures and I know that's relevant
relative but still I think uh northern
European uh production might not have
the same issue
uh
uh okay and I can't remember if Tracy if
we
I think we got Tracy's question she's
going to be leaving us soon uh question
from Bob
um oh does this uh prom occur in soybean
Illinois or in soybean anywhere I guess
where plants are under stress uh and yes
the answer is uh yes macro firmina is a
well-known pathogen of soybean so
soybean has been a known host of Macro
femina for for a decade or longer
probably a long time and so that's very
much a known part of the problems for
soybean and I don't know about the
stress thing for soybean but I imagine
the profile is similar if the soybeans
are under water stress or other issues
we do tend to see macrophilia to develop
faster on any crop under stress so
definitely yes to that good question
so in the time I have left with you just
a little bit about our research to
highlight what we discussed earlier so
um there are differences in Strawberry
varieties in terms of susceptibility to
the macrophobina and we're doing similar
work with this on fusarium as well just
want to show you a little bit of
information here so for example in this
scale a bigger number is bad so Diamante
here at the bottom the maximum is five
Diamante has the 4.9 disease severity
ranking that means that it's a extremely
decimated by the macro femina when you
infect it however the Seascape has a 2.9
it is significantly more tolerant to the
fusaria sorry to the macrophobia it
holds up much better but I hasten to add
that it has a 2.9 we would like to see a
1.0 there a 1.0 means basically no
symptoms the plant is not affected by
the macroflamina and we are looking at a
resistant plant Seascape is not
resistant but it is more tolerant so it
holds up better but it is still diseased
but this shows you that our hope is to
develop varieties that are resistant and
so that we would have a chance to
develop that and replace the ones that
are very sensitive
uh Bob is asking are these numbers the
severity index numbers here related to
crop load in this particular experiment
No in fact I'll show you the next
photograph this is a controlled
experiment in a shade house we
inoculated potted strawberry plants just
to see the basic reaction to the fungus
and this does not have anything to do
with Harvest fruit load or just the
fruit load of the plant itself so no it
is strictly susceptibility of the plant
to the fungus
and this is what I'm talking about Bob
uh so here is our Seascape on the far
right it has been uh injected with the
macro for me that just like the other
varieties but you can see that even
though they're inoculated at the same
time the Ambiance Ventana are much more
sensitive to the macro femina the
Seascape holds up much better however if
I gave you the Seascape plant and you
cut it open you could see slight
discoloration in the crown meaning that
it has been infected and if you wait
long enough the Seascape will start to
show collapse problems as well but it'll
take a much longer time to develop
and this is kind of summarizing the work
overall in terms of some of the
resistant variety so let's look at the
column here for macro fomina I just
showed you Seascape Seascape and
Chandler are two strawberry varieties
that are we're calling it resistant
resistant does not mean immune immune
means you don't even get infection but
they are infected but Chandler and
Seascape hold up much better to macro
femita than say the varieties Monterey
San Andreas and Fontana which are
extremely susceptible or sensitive
and the other column under fusarium
however the Chandler and Seascape
unfortunately are very susceptible so if
you have both of these problems in your
field one or the other is going to get
you unfortunately
if you inject these plants with fusarium
the Monterey San Andreas and fentana are
resistant so that's good news but of
course as I mentioned they are
susceptible to the macro femina so we
have the unfortunate situation where
there's not yet one variety that will
withstand both of the new challenges in
California
okay then finally just to talk about
chemicals so the the deal is as I
mentioned we're losing the best of
bromide chloropicrin the the standard
methylprylic grin at a high rate used as
a flat fume application in California to
treat the whole field that is going out
and we strongly believe that is why
these new problems are coming in the old
traditional meter controllers going out
so the new pathogens are coming in so we
have looked at alternative treatments uh
the list is here to see if there's
something else that can really help us
in combating these problems and two
things to note here one there's a lot of
different treatments I won't take the
time to go through this but a lot of
different treatments this is one of
several uh one of three experiments
we're doing in this type of research
Define an answer to these sober problems
so we have a lot of Alternatives we're
looking at
secondly the photograph is important to
remind me to tell you these are applied
to the bed in California we're getting
away from applying it to the whole field
the public opinion The Regulators the
general direction of the world is away
from using all these chemicals at high
rates and high volumes so one way to
address that is just to apply it to the
beds the beds are pre-formed they're
almost ready to plant the the fumigation
material or the fumigant material is
then injected or applied to the beds
sometimes applied through the drips drip
irrigation that's in the bed already and
then later after time has elapsed the
plants are put into the beds that's bed
fumigation so we're applying these
materials in this system in this bed
fumigation method
and again time will allow me to do this
or go through this individually nor do
you want me to do that the bottom line
is if we saw something that was
um equivalent to a methyl bromide
chloropicrin traditional fumigation the
bar would reach the number one here but
go no further we are looking at trying
to get something equivalent to a level
one in terms of disease severity
you can see the good news here the good
news is a lot of these Alternatives the
first nine or so control the problem
quite well and so they're doing a good
job at controlling or at least knocking
down populations the bad news is they
are not comparable to that level one
they all allow some macro formida and
some fusarium to creep through and
that's what we're continuing to see in
these fields we do see die back and
collapse even though the the field the
plots have been applied with these
materials and you can see uh controls
number 10 so over here way on the right
that's something that is not acceptable
and we have three treatments that are
about the same as a control so our
situation in California we say none of
the New Alternatives some of which can
already be used will give you the same
level of control and we are seeing
breakthrough in some disease occurring
despite the use of those new alternative
materials
so I think I'm about done here in
summary uh I've walked you through two
new soil borne issues in California for
our strawberry producers these are
fairly recent developments uh we're not
unique we in California share these
problems with other places in the world
and the country but being the country's
number one strawberry producing state
we're quite concerned about these new
problems caused by macro famina and
fusarium
uh hope I made my case to you a precise
field diagnosis is not possible so if
you're in a different state and you
begin to see begin to see diabetic
issues in your strawberries I encourage
you to again locate your friendly
neighborhood plant Pathologists or
someone qualified to help you with
diagnosis because it will take
Laboratory Testing to confirm what
you've got there
and again the way things happen in our
country in our world with movement of
materials and such you likely will see
some new disease at some point maybe not
these two but something in the future
if they are something you'll see you'll
be likely to be concerned like we are
that these are going to be persistent
problems that would need to be dealed
with in a long-term strategy
and again really excuse me there's
really nothing new in terms of the
strategies
you'll be similar to what we do for
other soleborne problems and I went
through that with you that's basically
nothing new there but uh something that
will have to be applied now to new
issues at least for strawberry
okay
um like Tracy before me I also want to
acknowledge and thank a lot of people
especially the strawberry growers in my
state of California and we have a very
nice Industry Group the California
strawberry commission that's funded our
research and then there's lots of people
who have helped us with the project as
well as our research team really want to
acknowledge all those people and again I
really want to thank Kathy and the
organizers for allowing me to share this
with you today and with that I will pass
this back to Kathy
thank you very much Stephen
are there questions for either of our
speakers
while you're thinking about that
thank you for participating today I want
to remind you that the second in the
series on emerging past ID and
management will be next Friday afternoon
at the same time they'll have Dr Robert
Martin who's going to be talking to us
about strawberry viruses and then Mr
Mark bolda who's going to be talking to
us about management of spottedwing
dysrophila in small fruits
so while we're waiting for questions I
also want to point out to you
oh the box is not here anyway
um I have posted the first two
recordings online and they are available
and
I will be editing last week in this
week's webinars hopefully this afternoon
and have those posted sometime early
next week
okay oh here goes somebody
okay no questions yet here is the uh
link for the webinar recordings
okay if there are no questions thanks
again speakers we really appreciate your
participation and we'll see all of you
next week thank you everybody
thanks Kathy