This is a production of Cornell
University. We're all here. We're going
to start. Um, yell. I'm a thirdyear PhD
candidate in plant breeding and genetics
here at Renault University in the Larry
Smart Lab. Um, organizing our lab's
annual hemp webinar. This is the seventh
one this year. And apart from this one,
we only have one left. I hope you've all
been enjoying
them. Um, as you know, we are focusing
on him this year and today's speaker is
Dr. Bob Pierce, who is joining us from
Lexington in Kentucky. Thank you, Bob,
for accepting our invitation. We are all
excited to hear your talk. Dr. Bob
Pierce is an extension professor and
director of hemp programs at the
University of Kentucky. Martin Gatton
College of Agriculture, Food, and
Environment. Dr. Pierce grew up on a
small Kentucky farm raising corn,
soybean, hay, and barley uh borlick
tobacco with his family. He received a
bachelor's and master's degrees in
aronomy from the University of Kentucky
and a PhD in soil chemistry from the
University of Georgia. During his more
than 30 years as an extension specialist
in Kentucky, he has conducted field
research and extension programming on
transplant production systems, soil
fertility, conservation, tillage
methods, and sucker control programs for
tobacco. Currently, Dr. Pier's hemp
research focus is on best economic
management practices, sustainability,
and rotational cropping systems for
field production. He coordinates the
broad hemp research efforts for the
college and assists researchers
interested in hemp with securing funding
and accessing them raw materials to
support the research efforts. Um
remember that we are recording the
webinars and we've recorded all of the
webinars so far and we've uploaded them
to our school of integrative plant
science YouTube channel. And without
further ado, please. Yeah, thank you
very much for the introduction and uh
appreciate everybody for for joining
today and and uh listening to this talk.
So, um I've made a slight adjustment to
my my title. This is one of those things
where you agree to do something and then
it's time to submit the title. So, you
submit, you know, the first thing that
pops into your mind and uh then you
start preparing for it and and you
think, well, why did I submit that?
because I think it would be a bit
premature at this stage for me to say
that I'm going to talk about the best
management practices for agronomic or
agronomic practices for grain hemp um
because we're still in the process of
developing those. And so I think a
better title for this topic is that
we're going to talk about better
agronomic uh practices for uh for grain
hemp. And in order to to do that, I'm
going to start uh by giving just a
little bit of a background of of my
journey with hemp. Um and so hemp was
not really on my radar. I was a tobacco
specialist uh working along and then in
in 2014 uh the farm bill allowed states
in the US to begin conducting research
on hemp. Prior to that, hemp was lumped
in with with marijuana. It was all
considered a schedule one controlled
substance. And so no no no research was
really being done on it um you know out
in the in the field certainly and a
colleague of mine uh Dr. David Williams
uh stepped up to initially lead the
program here at the University of
Kentucky uh beginning with that 2014
farm
bill. I was sort of there on the
periphery. Um tobacco had already
started to decline at that point and we
knew that that was going to continue.
So, our tobacco growers were were
looking at other options and my interest
in hemp was really in in trying to find
other things for our tobacco growers uh
that that they could grow and apply
their knowledge to. So, um between uh uh
between 2016 and 2018, I had uh about
one trial a year working with hemp. And
uh to say the least, my initial attempts
at growing hemp were were certainly less
than spectacular. Um poor stands. I had
a lot of difficulty. Um you know, when
hemp came in, everybody was talking
about what an easy plant this was to
grow. Um so, you know, it had me
questioning my agronomic abilities. Uh
but I soon learned that a lot of us were
really struggling with uh just how to
manage this this new new to us uh in
many cases. uh plant. But with that
experience, um a year later,
unfortunately, uh Dr. Williams was
diagnosed with the with the terminal
illness and he and others asked me if I
could step in to um take uh a little
more uh part of the of the hemp program.
And so I became the interim director of
hemp programs and later the director of
hemp programs here at the the college in
2019. And that was a really busy year
for us. Um Dr. Williams had already set
up a lot of things that were were in
place. We had a visit from the the then
US Secretary of Agriculture, Sunonny
Purdue, our Senate leader, uh Mitch
McConnell. And fortunately, uh with some
help from uh Wade Turner and our crew at
the Quicksand location that had been
helping David previously, uh we were
able to get some good good stands going
so our politicians had a nice backdrop
uh for their for their photo op. Um, we
also had multiple visits from USDA
agencies that year from ARS and RMA and
NRCS
um coming to to see what hemp production
was uh was all about. Um, we had a a
massive field day. Over 600 people from
uh 25 different states in the US and I
think four or five different countries
um came that year to uh in in August uh
to view our plots. Um,
and during this time in a in about a
four to six month period, I went from
being a a you know, just on the
periphery of the hemp program, uh, to to
being, um, a an aronomy hemp aronomy,
uh, expert, so to speak. And so, uh,
that was that was quite a whirlwind. And
in the backdrop, all of this was was
going on, uh, was the what I call the
CBD hemp boom and bust. Uh we went from
about 5,000 acres of hemp in Kentucky to
26,000
uh in 2019 and then back down again um
to about 5,000 the year after. So it was
a you know really really whirlwind kind
of a ride in
2019. In 2020, things were beginning to
calm down a little bit and of course we
hit COVID, but uh been in the process of
of building our hemp aronomy research
program. Um we have had a bit of
research on uh CBD or uh floral type
hemp. Uh but really have have built a
lot of our program around grain and and
fiber uh production. And in order to to
do that, had to put together a good team
of folks.
Um, Tara was my my field technician uh
field manager initially. Uh, John Weey
has has taken that over for the last uh
year or so since Tara went back to
Pennsylvania. Tom Keane uh Wade Turner
who I mentioned and their crew uh that
helped us with a lot of the planting. Uh
Natalya is my lab manager. um Manahar
and Andrea um postocs in my lab working
on uh seed seed quality seed germination
issues. Um Magdalina uh is a PhD
candidate working primarily on uh
integrated pest management and working
directly with u Dr. Gocha whom I think
you you heard from earlier this year in
this seminar series and also with our
enemologist uh Dr. uh via AVA. Um and
then Paul Coxin's a PhD uh student in my
lab uh that is is working on uh root
growth and seedling bigger. And then
we've had a whole host of of
undergraduate workers who have come
through the lab in the last five years
uh that have been incredibly valuable in
in working on these projects. Also need
to take just a moment to acknowledge our
funders uh because that's been an
important part of what we've been able
to do. Um we started with a with a
project from a company called Pixus. Uh
that lasted about a year. Um had a
couple of projects with the hemp
research consortium in conjunction with
both Cornell and uh North Carolina State
University. We've been very fortunate uh
to have a good relationship with a local
with our local um USDA ARS lab here in
in Lexington. and in the last couple of
years have have developed uh a project
uh collaborating with the uh uh plant
genetic resources unit there in New York
as well with Zach and Tyler uh as well
as some funding through USDA NEA to help
keep our our program
going. So, I mentioned that I'd done a
lot of back in 2019 was doing a lot of
national webinars and some things like
that. And this is a slide that I used uh
quite a bit then um just to try to help
folks understand what we really didn't
know at the time about hemp and and
where we
uh many of the things that we needed to
to learn about. And a lot of this is
still applicable today. Um you know
initially uh we didn't have hardly any
information about the varieties. All of
the all of the varieties or the
cultivars that we were getting at that
time were generally being imported from
out of the
country and you know there hadn't been
any breeding efforts or anything that
had taken place in the in the US for
many many years. Um so we had a lot to
learn about uh cultivars. Um, initially
again we were just getting seed from all
over the place. The quality was highly
variable and and not too good in many
cases. We had a lot of issues with stand
establishment. Uh, I'm not going to talk
anything about the transplant
production. That was primarily um, you
know, work that we were doing for u
floral production. So I'm going to
concentrate more on the grain today. Um,
the next one, the the fertility
management is honestly, you know, when I
went into this, I thought that this is
where I'm going to make my mark because
of my training in in soil chemistry and
soil fertility. Um, but I found out
pretty quickly
that if we don't have the proper variety
or cultivar, and if we can't
consistently establish stand, is very
difficult to do meaningful fertility
management work. And so we had to tackle
some of these other issues before we
could even begin to fine-tune some of
our recommendations uh with regards to
that. And then, you know, we had a we
did have a lack of of registered
pesticides. That's still a bit the case,
although we've got more more options now
than we we did. Um and then we still are
are working out, you know, some
appropriate harvest uh and post-h
harvest processing methods. And I'll I
will um make some uh ending comments on
on that um this afternoon when I when I
get there uh to the to the end of the
presentation. Um I also made this
comment at the time. This was when you
know the CBD floral hemp was going like
gang busters and and growers were
receiving recommendations in some cases
not not good recommendations from all
sorts of people. um and that you know
industry was was moving faster than than
research was being able to keep up with
appropriate production practices. Um
since the industry's cooled off, we we
begin to get a a little bit head of more
ahead of that curve, but we still got a
long ways to go. So, I'm primarily going
to kind of focus on the things that my
group my my lab has been doing uh around
cultivars and seed quality and stand
establishment in in hemp today. Those
are are going to be my focus areas uh
for
today. So when it comes to
um gaining more knowledge about uh
cultivars uh we are a participant and in
fact coordinate the the multi-state
dualpurpose trial which dual is is grain
and fiber uh as part of the S1084 USDA
multi-state project. This began in 2019
and actually David Williams was was
quite instrumental in getting S1084 up
and running and had already volunteered
to coordinate this
um project. And so then he turned that
that over to me. And we have about
anywhere from about 12 to we've had as
many as 20 um universities participating
in this um in this project in any one
year. Um and typically we select a group
of 12 to 15 cultivars uh that go out to
all of those those folks. Now you know
some of the challenges that we've had
with that is that the availability of
seed changes from year to year. So
keeping the consistent list of seeds has
been difficult. Uh many of the owners of
these cultivars require material
transfer agreements and so there's um
some um legal barriers at times uh that
universities don't want to uh agree to
all of the requirements under those or
um you know just a matter of trying to
to get uh get everybody to to agree uh
on what needs to be in those um those
agreements.
stand establishment. Um you'll hear that
as a common theme throughout my talk
today. Uh is has been challenging. Uh
weed pressure. Not to mention the fact
that that this is a rather massive and
uh somewhat messy data set when we've
got all these different uh participants
and uh different cultivars and and
things like that going on. And I'll just
point out in the in the picture here uh
when we first started this process uh we
didn't have a lot of funding uh to go
with it. And so we were using a lot of
handme-down equipment. So this is an old
tractor from the turf unit. Uh this was
an old soybean cone planter that we had
modified. It was a 16-in um planter and
in order to get the narrow rows that we
wanted, we actually had to drive two
passes over over every row uh of plants
in order to to get the uh the row
spacing that we wanted. So, quite a few
challenges. We just recently published
uh and this just came out in in January
of this year uh the first three years
from 2019 to 2021 of the multi-state
data.
Um want to acknowledge uh Dr. Zach Brim
at the University of Florida and his
student Ajet uh who dove into this
massive messy data set and did the uh
did the analysis and really wrote the
first draft and and led that publication
effort into all the co-authors for
getting this this information out there.
And I'm just going to share with you a
couple of of excerpts of this this data.
um 2019 I don't even think we knew
enough or we we hadn't developed the
program enough to to request that
everybody do a a stand count prior to
harvest. So we didn't have data for that
year. But for 2020 and 2021 uh we got
some uh pop plant population data at
harvest. uh in
2020. Well, in 2019, everything was
planted at the same rate, just a
straight u number of of kilograms per
hectare of seed regardless of
germination or um or seed size. In 2020,
we corrected for germination. And
finally in 2021 we corrected the the
seeding rates for both germination and
seed size so that we were approaching a
target of about one and a half million
seeds live seeds per hectare. And you
can see that again getting back to our
theme on stand establishment our our
established stands or our harvested
stands on average were only about a
third uh of that
target. And you can see across our
different locations um there was a wide
range of populations. We only had seven
cultivars uh that were were consistently
included in the trials over the those
years. Anka, CFX1,
uh Katani and X59 were all uh of
Canadian origin and the others were of
Eastern European uh origin of the of the
cultivars that we had. And in all of
these these next sets of of graphs,
you'll see those um those seven
cultivars, our locations are colorcoded.
Uh starting with kind of the dark purple
and going to a lighter purple and then
coming to a light green and going to a
darker green. That represents a north
south gradient with purple being the
northernmost and the dark green being
the southernmost of the locations. Uh
incidentally, we did have during this
same time frame, we had locations
attempted in uh in Alabama and
Louisiana, but um they never were were
able to get u enough uh enough stands or
enough yields at that time um to to be
put into the to the data set because of
some of the
challenges. If we look at grain yields,
um pretty low in in 2019. Everybody was
really just kind of in a in a learning
mode at that point. Uh 2020 2021 we did
a little bit better, but you you do
begin to kind of notice this north south
gradient
uh with some of the more northern
locations doing well. Uh in Kentucky
where these uh light green uh bars down
here at the bottom, we really struggled.
Uh in in 19 we did okay. We had some
decent yields there, but in 2020 and
2021,
um we were we were struggling with uh
with establishment. After 21, we made
some changes to our rotation and to our
planting methods and and things began to
to improve uh after that. Overall, uh,
X59 CFX1, uh, out of this group of
cultivars, you know, tended to be the
ones that that had the the best, uh,
grain yields, and those are indicated by
these solid black dots, uh, with the
with the error bars on them. That was
the the overall uh overall locations
means for for those
cultivars. our fiber or straw yield.
Again, very low in 2019, uh quite
variable in 2020. And you really uh with
fiber yields, you really start to see
this north south gradient in in yields
there. Um Anka and some of the Eastern
European cultivars generally uh on
average were a little bit better uh a
little bit more consistent for fiber
production uh than CFX and X59.
So, you know, we've learned a lot from
from those early uh early seasons uh
about which varieties are are better
suited to certain
uses. We're working on compiling the
2022 to 2024 uh data and hopefully we're
going to we're already beginning to work
on a on a publication for that. I'll
just give you a quick summary and
apologize I don't have a uh a nice
pretty graph uh put together yet for the
for the 2024 data. So, we've got
locations across the top here, cultivars
going down this way, and our cultivar
averages. Uh, this is for grain yield
across all locations over here on the
far right hand side um of the
table. You know, couple of things that
that I'll point out. You can see we we
have gotten a little bit better
certainly in our locations in Kentucky
going from some um you know sub 500
pound yields to uh over close
approaching 1500 pound yields in in this
trial. Um of course we'd all like to uh
figure out what Heather Darby up at the
University of Vermont is doing what her
secret sauce is for uh for getting these
kinds of yield sheet. She had a a really
good production year up there. Um, and
overall we're we're seeing, you know,
we've got some some cultivars like
Futura 83 um that are performing uh
fairly consistently across uh across a a
large number of locations. So, we're
definitely seeing some improvements in
that variety trial
program. When it comes to fiber
production, um similar sort of thing. Uh
here we've got Ursa Alulta which of
course is developed at at Cornell uh
being the the overall the best fiber
producer uh that we had in the
multi-state last year. Of course it
didn't produce much seed uh only we only
had seed at the our grain really at the
Kentucky location um but we harvested it
really late
there. So, you know, we're beginning to
amass uh a body of information uh about
at least some of these different
cultivars over a wide range of u of
conditions. And I wanted to put up this
up here because in addition to the
multi-state cultivars, which are these
here on the left hand side of of this
graph, and again, we've got our yields
now approaching uh 1,500 lb uh of grain
uh raw grain per acre.
Um, we had some additional cultivars
that aren't in the the multi-state trial
that we were just triing locally uh
where we're actually even getting better
yields than that. Um, and some of these
are are experimental uh cultur breeding
lines. Uh, some of them are hybrids. So,
we tested our first hybrid about two
years ago and we're we're getting more
and more hybrids in into the trials. So,
I'm I'm very uh optimistic uh about our
opportunities to to improve yields um
through through better cultivar
selection. And you know, I think it's
been just been a very short time over
the last four or five years and we're
already beginning to to see some pretty
significant improvements there. So, I'm
very optimistic about seeing that uh
continue. So future directions for our
cultivar trials or variety trials. Uh as
I said, we're working on publication of
the 22 to 2022 to 2024 data. Um we want
to continue to evaluate these u range of
cultivars across different environments.
And you know, one of the things we've
discussed as a as a goal for our group
is to work towards developing a a system
much like we have for soybean of
different maturity groups uh that would
help in the selection of hemp cultivars
for different
latitudes. Uh certainly we want to try
to get some of these new breeding lines
and improved hybrids and cultivars uh
into our trials. Continue to develop
best management practices.
um working on refining our measurements
and evaluations especially when it comes
to like flowering so we can can work on
developing this grouping system and
we're working with uh with Zach Stanzel
uh and the phenotyping guide uh that
that they've put together to try to to
work on our u on our methods for
evaluating this and also refining our
integrated pest management practices
with regards to to these different uh
cultivars.
cars. So, I want to switch gears a
little bit and start talking uh more
about some of our infield establishment
work. Uh going back to 2019, uh went
back and I, you know, got some seed size
information and germination information
on on the seed lots that we had and then
went back and looked at our population
counts that we had. And, you know, I I
thought we had really good stands in
2019. Um, but it was kind of
disappointing to look and see that we
still were were just kind of hovering
around 50% establishment. Meaning that
50% of the live seed that we planted
resulted in a a harvestable plant. Uh,
which agonomically speaking is just is
not not really acceptable for a
commodity crop. If you think about corn
or soybean or even wheat, um you know,
you you're certainly your expectation is
for better efficiency than that in terms
of of the amount of seed planted to the
number of plants that are are
harvested. So, uh Paul uh my my PhD
student has been taking a a closer look
at some of this establishment um and
looking at at population counts. Um and
what we had there was just counts that
were taken um sort of 14 days after we
after we planted. Um Paul did a little
more intensive counts uh starting at 3
days after planting and every two days
thereafter went out and counted the
number of plants uh for the first 23
days which we kind of considered that to
be our establishment period uh of what
was was going on um there. And he did
this for a selected group of cultivars
that were in our cultivar trials. And so
for example, this was in the fiber trial
in in 2023. Um you can see there our
best performing cultivar in terms of
establishment was Fedora 17. Uh and we
got you know close to to 90%
uh of the seed that was planted was
appeared to be established by the end of
the establishment period. And we had a
range, you know, down to about 70%
establishment for uh for the cultivar
Yuma. We also did our our typical uh
population counts at harvest right
before we harvested materials. And you
can see that in almost all cases, we we
lost a considerable number of plants
from the end of the establishment period
to the to the time of of harvest.
Um, so not only do we have the initial
establishment, we also have this loss of
plants that's that's occurring. And
that's been something that's been pretty
consistent uh throughout a lot of our
trials. Uh, for a dual purpose trial in
2023, um, lower lower target population
of 32 plants per per linear meter. Um,
and we didn't get quite as high a um
establishment rate as what we did in the
fiber trial, but still Fedora 17 here in
the purple um was our best uh our best
establishing cultivar in in both trials
um that that particular year did did
very well for both. But again, we see
that there was between the the end of
establishment and uh and the harvest
period, we are continuing to lose some
plants along the
way. Now, I'm going to go back to this
one, and you'll notice that this was in
2023. These cultivars, you know, we were
approaching uh 20 to maybe 25 plants per
linear meter uh relative to our target
of 32. uh 2024, same cultivars, same
planting system. Um planted about two
weeks later because we had had some some
wet weather and then we got uh fairly
hot and dry. And you can see our
establishment was was uh much less in
2024 uh under under those conditions.
And this was also we did have irrigation
that we were applying. So was wasn't
just a moisture um moisture deficit. Um
there was something going on with the
temperatures were warmer as well and uh
just conditions were were were different
in 2024. And so again we're we're having
this this issue with you know we got
good stand establishment in one year and
then not so good in the the next year.
Even with these lower populations, we're
still seeing some drop off in the
numbers of plants. By the time we get to
harvest, we've only got well, we've got
less than than 30%
uh of the live seed we planted,
resulting in a in a harvestable
plant. Now, another thing that that Paul
did in his counts was he didn't do this
with every count, but at least once a
week, he was counting the number of
nodes on each plant. And so this is a
representation of the number of plants
within each row that that had a certain
number of nodes on them. And so, you
know, you can see we start out with
with, you know, u one, two, three, and
four node plants. Then a week later,
we've got some five node plants, six
node plants that are are coming in. Um,
and you know, we don't have as many
small plants. The interesting thing and
we saw this on several occasions was
that three weeks after planting when it
came to count now we have you know we
all our plants had grown beyond the one
and new to two node stage but now we've
got more one and two node plants showing
up which is suggesting to us that we we
have secondary flushes of seed emergence
plant emergence that are are going on.
And so we've got this established canopy
and then these smaller plants coming in
underneath. And so while these might be
counted towards our establishment
period, uh they you know some of these
plants may or may not compete
successfully to to uh become harvestable
plants. And Paul did observe uh you know
some some plant loss. Um you know we had
some um wilting of plants which we
presume uh is probably dampening off. Uh
we had predation by insects uh chewing
on plants both you know what we called
larger bivvery and smaller bivvery which
would be things more like flea beetle.
And then there were some some instances
of of just necrotic tissues that we
couldn't explain um from environmental
stressors that were happening in the in
the plant. So we did know that there
were some we were losing some plants
during that establishment period.
So what we've seen from this is that you
know these inadequate stands you know
may be a result of low initial emergence
seeds that that never emerge which is
what we saw seem to see a lot of in in
2024. Seedling death that occurs during
the establishment phase itself while the
plants are still young. And then we've
got this loss of established plants
occurring through the growing season.
And these are all areas that we need
additional research on in order to to
really understand what's going on with
our population dynamics uh through the
season with uh grain and fiber
hemp. So one area of study that we have
have worked on in my lab is looking at
seed
quality. Initially our seed lots were
were pretty poor. Uh a lot of the seed
lots we were getting. you know, we would
have seed lots with 60 or uh 70% uh
germination rates and these were
standard germination in a growth
chamber, not not what we were get seeing
in the in the field.
Um, hemp presents a challenge I think
for seed producers because of the way it
matures um and the fact that at any time
that they harvest there's going to be a
certain proportion of immature seed. Uh
also, you know, hemp seed apparently
does not store well, particularly at
high temperatures. Uh and certainly if
you have high moisture and high
temperatures, um then those those seeds
won't won't store as well. But um you
know, we've been doing cold storage for
the last several years and having much
better luck with preserving our our seed
lots that we've got and also I think uh
the germination of seed lots has
improved. Um, we do adjust all of our
seeding rates, as I said, based on a
target seeding rate for with germination
and seed size. So, we correct everything
uh to make sure we're putting out the
same number of seeds for for each uh
cultivar. So, as I mentioned, I think
that that uh seed lots have improved in
germination. The green bars represent
the germination for our seed lots that
we received last year for the uh for the
multi-state variety trial and you can
see a lot of these are are at 90% or
above. There's a few that are closer to
to 80 particularly for some of the newer
cultivars. Um but in my experience even
with tobacco it's not uncommon for a
newer cultivar to to have lower
germination rates while they're in the
process of trying to increase the the
seed for production. And then the purple
bars uh were those same seed lots that
we had stored for a year at 4C
um and four degrees C. And um looking at
germination and you can see for the most
part our germination is pretty well
preserved. Again, we had one seed lot
that looks like it it may have gone down
a little bit more than than
others. In addition to doing the
germination work, um Andrea is also uh
looking at we we've acquired a vibe seed
analyzer and among other things that
allows us to sort seeds based on um
various parameters. In this case, we're
sorting based on color. So we have brown
seeds, which are presumably uh seeds
that were mature at the time of harvest,
white seeds, which were approaching u
maturity, and green seeds, which we
presume to be relatively immature seeds.
And we've got them separated. She's got
them separated here just for the
purposes of of this picture to to show
the differences. But with this machine,
we can put a a you know a sample of seed
in there and it will come back and give
us the proportions of brown, white, and
green
seeds. Looking at seed sizes on those,
um you know, we've generally found that
the green seeds do tend to to weigh a
bit less, be a bit smaller. white seeds
uh sometimes are weigh less, sometimes
they're pretty similar to the brown
seeds in in
weight. And when she puts those in a in
a standard germination test, you know,
blue is so blue is our our original
seed. Um and we see from that, you know,
about 80% germination. Brown seeds
germinate at a higher rate. White seeds
kind of at a similar rate to the
original seed lot. And in some cases,
green seeds can be quite a bit lower uh
in in
germination. And so the you know the
overall germination rate of that seed
lot uh is
um depends on the on the proportion of
these lower germinating seeds that are
that are in there. But uh really
interested uh to to try to continue this
work. Um like I said, this is just
standard germination. We also want to
look at whether or not these green seeds
perhaps have lower viability as well.
So, not only may they germinate at a at
a lower rate, those that do germinate
potentially may have uh lower seedling
by uh vigor and not be able to establish
as well. So that's a an ongoing area of
research within our lab to to try to
better understand um the role of of seed
quality in in seed
vigor. Um uh Paul has also done some
work um looking at root vigor and root
growth in hemp plants. And he's done
this by growing uh growing hemp
seedlings in clear cylinders in a gel
material uh that's meant to simulate a
root growing environment or soil. But we
can come in and periodically
um take pictures uh of this. And then
Paul is using a u software to extract
information out about the root length
density uh rooting depth, root angles,
all kinds of information that we can
relate back then to the to the
performance of these uh varieties in
their establishment.
And so this is just an example over time
uh of the variety X59 at 6 days old, 9,
13, 15, and 21 days. Um the same same
root system, how it's developed over
over time and rooting depth. And just an
example of of what we we're trying to do
with this, we took the the rooting depth
at 21 days and the population counts
that we had u from our field studies. So
this is a relative stand establishment
here. Um which basically is the stand
establishment percentage of the of the
cultivar compared to the average for
that year in trial because remember we
had a big difference in the in the in
the two different years there. So we
kind of had to correct for that. So this
is this is how each variety performed
relative to
uh the average of that particular trial
and and year. And we've correlated that
with the rooting depth that Paul
measured in the gel and we get a pretty
good positive correlation there. Um R
squared is not real high but point4. Um
and you know Paul's going to continue
with this work to
[Music]
um to to try to to relate more of these
rooting characteristics to the
performance that we're seeing in the
field and hopefully come out out of that
with some some breeding targets that we
might go after. um for
that. So I've talked a lot about trying
to reach the the target populations
which brings up the question of what is
the target population? What what should
we be shooting for? So this is a trial
that we did. This is with a variety
called Orion 33. It's a monicious type
uh of of
hemp. and we planted it at um target
seeding rates of 100,000 up to 1 million
seeds per acre in 100,000 seed
increments. And then again, this is our
our count of uh of plants at harvest.
We've got healthy plants in the blue and
then the gray represents what we call
diseased heads. Those that were showing
obvious symptoms of of um some sort of
of disease uh that was affecting that
that uh floral structure. And the
interesting thing, you know, I thought
we would have
um, you know, where we would would see
better establishment maybe at some of
the lower rates and less of the thinning
effect, but what we found was that
across all the planting rates, we
roughly got about 20 to 25% of the live
seed we planted turned into a
harvestable plant. So, you know, at
100,000 planted seeds, we got 20,000. at
a million planted seeds, we got 200,000
uh
seeds. Okay, so we didn't get anywhere
near our target, but surely this big
difference in population will make a
difference in grain
yield. At least that's what I
hypothesized would happen. Uh, but he
pimp is a very plastic plant and so even
at lower populations we got more
branching and we found that our grain
yields really didn't change that much
across all of those different
populations. So, similar thing we did in
2024. Um, you know, same sort of thing.
We only got about 20% of our plants. We
did increase up to 1.2 2 million uh
seeds per acre, but we still didn't
didn't get much over 200,000 plants per
acre at at harvest. And again, our
yields were a little more variable in
2024, but still no consistent pattern um
related to plant population. And you
know what we get at a lower population
as I said is fewer individuals but
highly branched versus single stalks uh
and and larger numbers of of single
stalks per uh per unit of
area. So you
know this doesn't mean the population
isn't important. We we still I think
need to achieve higher density
populations for some practical reasons
of harvest and um certainly for fiber we
need to be trying to to achieve you know
some of these higher higher plant
populations but um certainly we have
more work to do to understand what's
going on with our our
seeds. Mention our planting methods just
very briefly. Um when we started out we
were using the old planter in
conventional ground very heavily worked
tilled
soil. Um in 2020 and 2021 uh we did not
have good results with this method. So
beginning in 2022 we shifted to a no
tail planting in our system uh where we
were going into a wheat cover crop that
had been sprayed um to to kill that
down. We also went from a planting depth
of about uh a quarter
inch deep or um about three/4ers of a of
a centimeter. We went to uh to about uh
2 cm deep or or 3/4 of an inch um deep
in in this this planting method. And you
know, one of the reasons for that is
that with where we do the tillage and we
have that very fine seedbed, we had a
lot of issues with soil crusting and our
plants not being able to to break
through that that crust uh very easily.
Whereas with our noill system, um you
know, this was our 2024 stands here. you
know, we're we're getting better better
establishment out of that no till
system, although we still have, you
know, some rather large gaps in some of
our rows when we we're still not
achieving our our target population
goals even with
that. I'm going to just very briefly
mention um some work that we did with
planting dates uh trying to to establish
the impact of planting date and planting
depth uh with with two different
cultivars. Again, our our target
population in this case was
680,000 pure live seeds uh per acre.
Um Tara uh Kaitton, who was my field
manager at the time, uh kind of was was
over a lot of this work. And you know,
about the only consistent thing that we
saw was that generally we did get better
stands with with deeper planting. um the
the planting date variable tended to to
be more impacted by what happened
immediately after that planting date. We
didn't see a consistent trend from early
to late with with planting date, but we
did tend to see better results out of
our our deeper planting. Uh same with
our our 2022 um thing. We did see in
this trial the light green bar was was
our populations at the end of
establishment and the blue
bars were at harvest. And so like we
were seeing in a lot of our earlier
studies, well a lot of our later studies
as well, but um like we've seen in a lot
of these studies, we're we're we're
losing a lot of plants throughout the
season um to to various losses there.
grain yield um in
2021. Very little impact of planting
depth um at the early planting dates. As
we got later, uh deeper planting date
was was more
advantageous. Then in 2022, it was kind
of the opposite. In the early planting
dates, we had an advantage for deeper
planting um than we did in the in the
middle dates. And then at the late date,
again, an advantage for deeper planting.
So overall, um, just quickly summarize
the the yield results on this. You know,
we did find that we tended to get better
yields with deeper planting. So that's
the the direction that we've moved in.
We've now gone ahead and and even moved
a little bit deeper. We're more uh like
now between uh an inch deep, so about
two to two and a half centimeters on
average is is what we're shooting for
now with our our planting uh depth.
So just to kind of wrap up um there are
some remaining challenges. Um we do have
a a herbicide um sonin or ethyluralin is
the active ingredient in that has
recently been um labeled for use on
hemp. We've used it the last couple of
years in our variety trials. But there
are certain weeds like the um uh yellow
nuts edge uh that's in this picture that
are not controlled by that. So, uh,
there's still some some weed control
issues that we're going to have to
tackle, insect pests and diseases like
fucerium head blight. Um, the most
prevalent one that we have here in
Kentucky. Uh, and the most prevalent
insect pest that we've got on our grain
uh grain crops, hemp crops is corn
earworm. And this integrated pest
management is something that uh
Magdalina has been working on uh in my
uh in my
program. Some other challenges uh that
we're we're facing and that I think our
growers will be facing if we if we
commercialize production in grain hemp
um is when to harvest. You know,
officially our target is at 50 to 75%
brown seeds. Um but is this true across
all locations? Is this true for all
cultivars? You know, these are things
that we need to to work out. Plus, it's
just hard to know. You know, even when
you're out there looking at them, it can
be really difficult to assess when
you're at this this point of 50 to 75%.
If we harvest too early, we get a high
too high of a proportion of immature
seed. They're high moisture and cause
problems for drying down. You know, if
we're too late in harvesting, uh then
we've lost seed. we we've had losses to
to birds, you know, that continues to to
be a problem as well. So, those are
things to be worked out. Plus, you know,
if we move to commercialization, we've
got a lot of of logistics uh in harvest
to work out. And and uh this is a
picture from um 2023. I'm not sure why
Paul Paul is smiling in this this
picture because he's just climbed out of
the back of that combine uh from about
30 minutes of trying to clean out this
massive water of fiber that was tangled
up in our our um straw beater in there.
And you know, this was a common
occurrence. We'd have to do this several
times a day uh to to clean out that that
machine. And so, um, you know, this is
this is definitely a challenge for, uh,
moving forward with with grain hemp for
us. Um, with that, uh, went I know I
went through a few things a little bit
fast there, but I'm going to stop at
that point and see if we have any
questions.
Thank you,
Bob. I might I might read the first
questions. We have a couple minutes
left. Yeah. Um, thank you for sharing
and explaining, Bob. What do you think
are the main factors for Kentucky not
doing as well as, for example, New York,
Vermont, or even Montana for grain and
fiber? Is it the latitude versus the
source of the seeds or is it moist
moisture or rain or something else?
Well, I think part of it we don't know.
It's I don't believe it's the seeds
because we're all using the same source
of seeds in the in that multi-state
trial. Um I I think the latitude has a
lot to do with it. Um and you know maybe
soil temperatures u playing something of
a of a role in that. But that's that's
something that I think we're we're
striving to to try to figure out um a
little bit better. Um, but I I think a
lot of it does have to do with with just
the the latitude. And if you look at,
you know, a lot of the the early
cultivars that we had,
um, they came from they were developed
at northern latitudes and then we're
trying to adapt them to the south. Some
of the the newer ones that we have
coming along that have been adapted
specifically for southern latitudes um,
are are performing more consistently in
our area.
That is good to know. All right. So, the
next question um is whether or not we
evaluate uh fiber quality as part of the
dual crop trials. Um we're not really
looking at
um you know specific fiber quality like
the tensil strength or anything like
that. About as far as we go with that,
we we are doing uh a simple
decordication. So, we're looking at the
ratio of bass to herd. uh with that, but
we're we're not uh we're not
specifically looking at the at the fiber
um fiber quality parameters right
now. All right. Uh next question is in
Kentucky, how many acres are being grown
and how many farmers are growing the
varieties that we're studying? Well, um,
this year we're probably going to
have I'm going to guess I haven't seen
the numbers yet for sure, but we're
probably going to have about five or six
thousand acres grown in Kentucky. The
vast majority of that is going to be
canabonoid hemp still. Um, that market
has come back a little bit in Kentucky.
Um and so um there's only probably going
to be less than well maybe about 100 to
200 acres of fiber hemp that are grown.
And yes, they are growing a variety that
we have recommended from our our trials.
Um and maybe 30 or 40 acres of grain
hemp that I know of u in the state. So
so most of what's being grown currently
is not grain or or fiber, but we're
working to to change that.
Um say the please explain the
differences between live seeds versus
the total number of seeds and then seed
quality with germination rate. For
example, 66% germination rate is for all
seeds. Yes. when we when so when when I
say a 60% 66% germination rate that's
basically taking the seed that we've
received the whole sample out of the bag
and testing it in a standard germination
test. Um so that's of that's of all all
the seed that that's there. And when we
make that correction and we say we are
planting
um pure live seed, we're assuming that
if it if it if we have germination in a
standard germination test, then it is a
live seed. Um, and so what we do then is
is, you know, we we correct we we
determine our total number of seeds per
acre or plants per acre that we're
targeting and then back calculate from
that to to only plant uh live seeds. And
then we also make an adjustment for the
seed size uh because there's quite a
range of seed size uh in in there and
make an adjustment for that. And for a
grower, um, as we move towards seed
certification, that information will
typically be on the on the seed tag that
a grower can use, germination, and the
and the the number of seeds per
pound. Um, bird predation is another
major factor. Did Paul see any loss of
seed due to bird predation? We should
try some seed coatings. I agree. We we
probably do need some seed coatings to
deter um bird predation. Paul didn't
specifically mention that. Um I will
mention that with that old cedar that we
had uh the the old red one that I that I
showed um the first year we were doing
it. I remember riding on that thing and
and we had made a pass down the field
with it and we were coming back up the
next row and I looked over and there was
a whole flock of morning doves on the
plots that we had just planted and they
were strangely walking in straight lines
down the rows that that that we had
planted. So, I agree. I think bird
predation of seed is is potentially
another another major issue.
Um, what type of pre-emergent would you
recommend for for fiber hemp? Well, the
only one that that I know of that's
labeled is the the Sonolin uh which is
ethylurelin from a company called Gowen.
Um, so that's that's the only one that's
actually labeled. Um, we do use in our
noail plantings, we are using glyphosate
as a burndown. Um, and that's it's not
technically labeled for that use yet.
Um, but um, that is what we've we've
been doing
there. All
right. What is the ideal pure live seed
to plant for grain fine bast fiber herd
production goals? I'm not
sure Sarah what you mean by if you're
asking about the uh uh what variety is
best for each one of those or the the
actual seed target numbers. If we're
talking about seed target numbers, what
we're currently planting for grain, uh,
we're planting, uh, the 680,000 seeds
per
acre. And for fiber, we're shooting more
for about a million seeds, pure live
seeds per acre. Obviously, you see our
results. We're not getting too close to
too close to uh to that uh to those
targets.
Um follow-up question on the fiber
quality. Do you know which university or
research organization is looking at
agronomic effects on fiber
quality? I don't know. Um I think North
Carolina State uh is doing some some
work. They they have some
u a some work going on with that. And uh
I see James has just put into the to the
chat there that uh the ARS unit in
Louisiana uh is developing some some
fiber standard or was going to be
developing some fiber standards. But
um you know I I do think North Carolina
is working with their textiles group as
well. And James has indicated that they
just sent some samples to the ARS in
Louisiana.
Um given that the grain yield does not
change at different planting rates, what
is the optimal planting rate for
practical harvest with a combine
avoiding the
branchiness? Louise, I think we're still
primarily at that 680,000
um range. Um, so you know, I mean that
if if we're planting that and getting a
couple hundred thousand plants per acre,
that's that's probably
um that's probably pretty good. So I see
we have a few more questions.
We do, but we will try to finish at Q.
So thank you everyone. Okay, uh for
connecting today. Thank you Bob uh for
answering all of our questions and for
that wonderful presentation. We
definitely learned a lot. Thank you. Um,
you're going to I'm happy to happily
answer questions if people want to email
me afterwards. Uh, rpierce.edu.
This has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu.