this is a production of Cornell
University it's really delightful to be
here I'm very thankful to to Alex and to
Kathy for helping to bring me to
Ithaca and uh very much to Lou as well
who's somewhere in the back for helping
uh on all the logistical
Arrangements um it's a little it's fun
and also frightening to to talk about
these topics in front of a room full of
scientists which is not my typical
audience uh because you all will know
when I'm uh saying things that are
totally wrong the historians don't um
and so I hope you'll be kind in the Q&amp;A
if I've totally butchered something but
uh I think I have an interesting story
for you I hope you'll enjoy it I have to
apologize to anyone who's listening to
this on Zoom because the PowerPoint uh
looks pretty nice in person but will
look clunky on the internet so you have
my
apologies okay so let me begin with the
problem of rotten
shoes so the year is 1942
it is late August and the Australian and
American armed forces are fighting to
defend a strategically valuable point at
the South Eastern tip of Papua New
Guinea known as mil Bay which is roughly
there from a Japanese assault although
the Battle of mil Bay uh was a small
engagement it was important for a number
of reasons it was for instance the first
time in World War II that a Japanese
amphibious invasion was
defeated but it was also fought in a h
hot humid jungle environment with almost
continuous pouring Lane this photo gives
you a sense of the landscape and its
challenges and this is a field recording
from elsewhere in Tapo inini so what
you're hearing is the experience of
being in a a rain in the bundle
there so Australian forces who had been
in the region longer noticed that much
of their equipment was malfunctioning
mine detectors did not detect tank mines
radio sets went dead soldiers found that
they couldn't even see through their gun
sits because they were clogged by
mysterious forces boots and Tents fell
apart overnight in the hot and wet
environment a guide book published in
1943 by the Allied Forces explained
quote that pop New Guinea is a primitive
hard country and a new world to men from
overseas you go there to fight a
dangerous enemy the Japanese but they
are not the only enemy the country
itself will fight you you must be
forever on your guard against this
silent enemy your environment it is
Relentless if you relax it will get you
down and as evidence of what that meant
this is an ammunition magazine after one
week of exposure in New Guinea compared
with a factory Fresh Magazine uh
although this was not the first time
that militaries had fought in a humid
environment the scale and the intensity
of the conflict in the in the tropics uh
caused a previously invisible
environment to make itself felt very
forcibly on world militaries
technologically scientifically and
strategically molds in particular
microscopic life forms that most
soldiers had never even thought about
were coming out of the woods very
literally to sabotage the war
effort so today what I'm going to do is
Trace the development of the science of
in deterioration prevention which we can
think about as the effort to understand
how environments damage materials and
how it made our system of sort of global
fast-moving Goods possible I've already
told you about the problem of moldy
shoes I'm going to continue by giving
you background on my larger Book Project
and sort of giving some context for this
undertaking I'll Trace how the field was
transformed uh or I'll introduce you to
the field of industrial micology and
talk about how that was transformed by
the fighting in World War II and finally
I'll end by showing how these Technical
and scientific advances from early
decades enabled the growth of rotten
capitalism you'll forgive the pun but an
economic system that is structured on an
ambivalent relationship with fungi both
Pro proactively utilizing microfungi to
produce products but also destroying
fungi to preserve a series of other
products so for the last few years I've
been working on a history of the
development of fungal science Alex very
kindly explained and I've been exploring
a number of connected disciplines so
taxonomic micology Medical micology
Plant Pathology industrial micology and
more and in the project I'm particularly
interested in thinking about how
previously ignored aspects of the
environment become knowable by
scientists and by Regular People and how
that knowledge propels novel forms of
utilization of those materials and
produces new Human Relationships so how
do we know that a mushroom is a fungus
rather than a plant which most people
throughout history did not think uh and
how does that change our Rel
relationship to that thing what does it
mean for how we interact with it I'm
calling the book Rotten Beauty to kind
of Index this ambivalent relationship
that people have with fungal things some
of them are lovely beautiful Etc some of
them are scary dangerous and need to be
destroyed So This research Builds on my
first book this is the Shameless
self-promotion moment uh which comes out
in May and there I provide a history of
the laboratory dog over the last two
centuries uh you might be wondering why
is someone who wrote a book about dogs
uh uh qualified or interested in writing
a book about mushrooms and one answer to
that question is my sort of repeated
interest in
Cornell uh I mentioned this in part
because an early section of that first
book talks about influential research on
Canine health and diseases that took
place not very far from we are now from
where we are now uh at the baker
Institute which was then known as the
research laboratory for the diseases of
dogs this facility opened in the 1950s
uh and you can see that if IA looked a
little bit different back then uh and
it's one of the many ways that my
historical interests have kind of
returned me to
Cornell and as a historian I'm kind of
interested in the knowledge that we have
about other kinds of organisms uh
efforts to make sense of dogs or pigs or
parrots or other kinds of living things
connect unexpected people across places
across disciplines across knowledge
communities and in the dog book I was
really interested in what is it like for
scientists and other people to an animal
that they identify with so they see
themselves in dogs they like dogs they
like being with dogs many of you
probably do as well the question is a
little bit different with a fungus that
many scientists who worked with them
don't really like them very much they're
kind of disgusting at times they're not
something that you want to have in your
house uh too much of perhaps uh and so
this changed the kinds of historical
questions that I was interested in in in
trying to understand how do we come to
deal with and understand alien or
invisible or micros opic organisms and
so as this sketch that I found in a
Dutch Museum helpfully demonstrates I
began to shift my focus from the dog at
the top of the tree to the mushrooms at
its bottom and I think with good reason
because today if you open newspapers
it's hard to avoid the sense that the
world needs fungi to save us from a host
of modern problems there is I think an
eagerness in the cultural Sphere for the
non-human power of mushrooms and other
fungal things to to save us from
human-made crises so in my project I'm
trying to bring together a number of
historical threads to explain how we got
to this point how did it make sense that
fungi could be a solution to Global
Climate problems and other
issues I'm not however the first person
to try to do this and uh I'm following
somewhat in the footsteps of Jeffrey
answorth the British myologist and
historian who attempted in three books
published in the 1970s and 80s to try to
do something of a broad sweeping History
of mological Science I think the benefit
and the fault of ainsworth's work is
that he separated these topics into sort
of their distinct disciplinary areas but
in doing so I think he accepted the idea
that these are different undertakings
and I'm interested in trying to bring
some of these things more together and
tell a more comprehensive story about
the development of this knowledge
project so I'll give you just a few
overarching kind of threads and then
I'll get back to the the question of
rotten stuff
so part of what I'm interested in is
tracing the development of General
micology as it emerged out of Botany and
separated itself from conventional
medical knowledge in the late 19th
century I'm looking at tools of
visualization from watercolor and
microscopes to DNA sequencing and image
recognition algorithms to show how a
vision of micology or fungal biology as
a sort of worldwide project began to
take began to take over in the early
20th century I'll say a bit more about
this a little bit later I'm also
interested in tracing how medical
micology gradually separated itself from
other uh ways of knowing and engaging
with fungal things and how the people
who study fungal infections became sort
of caught at times between different
worlds between medical schools and
biological Laboratories and often
suffered the uh funding challenges of
both the historic marginalization of
medical micology I think is really
important because today we know that
that uh fungal diseases are of growing
prominence and importance at an
international scale so the World Health
Organization has said that the next
pandemics could be fungal in origin
climate change of course is increasing
this risk so I think it's important to
understand this history and understand
why we haven't done so much research in
that
area another uh area of the book that's
of course very relevant here is the
development of Plant Pathology there's a
major transformation at the start of the
20th century where suddenly universities
all around the world are opening
programs in Plant Pathology including
this one here Cornell uh and begin to
see the subject as essential for the
development of international agriculture
so how did that happen why why did that
happen and how did that influence our
sort of modern version of Agriculture
and those of you who know a lot about
rusts will maybe recognize this as part
of Elvin Stan's early Research into uh
wheat rust so those are a few of the
threads of the book I can talk more in
the Q&amp;A I didn't want to bore everyone
with too much sort of overview uh but
what I'm trying to argue is that uh
although often kind of ignored and
thought of as a subsidiary or
unimportant area research about fungal
things really transformed and shaped the
20th century in in very prominent ways
and I think I'm preaching to the choir
here but I think more people need to
think about the history of mological
Science and and understand its
importance all
right so to illustrate a bit of this
ambivalent relationship that people have
to fungi I want to talk a little bit
about the field of industrial micology
where it came from uh and you and uh and
and sort of show how this developed into
a much kind of broader and more nebulous
uh sort of study of environmental
deterioration in 1938 British myologist
George Smith published the first edition
of the introduction to uh industrial
micology and acquainted many people with
a new area of knowledge concerning
fungi as Smith explained in his preface
to the first edition
quote this book is intended to assist
those who are commencing the study of
molds rather than a fungi in general
there is already an extensive literature
of systematic micology Plant Pathology
and medical micology but there has been
up to the present no book in English
dealing particularly with the fungi
which are of importance in Industry so
as Smith made clear there was a great
amount of mological knowledge in
existence but biochemical knowledge of
molds was urgently needed so what had
changed to make that
necessary biochemist Harold rrick who is
today so little remembered that I
actually had to create his Wikipedia
page um explained that the two basic
challenges of industrial micology in a
forward to Smith's book so he said on
the one hand you have all these
industries involved in handling organic
materials including the food industry
the textile industry wood Etc and all of
these industries were losing extensive
supplies and products to the destructive
powers of fungi antifungal sprays and
other kinds of things were needed to
combat these
molds but then on the other hand
biochemists had recognized The Marvelous
powers and capacities of fungi for
producing useful Industrial Products so
many of you may know that prior to World
War I most of the world's citric acid
came from lemons and Sicily which are
shown here and they were used in the
production of things like sodas desserts
Etc but World War I cut America off from
citric acid so they had to find
artificial and synthetic ways to produce
citric acid without getting all of these
Italian lemons uh this was an important
development for a whole bunch of reasons
it's really bad for Sicily um but it it
introduced a lot of researchers like rri
to this idea that you could use small
fungal organisms and produce these kind
of fantastic and useful Industrial
Products rrick knew about all of this
firsthand because during the first world
war he had participated in secretive
research to use yeast to produce
glycerol which was a key chemical for
explosives his findings were utilized in
the war effort but they were also really
valuable for the British mining industry
in peace time so a lot of synthetic
explosives were produced for mining in
subsequent years rerk uh focused his
attention on assaying fungi for a whole
bunch of other useful industrial uh
purposes and in the 1920s he took up a
chair in Biochemistry in the London
School of hygiene and tropical medicine
where he appointed Smith the author of
the book his research
assistant rather than explosives though
Smith came to Industrial micology via
the clothing industry he began his
career as a chemist for the textile
manufacturer Borman and baron which is
the headquarters are very blurry they're
hard to see uh Borman and a number of
other companies at this time were
producing doties which is a sort of
white cotton fabric that was shipped to
British India to use for fat uh clothing
and a bunch of other uses during the
long Oceanic Transit however
however from England to India a lot of
these things miled they became sort of
destroyed by a fungal uh processes that
was then known as
tendering this was not a brand new
concern at this time period uh for
instance this print from the 18th
century Japanese artist katsuk kawash
shuno appears to depict women airing out
books to prevent mildew and insect
infestations uh According to curators
which kind of demonstrates that this
fight against spoilage was a very
long-standing one
but Smith's work showed how the British
Empire in this kind of continent
spanning uh scope made a lot of these
economic problems much more serious and
and requiring action although the exact
numbers are difficult to come by it's
clear that a huge number of cotton goods
were destroyed by milus uh during this
period in response the British cotton
manufacturer's research arm in
Manchester known as the Shirley
Institute shown here uh invested
significant effort into understanding
how to to vent and Destroy these molds
at the time the most effective solution
was the application of zinc chloride
which protected clothes but you needed
to use a ton of it so it was really
expensive but around 1930 researchers at
the Shirley Institute had a breakthrough
with a new antifungal product known as
salic
salano uh because that was a mouthful
they called it Sheran for their
Institute for over a decade Sheran was
the single best way to prevent cotton
products from deteriorating over time in
warm moist environments and to prevent
their tendering and so building on their
work in the 1930s Smith was able to
identify a number of species of
aspergillis responsible for this mildew
and so here what you're seeing is the
the aspergillis organism inside the
fabric of the doti many of you may know
that they're called this because Pier
Antonio McKelly thought that under a
microscope the asper aspergilli looked a
lot like the uh sort of holy water
dispenser that he found in in the
Catholic Church
so importantly at roughly the same time
a lot of American mycologists were also
studying at spum and uh they were
reclassifying the asperula species so
Charles Tom and Margaret church publish
a big monograph reclassifying the family
at around this time or the genus around
this time so Smith's work took that kind
of laboratory mological research and
combined it with a much more economic
orientation and it showed how laboratory
micology could really have a sort of
major economic signific ific an This
research was pretty important people
were interested in it so race bought
brought him to the London School of
hygiene and tropical medicine to work on
Industrial micology
full-time so Smith's book introduced
industrial micology it would go on to
have six editions it was a pretty
popular text but it Remains the case
that this sort of general area of
research only became truly popular
because of World War
II as Smith explained toward the end of
the conflict quote before the war much
of the loss in tropical countries caused
by molds was taken for granted and
moreover there was no coordinating body
like the ministry of Supply to initiate
research which would benefit many
different Industries there simply had
not been enough modern military
equipment in a tropical place like New
Guinea to justify research at the
necessary
scale a similar thing is true many of
you probably know for penicillin the
antibiotic activity of penicillin which
is produced from penicilium molds was
known for decades ades before World War
II but it was only produced at
industrial scales because the war added
sort of millions of dollars into finding
ways to produce penicillin much faster
so World War II is often thought of
generally as the physicists War uh and
and people think of this fellow here
Oppenheimer but I think that we can also
think about World War II as The Mists
War because without Mists the war would
have gone dramatically
differently in retrospect it's a little
surprising that it took this kind of
large scale International conflict to
get people interested in the question of
tropical
deterioration uh after all the bananas
that arrived from Central America to
places like New Orleans which is shown
here in the 1920s were gathered in
tropical climates by workers whose
Health was a major economic and social
concern at that time Public Health
researcher Alfred Reid for instance
explained in an overview of the field of
tropical medicine that attention to
Tropical medicine was appeared was one
key indication that everywhere Commerce
business and government are recognizing
that more and more of mankind must live
in close relationship with the tropics
so there was this idea that a lot of
Western folks were moving to the tropics
and that it needed to be made safe for
them one uh example from the time this
is a 1914 newspaper headline of a speech
by uh Army Surgeon General William
gorgus who said that science had so
advanced in the last decade it is now
safe for any white man to make his home
in the tropics so this was a time uh but
as you can tell the focus here was
really on making white people safe from
tropical diseases not so much on the
technological infrastructures that
existed in tropical
places it was instead the mass
quantities of material moving during
World War II that made this
consideration somewhat
unavoidable according to one early
estimate nearly 50% of all items shipped
by the British military to Burma were
lost in transit or sort of dest
destroyed by molds in transit uh which
is an astonishing amount of stuff if you
think about it uh as researchers learned
the majority of then identified molds
live really well between 75 and 85
degrees at high levels of humidity which
was the exact conditions that were found
throughout this region so this was kind
of mold heaven and it and it w havoc on
a lot of their stuff in the early 1940s
uh scientific collaboration began
between Australia England and the United
States which sort of pooled findings
together to figure out how could we
protect all of our stuff from
destruction by mold and
humidity on the American side the
research organization was partly led by
this man Selman wman who is better known
for coining the word the term antibiotic
and leading the discovery of strepto but
wman was important in leading the kind
of American side of the tropical
deterioration fight over the course of
the Allied work the Australians found
for instance that us packed things were
were a lot better than British packed
things uh I'm not totally sure why but
Americans were I guess just better at
that um and this was actually one of the
major Revelations that pushed Australia
away from a traditional relationship
with England and toward a relationship
with the United States so the kind of
Australian American technological
relationship really got going at this
moment in World War
II because of the urgency of this
concern research initially took place in
Metropolitan Laboratories so in London
Smith and rri at the school of hygiene
and tropical medicine became kind of the
semi-formal experts on how to protect
things from tropical
deterioration they constructed tropical
Chambers where temperature and humidity
could be kept at artificially elevated
levels to facilitate mold growth and to
try to kind of test product
deterioration as simulations of a a
farway environment I think the that they
didn't really understand very well these
experiments are really important as an
attempt to kind of domesticate far away
tropical places and recreate them inside
of temperate uh climates so the same way
that we can uh grow all kinds of
wonderful trees here despite the snow in
IA um but the question uh was or the
problem was this didn't work that well
for them these these tropical Chambers
just didn't uh produce the right
conditions so as the war pressed onwards
it was also deemed important to
establish tropical testing stations
throughout the
world so in the early 1940s the Britain
found founded the West African tropical
testing establishment in colonial
Nigeria in Port harcour which you'll
see oh I lost my little arrow down kind
of the bottom on the coast uh and uh
Port harcour there we go yep there's the
arrow and at the station both electrical
and textile goods were tested
aggressively in sort of similar tropical
conditions to see how they would hold up
over time what kinds of products could
protect them from
deterioration an exhibit in Australia in
July 1945 confirmed just how Central
packing seemed to be for the war effort
we don't typically think of like
waterproof cardboard as an exciting
development of World War II but here it
is literally Central in this Museum
exhibit to like what are the
technological developments of the
period Tropic proofed items emerged as a
really visible s signal that could be
shared with the public of the kind of
Innovations of the Allied military's
flexible approach to Warfare there were
similar exhibits also in the UK which
kind of showcased these findings to the
general public so Tropic packaging
became this really essential example of
sort of how uh how adaptable the
American and British militaries
were by the end of the war Electronics
were being hermetically sealed to resist
moisture B binoculars were shipped with
silica gel inside to to resist in molds
packaging materials were now waterproof
and resistant to humidity so an entire
tropical iCal sort of protection regime
had come into operation and these
developments were very much a shared
project but if British researchers like
Smith and rrick had had kind of the
initial Advantage by the end of the war
it was really American myologist who
were the leaders in the development of a
lot of these findings for instance the
tropical deterioration information
center which was located at George
Washington University became kind of the
centerpiece of collating all the
information that existed about mold
management and
prevention many British researchers
found this to be a rather upsetting
development because they had been the
traditional experts in micology now it
was in the United States that sort of
fungal knowledge was most wide was was
best kept and this was a scientific
shifting of the guard that had really
important implications for the history
of biology in the 20th century uh Tropic
proofing may not have really won the war
for the Allies but I think it aided in
their fight and it caused some major
changes
the first and I think most important for
those who work here is that it spurred a
really large transformation in the field
of what we maybe now think of as fungal
biology so in his presidential address
to the mological Society of America in
1949 Fred Sparrow who you see here
explained quote that the field of
micology has been given a new impetus
and drive in the United States in recent
years for many years research in
micology has been primarily
morphological and taxonomic and it has
been fruitful work work indeed but new
research Sparrow continued was making
possible the recent development and
expansion almost by Leaps and Bounds of
new fields of investigation and in one
of the examples of these sort of new
fields that were really important he
talked about new research on
neurospora uh Sparrow perceived the
emergence of what he called a new
micology and he argued that the MSA
needed to adapt itself to this new
biological laboratory style of inquiry
Mists were no longer princip taxonomic
botanists they were practically inclined
they worked with the military they
worked with agricultural groups and
increasingly much of their research was
focused in high-tech Laboratories they
use things like electron
microscopes and a major cause of this
change Sparrow mentioned in his
presentation was the war that it had
given tons of money to a lot of these
researchers and allowed them to develop
brand new biological uh research
regimes it's around the same time the
mid
1950s that oh they're coming that
Jeffrey anworth started to publish a
series of articles on a problem that was
facing researchers of his generation
there was too much mological information
for them to keep up with there's just
too much knowledge in a lecture he gave
to graduate students at the University
of Wisconsin in 1962 answorth explained
quote mological information is
increasing exponentially and the
literature of micology is today
published in more language and scattered
through more Publications than ever
before Mists in common with other
scientists have the problems of noting
sorting storing and retrieving
information problems that are
Complicated by the fact that in addition
to the literature much mological
information is kept as dead specimens
preserved in herbaria and as living
specimens conserved in culture
collections so many of you are probably
familiar with this idea that there's too
much science to keep up with but the
point is that this was already acutely
felt in 1950
and in fact it was felt even earlier
than that so the third group in this
figure uh that I think looks like a kind
of avantgard heavy metal band is Italian
myologist Pierre Andrea sardo in the
late 1800s sardo began collecting all
known species of fungi with the help of
a bunch of assistants into a single
multivolume book which he called the
solo fungorum omnium hus cognitum the
the collection of all presently known
fungi he wrote it in Latin because he
considered Latin a universal language
that everyone could speak and so it
solved the problem of translation you
have Italians you have Americans you
have Japanese folks they're all doing
micology but they can't speak to each
other well if they use Latin that'll
solve all of those
issues he sent letters and postcards
like this one below to researchers all
around the world to exchange samples
turning the botanic garden in Padua into
a kind of Center place for the
collection of specimens and this this
sort of male exchange was uniquely
possible at this moment in time because
the universal Postal Union had just
gotten started during this period so in
the past if you sent a postcard you had
to worry about the local cost exchanging
your money whether you'd be charged
extra at Transit the universal Postal
Union meant that sardo could send a
letter from Padua it would get to
America and everyone is paying roughly
the same price so the ex the the
exchange of exata things like that was
uniquely possible in this
moment sardo got started in the early
1880 and he thought that he could list
every species of fungus uh within 8
years unfortunately it turned out that
it was a really difficult project and he
was still working on it uh and the 25th
volume came out in 1931 so for almost 50
years his most of his life sakaro was
trying to list all of the
species and even more recently we know
that the arrival of Internet enabled
micology in the 1990s did not cause the
information problem to disappear but
rather to mutate so in a 1998 paper
Kathy hodj and Tom vulk predicted that
the worldwide web would enable
researchers across the planet to search
large databases of species and access
specimen identification keys that were
formerly only available to those with
privileges at specialty libraries so
there's kind of a democratizing vision
of mological research and I I'll say
that they were right about this uh that
you can do all of these things now right
but Scholars at the time also worried
that this this internet enabled micology
was creating new problems for For the
Working scientist after all if a species
was first published online and the
website went away how could you ensure
that that information would be saved how
could you believe that something was a
species if it wasn't published in a book
I think today we're now very aware that
when databases disappear a lot of
knowledge can go with them and even more
close to the present with the flood of
new possible species identified with
Advanced sequencing techniques yet
without obvious morphological
characteristics there are new questions
about what it means to name or identify
an organism in the first place so what
I'm hoping to suggest here is that I
think history can help Orient us uh to
some of these ongoing conversations
about arranging and controlling
mological knowledge subsequent
Generations have felt flooded by
overwhelming quantities of information
for over over a hundred years each time
made possible by new technological
developments of their ages each of these
Generations
developed new tools and new ways of
coping with this changing world of
information but it was really the war
that kind of got a lot of this started
and and sort of made the massive
expansion of micology
possible so that's the kind of
scientific transformation but another
major sort of result of a lot of this
wartime Research into tropical
deterioration was in how this affected
the world of Industrial Products and
their movement around the globe
the US tropical deterioration
information center which was that
bibliography group I mentioned rebranded
in 1945 as the prevention of
deterioration Center its bibliographers
carefully collected all kinds of
information about deterioration problems
but the name change I think signaled
that they were expanding from a focus on
tropical questions to deterioration at
the kind of broadest possible
level in 1954 they published a general
guide the deterioration of materials
which its cover celebrated as quote the
first book ever published to cover all
aspects of deterioration prevention
which is very exciting claim you can
imagine uh and the center which
continued operations until 1964
continued to receive extensive support
from all the branches of the American
Military and part of the reason is that
the American Military did not give up on
the importance of tropical deterioration
after World War II instead the US kept
access to Tropical testing facilities in
places like Panama uh and uh Britain
maintained access to them until uh they
were kicked out of Nigeria when it
became an independent country in
1958 uh well they they closed in 1958
Independence came later uh the US
military has has fought to maintain
these and part of the reason is that
studies in the middle of the 20th
century predicted that all future
conflicts were likely to take place in
tropical environments so the American
Military had to continuously test all of
its goods in tropical
places this kind of came to a head in
1977 when the Carter T rehost treaty
required the US to leave Panama
potentially lose access to this tropical
testing facility uh that didn't quite
happen and the US actually maintains a
lot of tropical testing all across the
globe so what I'm hoping to kind of
suggest also is that this this early
sort of mological research focus into
tropical deterioration was not just
important for scientists it also
underwrote an expansion of the American
Military all across the planet in a
vision of sort of American milit Ary
power that could be projected anywhere
at any time because American Guns could
be safe and protected whether they're
here whether they're in Guam or whether
they're somewhere else so it didn't just
change science it really changed how the
American Military imagined its Readiness
on a global
scale and it also really affected
visions of post-war International Trade
so after the war you have a lot of
companies who emerge and start to talk
about the exciting new ability for
American corporations to expand their
business across the
planet in 1944 John Glenn of the
Pan-American Trust Company noted that
American Business could take advantage
of post-war World Trade expanding into
new markets he wrote that the
restoration of world economy after the
war will offer a tremendous opportunity
to American production and importantly
he stressed that this opportunity would
rely on willingness to take advantage of
all of these wartime developments in
packaging and
shipping the new technique developed
during the war were perceived as sort of
essential elements of the expansion of
American corporate uh uh sort of
development a Scientific American
explained in
1945 commercial shippers may not be
working in quite the same areas but they
could use these new Tropical Shipping
and prevention discoveries in order to
sell their goods in all kinds of places
you could build a motorcycle in the
United States you could get it to the
Philippines and it would be in fine
working condition when it arrived so it
enabled this vision of a truly GL Global
kind of capitalist
Enterprise there were a vast array of
research programs into various sort of
modes of fungus prevention and Tropic
proofing paper and paperboard got
studied extensively and I'll just note
that this uh study for instance
emphasized that trade with tropical
areas was increasing so the reason for
doing a lot of This research was this
expansion in tropical trade there are
countless examples of This research I
won't list all of them but much of it
concerns this idea of adapting wartime
discoveries to the new peaceful uh
post-war
environment and even at the height of
optimism about peaceful uses of
radioactivity there were Suggestions by
some people that you could zap
underground cables uh with high levels
of radi radiation to keep fungi from
destroying them so a lot of ways to to
fungus proof the the New World
Order there's one more important
development that I think came from a lot
of this and it concerns a new material
that was popular IED during this period
because of its fungal resistance so PVC
or polyvinyl chloride was discovered in
1872 by chemist oan Balman but it only
received widespread application in the
1930s and 1940s after chemist Waldo
Seaman at the Goodrich company boiled
some waste PVC and turned it into this
flexible plastic virtually immune to
fungal deterioration PVC was used widely
after the war for things like vinyl
record
uh pipes and even uh some mini golf
hazards in 1966 the Goodrich company
produced 260 million pounds of PVC a
year and today the most recent estimate
I could find is that nearly six billion
pounds of PVC is produced annually in
the United States so massive amounts of
this
stuff and the problem as you can
probably predict or already know is that
PVC is extremely damaging to the
environment both its production and its
life cycle rele release harmful
chemicals that build up in water air
food chains Etc and cause a variety of
human health problems so I think from
the present sort of vantage point we can
tell a very different story about fungal
deterioration this was not just a
development about kind of miraculously
overcoming the environment and building
all these wonderful fungus proof things
but of creating a host of new materials
and processes that didn't just resist
the environment but actually potentially
Destro destroyed the environment so it
was a a multifaceted uh
transformation and today with all the
stories about how fungi might save us
we're experiencing a kind of ironic
inversion of a lot of this history as
unrecyclable Plastics give way to
sustainable Alternatives now you have
the idea that we can actually build all
of our shipping boxes out of fungi
themselves so you don't need to Pro you
don't need to protect boxes from fungi
you can build boxes out of them uh
industrial micology is thus kind of
reemerging to neutralize a problem
partly of its own
making industrial micology was thus an
essential component in the system of
production and exchange that expanded
around the world after World War II the
universe of fast-moving Commodities in
waterproof boxes with those little
desiccating silica gel packets that you
never totally know what to do with
shielded by plastic wrap all of this got
started after World War II and it was
made possible by Major advances in
micology the system as we know is also a
rather intive one and by studying how
sort of this this knowledge changed and
transformed how it was lost how it
developed I'm hoping we can better
approach the present and the ecological
problems that we deal with
today now I'll end by returning to a
more basic question uh for you all which
is what it means to study a fungus and
why anyone would want to do that in the
first
place so in 2011 the late Cornell Mist
dick Corf addressed address the Congress
of Latin American micology at the time
cor worried that granting agencies were
now aggressively dictating what kinds of
research people could do the traditional
Ivory Tower he worried was disappearing
it was being destroyed by commercial
forces which I think we're familiar with
but Corf insisted that I do not find
this to be a doomsday picture but rather
a candid view of our future in which we
can hope by changing our Focus to pursue
the Holy Grail of saving whatever we can
of our natural diversity I see this as a
moral duty and I'm convinced that we
have the ability to change our Focus to
one of serving Society so in a
complicated moment like the one we find
ourselves in today perhaps we can take
some solace in knowing that others have
faced down a lot of the problems about
funding uh political involvement with
research and we can embrace the work of
saving what we can I'll stop there
thanks so much everyone for
listening yeah and I yeah
um you didn't mention it but I'm curious
if part of the research for your book
includes like culinary
micology yeah uh can you can you say
more about what just like the either I'm
thinking of like culinary like
production for edible mushrooms but also
I guess like foring big thing yeah yeah
absolutely so uh yeah I almost I almost
talked about this today in fact so I I'm
sorry I feel like I missed an
opportunity one interesting part about
it there's a major transformation in how
how mushrooms are grown and produced for
for agriculture starting in the late
19th century continuing into the early
20th century so in the early 1800s you
have these like interesting French guys
who start going into the catacombs of
Paris and growing mushrooms underground
which they realized it's the perfect
place to do it because it's kind of
artificially temperature controlled it's
protected from rain etc etc and this
idea of using caves to grow mushrooms
become super super popular at the end of
the century uh you have Americans try to
do it for instance Mammoth Cave the
national park this kind of fails because
it turns out there isn't a big Market in
Kentucky for mushrooms but you get a lot
of these projects to kind of turn caves
and abandon tunnels Etc into into
mushroom production facilities but the
Americans make really major advances in
pure culturing and then growing
mushrooms in sort of uh controlled like
outside green houses and stuff so that's
how you get to the fact that kenet
square for instance is now you know one
of the World Mushroom production uh uh
meccas uh and a lot of this has to do
with with sort of research in a little
bit of an earlier time period but that
takes some of these pure culture
techniques and then applies them to
agricultural production so it's part of
the project and I am interested in kind
of tracing this further also there's a
kind of connected question of like
production of soy sauce and a lot of
these culinary products that require
kind of industrial uh mological work so
so all of this will hopefully be in the
book but thank you for the
question yeah um thanks for your talk it
was really great you mentioned that uh
it's kind of surprising that it took so
long for industrial micology to emerge
as as an area of study given how long
before that uh trade in the tropics had
been going on with perishable things I
wonder if you could say a bit more about
why you think it took that why why do
you think it didn't emerge in previous
centuries yeah well I think that part of
the the easy answer I suppose is that uh
there was not enough stuff yet in
tropical places and it wasn't
deteriorating at a fast enough rate and
I mean as as I kind of said here I World
War II is a really wonderful moment in a
well not it's a bad
moment from a kind of industrial and
scientific standpoint um it's a really
interesting moment because you have so
much money being invested with very
little sort of concern about you know
like wasted funding it's like if there's
an urgent problem it's worth working on
and so you get massive investments in
the problem of tropical deterioration
which are just Unthinkable in any
earlier decade there's nobody had enough
money for that to make sense but if our
soldiers are literally getting lost in
the jungle because their radio sets are
being eaten Away by molds and they can't
even talk to each other they can't see
through their guns I mean that's a life
and death problem and so the US military
invests a massive amount of money and of
course the same is sort of true with the
Manhattan Project that you have these
massive fundamental advances in physics
that are possible because an enormous
amount of money is invested into these
questions right during that time period
And if I had an audience of of
politicians here I would argue that that
that this kind of massive expenditure
has all kinds of sort of fundamental and
basic benefits right it's just that that
kind of broad project dream of of sort
of spending tens or hundreds of millions
of dollars at a time to solve these
problems kind of dries up afterwards but
it just it doesn't exist in kind of the
earlier
period yeah um I had a question about
permits when you're talking about the
exchange material um and collecting all
the different fungi I imagine that maybe
it's gotten more like permitting and
exchange is more restricted over time
but is that true or does that play out
where there's relaxes in regulation and
then um stricter regulation is that
influence the process so this is for
like collecting samples and and sort of
shipping them around the world yeah so
like there's negative impacts by you
could have Outreach in other areas
things like that yeah well
disappointingly in early in the 20th
century there are very few restrictions
about uh what you can take from a place
and and ship elsewhere and uh a lot of
the sort of charm or humor of looking at
like sardo's correspondence is that the
biggest problem is just that if someone
shipped something from North America so
like JB Ellis would send him stuff and
it it would just get lost at you know
all the time on boats and and it would
get stuck at the post office for months
because the post office didn't know what
was in it and it was you know the the
real concern was that it was a weapon or
you know something was being kind of uh
illegally moved across International so
so there's very little concern about
that early
on that said there's also not that much
interest at the time in studying the
sort of uh the funga of nonwestern
places so the really intense focus is on
European North American to some extent
sort of Japanese uh species there's not
a lot of attention to Central American
South American African uh populations so
even though there are very few
restrictions the kind of um ideological
uh Focus meant that a huge amount of of
sort of possible questions weren't
really asked at this time uh in terms of
species that could have been studied but
just there wasn't enough attention to
them um it definitely changes of course
as you get into the later 20th century
when things become a lot harder to just
kind of pick up and ship around but um
yeah there weren't there weren't a lot
of restrictions early on and uh Curtis
Gates Lloyd is a wonderful sort of
mological History figure that some may
know about lives in Cincinnati and he
creates this this journal called
mological notes and he says that if you
ship him a mushroom from anywhere in the
world he will identify it and he'll send
you a free copy of mological notes and
he has a bunch of money that he's made
through pharmaceutical research so he's
able to do this in a way that most other
people can't and the amazing thing about
Lloyd is that he is getting things
shipped to him from just everywhere
across the planet at a kind of
breathtaking scale and develops this
unbelievable dried specimens collection
in part because there are almost no
restrictions and he's got all these guys
like who are just board Colonial
administrators in like Angola or
Singapore and they're like you know I
didn't have much going on so I went out
the other day I found this mushroom what
is it you know please let me know in a
couple months so you get this kind of
spectacular international trade at that
time uh but it's also it's slow to
communicate there's a lot that's lost in
transit because dried specimens don't
hold up very well when they're received
so there are different kinds of problems
at that
time any other questions from our
audience
today well I hope you'll join me oh go
ahead oh this is a little random but so
early on you showed the magazine being
like completely destroyed by mold so I
imagine that that would be made out of
metal but molds can't eat metal and so
I'm wondering how like how did it get
that destroyed that quickly is it just
like acid production or yeah I mean so
so there there are a couple problems
that they deal with during this time and
there one thing that I suppose I should
have talked about a little bit more is
that at first the major concern is only
about mold action so it's initially a
kind of purely mological concern is like
how do we stop the molds from getting in
because they do like Cloud gun sits from
the inside which people can't figure out
but it does become clear that after a
while molds aren't the only problem that
the other problem is just massive
constant humidity and so you have things
that are just in very wet environments
Where Metal is corroding very very
quickly over extended periods and it's
kind of the combined effect of kind of
moisture corrosion and kind of fungal
activity that causes this like massive
destruction so boxes get destroyed by
fungi but then you know Metals get sort
of ruined by by all kinds of other like
rust and and other
processes all right well will you join
me and thanking Brad for thank you all
so
much this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu