will
will everybody um
participating and now without further
Ado we're going to move into the second
phase and I'd like to introduce our
first speaker um Dr David Handley works
for the University of Maine at the
Highmore research farm he he is um is
responsible for vegetable and small
fruit variety evaluations and integrated
Pest Management strategies and he's been
a cooperator on this project and I
really appreciate having him here he's
going to speak to us about cultural
control options for Bramble weed
management and Dr Handley thank you
Laura well good afternoon um I'm going
to cover the basics of weed management
without chemicals uh we're going to of
course discuss chemicals as uh part of
the options as we go along but Rich
banana will'll get into those
specifically a little bit later on so to
start off and just to introduce the
topic we need to understand exactly what
a weed is and what it's doing and and
how we're going to manage it based on
that um a weed is basically a plant
that's in the wrong place at the wrong
time from your
perspective this means that it's going
to compete with those plants for light
nutrients and water uh given that
definition raspberries can actually
become Their Own Worst weed if you're
not doing a good job of pruning them and
keeping the plant population down for
they too will compete amongst themselves
for light nutrients and
water raspberries create kind of a
special case for weed management if
you're used to Growing other crops like
vegetables for example uh that can make
it a little more challenging to get
weeds under control and keep them under
control for one thing they're perennial
and this eliminates the opportunity for
crop rotation in other words you can't
say well it was a bad weed year this
year I'm just going to rotate out and do
something uh different next year
hopefully that planning is going to be
with you for 10 or 20 years in addition
raspberries are shallow rooted and this
means that uh they're not really suited
to close cultivation because any
equipment you have in there disturbing
the top layer of the soil is going to
harm the roots of the raspberry plant
and also because they're shallow rooted
they tend to be very poor competitors
with weeds if you can imagine a grass
for example in a raspberry planting
their roots are in the exact same spot
because over 70% of a Raspberry's root
system is in the top 8 in of the soil uh
this is also uh an issue with just about
any uh perennial weed that's going to be
in there directly competing with them
raspberries are also herbicide sensitive
especially younger planting so the use
of herbicides has to be carefully
monitored there are only a few chemicals
out there that uh will control weeds
without actually harming the raspberry
plants and Rich will'll talk about this
later so your options are are fairly
Limited in that regard
so one of the keys of having a
successful weed Management program in
raspberries is to make sure that you get
off on the right foot and what we're
talking about here is pre-plant weed
control this is really the Cornerstone
of a successful weed Management program
and this should begin anywhere from 1 to
3 years before you plan to single
raspberry in the ground depending on
what condition the site is in when you
get started um and when we talk about
what are we the types of things that
need to go into pre-plant management
we're talking about looking at site
selection what amendments you're going
to add to that soil and how that's going
to impact weed weeds in the future uh if
you're going to use cover crops what
cover crops you're going to use and how
what sort of strategies you're going to
use with them uh the possibility of
fallowing before planting in other words
uh keeping that soil bare for a year or
two to try to deplete the weed seed
population and then as we get ready to
plant using some techniques to keep the
weeds down in that planting year such as
stale seed beds or strip tillage and
we'll cover each of these in a little
more Tail as we move
along so looking at site selection
specifically one of the things you want
to do when you decide you're going to
plant raspberries and where you're going
to plant raspberries is to take a look
at that site and determine what's
happened there previously with an ey
weeds management for example what
previous crops have you had there uh
it's going to be a big difference
whether this was a well tilled and
well-managed vegetable planting as
opposed to a neglected pasture for the
last 20 years in terms of what types of
weeds you're going to be facing and then
looking at that ground what sort of weed
history do you know there's a particular
perennial weed that's been a problem
quack grass or nut Edge for example that
is going to cause a special issue for
you if you're trying to plant a
perennial crop like raspberries in there
and then also take a look at the weed
management history again if this has
been a corn field or something where
herbicides have been used in the past
try to get an idea of what chemicals
have been used and how recently they've
been used and whether or not there's any
plant back restrictions that might uh
cause a problem with the plants
themselves so not only weeds but the
potential for herbicide residue could be
an issue for you you want to take a
close look at that site for what
existing weed species there are not only
annual weeds
which might be relatively easy to
control but especially perennial species
that might be in there that need to be
controlled before we start planting and
you can develop a strategy to get them
out of there before those plants go in
the ground pay special attention to
whether or not there's wild brambles in
there for the not only the reason that
these can be a challenging weed to get
rid of but they act as disease hosts
especially viruses and wild brambles
really need to be controlled before you
put any of your cultivated varieties in
there what soil amendments are you going
to use we often add soil amendments to
try to build soil organic matter and
improve the nutrient holding capacity of
the soil and soil drainage but if we use
animal manures these can often contain
wheed seed uh horse manure is is popular
in my area and unfortunately horses are
very poor at processing wheat seed and
as a result unless the animal manure has
been composted you can be spreading
millions and millions of whe seeds on
your ground as you think you're helping
it uh by trying to get some organic
matter built up one of the ways you can
get around this is to try to compost any
Manu that you have uh compost however
also can contain weat seed unless it's
properly done it should be finished in
other words that compost should have
been warmed up to at least 140
preferably 150° to kill most of the weed
seeds that's in there and regularly turn
to make sure that there's a uniform
product throughout the other thing I
hate to see is people saying they're
going to put compost on and you walk
over the compost pile and you can see uh
knee high weeds growing on the pile
because it's been sitting there for
several months uh so if you're not going
to be able to use the compost right away
you should either turn it regularly or
cover it to make sure that wheat seeds
aren't blown on and start to get
established and then drop their own seed
in there and cause problems in the
future as we move into site preparation
one of the things you may be considering
is cover crops Now cover crops are
typically added to build soil organic
matter but they're also promoted as a
strategy to reduce wheat seeds in there
um while they do improve soil structure
whether or not they reduce wheed
pressure is really up to you and how you
manage those cover crops just saying
you're putting a cover crop on there
doesn't mean you're going to get good
weed control although cover crops can
shade out some species uh some may
survive quite well beneath the canopy
you just can't see them there and indeed
they're shedding seeds and adding to the
wheat seed bank instead of depleting it
as you would like them to do so overall
in discussions with Rich banano who
you'll be hearing from later uh we feel
that unless they're managed very well uh
cover crops can actually have little
weed little impact on the total weed
seed
population if we use short-term cover
crop CRS in other words two three or
maybe even four crops over a summer and
combine these with repeated tillage
you're much more likely to get some
impact on the weed seed bank over time
the other strategy you can use is toel
let cover crops that have some
allopathic uh characteristics such as
Rye or sudex and these can uh give off
root exudates or chemicals within the
roots that actually inhibit weed seed
germination if you're interested in that
I'd suggest you look at some of the
literature that's out there on a lpath
species and determine whether or not
this is something that's actually going
to work uh for you and your and the
particular situation that you're
in here are some of the cover crop
options I don't want to spend a lot of
time on this you can go back to this
later uh but these are some of the more
popular crops uh looking at things like
buckwhat for example is very easy to
grow and actually has very good wheed
suppression the problem with buckweed is
doesn't offer you very much in the way
of organic
matter and if you allow it to go to seed
before you get it down it itself will
actually become one of your worst weed
headaches uh oats are also a very
popular one uh the nice thing about oats
is that they winter kill uh so you don't
have to worry about trying to kill them
and having them come back on you um but
uh they don't tend to do a particularly
good job at choking out weeds unless you
seed them very thick uh Dutch white
clover is not one I'm a big fan of but
people like it because it's a legum and
can add some nitrogen to the soil but
you find over time uh it's a little
difficult to establish so that weeds can
come up and kind of get in there and
Seed before the the watch white clover
actually becomes well established uh
also Dutch white clover itself can
become a weed issue uh in and
raspberries just one of the plants that
will happily grow through a mulch red
clover is one I would suggest if you
have a hard pan situation because it's
very deep rooted and can crack break
open some hard pins but it really takes
two seasons to get established uh annual
Ry grass don't let the name fool you
this one will act as a perennial uh in
some situations but it's one that people
are starting to look at uh as a good
Miner of soil bringing soils back up uh
to the surface and then reincorporate
them winter eyy is one that gives very
good cover and offers a pretty good
shading and choking out of weed species
but it is winter hardy and it will have
to be killed either by tilling or using
herbicides in the spring time and then
finally sorghum Sudan is another one
that has some little pathic qualities
this one produces a lot of vegetative
growth and uh you might need special
equipment just to plow it down just
taking a look at a slide here you can
see the top slide is winter Rye uh even
a good stand of winter Rye unless you've
got a good mower uh is going to be
difficult to put down in the springtime
as I said this one will overwinter and
will go to seed and you need to mow it
down
before that seed uh matures on the
bottom slide you see sorghum Sudan again
this isn't something you're going to do
with a hand mower or a weed whacker you
need to have good equipment in a bush
hog to be able to get this down but you
can just see the amount of organic
matter you're working into the soil and
the potential for choking out beeds
there now let's move into getting
actually ready for planting these after
we've hopefully overcome most of the
more serious weed problems uh we can get
ready to uh plant these and we want to
plant them in such a way that we're not
actually encouraging more weed growth uh
one of the ways to do this as we
approach the planting year is to maybe
fow it for the season before planting
and this is just a case of using
repeated tillage throughout the growing
season not allowing anything to grow on
that soil for an entire season this is a
very good way of depleting the annual
seed bank because you till you bring up
more weed seeds they germinate you till
again before they go to seed you keep
bringing up more weed seeds and killing
them out before they have a chance to
reproduce you can also get ahead of
perennial weed such as quack grass this
way uh by com uh continually bringing up
the root system dehydrating them not
allowing them to get ahead of them and
basically dep depleting those plant
reserves in there the problems with
fallowing is that it's somewhat energy
intensive it can be a little hard on the
soil structure because you're not really
adding organic matter to that and you're
regularly stirring up the soil breaking
up some of those clouds but if you have
a lot of organic matter in the soil
there shouldn't be too big an issue
doing this for one season erosion of
course is a problem if you're on a slope
for example and water is going to pull
your soil off or if you're in a
particularly windy area you'd be
surprised how much soil it can actually
lose by wind but fallowing is a strategy
that can work fairly well for uh getting
rid of some uh nasty weed problems
without having to use uh
chemicals as we're getting ready
to plant there are some other strategies
we can use steale seed bed is one that's
popular with vegetable Growers but could
also be used with a perennial crops such
as strawberries or raspberries in this
case we prepare the ground either in the
fall or the early spring all set nice
and tidy ready for planting but in the
spring we allow that soil to sit and
weat Steed starts to germinate I have
two to four weeks here it's probably
more likely 4 to six weeks that you
allow those those weeds to start coming
up but not to the point where they're
going to be uh flowering or or setting
seed then we kill those weeds back
either with a contact herbicide or
flaming we don't disturb the soil
surface in other words we're not
cultivating here we're just killing out
what's on top if we don't dist disturb
the soil surface we're going to prevent
new weed seeds from surfacing and
basically keep that Toof layer of soil
acting somewhat as a mulch then we plant
keeping the soil disturbance to a
minimum so just plant right in the plant
rows the area between your rows which in
the case of raspberries is a good 8 to
12 ft a good bit of soil surface there
uh undisturbed and that should keep your
your weeds under control anywhere from a
few days to weeks depending on how much
rain you get anything else that might
disturb the soil surface and how much of
a weed seat Bank you have but still seed
beds can be a good way of getting your
plants off to a good start give you a
few days to a few weeks of relatively
weed-free uh conditions this is not
going to be true of where you've
Disturbed the soil every place you've
dug a little hole or or dug a trench to
put those plants in you're going to see
weed starting to come up so you will
have to have some other strategy for
that such as hand
pulling strip tillage is another thing
that's being looked at again we're
seeing a lot of this being used uh in in
uh vegetable crops but there's no reason
it couldn't work with uh perennial crops
such as raspberries or strawberries in
this case again we
prepare the ground in the early fall and
in this case we see a cover crop uh the
most popular one is winter Ry but we can
also use annual Ry or oats now this crop
will grow up during the late summer and
fall of that previous year then in the
spring spring time we go through and
kill that cover crop now in the case of
Oats they winter kill so we don't have
to worry about it but in the case of the
annual r or the winter R we would
probably have to use a post emerging
contact herbicide choone is typically
used but there might be something like
paraquat as well and Rich can speak to
this a little bit later then without
without barely disturbing that plant
residue we leave the residue there to
act as a mulch we till narrow strips
through the dead cover this does require
specialized equipment I'll show you a
picture of that in a minute and then we
just plant The Raspberries right into
these strips um the dead vegetation
inhibits weed growth it also tends to
keep the soil kind of cold so you may
see that this uh delays a little bit the
emergence of new primocanes and uh root
growth uh in your plants but raspberries
are pretty tolerant of cold cold soil
temperature so I don't think this would
be too big a deal here's a picture of a
strip tiller going through uh in this
case it was also a fertilizer injector
on the back of it but what we see here
is that there's just a series of of deep
tillage blades here uh some blades that
go down deep and then a couple of little
couter blades that just roll behind and
bring that stir that soil surface up to
make a a decent planting strip and we
can see the strips here in this case of
course those strips are far closer than
we'd have them in a raspberry situation
uh but you get the idea so this works
fairly well and again that residue is
going to hang around in the case of Rye
it would hang around probably through
most of the planting season in the case
of Oats you'll probably find that
residue will break down by about halfway
through the season
now as we move into the planting year
itself it's important to understand that
we really want no competition uh plant
competition for the raspberries in that
planting year one of the things I hate
to see is going into an established Turf
uh and then carving out some narrow rows
uh with a Rota tiller and then planting
our raspberries into that uh frequently
those uh Turf species are fairly
aggressive and will move back in and
become the predominant plant right over
your raspberries so I really prefer to
see that there be no competition in the
planting year between the rows now we
can keep that area between the rows
clean with shallow cultivation uh or
with flaming there are good flame
weeders out there it will have to be
directed so that the Flames aren't going
to burn the the raspberry plants you've
put in there so there'll have to be some
shielding involved and within the rows
we can either use hand pulling uh and
that won't be too big a job if we've
done a good job of pre-plant weed
management or there are some detail
cultivators out there that will do a
reasonably good job between the plants
they won't get get you completely out of
hand weeding but they will help here's
some of those cultivators uh just taking
a look at them uh this is a budding
cultivator that you see here uh what you
see is the plant actually runs through
this series of Wheels with fingers on it
uh that means that these can get quite
close and these little tines just
disturb the top inch or two of the soil
keeping those weeds down um of course
the toolbar you can see here is set
fairly low so this is only going to work
well if you're using plug plants for
your raspberries but also if you use
dormant canes as long as you've cut the
handle off you you'll be able to get a
couple of good weeks of use out of this
the Reggie weer that you see here is
very similar in that we have two
spinning heads with fingers on them down
here that will get rid of a lot of the
weeds and we have handles up here that
we can bring in or out and make those
heads
go closer or further away as we approach
the plants uh this also will work fairly
well again you see we have a little more
clearance here so we'll probably be able
to use this throughout I would guess
most of the planting year um but
there'll still be uh some hand weeding
to do in terms of using cultivators um
between the rows and in the aisleways we
can just use a broad cultivator this is
a l time cultivator does a pretty good
job of just disturbing uh the top inch
or so of the soil does a very good job
of keeping the weeds down provided that
you're using this before the weeds
actually break the soil surface we call
this blind cultivation you want to get
these weeds under control where they're
still in what we call the white thread
stage before they've actually emerged
from the ground uh so this has to happen
about every 10 to 14 days depending on
how much moisture you're getting just
going through there and raking this uh
over the plants um and here we
see a uh flame weeder there's many
different sorts of this but many heads
on this this could go between the rows
with uh some uh propane tanks in the
back leading to this then it's ignited
and the Flames just go over and burn
them out um again you don't have to
toast the the whole weeds with a flame
weeder you just need to go over them uh
very quickly and the cells will uh
basically explode and and kill those
plants well what about mulch actually
between the rows using that space
between the rows and covering it up with
mulch if we don't want to cultivate um
well if we're using strip tillage the
residue is already there acting as a
mulch so that will help you could apply
straw between the rows but it's going to
be fairly expensive I would not
recommend using mulch hay because this
is loaded with wheed seeds and you'll
have a lovely hay crop coming up in your
raspberries the next year um landscape
fabric can also be used but it's very
expensive and it's hard to maintain
because dust and dirt will be dragged on
there by your equip and so forth in any
place that
H happens you're going to have weed
starting to grow through it it's also
extremely costly the only place I've
seen landscape fabric used to any effect
is under high tunnels I don't think it
really has a place out in the field uh
and as I said the cost is very high and
the maintenance can be also quite high
but it is a strategy you can use if
you're only using a small planting to
mulz between the rows I've also heard
people say that they'd like to try to
get some row crops between there such as
beans um or one of these other vegetable
crops uh these these can be used again
as long as you're keeping them far
enough away and you don't feel that
they're going to be uh competitive with
the raspberries
themselves well what about within the
row uh within the row mulch is also an
option uh straw can be used this has
actually uh been shown to be very
helpful especially around plug plants
however I say this with an important
caveat the straw does need to be removed
in the fall so we can put it over the
plants right after planting in the
spring but we do need to remove it in
the fall the reason for this is that
through the winter and in the early
following spring what'll happen is it
keeps the soil very cold and wet and
tends to make some plants very
susceptible to phost Marvin pritz did a
nice study on this a few years back so
what I would recommend is go ahead and
use straw around the plants to try to
keep weeds from around growing right
around the plants if you will but
remember to take it off uh because you
want that soil to dry out as quickly as
possible in the spring using raised beds
can also help you in this situation wood
chips and shavings can also be used
they're a little bit heavy for using in
the planting year and they will delay
the emergence of the Prime canes but if
you feel that you've got a long growing
season ahead of you and you've got nice
vigorous plants a light application of
wood chips or shavings could be helpful
I'm not a big fan of sawdust sawdust
tends to be have too fine a particulate
in it it tends to crust and as a result
of that you'll find that the water has a
very uh does
not penetrate very well through sawdust
in fact it'll bounce right off and water
uh the Weeds on the sides so what I
would recommend is if you're going to
use sawdust blend it with some wood
chips or shavings or try to help that
way if you've got a source of good clean
compost uh this can be used as a mulch
and you can see that in the lower slide
here I've tried this myself uh and we
got very good weed control throughout
most of the first growing season the
problem with compost of course is it's
actually a pretty good metor for plants
to grow on so if you had a lot have a
lot of weed seeds blowing in uh it can
result in some problems for you but if
the mulch itself if the compass itself
is quite clean and you don't have a lot
of wheat seeds blowing in this can
actually provide a good surface cover
cover up any wheat seeds that are in the
soil uh and also over time as it's
breaking down provide nutrients for
those growing plants I often get
questions about uh using pine needles or
leaves or these sorts of things usually
if we've got a big planning the issue
here is with Supply and cost is it
really worth your time to go and rake
all those things out pine needles are a
great mulch they'll work terrific uh but
the question is whether or not you can
get enough of them um leaves I'm not so
fond of unless they've been broken up
because they tend to again mat down
around the plant keep it wet and can
lead to phyto problems as opposed to
pineals which are nice pores and D can
Qui oh there you're going to talk about
it here I was just going to talk about
yeah and and Molly shw I'm approaching
plastic mulch folks I'm not forgetting
leaving the mulch in place if you're
planting on ridges or raised
beds okay with with straw I would say no
the the evidence is pretty clear that
straw mulch uh just is is really bad as
as far as phyter is concerned if you're
using something that's more porous and
allows uh air through it so it will warm
up more quickly such as the shavings uh
that we talked about I would say
okay okay uh but straw mulch in my
opinion is fine for the planting year
but even with raised beds I would be
inclined to take it off uh the year
after that unless of course you feel
it's broken down if it's degraded enough
that it's not really going to be causing
you any issues in that case you could
probably leave it
on well what about plastic we get this
question a lot about using plastic mulch
uh first and foremost it's a little bit
expensive uh you're looking at something
between anywhere depending on what types
of plastic you use $600 to $1,000 an
acre um actually I should pull that back
it would be a little bit less than that
because you're using uh you're not using
quite as much in a raspberry planting it
really depends on what sort of plastic
you're using and how long you want that
plastic to last um what we have found
with shallow rooted perennial plants
like raspberries and blueberries that we
do get a little inhibition of of roots
right near the surface of the soil and
we think this is because the temperature
gradient under the mulch is a little bit
different than it would be under bare
soil but overall it doesn't seem to have
a huge impact on plant growth it will
inhibit primocane growth if you just lay
black plastic out there punch some holes
in it and plant through those holes
remember that your new Primal canes are
going to be coming up uh from root buds
further away from those initially
planted uh crowns so after those plants
have been in for a couple of weeks you
will need to run a slit down the middle
or maybe cut out a strip about a foot a
foot and a half wide to allow those new
primocanes to come up uh or else you're
not going to get good plant growth from
there now the biodegradable mulch may
offer a good answer here and that you
can put these mulches down uh and then
they will start to degrade the problem
with these so far is that they're
usually designed to last perhaps a
little bit longer uh than we'd want them
to in order to get those Pines up and
growing earlier so you'd want to take a
look at the
biodegradable Moes are usually rated on
how long they will last before they
start to degrade and you may want to go
with one that will start to degrade
relatively early bear in mind that
they're going to degrade all the way
they are they aren't going to give you
protection on the edges like you'd see
with the more permanent mulches you see
in this picture this is actually under a
high tunnel in California and the
biodegradable types are more expensive
right now they're somewhere between two
or three times the cost of the regular
black plastic mes but black plastic can
be used just bear in mind that you've
got to make room for those Primal canes
to come up and that it's going to be a
little pricey but it may be a cheap way
out if you consider how much it cost you
to go through there and do hand weeding
okay now let's move into actually the
years after planting as we move into
years 2 3 4 and five as we're getting
this planting established there are some
options for we control as we move
through here one of the options is to
keep this clean cultivated and this is
the way that a lot of the uh Growers
handle this in the larger R raspberry
growing regions of the country where the
crop is mostly harvested for processing
how can we keep those uh weeds down in
the areas but both in the Iowa and in
the row well frequent light tillage as
we've already talked about uh in the
planting year using flamers uh is
another way to do it again it' have to
be directed so that we're not burning
the plants them the raspberry plants
themselves hand pulling practical in the
row I don't think it's very practical in
the ale ways there um and of course just
the idea of clean cultivation here is
fairly going to be energy intensive it's
going to be difficult with perennials
especially if you've got one that snuck
in there or was already established in
there before you got planted uh erosion
is going to be a problem for you here
again if you're on a slope or
susceptible to wind and dust can also be
an issue if you're cultivating in there
when the fruit are ripe you're going to
have some dust issues on there the other
issue we have with dust if your planting
is quite Dusty it tends to be a real
attraction for two- spotted spider mines
uh so something else to keep in mind but
a possibility if you think you've got
the equipment and time to manage this
another way of going at this is looking
at using clean cultivation in the summer
but then planting a fall Co cover crop
so as we talked about in the previous
slide during the the summertime we would
use frequent light tillage to keep the
weeds out then we would seed a crop of
oats in the late summer or early fall
about the time we're finishing up
Harvest of our summer our florane
bearing varieties the oats will
winterkill and then the residue acts as
a mulch in the spring similar to what we
talked about with strip tillage summer
tillage is still going to be needed
because the oat residue will probably
break down uh and weeds will start to
grow through it before the end of the
season so you'll probably find you have
to till one or two times uh before you
could reced the oats next year bear in
mind if you're going to grow oats you
are going to have to put some fertilizer
down there for them in order to get them
established you can't just keep planting
them and expect them to do well this
might not be practical for Primal
fruiting varieties because you're going
to be seeding those oats and having it
come up about the same time that you
need to be in there doing harvesting and
other operations so you may not be able
to establish a good uh cover crop in
there with the prime fter but this is
something to be looked at uh Dr pritz
has done quite a bit of work with this
and strawberries and found it that it
can work very well there I don't see any
reason why we couldn't uh exp expand
that into raspberry production as
well but what is most commonly done here
in the Northeast is using a living mulch
between the rows and this is just a turf
grass established in those aisleways but
not allowed to get into the plant rows
themselves so we leave about a 3 to 5
foot strip a bare strip in the plant
rows so I point that out here so this
area in here has no grass growing in it
or so we hope and then the aisleways
themselves have a perennial grass
species growing in
them now I don't want to see this uh put
in prior to the plant going in as I said
I don't want any competition in the
planting here so generally what I
recommend is that this be sewn in the in
August or September of the planting year
or sewn in the following spring
generally what we want to see used here
is a weak perennial grass species such
as a non- creeping hard Fescue or
perennial rye or a mix of those two um
these are slow growing they tend to be
slow to establish so we have to be
patient with them and we may have to
control weeds coming up through them but
if they have enough uh nitrogen
eventually they will uh cover the crop
pretty well and be able to out compete
most of the weeds that are coming in we
don't want to use a conservation mix or
a contractor's mix or a pasture mix
because these contain very aggressive
ramous grass species that will quickly
become your worst weed problem I also
don't really care to use Clover I know
it does add nitrogen to the soil but
Clover can also become a weed problem uh
it will grow through mulch so it is
difficult that way and it can also uh
carry some uh diseases that they will
share with raspberry such as filium and
tomato ringspot fires uh believe me
Clover is going to come in on its own I
don't panic too much about trying to
control it but I certainly don't like uh
seeding it in there now once we have
this established it should be moded
regly to make sure that any weeds that
are in amongst that grass is not allowed
to grow up and shed seed uh so if we
keep this grass mowed quite tight the
grass Will Survive and the weeds will
eventually be
depleted as we move on uh to just
looking at this here we are seeing a
crop that's been seated in the
establishment year um you can see
here here I've got uh grass just
starting to come up I've mulched between
the rows uh this is a little heavy for
what I'd like to see in the planting
here but the it's doing fairly well
please note the trickle irrigation line
that's a awful nice thing to have in uh
raspberries really helps them go as we
move into the spring of the second year
in this slide again you can see the
grass getting well established you can
see that nice interface between the
grass and the mulch the grass is not
encroaching in of course you can see the
Clover is coming in on its
own
okay and then what about mulch in the
rows within the rows again just like we
talked about in the planting year wood
chips and shavings once those plants are
established a good thick layer will do a
pretty good job we don't want don't want
to use an old pile that has lots of
wheed seed in it but a good fresh pile
of wood chips will help this should be 4
to 8 in thick we can add to this as
needed because it will break down over
time and yes mulch does have some impact
on fertility it will deplete the soil of
the nitrogen right at the soil surface
and it can drop your pH but this can
easily be compensated for by having a
soil test see what you need to add for
fertilizer see what you need to
occasionally add for lime over the top
and you can compensate for any impact on
the soil fertility that this mulch might
be having um and overall this is
probably the best way to control weeds
in the planting during those early years
of
establishment and then as we look at the
annual maintenance of this as we finish
up here um we keep our grass aisles mow
tight as I said to prevent any weeds
from starting to come up and germinate
that don't over fertilize those aisles
we do need a little nitrogen to keep
that grass growing and to prevent other
weeds from coming in but if you over
fertilize them they will become more
aggressive uh and try to get into that
plant again you're going to have to mow
more you need to control encroachment
those grasses will try to move in on the
raspberry borders and you can do this
either
with herbicide strips or with uh
shielded flamers uh or just with an
edging tool for the grass now this will
hurt the raspberry Roots a bit but if
you're out far enough it shouldn't have
a big impact on them uh we need to
replenish The Mulch occasionally just
take a look at it each fall and spring
see if you need to add another inch next
year but over time you'll find as these
raspberries come thick and established
as you see in this light they do a
pretty good job of shading out most of
the weeds that are coming in there and
you may find that you can allow that
mulch to get depleted fairly well and uh
then it won't be have that cooling
effect on the soil that delays emergence
of the primocanes in the spring don't be
fooled some hand weeding is still going
to be necessary and it's important to
keep the area around your planting mode
as well um because if you're busy mowing
in here and keeping the weed seeds down
but they're blowing in from the unmowed
area around your raspberries you're
still going to have weed
problems so in summary with our our
non-chemical weed control uh bear in
mind that the average bed life of a
raspberry planting is 10 to 15 years uh
however I've been in plantings that are
20 25 years old the most common reason
for early bed failure in raspberries is
weeds period uh we talk about insects we
talk about diseases but weeds are really
the reason that of raspberry planting
becomes non-viable economically your
paths to success we're making sure that
your raspberries are not going to fall
victim to weeds good pre-plant
preparation as we talked about regular
cultivation using mulch in the rows can
help hand pulling is going to be
necessary and of course vigilance
keeping an eye on the weed situation as
it develops don't allow any particular
weed species to get ahead of you walk
through that planting if something is
starting to develop control it before it
becomes uh throughout your planting I
just point out this this last slide
here uh I I always find it amusing to be
in a raspberry planting like this where
the weeds are up to my chest but the
grower has diligently put a a Japanese
beetle trap on the end of the row um
believe me his problem is not Japanese
beetles at this point he's losing a lot
more money to those weeds than anything
The Beetles are doing
and with that actually we have a minute
or two do you want me to take questions
now or Dr Handley this would be a great
time and if you he'll still be there at
the end of Dr bonano so if you think of
it then you can ask him but just type
your question into the chat
box and while um we're waiting for
people to do
that I'm going to change the
presentation here
I hope I answered your questions about
the degradable mulch I don't know of
anyone who's actually been working with
degradable mulch other than a few
Growers who have been trying it uh I do
think it holds a lot of promise for
raspberries and and uh my suggestion at
this point is uh if you're interested in
the plastic mulches you can find a
source at a reasonable price give it a
try uh it looks it looks promising to me
my only worry is again that it won't
degrade in time to allow those Prime to
easily come up through in guards to the
raised ridges I I do I do like
raspberries being planted on raised beds
I think it's an ideal situation for
raspberries because it really helps
Define where the raspberries end in your
isway should begin and that is very
helpful as part of your weed management
plan and it also will help with things
like phyter but just be aware that uh
straw mulch can be if a thick straw
mulch layer is on there in the
spring time it's keeping those roots wet
it's keeping those roots cold even on
raised beds it could be an issue if
you're in an area
we we tried the biodegradable mulch with
a few Growers and had very mixed results
um some people thought that you know
they were very encouraged by it and then
we had other folks that hated it so it
was interesting oh there is one question
about the best time to put Mulch
on in the planting year uh in my opinion
if you're using straw you can put it on
right away it's so light and fluffy that
it will provide some weed control if
you're with a heavier mulch uh like the
uh wood chips I would probably wait
until your Primal canes have started to
emerge because if you put it on real
thick right off the bat you're going to
delay that primalan emergence so I'd
probably be putting it on Midsummer time
as we're moving toward the fall and
until that time you're going to have to
thank you very much Dr Handley um I'm
going to if you turn off your uh speaker
or your microphone well I'm going to
introduce uh Dr Rich banano who is the
weed um management specialist for
vegetable and fruit crops at the
University of
Massachusetts and um uh Rich if you are
right there I'll have you come on and
you can just take it from
here we can thank you I am here can you
hear me can you hear okay great
hello okay great okay so I'm
here okay so what I'm going to do is is
uh uh sort of pick up where David left
off and talk some about uh uh how
herbicides fit into this and and we'll
go through a number of different slides
here including some uh slides on
different weed species so Bramble floor
management David really uh talked about
two different areas one is um between
the rows and also in the row and
um what we um um are looking at is uh
mostly herbicides being used in the row
between the row as David mentioned is
always cultivation uh or some sort of uh
living mulch uh how wide of a middle
David mentioned 3 to 5 ft and really
what it comes down to is um research has
demonstrated that there's always a
benefit from having as much weed-free
area or cover crop area as possible but
there's some sort of practical uh mix
there where um you want to have u a weed
free area in the crop row but there's
issues related to trafficability whether
it's customers walking up and down down
or whether it's attractive moving um so
most people do have something planted uh
between uh the crop rows
um some people will plant something
there but if they don't want to mow it
all the time because of energy
constraints uh you can use low rates of
something like Roundup uh a very low
rate something like 4 or 8 ounces per
acre uh to go in and kind of hurt the
cover crop and in the wintertime excuse
me in the in the in the spring and it
doesn't have a lot of competition uh in
the summertime you won't have to it very
much but it still uh is there and it's
and it's growing uh so why do you want
to maintain a weed free strip in the row
David covered a lot of this but
basically it's competition uh broad
leaves are competitive grasses are
incredibly competitive because they have
a very shallow root system and and
compete most aggressively with those uh
shallow uh uh roots that are there from
the from the Bramble planting and of
course weeds Harbor insects diseases and
unwanted animals and sometimes they can
be allopathic effects of weeds even to
the Bramble
planting so we look at weed species
there's a number of different species
that are going to be out there and they
include summer annual weeds winter
annual weeds bals and then various
perennials so summer annual weeds are
more of a problem in new plantings uh
especially when you're going from an
annual culture system maybe vegetables
or um even strawberries for that matter
into uh something like brambles uh they
are very easy to control though with
many of the residual herbicides and and
uh some people especially in other fruit
plantings tree fruit plantings
blueberries uh are very into total
postemergence controls uh even grape
Growers I've seen people just use
multiple applications of Roundup one of
the things that is of benefit when you
are looking at a total post emergence we
control option is the presence of bark
bark is what allows you to make multiple
applications of Roundup and and to worry
a lot about residual herbicides but with
something like brambles where you're
always talking about these canes coming
up nothing is really ever more than a
year or so old you never really have
bark developing there's always green
tissue there postemergence only control
practices are not what I recommend I
think residual materials are important
and post emergence should be really to
help uh clean up
problems so some of the these are some
summer annual weeds they include things
that you've commonly seen common Lambs
quars common
Ragweed um uh also many summer anual
grasses like crab grass for example in
panacom and so forth uh winter annual
weeds uh can be a problem for many years
into a planting especially if seed
production is allowed now contrary to
Summer annual weeds that germinate in
the spring and set their seeds and drop
their seeds in the fall winter annual
weeds germinate in late summer or early
fall grow through the winter or or basic
Al stay dormant in the winter time and
then produce seeds the following spring
one of the problems with a lot of winter
annual weeds being out there or any
cover for that matter being out there in
the wintertime is the increased
potential for frost damage the cleaner
soil is under the crop the more that
soil will warm up and the less impact on
uh that Frost uh damage might have uh so
just something to keep in mind in terms
of how clean you want that cover to be
under those under that crop in the
winter time um and also if you have a
lot of winter annual weeds growing and
you're trying to put a residual material
down in the spring a residual herbicide
a lot of that herbicide will be
intercepted by the leaves of that
growing winter annual so it can cause a
problem with getting the herbicides to
work very well so some common uh winter
annual weeds include chickweed field
pansy henbit and again all these weeds
usually start to germinate after Labor
Day um and they can germinate even
through uh mid to late October depending
on the season uh bals are a different
kind of species they actually live for
two full growing Seasons uh they grow
vegetatively in year one they produce
seed in year two but it's usually a full
two-year growing season but they from a
practical standpoint they cause a lot of
the same problems as do winter annuals
uh an example of a winter annual uh weed
is uh berock or excuse me a banial wheed
is is
burdock so perennial weeds come in a lot
of different varieties and shapes uh
simple perennials like gandel lines uh
that just have a Tap Root creeping
perennials uh which are usually Vining
type perennial weeds that have an
underground ryone system and of course
grasses uh common dandelion a Tap Root
produces reproduces primarily by seed
and uh does not spread vegetatively um
for the most part in in plantings uh a
lot of Vining perennial weeds they
reproduce by romes that grow underneath
the ground and and come up in various
places one of the hardest problems to
deal with with Vining perennial weeds
like field Bine weed is that they tend
to come up in the spring and will tend
to grow up into the planting so even if
you wanted to say for example apply
Roundup in the fall to control these
weeds many times they're they're up into
the planting of the crop and it's very
difficult to make a postemergence
application uh without also uh hurting U
the Bramble crop quack grass is an
example of a
perennial grass and if I can remember
how to use the pointer here uh what's
specific about perennials is that you
not only have this these small fibrous
Roots which are um uh right close to the
plant but you also have uh these romes
which is sort of the spaghetti looking
things that are sticking out and it is
from these ryom that the new plants uh
uh can continue to grow uh one of the
one of the key characteristics of quack
grass of course is it has these little
oracles and it's one way to tell it from
a lot of the other grasses there to know
you really have quack grass and that you
have a perennial species uh to deal
with okay so uh for inro weed management
we're looking at uh pre-plant and David
covered a lot of that uh cultural weed
management um mulches and so forth David
covered physical weed management
cultivation and hand weeding and and
chemical so we're going to talk a little
bit about chemical uh and and uh and
about pre-plant as well so just a little
bit about herbicides and selecting the
proper herbicide you should really know
what weed species you have do you have
an annual weed or a perennial weed is it
a grass weed or is it a broadleaf weed
the age of the planting matters uh if
it's a new planting or it's one that's
established especially with new
plantings and especially if you're using
tissue culture plants you have to be
very careful on what herbicides you
might want to use the first year um the
older the planting is the more they're
able to handle herbicide applications
soil type limitations some materials say
um not to use them on very Sandy soils
or very grally soils and then also the
time of year is important because most
of these applications will go on in the
spring uh prior to um a a lot of growing
of the of the
crop okay uh so to select the proper
rate of a soil applied herbicide
whenever you're applying an herbicide to
the soil to prevent weeds from coming up
the rate of that herbicide is dependent
on the type of soil you have so the more
Sandy the soil the lower the rate the
heavier the soil the higher the rate
also it's based on organic matter less
organic matter equals less of an
herbicide rate a higher percent organic
matter would give you more of an
herbicide rate and this would be listed
on the label so something just to look
for if you're using a postemergence
material something like gmox or Roundup
or post or fusilade and we'll get into
these materials in a minute then it's
really what species do you have and
sometimes also the size so more material
might be required to control a larger
weed uh than a smaller
weed okay so some general guidelines
about control about applying herbicides
generally we're looking that all
applications that are made to the crop
row should be directed to the soil or to
the weeds at the base of the canes and
they should avoid green tissue now if
you're using a residual material a soil
applied material it's usually acceptable
that you might hit the base of the canes
a little bit uh you're going on in the
spring before you get a lot of new canes
coming up or really any new canes coming
up and you are going to be usually
applying the material from both Sid so
you're going to be walking down one side
of the row coming back on the other side
of the row so one of the things you want
to be conscious of is overlap you want
to make sure that you're not shooting
the herbicide to the other side as
you're walking down one side and then
coming back and doing the same thing
because right in the center of the row
you'll end up with a double rate so
whatever nozzle setup you use whether
it's an offset nozzle whether it's a
single 110 degree nozzle that puts out
an even rate over the entire uh amount
of soil that it touches or whether it's
uh a couple of maybe 80° nozzles that
are designed to overlap each other a
little bit just make sure that in the
center of that crop row that you're not
overlapping to the extent that you have
a double rate
there okay so here's the list of
herbicides that are registered in
brambles and it's actually quite a list
um it's it's a bigger list in
strawberries but actually quite a
smaller list than would be in
blueberries or even in tree fruits so
I've broken the list into soil Applied
Materials and also postemergence
materials so soil Applied Materials um
on the left here and they've broken up
also into two categories the first are
materials that are particularly good on
Broad leaves but not particularly good
on grasses and they include ceron
princep simazine and sinbar the
materials that are very good on annual
grasses will control some broadleaf
weeds but are not as good as the three
materials I just mentioned they include
solar cam Devol and surf so you
basically have three materials that are
great on Broad Leafs three materials
that are great on grasses and in most
cases you would use one of each one from
each
category combined usually in the spring
and we'll talk about that in a little
bit and that what gives you sort of
broad spect Wei control a gallery here
is a a broadleaf material similar to
princep and simine and sinbar but it's
only registered on new plantings it's a
material that is used uh predominantly
in Nursery production um and uh doesn't
have a lot of presence in in Fruit crops
it is not registered for bearing years
but just for non-bearing years so just
something to to keep in mind as an
alternative really to either princep or
simazine or sbar so on the other side
here we've got post emergence materials
and they're broken up actually into
three categories here post and fusillade
are are both postemergence grass
materials they are designed to control
grasses but only after the grasses are
up they've got good activity on annual
grasses but limited activity on
perennial grasses uh touchdown and
Roundup are both postemergence materials
that are broad spectrum in other words
they'll control both grasses and Broad
leaves they will also control annual
weeds as well as perennial weeds so
whether it's a summer annual or a winter
annual or a banial or a perennial
regardless if it's a creeping perennial
or a Tap Root perennial whether it's a
bro leaf or a grass these materials have
excellent activity touchdown is only
registered in the non-bearing year
Roundup can be used at any time but also
remember these materials will have
activity on the crop and so uh small
canes coming up uh or excessive contact
with the foliage and even contact with
the base of the canes uh can be a
problem so my recommendation is that
touchdown and Roundup really should be
used for control of perennial weeds and
and probably spot treatment or
individual hand treatment rather than
any sort of broad spraying on the crop
the last three materials Groome also
known as paraquat Scythe which is a um
um material that's made from sheep fat
actually but it's not Armory approved as
far as I can tell and also Rage which is
a new material are all um they're all
burndown materials they have they do not
translocate um they do not go down to
the root system and kill perennials they
simply burn the tops of the weeds off so
they have some benefit for example if
you wanted to burn off uh small winter
annuals if you wanted to have a clean
cover uh under the crop in the winter
time uh but they will also burn
perennial weeds but they'll only burn
the top so in effect they're the same as
mowing sometimes the use of these
products is called chemical mowing where
you can burn off green foliage green
tissue uh but then especially in the
case of a perennial it'll it'll just
come just come back rage is the newest
of these materials so I just wanted to
have a couple of slides to tell you
about rage common name is carfentrazone
it's it provides post control of broad
leaves and grasses all of the three
postemergence contact materials that I
mentioned gramoxone and scythe and rage
uh will control both grasses and Broad
Leafs or at least burn all grasses and
Broad leafes above the soil line the
rate of carfentrazone AR range is 20 to
40 ounces per acre of the formulated
product usually you'll add either a crop
oil concentrate at 1% which means 1
gallon per 100 gallons of spray or a
nonionic surfactant at a quarter of a
percent by volume which would be one
quart of surfactant per 100 gallons of
spray you basically would direct this um
to the base of the plants before Bud
break uh they suggest a hooded or
shielded application after Bud break I
frankly am always concerned about any of
these postemergence materials The Only
Exception would be the grass materials
poster fusilade which will not hurt the
canes um in the case of whether we're
talking about touchdown or Roundup or
whether we're talking about any of the
contact materials I still have a little
concern about spraying it and contacting
uh the canes at the bottom especially if
there's green tissue and again this is a
contact type material which means that
it will burn green foliage um it'll
it'll burn green tissue of any type but
will not translocate uh the other quick
thing I guess you should keep in mind
with any of the postemergence materials
if with talking about um I see if I can
go back to the list here yep if we're
talking about post ausel or touchdown or
Roundup these materials all translocate
so when you're talking about how much
water you should use in the application
the less water the better 10 gallons of
water per acre will give you much
greater control than 40 gallons of water
per acre using the same rate of the
chemical uh in this case we're talking
about a material that translocates it
goes in through the fold it translocates
through the entire plant it not only
kills the above ground part of the plant
but kills the root system as well and so
um more concentrated droplets are the
key when you're talking about a contact
material gmox scyth or rage the more
water the better because coverage is
everything if you contact every leaf
every leaf will turn brown if you only
contact leaves at the top of the canopy
only leaves at the top of the canopy
will turn brown you won't get the
control okay uh one other possible use
of carfent own or rage is to suppress
vegetation between rows it actually
listed on the label so 3 to 4 ounces per
acre of this product combined with crop
oil concentrate or nonionic surfactant
uh using a shielded sprayer especially
if you're doing it after Bud break and
that cannot be used even though you're
only putting it in the row middles here
uh cannot be used within 14 days of
harvest okay so uh again again I
mentioned some of these already Bramble
postemergence issues there's always New
Growth there's no real bark green tissue
can be hurt and shielding is almost a
necessity uh so one of the things I
wanted to mention real quick and I hope
it's on the next slide is what I call a
spot or cut treatment uh that really
makes sense when we're talking about
some of the perennial weeds and again uh
let me say that the original list of
materials that I mentioned the soil
residual materials we're really thinking
about those materials controlling summer
annual broadleaf weeds and winter annual
broadleaf weeds but not perennials when
it comes to perennials you need some
other measure of control and that's
really where the Roundup where the
touchdown uh comes in and
um so I I get a couple more slides
before I talk about the spot treatment
but uh David mentioned some about
pre-plant uh if the field was an annual
culture then a cover crop followed by
tillage uh and David mentioned this is
is really preferred if there not a lot
of perennial weeds out there and David
talked about cover crops and also about
fallowing but when he talked about cover
crops he talked about multiple cover
crops and um that's really the preferred
method uh even though yes leaving a
field fow for the whole year and just
going in with frequent tillage uh does a
great job of reducing the weed seed
population it's not really the best
thing for the soil so and and this is
very common in organic production also
is to use multiple cover crops the idea
is that if you plant a cover crop in the
spring and you expect at the end of the
season to have fewer weed seeds than you
started at the beginning of the Season
you absolutely will not have fewer weed
seeds and I will guarantee you you'll
have more weed seeds the idea with the
multiple cover crops in the frequent
tillage every time the cover crop gets
any real good amount of biomass is that
there's always going to be some weed
seeds that are going to germinate and
emerge and grow even with the cover crop
there those weed weeds then produce seed
you don't want them to produce seed the
idea is to go in and disc or provide
some tillage Rota tilling whatever it is
uh before those new seeds uh new new
weeds produce seeds and by doing it
multiple times maybe every eight weeks
or so you still get the benefit of
having a cover crop there but you're
also doing a good job of controlling
those weeds if you have a perennial
problem out there maybe there was
strawberries there before maybe there
was blueberries or some other plantings
or maybe you pulled out some apple trees
you have a pretty good chance of having
perennial weeds there you might still
want to use a cover crop early or late
but you really need to attack that
perennial weed problem with Roundup in
the year before you plant uh you do not
want to put yourself into a situation
where you're waiting till the planting
year or Beyond to start thinking about
controlling peral weeds it really should
be done the year prior to planting and
the best time to apply Roundup is in the
late summer or fall and the reason is is
that you're not just talking about
burning off what's above ground you want
to control that underground tap rot that
underground ryome system and the only
way to do that is to apply that material
at a time of the year when you're going
to get the translocation going down to
control those weeds and fall is the time
to do it now if it's a broadleaf species
like bindweed for example or poison ivy
or any one of these other Vining
materials or even um dandelion
late summer early fall when they're
actively growing possibly producing a
reproductive structure like a flower um
you can still get good translocation at
that time the danger with the broad
leaes is you don't want to wait too late
because then if you start having cold
weather or Frost you will not get the
translocation grasses on the other hand
can go later in the season now in the
north uh the the rule of thumb is we
always tell people if you're going after
a perennial grass with Roundup it's not
too late if you haven't sat down for
Thanksgiving dinner yet it's not too
late to make the application because
those perennial grasses especially quack
grass Orchard Grass are still usually
green and actively growing the only
criteria would be is you'd really like
to wait for them to wait for a day where
maybe is going to get into the high 40s
or low 50s so maybe you had a frost at
night or a freeze at night but you're
going to have a fairly warm day uh the
middle of that day would be the best
time to make that application um so we
really look at sort of a common weed
management strategy using herbicides in
in brambles we're thinking about using
princep or sinbar for broadleaf weeds as
a residual material we're looking at
using solar cam or deanol or surfland
for grass weeds um so annual grasses now
one other thing I'll mention is for new
plantings Devol is probably the safest
material it can be used on root pieces
it can be used on tissue culture plants
uh so if something for the first year
Devol may be the better of the grass
choices in the case of the broadleaf
materials sinbar really is not a good
option during the transplant year and if
you use any PRP it really should be at a
half rate and I'm not really crazy about
using PRP the first year until maybe the
first fall um of making maybe a half
rate application the first year and that
is in our recommendations that are are
listed as uh that you can find online uh
with the UMass website in the New
England small fruit uh pest Pest
Management guide ceron I didn't say a
whole lot about ceron is not really a
replacement for princep or sinbar what
ceron is is a soil applied material that
can do a good job of controlling a wide
range of perennial species and the
reason I I want to spend just a minute
or so on ceron is because unlike these
other crops that have a lot of bark
where you can use Roundup in the fall
and you have bark there and the crop is
protect protected you need to be really
careful in raspberries because just like
uh the weeds will have a better chance
of dying in the fall um if you get
Roundup on your raspberry crop there is
also a lot of translocation going on at
that time of the year for the crop so
the time that you can you could provide
the biggest danger to your raspberry
crop or your Bramble crop in general is
going to be with a fall application of
Roundup so if you just have a few
perennial weeds here and there spot
treatments make a lot of sense but if
you've got a lot of perennial weeds
maybe you've already got the crop
planted you forgot about perennial weeds
during the fallow year or time has gone
by and you've got a lot of perineal
weeds present you maybe you should think
about using casson ceron comes as a
wettable powder it also comes as a
granular formulation if you're going
after perennial weeds the granular
formulation makes the most sense the
wettable powder material does not work
as well as the granules the key about
casserine application is the probably
the best time would be very late fall
early winter before the ground freezes
and just before the first snowfall you
want to get this material on when the
ground when it's weather is cold above
50° is not good it will volatilize so um
even this time of year um if we have a
little break in the weather you can get
out there maybe there's no snow but
there's a snowstorm coming it still
makes sense to put some cter on some
people wait a little bit later but when
we start getting into a situ sitation
where you might have temperatures 50° or
higher it's probably too late to apply
the casson and again we talked about
some of these postemergence materials
Roundup gmox or rage for post Emer
control again uh gramoxone and rage are
only uh contact materials round up once
we get into the establishment year
because touchdown can no longer be used
uh is used for perennials um now the the
spot treatment I mentioned before is
something you won't find in the
recommendations but I wanted to mention
it real quick
there was a time when you could buy a
little Clipper uh one of them was called
clip clean both with a K Kip
Kleen and if you Google that you might
find some other products that are out
there and what these are um are ways to
apply a small amount of Roundup onto the
blade of your Clipper but it can also be
done by hand so we're talking about
using a handheld Clipper uh you cannot
use straight Roundup because it's too
thick you need two parts water one part
Roundup you basically would dip the
blade of your hand Clippers into the
solution and make a cut near the base of
the perennial weed now what makes this
the good part about this let me tell you
about the bad part first the bad part is
it's obviously very labor intensive
because you're going to go out there and
you're going to cut every one of these
weeds the good part is is it doesn't
make any difference what time of year
you do it unlike a a foler application
of Roundup which is really only going to
work late summer or fall to get the
translocation and application with a
Clipper in this manner will work at any
time of the year so if you have a Vining
perennial for example that's growing up
into your planting you can go out there
in the spring when it's 3 or 4 inches
high before it ever grows into the
planting and you can make some cuts and
maybe you take a row this week or this
month and another row next month but
over the course of the growing season
you can go after it just about any time
that the weeds are growing so it has
potential for spot treatment of perineal
weeds without making an application with
a sprayer without um potentially
contacting the crop and causing problems
but something that is highly effective
so just something to consider so again
here's the list as as we mentioned um
and again soil applied post emergence uh
grass materials bride Leaf materials and
um hopefully after I went through the
explanation that entire list makes a
little bit more sense about how things
uh uh fit in so some final thoughts know
you weed problems uh mulch effectively
when you can do it maintain the middles
as David has mentioned uh if you're
using herbicides apply them at the right
time at the right rates and with the
right equipment to avoid crop injury and
to maximize control I I believe that
using residual materials makes more
sense than postemergence materials in
brambles for the most part uh rotate
chemistries means that if you use one
product this year for broadleaf material
control use a different product next
year if you're using a grass material
and you use surf land this year use de
all next year try not to use the same
materials over and over again and please
uh read and follow all label directions
don't forget about the work protection
standards they apply to All Growers they
apply to Conventional materials they
apply to organic materials read and
follow all the label directions follow
the work protection standards and keep
yourself your family and your employees
safe all I excellent job of giving us an
overview of each um cultural and
chemical we control op options I think
it's probably one of the best
comprehensive presentations on weat
control for Bramble crops that I've ever
been at um I also want to just say one
thing and maybe um Rich you could answer
this I do not have Gallery touchdown or
rage in our
2010 guidelines and I just attempted to
try to check that you don't happen to
know whether those are registered in New
York do
you I believe touchdown is touchdown is
actually uh the hopefully the lawyers
want hear this is exactly the same thing
as Roundup different company um but it
only it only has a a um non-bearing
label um and uh but it it it's exactly
the same product you could certainly use
Roundup in the in the transplant year if
you don't have um um if you don't have
uh touchdown registered uh rage's brand
new it is possible that your DEQ has not
approved it yet in uh in New York state
it's I believe believe this is the first
year we just put it into our our new
guide which will be coming out in 2010
um and gallery has been around for a
while as I mentioned it's a nursery
material but it is possible that New
York has never registered one of the
reasons some people might not have put
it in all their recommendations is it's
quite expensive and and for for that
reason alone it might not be in your
guide but it is worth checking for New
York State okay I will do that so for
those of you who are from New York State
we'll try to make uh if if any of these
are um actually legal and able to be
used we'll try to put that on the
Cornell Berry website and I certainly
thank Dr Bano for letting us know about
them so I'm hoping that we have some
folks who have questions we're going to
move into the Final Phase but now's your
chance to ask um anything that's on your
mind or um that you might want to know
about we control for Bramble crops very
quiet group I'm hoping that you can
actually hear us I'm sure you would let
us know if you couldn't
and um I just put the last
uh the um page up here that has the
handouts and other information about uh
weat control for Bramble crops that you
can
download um I have one more poll well oh
we've got a few people typing some
things that's great so let's see what
they say I'll open up this other poll
just to get some ideas about whether or
not people had some um um challenges
with the webinar this
time uh Jeff asked about any experience
with
wipers uh so let me let me address let
me address that so a wiper application
uh is similar it's sort of a cross
between uh making a spray uh or using
the Clippers in terms of Effectiveness
it will work the same as a spray will
work uh it it does not have the benefit
of the clipping which will uh give you
the quick translocation but certainly
any of these wipers they make these
little little ones that are like hockey
sticks with the nylon rope uh just
remember just as I mentioned before
about the Clippers uh you cannot use
straight Roundup in there um and um you
have to use some water because um the
Roundup is too thick uh it will not flow
through that nylon rope but it will give
you the same effect as if you are making
a a foler application and again because
it's similar to a foler application fall
is the best time uh there are uh many
generic glyphosate labels out there as
Eric has mentioned I have not seen the
labels of all of the generic glyphosate
products because of course Roundup is is
about is more than 15 or 17 years old
now so it is off patent um I believe
that many of the companies especially
when they're gearing towards vegetable
and fruit Growers have tried to uh make
the labels very similar uh but of course
if you buy any of the generic glyphosate
products make sure that these crops are
actually listed on those uh those labels
all right we've got one other person
typing I'm not sure if he's typing to
the group I did want to let you know if
you do type your question into the whole
group it will be recorded for um during
the archive recording so everyone will
be able to see it later and that's
helpful and uh most a lot of people have
voted but um I I do want to thank both
of our speakers um we'll give a few more
seconds and see if this question is
coming thank a few our speakers for
joining us today I also want to thank
all of you
attendees uh we had some challenges at
least on my end we had some video and
audio challenges um but it doesn't look
like it was too bad for folks um but I
appreciate you hanging in there with us
in case uh you did lose audio it did
come back and um I guess that question
was not for the group but anyway so I I
guess there's no more questions coming
and I just uh want to thank you I will
leave this web page open so that those
of you who would like to uh continue
trying to download handouts can do that
for a few more minutes and I guess
that's it thank you so much uh Dr banano
and Dr Handley for being with us and
thanks the rest of you and hopefully
we'll see you for the next um Berry
webinar it's the Bramble disease
management webinar on February 3rd at
1:00 in the afternoon and don't hesitate
to give me a call or send me an email if
you have some questions about uh running
the webinars or or registering for them
all right thank you everybody I guess
that's it thank you so
much
e
e e