and you can see that red a raspberry
Crown B has really devastated the Vigor
of these plants and the
productivity at this point when we were
doing some insecticide efficacy studies
uh we had greater than five raspberry
Crown boore larv per plant and this is
what the plants look
like
biology and identification
this is a clearwing
moth it's native to areas from New
England to Georgia and west of Nebraska
and South to Louisiana it's been
reported damaging plants in British
Columbia and California and even in New
Mexico identification you can
see the adults have these
yellow boms
makes them look like a yellow
jacket and the the young the larvey are
in the in the cane or in the crown and
they're just a typical white cead or
clearwing
moth
hosts typically in in Arkansas we see
them mostly a damaging Blackberry but
they are reported to get on DeBerry and
raspberry further
north symptoms tunneling in the
crown sometime
in May and June you start seeing them
tunneling into the lower part of the
cane and here you can actually see
inside there inside that tunnel the head
of the
larvae canes are girdled at the base and
they Wilt as you can see to the right
here it kind of it looks like a
shepherd's Crook and they're dead all
the way to the soil line and this type
of thing happens in June July and
August and as I mentioned in the
previous slide yields do drop
considerably and the plants will
eventually die if they get enough laral
damage
biology eggs are laid on the underside
of the
leaf The larva walks down the cane to
just below the soil line and then
tunnels into the side of the cane where
it over Winters this is a photo from
Washington
State then in the spring starting in
early April in our area and probably
more likely May further north uh the
larvae tunnels in the in the
crowns and you can
see in the South we have 11mon life
cycle where it finishes in one full year
and in the north it actually takes a
full two years as a larva 22
months sometime in the fall I think in
the further north you start seeing these
pupil
skins um coming out in late August early
September in our area it comes out more
like in mid-september and you can find
adults throughout most of September or
October
and here's a a both a male and a
female there's a mating
pair and during the day you can find
females in this
posture where you can actually see them
curling their abdomen under the leaf and
laying an
egg scouting there's two way ways of
scouting in July you if you're just
looking for damage you can actually look
for
the dying
canes and in Tris plantings a lot of
times the canes don't get to move very
much with the wind and they don't break
off at the
bottom so you don't see the dying
cane uh but later in the season you can
also
cut and look for the larvae in the hole
in the tunnel
in September or late August you can look
for females laying eggs or you can
actually look for
eggs now in terms of
control we have been working on some
biological
control and we've also been testing
various other
insecticides cultural control if the
population isn't too high you can
actually find which plants are infested
in in July before they p at and remove
the
plant we have been having slight success
using biological
control and this is something that we
find that sometime at Bud break in
Spring um we can irrigate soil drench
the plants with some
nematodes but the best we've done so far
is about 53% reduction in l
[Music]
count this is research done by my
student Jackie
mccar we have done both releases
of nematodes s FTI H bacteria 4 and S
caroc capsi you can see the
rate and the dates late October this is
after egg
hatch may this is really about the time
when the larve in our area have started
moving up into the the
cane again we try to second year in
November with applications and then the
following year we did it right at
budwell uh trying to make sure we got
the
larvey here you can see the results of
correct timed applications we can get
anywhere from 80 to 100%
control
Brigade or Guth is now cancelled it used
to be our standard compound as a soil
drench but Brigade which is by fenin
works real
well and that's the only thing
registered right
now some of our Growers did not like the
label it says use a use 200 gallons per
acre of this material so we
tried 50 100 and 200 gallon rates as is
a soil
drench and you can see we had similar
fairly similar control with all rates
from 50 to 200 gallons but right now the
label says
200 you can see in May when the larvey
have already tunneled into the crown
they're pretty much unexposed to
pesticide and they also it's very
difficult for
nematodes we had very few nematodes
controlling the larv at that
time compared to an earlier application
just when they're starting to feed on
the on the
canes so we do have some success with b
control but not a whole
lot now applying your soil drench
whether it be nematodes or uh
insecticide you have to keep a weed free
strip so the material gets down to the
crown weeds cause poor
coverage here you can see our tractor
driver uh trying to apply this
material to the base of the plants but
he has to go through all that
grass and in this case he's applying
that egg hatch which is in October in
our area or even as late as early
November and you can actually delay
until Bud break in the spring which is
April in our area which may be May in
yours and like I said Brigade is the
only thing
registered okay um I've moved my speaker
a little bit away from my mouth is that
any
better I I think it's good Don I think
uh okay yeah I I think it's okay
green June beetle uh you can see you can
see this map in the green are all the
locations where they've been reported
feeding on ripening
fruit so if you're outside that area you
can ignore the next few minutes but it's
an interesting
insect identification the adults have
these almost fluorescent green wings
they're from 1 to 1 and 12 in Long the
larvae is a grub it's
c-shaped and has a vertical
roster you can see that right here these
hairs are in a two rows
vertically these are the hosts they
attack ripening
fruit you see grapes apples and you can
get them on black
berries typically most of our
blackberries are almost finishing uh by
the time the adults come out here you
can see the adults coming out in mostly
in July and
August there's a larvae it's easy to
recognize it's you usually nocturnal but
it ambles Along on its back in the
grassy
areas pupates in the soil in a soil
cell you get some adults coming out in
late June early July they lay eggs they
get hungry go feed on fruit anything
ripe the ly feed on decomposed organic
matter so if you have a pasture with
Organic Matter U manure that's where
they'll
be we do have a rearing method for our
various studies we just use soil with
some alala meal as a nutrient Source in
may we can actually sift the
soil we get the pupil cells get some of
the larv there's a soil cell right
there and we can sex The Beetles the
adults can looks like two Cat's Eyes on
the female and this more horizontal
structure on the on the male in terms of
their abdomen tip
we've been developing a trap for Mass
trapping green je
beetles and you can see the the Box on
the upper left we have we catch
thousands of these beetles so we had to
increase the Trap capture
size we have a green June beetle lure
that's actually available like from
Great Lakes
IPM which we
developed and also also uh we use 90 91%
isopropanol and you can see that both of
those uh give fairly similar counts
10,000 14,000 this is a week count in
one week's time we catch that
many green Gene Beetle control uh
there's a number of
compounds registered for green Jean
beetles but most of them have more than
a three-day preh Harvest interval and
what you're trying to do is get them off
ripening fruit so it's it's kind of a
tricky deal to find the right
compound Mass trapping so far has not
been effective after our first year but
we think that using several traps around
a planning we may after several years be
able to mass trap the population out of
the area so they'll be below damaging
levels I know Japanese beetle is in your
area you you can see this is the
distribution map anything in
purple so basically
anything from Iowa Minnesota Iowa
Missouri
Arkansas and Georgia North to all the
way into Vermont and and
Maine just for your information I'm
located in this Hotpot right here
Northwest
Arkansas Japanese beetle
D fairly easy
to identify it's about half the size of
a green jein beetle has brown
wings has these six white spots on the
side of the abdomen with this nice
couple toughs on the
tip C shaped larva and a v
raster that's this kind of v-shaped
hairs right
here
Japanese beetle is an introduced pest
from
Japan 300 species of plants that it
feeds on and mostly it's a
defoliator but you can see on the crepe
or crab apple in the middle it will feed
on fruit and it does get on blackberries
but we see more damage on the leaves and
the and the
flowers recently Maxi and Fifer produced
this nice graph showing the number of
Japanese beetles per 2 m a
row relative to several varieties of
raspberry and you can see that the first
four are
very low in terms of Japanese beetle
counts but then you get uh Autumn Bliss
fall gold and Prelude seem to be a
little bit more
susceptible
Japanese beetles differ in defoliation
of those same raspberry varieties here
you can see percent
defoliation and again fall gold Autumn
Bliss and Prelude seem to have the most
folar damage but even 5% doesn't seem to
be a whole lot but in our area it tends
to be more the leaves around the
flowers so that could be
damaging scouting in control
Japanese beetles come out in June in our
area uh July up in
Michigan and you can see they like to
feed on things on the top part of plants
these are this is grapes they just
skeletonize the top part of the
plant and our Growers ever since they've
been here since about 2002 we've been
having to apply weekly insecticides to
prevent that
defoliation this this year we tried
using surround K and Clay on the plants
and you can see the difference in
defoliation we' drastically reduced the
defoliation with the surround but ever
after every rainfall we've had to
reapply it to maintain that whitewashed
look so that does seem to be a a good
alternative to several weekly sprays of
insecticide okay our last the
last insect I'll organism I'll talk
about is a broad Mite this is a new pest
in our area it's usually a problem in
Greenhouse plants in temperate and
subtropical
regions as you can see it gets on pepper
and
impatients and causes Leaf
deformation but in 2007 we actually
found this on priman Berry and
blackberry Prime Arc
and I'll address the Japanese beetle
traps here in a second I saw that come
up
um on the far right you can see promane
Blackberry being
damaged here's the broad Mite
distribution with all the little black
dots these are the two new locations in
Arkansas North
Carolina we found them in both locations
I don't know what it is about Primark 46
but it seems to the broad Mite seems to
like that
cultivar what does it look
like you can see it's about a tenth of a
millimeter in size they're not very big
the
males are yellow have longer
legs the
female is more
white and it kind of you can almost see
the egg inside the Fe
fale and then the egg is clear with
those 30 29 to 37 white tuffs very
characteristic what does it
do
acce pictures are infested plants
compared to the healthy plants BDF you
can see it greatly reduces uh cluster
size and leaf size and it curs curls the
leaves
management uh we're just starting to
learn how to manage these but we did use
some predatory mites we we purchased and
released uh predatory
mites and javic has also indicated that
he used neocis
californicus and got fairly good control
um on
pepper might decides of course that are
labeled that you can find broad might on
the label and some of the insecticidal
Soaps and and
oils these are many of the Publications
that I mentioned during the
presentation and just to acknowledge
some of our funding sources in organic
or integrated organic program ir4 minor
use
program uh we also have some funding
from our uh small fruit
Consortium at this point I'll try to
answer any questions I guess I can go
back and answer that question about
Japanese beetle traps yeah we've used
Japanese beetle traps around um a grape
vineyard we had like 17 traps we could
only trap on one side because there was
cows that were eating our traps on the
other
sides and we trapped over a million
Japanese beetles and there was still the
grower still applied three sprays in his
Vineyard and was still losing foliage so
in a very high
population Japanese beetle traps will
not mass trap and remove enough to
prevent having to use
insecticide um do we have any other
comments or questions for Dr Johnson uh
I think people are typing and maybe oops
um there's another one the with the same
cultural controls for Crown board work
with cane
bore yeah I think uh Hannah will
probably mention that um she'll be
talking about redneck can boore and one
of the controls is if you have about
less than 5 to 10% of your canes Gall
you can remove those during the pruning
period but if it gets above 10% you're
starting to cut into your yield by quite
a bit uh so that's kind of where we do a
cut
off and then there's a question from
Marvin pritz about the photo um showing
the big differences in Crown board
damage and whether that was the age of
the planting or the cultivar that
provided that
difference well the the cultivar in the
back and that second very second slide
was very new that was about 2 years old
go back to that and then the cultivar in
the front yeah I think it was slide two
I don't know where it's at really it's
slide four
um yeah that
one these are 2ye
olds these are about seven or
eight-year-old Navajo these are I think
it was Apache or
aapo and then Jeff Miller had a question
about the mode of action of the clay
application and that's just a surface
kind of thing right yeah it it's
basically makes the the leaves white and
it also creates a
kind of a dust on the on the plant so I
think one the Japanese beetles don't see
the plant as a yellow plant they see it
as a white structure so it's kind of
camouflaged and two I think it really
they spend more time cleaning their
mouth parts and their legs when they're
on those leaves so it it's kind of a
disturbing uh dirty appearance on their
food it's it'd be kind of like
us putting sand in our in our food and
trying to eat that it's not very
appetizing I don't think it kills any
and then there's a question about the
application and I think around us we
just spray it on is that how you yeah
it's all sprayed on and it's one of
those things you have to be patient with
because it kind of goes on slow you
spray it once I had a commercial grower
used his Air Blast sprayer he he went
down the roow once and looked at it and
he said well it's still not quite white
enough so he went again and it took
about two or three trips to get get it
to a accumulate to kind of a whitewashed
appearance the challenge to keep it
agitated too I know that's an
issue yeah you have to have an you have
to have an agitator uh system in your
tank or if you're doing it by backpack
you do a lot of
dancing a lot of dancing I I just wanted
to comment to those people who think
that the June beetle might not be an
issue for New York and New England but
certainly in the Hudson Valley we've
seen these in sex um and I think that
probably in the lower Southern Tier they
may have seen them uh and perhaps
certain areas of um New England as well
so that it's we're not completely out of
the woods with that one and I just
wanted to ask a question quickly before
we move on but um the broad Mite that
you're talking about is it the ex is it
the same broad Mite that's a greenhouse
pest is that what you said
earlier okay yeah right thank you thank
you very much does anyone else have any
questions or comments for Dr Johnson he
will be here through the next
presentation so perhaps at the end and I
think we'll okay great thank you yes
let's move on to our second speaker
um
things here I'll turn mine
[Music]
off this is um I'd like to introduce Dr
Hannah Barack um she is from North
Carolina State University and is the uh
an assistant professor and extension
specialist there she actually has um
some responsibilities with small fruits
as well as tobacco working to enhance
Pest Management in both of these crops
she's interested in landscape scale
management issues host preference
behavior of insects and invasive species
biology so I'm very happy to have uh Dr
Barack join us to talk about U more
caneberry insect
management are you able to turn on
your sorry
oh can you hear me all right
now
I have the little mic icon can you okay
excellent excellent all right so I'm
going to go ahead and get started here I
have um just one quick comment about
Japanese beetle traps and Surround first
of all Don I'm incredibly impressed that
you apply surround with a backpack um my
experience with that has always been the
rates of the material you have to use
make it a pretty heavy duty amount of of
clay that's going on there and um I
actually worked on it uh in olives in
California and to get good coverage on
tree crops is particularly challenging
you need a lot of water and a lot of
clay so it's a pretty heavy duty process
and then uh just to comment briefly on
Japanese beetle traps we actually
discourage Growers from using them in
North Carolina because the lures are
incredibly attractive they'll draw
beetles in from a great distance but um
they don't actually as Don said trap
them out of the area they've been shown
to pull beetles in from as far away as
up to a mile so basically you're putting
out a little signal that you've got
something interesting they should come
check out and along the way they might
find your planting in addition to the
Trap itself so we we don't recommend the
use for the the use of them by Growers
because typically they tend to either
not help with the problem or potentially
make it worse and I'm going to focus on
another set of caneberry pests
particularly some Beatles mites talk a
little about thrips work that we're
doing and I'll talk briefly about some
potential pests Laura mentioned that I
have an interest in invasive species bi
biology so that'll come out a little bit
at the end of this talk as
well but first I want to acknowledge
some folks who've done a the bulk of the
Canberry work before I arrived in the
Southeast you've heard from Don this
afternoon and Don presented some work
that's been done by Doug feifer and his
graduate student Laura Maxi I'll also
have some information of theirs in this
talk as well and I also want to
highlight one of my Horticulture
counterparts down here at NC State Gina
Fernandez she is the Berry
horticulturalist as well as a breeder um
looking particularly at developing some
heat tolerant raspberries because those
of y'all north of us get to grow all
sorts of great raspberries but we're
stuck uh in the Southeast with the the
inability to grow raspberries in the
warmer parts of the state here I also
wanted to highlight a couple Internet
Resources um Laura mentioned my blog and
feel free to check that out I post about
two to three times a week and I try to
keep that fairly up to date if there's
any comments that you have on that feel
free to post them there or get in touch
with me if there's something you'd like
to learn more about and then my personal
website is here we're in the process of
De of developing integrated Pest
Management web pages as a part of this
website so that's in process as
well I want to talk a little bit about
um my philosophy of integrated Pest
Management before we jump in here um
primarily because I'll be talking about
IPM in the context of this presentation
and I want to make sure we're all on the
same page first so so when I think of
IPM I think of the three M's and for me
that's minimize Monitor and manage and
practically what that means is we
minimize the likelihood of having a pest
problem in our planting by reducing the
things or changing the things we can to
result in a the least hospitable
environment for pest as
possible secondly we monitor our pest
populations which means we track both on
an individual point in time and through
time to see what our pest populations
are doing also under here are some
things that Don touched on really well
specifically we need to know what
insects we have so those ID techniques
are really important and that falls
under monitoring and finally manage and
this is the thing we tend to think about
first when it comes to integrated Pest
Management but really it's a logical
outflow of these first two minimizing
and monitoring then we decide whether or
not we have a pest problem that requires
management so the ways we manage pest
are threefold and again I have these
listed kind of in terms of hierarchy
first off we start off with cultural
control those are the things we do in
that minimized category we select the
right variety we fertilize in the way
that's appropriate for Pest Management
we um prune in ways that reduce our pest
population I'll talk about how some of
those tools apply to specific Canberry
pths as we get further in here
biocontrol is the second tier I like to
exploit so first we do everything
culturally we can to make the least
hospitable place for pests secondly we
move in and see if there's cultural
control techniques that are appro or
sorry biological control techniques that
are appropriate for the pests that we're
trying to Target and again these are
things like using Predators um or as Don
mentioned using nematodes those are
different biological control organisms
that we can utilize in the Canberry
system and then third I like to consider
chemical control after we've considered
the first two and I break down organic
versus conventional because I think a
lot of folks particularly people who
aren't producers get organic kind of
thrown all up in there and really
organic producers still to a certain
extent may use chemical controls they're
just omy acceptable chemical
controls so as long as we're talking
about chemicals let me first mention um
I'm not going to be talking about a lot
of pesticides in this talk and that's
primarily because all of you all are
from different parts of the country so
both pest status and biology are going
to differ based on where we are where
there are differences between people in
the Northeast and the southeast I'll
point out because I think that's where
most of our folks are from and in
general the insect pests covered in this
talk are east of the Mississippi so I'll
point out any Critters that might differ
along those lines but there's as Don
showed in some of the maps that he
Illustrated with most of the organisms
that we're going to talk about are
Canberry pasts East in the
Mississippi so biological and cultural
control methods can generally be
generalized over lots of different
places using predatory mites using
nematodes pruning those are things we
can do pretty much anywhere but the time
at which you do those might change so
bear that in mind when I talk about
those methods chemical control options
specifically pesticides are not
generalizable registrations for
materials differ between states so I may
slip and mention some specific
pesticides at points in this talk but
contact your local Cooperative Extension
folks for local recommendations about
which materials are registered and
recommended for the pest in your area
because the label is the law that's the
most important thing to follow whenever
you're using a pesticide if it's not
labeled for the use that you're using it
for you cannot be using
it so this is a a timeline for the
southeast for some of the Canberry pests
that Don mentioned and that I'll be
mentioning um I have the months down
here along the bottom but I also broke
out the plant phenological timings along
with that so for those of you who are
not in the Southeast refer to the bloom
fruit development and harvest timings as
for when these organisms are going to be
showing up I'll be talking a little bit
about Clippers let me hop ahead to the
next slide here I'll be talking a little
bit about Clippers about cane bores
about stink bugs thrips and two spotted
spidermites so let's jump right into
those so we already already had a
question about cane bores we've got two
different cane bores in this system the
first one that I'm going to talk about
is the raspberry cane boore it's a Lorn
Beetle you can see where it gets its
name from it has these lawn and tenny
and it's actually in the same genus as
the rasp uh the blueberry stemor so this
is a Genus that is an issue on other
small fruits as well so the adults for
this particular insect appear in June
the eggs hatch in July and the larv over
winter in the canes when the eggs are
laid there's a girdling that's about a/
inch apart about 4 to 6 in below the
growth point on a cane this will result
in some pretty distinctive tip wilting
above these two girdle points the larvae
is then going to move down the cane as
it feeds toward the ground and that
entire cane will
die most of the biology studies for this
particular past are from the north and
they suggest that there's a 2-year life
cycle Don mentioned that there's a
2-year life cycle for the raspberry
Crown bore in the North and a one-year
life cycle for it in the South we lack a
lot of studies on this particular
species in the South so it may be a
similar situation that we have a shorter
life cycle here I mentioned the larv
move down the cane as they develop we'll
talk about some cultural control methods
for cane borers in general but for
raspberry cane bore it's particularly
important to prune below the damage keep
going on down that cane until you no
longer see tunneling in there when
you're removing them because if if you
don't you might not be removing the
insect and it'll continue to
develop the other can Bora that we have
and these are some slides that Don
graciously provided for me to use as
well is the rednecked canbor and this is
what we call a metallic wood boring
Beetle they don't have those lawn and
tenny on them and these are native to
Canada New England out west to Minnesota
and South to the Gulf States so again in
east of the Mississippi pest this is
what they look like you can see their
antenna are much shorter than the
raspberry
camore so the adults feed and mate on
the
leaves and they lay their eggs only in
the prime canes in the early summer the
larv then girdle the cane you can see a
feeding cell for the larvae right here
with some frass in
there the girdling produce Gall produces
Galls in Midsummer the larv over winter
in the pit of the cane these Galls
actually will predispose these canes to
Greater degrees of winter injury because
you'll see some photos in the next set
of slides that actually show the canes
are kind of bunched out so they become
more susceptible to
damage there's some historic work all
the way back in the 30s that actually
listed some cultivars as perhaps having
some resistance to Redneck can bore of
course these are cultivars that were not
really growing much anymore so not a lot
about our currently grown cultivars is
know but it appears that at least
there's some resistance out there in the
germ plasm to this particular
pest there's really no known biological
control for either of our cane boring
beetles in in this particular system our
cultural control method is very similar
to the the cultural control method for
rasbury Crown boore during the winter as
Don mentioned if fewer than 5% of the
canes are gall prune off those G canes
and Destroy them it's very important
that you don't just pile up those canes
on the side of the planting and let them
sit there because the insects will
continue to develop in them and can
emerge out as adults and reinfest the
planting so they need to be burned
chipped removed off
site you can also cut off Prime Gaines
down to the soil
surface and that reduces that guling
pretty distinctively and Don has some
photos from a trial that was done in
Arkansas and this is I I mentioned what
that guling looks like and you can see
how it distends the cane there and can
result in some greater potential damage
so the logic for this trial was to avoid
Galls on primocanes after the egg Lane
was occurring in early
spring and pruning was done at several
different
dates and this photo was taken about in
the middle of this and you can see the
three different different plots that
were pruned out there and the go number
of Galls were then tracked and the
take-home message there is that after
that egg laying period was when the
lowest degree of Galls were
observed and you can uh we can talk with
Don a little bit more about any
additional questions you have about this
particular trial we're I'm glad that
he's sticking around for the rest of the
session so as we mentioned cultural
control if you have less than 5%
injury if there's greater than that
degree of injury and 5 to 10% is perhaps
a rule of thumb that is a rule of thumb
that we use a bit more in North
Carolina if there's greater injury
there's some also some pesticide options
that are available that would be used
during that egg laying time when the
adults are out and about the target
insect for treatment is the adults we're
not targeting the larv in this case
because they're going to be feeding
inside of the cane and difficult to get
a contact with an
insecticide so spray where the adults
are the lower part of the canes
especially in the primee since that's
where they're going to be laying their
eggs there are also there's a a label
for systemic insecticides use pre- Bloom
that type of treatment would be
targeting the larve and the cane and not
the
adults moving on to Strawberry Clipper
this is a weevil it's in the same genus
as the bull weevil so those of you who
might be more familiar with that it's in
the same group the adult is a small
Weevil this is the type of injury that's
attributable to Strawberry Clippers they
do exactly what their name suggests they
clip right below the bud what that is is
them laying an egg at that point and the
larv will then feed on the tip of that
bud so the threshold um or the number of
buds to sample is sampling 100 clusters
beginning after first Bloom these are
thresholds that were developed in
Arkansas and then when damage is
observed begin insecticide treatments
but I want to caution all of you be very
very careful with Bloom insecticide
treatments and this is just a link to
one of the North Carolina egg hem manual
sections on insecticides that have
varying degrees of B
toxicity so this is the sort of
thing to keep an eye out for if you run
into an issue where you expect to be
treating during Bloom for whatever type
of insect we try to avoid recommending
Bloom treatments unless they're
absolutely
necessary and I'll be interested to see
what people say in response to Laura's
question down there in the chat as to
whether or not anyone's seen damage in
New
York moving on to
spiderm because we primar L grow
blackberries in North Carolina they're
usually a secondary pest for us we see
them in
the fall on primocane
leaves however there are much more
serious pest in raspberries and I will
show I'll show you some photos that
illustrate that from the Pacific
Northwest and that's where the most work
has been done on spidermites and
caneberries so these are images of two-
spotted spidermites tetrus ER is the the
scientific name and this is an adult
female you can tell that it's a female
by her rounded abdomen versus the male
here who has a pointed abdomen these are
some eggs they're perfectly spherical
they almost look like little perfectly
round grains of sand these can be pretty
easily observed with a handheld hand
lens 10x or greater would be my
recommendation these are images from the
ucim web page it's just
www.uc or IPM davis.edu and I'll type
that down in the
Box
one of the challenging things with using
the internet is your IPM tool is that
there's going to be things that are
different from region to region and the
IPM website at UC Davis is an excellent
resource for images I wouldn't
necessarily use it as a source for Pest
Management because as a west of the
Mississippi Source it's going to have
some very different recommendations than
we would
have spider might's diapause in the
winter and a diapause ing spidermite
looks like this they're kind of salmony
orange color and these food spots will
go away as they're diapausing because
diapause means they're not eating and
they're not
reproducing spidermites could be flared
by the use of broads Spectrum
insecticides and caneberries this is
where we tend to see most of a problem
in the Southeast is if people are using
broads Spectrum insecticides they can
create a spidermite problem where there
may not have been one before there are
very good might specific contr control
options that should be used instead of
broadspectrum
insecticides there's no developed
threshold or scouting program for mites
and caneberries but a suggested scouting
plan for those of you that might be
concerned about them would be to sample
at least 10 leaflets per Acer count the
number of mites present and treat when
there are visual Leaf symptoms and this
is what I mentioned about raspberries
being far more susceptible to
spidermites then blackberries will these
are this is an uninfested Leaf this is
an infested Leaf in raspberries and
apologize for the picture quality here
but these are plants that have been
essentially defoliated by spiderm
feeding and I mentioned that there are
primarily there have been primarily
worked upon in the Pacific Northwest in
addition to the two- spotted spidermite
which is shown here they also have two
other spidermites that they've recorded
from canberries the yellow spidermite
and the McDonald spidermite so those are
also out there they're going to differ a
little bit in appearance but they
management and feeding Behavior will be
essentially the
same
when we talk about those two of those 3M
of IPM minimizing and managing the most
important thing to do for spider mites
is to select the right pesticide when
mites are present particularly in
blackberries because they don't appear
to be as much of a concern from the
defoliation standpoint as they are in
raspberries so select a material that's
not going to flare spidermites
minimizing Road dust can also contribute
to reducing spidermite populations
because they have out on the undersides
of leaves dust can adhere to the webbing
that they create hence their Nam
spidermites and create these refugia
that they can hide in so dust can
exacerbate problems there are also
native and introduced biocontrol methods
that are available this is just some of
the commercially available predatory
mites phyto cilus pmus neilus cnicus
galendromus oxident Talis in addition to
many other predatory mites that are
available some of these may already
occur in regions or they can be
purchased and augmented if they're
already there see if they're doing the
job for you and finally use might
specific tools to control them so use
MDES to treat populations rather than
using broadspectrum
insecticides moving on to thrips we've
been looking at thrips in my lab in
blackberries for two years now and we're
going we're getting ready to rule into a
third year and the reason why we're
looking at them is because there's been
grower concern about fruit injury and
potential pollination impacts they're
also a potential contamination pest this
is a box of blackberries that I bought
at the grocery store this summer and I'm
not going to say where they were from as
I was sitting driving in my car the way
home I noticed that thrips were crawling
out of the box so I had to make my
significant other take a detour to the
lab so I could take a picture of uh of
the thrips that were coming out of these
blackberries that I just purchased at
the gr grocery store so they are a
potential contamination
pest uh the objectives of This research
were to figure out because we
essentially knew not nothing about the
thrips that were here um the diversity
and the seasonal biology of what was
present and if they were actually
causing a problem if so what management
strategies could we
use so what we found is that thrips are
present in both flowers and foliage in
much higher numbers in the in the
flowers however and the plant samples
Peak during
Bloom you can see in the dark orange
line and the open Square line here those
are our larvel thrips and our adult
thrips in samples those samples Peak off
the plant in
bloom
however our trap captures continue to
increase even though our plant samples
decrease so our trap captures although
pretty decent at tracking our plant
samples early in the season just keep
going up because they continue to move
around but they're not present on the
plants in the same
way the traps that we're using are these
two commercially available traps this is
a yellow am trap and a blue card trap
both of these are available from Great
Lakes IPM and Laura gave you the link
earlier in the chat and these are some
homemade traps that we use because they
allow us to identify to species the
thrips that we're catching on them so
they're the same color as the two other
traps that we're using but we use them
because they're a little a nicer
research tool but commercially these are
the types of traps that would be out
there and I'll go back to that slide for
a second just to illustrate numerically
we tend to catch more thrips in the blue
traps but the results between the two
years have been a little conflicting we
got significantly more thrips in our
blue traps in 2008 and in 2009 we didn't
see significant differences except for
one date between our blue traps and our
yellow traps the reason why we use
different colors is because different
species of thrips are attracted to
different colors so we wanted to make
sure that we were catching what was out
there as I mentioned our Blossom samples
have a much higher density our foliage
samples have some thrips out there but
they have a much higher diversity and
that's just illustrated by these two
figures our Blossom sample over here and
our foliage sample over here lots of
different species showing up here really
only one species here which are Eastern
flower
thrips we've been looking at insecticide
efficacy for these for this particular
group of insects as well and I'll just
give you the cliffnotes version of that
we can reduce strips numbers with
pesticides but this reduction hasn't
corresponded with an increase in fruit
size an increase in drupelet number or
an increase in
uh better shaped fruit and I'll show you
some some data on that um fruit set was
not assess assessed in these
trials but we did a small scale caging
trial in 2009 to see if we could force
damage from these insects and
blackberries this was done in Kinston
North Carolina we caged buds or flowers
either mature buds that were going to be
flowers in a matter of a day or so or
open flowers with different densities of
thrips with 0o 5 10 and 20
thrips and then we assessed fruit set
size shape drupelets white drupelets
because we folks were concerned that
white drupelets may also be related to
this there are some limitations this
trial that I'll be completely upfront
about we didn't look at survivorship of
the thrip so we didn't go back and make
sure they made it through the week that
they were caged on there we used Western
Flower thrips because that's what we had
in a colony and we also there might have
been some potential effects to caging
although I don't think so
however at those densities we saw no
difference in the number of fruit that
were set so this is 90% fruit set in
almost all of our cages we saw no
difference in Fruit volume again none of
these are significantly different from
each
other and we saw no difference in the
number of
drupelets so our our take-home message
there is we've been doing a lot of work
with thrips but we don't think based on
this evidence and the fact that we seen
no correlation in our insecticide trials
between reducing thrips and having
increased fruit quality that we actually
have something that's causing damage to
the fruit so instead we're shifting our
Focus to looking at them as potential
virus factors the thrips that are in red
boxes on these two pie charts are known
vectors of viruses that can be found in
blackberries we're also as part of a
greater group that Don is involved in
and that one of our attendees here Danny
um Liddell is also involved in we're
looking at other potential virus factors
in caneberries including Leaf Hoppers
white flies and
aphids and this is just an illustration
of some of the leaf Hoppers that we find
in our traps these are a leafhopper
species called graphos veruda that's a
known pathogen Vector in other simp in
other systems especially
grape so just to briefly touch on some
of my other um interests here uh to talk
about some potential caneberry pests the
first one I want to briefly mention is
the light brown Apple moth this is the
region in California where this
particular invasive pest is currently
located at and is under quarantine
for the light brown Apple moth is a leaf
roller and it does pretty much the same
thing as many other native Leaf rollers
that we have here these are photos off
of Mark bould's blog I gave you all the
link in the notes page and I encourage
you to take a look at that Mark bolda is
a farm adviser in Santa Cruz County
California one of the areas where they
grow a lot of their their cane berries
and here's some potential damage the
light brown Apple moth can cause to cane
berries the actual um feeding of the
insect on the leaves is not as much of a
concern but they'll tunnel up and build
these silken cases for themselves and
that can be a contamination issue and
this is what the larvae looks like
I don't anticipate that libron Apple
moth is going to be a game Cher in terms
of management for us but it is a
quarantine Pest and that can raise
issues for export and import from areas
So that's its primary role as as as a
issue in terms of being an invasive pest
but it has yet to have spread widely
Beyond California there are active
trapping programs in the Southeast and
if this is something you're concerned
about definitely talk with Cooperative
Extension agents in your
area the next insect which may
potentially be more important than
libron Apple moth is a spotted wopa this
is a male spotted wopa you can see right
there how it gets its names it has two
spots one on each Wing this is a female
spotted wi dropa and this is a closeup
of what makes them interesting in terms
of Pest Management she has a serrated
knife likee ovap posit or egg laye
device that she uses to infest sound
fruit this is what makes this particular
fly so different from other dropa
species which we're primarily familiar
with as being the little flies that get
on our bananas if we let them get over
ripe in our house these guys like sound
fruit out in the field and this is a
larvae feeding in a
cherry what's particularly troubling
about them is that they've spread
rapidly since their initial detection in
2008 in some backyard cherries in
California up and down the West Coast so
they're now found at many locations in
California many locations in Oregon some
spots in Washington and they've been
detected in
Florida so that spread itself has been
pretty rapid that being said they don't
like cold weather that much so I'm
really interested to see what's going to
happen after this winter I anticipate
that if we have decent overwintering
populations in California which we do
that that spread is just as likely to
occur again even if the harsh winter
conditions in Florida and on the East
Coast have knock down those populations
there as I mentioned the larv feed on
sound soft skin fruit they're probably
not going to be an issue for citrus
production it's just too thick for them
to get through but for things like
caneberries they're particularly
problematic Mark bolda again in
California has some really nice posts on
this particular insect so if you want
more details on management tools that
they're working out that's an excellent
resource to check out they have a very
short generation time that means they
can have lots and lots of generations in
a ripening caneberry plot females lay
lots of eggs and I mentioned um there's
a high mortality at freezing
temperatures so it's possible that this
winter was a little hard on them
particularly on those East Coast
populations which would be encouraging I
have on here that the males are sterile
at greater than 86 fah I don't want
that to be too comforting to folks
because folks in the Southeast see that
and we think okay well we're not going
to have to worry about them as much but
there's pretty much
somewhere during the summer where the
insects could hide out and find
temperatures that are below 86 degrees
even on really hot days so I don't know
if that's necessarily going to be a
gamebreaker again I mentioned Mark
bold's blog is an excellent resource for
information on this particular pest
we're developing an early detection
monitoring Network in the Midsouth
specifically in North Carolina South
Carolina and Virginia we're going to be
we're going to be training people in
March and there's a lot more info on
that on my
blog finally I'll just talk a little bit
about stink
bugs the stink bug work has been done by
Don uh Doug feifer and Laura Maxi at a
un at Virginia Tech and there's a number
of different species of stink bugs that
can be present in caneberries
particularly in the Southeast the fruit
damage that they're causing however is
unclear there's no threshold or scouting
procedures for them and only
broadspectrum insecticides are
registered and therefore
recommended what Laura's been working on
is actually looking at the feeding
behavior of stink bugs and seeing what
type of damage they might actually be
causing what she's observed them doing
is feeding on veins of leaves seil on
developing fruit and then this is some
of the injury associated with stinkbug
she's been seeing on fruit she's been
seeing this type of injury to individual
drupelets and this is actually doe to
feeding by the bug between the drupelets
not on the individual drupelets
themselves and I'll mention that again
as we flip through to the video at the
very end this is the other type of
damage we're concerned about stinkbugs
are potential
contamination uh nuisance as well as we
all know they're Nam stink bugs for a
reason and you can actually smell and
taste when stink bugs release their
odorous compounds on and around
caneberries so there are contamination
concern because of
that this is the video I mentioned um
this is saved as a file that you can
download in the file sharing section I
encourage all of you to do it do that
what what it actually shows is the
stylet of this green stink bug here
going between the
drupelets and
feeding so unlike what we thought just
thinking beforehand before Laura did
this work we were assuming that the stin
bugs were probably feeding on these
individual drupelets and potentially
causing them to be leaky causing them to
turn white causing damage to them but
that hasn't been what they've observed
what they've observed is actually
feeding between them that may damage the
drupelets surrounding that feeding
puncture because of damage to the the
recepticle underneath but not
necessarily individual duplet
feeding and I think that's my last slide
so with that I'll encourage you all to
download that file from um from the file
sharing section and I'm sorry we
couldn't play it for you and I'll take
any questions that you
have I'm going to move us into that file
sharing so that people can um download
this one it's the greens by yellow rasp
um right there that's the file that you
can upload and I will also post both PDF
of both Dr Johnson and Dr barack's um
presentations right now so that you can
get them before the end I do hope um
that folks if you've got questions for
uh Dr barck or do Dr Johnson please um
now's your
chance we have any um questions anybody
uh they're trying to soak it all in I'm
sure that was a lot of great information
and I also want to um comment that it
really is uh it's really interesting for
me as an extension person to watch uh in
other areas where some of these pest the
different pest problems because uh it's
been alarming to me I've I've worked in
extension for uh 20 years or so and just
the change and the diseases and insects
that we see that we thought we would not
see in our area we are seeing now and
this is a nice opportunity for us to get
a little heads up about what might be
coming our our way
um no questions for Dr Barack or Dr
Johnson
anybody well I think they I think we've
totally wowed them thank you guys very
much um I also want to thank all of you
for joining us for all these Berry
webinar series um I really am indebted
to uh my colleagues um Kathy heidenrich
for all of the um PR work she helped me
with for all of the extension hosts Jeff
Miller Colleen Kavanagh Sharon Bachman
sug wise uh for hosting live sessions
and Dr Marvin pritz for his guidance on
this and I also um want to thank all of
our speakers we had some excellent
excellent speakers and I'm looking
forward to having those archives
available to everyone thank you so much
Dr Johnson and Dr Barack and please all
of you registrants be looking for a
survey that will be coming in the next
couple of weeks this is very important
for our final um analysis for the
program and uh this will help us with
future webinar series and we want all of
your comments uh constructive criticism
and otherwise please don't hesitate to
share that and thank you all very very
much I will post Don's presentation
right now and um again thanks a
lot and you all have my contact info
both from my presentation and um from my
web page and feel free to uh to get in
touch I put that there for a
reason