welcome everyone this is our fourth
webinar in our first spring webinar
series um and you can see our two
speakers bios in in the screen uh we're
going to do some quick announcements and
then we will launch right in what is the
national extension climate initiative or
necki uh we serve as an anchor for
extension professionals researchers and
partners to collaborate on climate
related issues share resources discuss
barriers and opportunities for advancing
climate change programming in extension
and engage in Prof professional
development activities we are 100%
voluntary and so we're encouraging you
all to join one of our working groups
this program is being presented by the
curriculum Development Group but we also
have a Communications working group a
just Justice Equity inclusion and
diversity group professional development
group partnership and policy group and
an evaluation working group you can find
more on National extension climate
initiative. net this is as I said the
fourth uh webinar May 22nd communities
and climates on co-created materials and
on June 26 we will have an event on
aging and climate um you can see the
recordings from past events at the
website on the screen and I'll put it in
the chat later um and you can also
register for the upcoming webinar aging
and climate we have not built out our
fall webinar series but we hope to do so
um soon and we will let you all know
about that when that becomes FAL we
aspire to be a resource of many sources
from which you can draw upon in order to
apply for your own Regional work if
you're inspired we encourage you to join
us um and you can learn more at the
necki
website um just so you see what is
happening on the next webinar these are
our three speakers Carl pilmer Danielle
aragoni and Leslie Wharton are going to
talk and three different um uh valences
so to speak on the topic of in and
climate it's a really neat group that's
coming up and I encourage you all uh to
join okay with that I'm going to pass it
off it's 303 look at that um Patricia is
going to go first and then Melissa is
going to follow so take it away Patricia
so today I'm going to talk about
a grant funded program that both Melissa
cray and I work on and we affectionally
call it C3PO which is climate change
community programs and opportunities or
there is a very long name right below
that that our funer National Science
Foundation gave us and I am going to
provide an overview of of the project uh
Melissa cray and myself along with
Roslin mccan and art mesh are the pis on
this project and um then I'm going to
give a more detail specifically on the
work that I have done in Washington
state with the latine and Hispanic
communities so this project came
together in November of
2020 uh it was election season and I had
a lot of anxiety about who was going to
win the election um bit of deja vu here
with this picture and now that is 2024
and once again we're entering election
season but on the night of the election
November 3rd I sent out an email to Paul
Chappelle and said hey Paul do you think
anybody in necki would want to do a
grant with me on climate change
education Paul said you're sure and
Melissa was one of the people that
responded I didn't really know Melissa
at the time but uh she has been a great
collaborator and the project was funded
in the summer of
2021 uh as I mentioned it's an NSF Grant
it's advancing informal stem learning
the category of grant that we have pilot
and feasibility studies uh is not on
their current list of opportunities that
they are offering for their next
deadline in
2025 um but there's lots of things there
and I think uh it's a great fit for
people working on climate change
education and extension typ
work uh we have been working with four
different upper under representative
communities in Alaska our colleague art
Nash works with tribal and indigenous
youth he presented in this webinar
series earlier this spring um in Utah
our colleague rosn mccan has worked with
indigenous communities in southeast Utah
and then Melissa who will be presenting
after me works with women Forest owners
and then I work in Washington state with
the Hispanic and Latina community and
going forward I'm just going to refer to
that as the Latina community
so when the project started when we
wrote the grant we had this idea that we
would be doing uh a very interactive
creation of the work that we were doing
that we would spend uh a lot of time on
the design of the educational program
around climate change uh we would be
soliciting feedback from our Advisory
Board from different groups that
represented the different communities we
are working with and then we would be
testing the curriculum and the products
that we we were doing and so these
arrows represent that we were hoped to
have uh very much a two-way flow of
information between everyone that was
working on the project today I'm mainly
going to focus on this testing portion
of the project and um how that has
worked for the past two years in 2023
and
2024 uh when we started this project as
a team we came up with learning
objectives that we thought that all four
locations can follow we were using a
curriculum based out of University of
California called climate stewards and
we were each modifying and co-creating
that curriculum for our specific
community in our
state and I had not reviewed this
diagram in a while until this morning
and I looked through it and what really
stood out out to me was the social
cultural values perspectives and
practices of specific communities and
how you respond to climate change and
how our work really needed to focus on
that and how we could not take a
curriculum um make a few changes to make
it state or region specific in many
cases there were pretty substantial
changes that we made for it to fit our
communities that we are working with
in Washington state what we started with
was a very thorough needs assessment of
our community we did lots of focus
groups and interviews with people in the
Latina
Community um and I could do a whole
webinar just on that portion of our work
but some of the advice that community
members gave us was to adapt how the
information was presented to make it
specifically for them they like things
to be very active interactive and fun
and
tangible uh they they encourage us to do
field trips and ecological outings to
show the importance of caring for the
environment and then recognition and
awards are very important to people in
the Latina Community as well as gifts
and um prizes and then you know make
sure that these events are fun and
providing food and music it's more of a
part
than just an educational
event so the curriculum co-creation that
we did um we took input from all of the
interviews focus groups and the needs
assessment that we did we worked with
four Community um leaders and then we
had an education consultant on the
project as well as myself and so we were
taking the curriculum from University of
California climate stewards and not only
were we
integrating to make it Washington State
Pacific but we were brainstorming on how
to make this informal learning and how
to make it appealing to the Latina
Community um the course components we
changed a bit from the organization that
is in the UC climate stewards uh we
started very much with community
building and trying to encourage a
community and create a community within
our
course uh then we went to environmental
systems and talked about that as well as
um some general ideas about climate
change and then from that point we went
to more into unit three which was foced
on local mitigation and Community
resilience we talked about that instead
of using the term
adaptation and then we finished the
course with how you talk about climate
and climate communication and then our
participants in our course they do a
final project which they can do as an
individual or they can work in groups in
doing
that so this is a Saturday morning at
WSU Everett um you can see that all our
participants in the course you know
they're actively working on a Saturday
morning um it's not everybody that's
going to be dedicated enough to come to
a course on Saturday morning but we did
this for 10 weeks and uh I would say
about three four of our classes were in
person and then we had maybe three that
were virtual
classes we had all of our classes were
very family friendly we provided Child
Care uh when they got there in the
morning we had a um Mexican pastry
called pendul so it's a sweet bread uh
fresh fruit coffee and tea to make it a
very welcoming atmosphere for them uh we
did have it in a university building and
facilities and I think that was
important to connect them to do the fact
that you know all of them and their
families are welcome at University
spaces and to encourage them for their
family members to uh be part of the
university and the different activities
that we have there uh another thing I
want to point out is that the University
of California program is called climate
stewards that does not translate uh as
well into Spanish and so we use the term
promotur Dela which translates to
climate ambassador
for this section of the program that I'm
going to talk
about so I'll be using promoturist Delo
or just promus going
forward so one aspect of the course was
to have people that were the lead
instructors and the um guest speakers in
the course to be members of the Latina
Community to be fully bilingual in
English and Spanish and so Christina OS
um she's my friend and colleague here on
the right she's a fabulous lead
instructor she also helped with the
co-creation of the curriculum and so she
has been involved for a very long time
in creating this uh promoturist
clima and then we were able to find um
six different guest speakers to talk
about different aspects of the work that
they do on climate change um Maria was
is from California she used to work for
California um extension she's now with a
nonprofit in California
uh Isabelle uh used to work at
University of Washington I have
collaborated with Isabelle for probably
six seven years now and she's a great
colleague to collaborate with and then
she was able to introduce me to Migel
from Earth corpse um Dr Garcia Perez is
a professor at WSU and a colleague of
mine and then Dr Ernesto Alvarado is a
professor at University of Washington
and then in reading the the newspaper
local newspaper Christina learned about
Dr Jesus Perez lerz who's a science
teacher and does a
bilingual um course for his classrooms
in Burlington and so they were really
critical to be able to find this diverse
array of people to give their time to
speak and answer the students questions
I think it was very inspirational to
them to see members of their Community
being professors and working for these
organizations AC across the United
States and so we generally appreciated
their
contribution so part of what we did in
this course is that we tried to make it
very interactive and to bring fun into
the course uh within the climate
stewards curriculum there's uh several
metaphors that are used that talk about
climate change and several of those
translated well into Spanish uh early in
the course we talked about the effect of
greenhouse gases in our atmosphere being
being uh a heat trapping
blanket uh here on the left of your
screen is my friend and colleague
Tatiana haraldo and she was involved in
doing all of the interviews and focus
groups and helping to create the
curriculum and so by showing the
Greenhouse Effect and having each
blanket represent a greenhouse gas you
know you start with one blanket then you
add another and another and another and
at this point um our volunteer for this
process has six blankets on there and
they're feeling a little warm so it's a
very visual representation of what is
happening to the
Earth uh the same thing we do to
illustrate another one of the metaphors
which is regular um carbon Cycles versus
a rampant carbon cycle and so what we
start is with these green tennis balls
and we show how the carbon cycle works
when there are are no fossil fuels in
the
equation and how it changes going
throughout the year how it goes up in
the summer and then down in the winter
in the northern H Atmos uh Northern
Hemisphere and then the opposite in the
Southern Hemisphere and then we take the
cycle and we integrate uh gray tennis
balls which represent coal we integrate
black tennis balls which represent uh
petroleum and what that does to the
carbon cycle
and then we either have a box or a
bucket or something and that represents
the earth and the atmosphere of Earth
and once we integrate these all these
different tennis balls at some point you
can easily see that it is overflowing
and so very visual representation of
what is happening with the carbon cycle
and how it's totally out of whack and
once you make it visual it's easier to
see and easier to understand um I did
part of this activity in Spanish I have
now given myself a challenge that I'm
going to learn to be able to lead this
entire activity in Spanish by the next
time I do it so we'll
see uh we did a lot of Team activities
and that was one thing our participants
loved doing was working in groups uh
this was an assignment early in the
course where they had to do a concept
map about Community connect connections
on this side of the screen this group
was thinking more globally in terms
terms of um the community and the the
global community that we all live in um
the picture on the right um that person
is thinking that group is thinking more
locally in terms of you know what's the
impact of all our urban communities on
for us here in the Pacific
Northwest and um one other thing was
that in both classes that we've done we
we're in the process of completing our
second is that we've had talented
members of the community that are good
artists and so that is a way to
integrate their skills and their
information into the
program um we did some of the courses we
did
virtual and part of what we realized
that we had to do in this class was that
um some of our participants were not
familiar with technology and so we had
to spend time helping them learn
technology uh so we use qual trick for
course Reg registration but we also use
that as a way for them to provide us
feedback after every class and then also
to submit their homework the original uh
climate stewards curriculum is designed
to be on campas and um that just wasn't
going to work for our community to use
that much technology we did have some
Zoom meetings and within that you know
they were able to learn about um
breakout rooms and how to use chat how
to use Jam
boards uh we also worked in glogle
classroom we didn't do that in the first
year but we've used that in the second
year and it's worked well and then uh
another online learning technique we've
used is parck learning platform which is
a interactive way um the first year it
did not work quite as well and what we
realized is that we needed to walk
through the program and the questions
with our participants and we got much
better results and interaction by doing
that as opposed to just letting them do
that
themselves uh we integrated field trips
into the course uh the first year we had
three the second year we've had two um
this was from in Spring
2023 uh and we went to the Northwest
streams dinner a very familyfriendly
place where we tour the the restoration
project that they had there and learned
a lot about the water cycle uh learned a
lot about forests and how forests are
important to carbon storage and
important to maintaining the water
quality here in the Pacific
Northwest and then more most recently we
went to a low tide Beach exploration and
did that on uh Saturday I think it was
May 11th it's beautiful day to be at the
beach to observe the low
tide um the one one thing that happened
during that event and I don't think any
of our participants are going to forget
this is quite a ways from Shore we came
across this concrete structure that was
kind of like a grid and it had pools of
water in it and there were a lot of
marine organisms in this in these pools
of water a lot of starfish uh sea stars
a lot of cucumbers um couple fish in
there it was just full of marine life
and if you can see in the distance like
way back here is a shoreline so our
leader on this field tour felt that uh
it was going to be hours before high
tide had reached would reach this area
and she also thought that this was not
natural that these organisms were
probably placed there by somebody and so
we ended up transporting them back to um
safe places closer to the actual
waterers Edge and hope that some of them
would survive it was also quite a warm
day um so it was also illustrating the
stress of having higher temperatures and
how global climate change is going to be
affecting our marine life during low
tide events when you have abnormally
warm summer days which we had during the
heat dome in
2021 uh as part of the the course uh the
promoturist do a final project in the
climate sewards curriculum is called a
Capstone project but um FAL project is a
terminology that that is better for our
group um last year they did a wide
variety of projects they worked
individually where they worked some in
groups um this participant on here had a
background in in health and so she did a
booklet specifically on uh climate
change and health uh so salude is the
word for help in uh Spanish another one
did a video on uh fashion and climate
change and uh others specifically worked
on um Recycling and very much interested
in that uh another participant did
specifically on women in science and the
environment and U made kind of a a
little booklet on that that was quite
informative and then we also had a
participant that um total P Tiera
everything for the Earth that was a
small book that was for children on how
to learn climate change that was
beautifully Illustrated all in Spanish
so it's quite exciting to see their
their final projects the current group
that we have now they're working on
their final
projects at the end of the course we ask
all our participants why they were
participating and um this is from 2023
their their data and we had 24 that
responded to the survey and the majority
of them are wanting to learn about
Solutions
and they're wanting to learn more about
climate science so those the two most
popular answers they were able to select
all that they felt were revent as the in
this survey questions the other um
top categories were to meet others that
had similar interests and then to learn
more about Community
resilience so this is our graduation
class from uh 2023
uh we are here at WS Everett they have
their certificates you can see they're
all pretty darn happy here's me um
here's my colleague Christina and the
one thing that's easy for me to point
out in this photo is this is very much a
family centered program it was last year
it was this year um let's see we've got
two people here I hope you can see my
arrow um
Lorina and Louise so they're a married
couple U we have over here we have
another married couple and then their
children are also part of this program
that's their son hob um over on the
right we've got another married couple
and then here's one of their sons and
then I think their other son is over
here on the right um mother daughter
pairs
siblings um and it's just exciting that
they bring the whole family to learn
about climate change and that they are
thinking about this as a family some of
our speakers that I mentioned earlier
this year they brought their brought
their Partners brought their spouses
with them when they came to present at
the course and so family is so important
to this in
community and designing the work that we
do to make it very
familyfriendly and appealing to all
ages um some of our prom tours last year
were selected to be interns over the
summer uh they went to a couple
different fairs and and carnivals and
they had a um what we call a climate
wheel and um people at the festival
would spin that and they get a question
about climate change and uh they'd
answer three questions if they got them
all right with some guidance with with
the person that was Manning the booth
they get a small
prize um here on the bottom these are
like compost bins that we were giving
out as part of this
event uh in the fall in 2023 we had a
climate Carnival where we specifically
had lots of different tables and booths
with different types of activities for
them to learn about climate change in a
very interactive way um that uh part
that we did in our class where we did
the heat trapping blanket and show the
different blankets and how that mimics
what's happening to the earth that is
one of the activities that we demon
demonstrated during the climate
Carnival so some of the feedback that we
got from our
promus um I'll read these in Spanish and
then I'll say briefly what what they
translate to
muchas so this is thank you for
everything this is one of the best
experiences that happened to me in the
past
year migusto
thank you for educating us about this
topic I mean so appreciative that we
were doing this for them that we're
making information available in Spanish
uh one thing I will Hammer home on is
that it is not enough just to translate
information to another language you have
to directly engage with that community
to help them learn to help them to work
with them to understand be involved and
cocreate The Learning Experience some
people reading is not their thing and
they're not going to read it and I was
at a conference last week and someone
who said to me who's from the Latina
Community you know printing a bunch of
translated materials is just a waste of
paper um so you need to interact you
need to engage and you need to make get
Hands-On um these are the impacts from a
prur 2023 class we had 23 promotur
Delina graduates eight of them were
selected to be interns in
2023 they had over uh direct
conversations with over 300 community
members this is in SN homish County and
we believe we really raised the
awareness about climate change and what
we need to do is talk more about it if
you look over here on the right of the
screen you can say um whoops that the
majority of them they shifted their
opinion from before the course to after
the course and their thoughts about you
know what we need to do about climate
change and their their feelings of
empowerment uh Lessons Learned you know
it takes time to build these
relationships I have been working on
different educational programs with the
Latina Community for about eight years
now and um you know it's it's taken that
much time to make it so that I am uh a
respected member of the community that
knows that I'm not going to just
disappear when the funding's gone and
only going to show up again when I have
another project that I want them to do
you have to make things inter
intergenerational so that it appeals to
um teens to grandparents is what I say
has to be fun engaging and
interactive and and one thing that I've
noticed is is talking about climate
change it can be extremely depressing it
can be very heavy but with this group it
seems lighter we're having these hard
conversations but there seems to be more
optimism more empowerment that we can
actually do something about this problem
um this is my team uh this is Christina
here in the middle this is Leonor who
does child care and this is Molina U
Molina's in Spain currently uh learning
to be bilingual in Spanish in English
and right now her mom's helping me so
just another idea of how the family
sticks together and then the extreme
number of people that have helped with
this project um I'm probably leaving
somebody off this list but we had over a
dozen people on the C3PO team that we
were meeting monthly we had an Advisory
Board um some of the Advisory Board were
people that responded to that email
blast I sent on out on Election Day in
201 20 and then we each had different
partners that worked with us there's my
contact information and I'll leave it up
to Jenny if there's time for maybe one
or two
questions so there is one question in
the
Q&amp;A um if anybody has any other
questions please type them into the Q&amp;A
I don't know if we can allow you to
speak um but if you would respond to the
question do you see it Patricia or
should I read yes uh I'll read it I'm
grateful for your sharing this exciting
collaborative work did you specifically
or generally Define community through
your process wondering about the
possibly possibilities of directly
empowering more than human elements
within your program EG personto person
equal person to Nature connectivity
Pathways thanks again for such important
exciting work regarding family driven
work um person to Nature connectivity
power ways that is a very interesting
question Scott thank you for
that I don't know that we really did
that I mean one hard part about this is
the Spanish speaking community that I'm
reaching to they are extremely diverse
in terms of their life experiences how
they ended up in the United States the
the countries that they come from I mean
all of that is just um it's a lot to
handle and I think this is a great idea
for for future work and I appreciate
your your
question and
um I know one of the initial surveys
that I'm getting about directly with
this course is um the marine field trip
that we did just a few weeks ago people
really like that and just people don't
think about you know you can go to the
beach during low tide and you can see
all these cool amazing things and learn
about them you know they think about the
beach as like sand and Sun and Fun and
Games and you know it's just so many
things that you can open the world
to so Sharon there's another there's
another great question from Sharon in
the the Q&amp;A but I really do want to move
us on to Melissa so Patricia if you
could respond um in text because it's a
great question Sharon um we can maybe
verbalize it at the end if there's time
but uh just Patricia do you want to just
respond uh you had one question from
Sharon just so verbally everybody can
hear it in case they can't see the
chat uh that was a question about uh how
you get
started is that the right one Jenny yes
so at one point at Washington State in
uh extension we had a a person fabulous
colleague of mine
friend who passed away too soon and he
he was a latino man and he um that's
that was his job was to engage with the
LA tea Community throughout Washington
State and to do economic Community de
development and he was based in her
office and so he was just
a fabulous motivator to get this
started and you know uh even though he's
no longer with us you know I see his
work living in through me and all the
people I'm reaching and so just finding
one person within the community that you
can make a connection with and you know
it was through him that he offered
advice and gave us introduction to this
organization
lety and you know I go to their
fundraisers um whenever they ask me to
write a letter for a grant they're
applying for you know I I make time to
do it and uh I make them just a priority
in the in the work that I'm doing and I
will for the rest of my career and
that's how you build build and sustain
those relationships it just takes it
takes time and investment