this is a production of Cornell
University okay all right well thank you
all so much for coming today and thank
you for that introduction and the
invitation it's really exciting to be
here um so I started at Penn State in
January 2020 so I feel like I'm no
longer allowed to say that I'm new I
feel like I'm leaving that world but um
I'm really excited to share some of the
work that my lab has been doing and so
all the work that you will see today has
been done by my amazing lab group um
here's their picture I've been really
fortunate since starting at a pen States
I've had some phenomenal graduate
students have been really lucky and I'm
excited to be able to share some of
their work with you so here are just
some of the themes that of research that
my lab is really interested in and I'll
be able to touch on all of these a
little bit today so we're really
interested in thinking about how climate
change will affect weeds and the way
that we manage them um how um we can
leverage plant diversity to increase
ecosystem services and agricultural
systems um weed microbe interactions
which is a new area of research for me
um but um when I started pen state had
um started their a huge microbiome
Center and so it's been you know really
great to sort of Leverage that expertise
um and then thinking about root traits
and how plant compete with each other
below ground um so my talk today I'm
gonna have talk about three different
components of my research program um and
so the first one is going to be looking
at whether or not we can leverage crop
species or diversity to influence weed
seed mortality in the soil um how will
climate change affect weed seed bank
Dynamics um and then thinking about do
interspecific interactions influence the
ways that plants um allocate carbon um
above versus below ground um so when we
talking about the first one right now um
so there's been a lot of interest in
thinking about how we can manage the
soil seed bang either by reducing weed
seed rain and Seed inputs into the soil
and then also accelerating seed
mortality and part of the reason that
people are really interested in managing
the soil seed bank is because most
annual weeds in a cropping field come
from the soil seed bank the primary
source of Recruitment and so if we can
figure out ways to either reduce seed
inputs into the soil or accelerate seed
mortality once seeds enter the soil um
we might be able to really decrease the
sort of density of weeds that are
emerging with our crops and so once a
seed enters their soil there's really
three mechanisms by which a seed can die
the first is just natural physi iCal
aging the second um is seed predation or
herbivory by things like mice or ants or
other insects birds um and then they
also can be infected by soil microbes
and then
Decay um and so when we think about
these sort of two major modes of Bio
control of seeds in the soil seed bank
um seed predation or microbial infection
and Decay we actually know so much more
about the organisms that the herbivores
that consume consume weed seeds compared
to the microbes in the soil so this for
example this is a results from a web of
science search that I did in March 2024
so exactly one year ago and just looking
at the number of articles that I found
that either talked about seed Predators
um and the sort of management practices
that we can use to try to build up those
populations and um increase the number
of seeds that we're losing to predation
compared to microbes in the soil and as
you can see we really know much less
about micro um you know microbes in the
soil that can infect kill wheed seeds
compared to seed predators and I want to
say that also the vast majority of these
Publications came out prior to Next
Generation sequencing becoming like an
affordable tool um for people to use so
really there's a lot of questions um
that we could ask sort of just thinking
about how we can leverage microbes to
accelerate seed mortality in the soil
and when we think about doing that
there's really two strategies that we
might be able to think about the first
is we can use something like an
inoculant to supplement those
populations of microbes in the soil so
adding microbes to the soil through
inoculations um or utilizing management
practices that may increase the
abundance and activity of microbes that
may infect weed seeds in the soil and so
my research really sort of Falls
underneath the second
category um and so the question that we
really wanted to ask was whether or not
we can leverage the plant Community to
affect rates of seed mortality in the
soil um and the reason why we wanted to
look at this is because the plants
themselves are one of if not the most
important levers that farmers have to
sort of manage the microbial populations
in the soil and so we know there's been
research showing that the plant
Community can affect soil microbes we
know that soil microbes can affect weed
seeds and accelerate mortality or and
and um cause seed mortality and so what
we were trying to do is to really link
these processes together and ask the
question whether or not we can use the
plant Community to influence the soil
microbiome and um infect uh and increase
um seed mortality um and so we decided
to do this research in a perennial
forage system and the reason why is
because perennial forages are a really
important tool um to include our you
know a component of crop rotations to
break up weed life cycles of annual
weeds and so during this time you have
this sort of consistent ground cover um
that really suppresses any new weeds
from emerging and also the frequent
cutting that they do each time that they
harvest a penal forage the that frequent
cutting can sort of um terminate any
annual weeds that did emerge thereby
reducing new weed seed inputs into the
soil um so we decided to do this in a
perennial forage system and we actually
created a perennial forage diversity
gradient so we had Alfalfa which is a
perennial legume um Orchard Grass which
is a perennial grass and I would say
that an alfalfa Orchard Grass mixture is
one of if not the um most common
perennial forages that farmers at least
in Pennsylvania are growing and then
with that we also included this um
forage chory um which is a a
non-luminous forb and the reason why we
selected chory was because it's really
the only perennial forage that is not a
legum or a grass that you know is really
um available to Farmers at this time um
and so we set up a diversity gradient
where we had each of them in monoculture
all combinations of the two species
mixtures um and then the three species
mixture and we had that replicated four
times and so what we did in each of
these plots where we had our perennial
forge community is we buried weed seeds
in these small bags um in various
locations throughout each plot and these
were buried shortly after planting in
2021 and then we had um multiple
extraction time points so one year after
burial one and a half years two years
and then two and a half years after
burial and so what we did is once we
extracted these seeds so we extracted
two bags each time Point um and then we
pulled those bags together
we wash the seeds in the soil through a
series of sives so that we could collect
the seeds and then we immediately spit
um split that population or that sample
of seeds into two batches half went for
aluminous sequencing so that we could
characterize the microbial community and
half we did viability testing with
tetrazolium
assays um and so in order to for our
amplion sequencing what we did is we
what we first did is we sterilized the
surface of the seeds because we really
want to know what microbes were getting
inside the seed um we extracted the DNA
and then we used um 16s RNA to
characterize uh Universal primers to
characterize the bacterial community and
then its that characterize the fungal
Community I'm only going to be
presenting on the results from on the
bacterial Community
today and so our primary hypothesis was
that a more diverse plant Community
would um support a more diverse
microbial community and that in doing so
we might get sort of accelerated
mortality in the soil underneath these
you know more diverse mixtures so you
know if you think about like viability
on the um Y axis here we'd have greater
loss of viability in these more diverse
communities um so I will say that was
not the case so here what we're looking
at is um uh Powell amaranth which is a
pigweed species it's sort of a common
pigweed species um in Pennsylvania and
all of the data that I'm going to show
you today is going to be um on Powell
amaranth seed and so this is looking at
our um mortality so uh is on the y- axis
here so the more the greater the bar the
more dead the seeds were um and then we
have our um seven different treatments
here so we really found no consistent
effect of treatment on sea mortality we
saw a trend um in the second year for
the monocultures have actually having um
greater mortality so sort of
inconsistent with our hypothesis um but
we really like did not find a huge
effective treatment on our seed
mortality and then what we also expected
is that when we looked at the bacterial
communities within the seeds that we
might see the um you know the
monocultures sort of separating out so
having different bacterial communities
in the seeds that were buried in those
monoculture treatments and then maybe
the mixture would be sort of some
intermediary between them um and so and
um again we actually really didn't find
much of an effect of treatment on the
mic uh material community that was
inside the seeds so this is results from
a principal coordinate analysis and so
the closer the PO um points are in this
ordination the more similar those
bacterial communities are and so we
really found no effect of our perennial
Forge treatments on the bacterial
communities that were getting inside
these pow amaran
seeds all right so I know you guys are
thinking did these people find anything
interesting well yes we actually did so
the data that I'm about to present to
you um is really like everything that
you would expect to happen to a seed
once it enters the soil but we really
have had so little work done on this so
it is sort of like exciting um to sort
of have have this confirmed so one thing
that we did find is that the bacterial
communities within our seeds actually
differed over time so again this is a
principal coordinate analysis the more
similar the points the more similar the
bacterial communities this was our
original population so this is the
bacterial Community the endic community
that was inside the SE seeds prior to
the seeds ever entering the soil um and
then you can see so here is one year
burial one and a half year then after
two and uh two and two and a half years
the communities kind of became more
stagnant and um stopped changing but we
did see this sort of like variation in
these bacterial communities over time
and then another thing that we saw is
that the diversity of bacteria Within
These um seeds actually tended to
increase over time so these are three
different metrics of um of diversity so
c one or chaan is basically sort of
similar to richness and then we have
Shannon and Simpson diversity and so the
zero is the seeds that were never buried
in the soil you can kind of see we see
this like trend of increasing diversity
of the bacterial communities in the
seeds over time um and then another
thing that we saw was that we actually
saw that in the samples that had low um
mortality and high mortality that the
bacterial communities actually differed
between them so what we did is we sort
of you know we classify for each sample
we classified the sort of percent
mortality of the seeds of each sample
and then we classified them so low was
less than 33% mortality medium mortality
was 33 to 66% and high mortality was
above 66% so as you could see the yellow
and the dark blue so is low um yeah low
and high and so we saw this sort of like
difference in the community of seeds
that had greater mortality compared to
those that had low mortality um so you
know this was pretty interesting and so
when we looked at sort of the different
bacterial Genera that might be causing
this there were a few that we saw sort
of like an increase in their relative
abundance um as the seeds tended to go
towards higher mortality so this really
sort of sets up some future you know
hypothesis testing of whether or not we
can actually sort of um test whether or
not these um specific microbes in the
soil can actually help accelerate rtin
mortality um yeah and so then here what
we're looking at is just our first axis
of our principal coordinate analysis and
on the Y AIS we have the percent
mortality in our pow amaran seeds so we
did see you know some association with
our bacterial Community um sort of
predicting the mortality of those
seeds however the one thing I really
want to point out is what we can't say
is like which came first was the seed
dead and then these microbes moved in
these bacteria moved in or did the
bacteria move in and then the the seeds
died and so you know future work really
need to sort of be um be up to sort of
test whether or not we can actually say
whether or not these specific bacteria
are sort of helping to induce mortality
of these seeds so you know and sort of
thinking about how we might be able to
leverage seed microbiomes to accelerate
seed mortality in the soil I think we
have a long way to go and you know in
order to get there we really need to
establish some causal links between
specific microbial populations um and
their communities and Seed mortality as
well as you know hopefully determined
management practices that can help
increase both the the abundance and
activity of these microbial populations
within the soil and our results suggest
that you know using uh altering the
forge plant community may not be an
effective strategy to get
there okay so now I'm moving into my
second portion of my talk thinking about
how climate change will affect weed seed
um seed bank Dynamics and I'm going to
actually talk about two different
components of our research one looking
at how um increasing temperatures affect
weed seed persistence in the soil and
the second looking at how um how warmer
Tempur can affect weed emergence timing
in both of these studies my lab uses
these open top Chambers to passively
increase temperatures out in the field
um they're commonly used in sort of like
climate change research in the Arctic
and so we've um been able to adapt them
more for like an agricultural setting um
to try to sort of to uh passively
increase temperatures when we're out in
the field um and so we know that
temperatures are increasing right and so
there's a lot of reasons to think why
why warmer temperatures might cause
weeds to become less persistent in the
soil so for example we know that seeds
you know stored at room temperature are
going to have a a shorter shelf life
than seeds that you put in um in the
fridge or you know in 4 degrees Celsius
so there's a lot of reasons to think
that warmer temperatures will actually
decrease the persist persistence you
know warmer temp soil temperatures often
result in increase microbial activity so
you might have greater sort of seed
infection um they can increase seed seed
respiration rates thereby causing seeds
to draw down on their reserves in a
shorter period of time um and then
potentially changes to Free Soil free
Tha cycles that could come from
decreased snow cover might fracture seed
coats and and leave seeds more
vulnerable and so there's this common
saying that maybe you've heard like one
years seeding equals seven years weeding
so really what we're trying to ask here
is maybe with maybe climate change you
know there might be some good things
that come from climate change and maybe
one year seeding will actually be equal
five years weeding in the future um and
so to do this this is work done um by my
graduate uh former Master student Ashley
isacson who's now an extension educator
in Pennsylvania and so she um um
compared two treatments a control so
that's no open top chamber and then with
the open top
chamber um and she was um evaluating the
Persistence of three different weed
species so red root Pig weed common
Ragweed and large crab grass and so
essentially what Ashley did is she um
extracted soil clores from the small one
meter squared plots and within each of
these soil cores she um spiked like 500
seeds of her um species of interest and
the reason why we chose to do this
method which is called the seated core
method is because I was really sort of
initially interested in sort of like how
decreased snow cover might change soil
physically properties and so I wanted to
have the seeds to be um in as much of a
realistic environment as possible which
is why we did not use those little bags
that I showed you previously and we
actually decided to just like directly
Spike the soil um and so we marked them
with these little uh sort of landscape
fa fabric Staples with tags um to do
that and then we oh and then we
extracted at three different points I
think they were about six months apart
over an 18mon
period um okay so now what we're looking
at is how much warming we got from our
OTC so the the Y AIS here is the
difference in temperature in Celsius in
the OTC compared to the control so on
average we are only getting a about a
half degree celsius increase in
temperature so for with this study we
only got a 04 degrees Celsius increase
in temperature and I want to point out
to you that some months we actually had
cooler temperatures in our otc's
compared to the control and the reason
why is because we once again did this in
a perennial Forge field so we're kind of
trying to like simulate um what would
happen to seeds during The Perennial
phase of their crop rotation and so we
had an alala orchard grass mixture in
here and so what ended up happening is
we actually had in these months much
greater productivity of the um alalal
orch grass mixture in the otc's compared
to the control so we think we actually
got cooler temperature is from like EV
vapo transfer of cooling maybe greater
shading and there's a sort of a number
of reasons so because we had like
greater productivity in those otcs we
actually saw um a decrease in
temperature underneath them but anyway
so this would be like very you know
indicative of very near warming or very
you know very near future essentially
and so looking at our results so here
the Y AIS is actually seed viability so
the lower is the more seeds were dead
and so we actually for two of our
species common Ragweed and large crab
grass we saw no um statistically
significant effect we did see a small
but um significant um acceleration of
mortality so loss of viability in our
warming for red root pigy but again it
was just like a very minor difference so
you know this was kind of like
unexpected for us we really like
expected that we would see sort of
Greater loss of mortality um you know
more accelerated mortality with with our
warming treatments and so some of the
reasons maybe why we didn't see that is
that seated core method that we used um
is actually pretty variable because
there was already some natural um sort
of populations of those seeds in the
soil that we spiked and so that just
created variability in the data and on
top of that maybe we just need a greater
increase in temperature to actually see
more of an effect so maybe in the future
using something like soil heating cables
you might be able to um see more of an
effect um but those are really
challenging you to like find an
electrical source out in the field so
there's all types of challenges when you
actually like are trying to pump
electricity out into your field and that
is like you know uh way above my um
assistant professor pay rade at this
point in time but I'm hoping you know in
the future maybe doing things like that
would be um more feasible so the second
question that we asked is how will
increased temperatures affect um weed
emergence timeing so this is um research
done by a PhD candidate in my group N
Cala and so we were really interested in
sort of thinking about how climate
change might affect emergence timing
because under understanding when weeds
emerge can be really important for
trying to adequately T um time
management activities so you really want
to you know if you're doing any type of
like post emergent weed control you want
to wait until you have you know a decent
flush of weeds so that you're timing it
to have the most efficacy but you also
need to hit the weeds before they get
too big so understanding that when they
um emerge can really sort of help
balance those trade-offs um and so again
so he used um with an O his treatments
were with an OTC and without but this
time we were not in any perennial forage
system we were just in bare soil so
looking at his results um so this is
from
20123 and this is days to 10% emergence
so as you can see our results were
pretty variable so we had two species um
giant fox tail oh so the red is warming
and the blue is controlled sorry I
should have said that um and then the
the axis here is days to 10% emergence
um and so we had two species where we
had no sort of significant difference
and then we had two species so Lamb's
quarters and large crab gas where we had
more days till we hit 10% emergence and
then we had two species where we had um
a lower amount of days till we hit that
10% emergence so really sort of you know
some species were responding to this
warming temperature but they were
responding in different ways and not all
species were responding um the same now
in 2024 so this past year we actually
found that the two species that we had
no significant effect of in the first
year we actually so like it could the
results could not have been more
variable that's what I'm trying to say
so here in this year we actually had
giant Fox taale and red pige that we
found statistical differences between
the warming and control um giant fox
tail had greater um time to uh hitting
this time we're looking at 50% emergence
and then red pig weed actually had a
lower number of days until it hit 50%
emergence so again you know it's really
really really sort of variable results
that we've found this is often the case
when people are trying to understand how
shifts in temperature or precipitation
might um affect plant communities um and
it can be really hard to make any like
actual recommendations to Farmers um
when your results are just like so
variable um but I'm really excited so we
will be starting a much larger project
where multiple sites including Cornell
um Tony's group at Cornell will be
looking at how I mean this increasing
temperatures with otcs can affect weed
emergence timing and hopefully by
increasing the environmental Vari
maybe we'll be able to find some um sort
of like you know Universal principle or
maybe we'll just have lots of more
variable results and try to make some
sense of them okay so the last portion
of my talk um is looking at whether or
not interp specific interactions can
influence how plants um allocate carbon
and so when I started at Penn State I
was really interested in sort of
studying belowground competition sort
thinking about you know how plants are
competing for resources below ground um
however our ability to study um
belowground competition is really
limited by our lack of ability to
identify roots to species so if you're
trying to assess how competition or
other plantplant interactions affect a
specific species often what you do you
use as your metric is biomass right like
plant biomass um but normally what
people do is they just harvest the above
ground portion of you know the plant
Community they separate plants to
species and you know often they just
sort of ignore what's happening below
ground um and again that's because you
know roots are just hard to work with
regardless you know it's pretty you know
pretty difficult to be able to identify
roots to
species however being able to have a
method that we can sort of reliably
estimate root biomass of individual
species when they're in these diverse
communities could really help answer
sort of fundamental questions about how
competition can affect productivity you
know competition for belowground
resources as well as what specific root
traits can influence a plant's
competitive ability um and then
Additionally you know many of our like
ecosystem services that we want from our
crops many of those ecosystem services
are tied to you know tied to Roots so
for example nitrogen retention um carbon
storage so you know some Studies have
shown that that carbon drive from root
tissue actually lasts is more persistent
in the soil compared to um Leaf tissue
and then also obviously nitrogen
fixation um so we were sort of really
interested in thinking about whether or
not we could develop a method method to
sort of identify or estimate the biomass
of individual species um in root biomass
diverse communities um and so this was
work done by a PhD candidate with my
group Emma rice um and so her research
questions was whether or not we can use
Next Generation sequencing to predict
the abundance of different species in
root biomass um and do cover crop and
asking do cover crop species alter their
allocation to above versus below ground
um Roots versus shoots when in mixtures
compared to monocultures and you know
now that there's sort of like all these
carbon markets being developed you know
trying to estimate how the abundance of
you know different species and how might
that influence sort of Persistence of
caret in the soil you know could be a
really valuable use of this tool um so
um so Emma asked this question in this
long-term cover crop diversity
experiment um at Penn State it's called
our cover crop cocktails experiment um
and she had four different cover crop
species that she was looking at crimson
clover winter pea tril and canola in
monocultures and then a four species
mixture and so what Emma did was she
would extract root cores from the soil
we would go down to 40 cmers we tried to
go down to 50 and we just hit rocks
non-stop so 40 was the best we could do
um I know if we were in deeper you know
if we were out in the midwest we could
go to a meter de deep but so she would
extract these soil cores she would clean
the roots from the soil she would freeze
dry them and so then she would use the
root biomass from the monocultures to
create all of these what we call her
mock mixtures where she was sort of
using fine scale um bearing the
proportion of each of her species in
these sort of microen auge tubes um and
so we would use that to sort of
calibrate the method she would extract
the DNA and then we use um Universal
primers for the rbcl which is a
chloroplast Gene it's one of the genes
that is often used in METAR
metabarcoding for plants they often use
the chloroplast genes um we tried
multiple chloroplast genes and rbcl was
the only one that we could work get to
work reliably um and then she would
submit that for aluminous sequencing and
she would calculate the proportion of
reads that was of each of her species of
interest and in order for this method to
work what we really needed to see was we
would get sort of like a predictable
response of a species proportion in the
reads that we would get from our
sequencing data and then the um the
actual species proportion and the sample
mass of all of these little mock
mixtures that we created so how well did
her does her method work so um so what
we're looking at now is the relationship
between um or so this is the on the x-
axis here it's the proportion of each of
these species that was in in mass that
was in all of her little mock mixtures
that she created and then the Y AIS here
is what we would have predicted
based on our models okay so really what
we're looking at is like The observed
versus the predicted so like how well
are the models that we generated based
on this data doing and predicting um and
so you know it's not perfect but it has
you know a somewhat um uh you know a
pretty good upward Trend I would have
liked an R square that was a little bit
higher but roots are messy fieldwork is
messy so you know an R square between 7
and 08 it could have been could have
been better but it could have been a lot
worse so you know we're happy you know I
think it for the most part works well
and we're sort of interested in thinking
about are ways that we can use to get
better predictions from this method in
the future um and so then using this
method to predict how each of these how
much um uh um growth these species
allocated to their roots and their
monocultures versus mixtures so um
here's what we're looking at um here so
we have our four different species on um
at at the bottom and then the blue bars
are the root mass fraction so the
proportion portion of plant biomass that
was allocated to the roots um is the Y
AIS um and so you know as you can see
there were some species that we had sort
of consistent Trends so for example
Clover we really only had one year was
statistically significant but we saw
sort of like a greater you know a trend
for um all three years having greater um
root allocation in the mixture compared
to monoculture tril similar only one
year was statistically significant but
there was a trend um for greater root
mass fraction in the monoculture
compared the mixture but for p and
canola we really saw sort of like
differing you know patterns over time um
so um for example especially canola you
know one year greater in the monoculture
another year greater in the fixure so
you know this really suggests that
plants are varying their allocation
patterns based on sort of like the
community Dynamics and what other plants
are around them and how that might be
affecting their own growth or
potentially abiotic factors and so you
know trying to develop methods where we
can really try to estimate um uh you
know how much root biomas individual
species um could be you know super
useful in the future because we can't
necessarily always predict a plant's
below ground biomass solely based on its
abovegr biomass um and so some of the
areas where I um excited to move this
method to in the future is whether or
not we can sort of predict our ability
to estimate root biomass and then also
what I'd really like to do is to be able
to adapt this method to work in more
diverse communities you know potentially
crops that are competing with weeds the
reason why we use cover crops is because
they're all like basically crops right
and so they had their whole genomes
available to us so it was a lot easier
when we were sort of like trying to
develop our Universal primaries and
things like that to have the Genome of a
of a plant um available um but there's a
lot more genomes of weed species coming
coming out so you know it would be great
to be able to adapt this method um to
have more diverse um diverse species in
the future
um so I just want to sort of end sort of
like here's some areas that my lab is
working on I'm really excited of some of
the work that we're coming out um if
you're interested in any of this I keep
my Google Scholar most up to date so you
could just sort of Google Scholar search
me I'm trying to get better about
updating my lab website but you know
it's hard um yeah and I want to end by
acknowledging all my collaborators you
know really a lot of this work could not
have been done um without sort of you
know the collaborators who helped me
sort of build up this expertise lab did
all of this work without owning a single
pipet and so I really like it was very
much the you know the collaborators that
have really sort of supported this um
and then my funding sources at the
bottom and then with that I will take
any
questions I appreciate your talk I have
a question that kind of spans all of
your experiments okay how did you manage
needs kind of contaminating h of
situation for you yeah so I would say
like the first situation the prenal
forage I mean like it it definitely
became more wey over time you know I
would say initially we had our stands of
um of you know our the for shg did not
do that well so that got pretty weedy
but everything else should have did okay
but you know weeds came in over time and
the best that we can do is we we um
measured we' biomass and we might be
able to use that as a co-variate but at
the same point in time like you said
there were no treatment differences no
real effect of the plan community so
yeah I don't know how much getting at
like maybe you had some yeah maybe weeds
possibly yeah it's definitely something
we could look into in the future um yeah
so then the the sort of climate change
we just sort of like handpulled
everything all of our plots are pretty
small so we just hand pulled everything
and then oh yeah okay so the the root
study okay so Emma two to three times a
year would go out to her sampling points
and we and hand readed everything
because she really was trying to limit
the amount of other species um that
could get in but even with that you know
there was a Legacy of root biomass root
tissue in the soil that you know
probably gave us some contamination um
but she did look at sort of like you
know she was able to characterize um for
the most common weed species and sort of
identify which um you know of her weeds
went to all of those and then so
basically what she was able to do is
like you know plot out whether or not
the proportion of her weeds that were
weeds affected the sort of like
difference between predicted and
observed from her model and there was no
relationship so it probably created
variability I it definitely wasn't like
variability that we could predict um but
that was really like the best we could
do at this time I mean it would be so
that long-term experiment is also like
insanely Bey so you know maybe if we try
to do that a similar study at um in a
field that like wasn't organic and you
know had didn't have that weed density
maybe we'd have some better results so
we're actually doing that now we've sort
of like moved to a field that is less
wey so we'll see what happens
yes yeah great talk a lot of very hard
things to do in the field yeah I
appreciate that a lot yeah I mean like
you don't even those open top Chambers
man like we've had those like blow
across the highway and like yeah anyway
yeah so thank you for for noticing that
oh yeah it's it's tough um out there so
I I was curious about your microbe work
cover cropping and I I think like you
know the thought is like oh okay we have
these cover crops and like they might
help lots of different benefits and
really are interested in knowing like
what all these different benefits are
yeah they like I'm going to bury my
seeds in these plots and then you didn't
really find any consistent Trends yeah
um I was at a farm once and the farmer
was like growing buckweed right cover
crop yeah and it was just shattering all
over the place like I asked him about it
and he was like ah you know I'd rather
weed buckweed seeds than than have to
deal with the regular seed bank yeah
yeah yeah so I'm curious what your
thoughts are on like should we have a
certain amount of weed seeds in order to
promote the microbes that then help to
suppress the bad weed seeds and is the
approach because the goal with the cover
crops is to suppress weed seeds right
yeah so if you're suppressing all the
weed seeds and you've eliminated the
host for the microb yeah eat on them
curious like if you could do it again or
if you have some other thoughts about
future directions for that work yeah so
I've thought about doing that of like
can we sort of like select for you know
can we sort of like have some
incubations where we have soil and we
crush up a bunch of wheat seeds and we
put them in and then we like take that
sort of community and we do it again and
we and sort of like have lots of
different Generations over time and can
we evolve microbes um that are more
effective at infecting and killing weed
seeds um I am like just dipping my toe
into this microbial world and so um it's
definitely like something that thinking
about and really interested in I feel
like I would need to buy a pip pet
before we went that route you know what
I mean like I feel like we would need to
sort of drastically increase our
capacity to work with microbes um but I
would definitely be interested like you
know working with a collaborator who
actually had you know the capacity to
sort of do that type of work like you
know be that sterile and that you would
need to do in order to do something like
that you know I would definitely be
interested in collaborating with
something like that but at this point um
I would say that's sort of like outside
the range of like what we're capable of
doing
yes um yeah great talk um I was
interested in your first area of
research and maybe I missed it but are
is seed Decay mainly by bacterial
microbes or fungal microbes
also yes microme sequencing or what
you're going to do next yeah so we did
do its we're sort of like um we are like
sort of dealing with that data right now
we just haven't we haven't sort of like
figured out that story yet we really
like just got our sequencing data back
like two months ago so we've sort of
like got night sort of got the bacterial
down but we're so we're going to look at
that there's a lot of reason to believe
that fungi might be bigger appliers
because seeds have such sort of like
protective seed coats and also I just
want out sort of like at a side know I'm
very excited for your seed biology
position to get filled we really need
like more expertise in the world of
people who sort of like understand these
seed defenses and you know maybe you
know maybe that's the strategy that we
need is sort of like targeting these
seed defenses more than the microbes um
but um so there's a lot of reason to
believe that maybe fungi would be more
effective at sort of like getting past
seed codes but yeah I'm just not totally
sure yet and we're kind of like dealing
with that data right now or working
through it I guess I should say but
hopefully we'll have you know like an
amazing story in like two
months so Caroline and I really
appreciate that you are tackling some of
like the hardest questions because it is
difficult to work in these kind of
natural environments that include soil
so my question was about like the open
top containers yeah when you started
evaluating some of that and could you
have seen any possible emergence like in
the fall like you know rather
than when those species are naturally
supposed to emerge could you have
facilitated yeah like a fall emergence
and then uh you know a kill of yeah so
what we did was you know that first year
we collected the seeds and we put them
out after temperatures got pretty cold
so they did experience winter in the
otc's um but they didn't experience sort
of like the prummer fall or sort of like
you know seed ripening on the plant or
anything like that um but then the next
year we sort of kept our plots in the
same spot and then we resp spiked some
seeds but we still sort of like had that
population there um and so maybe we saw
some effects but we couldn't really
tease it out apart from like what
happened the previous year and then also
um what happened sort of like you know
the the seeds that had been there for a
year versus the ones that we recently
spiked it's definitely something that
I'm like interested in looking at in the
future and sort of also just thinking
about like you know can we tease apart
sort of like emergence from dor like
breaking dorcy and um yeah so those are
all sort of I like I would love to be
able to like increase temperatures even
more than what we get like by having
something like soil heating cables um to
have more in effect but you know I think
that there could be some interesting
questions about sort of like trying to
tease apart dormy breaking versus like
actual germination
emerence yes I'm wondering the open to
Chambers even increase the temperature
there I believe there are some
compounding effects for example s
radiation might be decreased or humidity
be increased Oh you mean like sort of
like there might have been like other
environmental variation consider that
issue too yeah so in the first year we
were kind of on like a a Sho string
budget um and so we did not measure soil
moisture because I like you know I just
soil moisture sensors are so expensive
but then we got a ni Grant so then we
bought the soil sensors for the second
year we did see quite a lot of variation
in how they affected soil moisture um I
don't know like you know I think we
still need to actually like
statistically test it but it seems like
we I would have expected the open top
Chambers to have been drier but our data
is showing that wasn't the case and
there were actually like points where
they were there was maybe a little bit
higher moisture and so we were wondering
like could rainfall have been like
running down the sides and I don't yeah
I'm not sure but um so we are sort of
measuring soil moisture and you know we
want to take that into
account the commity might also affect
the possibly
yeah I mean the seeds are like in the
soil and they like IDE water from the
soil so it's possible that humidity
could be plain Factor but I think that
probably soil moisture would be more
more important and often what people use
to model emergence is like you know the
often used hydrothermal time so they'll
sort of like be integrating soil water
potential into that I have another
question from your your first study
within microbial um you you showed pal
amaranth and pal amaranth is really
really really small seed yeah I know um
and um did you do any other species you
know like the Velvet leaves like the
yeah the fox tails that are going to be
larger seeded and like you know the
Velvet Leaf also has a hard seed coat
yeah so we actually did have a second
species we had Velvet Leaf but the thing
that was we actually did not submit the
Velvet Leaf seeds for sequencing and the
reason why was because Velvet Leaf was
either gone like we couldn't recover
them or they were alive so we didn't
have this sort of like some seeds were
dead but we could still extract DNA from
them and some seeds were viable it was
just like viable or gone and so you know
I think what happens with a Velvet Leaf
is the moment that seed coat cracks that
hard seed coat cracks it's just like a
free-for-all like you know that's all
that's it invests all of its defenses
into that hard SE coat and when that
cracks it's basically gone um and so so
yeah I want to try more with like some
other species so the pigweed really
limited us because what I wanted to do
for that final time point was with
viability testing you cut the seeds in
half and so I wanted for each individual
seed to submit half of the seed for
viability testing and then half would
get Frozen and then we could pull all of
the viable seeds and like because all
the data I presented was like this
sample had this percent mortality and
this sample had this microbial Community
but I couldn't say this seed was dead
and this was the microbial you know and
so it would have been nice to be able to
do that and Cara eer my master student
who did all that work phenomenal um she
tried and like if if if there's anything
in the world that can be done Cara could
do it and she was getting so
unbelievably frustrated trying to do
that like you know trying to preserve
the seeds enough so that she could do
use half of the seed for both purposes
and it just was not working and so so I
would like to do it with larger seeds
that we could then actually have like a
you know like like really do more
indepth seed work by having half the
seeds go to viability testing half the
seeds go to
sequencing yeah so I have question but I
was wondering if there's might be
anybody on yes thank you thank you there
is nothing nothing
online so um I'm just wondering the the
first experiment you highlighted a few
um bacterial species yes were different
among the different populations and I'm
just wondering if you looked them up but
they were to me yes there any sort of um
known function that maybe could be
related
TOS can I go there yeah okay I'm there
okay okay yeah so this this kenoia um
all three of these there wasn't a lot of
information that I could find on them so
this one is you know as the name applies
sort of um it can break down kitan so
actually it's like a bacteria that like
breaks down kiten in viral like in
viruses or something like that like I
know was super weird and I was like oh
like you know kitan is a really sort of
like recalcitrant compound and I think
that would make sense that some that was
good at breaking down these calcitrin
compounds would be good at infecting
seeds so I could see but it was like
very viral focused I was a little bit
confused um and then I can't remember
which one of these had some pathogenetic
function sort of characterized by uh by
it I can't remember if it was the kbella
or the lysobacter but the other one I
like really could not find that much
information about so um yeah and you
know um uh sort of like getting into
these micro functions and what they do
sort of like a whole new area for me um
but yeah so you know it' be interesting
to sort of like do future work and see
like do we still get like if I was to
bury seeds in a completely different
field let's just say a field that was
like two hours away would I still see
these same gener in the seeds and I
think that would be super interesting to
know and then that would really sort of
like support sort of like investigating
whether or not these actually could be
involved in
mortality so definitely a lot more work
to be done but you know this sort of
like sets up some potential future
hypotheses we could test and I would
like to see you know are these players
that you know are these bacteria ones
that we will frequently find in these
seeds and how much is it very by species
um you know and that could really sort
of set up support for actually testing
whether or not there's some mechanistic
way
yes look at what the like naturally
occurring sorry microbial composition is
in just the like bulk soil or other so
we so you know um we did the sequencing
of the soil that was in proximity to the
seed bags but what we didn't do and
again it was just sort of like I didn't
have a lot of funding for this and sort
of like funding came later we didn't do
like the starting microbial community in
the soil um like before like when we
bury the seeds and that is like you know
when you have these like regrets I don't
know that's like a regret like I really
have you know um like I wish we had done
that because I'm wondering maybe what
matters most most is the microbial
Community like the moment seeds hit the
oil like maybe that maybe those priority
effects are what govern govern this um
and so we did so we had like the two and
the two and a half year time point we
were able to sequence the micro whe
Community we found an effect of
treatment so we found a statistically
significant different in our difference
in our um treat our uh uh the soil
collected from our penal forage
treatments um with a permanova but then
when I tried to do like you know
principal coordinate analysis to see if
I could visualize that they all looked
very similar so it's something that we
need to sort of like explore further
maybe with different sort of statistical
techniques to be able to figure out what
sort of um variation in the community
actually explains that difference so
it's something that we're going to
explore further but you know I really
like I could go back in time I wish I
had that soil but I don't
yeah oh yeah yeah I just have a quick
question with the principal coordinate
analysis I was just wondering what's the
dissimilarity metric with us and if you
tried any other one so we only tried by
Curtis since we haven't tried any others
but yeah something that we'll probably
be playing around with in the future it
just sort of seemed that like that's
what all the micro people use and so I
was like all right well that's what you
all do but now you know the more you get
into it you realize that not all micro
people agree on things and so yeah so
it's definitely something we're going to
play around with a little bit or maybe
use other sort of type of ordination
techniques like an nmds see if we can
you know visualize some
differences nothing on chat any other
questions is there any other questions
know like not sure when you when youall
are done okay yeah all right thank you
so much for
coming this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu