[Music]
Hi my name is Solveig Hanson and I'm coordinator  for the Cover Crop Breeding Network. I'm here at
one of Cornell University's research farms at our  winter pea nursery. For about 6 years the Cover
Crop Breeding Network has been breeding  winter peas for cover crop use -- which
means reliable winter survival, strong  spring vigor and high biomass. Winter pea
breeding starts here in breeding nurseries where  we select the best individual plants. Winter
pea breeding continues here in our advanced  line trial fields. Over the past six years,
we've trialed winter peas in about 50 different  locations. The best of our breeding lines are
moving toward commercial availability and we've  also identified some excellent commercially
available cultivars. So now if you live in  Hardiness Zones 3 through 6 -- so a place with
a cold winter -- we're inviting you to join our  winter pea trialing efforts. If you participate,
you receive enough seed to sow about a 15-foot  row of four different varieties. We'll ask you to
photograph and rate the plots three times during  the season using an app called SeedLinked, which
is designed for collaborative variety trialing.  We'll ask you to rate for traits like emergence,
vigor, winter hardiness and yield. Cover crops are  essential for soil health, but they can also be
delicious. We will be working with the Stone Barn  Center for Food and Agriculture and Blue Hill at
Stone Barns to learn about evaluating flavor in  winter peas with tips like this. So there's two
main traits that we're going to look at. One  is the flavor. So that's the overall enjoyment
of these peas sweetness, earthiness. 1 through 5.  So 1 is very unpleasant, never try it again. 4 or
5 is I would seek this out. This is my  favorite salad green ever. We hope you
join us this fall in trialing winter pea cover  crop varieties on your farm or in your garden.
To sign up or for more information visit the  opportunities page of covercropbreeding.com
or email ccbn@cornell.edu. This is  a production of Cornell University.