[Music]
Hi everybody. This is Soul. I'm out at
my winter pee trial plots. Um, and I'm
going to do some spring raidings. I'm
doing the group of ratings that we've
timed for spring green up. And what is
spring green up? It's when you go, "Oh
my gosh, the world is green again." So,
that happened here about 10 days ago,
but I waited because we got a couple 20
degree nights last week and I wanted to
make sure that uh we didn't see any
further damage after that. So, I've
heard from some of you, especially in
the upper Midwest, that you had no
survival for the winter peas in your
trial. And this is a bummer. It's also
uh pretty common when we have open
winters or winters that are very cold
but um with little to no snow cover. So
um it's still important to record those
no survival ratings. Uh that helps us
establish a baseline for survival of
commercial cultivars and the range of
places uh where your trials are. Um but
it is a bummer not to see anything in
the spring.
So, I'm here with my handy dandy rubric
to help me with my ratings. We're going
to start with winter survival. Uh, so a
one for winter survival and 0 to 20%
survived. If you did have total winter
kill, one is the rating you choose. So,
important to record. Uh, five is the
best rating. That's uh 80 to 100%
survival. The downfall with this type of
rating is that you have to remember what
your stand looked like in the fall. So
maybe you have some photos to remind you
what those plots looked like. So um
gauge as best you can what percent of
the plot that was there in the fall
still remains in the spring. In my plots
I had really nice winter survival.
Definitely winter damage, which we'll
talk about in a moment, but you'll see
that my plots look pretty full of nice
green pea plants. And so I'm going to
give these all five. They definitely all
uh survived at 80 to 100%.
Winter damage for me was the hardest one
to rate. So, our scale goes from one,
which is damage to the whole plant. If
you have no survival, that's the one you
choose, to uh five, which is no damage
or just the borders of the leaves
looking like crispy paper.
So, I'm seeing a lot of plants like this
where there is damage to the stem, not
just to the leaves, which puts these
plants between a two and a three on our
rubric. So, a two would be major stem
damage in the range of 75% of the stem.
Uh, a three would be minor stem damage,
more like 25%.
So like these individual plants um I
would give a two but there is a whole
plot of other plants that um have
different levels of damage. So this is
the challenge of making a rating on a
plot basis rather than a plant basis. Um
so really just do your best to choose a
rating that is reflective of the entire
plot.
Um, in the same plot there are stems
like this which are barely damaged.
There's a little bit of leaf damage. Uh,
so that would be more like a four. So
I'm going to kind of average that out
and say this plot gets a three for
winter damage because we have some
that's, you know, barely damaged at all,
some that is really uh quite damaged
down here. So for spring vigor, we're
looking at not necessarily the absolute
plant size, but how fast, how vigorously
is it putting on new
growth. So this is an awesome example of
uh high spring vigor. So putting on a
lot of new tender growth. Um you can
tell the plants really um awake and
alive and photosynthesizing and putting
on lots of new leaf tissue.
Um, again, we're rating a plot, not just
a plant. So, the other part of this plot
is not looking quite as hot. So, I'm
going to give this a four. So, that's
strong growth as kind of an average of
the really awesome looking uh part of
the plot and the less awesome looking
pot
part. This plot I'm going to give a
three. So, that's acceptable growth.
Like, it's it's certainly putting on new
growth. Like you can see at the end of
this like pretty damaged stem, it's
putting on this really nice uh new leaf
tissue. Uh but it really hasn't gotten
cranking to the degree that that other
plot
had. And now for arguably the most fun
trait, uh flavor. So you're going to
want to try the new growth. So something
like this that you can tell is new and
tender and it's easy to pinch off just
like
that. as opposed to say something like
this, like this is not going to be good
eats. That's going to be more woody and
not very tasty. I'm not going to make
you watch me chew things, but I found
some of these really delicious. Um, a
nice mix of sweetness and that rich pea
flavor that I think is really yummy. So,
uh, please sample if you like if you
like only if you like. Um, and rate
flavor and texture. It's a really easy
rating. just I want to eat this all the
time. I would seek it out. It's great.
That's a five. And one is yuck, no thank
you. I don't want that again. When you
rate flavor, you may have rated that in
the fall as well. So when you choose
flavor from the pull down menu, uh your
original ratings will come up. You can
click the little arrow next to uh your
star rating and you'll get a chance to
enter a new rating. So, if uh if
especially if your rating's changed, a
couple of mine did from fall to spring,
you can enter your new rating and if you
want, you can enter a comment like in
the spring this was very sweet or
something like that. Um and we we will
be able to distinguish using the time of
the data entry um what you thought about
fall flavor versus spring flavor.
[Music]
This is a production of Cornell
University.
[Music]