[Music]
hi I'm sve I'm here at one of the
Cornell research Farms with my winter
pea plots that I planted about a month
ago I'm here to do my fall evaluations
which we're asking that you do four to 6
weeks after planting and before
snowfall we've had a really mild winter
here in Ithaca that's just starting to
break we had our first light frost last
night uh so we have vigorous plant
growth and lots to look at I want to
thank those of you who have shared
photos of your plots and your
experiences with planting and your
questions on the seed link uh social
feed uh it's really exciting to see
things coming up and it's cool to see uh
you guys interacting with one another as
well the first trait we're evaluating is
emergence we're using the germination
trait in seed link even though they're
not exactly the same thing but close
enough for our
purposes we're using the evaluation
rubric on page seven of your protocol
packet and using that we're asking what
percentage of the plot or what
percentage of the planted rows are
filled with plants as opposed to having
bare
soil so you will notice as we walked
down our plots we have some bare spots
like this um the beginning of the row on
this right hand side so we had an issue
with our planter where that cone was not
uh opening properly at the beginning of
our planting you see it gets better as
we go down the plot if you had an issue
like this whether it was a planter error
or your dog dug a hole in the middle of
the plot um please just rate the part of
the plot that was planted correctly if
the seed didn't get in the ground or got
dug up or something um you can ignore
that part of the
plot on the rubric emergence or
germination ratings range from one which
is less than 50% emerged to five which
is all or almost all plants emerged so
my plots look really good so I'm going
to be choosing from the top two ratings
so four which is more than 75% emerged
or five which is all or almost
all so for this row keep in mind we're
just rating the one row um there are a
couple of bare
spots including the space at the end
here
um so I'm going to say if I stacked all
that bare soil at one end I'd get maybe
15% of the row so for me this is going
to be a four this double row in contrast
is really nice and full there's maybe
one open spot there but I'm going to say
that all or almost all of the seeds that
we put in um have emerged so for me this
is going to be a
five for Vigor we are asking how vigor
ous how robust how fast growing
resilient to stress are the plants that
we're seeing so the scale runs from one
uh weak or slow growing plants to five
exceptional growth robust appearance we
need to remember that emergence and
vigor are different traits so if you
have a plot with not very good stand but
the plants that are there are healthy
and strong and and big uh that might
receive a good score for even though the
score for emergence is
lower so as I look across my plots I see
really nice Vigor across the board uh so
I will be choosing from the top couple
of ratings four which is strong growth
and five which is really exceptional
growth three of my varieties had growth
that was pretty comparable to this so
really nice and strong the tallest
plants are about uh 6 in tall uh very
full Lush looks really nice so this is
going to be a
four then compared to this which is my
four I'm going to come over
here to this plot which is even a little
more Lush so the plants are a little
taller maybe seven or 8 Ines for the
taller plants very well filled in um
this one really stood out in my plot so
I'm going to give this one of
five depending on which subset of
varieties you have you may or may not
see difference
in emergence or fall Vigor so if they
really do all look the same for one of
those traits it's okay to give them the
same rating we will or we won't see
differences later in the season but if
they look the same it's okay to score
them the same I've just been cutting
some peot samples to take down to J
Jason and Andrew at Stone Barnes and
blue hill at Stone Barnes so they can
give us some tips on tasting peash
shoots but I've been nibbling as I go
along and I'm finding some really
interesting differences in sweetness and
um kind of that rich starchy pea flavor
um and I wonder what else they will
taste and I wonder what you will all
taste when you um snack on your cover
crops if you decide to hi I'm Jason
grower I'm the senior director of farm
and Innovation at the Stone Barn Center
and I'm Andrew lesmore I'm the director
of special projects at Blue hillt Stone
barns we're really excited to dive into
the tasting component of this winter pee
trial um blue hill and St Barnes have
engaging in cover crop trials both out
in the fields and in the kitchen for
tastings over many years and we're
really excited to be a part of this
project now with seed link and Cornell
and the expansive group of farmers that
are involved so as you are going out and
using seed link to evaluate the rest of
the plots we're going to be
incorporating two different flavor
traits into this analysis so there are
two different traits one of them is
Flavor the other one is texture both are
going to be rated on a scale through 1
through 5
Cornell and seing TB provides the rubric
for what each measurement looks like one
being unpleasant five being very very
delicious so you're going to be
inputting that into the app as you're
doing the rest of the work if you have
any questions feel free to reach out to
Jason or myself we'd love to help
thanks this is a production of corn
University