this is a production of Cornell
University yeah I want to thank the
students for inviting me it's always
really an honor to be invited by the
students we never quite know why they
picked you but this is really great so
okay so today I'm going to talk to you
about responses to DNA damage and
responses to a an acute dose of heavy
DNA damage can go on for weeks but what
we're mostly going to focus on are these
immediate responses that happen in the
very same day as being hit by this acute
dose and these things have to do with
well this is tricky these these kind of
responses are really responses to the
damage that we're inducing Downstream
things have more to do with responses to
the responses you know some cells have
died things have to be replenished I'll
talk about that very briefly because I
my talk is probably too long
already okay so our model DNA damaging
agent which we're going to use through
at this talk at gamma rays just to make
it clear what gamma rays do the Rays
themselves do not probably induce many
double strand braks so these are photons
they zip right through the cell the
great majority of them are not even
going to interact with any of the matter
in the cell they're just going to go
right through but if one is lucky it
might interact probably with a water
molecule because that's most common
molecule in the cell it's going to spit
out through comptant scattering a very
high energy electron that electron can
travel quite far in the cell and if it
happens to come to a stop within the
cell it'll depend deposit all of that
energy in a little burst of reactive
oxygen species so this is really quite
an indirect effect but it's making
several different types of damage right
here and again most of the damage will
be to water because most of the cellular
components are water but if that little
burst happens to Lodge in the nucleus it
has a good chance of hitting the DNA and
the burst itself happens within a
certain radius which just by chance is
about the same as the radius of the DNA
so you'll get multiple damage to both
sides of the DNA and that means you
don't have a good template strand for
repair it's possible you could introduce
a break in the backbone to begin with
but also repair activities will
introduce double strand brakes and this
may take time for those braks to be
induced so things are going to happen
gradually so again the burst could have
been over here and you get single ided
damage or if the burst happened to be
right where a DNA molecule was you'll
get a double strand break
eventually all right now double strand
braks sound horrific but they actually
have very little biological significance
provided the cell doesn't divide so the
only point of having genes be connected
to a chromosome is if you're going to do
cell division again so the whole point
of being on a chromosome is to be
attached to a centrom if the cell
doesn't need to divide the DNA can still
replicate it can still do transcription
there's no problem there are many
origins of
replication um and everything can be
just fine it's only in the context of
cell division that you'd end up losing a
chromosome arm because there's no
Centere here and here in yeast you would
end up with a dead daughter cell because
you've lost a chromosome arm it's going
to carry something that's essential on
there so that's really bad news but as
long as cell division doesn't happen
dble break are not a
problem all right
so the immediate DNA damage response the
stuff that happens in the same day as
the DNA damage is to have some sort of
system for monitoring the presence of
damage and that system has to talk to
the cell and give it some good ideas
like arresting progression of the cell
cycle until that signal disappears maybe
inducing repair if that's something that
needs to happen both bacteria and UK
carats are extremely exquisitly
sensitive to the presence of double
strand brakes and in yeast of single
double St Brakes in a completely
unnecessary plasmid will prevent cell
cycle progression now yeast and other
single whoops single celled
organisms if they detect the presence of
a break for several days and it's clear
that it's never going to go away since
they're single single celled organism
they might as well give it a shot go on
with replication maybe the find they
didn't need that chromosome arm after
all in the daughter so right but um in
an animal that's a risky thing to do we
carry a a huge genetic load on our
chromosomes if we go from being
heterozygous for mutation on one of
those arms to uncovering that recessive
mutation it can easily lead to cancer we
have trillions of cells so in our case
rather than adapt to the presence of
double Stone brakes the cell would
decide to die or permanently arrest
instead so that it never undergo um DNA
sorry cell division and exposes that he
that um deleterious alil so the question
we're asking here is what about plants
do plants have the exact same issue as
single celled organisms or animals or
are they somewhere in
between all right so let's think about
it do we expect plants to have
programmed cell cycle responses to DNA
damage at all of course we do because
it's a very sensitive sensible thing to
do but let's just play devil's advocate
for a second here
plants are diploid and often polyploid
and they tolerate anupy well they have
backup copies of things in my case I'm
working with arabidopsis arabidopsis is
a self-pollinating organism so it's
homozygous for all low size so it's not
going to be exposing heterozygosity by
Le losing a chromosome arm because it's
already totally
inbred plant cells can't move so cancers
can't metastasize so even if you messed
up the regulation of the cell cycle in a
single cell you might end up with a
tumor on a plant but You' rather you'd
probably not end up with death and again
in case of arabidopsis we have a 10we
life cycle anyway really doesn't matter
plant development is extremely flexible
so if some cells are messed up and
starting to take off on their own and
there aren't many examples of them ever
doing this you know you know viruses or
bacteria can reprogram cells that cells
rarely ignore the signals from other
cells so this is an example of the
flexibility of plant um growth in that
you can take a fig tree in this case a
ficus and you can turn it into boards
and you can pound them into the ground
and staple barb wire to them and if
there's any living tissue still in the
board it'll make another tree right so
animals don't do this but plants can
easily do this sort of thing so they can
work around a lot of problems now still
why not do cell cycle arrest well the
reason not to is plants compete for
resources only through growth animals
don't do that they can run around and
compete for resources the plant if these
plants two little seedlings are going
next to each other and they're competing
for light if one gets bigger than the
other even transiently it'll overshadow
the other and have an exponential
advantage that will never stop it's a
little like uncontrolled capitalism
right if you don't have government
regulations in place as soon as one
person gets Rich he can dominate all the
others so in this case sorry yeah
plants have to worry about growth rate
versus genetic Purity you know which is
really a more important issue so this
immediately leads us to think about
sematic versus germline cells maybe it's
okay to grow like mad and ignore genome
Fidelity as long as you're outpacing
your competitors but the germ line
perhaps is something you don't want that
to happen in and unfortunately I'm not
going to be talking about the germline
in this talk at all because it's harder
to look at than the root tip so instead
I'll talk a little bit about
meristematic versus terminally
differentiated cells and how their
responses might be
different all right so do double strand
braks occur at all in nature there's no
natural source of radiation that plants
really have to worry about the kind of
doses I'm using are enormous you're even
if you growing plants in Chernobyl where
they grow just fine they wouldn't get
this sort of
dose all right so double strand breaks
are generated during DNA replication
quite frequently so these are
single-ended double strand braks due to
breakage of a replication fork so larger
genomes will have bigger problems with
this sort of issue and here's an example
of what I'm talking about if you have a
replication fork and there's maybe a
single-sided you know a lesion just one
base DNA pmer is very fastidious and it
doesn't want to replicate past that it's
going to leave single stranded DNA on
both of these sides and that is a very
fragile thing and so it's quite likely
for one of these branches to break off
right this is essentially in a complete
chromosome that's fine but this is a
chromosome that has a break and nothing
to rejoin it to so that's a single-ended
break so every round of replication this
probably happens in every cell right in
a rabid opsis a genome size is 130th the
size of maze so I would think it would
happen 30 times more often in maze than
in a rabbit op
double Str breaks can also be generated
naturally during desiccation and
rehydration and I don't mean drought I
mean desiccation when biological tissues
reach you know air levels of humidity
they're just left out to dry out and
animals most animals cannot withstand
desiccation but some funy can and plants
can seed plants do it every generation
in the seeds sometimes pollen is
desicated tolerant and some kinds of
pollen are not so this is another
example of where double strand braks
could be generated substantially in the
genome and of course bigger genomes just
because they have more DNA have a
greater probability of getting a double
strand
break and is this damage acute so we're
throughout this talk going to be talking
about acute damage right slam the plant
with gamma radiation then I look at its
recovery rather than leaving it to grow
on something that induces double strand
braks damage to seeds acute it depends
whether you believe that seeds in their
desiccated cryptobiotic state are
actually still metabolically active in
repairing things but there is an older
literature about the fact that seeds if
you watch them germinate they will
undergo what's called unscheduled DNA
replication which means that all of the
cells are doing a little repair here and
there and once that period is done then
the seed will actually proceed with cell
division and it won't do that so it
seems to be cleaning up its genome at
the beginning of replic of germination
after it's emed and then it goes on with
its life so it's a little like suffering
an acute dose of DNA damage it suddenly
a wakens to the fact that it has
accumulated DNA damage all right our
model system is the Rabbid opposite
seedling it has highly stereotypical
development we know what all the cells
are doing pretty well has lots of eally
visualized cell types and has a variety
of cell cycle modes so if we look at
this young Arab Ops of
seedling the different cells are doing
different things and this is a plant
audience mostly so I can go through this
pretty quickly there's an apical marem
here and an apical meristem down here
and both of these regions are rapidly
dividing and there's sort of a stem cell
Niche that's creating all these new
cells those are mitotic cells now unlike
animals there's also a lot of endid
duplication so all of the growth of the
hypoc cotle after germination is through
expansion of cells not cell division and
so those are becoming Ender duplicated
undergoing S phase but not mphase and
the cells are getting bigger and bigger
same thing in the zone of elongation in
the root after they're done being
mitotic the cells will start to expand
and increase the copy number of the DNA
without undergoing cell division and
then there's
differentiation um sort of after that
expansion is done so we are looking at
all kinds of different cell cycles when
we radiate these seedlings every single
cell is getting the exact same dose of
brakes right the radiation as I said
goes right through there's no higher
dose to outside cells than inside cells
everything's getting the same
dose but there the cells have different
Destinies and so they might have
different responses to DNA
damage all right do plants exhibit
program responses to DNA damage and of
course yes I wouldn't be talking here
and um how first the questions more
intellectual questions to ask are how do
you know a response is programmed rather
than just a Toxic effect for instance if
you if you expose a plant to Drought you
might see it Wilt you might think poor
Plant it's suffering from drought but it
is in a way undergoing a programmed
response to that drought it's dropping
its leaves so it's not picking up as
much sun as it used to it's doing this
intentionally so we're trying to
distinguish between intentional
responses which we call programmed and
toxic inevitable effects of ionizing
radiation then for the programmed
responses we'd like to know how they're
regulated and we want to know what their
biological significance is
to all right so most cases we will be
radiating seedlings but sometimes we
irradiate seeds so this is the mature
embryo of a rabid opsis inside of its
seed it has two calans it has a root but
it has no true leaves no visible true
leaves at all there's a meristem that
will divide to give true
leaves so if you radiate at this stage
for wild type seeds we look a couple
weeks later we have plenty of true
leaves who can spot them with their Leaf
hairs 100 Grays basically no effect on
growth this is a dose that is about 30
times the dose that would kill a person
um but the genome size is 130th that of
a human genome size right but this is
you know clearly it's not a lethal dose
at all it has no effect on growth if
irradiated as seeds now if we take that
up to 500 gray which is about 150 double
strand breaks per diploid G1 genome we
actually see miniaturization of
everything the calines everything that
was in the embryo is alive it's
gravitropic it's
phototropic um but it's not growing and
the cells are miniaturized they're also
not expanding so is that a Toxic effect
or programmed effect I can't tell
you another thing we can look at that's
an effect of ionizing radiation is
mutagenesis so we have this assay for
mutagenesis where we have a boster
resistant knockout of an Al that cause
causes albanism so we can select for
heterozygotes they have to be green and
they have to be Bost resistant and then
we can irradiate those seeds and ask
what the rate of sectoring is and the
rate of sectoring if you don't irradiate
the the seeds is zero you can't look it
enough to to find those sectors but if
you r them you can produce these sectors
that reflect chromosome loss breakage I
don't know what it's a very large broad
net that catches all mutations at this
Locus and it maxes out at about 4% of
plants because the plants get smaller
and smaller and smaller and smaller
until you can't look at sectors
anymore as part of their programmed DNA
damage response but that sectoring
mutagenesis itself it's hard to believe
that's a programmed response that is a
Toxic effect of ionizing radiation now
you think cell death would also be a
Toxic effect of ionizing radiation but
the reason you die from five Grays of
radiation is not
because your epithelial intestinal
lining is especially sensitive to ioning
radiation it's because it's a sensitive
to the response to destroy itself in
response to ionizing radiation so you
Slough off your EP all your epidermal
cells similarly here if we look at
plants we radiate the whole root tip
everybody gets the same dose but we get
death not entirely just you know I can
see a dead cell here Pi staining
indicates that the cells can no longer
pump out pi and so they they start to
glow and you might say well maybe this
is a highly mitotic population that
makes it more sensitive because it's
running through the cell cycle faster
but if we look at the mitotic population
using cyclin b11 gfp as a marker we see
that this whole mass of cells here is
highly mitotic and um they're not all
dying it's instead focused on the stem
cells for the steel of the room here all
right which suggests that it's a
programmed response rather than a toxic
response another thing that cells um
root tips do in response to radiation is
here's a root tip growing 4 days old 8
days old here's a root cap you can't see
any root hairs because they're farther
up the
root if you hit them with ionizing
radiation 4 days later you can start to
see root hairs as differentiation
approaches the root tip the root tip has
stopped dividing and stopped growing
away from the differentiating Zone it's
coming down at 8 days all the cells have
become really massive and huge the
entire root tip has swollen up their
root hair is everywhere because there's
no cell division and the root tip is not
growing away from this differentiation
zone right so we you could say that this
is premature and red duplication
differentiation or you could say it's
just waiting for differentiation to
catch up with
it um another cute phenotype is this if
we look at this DNA repair mutant xpf
that's defective in a flap
endonuclease we irradiate these plants
as seeds wild type is not sensitive to
this dose the DNA repair mutant
is these calans are still undergoing
cell division there's not a lot of cell
division in a Cod naturally but there's
um there's the formation of stamata for
example that's all post emion and that's
still occurring those cell divisions are
still occurring but these cell divisions
to make leaves are not and so again that
suggests it's a programmed response some
cells are undergoing arrest or death
other cells are
not okay so how do we know which
responses are due to DNA damage because
ionizing uh radiation affects everything
in the cell and how do we know which
responses are programmed versus Direct
effects well to look at the
responsibility of DNA damage we can't
quite do that directly but we can do a
fairly convincing
experiment where what we do is look at
mutants that are defective in endtoend
non- holics end joining of double strand
brakes so in a G1 cell this is what's
doing the bulk of the DNA repair the
ends are simply religated together it's
a reasonably error free process so long
as the ends haven't been
reected there is also um this Gene which
I mentioned before xpf which is a flap
Ender nucleas and is sometimes required
for some types of nonhomologous end
joining all right so we can look at
these and we can ask if you're defective
in doubl strand brake repair do you
mimic the effects of ionizing radiation
at a lower dose you know in the mutant
that any phenotype you see is due to
this deficiency and therefore due to
double Strone
breaks so for example if we look at a
DNA liase 4
mutant at Zer gr of radiation it's wild
type at 100 gr of radiation when
radiated as seeds it makes this
miniaturized tiny Calen Little Seedling
that's not going to grow again and this
mimics the effects of 500 gr of
radiation all right
similarly at only 20 Grays of radiation
before we looked at 100 wild type
is very slow to induce any cell death in
the root tip it's not particularly
focused there either but if we look at D
lagus 4 at 20 gr we can see within four
hours there starts to be self death so
this is also apparently a response to
double strand breaks doesn't mean it's
programmed but it's a response to double
strand
breaks and interestingly different kinds
of persisting DNA damage can induce
different effects on growth so I just
talked about xpf having this lovely
phenotype that we call the gamma
plantlet in which everything is normal
you know hypoc codal development is
normal Calene development is normal but
you're just not getting true leavs as
opposed to DNA lagus for at the same
dose which has this highly miniaturized
seedling there's no dose of gamma
radiation where we can get lag four to
look like this right so it's not just a
matter of degree right by the time the
calans look this good we have true
leaves also and so this is a response to
something that's a very potent signal
for telling these cells to not divide
whereas this is a response to something
that's making all cells
miniaturized and inhibiting growth right
again this differential sensitivity of
these cells versus these cells again
these still have cell division they
still forming a stamata suggests that
this is a programmed
response all right so we felt so
strongly that this was a programmed
response that Sasha PR was willing to
undergo go a genetic screen to look for
Regulators of this so if it's a
programmed response there must be
something that's telling the cell here's
a break this is what you should do in
response to it or whatever it is that
xpf is repairing right so he took the
xpf
line and he mutagenized seeds with EMS
and he treated them actually with 100
Grays and then he looked for plants that
could grow in spite of the fact that
they've been irradiated so he's looking
for true Leaf production and he found
several mutant
and one of them was SOG one you can see
the leaves are not great but the phoxy
is normal and the the time at which
they're produced is normal so the leaves
are struggling but they're still
emerging so they've lost the ability to
induce probably a checkpoint in the
apical
marem and SOG one as Tomo discovered is
also defective in this program cell de
so if we look at sag one at 04 and 8
hours after radiation Sagan has no cell
depth it's not sensitive to ionizing
radiation in the way it's resistant
again because this is a programmed
response and Sagan tells you it's a
programmed response this is not
happening it's not a Toxic effect it's
something the cells are doing
intentionally and just as to be entirely
forthcoming with you if we go to the
next day and we look at Sagan mutants we
do see cell death so here's wild type 24
hours you see this Focus cell death
here's SOG you see this checkerboard
cell death instead it hasn't got the
focus and same thing we go to 48 hours
we see continuing cell death so this is
so one independent cell death I don't
know if it's programmed or not right
this is clearly programmed and stuff at
the earlier time
points all right so if losing SOG one is
so great for the plant because it
doesn't have cell death and it can go on
and divide in spite of radiation what is
San for well it's the same thing any
checkpoint protein is for is to prevent
um the accumulation of mutations so if
we radiate seeds again with that albino
pale green marker and we look for
sectors here's wild type
xpf xpf plus SOG and just SOG by itself
so this is suggesting that Sagan is
really important for minimizing
heritable DNA damage induced by ionizing
radiation so it can control chromosomal
stability it does this by inhibiting
progression of the cell cycle I haven't
showed you all this data it switches
cells from a mitotic to Ender duplicated
cell cycle so again as long as you are
not doing cell division double St breaks
are not a
problem and it induces cell death in
dividing meristematic
cells all right so the isolation of
mutants defective in these responses es
indicates that they're programmed
responses rather than toxic effects of
radiation all right so car yoshiyama was
postto in the lab and she mapped SOG and
figured out what Gene it was and it
turned out to be a transcription factor
a nact domain family protein it has a um
single amino acid change from a glycine
that's entirely conserved in all 100 NAC
domain proteins and rabid opsis to an
arginine
right and it looks like um unfortunately
you know we would love to be able to go
to NIH and say we're going to look for
SG mutants in humans or something but
this nact domain family does not exist
outside the Plant World in fact it only
exists in land plants and if I want to
really go out on a limb I could say that
you couldn't become a land plant without
SOG because it's important for response
to desiccation but that's really pushing
it okay anyway you can find homologues
of sog as opposed to other nacom main
proteins in related angiosperms so they
have more closely related genes to SOG
than to the next nact domain protein in
a rabid opsis so they probably are all
carrying this response but it hasn't
been shown at all now sogg itself is not
transcriptionally induced by ionizing
radiation it's always present and that
makes sense for the master regulator
it's going to be at the top of the chain
has to be present to detect the DNA
damage so how does it do
that well damage sensors are conserved
among UK carots and they're two classes
and sometimes they trade off some
functions but you can distinguish
between them pretty well there's
ATM uh which detects double string
brakes directly with the help of other
factors and there's
ATR which slightly indirectly detects
persisting single stranded stretches of
DNA not single strand braks but single
stranded dnas uses these factors to do
that both of these um sort of touch the
lesion before becoming activated then
this is in mammals there's a check one
and check two kinases these don't exist
in plants at all so plants have the
detectors don't necessarily have the
same connections but when you get down
to the regulation of the cell cycle
itself of course they do share some
factors and we1 is one of
those all right so for instance this
gamma plantlet formation
which these are all radiated seeds
here's wild type it's resistant to
radiation here's xpf making a lovely
gamma plantlet here's xpf SOG making
these sort of crappy looking true
leaves if we look at ATM ATM still has
the arrest so ATM is not required for
that
arrest if we look at ATR mutant we get
the true leaves back again and they look
a lot better than SOG too so ATR is
apparently detecting whatever lesion it
is that xpf is leaving behind in the
cell ATM is not required for that ATR is
absolutely required and in fact we1 is
also required for the detection so this
is probably some kind of replication
block and we1 is part of that pathway
responding to
that okay so so one is a transcription
Factor so does a Rabbid opsis have a
transcriptional response to ionizing
radiation so with this experiment is to
take day old seedlings irradiate Not
seeds but seedlings um with 100 Grays
which is a dose that slows them down a
little but then they all can recover
from that dose and look at the entire
transcriptome 1.5 3 6 12 24 hours which
is presented on a timeline across here
and the red bars are genes that are
repressed and green bars are genes that
are um I'm sorry red is induced and
green is repressed and this has been
sorted by the computer into similar
expression
patterns so there are hundreds of genes
that are induced and Peak between about
1 and 3 hours right here there are also
hundreds of genes that are s suppressed
and that maximum suppression is about at
nine nope sorry 6 hours six hours and
these include transcripts that promote
cell cycle
progression and then there's this little
cluster of genes that are induced at 12
hours also
all right so is this a response to
double St breaks or is this a response
to damage to other cellular components
it could be
both if we look at the list of genes
that are induced the most highly induced
genes and these are all on apy chips the
fold induction for genes like Brea one
which are extremely repressed under
normal conditions in the cell is highly
variable when you do the experiment
depending on how you process the data
from the chips and where you draw the
line about about background levels of
expression so I don't know that this is
really induced 581 fold and it's
certainly not two to the 581 we're just
talking about 581 fold all right so if
you look at this you can see Wild type
is inducing these genes to these degrees
and if you look at the list of genes and
you happen to know anything about um DNA
metabolism you can see that they're all
DNA metabolism
genes all right ATR mutation has no
effect on the induction of those genes
ATM is critical for the induction of
these genes so at this time point in
response to gamma radiation ATM is
driving the induction of this cluster
this little red cluster of
genes okay all right so if we then go
ahead and expose the ATM mutant you can
see that a lot of this response is still
going on but not this
cluster so ATM that's the double strend
break response because ATM is a double
Brak detector you can see that we're
still getting repression of the cell
cycle and that's because if we look at
Gene by Gene basis ATM and ATR both play
semi- redundant roles in that response
so this is ATR driven in an ATM
background okay so what about SOG SOG is
a transcription Factor what does it
regulate in this response and what C
found is that it regulates everything so
for this little cluster again of genes
SOG one is essential for its induction
so um so one must be a transcription
factor that doesn't bind to every one of
these promoters but perhaps binds to the
promoters of transcription factors that
then bind to the promoter of
these so soan is remarkably important
for this
response all right and how does San work
um K had a paper published recently she
went on to work on this Sagan had um um
we knew that it had a SQ Motif a couple
of them that were highly predicted to be
regulated by both ATM and ATR so what
our model is is ATM is induced by a
double strand break it becomes an active
kise and it activates the activity of
pre-existing San protein and this goes
on to induce other effects
too okay and um again if you're
interested you can see K's paper
here
all right so we talked a little bit
before about what relevance does
ionizing radiation have for plant
biology at all because obviously plants
have a lovely programmed response to it
but it's never encountered in nature so
something that DNA repair people like to
say in the literature is for instance
any conventional stress induces reactive
oxygen species and that induces DNA
damage and this is probably important
for response to stress but if you
actually use this stress this DNA damage
response as an indicator for the
presence of double strand breaks we
could say if we look at other stresses
do we see the induction of this response
at all so again here's with gamma this
is another kind of ionizing R radiation
hce this is in the ATM mutant and this
is a particularly nice diagnostic
cluster of transcripts that are ATM
dependent induced so if we mask all this
and look at some other
stresses salt osmotic drought cold heat
blah blah blah blah blah we are not
seeing these clusters of genes so again
we've clustered expression based just on
gamma and then we've extended that
analysis to look at other stresses and
we see a nice block here this is
genotoxic stress it's a combination of
MMS and momy C so again it's just a DNA
repair experiment
hydroxy Ura is an inhibitor of DNA
replication and we can see a little
there but if we look at these more
generic
stresses you know if you squint you can
see it in salt and that's the roots as
opposed to the shoots and this is UVB
you can see it a little there but that's
about
it all right so if we look at the Go
category and we've already discussed
this a little of these ATM dependent
gamma induced genes it's it's massive ly
over represented for RNA and DNA
metabolism and if we again look through
all these stresses and just take the RNA
and DNA metabolism genes that we really
understand and look really hard for
their induction by generic stress we
don't see it right so this response is
not there to deal with generic
stresses it may be there to deal with um
seed
storage Okay
so this is just what I told you
here um surprisingly it's not even
induced by paraquat which is
specifically a Ross
inducer so what's different between
paraquat and ionizing radiation again
ionizing radiation is producing clusters
of Ros the the amount of energy
deposited in a very small area is very
high and you damage both strands normal
Ross just doesn't do that damages single
bases happens all the times that plants
and they're very very good at coping
using excision repair to repair singly
damaged
bases okay so desiccation tolerance and
radiation tolerance seem to be two sides
of the same coin so this is a famous
organism that's extremely radiation
resistant and it was found that it's
also extremely desiccation resistant
mutants that are sensitive to IR are
also sensitive to dehydration if you do
the transcriptomics the two stresses
induce the same thing and um dehydration
indeed induces massive amounts of breaks
it's not just dehydration it's
dehydration rehydration
cycling and um Chris West and wander
waterworth have done some research on
this and they have shown that as the
plant as the rabbit Ops the seed is
germinating there's a one or two hour
window during inhibition at which you
see the induction of this response and
then it goes away again but you have to
really take thin slices of time to see
that so and they've also shown DNA lagas
4 is important for seed longevity so
that probably is what this really
elaborate response is all about okay so
to summarize so far and I'm not going to
get all the way through this talk for
sure um the we're looking at the
immediate actual response to double
strand breaks and rabid opsis has a
robust very reproducible transcriptional
response to IR which is governed by ATM
and so one and transcriptional response
to IR is important in mammals and Fung
p-53 is a transcription Factor but it is
nowhere near this amplitude or this
reproducibility all right the
transcription scrms induced early after
IR a dsb
specific and um you can
see uh that a rabid opsis induces a
program cell death response that is also
ATM and San dependent to both UV which I
didn't discuss and ionizing radiation
and this is focused largely in the
precursor cells of the
steel all right so we know that
different cells respond in different
ways to gamma
radiation and so we can ask is the
short-term transcriptional response
different in different cells so this
requires the presence of SOG one SOG
one's a transcription Factor we can
cross our fingers and hope that these
cells have a different transcriptional
response then these cells around them
and if we could do the transcriptomics
of just these cells um it might give us
a clue as to some of the connecting dots
between the double strand brakes and the
induction of cell
death all right so just as an example of
the cell type specificity of DNA damage
response Phil made this construct of a
Brea one promoter fused to LFR and what
he's going to do is going to take the
same plate here he's going to collect 20
minute batches of photons for 9 hours
after radio
ation so again this is exact same plate
and here are these plants growing you
can see the true leaves the codal
leadens are dimmer this is at one hour
and here's the root tip and when you
watch this and we'll cycle through it
several times you might check out the
root tip first and then you can look
farther up to see what's going on next
time around so here it
goes we're at 3 hours and this flare has
come up and now it's starting to
disappear here's something particularly
beautiful you see these evenly spaced
spots of Brea one induction so we're
coming around again if we look higher up
we can see the root tips of the lateral
Roots lighting up lighter than the root
tip down
here and one more
time we can also see at this time Point
evenly spaced white spots within the
roof which are probably the areas where
the lateral roots are going to come out
and emerge later that's not clear to me
that those cells are dividing already
but they know that they're miror stem
already okay so in the case of Brea 1 we
we can clearly see that timing is
different for different cell types and
some cells never express braa one and um
some cells express it more strongly
there's lots in the highly mitotic new
leaves there's less than the already
developed
calans so in the case of Brea one we'll
probably see induction only in cells
that
undergo or can undergo or are undergoing
DNA replication
because braa one is involved in
homologous repair of double strand
brakes and that occurs during S phase in
G2 because it uses the sister chromatid
as a template to repair the DNA so the
process at least in mammals is is very
cell cycle regulated and it's absolutely
suppressed in
G1 so Phil went on to ask this the
quality of the transcriptional response
vary with cell type so this was all
about quantity and timing for one cell
so we're going to go ahead and do the
transcriptomics for a particular cell
type and cells type specific
transcriptomics can tell us lots of
things they help us identify First
transcripts that we would never have
seen on a whole groundup seedling
because they're only being induced say
in four cells that you're interested in
you're going to have to do a lot of work
to isolate those four cells and look at
them and then but the suddenly that
signal will stand out you wouldn't have
seen it before now cell Phil's not
looking at just four cells he's looking
at a whole batch of cells that turned
out to be about 5% of the total cells of
the root tips that he's looking at you
can identify candidate genes for
Regulators of the effectors of cell type
specific processes and that's the gold
that we're really looking for in this
kind of experiment is to identify new
regulators and you know just looking at
go analysis can provide clues as to
what's going
on okay so again we're going to attempt
to at these cells we can't do this
perfectly but what we're going to use is
a p wooden leg gfp Fusion that labels
these really the dividing steel cells
the ones that are still undergoing
replication so the timing we didn't have
a lot of money so we didn't do a lot of
time points just one Phil chose
something between four hours at which he
could see no cell death in 6 hours at
which he could after
radiation and and his protocol is this
so we're taking the gfp positive line
we're cutting off just the root tips and
throwing away the top of the plant then
we're going to protoplast the root tips
we're going to sell sort away the gfp
plus and collect this population it's
about 5% of this population now Phil did
not sort away what we're drawing here is
red versus green he just took the entire
thing so we're comparing GP plus to the
entire all right and just to that the
sort worked short root is a transcript
that should only be expressed in this
population and you can see that it's
enhanced for expression of short root
whereas um actin is expressed throughout
and you can see that if you take the
entire root tip versus a gfp pu positive
these are pretty much the same but short
root is ened here so the sort
worked and just to go through this
really quickly this is he's doing his
RNA seek analysis most of this is
gibberish to me but I trust my people in
my lab if we do the go analysis of these
genes that are induced in both tissues
equally what we see is this gamma
response that we discussed before the
res we the response to double strand
breaks so this is happening in the outer
shell and in the inner core of the root
tip both of them are responding to
double strand
braks this is just telling you the same
thing repressed in both tissues is the
cell cycle so all these things about
building new cells it's being shut down
tempor
while the root tip is responding to the
under gr of
radiation if we look at genes that are
induced more strongly in the gfp plus
which is really what we're looking for
that's why we're doing the experiment
and you look at these go categories and
again these go categories are are
somewhat redundant and the same genes
may be falling into multiple go
categories these all have to do with
immune response so as plant biologists
I'm sure you're sensitive with a hypers
sensitive response to pathogens and this
is suggesting that there are
commonalities between the two probably
the detection is
different but it may be that the cell
death itself is similar and the
connection somewhere those two processes
meet up into the same signal
transduction chain perhaps so we're
seeing a similar effect again induced
specifically in the population that's
going to
die and this is just showing you the
relative fold induction in gfp Plus
versus the entire root tip
here and um Phil took a couple of these
genes made gfp
fusions transform them into plants and
he can get some very pretty pictures
without ionizing radiation this is a
sence Associated Gene 14 this is with if
you look carefully and you know your
root tip morphology you see that this is
not part of the steel right so even
though we're purifying cells in the
steel this is also induced outside of
the steel steel but it is induced right
here in the root tip and it's very ir
inducible and there's lots of expression
within the steel going up
too all right so that we told you that
the cell type specific transcriptomics
can identify transcripts from selected
cell types whose signals are normally
swamped and that's another interesting
result that Phil got there is a gene
called ear
F-15 which is very hard to detect
because it's very very very poorly
expressed and he sees it as being
induced in his gfp plus population by
ir and what is the function of this Gene
Le develder lab had this paper in
science
2013 erf 115 if it's
overexpressed causes the cells in the um
QC you know the sort of organizing core
of the root tip to divide so it
stimulates division of the QC so it's
interesting that at a time at which cell
division is being actively repressed in
the root 10 this stimulating Gene that's
specific for the QC is being induced and
Phil and I are still arguing about this
but I believe we're also seeing
induction of loxs 5 which is another QC
specific transcript right that
suppresses division of cells in the QC
so I think what we're seeing is
induction of QC identity in tissues
where it shouldn't be
present okay so the other thing we
promised you was that we could identify
candidate genes for Regulators or
affectors of cell cycle specific Pro um
processes and this is where our story
gets a little bit sad because we're just
starting to look at this but I don't
know so Phil took 15 different
homozygous exonic insertion lines
representing 10 of these iron induced
transcripts and none of them were mutant
for PCD program cell death and he took
seven exonic insertion lines
representing seven repressed transcript
and none of them were mutant for
PCD and then he just got a little
desperate and he took 11 genes that
govern already known to govern hypers
sensitive response and none of them were
mutant for PCD either so you know we
need to look more carefully at this but
no one's particularly motivated to
because this is this rather depressing
result in the beginning so the
conclusions for part two and I don't
think I can go on to part three but I do
want to show you just one picture Roots
can recover from massive doses of ir um
oh this is the early results so I
haven't I haven't discussed this yet the
transcriptional response is required H
this is all later so I'm going to go
into this um talking about day one a
little bit so this is things that happen
after day one so the root tip undergo
cell death in this programmed way at
later time points it spreads up the root
is going to have to recover because it
will at this dose recover and go on with
growth um as plant biologists you're
familiar with the QC which is a
population of about four cells that
basically provide identity to this but
as a DNA repair and Recovery person I
have always thought of the QC as a
population of cells that is
intentionally never dividing so that it
never has problems with DNA damage it's
not undergoing replication making
replication errors it's not cycling so
it's not so sensitive to double Stone
breaks and it's there to replace these
cells which are foolish enough to be
dividing right so so that's a great
reason to have a quiescent center but
what I'm seeing when I look at the
expression of qci identity after
radiation makes me think that perhaps
this is incorrect so just to move on
with
this okay
if we look at a wild type plant we give
it 150 gr of radiation we watch the root
growth over the days there's still
growth During the period after radiation
because most of the growth is elongation
you don't need to supply new cells you
run out of new cells by then the
meristem starts growing again and you
get root growth again if you look at a
SOG
mutant at this dose the sog mutant
actually stops growing and doesn't
recover so Saga is doing something
that's important for Recovery of the
root tip 24 hours after 150 gray you can
see that um wild type has experienced a
fair amount of cell death at this
particular dose this particular
experiment we can still see the QC in
these root tips not getting cell death
and this is the complemented line just a
control to show you that's really a San
dependent effect if we look 3 days after
150 gray we're starting to get
elongation of these cells as the
differentiations Z proceeds down towards
the root tip we can no longer see the QC
in Wild type so this structure is
getting messed up still looks nice and
organized in SOG and if you put them on
constitutive rather than acute DNA
damaging agent SOG looks lovely compared
with wild type so it maintains its root
shape and again this complimented line
QC is gone we can't see
it if we look 5 days after we can still
see the QC and SOG we only see a mess in
these root tips and then 7 days after
the situation changes the root tip has
recovered in Wild type it's
reestablished and has grown away from
all that big fat cell crap the root tip
is now growing again same thing here and
differentiation has proceeded all the
way down to the tip and SOG and it's not
going to be a marem
anymore all right so if you look at the
growth day after
day both of these things keep growing
and then they slow down when they
finally stop growing they produce a lot
of root hairs at this point it leaves
what we call a scar so you can tell
where they stopped and then as the days
go on a new maristone will be formed in
Wild type it has to reorganize itself
and then it'll grow away from all of
this mess giving you this growth curve
here interestingly if you look at
expression of walks five which is a QC
specific
Gene transcript what you see is that um
as the days proceed after radiation in
Wild type and we haven't looked at SOG
yet because we don't have the line yet
walk 5 expression spreads throughout the
root tip so it's as if all of these
cells are volunteering for the position
of new QC and when this root tip finally
reemerges you're back to having walks 5
expression only in those four cells so
somehow the QC is selecting among all
these potentially cra happy cells to
find perhaps a really good one that is
going to make up the new QC which is a
bit of a stretch but that's what they
seem to be doing okay so I
should just move on to thank the people
responsible for this so you may have met
Phil Conlin he's moved here in Mike
scandin lab just recently and he and
Victor were responsible for a lot of the
transcriptomics analysis but filled it
all the wet lab type
experiments and this is just to thank
the rest of my lab who's doing other
projects and other things that you can
ask me about too and of course I'd like
to thank the students again for inviting
me here it's been a pleasure so
far this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu