this is a production of Cornell
University um hope you're all having a
wonderful amazing Wednesday I'm L Lu VI
I'm the organizer of the webinar this
year I am a third year PhD candidate in
the Larry Smart Lab at cornal University
where I'm working with on Father M we
have two featur speak ERS for today
Chadwick white and Kim Mayo they are
joining us from Colorado Chadwick white
is the chief Visionary officer Chief
Innovation officer and co-founder of
Neer Foods a leader in allergen free and
plant-based food and ingredient
Solutions with over 35 years of
experience in the food industry he holds
a master Baker certification and has
pioneered Innovations in gluten-free and
hemp-based
formulations chel with co-founded udis
glutenfree food growing it to over 125
million in Revenue before its
acquisition by Boulder Brands Kimberly
Mayo is an experienced registered
dietitian and accountant manager with a
strong background in nutrition science
and Regulatory Compliance within the cpg
fooding industry after working in
hospital and Community Education
settings she wanted to improve the food
options available on store for shelves
getting diagnosed with ciac disease in
2010 she only strengthened her passion
about improving uh the nutrient density
of gluten and allergen free foods which
began her path to working with depra
thank you for coming before they start
sharing their experiences and insights I
want to remind everyone to use the chat
for greetings and other Communications
but please submit the questions for
child we and Kim using the Q&amp;A bottom
The Talk would last approximately 30
minutes followed by a Q&amp;A session we'll
then wrap up and thank them for their
time and insights all webinars are
recorded and uploaded to our school of
Integrative PL science sips YouTube
channel feel free to check out the
previous ones sh we Kim our virtual
stage is all
yours hi everyone thank you for
attending this is exciting for us I I
have a lot to share
uh on hemp and and how it performs in
food um seems to be a new category for
many I think the the features and you
know the understanding and the the
interest in hemp in the past has been
around canabo and fiber so I'm excited
to show what this what the seed the
protein specifically from the seed does
in food
formulations um and again I'm I'm
incredibly excited about this it's it's
a an amazingly versatile ingredient I'm
going to uh start sharing my screen I'm
kind of go through presentation that we
put together I'm going to kind of just
you know it's mostly a collection of
photographs and uh I'm going to just
start explaining a little bit about what
we do
so um as Lucia had mentioned I'm a
certified Master Baker um I've been in
the bakery industry for 37 years this
year
and
um I started off in conventional Bakery
uh in 1998 I got certified got my
certification as a master Baker 2001 I
moved to Colorado a couple years later I
met a woman with severe food
allergies and she introduced me to the
free from Market uh previous to that I
had really had no exposure to it um I
specialized in product development so I
immediately started formulating products
for her and for her children who were
both Celiac uh a few years later you
know this this really changed the course
of my career um a couple years later I
had a full Suite of formulations and uh
started looking for business partners to
bring those to Market met a couple of
guys here in Colorado udy and eai Baron
and we started a company called gluten
ud's gluten-free foods um and I learned
a tremendous amount during that
experience uh one was that we really
needed to work more on the specific
ingredients available for bakers baking
gluten-free products the the ingredients
had to be designed specifically for
gluten-free uh the other thing was that
we needed much better nutrition and and
the formulations at that time even
though they were decent uh they they
they could be better and so you know
post udis we I started a company called
gluten-free baking solutions that was in
2016 that company and a couple of others
a sprouting and malting Company and a
blending company all got rolled together
into uh what is today Nea Foods so nepra
uh is actually an adjective it is
Esperanto uh it means absolutely
essential and that's really how we view
what we do every single day we we don't
just create ingredients for the greater
Market we also create formulations and
we and we really center around better
for you and and uh you know nutritious
eating so with me today is Kim she is
our registered dietitian our project
manager our account manager our
everything uh she is actually our
internal rock star so I'm super excited
to have her here I'll go through some of
the applications of the hemp in food and
then I'll pass it over to to Kim at the
last half to uh to kind of discuss the
the nutrition a little bit more at
length because there's a lot to unpack
there as well
so obviously we'll go over these points
here in just a few minutes um you know
what our general mission is you know why
we're so interested in hemp uh and then
some of the the characteristics of hemp
it's versatility you know the
functionality what foods it's really
suited well for uh and then some cpg
brands that are starting to launch into
the market today with hemp included and
uh and then of course those things that
Kim will address the the nutrition and
then some of the other things that we'd
love to see moving forward from
institutions like Cornell uh as they put
together their hemp programs we'd have
some we have some requests some things
that we would like to see uh you know
done in the
future so
nepra you know we we really are
interested in making food for everyone
uh allergen-free foods that taste great
that that you know that there's nothing
lacking right we don't want our
consumers to feel like you know they're
they're they're getting less and so we
really concentrated on worldclass Foods
um my brother for instance is a port is
a part of our company and he was a sue
chef at The French Laundry and we've
taken some of that high level expertise
and Incorporated that into what we do uh
you know every day here in terms of
developing uh new food
products the similarly
um you know we we develop formulations
for Brands globally and our primary
objective is to make these Foods
absolutely delicious but then to back
that up with a really great nutritional
profile so that you know a lot of times
some of these individuals that have
celiac disease and some other autoimmune
diseases they they really are lacking
and certain nutrients and and so we we
really make a strong effort to bring
these things incorporate them into the
foods that we're
producing so you know one of the bullet
points here deliver nutrition without
compromise and that's really that really
kind of sums it
up the other thing that we're really
doing that I think is important it's
this last bullet point it's
standardizing the ingredients that are
used in allergen-free baking um you
think about wheat flour for instance
wheat is highly standardized for protein
content quality of protein damage starch
levels enzyme activity all these you
know uh characteristics that become very
important for a for a food producer to
be able to produce consistent products
well many gluten-free ingredients don't
enjoy that same level of standardization
so nepra is really working on that as
well and hemp definitely plays a role
here and what we're trying to do is is
as we work through the various
extractions of hemp protein um we look
at what we can do to to uh standardize
that ingredient so that other food
producers know exactly how to use it and
and
uh and what forms of the protein they
should be looking for so why hemp uh I
think first of all you know I I would
say the nutrition is is outstanding Kim
will speak to that in a few minutes but
from my standpoint it's the absolute
versatility of the ingredient if you see
that
picture on the side here we've got uh a
few different items that in the middle
is a hemp heart flour that we produce
internally we got toasted hemp seeds we
have the hemp seed oil in the very back
and on the left is actually a hemp uh
margarine so lots of different
components within the seed itself um
we're talking about a pretty significant
amount of protein you've got a outer
shell uh once the shell has come off
then you've got a hemp heart the heart
itself is is about 50% oil it's about
34% protein and then you've got smaller
fractions of starch and fiber uh and
then you've got a really great Ash
content lots of
minerals what's interesting is that once
you get the oil out of the way once
you've extracted the oil and and how you
extract it too is very important um you
want to make sure that you're not
damaging the protein during the oil
extraction process uh a lot of a lot of
protein producers will use a screw press
with the hole on there's some some
negatives to doing that one you end up
the high pressures involved in those
systems denature the the hemp protein to
an extent um and then you get you know
tannins and uh chlorophyll and some
other things that that penetrate the
protein and those become very difficult
to get out and as a result the proteins
that you see in those types of systems
are green uh they are slightly bitter um
they have very limited functionality in
terms of of structure building property
those types of things and as as a
consequence they don't tend to be very
usable in Food Systems and so what we've
really done is identify the best ways to
extract the protein and uh and and
enhance it its
functionality so what we're doing
basically is is dehulling the seed first
and then we're going through a uh
solvent-based ex we're going through a a
pressing uh stage uh kind of liquid if
Ying the the hearts and then we're going
through a separation process being being
highly cognizant of the uh proteins
functionality and trying to preserve
that the end result is a protein that is
white in color slightly sweet and nutty
and has this amazing functionality very
similar to whole eggs which is
incredible because it's that level of
functionality that will that will allow
for all the foods that that I'll kind of
go through um and we've kind of centered
on on Bakery items but we got a few
others in there as well
so because it's white in color obviously
there's you know no negative impact to a
bakery formulation uh I'm not turning my
my Bread's green which is good uh the
slight you know the the the very um
palatable flavor it's like when I say
sweet and nutty I mean it there's a
subtle sweetness to the protein uh it's
nutty and it's quite Pleasant just by
itself but again that really lends
itself well to formulation because you
don't have to cover over any odd flavors
I work with plant-based proteins across
the board potato protein uh canola
protein both of which taste terrible but
have great
functionality um you know you think
about P protein limited functionality
it's got a decent gel but but doesn't
have a lot of other uh properties tends
to be somewhat chalky um
you know soy obviously has some problems
and that uh you know it carries the
allergen
um you know these as as hemp relates to
back to each one of these uh in my
opinion it is the king and as we talk
about the hemp industry and where it's
going it is my humble opinion that uh
that uh hemp protein and hemp foods will
be the first multi-billion dollar hemp
industry indry um and I think and I hope
that that some of these images and some
of this conversation really kind of
illustrate why that is or why I think
that will be so here in these in these
pictures we've got on the left here
we've got a textured hemp protein that
we've manufactured if you look so this
is this is High Press Extrusion this is
just hemp by itself and when you extru
the hemp you can see that it forms these
really nice textures uh when this is pre
when this is wet again uh those textures
are very reminiscent of chicken
structures like chicken protein
structures um also interestingly because
of the and you know that we've got a
really fun fundamentally inhemp you've
got an amazing Amino
complex um that Amino complex is very
high in glutamine and glutamine as we
know is is the primary uh amino acid
responsible for Umami flavor so within
the hemp when we extrude it uh it sounds
like popcorn in the factory you know
it's like pop but it smells like turkey
and it's the most bizarre thing but when
you rehydrate this protein the natural
flavor is meat you can't identify what
it is but you want to call it a poultry
so it's very interesting from that
standpoint that kind of leads into the
next slide where we've made a
mayonnaise so
so this mayonnaise is really just hemp
it is hemp protein with hemp a clarified
hemp oil so we actually remove the gums
and waxes from the oil and then we we
create internally an enzyme hydrolized
hemp Amino that liquid amino we
standardize at 12% uh saline uh we can
dilute it down to about 6% and it'll
still be uh stable at room temperature
but that that uh that that Amino uh
liquid the Umami flavor is absolutely
outstanding it's amazing and so this
mayonnaise we add a little bit of that
uh hydrolized hemp Amino liquid back in
for some Umami flavor but then also to
satisfy the need for the salt in the
formula and then we add a little bit of
vinegar and lemon juice uh just to you
know bring the acidity down a little bit
the result is a product that tastes just
like helman's mayonnaise it is
absolutely incredible the flavor is so
good and this picture also has our
gluten-free bread uh featured that bread
we use the hemp protein as the primary
egg replacement of course in gluten-free
baking we don't have gluten obviously
and so we end up usually um using eggs
for for the the the protein
structure excuse me so hemp because it
replaces eggs in literally every Bakery
formula that I've tried it in um it it
does an amazing job of of uh helping
create this backbone and this structure
further comment here that I think is is
very cool and important to
Bakers egg whites when if I were to use
uh egg whites in this formulation for
our bread um and I should back up a
little bit we have a we have a we have a
gluten-free bread technology that we've
developed that uses some some of our
proprietary starches and some of our
other ingredients but then it also uses
our hemp protein egg
replacers if I were to make that
formulation with egg whites that product
would only get about 21 days of ambient
shelf life stay soft and flexible but
the egg whites actually have a drying
effect on the crumb structure by using
hemp protein I'm able to get an
additional 10 days of shelf life out of
that product primarily because of the
globular nature of the uh of the hemp
hemp protein is roughly 65% globulin uh
specific globular protein called IND
destine and 35%
albumin the albumin and the globulins
are both highly soluble uh in
combination you know the albumin's fully
soluble the the globulins to the to
about 70 so percent give or take uh but
be because the globular proteins are so
efficient at binding water that that
moisture is bound up in the product for
a long period of time one of the other
things that we're finding is that the
protein structures actually help
encapsulate some of the starch the
starches and prevent retrogradation so
very very
interesting the next slide over the next
picture is a hemp milk that we've made
and what I wanted to illustrate here was
the uh the the foam that could be
created uh through steaming so you make
a hemp milk not only is it incredibly
neutral in its flavor very very Dairy
reminiscent um
there's the uh I was going to say there
was we've got some versions that have a
little bit of residual oil in them as
well and they have a wonderful creamy
flavor that kind of is just again very
Dairy like um hemp oil the the U uh
specific oils in hemp it's a very low
molecular weight oil it's got It's a
very small molecule and and then uh
similar to Dairy oil you know Dairy
and so there's kind of a creamy effect
there that that you get that's really
quite nice
um moving over uh those pretzels what we
wanted to kind of demonstrate there was
the the impact of the amino acids in the
hemp on the mayard
reaction um as I make gluten-free
products obviously what I'm trying to do
is emulate wheat based products I want
uh I want the the consumer the person
eating eating this to really feel like
they're getting a a true a real piece of
bread and and so um the mayard reaction
is obviously a part of that and it's
just very interesting that that uh the
specific Amino complex in hemp ends up
creating very similar flavors and colors
to as to what you would see in a normal
wheat-based product uh to kind of
illustrate that further I got this next
slide um I was producing these pretzels
on a line in
Indiana and uh Plymouth Indiana
specifically and uh we were running
gluten-based pretzels on on one line and
gluten-free pretzels on a line in the
next room so I grabbed some of the
gluten-based pretzels those are the top
three you see in my hand there and yes
I'm not wearing gloves in the uh Factory
but that's okay um the bottom three are
are uh gluten fre and with the addition
of hemp and so the reason we were adding
hemp in this formula specifically was to
capitalize on its pseudo emulsification
properties um that prior slide that I
should have mentioned this before I'll
go back just very quickly to mention
this this mayonnaise down below where uh
I got this little caption 10 grams of
hemp protein is emulsifying in this case
300 gram of oil so the pseudo
emulsification properties of the hemp
are quite amazing and so in this
particular formula we were looking to
replace leian we wanted to get the
sunflower leian out and uh we wanted to
try to use hemp for that purpose so we
started at around two Bakers percent
which is about one one and a half% true
in this type of
formulation and um we we uh we got good
results there but we wanted to see how
little we could add and get the same
effect and so we started taking it down
we found that with only a half a percent
addition of hemp to that formula that we
ended up with a mayard reaction that was
almost identical to wheat and also a
flavor impact even at that smallest
level so this slide kind of speaking to
some of the functionality we we we test
and play with all different types of
hemp extractions and uh we've played
with all different types of uh solvents
uh we we favor obviously the clean
solvents uh you know we're we're going
down the road of organic EOL extraction
with a
refunctionalization step uh right behind
it uh the solvents do denature the
protein slightly as you extract it but
as long as they have not been heat
denatured they can be refunctionalized
and so we go through that process uh
We've also played with CO2 uh my
Discovery there has been that the high
pressures associated with liquefying the
the CO2 uh actually have a damaging
effect on the proteins so I do a little
bit less of that but those types of
processes that process in particular
yields a very bright white uh high
quality protein so nutritively it's
great in some cases I want less
functionality out of the hemp and so I
really kind of favor those types of
extractions for formulas where I'm
looking to build in nutrition but I
don't necessarily want those egg-like
you know structures to overpower the
formulation uh something like a pretzel
for instance where I want the starches
to really be the uh the focal point you
know for mouth feel and everything else
uh in in low pressure Extrusion systems
like that crackers and and pret pretzels
um you know too high of a protein
content can lead to a rather hard bite
and so I'm always trying to make these
I'm trying to balance these these uh
these these factors and effects and so a
form so a protein specific for that uh
you where where you're seeing a little
bit of protein denaturing I think is is
uh is is a good thing these images here
we're really just testing the foaming
capacity of the hemp uh we're testing
the gel strength uh after we've after
we've baked it and then we're performing
a hydration test so there's all these
little tests that we'll perform
internally uh and we've got various
pieces of equipment too that will really
U kind of Aid and assist in that so that
because you know at the end of the day
we're looking for consistent results
so these pictures all bread obviously um
the all of these formulations utilize
hemp primarily these are all
gluten-free uh and and they and they all
utilize the hemp primarily as the egg
replacer and we've we've got lots of
partner brands that are going to be
releasing products into the marketplace
uh this year and going into next year
that contain hemp so what's really
exciting is that you are going to be
seeing at Shelf multiple products with
hemp in the very very near future um and
and and it's it's kind of a cascading
effect as we introduce these ingredients
uh you know these variations of hemp
protein to specific manufacturers they
are finding that it is solving problems
for them um I mentioned the enhancement
to shelf life and the bread that's one
um but but there's but there's others as
well
and um I guess too I could I can mention
a little bit about you know relative
ratios of hemp and how much you add in
for those types of things if anybody's
got questions about that you can
certainly put it in the chat
um but uh I'll kind of talk through it a
little bit as well um I find that in
most formulations for bread I don't like
to go over about
20% uh hemp uh because it just ends up
being too much the globular protein uh
coagula at around
170° so higher than egg wood but uh but
this is good in gluten-free formulations
truly because I'll get additional
volume um up until the point that it
sets uh we do get good expansion in the
products uh but once the protein if it
at higher concentrations once that
protein starts to coagulate you do see a
a a slight reduction in volume as the
proteins kind of um Aggregate and
collapse a little bit
so um obviously we we have done just
about every type of Bakery product you
can imagine uh these tortilla chips are
actually mostly hemp and what we're
doing is we nixtamalize the hemp so
we're putting in a giant steep tanks
with calcium hydroxide uh there's not
much starch in in uh in the hemp to
swell but they do swell a little bit um
you know those relative percentages
about 5% starge 5% fiber give or take so
we do see some some swelling of the
starch uh and it does form a dough when
we subject it to the calcium hydroxide
the um the other interesting thing is
that
uh um it tends to uh uh well you get a
good amount of rology in the dough but
then you get this really nice flavor
development uh it's a very very cool
process these chips end up tasting very
similar to corn chips uh you don't get
the the corn flavor obviously but but
they're very sweet and nutty and and and
very neutral in their flavor over here
on the right you see a band full of uh
low press extruded pretzels uh they're
they're being cut with the guillotine on
the inside of the cage there and laying
down on the Belt these you'll see these
actual pretzels you'll see in a bag with
one of our uh Partners here in in
a in a couple of minutes one of the
slides um and we're excited because
again you know we're seeing hemp really
make its way into common
foods uh not you know there's no reason
to to necessarily call it out it's a
functional ingredient uh but we're using
it you know primarily for for these
specific you know structural
purposes foam stability this is
obviously a mering uh technically it's a
pavlova uh so we keep it a little bit
soft we it's an underbaked mering I say
I guess you could call it uh um if you
look at the the the mering on the Whisk
there uh you notice it's not as stiff as
egg whites and I think that really
speaks to the higher level of globulin
um it does you know it kind of sags a
little bit as we would say in the bakery
industry uh you know on the pictures on
the top right you see that I've kind of
piped it out and and I've used a star
tip to illustrate uh that that it kind
of just melts in a little bit it doesn't
really hold the peak um baking those
those uh that star pattern is kind of uh
disappeared entirely but if you look at
the bottom right picture you can see the
structure on the inside it is incredibly
delicious this is this formulation is
literally just hemp protein water and
sugar so um the Pavlova taste amazing
they look great uh they function for all
intents purposes identically to a to an
you know to their egg counterpart
just without the
allergen we heavily we're heavily into
pastas um we're actually looking at
bringing these products to Market
potentially under our own brand uh
future Endeavor uh but we've come up
with a really special formulation so
here on the left we've got a u uh kind
of a chowman if you will the noodles are
hemp this formulation of hemp pasta is
30 gram of protein per serving so on 100
gram dry basis uh you boil that 100 gram
it becomes 220 gram which is essentially
a full bowl of pasta that serving 100
grams is 30 gram of
protein uh only 30 net carbs and 20
grams of Prebiotic fiber has the same
alente chew as a regular wheat based
pasta and that is partially due to the
hemp protein that globular protein once
it's cooked gives you this amazing chew
the bite is phenomenal so that same chew
or that bite is communicated through
what looks to be pork on top of that
Chowan it's actually more hemp that's
our textured hemp protein in this case
we did Flavor it uh to taste more like
pork uh that was what we were going for
the center pictures there we've got a a
chicken crumbled um uh like enchilada uh
with actual hemp cheese on it as well
and then the tortilla itself we made
that with hemp the meatballs that you
see there those are lamb flavored uh
lamb and beef flavored but they are all
hemp um
so the again going back to the fact that
that uh you know when you texturize the
hemp it it forms these really
wonderful uh textures uh reminiscent of
meat structure we pair the hemp
sometimes with other proteins to achieve
various results in this case with the
meatballs we paired it with PE protein
where we wanted a little bit more of a a
firm bite less chicken-like more beef
likee so um you know it kind of speaks
to the again to the versatility of hemp
being able to stack it with other
proteins to achieve various results on
the right uh we have a picture of our
ravioli the the the shell of the ravioli
is again our our hemp pasta but on the
inside there we've got our hemp Rota
so you know going back to the glutamine
levels in hemp they sit at about 19% of
the total Amino complex Dairy proteins
are like
21% uh glutamine so you've got a lot of
crossover flavor with dairy products um
treated in the right way you can create
hemp based you know Dairy Alternatives
that are on are flavor-wise with dairy
uh really great levels of functionality
as I demonstrated before with that foam
you know you can do if a barista at
Starbucks got our hemp milk you would be
hard pressed to tell it wasn't really
just dairy milk uh and the foam is is
almost
identical
so kind of keep going on um we did a
dinner here in our Colorado location two
years ago um I believe two years ago
maybe
three been here a while uh we'll call it
two years ago um we we did an 11 course
fine dining experience entirely based on
hemp every single uh every single course
was primarily hemp obviously the focus
was hemp and so in this uh cucumber
salad we've got a breaded hemp goat
cheese quote unquote goat cheese uh
texture though and flavor came off
exactly like goat cheese it was really
really quite nice now we put sprouted
hemp seeds on top this uh shepherd's pie
this the the second one over we did what
we called an inside out shephard's pie
so it was the meat quote unquote meat on
the outside and it was stuffed with
mashed potatoes on the inside so we used
a uh Ron co-extruder a kayen to to uh to
to build these uh and then we made a
hemp demig gloss and uh and then put the
of course the the carrots and and peas
around the outside the tagat again it's
that hemp pasta uh we did shaved truffle
with this and um and then we did a hemp
cheese uh like a a crini hemp cheese you
know and then the cream sauce just
really really amazing flavors um hemp
lends itself well to uh to desserts as
well um that is a little miniature
p uh p is basically a puff pastry and uh
so this is a hemp based puff pastry
gluten-free and on the inside we did a
uh a Fran jaipan so frangipan is
normally made with almonds and sugar and
and you bake like a paste um in this
case I did a hemp FR Japan so I toasted
hemp seeds I combined them with sugar
and I and I made this uh particular
paste on the inside it was really really
wonderful uh and then you know aside
from the U the Cherry compot there in
the middle there's a a a hemp based
Chantell on the right and so again
speaking to the functionality of hemp
you this one protein can emulsify and
make a mayonnaise or it can be whipped
into a a whipped cream uh but then it
can also make a mering at the same time
and and uh I mean I challenge you to
find other proteins especially
plant-based proteins that will do that
again just speaking to the versatility
it's quite it's quite
amazing so these are some of the uh
products that we'll be seeing coming
into the market this
year uh you know again what hemp is
doing in every one of these is slightly
different uh in in the in the case of
the breads it's an egg replacer in the
case of the pasta It's a feature so
we're talking about a huge amount of
hemp and uh and then that hemp is is
specifically adding to the bite as well
as as obviously carrying a large portion
of the flavor and the the pasta eats so
well the flavor is so good uh but what
really rounds it out are those Beautiful
Textures that are REM reminiscent of a
real pasta um the other thing that's
interesting too is that most gluten-free
pastas tend to fall apart in the water
uh and they don't hold well they don't
retort well um and so what's very cool
about this pasta is that you can par
boil it so for a restaurant setting this
is incredibly important you can par boil
it you can pre-portion it and hold it
and then you can Flash it to order so a
restaurant could take it put it in the
fridge and when they have a customer
that requests a gluten-free pasta they
could bring this out and they could just
put it right into the sauce reheat and
then serve immediately fresh so uh
again just it's it's so cool that that a
single ingredient will will have so many
levels of
functionality um these pretzels you saw
on the uh the pretzel band a little bit
earlier uh and then we have our other
partner on the right that's that's
likewise released a pretzel but in this
case the hemp is really driving uh the
nutritional profile going back to the
fact that we don't want a lot of
functionality in that hemp we want it to
just have a neutral flavor and color and
then and then Supply you know a great
amount of nutrition we stacked various
uh proteins into that pretzel so that we
could uh uh so that we could kind of
increase the overall pcast hemp uh has
and Kim will speak to most of this but
uh you know hemp has a picast of about 0
65 so in many cases we'll want to Stack
other proteins in there uh to to make up
the difference in in
aminos and then yeah I'll let it I'll
let Kim go from here uh she'll really
just jump in and talk about the
nutrition awesome thank you I know I
already have questions for you and I get
to see you every day um but kind of
continuing on from this cpg highay over
the last couple years protein is really
King in the industry and along with
making protein content claims on the
front of packaging the FDA requires that
you calculate the percent daily value
and then put that on the nutrition fact
label on the back of your package and
the question kind of all ties into
protein quality and with this protein um
percent daily value chaek alluded to
pcast which stands for protein
digestibility corrected amino acid score
and so what's being corrected for is
really what still um ties into this
complete protein so hemp is considered a
complete protein Source meaning that it
contains all nine essential amino acids
so out of 20 total amino acids nine of
which have to be consumed from our diet
and protein quality now um is more than
just a number on the back of a package
or on the front panel it's really taking
two things into account it's taking into
account the composition of these
essential amino acids along with the
bioavailability and this digestibility
score that is um determine on how well
we're able to actually break down
process and utilize these amino acid
acids in our body so for hemp and chaak
already alluded to it a bit so um
they're able to calculate this
digestibility score so for a DEH hold or
a hemp heart it's around and the scale
is uh the max you can get is one so
dehle just regular hem seeds is at about
87 and then hemp heart flour hemp
proteins is around that 94 to 96 amount
as well so why does this matter it's
important because the fact that not all
proteins are considered complete
animal-based sources typically are but
plant proteins it varies and it lends to
this concept of protein stacking and how
can we combine different types of plant
proteins not only from a functional
perspective but also making sure that
we're getting um all these essential
amino acids for uh hemp in particular
our limiting amino acid is lysine and
the way I like to think about a limiting
amino acid because that's also what's
getting corrected in this digestibility
score to determine your percent daily
value is it um kind of like a car
analogy you could have 20 tires five
Motors four windshields but if you only
have one steering wheel production
ceases after that one car is made so if
you're not be able if you're not
ingesting enough of the essential amino
acids the building blocks for protein
really cease before they even begin so
this is really
critical um continuing on chaak has
already mentioned this ad destine so ad
destine is the globular seed storage
protein inherent to hemp and it's really
unique and special to hemp in particular
so it's about 65% um the remaining would
be that albumin and it the globular form
and chaak mentioned that there's some
around 70% solubility along with this
fact that it closely mimics the serum
globulins already in our blood so this
resemblance upon inest in makes it
easier for a body to actually break down
and therefore views it to be significant
significantly lower risk of an allergen
so now as of January 2025 Sesame is now
the ninth top allergen per the FDA and
it really limits some of these allergen
free and gluten-free options when you're
trying to create a nutrient-dense
delicious food product so this um the
globular nature of the protein
is beneficial on many different levels
and then we have a picture here on the
right which is our cold pressed hemp
heart oil that we make at our facility
and you can see it's a beautiful kind of
golden yellow color and hemp oil is a
polyunsaturated fat so due to the double
uh some of the double bonds throughout
the molecule it's a little bit more
susceptible to oxidation and rancidity
but of that fat content about 70% of
that is omegas and it's really wonderful
that a plant-based product is able to
contribute this much Omega to the
overall um kind of diet from a whole
food source and even better it has the
optimal ratio of Omega-3 to omega-6
fatty acids so that ratio ideally would
be one part omega-3 to around six part
Omega sixes typically in the western
diet it's been getting um pretty well
known for having elevated omega-6 levels
which tip your body more into a
pro-inflammatory State versus when you
consume you know that ideal ratio of
Omega-3s into a more not necessarily
anti-inflammatory but it's keeping that
inflammation at Bay some of the other
seed oils and um like sunflower oil for
example have about 14 Parts Omega 6 to
one part omega-3 so whether or not not
saying that it's bad but it does tip you
into that pro-inflammatory kind of
reaction because when you're eating
anything um with omegas you're only
really able to uh convert 16 to 20%
different than an animal play u Source
but for this situation you really want
to make sure that you're kind of
stacking those Omega-3s so that you're
able to keep your body in a less
inflamed State and then just due to that
sensitive nature of the oil the smoke
point is around 320 to 330 degrees
Fahrenheit and making it more of a
culinary based oil than something you'd
want to cook
with next SL please
please awesome and then this is one of
our favorite Graphics that we've done um
this is so the name of the pasta that we
had developed previously was called prop
pasta and I love this this graph because
it shows a great example of protein
stacking so in our hemp protein pasta
there's also PE protein so it's
comparing 100 grams of dried pot pasta
to 100 grams of chicken breast and you
can just see this amino acid composition
in general is pretty balanced so there
are ways that you can create a
plant-based product that is comparable
to the to um an animal Source
highlighting that glutamic acid and the
glutamine from the Flavor and Umami that
chaik mentioned some of the alanine is
really
great and uh in in lie of time we'll
just skip to the next slide as
well awesome and then real quick just
Trends and claims that are typical now
in in the food and SE BG kosher Halal
actually consumers tend to view uh a
product that's kosher to inherently be
more healthy whether or not that's true
it's regardless um keto low carb you
know seed oil free vegan um but one one
of the topics that is near and dear to
us is this contamination on the field
for gluten so in our line of work we're
always trying to be you know very
mindful of the parts per million that
are that of the of the hemp that we're
getting that we're receiving so
typically it's getting
cross-contaminated or the field is
getting rotated with rye wheat and
barley so just being very aware as a
grower and a farmer of hemp that we here
at nepra and other food companies really
um value a gluten-free Source or happy
to to walk through and talk about how we
might be able to collaborate on
something like
this which lends to our uh kind of
called action so we would love for you
to continue supporting brands that are
using hemp in the marketplace some of
which we were featured today educate
others about the benefits of industrial
hemp both functionally and nutrition
wise and then this last one of research
roles focus on hempy genetics is
something that is also uh really
important for us because not only are
there is there opportunities to create
hemp genetics that maybe are higher in
protein but also kind of highlight some
other varietals and chff do you have
anything to to add about the genetic
component yeah I think crop yield is a
big one you know we've we've done so
much genetic work around cannabinoids
and so much work around fiber and and
you know some great fiber varietals out
there but they all only produce around
you know 12 to to 1,700 pounds of grain
per acre you know we really need
varietals that are producing that are
pushing the limit and producing closer
to like 3200 to 4,000 pounds of grain
per acre and I think that at those
levels we would really see the economics
begin to open up uh so obviously we're
very interested in that but we're
interested in working with groups that
have these capabilities to to uh to
really start pushing what you know we
need food varietals that's really what
we need we we need to improve on the
size of the seed if possible um you know
get get larger size more consistent seed
uh possibly even playing with protein
ratios and in the in the seed you know
if we can get higher levels of protein
offsetting the oil perhaps you know then
the uh the yields of protein uh will be
higher and the economics come down
further you know one of the things we
didn't really talk about is the price of
hemp compared to other proteins and uh P
protein for instance is you know won't
talk about soy because soy is subsidized
right so it's kind of artificially low
price if you ask me and then you got
huge factories built for soy we don't
really see that with the other
plant-based proteins except for p p is
really you know uh mass-produced but PE
protein is about
$350 to
$3.75 pound and we need hemp to be on
the same level and this is really kind
of how we do it we do it through
genetics and we do it through uh
agricultural processes that are that are
uh you know prone or capable of of
yielding higher levels or higher amounts
of
grain and that is it so I now now we'll
talk but of course I talk too much so we
don't have very many questions we can
answer at this point but uh
uh let's see we got the uh
Q&amp;A yeah we have 14 questions right now
so please go
ahead so first question is since it's
gluten-free does it rise uh like bread
and wheat the answer is
no um it it does because of it you know
similarity to to the functionality of
eggs you could pre-ip it you could add
it into a batter based formula and and
you could get uh you know some pretty
great volume that way uh but typically
speaking no it just it it forms a rigid
structure within the bread kind of
bolstering and holding up the uh uh you
know the starches as they cool so you
think about starches they gel anywhere
between 165 and 175° F uh they're
complet completely gelled by around 180
as they come out as the bread comes out
of the oven it's really quite soft and
those because because there's no gluten
in a gluten-free bread uh you you're
lacking the structure so that protein
structure sets in a rigid form and it
prevents the starches from collapsing
back on themselves so that's really the
benefit
there um so have you experimented with
hemp in a bulk ferment process similar
to sourdough yes and the flavor results
are amazing I would definitely uh I
would definitely try that such a mild
flavored protein it suits itself very
well but there's some interesting
flavors that are developed in this case
so I would definitely try it um really
really Pleasant
sour uh it's this next question have you
found that any that some industrial hemp
seed varials are better than others
uh you know
yes and no um we tend to play mostly
with phola uh some of our Canadian
partners are producing x
x59 uh you know we've gotten carola
we've gotten a few others that are that
are uh they all seem to be fairly
similar I've you know this is again I
think a a huge body of work that needs
to be done as we start identifying you
know all of these strains which ones and
by the way they might not be hemp
strains that have the best levels of
function ity I have seen some marijuana
strains that the seeds have incredible
functionality so what kind of future
work could really be done around
hybridizing and you know first of all
isolating the proteins making a judgment
around functionality chasing down which
attributes might be the best for food
systems and then uh and then and then
hybridizing you know to to to get the
appropriate uh genetics in the field for
these purposes
um next question how much time does it
take for you guys to create formulations
for other companies it's dependent on
the formula we have thousands of
formulas in whole just waiting for
somebody to ask us for one so sometimes
uh those formulations will be you know
turned around very quickly average time
I would say is probably you know three
to six months to really go through the
entire process if you want to include
scale up in a factory and those types of
things there's additional time that's
tacked onto that and it's really just a
it's a matter of going back and forth
and and making sure that you know the
the customer is happy with the the
formulation first and foremost and then
it goes into Consumer Testing and that's
where a lot of the tweaking is done and
then of course there's final tweaking
done at at the
factory oh so what hemp seed
characteristics would I like uh hemp
breeders to focus on I've kind of said
some of this already but um I'm protein
content protein quality seed size yield
per acreage those are I think the big
ones uh I'm very interested in the oil
too I'm not trying to Discount the oil
at all but you know we use a lot less of
the oil than we do of the uh the protein
for our specific purposes
so
um so this
question uh did you say that the hemp
flowers derived from the hemp hearts uh
yes it is and uh it's not boiled and
separated we don't want to to cook the
Protein or else it's denatured so we
want to gently separate the two so we
put them in a uh we run it through a
colloidal Mill basically uh or sheer
mixer and then we we uh you know create
essentially a wet puree of of hemp uh
hemp solids and water and then of course
the oil starts to separate and then we
use enzymes to further get out uh
release the oil we we um you know these
are all done at lower temperatures right
because we're trying to maintain the
functionality of the protein
and so it's a very gentle process that
we're going through and that's really
what's important here uh try to treat
the pro the protein
appropriately uh separating the ad
destine and albumin well I don't really
go through that separation but we've
talked about it albin's water soluble so
there's that but ad destine is salt
soluble so you can actually extract the
you can get the Destin to bind to the
salts and then the the album will stay
um it'll precipitate out at that point
you can separate it the albumin stays in
the water and then you can go through a
drying process for that if you wish so
that's the simp that's the simple answer
it's a little more complicated than that
but uh um salt precipitation is the
answer so um what is the Omega 3 to6
ratio it's about 3: one uh so you got
three parts LA to uh one part
ala a menu manufacture the hemp oil and
protein I also make the hemp feed for
laying hands oh cool
um I have not really delved into animal
nutrition so I don't I'm not very well
equipped to answer that question
unfortunately uh but I've got some
friends in the San Louis Valley here in
Colorado that are doing uh that are
making feed for hens and uh uh they're
growing varietal of phola so and then uh
we've got a company here in colge New
West genetics and they have introduced a
new strain into the marketplace called
amplify and I've seen lots of farmers in
the State trying to play with that one
so I think it's just you know trying to
identify new varials is is going to be
important um specifically too for the
latitudes where these Pro these products
are being
grown
um so when I uh this question is good
because I mentioned 4,000 pounds of
grain per acre so that is for the whole
grain ho on assuming that once we dehull
it you know we're losing about 40 to 50%
of the weight uh I'd like to see a
larger seed size so that that ratio goes
down so we're getting larger hearts in
relation to the to the hole I think
that's very important um but then I
expect I uh uh you know based on that
then we're looking at about once we've
taken the oil out which is again 50% of
the heart so you know you're losing 40
to 50% of the hull off the top the
weight there and then you're taking half
of the uh heart is oil so you're only
left with about 34% protein at the end
of it so those are the ratios that I'd
like to see increased more
protein yeah so this question is around
U the uh the egg market and the Aven flu
and are we seeing ingredient demand for
egg replacement yes that is the short
answer yes we are and you know know that
hemp will do this effectively and you
know you can modify uh you there's
ultrasonic you know cross linking there
there's other processes for
cross-linking uh you know proteins and
and uh you can fully solubilize the hemp
there's a lot of really cool things that
you can do with it to enhance the level
of functionality and make it uh better
for egg replacement and we we have not
really concentrated very much on this
but we have played a little bit around
actual egg replacement for home Cooks uh
being able to form a liquid similar to
like just eggs uh formulation they use
of course mung bean Protein that's been
hydrolized um we have played a little
bit with hemp proteins in this regard
and we've had amazing results uh really
really great textures soft creamy gels
that uh that have a very very pleasant
flavor at the same time without any uh
flavor
additions um the highest cooking
temperature for Powder and oil with the
oil I'd be very careful I would not deep
fry in it to to uh to cook with it is
fine just try to stay within that you
know stay below the smoke point um again
that smoke point is around 320 to 330
degrees so Fahrenheit so uh we want to
make sure that you know it stays below
that or else you start damaging the
omegas and that's not good so
um the uh the the the protein itself
uh coagulates around 170 degrees F uh
so um I wouldn't say that there's a
highend you just be concerned about
burning I think of baked goods in the
oven you know they'd get a little too
dark if you're not
careful
um and uh yeah that's about it so I see
a question around working with nihc no
we are not currently but we do have lots
of projects with you know in official
capacities that we're following up on
and obviously we're really trying to
drive the hemp industry here we really
want to see the greater industry come
into its own um you know I want grain at
good prices that's what I want and
today's prices make it very difficult to
uh to get the protein extracted in an in
an economical way you know that I have
to be highly cognizant as a product
developer of what the Shelf price of you
know the Consumer Price of these
finished goods is going to be and if and
if a protein is too expensive I just
simply can't use it uh at least not to
the degree that I would like to every
ingredient that you use has its own
relative percentage with it with which
it's used in a formulation right and so
with hemp I like it to be around that
30% value goes all the way down to like
you know half a percent as I showed in
the example uh using it to improve the
mayard reaction but um you know if if I
have a formulation where it demands 30%
hemp I can't put it in there if it's 15
bucks a pound so you know if I can get
it down closer to the price of PE
Protein that's that's really that's the
goal well thank you so much for this
amazing talk and for answering all of
our questions we are wrapping up for
today's today's webinar it has been
recorded and we will upload it to our
school of Integrative T science
sips YouTube channel and I wish all of
you a great rest of the week thank
you this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu