plenty of gardening is probably one of
the most important parts of
developing a garden location is
important what you want to grow is
important he brainstormed with the
community what do you want to grow how
do you want to grow what foods do you
want it fosters a culture of learning at
all levels everyone doesn't learn the
same way so we have to honor that
respect that and going into a community
and playing the garden around those
principles and understanding and you're
using physical soil but you also have
this community soil that also has to be
taken care of and continuously created
and recreated I
think the most important part of the
garden is ensuring that the food is what
the community needs and the food is what
they want and then it's our job to make
sure that we provide like a design or
help them design it or exposing the
different designs with them choose what
design because the garden has to be well
designed to make sure we get the most
food out of it so this is also something
important to see the organization of a
community garden because this is
something that a facilitator would help
a community develop as in they would
help the community figure out how they
want something plots who wants to plant
word plant where actually sit down with
the community develop their own rules
and regulations although also if you're
in a city or in a certain County or a
town or community that already
regulations around land use so but still
trailer can help a community understand
the rules and regulations around land
use then also help them decide on how
they want to plan their garden and
organize these habits again this is a
like a facilitation method as in your
facilitating I'm a process between the
community and also the county in the
city in which it lives in and also the
structure and design of its ultimate
garden
so if you already have a site available
you use that site and you grow on that
site but if you're going into a
community where they want to brainstorm
sites visibility is very important
because you want to attract diverse
people diverse communities and you want
to create again you're creating a space
for people to learn from each other as
well so ability is very important but do
you want to go behind the tractor you
think about accessibility and if a
community accesses a certain space
easier than other spaces you want to
choose an easier space to access cuz
food access is not only just about
social access but it's also about
physical access as well
you