this is a production of Cornell
University and uh thank you for the
invitation to uh to be here today um and
for letting me choose my own topic to
speak about because those of you who
know me probably know that for much of
the past decade I've really work mainly
on irrigation control my students like
to say that I'm a control freak I've
been controlling irrigation I don't want
to stop there I now want to control
light and I want to control light in a
smarter way than what we have done in
the last uh much of my work was inspired
by a book that was published in 2011 I
think it's an interesting book it is
full of uh vague claims uh poor
understanding of PL science but it
inspired a lot of people and quite
frankly the book was written by Dixon
desier we may not agree with the claims
that he makes but I think we should
thank him for putting controlled
environment agriculture on the Forefront
of night of of a national discussion
about how we are going to grow food in
the future and so I think because he is
incredible at PR there are lots of uh
people who are really interested in
vertical farms in producing food in
places where we may or may not be able
to grow food efficiently but it has
generated a lot of research
opportunities if nothing else I think
the people were probably most fascinated
with vertical Farms were Architects
because as soon as this book came out
architect started architect started
making beautiful designs for what
vertical Farms should look like and it
is actually a lot of fun to just Google
images for vertical Farms because they
are absolutely beautiful um they
probably don't work but I would love to
see this building right here wouldn't
that be cool to be able to visit that um
let's hope someone is going to invest in
that thing and make it happen um German
engine Engineers not architect they took
a slightly more pragmatic approach to
what it would take to actually run a
vertical farm so they came up with this
design it is not nearly as pretty but
they did all of the engineering to try
to figure out what it would actually
take to build a large vertical farm and
produce food year round in a facility
like that so this vertical Farm has a
footprint of 44 by 44 uh met it is 37
floors tall and um they um probably over
engineered the building since these are
aerospace engineers and they do like to
over engineer things but I looked then
at how much does it cost to build this
and this building would be a little bit
over $300 million so we need a
substantial investor to be able to make
that happen but what I was more
interested in is uh the analysis that
they did on what it takes to actually
run that facility on a year-to-year
basis so it turns out that the power
consumption for this veral farm would be
400,000 kilowatt kilowatt hours per day
and it would cost about 32 to 35 million
these values here are in Euros a year to
pay for the power for this electricity
now this number probably doesn't mean a
whole lot to you but 400,000 kilowatt
hours a day is pretty much when you
compare that to a household a typical
household is about 30 kilowatt hours per
day and it turns out that this number
right here is probably pretty close to
the power consumption of Etha a c size
so that's what it takes to run this one
vertical farm so there is a tremendous
amount of power that you need to do this
and much of the cost of running these
things 60% is in power consumption their
calculations show that half of this 30%
of total operating cost was to run the
LEDs much of the rest U of the power use
would be for uh air conditioning and
part of that air conditioning is is
needed to remove the heat that you
actually get from the LEDs so in reality
um the cost of running lights is
probably about 40 to 50% of the total
cost to run a facility like this and
it's a lot of
money um my research isn't just limited
to Vertical Farms this is an example of
a small vertical farm that is actually
just outside of um uh Atlanta that are
close to the airport they located next
to the airport because they get
naturally 800 PS per million CO2 there
apparently just from the airplanes
taking off it's pretty amazing how much
CO2 that generates so they uh typically
use very little CO2 enrichment they
don't have to but so you can see here
that they're working with fluorescent
lights they grow these plants under
amazingly low light levels but still for
them um the light is a big cost for them
um in green houses worst case scenario
you you may be spending up to about $500
a day on the power to run supplemental
Lighting in the greenhouse so this too
when you add that up over the course of
a year um that can be a substantial
amount of money just last week I was in
a 100 acre
greenhouse um where they use
supplemental lighting I don't know what
the power bill is but they spend
millions of dollars a year on
electricity
uh for the lighting um so it can be
expensive so people think that LEDs are
the solution to everything um and the
question is are LEDs the solution to um
solve these lighting issues and
controlled environment agriculture first
of all when people tell you that LEDs
don't generate heat just laugh just
start laughing right away you hear that
claim a lot it's just not possible
so LEDs uh good LEDs right now I think
are 30 maybe 40% efficient that means
that's the energy that gets converted
into light all of that other energy is
going to have to go somewhere that is
basic physics so all that other energy
is heat that gets
generated um the difference between LEDs
and most other lights are that we
normally use is that the LED light
itself you can get really close to it it
doesn't generate a lot of heat it's the
electronics on the back side of the LED
where the heat is generated and that
heat you actually have to remove if you
don't remove that an LED will burn up in
a matter of probably milliseconds if not
seconds um so LEDs have been around for
a while the two green lights show
different kinds of LEDs right here but
they have really become more prevalent
in the last 5 to 10 years and one reason
that I have become so much more common
than they used to be sorry is that the
efficiency of LEDs has rapidly increased
so it is a rapidly evolving
technology and right now people may
argue about whether they are more
efficient or equally efficient as the
best high pressure sodium lights that
are out on the market there may not be
much of a difference in efficiency at
this point but led technology since it
is still relatively new is likely to
become substantially more efficient than
any other light source we have uh right
now so that makes it a good choice
potentially for supplemental lighting or
for sour Source lighting where you grow
plans in a completely enclosed
environment so another advantage in
addition to the efficiency is that LEDs
if you use them correctly they can last
a very long time and that using them
correctly is mainly depending on making
sure they don't get more power than they
should because that will quickly wear
them out and make sure that they cool
that they are cooled appropriately I
mentioned previously that the light
itself does not get hot so that means
that you can have these light these
lights very close to the canopy or you
can even put them inside of the canopy
so this is a picture of Philips light
bars where they put them inside of a
tomato crop and it doesn't burn the
leaves so that's that is a big
difference compared to the more
traditional high-intensity discharge
lights that we've always used in um in
green houses another advantage of this
is that this actually allows you to get
light into the bottom part of the canopy
when you use uh traditional
high-intensity discharge lights you
would have your light somewhere above
the canopy obviously off the picture
here that light is coming down but it's
going to be absorbed almost entirely by
the leaves in the top of the canopy so
this is a way to get a more even light
distribution and that should help
overall canopy
photosynthesis there is a drawback to
LEDs and they are still very expensive
they are getting cheaper they are
continuously getting cheaper but right
now the question of whether or not it is
actually cost effective to
replace um high-intensity discharge
lights with LEDs is a pretty tough
question to answer do you get enough
benefits from them to make it worthwhile
to make that
Replacements but we are still in many
cases when I look at LED research we are
using LEDs as if they are just a
replacement for traditional lights and
LEDs have much more capability than a
high press sodium or a metal halight
light you can get them in pretty much
any spectrum that you want but what I am
most interested in is controlling the
light levels that we get from the LED
lights and matching that light level to
the physiological ability of the plants
to actually use that light so it turns
out that controlling in LEDs is actually
very easy and very cheap it's not often
that you have that combination um the
investment is practically nothing if you
want to do this so with LEDs one thing
that we can do is we can very easily
control the frequency at which they turn
on and off and you probably don't
realize that but the standard demo that
you may have in this room or that you
may have at home and light dmer actually
does the same thing it turns off the
current to your light bulb on and off um
at a high frequency we can tell that
because it goes so fast that our our
eyes cannot detect it but so with LEDs
we can turn these lights on and off but
in addition to that what we can do then
is we can control the duty cycle of the
LEDs so what that means is within one on
off cycle so this is off on and off
again how long are these LEDs actually
on so in this example here we have a 50%
duty cycle and and that basically gives
us effectively half of the light output
that you get from when the LEDs are on
fulltime so this would be a medium light
level if we go to a 10% duty cycle the
LEDs are only on a small um amount of
the time and you get a much lower light
level and then likewise if you increase
the duty cycle you get higher light
levels so adjusting that duty cycle is
really easy I didn't realize that this
until I as an engineer if he could build
a board for me and he said well yes I
could but I'll just have an undergrad
put it together for you um apparently it
is that
complicated um so sometimes it is good
to talk to
Engineers is Lou
here um so what what I am focused on is
what I want to do is to optimize the
light use efficiency so I'm going to go
through the physiology of what actually
happens to light when you are providing
light to a cross prop and then that will
get us to how we are using that um plant
physi plant physiological background to
actually control the lights so
ultimately what really needs to happen
in the light reactions of photosynthesis
is that we have to make nadph and
ATP plants don't use light very
efficiently necessarily sometimes they
do sometimes they they don't it largely
depends on how much light you give them
the more light you give a plant the less
efficiently the plant is actually using
that light but the way this works um in
the chloroplast is that light gets
absorbed by chlorophyll molecules and
what hopefully will happen is that
excitation energy from that photon is
transferred from one chlorophyll to
another and ultimately to the reaction
Center of either photosystem one or
photos system 2 and there that energy
from that photon is used to move an
electron from one from a donor to an
acceptor and then there is a whole
electron transport chain that follows
this so this process is referred to as
photochemistry this is what we want to
happen with the light that is absorbed
by
leaves and when that happens so this
gives you a better idea of the overall
electron transport uh chain we have a
photon that comes in this case from the
Sun it reaches the reaction Center of
photos system to and then electron goes
from water it is transported initially
to this point and this is the rate
limiting step I'll come back to that
later this turns out to be important for
some of the work that we do um and if it
gets past this bottleneck then that
electron moves ultimately to nadph and
now we have reductant that gets produced
that can be used in the Kelvin cycle to
ultimately make carbohydrates at the
same time what is happening in this
process is that hydrogen actually moves
from the stroma into the Lumen and
hydrogen is produced from the splitting
of water right here so we got a pH
gradient across this membrane and that
that pH gradient is used right here to
make ATP so now we have nadph and ATP
and that is ultimately the energy that
is going to drive the Calin
cycle unfortunately not all of the light
that is absorbed by a leaf is actually
used for
photochemistry some of the light is
actually going to be converted into heat
and plants have the ability to control
how much of that light gets converted
into heat and that control is actually
based on that pH gradient that develops
across the phid membrane inside of the
chloroplast so we're moving hydrogens
into the Lumen if a plant can use all of
this hydrogen to make ATP then we don't
get much of a drop in PH right here but
if the hydrogen transport across this
membrane m braan is faster than the rate
at which that hydrogen can be used to
make ATP then we get a drop in PH right
here if that happens that triggers an
enzymatic activation with an enzyme
called VI violan and deepoxidase that
get activated by low PH inside of the
Lumen Viola zantin deepoxidase converts
Viola zantin which is a zenil pigment
that is present in the Chlor in the phid
membrane it converts to ananin and
subsequently to zantin and that
conversion is reversible when the pH
increases again the reason that this
conversion is important is that Viola
zantin is a pigment that helps
chloroplasts absorb light and transfer
that light to the reaction
centers when Viola lantin gets converted
into anos lantin or
zantin these two pigments actually act
very differently those two pigments
cause um the absorbed light energy to be
converted into heat they have an impact
on the surrounding chlorophyll molecules
and prevent chlorophyll molecules from
transferring that energy from one
chlorophyll molecule to another and
instead that energy now is lost as heat
that may seem like a bad thing but this
is a way that plants can protect
themselves from excess
light and then there is a third
potential fade for absorb light energy
and that is chlorophyll fluoresence this
doesn't seem to be something that is
actually actively controlled by plants
but it happens so um you cannot see it
but every plant that is exposed to light
is fluorescing it is giving off red
light with a wavelength of around 690
nanometers you actually can see it if
you get a green laser pointer and you
point that at a leaf you can see a
reddish glow where you hit that leaf
that is actually red photons coming from
that leaf after you give it only green
light um so chlorophyll fluoresence
turns out is actually really easy to
measure um there are very good
techniques out there you can buy the
equipment not necessarily cheap but it's
not difficult to do um so this is an
example here of a chlorophyll
fluorometer when we measure chlorophyll
fluoresence basically what we are
measuring is how much light is emitted
from that leaf um at a wavelength of
around 695 nanom and so this is light
that is emitted that photon is created
inside of the leaf it is not reflected
that's a very different thing and so to
measure that we typically measure the
fluoresence coming from the leaf under
ambient light conditions and then in
this picture right here you can see a
very bright spot right here where you
also measure the chlorophyll fluoresence
when you give the leaf an amount of life
that completely saturates all of the
photosystems in that little part of the
leaf um and from those measurements we
can actually calculate all kinds of
things and this is where we can get a
lot of in-depth physiological
information incredibly easily I'm still
always a bit dumbfounded when I think
about the biophysical processes that we
can measure so easily by shining a light
onto a leaf um so if you take these
measurements on a leaf that has been in
the dark fall while then you can measure
something called the maximum Quantum
yield of photos system too and that
indicates whether that leaf is healthy
or not whether photos system to in that
leaf has been damaged by heat excess
light salinity whatever it doesn't
matter but you can detect whether or not
was damage to photosystem too so for a
healthy leave you're typically looking
for a maximum Quantum yield of
0.82 what that value of 0.82 means is
that under those conditions that leaf
uses
82% of the light that it absorbs for
photochemistry for electron transport
and that's the process that we need to
get transpiration uh sorry to get
photosynthesis um we can take these same
measurements on a Lea that is exposed to
light and now we can measure the
intrinsic Quantum yield and light and
that is actually more interesting
because that actually tells us um under
let's say Greenhouse conditions if you
do this in a greenhouse you can measure
how efficiently that plant is using the
light that it is getting what fraction
of light that is absorbed by the leaf is
actually used for
photochemistry so that in principle is
something that we would like to be as
high as possible we want plants to use
light as efficiently um uh as possible
if we know the quantum yield of photo
system to the intrinsic Quantum yield we
can actually so that's going to be
abbreviated as F PS2 the efficiency of
photos system 2 we can calculate the
electron transport rate of photos system
2 because we know the efficiency with
which light is used we can very easily
measure the amount of Life of light that
is getting to the leaf and we typically
make the assumption that 84% of the
light that reaches a leaf is going to be
absorbed by that leaf that's a value
that is roughly accurate for a wide
range of different species and then we
multiply that by
0.5 and that is to account for the fact
that we have two photo systems and the
assumption is that half of the light is
going to photo system 2 half of the
light is going to photo system one and
then based on that um we can calculate
the electron transport rate in in that
leaf and so we got all of that basically
from Shining a light onto that leaf and
measuring how much fluoresence is
emitted from that
leaf um the last parameter that I want
to talk about that we can calculate is
non-photochemical quenching
non-photochemical quenching is an
indicator of um the activity of the
zenil cycle how much of the absorbed
light energy is actually converted into
heat so non-photochemical quenching in
principle we would like to be low
because um if you get a lot of thermal
dissipation of light energy that means
that the efficiency of photos system to
is going down less light is actually
being used for
photochemistry and this is calculated
from the fluoresence that you measure
under that saturated light
bols um so our goal um we started on
this about a year and a half ago was to
develop a bio feedback system to measure
chlorophyll fluoresence then calculate
the electron transport rate and then
adjust the duty cycle of the LEDs to
maintain whatever electron transport
rate we program into the
system so before we started doing that
um we needed to understand just what
these plants were doing under LED light
so we had um an LED light right here
with a power supply a plant below it a
fluorometer for chlorophyl fluoresence
connected to a Data Logger the Data
Logger is controlling the fluorometer it
tells the fluorometer when to take a
measurement and it gets the data from
the fluorometer then and a light sensor
so that we can calculate the electron
transport
rate um so we just collected data under
staty State conditions where we turned
the LEDs on this is a picture of what it
looks like inside of the growth chamber
this is a very early picture you can
actually see the flickering nature of
the LEDs in that picture that's that was
captured by the camera right here the
stripes that you see is actually uh the
result of how the camera shutter is
detecting the light and this is our
rather ugly control system that runs the
whole system it's not pretty but it
works most of the time um so when we
Expos these plants this was with lce for
uh in this case this was 14 hours I
believe um to 400 micro moles of
photosynthetic uh Photon flux what we
see over the course of that period is
that the electron transport rate
gradually
decreases and the electron transport
rate decreases because the efficiency of
photosystem 2 decreases over time and
the efficiency of photos system 2
decreases because nonphotochemical
quenching is
upregulated um as these plant are
exposed to these relatively High light
levels for lettuce for a prolonged
period one thing that I do want to point
out though is that the scales here when
we look at the magnitude of the change
it's actually fairly small so we have
about a 5% change decrease in electron
transport rate the same for the
efficiency of photosystem 2 decreases by
about 5% npq those values are just
really difficult to interpret the number
itself doesn't mean a whole lot other
than that a higher value indicates that
more of the absorbed light is being
converted into heat Mark are those
24hour illuminations no these plans were
under 16 hours of light 8 hours of
dark um so when we look at the
relationship between non-photo
non-photochemical quenching and the
efficiency of photosystem too you see
that there is a pretty nice relationship
between the two so that uh is very
consistent with the idea that the
upregulation of the zenil cycle um is a
mechanism that decreases um the
efficiency of photos system too but at
the same time helps to protect the
plants against damage from exess light
so um we have we had this system where
we just had LEDs and we could measure
the plans below them so we had to adapt
this system to actually give us control
active control over the LED so the
engineer that I mentioned previously he
build us a duty cycle and frequency
control board um we can control that
from the Data Logger um by sending a
voltage signal using an analog output
module to the frequency control board
and now the data log
can tell the LED Lins basically what
duty cycle should you maintain what
should the frequency be and I'm not
going to talk about frequency that has
turned out to be a really boring aspect
of everything that we've done it had no
impact
whatsoever um but the duty cycle
basically when we adjust adjust the duty
cycle we're adjusting um the light level
that we give to the
plants um so the question was can we
maintain a steady electron transport
rate well well so we tried we actually
use a different lce plan this time but
we tried to maintain a stable electron
transport rate of 70 micr moles per
square meter per
second um so that the 70 micro moles of
electrons that move through one square
meter of leaf in 1 second and other than
the first few minutes we were actually
able to control that electron transport
rate I thought very nicely we were very
happy to see this as I'll point out in a
second it was amazingly easy to control
the electron transport rate at 70
micromoles though um but we tried
different levels so this is a similar
graph with higher uh electron transport
rates it's a little bit more noisy but
overall we still have very nice control
over the electron transport rate so we
have a way now that we can actually
control the rate of the light reactions
of photosynthesis by simply adjusting
the Duty Cycles of the the LEDs one of
the nice thing about fluoresence
measurements is that you get a lot of
physiological information so this showed
how the efficiency of photos system
2 changed with an electron transport
rate uh set at 70 and the efficiency of
photo system to is always the same there
was no down regulation um so what that
basically means is to maintain an
electron transport rate of 70 micromoles
per square meter per second if the
efficiency of the leaf doesn't change
you're always maintaining the same light
level and you're right there so you just
turn the lights on walk away and you're
actually fine um there wasn't any active
control needed one thing that was good
to see is that in the dark before and
after the trial we got Quantum yields of
over 0.8 and that indicates that these
leaves were actually healthy and not
damaged um during this process I'll get
back to that later but it turns out we
can actually cause severe damage to the
leaves just by taking these measurements
so when I add the quantum yield of
photos system to for the higher electron
transport rates to this first of all you
see that the efficiency is lower when
you have higher electron transport rates
when you give plant more light again
they use that light less efficiently so
we see a decrease in the quantum yield
of about 63 to maybe. 58 or so so the
plants at this higher light level they
become less and less efficient over time
so we also looked at nonphotochemical
quenching what we see at the lower
electron transport rate is that
non-photochemical quenching is very
boring and always the same when we go to
higher electron transport rates we have
more nonphotochemical quenching than at
lower electron transport rates because
we have more light and at the same time
we see that non-photochemical quenching
is upregulated over the course of this
day so the plant is inducing that zenil
cycle activity to help protect itself
from light
damage and then ultimately when we look
at the light levels that were needed to
maintain these electron transport rates
so this is the light that we needed over
this period to maintain an electron
transport rate of 70 so basically the
bio feedback system that we developed
didn't have to make any adjustments
whatsoever um a light level of 240 micro
m/ second was just um what these plans
needed um at the higher Target electron
transport rate of 100 though we see that
the biof feedback system needed to
upregulate the duty cycle and the light
level to maintain a stable rate of
electron
transport um so it showed us that the
system works that was exciting enough to
see in the early days of this work the
whole Lab group would come sit around
the lce plan in the lab and we would
just see what would happen next to the
light we had hooked up to it and it was
actually really fascinating to watch
that plant basically adjusting the light
to whatever level it
needed um we were also interested in
seeing what rates can we actually
achieve with this kind of a biof
feedback system um we worked with
different species I am only going to
talk about lce because the other species
didn't respond all that differently so
it's not that interesting and we were
interested in looking at what is the
physiology
that underlies the processes that U that
we see so our goal was to maintain the
electron transport rate of letters at
different levels over the course of a
day so we would increase the target
electron transport rate according to
this doted line that you see right here
going from initially zero up to 70 micro
mes per square me/ second and then back
down again because we had each Target
electron transport rate for only 1 hour
we were colle colting chlorophyll
fluoresence data more often in this
study to give the system enough time to
measure electron transport rate at a
particular level and to make the needed
adjustments in the duty cycle of the
LEDs to be able to maintain that
electron transport rate so here we were
measuring every 2 minutes um and so this
is the level of control that we got that
actually I thought looked pretty good
where we can maintain these def electron
transport rates pretty well so we
reached a limit right here this plan
simply couldn't do any more than this
and then going back down again we regain
control of the electron transport rate
but so one thing that you may notice
here hopefully you didn't this is what
things didn't work the maximum electron
transport rate that we got was only
about 60 micr mes per square meter per
second I just showed you in the previous
studies that we have no trouble
maintaining electron transport rates of
up to 100 micr per square met per
second um so when we looked at the light
levels that were needed to achieve these
electron transport rates we see a
stepwise pattern here we were maxing out
the light that we could get from the
LEDs and then it goes back down again
but one thing that is interesting in
this is that we needed a lot more light
to maintain a specific electron
transport rate during the first half of
the trial then during the second half of
the trial so both of these lines
indicate the light level needed to
maintain an electron transport rate
right here of 10 micr per square me/
second but at the end of the day we
needed almost twice as much light as we
did during the beginning of the
day and so our initial thought was well
this is upregulation of
non-photochemical quenching in these
plants we see the same difference here
at an uh electron transport rate of 50
this is the difference in light level
that we needed at this point in time
versus this point in
time um so these plant were becoming
less and less efficient over the course
of this uh 14-hour
period when we uh looked at the
efficiency of photosystem 2 or the
quantum yield we see that during the
initial part of that trial the quantum
yield dropped which is what we would
expect as you increase light levels the
efficiency of photos system 2 increases
but the efficiency did not really go up
a whole lot the second half of the trial
until we actually turned off the lights
so the efficiency of photosystem 2 here
did not recover and when I took a closer
look at these data another thing that I
noticed was that when we look at the
quantum yield this initial data right
here that's in the dark first of all
these values are pretty low we started
about 72 and then the efficiency of
photo system 2 was decreasing during
that initial hour in the dark so that
was actually indicating that our
measurements us measuring chlorophyll
fluoresence was changing the efficiency
of photosystem too and then at the end
of the trial when we measured the yield
again here in the dark we only got
Quantum yields of around 0.6 0.6 at the
end of the day and that told us we are
really damaging these leaves um so this
indicates a problem and we have now
narrowed that problem down to the fact
that we were simply measuring
chlorophyll fluoresence too often and
it's a saturating light pulse that has
an intensity of around 6,000 microl per
square meter per second that's a lot of
light that is three times of the maximum
amount of light that you may get during
the middle of summer and exposing that
leaf to that very high light level every
2 minutes was actually causing damage to
that leaf so when we look at the changes
in non-photochemical quenching we see
that non-photochemical quenching gets
upregulated as the light levels increase
and non-photochemical quenching is
actually nicely downregulated again as
we decrease light levels when we try to
maintain progressively lower electron
transport rates so non-photochemical
quenching could not explain the
difference that we saw in yield um early
in this trial versus late in this trial
this is another way to look at this so
the solid symbol right here they
indicate the relationship between
non-photochemical quenching and the
measured Quantum yield and we see this
is in the dark um the yield decreases as
nonphotochemical quenching increases but
then during the second half of the trial
as the light levels decrease
non-photochemical quenching decreases
again but the yield doesn't increase the
way you would expect um so after I
realized that this was was happening um
we had a lab meeting to talk about this
it took us a while to figure out what
was going on why do we not see that
yield recovering in the afternoon um
even though non-photochemical quenching
gets
downregulated and then we took a look at
the raw data from the fluoresence
measurements and so this is the
fluoresence that is measured under the
saturating light this is an indicator of
non-photochemical quenching the lower
this value the more non-photochemical
quenching and we see that uh stepwise
pattern that is associated with changes
in the electron transport rate changes
in light level and a recovery again
later in the day um the next line This
is the floressence signal that we
measured on these leaves under ambient
light conditions without the saturating
light pulse and what we saw early in the
day is that that fluorescence increase
and that is normal as light levels
increase inrease but during the second
half of the day that fluoresence didn't
decrease back down again that
fluoresence actually kept increasing and
this indicates damage that we had caused
to photosystem 2 by trying to measure
chlorophyll fluoresence more frequently
than these plants could handle so the
way that that damage happens is through
a process that is called photo inovation
so under normal conditions you have an
active photos system too that is capable
of uh taking an electron from water and
moving it on through the electron
transport
chain if you apply too much lie to
plants photos system 2 can actually
become inactivated and it is actually a
really ingenious mechanism through which
this
works so if you have too much light
basically what happens is that too many
electrons get taken from a water
molecule these electrons normally would
be moving through this electron
transport chain but they can't in this
case because there's so much light that
was not enough capacity that electron is
going to react with something and in
this case what happens is that in
photosystem 2 that excess energy is
actually specifically directed towards A
protein that is called the D1 protein
that protein gets damaged and the plant
can then take that protein out of the
reaction Center of photo system to and
put a new one in but this takes a few
hours so it is a slow repair process but
think about how genus this is when you
think about this in the context of your
car let's say you're driving your car
something goes wrong in the engine if
you had a smart engine that was as smart
as a plant that engine would direct
whatever is going wrong in that engine
to your first spark plug make that blow
up and all you need to do to repair it
is replace that spark plug no matter
what that is basically what plants have
done they direct all of that energy well
maybe not all but that directed energy
to the D1 protein and then the plant
essentially knows what it needs to
repair it's the D1 protein that needs to
be repaired and obviously plants have a
very efficient mechanism to repair that
protein because they know that that is
what uh is going to be damaged so we get
this photo inhibition plants can
reactivate uh photo system too but this
can be a matter of hours so what we saw
in our trials we think we're pretty
confident about this is photo inhibition
that was induced by those light pulses
so what we do know from these studies is
that we can control electron transport
rate over a wide range of different
levels and we can do it in many species
I haven't shown that here because it's
not really interesting to look at the
same graphs for different
species when we do get high electron
transport rates that is associated with
a low yield and high non-photochemical
quenching so um we also found that that
two frequent of measurements can result
in photo inhibition and what we do now
is we measure that fluoresence under
saturating light only once every 15
minutes and that seems to be fine we're
not seeing any damage from that but the
good thing is that we can actually see
photo inhibition happening if we take a
close enough look at the data because
that photo inhibition should be evident
from an upward Trend in the basal
fluoresence that you're measuring so
this was part of uh of what we've been
working on we have a biof feedback
system and now that we understand the
damage that we get from the measurements
um I think we'll be able to run this
without causing damage from the
measurements but we're working on other
things as well and one thing that LEDs
have done is they have actually
generated a lot of interest in McCree
action spectrum of
photosynthesis so this curve right here
shows how efficiently plants use
different wavelengths of photons for
photosynthesis and it's normalized to a
peak of one right here so with LEDs we
can actually get very specific
wavelengths and there is a lot of
interest right now in trying to recreate
the action spectrum and see if this
holds up under LEDs and see if it holds
up under different light intensities so
because there was a lot of interest in
this I'm not doing it all of people are
and what I'm going to do is try to
convince you that this doesn't work
because that's much more fun I like to
be contrarian but so because the
efficiency is relatively high in the
blue and red part of the spectrum and we
have good LEDs in those uh wavelengths
efficient
LEDs the typical grow light now has a
mixture of red and blue LEDs we are
actually using some of these exact same
lights this is just another grow light
but that has become the standard mixing
red and blue and some cases white
LEDs but what Keith McCree in his
groundbreaking work in the 60s didn't
seem to think about was even more
groundbreaking work that was done in the
50s by Amazon so
Amazon is largely credited for doing the
initial research that showed that there
were actually two different photos
systems that work together an electron
transport rate and what emson did was he
looked at photosynthetic rates if we
only GI plant light with wavelengths
greater than 680 nanom and what we found
was that you get very low photosynthetic
rates and with what we know now that is
actually to be expected because photos
system 2 can only use light with
wavelength of 680 or below well photos
system one can use light up to 700 nanom
so with this kind of light you really
only stimulating photos system one not
photos system 2 so what Amazon also
found and I think we have failed to
really recognize the importance of this
is that if you gift plants lighted with
wavelengths only below 680 nanom and
that's this right here we also get low
photosynthetic
rates but that light can still excite
photosystem 2 and photos system one both
but we still get only very low
photosynthetic rates and when we combine
these two lights then you get this right
here you get much much higher photos St
static rates much higher than using e
well than the combination of these two
lights when used individually so there
was aestic effect of light below and
Light Above 680
nanom um and the idea behind that is
that I showed this slide before the rate
limiting step in the electron transport
chain is right here where this electron
needs to be transferred to uh a plastic
Kone right here and that will allow that
electron to move further down the
electron transport chain so we often say
that photos system 2 is the rate
limiting step for the light reactions
and that is because photos system 2
right here is not capable of donating
this electron to the plasticon pool
right here if most of that plasticon
pool has already been reduced there is
only so much plastically
known but um based on what Amazon found
basically what we can do is if we excite
photos system one more what we can do is
reoxidize all these Downstream
intermediates in the electron transport
chain and if we can oxidize the plastic
kones right here then they can accept
another electron and photos system to
now is capable of transferring that
electron more efficiently and electron
transport can occur at a higher rate
theoretically so there goes the electron
all the way to
nadph so um I told a graduate student of
mine about 10 days ago if she could get
me convincing data on this by last
Wednesday so she had about four days to
do this I'll let you go to the light
Symposium at Michigan State and she got
pretty motivated so she grabbed u a red
and blue LED bar that has this from
right here and we have some Far red LEDs
sitting in the lab and she added
incrementally more um far red light to
it and then she measured photosynthetic
rates and she measured um the quantum
yield of photo system too and so this is
the far red LED right here it adds
practically no photosynthetically active
radiation there was virtually no light
below 700
nanom so when she did that the Y AIS
here is really confusing because this
data is so new that we haven't figured
out yet how we actually want to express
this but this indicates the current that
we were given to the far red LEDs it's
basically the intensity of the far red
light so it goes from zero with the far
red off to more and more far red light
and then the far red light turned off
again and what we see is indeed an
increase in photosynthesis that is
disproportional to the amount of light
that we were adding
so we have now made the great discovery
that science da in the ' 50s was
actually right but I think we have
forgotten about the science from the 50s
and that's really the point I'm trying
to make um it is really worthwhile to
look at some key papers from a very long
time ago um because there is a lot of
good information out there and what we
were also able to do what Emison never
could do because he doesn't have the
equipment we looked at the quantum yield
of photos system 2 and it actually
follows a very very similar pattern but
the increase that we see in the quantum
yield the photosystem 2 is actually not
as big as the increase that we see in
photosynthesis so this by itself doesn't
explain the entire um effect that we see
on the actual photosynthetic
measurements um we haven't had any time
to look at this in more depth or to
think about this a whole lot um I got
these graphs on Saturday I think so um
but I think it's just interesting to go
back to that old literature and so there
was a lot of interest in mccree's action
spectrum of photosynthesis and the
reason that I say maybe it's not all
that important is that that action
spectrum that McCree developed and it it
was great work but it assumes that all
of these wavelengths are acting
independently and they don't we know
from Amazon that far red light has a
synergistic effect and that becomes
really difficult to capture in an in an
action SP spectrum that might mean that
you need to develop an action Spectrum
with different amounts of far Red Light
added to it or something like that and
it's far red light the only kind of
light that has this kind of an effect
who knows we can't possibly test all
different possibilities all different
wavelengths of light because that would
be hundreds if not thousands of
different wavelengths that you can
combine to try to figure out what the
most efficient combination actually
is so we did see that far red light has
a COGIC effect so again that is nothing
new but it is I thought was worthwhile
revisiting and it does increase the uh
Quantum yield of photosystem too it does
make photos system 2 more efficient
presumably because it helps to reoxidize
that plasticon pool that photos system 2
needs to donate the electron to and
again wavelengths do not have
independent effects so how can we come
up with an action Spectrum for
photosynthesis um something to think
about so our future goals is to um try
to commercialize some of this bio
feedback technology and I'm doing that
in collaboration with a local startup
company called fyto synthetics um that
was actually uh a company that was
started by two graduate students that I
had in a photosynthesis class that I
taught um eight or 10 years ago we
talked about some of these
ideas um they talked to their adviser
about it he got a patent on the
technology with telling me about it
um and the two students started uh two
years ago this company to try to get
this technology to Market so I'm now
working with fyto synthetics pretty
closely to um to do all of this uh so
one of the things that we want to do is
to build a lowcost chlorophyll
fluorometer that is done between phyto
synthetics and an engineering Professor
the instrument we use costs
$115,000 um we hope we can build
something for $300 or $400 that would
make this a lot more appealing to
potential
users um so this is a picture of the
Prototype of uh the fluorometer you can
see the saturating light bus coming from
a laser right here shining onto that
leaf um I hope that uh in the next week
or two they'll get me an updated version
of this fluorometer that may actually
work um apparently it's not easy to
build a chlorofil
floma um I would like to uh thank janito
faresi he was the post do in my lab who
built the very first iteration of the
bio feedback system uh Jeff Weaver who I
subsequently hired to work on this
project and who will hopefully become my
PhD student soon um did a lot of work on
this Shu yangang Zen is a PhD student in
my lab she did to work revisiting the
Emison effect and my current post
working on this Michael Martin the whole
Lab crew I would also like to thank Dex
and desier for getting this topic on the
radar um because again I don't think
that I would have been able to get the
funding I got if it hadn't been for his
Pie in the Sky well corn in the sky
views um so we may really disagree with
what he did but I think he has done us a
great favor in many ways as well um and
these are the various funding agencies
uh that obviously I would like to thank
as well and hopefully with that we have
time left for
questions um if if you were lighting at
247 and
not and um if if you knew the level in
intensity you would not necessarily need
a
dyamic uh control correct well so if you
lied your plant 24 4 S um you may have
an increase in non-photochemical
quenching over time and you may be
decreasing the quantum yield of
photosystem too so that may or may not
happen but I I would love to see data on
that before I would make any hard claims
about that I'm not convinced that you
would necessarily maintain a stable
electron transport rate if you keep the
plants in the light all the time and
some plants don't tolerate it like
tomatoes uh they need their rest at
night um
have you tried growing lettuce on the
continuous light I never have and
lettuce is fine with
it yeah um it would be easy enough to
find out if you have changes in Quantum
yield yeah so no it is not a whole lot
of light it is A8 second pulse so if you
were to integrate that over the 2 minute
period it's not a whole lot of light but
it is a whole lot of light that that
leaf has to deal with all at once and
that the leaf cannot do it's just it's
overwhelming the system do you have any
estimates
of
fraction
Rel
backal no pretty small um yeah that most
a few percent but so it's it's not
really everything it out doesn't take
into account that all of this light is
coming just in a very very brief burst
and that is more than the leaf can can
handle
and doing that over and over and
over yes simar to the first question do
you think
the has to
do um no I don't think so because when
we tried to maintain an electron
transport rate of 70 we saw a completely
flat line the quantum yielder photos
system 2 was completely stable so there
was no evidence there of any kind of
Cadian Rhythm while at a higher electron
transport rate we see that that Quantum
yield starts dropping over time so it
doesn't seem to me like it's the cadium
Rhythm that is involved yes um yeah
great question and plans definitely
adapt to different light levels and
Shang Zen um has done work on that as
well so if you grow plants under higher
light levels they will actually be
capable of achieving much higher
electron transport rates they are making
more reaction centers to help use all of
that light
there's definitely acclamation going on
you see thisal
application well so you mean the LEDs or
so the LEDs are going on and off at the
frequency of 1,000 Hertz um you don't
see it you don't see that yeah but if
you start to do it in a second or a
little more you'll see it yeah but
there's no reason to do it at a at a
different frequency you can do it at a
very high frequency my understanding is
that it doesn't harm LEDs at all Tessa
may be able to uh corroborate that but
um so we're doing that already with a
lot of lighting that we are exposed to
every single day a lot of this lighting
is being controlled using the same pul
withth modulation um
so uh there was other old research where
people were actually looking at how does
the frequency of the light affect the
photosynthetic rate
and there was a lot of really bad
science out there um but it turns it
looks like there is no effect of
frequency to speak of and um we've um
tested that as well that was really
boring data if we keep the same
integrated light level and change the
frequency the plant does exactly the
same
[Applause]
thing this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu