[Music]
Welcome to our lab tour thanks so much
for joining so I'm sitting here in my
office in the plant science building at
Cornell University opposite Mr Jensen
and jagy our brilliant and accomplished
filmmaker here and he's going to take us
on a whirlwind kaleidoscopic tour of our
facilities so it's nice to be here and
I'm just going to mention now a few of
the sites that Jensen who's a member of
our lab is going to take you on so
Jensen's going to show but a few scenes
and a few other people from the lab will
make appearances in some of these
different places so um so here in plant
science I hope you're going to see a
couple of our PE collection points at
Cornell and you're also going to see our
laboratory u in a different building
you're going to also see our kind of wet
lab where we do our pee work we have a
pasteurizer from the rich rich Earth
Institute there we have our IC tanks and
it's right near our Greenhouse so
connects with our um setup and Analysis
work and uh our green Greenhouse work
there um you'll also be visiting dilman
Hill student organic farm where some of
our experiments take place in the high
tunnel and out in the on the Saxon racks
and see our little garden there and then
we'll also be making a quick visit to
the soil Factory where we have Community
engagement and even a few scenes from
our work in Kenya so just real quick to
acknowledge a couple of our
collaborators
um Professor Johannes Layon is a biochar
expert who's a key conspirator for some
of our resource recovery work with
involving biochars he's involved in our
project on um also on PE powered
composting and grow as you go gardening
also in East Africa where our lead
collaborator is professor Charles Mida
another world famous uh he's a biologist
uh entomologist a public health guy and
all around circular om IST so anyway
just want to want to uh TI my hat to
them and many other collaborators who
are involved in our work thanks the P
cycling that we're involved with is
entirely container based sanitation so
all the urine collected from all the
sites and all the collection schemes is
collected in containers that transported
Dr Nelson transports the
containers um to this site here you have
a tank just outside this window that um
uh receive y from various places we
collect it dump it in there and it's
pumped into the pasteurizer from the
rich Earth Institute and return to
another tank which we then we can draw
down and and use in
experiments as with any area of
agricultural innovation you know we have
a lot to benefit from working with
Partners who are engaged in uh either
exploring the same questions but a
different contexts or exploring
different but related questions and so
the Nelson lab collaborates with many
many collaborators on Cornell's campus
uh
Cornell's uh the university slogan is
any person any study so there there are
people across the university pursuing
different areas of of study but who have
who share an interest in in circularity
and so there are collaborators all
across campus in other disciplines
within the school of Agriculture and
outside that school um that we who we
collaborate with on campus one of our
most important collaborators is the
student Farm Cornell has a network
of agricultural experiment stations uh
Farms where researchers host research
host extension
activities
um and one of the sites closest to
Cornell's academic campus is the student
Farm which is right on right on campus
and it's
a it's a site that hosts student Le
research including students you see in
this video here who lead research
projects with the Nelson landb based at
the student farm and this summer I've
been working here on the dman hill
student organic farm and also a bit
inside the lab uh where we're taking a
look at how our uh organic underutilized
resource substrate and a variety of
alternative organic fertilizers such as
urine and fish effluent are affecting
the health and growth of two culturally
significant indigenous crops which are
honani skunk beans and Cherokee tobacco
it also is a place where students um can
work as Farm managers and be hired into
that role when they learn how to manage
a farm and they also lead a number of
community engagement initiatives that
bring uh really substantial amounts of
of the student body onto the farm to
engage uh and the P cycling efforts that
the Nelson lab leads there at the PE
collection the the EOL the
collecting toilet as well as our
experiments in the high tunnel there are
featured really really prominently and
students are exposed to that through
that facility we are studying different
aspects of the circular bionutrient
economy and as you can see we're up at
dilman Hill student organic farm in our
high tunnel working with some
[Music]
Tomatoes we're also interested in
looking at alternatives to Conventional
nitrogen fertilizers so in this case
we've grown some of our tomatoes with
Miracle Row a standard fertilizer used
by many gardeners
uh but we've also grown some plants with
pasteurized human
urine and we're here at dman Hill
student organic farm at the pollinator
Garden that is a pea powered pollinator
Garden beautiful bees all around me with
these beautiful flowers that are growing
because of
pea also in this vicinity
is uh an
indigenous research project using
culturally relevant crops that are also
fertilized with PE as well as black
solder fly
frass and comparing that against
conventional Miracle Grow where we made
this P indigenous panamerican Garden as
a model for marginalized areas where
their soils may be contaminated or
depleted by nutrients from synthetic
fertilizer and pesticide abuse
so the soil Factory is an off-campus
site with a big warehouse and a lot of
space and an artist residency so that's
where um a group of us uh key
coconspirator again being johanes Layman
and um many others uh we have uh art
science events where artists come visit
and put on shows we have PE cycling uh
toilets being invented there and we have
a big grow as you go Garden where we're
doing PE powered composting and
gardening um and when people come from
abroad for instance I also mentioned
Charles midega when he and other people
come to talk about whatever um circular
economy topic you know they they'd
always have a a community event there
with a dinner and people an informal uh
exposure to the community and exchanging
ideas with people from around here so
it's a it's a nice place for all sorts
of exchange of information and um P
cycling gets a whole lot of press
welcome to the Rebecca Nelson
[Music]
lab I'll guide you through our lab
facilities and showcase some key areas
and equipment that support our research
activities I'll start with the
workbenches where we conduct most of our
Hands-On
experiments each bench is equipped with
standard tools and equipment such as
microscopes for obser
microorganisms pH and conductivity
meters for monitoring the ph and
solinity of samples as well as the
sentug for separating different
components of
samples above the workbenches are
shelves with mostly region glassware and
items we use for chemical and biological
analysis we also have refrigerators and
freezers that we use for storing and
preserving
samples there's also a fume hood and
bios safety cabinet that we use for
experiments that that involve volatile
chemicals in the agricultural College we
collaborate with johannas Layman and his
research group on the uses of biochar in
these systems and and and other
questions I as well
internationally um Dr Nelson Has
colleagues around the world but
especially in Kenya uh is our closest
collaborator Dr Charles Mida at poverty
and Health Integrated Solutions
uh where he focuses
on different uses for urine and
agriculture there especially targeting
the per Urban and
urban uh
applications uses of urine with biochar
and is really intimately engaged with a
number of community- based organizations
there uh both for the P cycing side of
the work and for the community
engagement and extension aspect
in addition to all the facilities that
facilitate our ability to study uh the
use of urine as fertilizer and to um
provide nutrients in in these novel
Horticultural
media um really the secret sauce to our
our work and and how we uh can study
what we study here is not the facilities
but the the colleagues we have so um all
of my team teammates that and the team
that Rebecca that Dr Nelson leads uh I
know we we all feel really lucky to work
with each other and and uh that that is
is really what what the Nelson lab
brings to the table