because yeah who defining Community
great great question um and I think
Community you know we can use
sociological framing techniques which
I've done in the past but I think you'll
see the community come forward as we
move through through this so but what
I'm targeting largely is women in a
rural context and there's a lot of
private land ownership in the United
States so women are often um in ways
have opportunities to engage in climate
smart forestry so um yeah the community
the platform in which to reach this
community is women owning Woodlands
which is um there's almost I think a a
network in each um in each state and
this is backed by the US Forest Service
and the national Woodland Owners
Association so it's a great group um and
this project um with uh Patricia and the
team is um complimentary to my other
extension program called Forest owner
carbon and climate education program um
which is I
will it's more Broad in terms of
reaching um land owners in general in
the eastern US with we have about 13
extension institutions that uh
participate in contributing to this
program so a lot of co-creation of
information um climate smart forestry is
highly interdisciplinary subject matter
so I'm the social scientist I um I
contribute in that way and um we're
looking to kind of just help bring more
awareness and opportunities to Forest
land owners um so just sort of like an
overview this is my one slide about
climate smart forestry but it's really
about how to it's managing forests based
on their current condition so that they
can either address uh mitigation uh
climate change uh mitigation or are able
to adapt to climate change um and force
management is key here so active Force
management and um proactive planning is
often needed in order to implement any
sort of mitigation or adaptation
strategy and Forest are living system so
they're very Dynamic um the biggest way
to keep a forest of carbon sink is to
keep it healthy and to keep it around so
you know preventing land use conversion
and managing it um to protect Forest
health is going to uh provide positive
benefits into the future but it can also
be managed to sequester additional
carbon um that can be sold as offsets in
a market setting and provide income for
the land owner so there's all kinds of
opportunities
so the problem statement when it comes
to um women and Forest land ownership um
I already highlighted that private
Forest lands are expected to be key
players about 70% of forest are
privately owned however land ownership
has been um not been an opportunity for
a lot of women
historically um however now in the last
few Generations uh ownership of land has
has been um including women more and
more uh over half of couples um own land
and so women are you know assigned uh
you know ownership um but usually the
men have the primary decision-making
roles and this just has to do with
traditional roles once again about who
whose jobs are to be outside and whose
are to be inside and and these kinds of
things so um so women don't often have
these formative experiences in Forestry
um there it is not uncommon uh well so
I'll just point out that Forest land
owners are generally around 60 years in
age and um women frequently outlive men
so there are periods in which women come
into Forest ownership unintentionally
they can inherit land you know they can
get it from their husband more and more
women are intentionally buying forests
but this unintentional ownership is is
not uncommon
and um forested properties at the
highest risk of mismanagement during
that period of land transfer from one
owner to another that is where the risk
of um uh unsustainable Harvest or land
use conversion is Mo most likely to
occur so thinking about this we want to
get women involved in Forest management
and also thinking in a proactive sense
about you know uh under climate change
but the literature has shown with Forest
uh with women Forest owners is that they
have limited formative experiences low
confidence they don't feel like they
belong in these spaces because forestry
is T tend to be male dominated and
programs are that you know for training
are usually geared towards men in the
context that um they're set up in a way
where uh you know the the kind of what
what I want to call like power Dynamic
is more more comfortable for men than
for women and so moving forward we
wanted to tra create a an extension
program for women that was in a in a
context that was more comfortable for
them especially in when there's low
confidence and kind of feeling like you
don't belong and so uh I'll share with
you our needs assessment study we did in
the codesign approach um and then I'll
go over how we designed the program
itself and then give you some uh
information of the data we collected uh
we did this program and we set it up for
Pennsylvania and South Carolina and so
that's the co-creation process uh but
we've only collected data in in South
Carolina right now so that's what I'll
show you um so uh let's
see my um graduate student kPa nupan did
um uh interviews so qualitative research
with women Forest owners in the network
that we're collaborating with and to
understand um how they thought about
forest and how they thought about
climate change and um when it comes to
climate change women had very mixed
opinions and just as a reminder these
women are generally mature and Rural and
so relatively
conservative um and you know climate
change is a thing but it's not the most
pressing issue in their life um but what
do they value about their Forest they
really valued um that it was a system
that supported multiple types of um
living things it provided services to
society clean water clean air it was a
place that was really important for
family bonding and being outside and
being together was something that was
they really valued about their Forest um
some of the challenges were again what
we saw in the literature they didn't
really know much about Forest management
I mean even they're part of this network
there's this low confidence and I'm like
if you're part of this network you
probably know more than most people but
there was still this like concern like I
don't know a lot um language barri
meaning terminology not understanding
when someone says um a select Harvest
what does that mean and it can mean a
lot of different things um lack of
capital in you know investing into their
land that's that's pretty common in land
ownership your land rich but you know
cash poor and then just a lack of trust
like are professionals going to take me
seriously uh when I go ask them for help
so so this was the issue how do we bring
climate change information to this this
group that where climate change is not
that
important and so we began to I got
together with some community members
that are listed on the left they um we
sent out a a request for women to
participate in this codesign process and
we had some criteria we wanted them to
sort of demonstrate leadership as well
as some experience in in forced
ownership at least um and then the other
program leaders were my colleagues in
extension at Clemson and at University
of Florida as well as here at Penn State
and we had a series of meetings in which
um we shared with those Community
contributors um the information from the
needs
assessment uh the literature what the
literature says um we shared with them
what kind of resources are available in
extension including climate smart
forestry content and said you know how
can we build a program that's going to
appeal to rural women and Forest owners
um and so this is the the logic model I
just put it in there because that's how
we kind of built it but now the next
slides are going to kind of show you
what that Ed up ended up being so the
way we um designed the program was that
it would be on Legacy planning that was
something all the women pretty much get
behind they're all about you know
protecting the forest into the future as
well as um supporting their family uh in
the future as well and so making it
climate smart is just the active
management part of of Legacy planning
which involves um some legal components
too and communication with your family
members about what you want to do in the
future those kinds of things um because
a lot of them just didn't feel very
confident in their knowledge and
experience in Forest management um we
knew we had to design an atmosphere that
was going to be safe and comfortable so
we set up these objectives to provide
information to support understanding or
support knowledge language and
motivation around climate smart forestry
and Legacy planning so two topics we
kind of put them together um we provide
planning documents and we also give them
opportunities to network with peers and
Forestry professionals so that's what we
want them to ultimately have that it's
about you know motivation ability to
plan and uh being able to network with
professionals or kind of our end goals
so the approach we designed was to
Foster group discussions with women land
owners that are led by their peers so
these are spaces where there are no
professionals leading the conversation
it is the women having conversations
guided conversations because we train
one of their peers to guide it but they
get to look at the materials reflect on
them together and do group work together
to come up with um their plan Envision
for their forest and so this was
implemented over um 3 weeks and um I
will let you know on the logic model
here is what we expected to be the
short-term mid and long-term impacts and
I think this is a really important slide
because we often get this sense like
well an extension we need to teach
somebody how to do something and then
they go do it and that's impact and
while that is impact that's sort of like
they they already had to have a lot of
motivation already and a lot of
experiences already in order to take
action but we're not talking about women
who are ready to take action yet what
they need really is to establish their
values and priorities for Forest
management understand what is climate
smart forestry what is Legacy planning
like what is it um and they need to find
their voice they need to talk about it
and they need to be initiated into the
forestry uh sector into the group as
being seen as a legitimate contributor
in the conversation in this space so
it's very much about early engagement
strategies and initiating people into a
space where they historically have not
necessarily been welcomed um and so the
long-term impact is you know that uh
land owners are more engaged and that
opportunities uh to get you know
incentives from climate smart forestry
be they from the state or from uh
private sector um that those incentives
were more equitably
distributed so the way we had it set up
is that there
are the FY program or this this
particular project we
provide um the platform in which to um
manage these discussion groups and our
collaborators in this case it was
Clemson um extension services they were
the ones that brought the people
together and so just to sort of like
describe a little bit a little bit more
cogently here um we provided
registration services the assignments
and discussion guides the extension
resources library and evaluation of
their program and our collaborators at
Clemson distributed the invitations for
these uh these discussion groups within
their Network um held meeting spaces um
and identified forestry professionals to
invite and also helped to develop the
the material that would be read um and
so there's there's a lot of different
participants in this there's the
facilitators who are training the group
leaders who are you know setting up
discussions with the Learners the forest
owners and their families and um there's
also the forestry professionals that
come at the end and say you know this is
what I do and this is how you can
contact me um so it did require quite a
bit of uh materials had to be created um
but the content the training part was
already in existing extension materials
um so it was more we had to set up the
registration we we set up a quiz to help
uh the women understand their priorities
for Forest management and then these
discussion guides so these are the kinds
of materials and the evaluation surveys
these are the kinds of materials that
were generated from this project and you
can see here in stage one we're
assembling the group so we use a qual
trick survey to um have Forest owners
register
um they got a letter of invitation from
their extension Network leader um and
said you know here's a program if you'd
like to be part of it so they come to
qualtrix and register and part of the um
qualtrix registration process included
uh the values Forest values quiz to help
them understand um their priorities and
it also was a section where they could
volunteer to be a peer uh group leader
and so they would attend a separate
training to prepare them for that and so
so here's the um quiz it's a two-step
quiz first they list what do they like
about their Forest so it covers a wide
variety of things um ecosystem Services
um as well as um sort of like uh climate
Well Community benefits meaning just
being part of the forestry community and
um we what they did is they listed what
they thought what they like about forest
and then what they were concerned about
and then we got to compare the two to
help them Identify some priorities
because if they thought it was important
and they were concerned about it that
should be at the top of their list
that's part of the reason why people
don't really start thinking about a
management plan they just get
overwhelmed like where do I start what
is my goal you know and this was really
C trying to help them uh set those
priorities so the curriculum was a
contribution from multiple institutions
uh Clemson um had a lot of great
materials just on basic Forest
management
uh they also have Penn State and Clemson
had uh resources extension resources on
Legacy planning uh tips for how to
conduct what it is and then tips for how
to to uh engage in that process and then
of course my program the forest owner
carbon and climate education program had
plenty of articles on climate smart
forestry and carbon markets and um
opportunities there so that's our
library of resources and what we do is
we got together and we said this is what
people valued in that quiz and then we
just basically put together a package of
articles for the women to read and so
the individual activity that the women
engaged in before the group activity was
to review the reading assignment so it
was just um two or three articles short
articles that they would review before
getting together and they met in Zoom
that's where we had our um group
discussions and and they the peer leader
would guide them through some planned
questions that help them kind of
articulate um what it is that they
learned what were um some of the uh you
know what was of interest to them and
then how would they like apply what they
learn to what their priorities are as
far as um on that priorities quiz um
they had a forc visioning plan where
they would document um their uh
conversations um and these were private
documents they aren't like you know they
could share them or not you know it was
really um open-ended how the group
wanted to engage with each other and
then at the end they would get to meet
with forestry professionals so in South
Carolina they got to meet with their
state Forester they also got to meet
with some forestry extension
professionals um and one carbon markets
person I believe so they got to see hey
these are real people and they all
happen to be women too which was nice
and they knew who to call like I have a
question about my Forest I know who to
call because I met this person and we
had an evaluation survey at the end
which is what I'll share with you now um
so 10 people responded to the survey and
I have a poster here you know I'm
willing to share it if anyone's
interested but just sort of as a summary
uh most people were curious they just
wanted to explore options which is why
they got involved in the discussion
groups which is great because that's the
purpose of those discussion groups was
really kind of to broaden uh their um
exposure to climate smart forestry and
Legacy planning um and
see this these are the scaler questions
that we use to measure that
Collaborative Learning Experience that
group work um that Collaborative
Learning Experience has both
psychological as well as academic kind
of impacts and so in the left uh table
here these statements um measuring
collaborative learning benefits um were
just about the conversations about
Legacy planning and so you know
participants felt free to communicate
their opinions on a scale of one to five
uh means score four means that generally
everyone agreed that they were able to
communicate their opinions once again
most people agreed they enjoyed
listening to other people's point of
view their understanding was
broadened uh they some of them felt like
they learned something from each other
and they feel more comfort able about
talking uh with their peers about these
issues in the future and so I would say
the Legacy planning definitely I mean
this is some challenging stuff to talk
about when you're going to die and who's
going to do what with your forest and
what do you expect from your children so
these are not light topics and so you
know the fact that they you know enjoyed
themselves and felt like they were able
to communicate is really a great impact
moving over to Forest carbon and climate
change again it was all above four um
and there was an enjoyment talking about
climate change it's so interesting I
think when we get together and have
these conversations there is more
optimism than kind of learning about it
in the news or having it pointed at you
but being able to verbalize your
opinions and views on um what can be a
challenging topic um is is really can be
a positive
experience um and so here's change and
perceived knowledge attitudes confidence
um once again it was on a fivepoint
scale and just like Patricia's um slide
she showed it was the score before and
the score after so we're looking for a
change hopefully in a positive direction
with the Legacy planning uh confidence
in understanding Legacy planning topics
increased uh you know the pleasure of
learning about these things increased
comfort about talking to their family
about Legacy planning um also increased
and making decisions in the future so
went up a whole point on a fiveo scale
so I would say that is really great um
also an increase on Forest carbon and
climate change topics and this one had a
little few more questions that related
to um to climate change uh a couple more
questions that related to um uh
communication to different uh categories
of people so like their Community to
their family to contributing to
mitigation and adaptation strategies
um increase in understanding increase in
like enjoying learning about um the
subject matter and some of the biggest
changes was the skills to talk to family
and friends about climate change and I'm
like that's so great because one
of we cannot move into a society that
addresses climate change till everybody
most everybody's on board and part of
that involves talking and right now
climate change is sort of like a tabby
word and a lot of um uh more
conservative or traditional communities
because it has so much uncertainty about
it and among other reasons so uh
encouraging people to talk about it is
just really really great okay I'm going
to finish up right here here's some
comments um I would say one of my
favorite comments is this big one here
where the respondent said she only
really thought about her forest in two
different ways but now she was looking
to expand to think more about
um in interested in the forest landowner
community and in habitat management
which is great because before she was
just uh interested in um income and
non-timber Forest Products uh the
comment down below here um said that her
brother was the one that talked to the
Forester but now she's like I know some
stuff so um I was like great you know
she's entering the conversation this is
evidence of being willing to now enter
that conversation and then the other two
comments basic Bally are talking about
how they liked the system that helped
them set up their ideas and and and
start making a
plan so what we learned is that climate
change Solutions should help Advance the
values and goals of the community so put
the Legacy planning first and then built
the climate change curriculum with it um
we don't have trust issues when working
with women in an extension context it's
just that's that's not the barrier but I
will say there was a little bit of
difference in there was concerned about
the political agenda that came up and
there was a difference based on age and
why is it we're focusing on women and
this is just was an interesting space I
can talk more about it if you want but
it wasn't a really barrier but there was
definitely questions like why are we
asking women about this or being
involved just women's only groups you
know um and the last thing is don't
discount the value of initiating people
to take part in conversations so that
concludes my presentation if you're
interested in doing something like this
in uh your community I can certainly be
of help we have a system in place and um
this co-design process is just part of
the programming it's we're building it
all the time depending on which group
discussion groups we're working
with oh that was fantastic I think this
is my favorite event so far I mean just
even talking about providing child care
in order to have families come or
helping people find their own voice in a
new field of
consideration
um you these are very common
sensical things uh but sometimes we
forget them and I just I just want to
applaud you both for bringing those very
real pragmatic things to the floor so
that we can really engage the the
collective Force because I do think I I
do think there is a common sense to
climate change and and I can see that
you are really you both of you are
really beginning to nail that common
sense and so and I wish I hadn't used
the word nail but you know what I mean
um so thank you um I'll say that um I
this is the first time I've done any
research that's like gender specific and
uh working in this space and I think
that um it is it's so valuable because
um they they're they're right there the
women are right there on the forest
lands and all they have to do is just
say something you know you know can we
just think about this this way Dad you
know what about this brother you know
and and um it it's it's yeah once again
it's like defining the problem it's not
this huge I mean there's there there are
underserved communities that have
significant you know um
socioeconomic you know constraints but
then there's others that can also make a
real difference where it's just about
increasing their confidence um so that
was something that I've been learning to
appreciate is the Nuance I guess um
that's different for every community and
I really like Patricia how your your the
the the Latino Community is just so like
let's have a good
time let's make this a party let's make
this about family and I'm like isn't
that it's just different everywhere you
go um and being sensitive culturally
competent I guess is the word um to uh
to to make that part of the program so
it feels like their
program I also think it's neat Melissa
how you're thinking about Legacy
planning it hasn't really even occurred
to
me um how hard it is to Broach that
subject let alone think about how to
manage land that results from from that
subject or think about how to manage
that land that results from that subject
to have a long-term climate impact like
there's so many temporal layers which
you made very clear in your presentation
but it's also just so poignantly present
like the decisions that one makes and so
I think it's just I'm curious in terms
of cart and horse did you come did you
come first to the Legacy planning or
were you coming from climate and then
realized that Legacy planning was this
interesting um co-
jooin in a in a trajectory that needed
attention and sort of climate just sort
of came along with it it's all about my
collaborators so Allison m is the leader
in Legacy planning at Penn State here
and of course I do the carbon uh climate
stuff where you know new money is coming
in and we're like What is the number one
challenge of forest management obviously
it's making it financially feasible and
then another challenge is at that land
transfer forests exist on longer time
scales than humans do and I think in the
US average L tenure is around 16 years
now some people will own for like maybe
20 years or 30 years but that's a really
short period of time and so not thinking
about the forest for the next generation
is self-limiting and so it definitely uh
in the context of um yeah Forest under
climate change the two really did make a
lot of sense and they were just kind of
separated parts of extension and we're
like we'll put them
together so I see there's a question
from
Lynn I'm interested in doing a similar
approach with pollinator habitat we'll
be working with South Carolina 4 Youth
Development would' love to discuss
further I'm also working with Leaders
with Native bees in Washington would
love to
hear uh think about I would love to
think about how we could build
collaborative opportunities so Lynn
you're in North Carolina and in
Washington state am I understanding that
or Washington
DC with the women Community is that I'm
not sure which uh starting with the
community kind of working that way
because I know it's easy to go like we
got to support pollinators um so
defining the community I guess would be
helpful I think there's room for all
kinds of collaboration so oh yeah
this event has gone over time and I
think I'm going to put um Patricia's
email in the chat uh but you I think you
should feel confident or comfortable
contacting any of us oh yeah
definitely uh but I'm GNA close it out
because I didn't actually realize it was
4:06 and I tried to stick to our time
limit so everybody can move on um I just
want to remind everyone that aging and
climate is next month I put the
registration in the chat please give us
feedback both about the structure of the
presentation um today as well as any in
the past and also give us feedback for
things that you would like to be
presented in the future we're trying to
cultivate a whole range of perspectives
on how to move forward so everybody
finds a friend uh to work with work for
and work on behalf and be inspired and
be inspiring so let us know and join us
at necki if you would like to join us
I'm going to call it quits right there
and um my very best to you all have a
good day