this is a production of Cornell
University okay I'd like to introduce
Marvin who's gonna say a few words about
the Dreer award one of one of the
wonderful things about Cornell is there
these pockets of money around and people
don't often know about it there's a
pretty big pocket of money called the
jur word that's was set up to allow
graduate students to travel somewhere
internationally to supplement their
career or their research or whatever
and uh it's about $28,000 a year and
sometime in March April we invite
graduate students to submit a proposal
it's very honorous they have to submit
five or six pages of what they want to
do they have to meet with the committee
of three for like 20 minutes and explain
what they're going to do and then we
make a decision it's the easiest money
you would ever get the only requirement
is after you travel and you do you say
you come back and give a seminar to all
of us it's open to landscape
architecture and what graduate students
and our speaker today was the recipient
of the jur award so let Justine
introduce all right I'll come up to the
microphone just so online folks can hear
me hello everyone my name is Justine
Vanden hubal I'm a professor of
viticulture uh in sips and I'm pleased
to be here to introduce Kobe chalk so
Kobe's undergrad is from the University
of Hawaii at the Noah uh and he grew up
in Hawaii he did spend a semester at
University of Massachusetts ammer where
he actually took his first vulture
course his background is in economics
and when he was here we actually
combined that he did a cost analysis of
a spatial sampling protocol that uh we
had designed and that paper was recently
published in the American Journal of
knowledge a knowledge and vulture so I'm
very proud of uh the work that he's done
here it's been a pleasure to have him in
my that I'm glad he has kept up uh the
long line of my students who have then
gotten the drewer and gone off and done
amazing uh things around the country so
we're thrilled to have him here welcome
Kobe nice to have you back thank you
Justine um so first I'd like to thank
Justine and thank the Jer committee as
well as all of the people who made it
possible for me to go and learn all the
things that I did abroad um so as you
can see my presentation today is going
to be covering tropical viticulture it's
something that's a little different than
standard wine making and standard
viticulture and the reason I'm
interested is as Justin mentioned I'm
from Hawaii and down the road I plan on
starting a Vineyard and Winery and
Hawaii
so we get
started so this picture here is of me at
the vineyard I was interning at in
Thailand in the kaay region so the
regions that I visited is in Thailand
Brazil and India
particularly in Thailand it was in the
Kaa area as I mentioned previously the
winery I had is Grand Monte Vineyard and
Winery this region up here is further
north than some of the other regions
that also have Vineyards and
wineries um however the largest
concentration of wineries were located
in this region
right here um generally Thailand has two
significant Seasons that are pretty
consistent every year they have a winter
and then a summer and in the
winter I'm sorry they have a mansu
season and then a dry season so the
monsoon season as you can imagine is
very wet they don't propagate uh or grow
any Vines grapes that year uh that part
of the year and in that time they just
pretty much uh
prune and expect vegetative growth they
don't want any grapes because even if
they had grapes it would be swelled with
water they would get a lot of diseases
and it's just not worth producing any
grapes during that time period uh
further down south in this area there's
another Vineyard that's a little warmer
the vineyard also has a monsoon season
so they also don't go and have two
yields per year um but they're sand they
have a lot more sandy soil and then to
this region on the right
there is one Vineyard that actually
closed um so they're no longer there but
this region was closer to uh the region
the
Southwest the second region that I
visited is in petrolina
Brazil in petrolina it is described as
semi arid it is very dry for the most
part when I was there they said that it
was actually the wetest they had been in
10 years once in every 10 years they get
a lot of rain and it was flooding but
it's so rare that they can continuously
Harvest 365 days a year uh
perpetually and it's one of the most
unique regions that I visited for that
reason um a little further south in
Brazil as more of you are familiar with
is Sal Paulo where they have other
Vineyards in three different regions um
appear a little bit to the north of
saelo a little bit further south and
then to the west of sou poo and this is
a little bit closer to the traditional
30 to 50 latitude that you'd expect wine
to be grown in but
um they grow it here and it's pretty
unique as well and the last place I
visited was in India it was in the
nashik region and in the nashik region
it is also pretty dry and arid um it can
be I would say a little bit cooler than
a lot of the other regions I visited um
but it's still within the tropics unlike
if you went to further south in India it
would be in the traditional latitude as
well so I'm going to go through instead
of describing each place that I visited
just the vineyard management practices
and we can kind of see how things were
different or similar so uh this is Vine
propagation as you can imagine because
Vineyards aren't as common in these
regions they don't really have a large
supply of vines a lot of the vines that
they do have were all imported in small
shipments and then it was grown based
off of the material that they already
had so of course this is going to bring
up problems of potential virus
transmission as you propagate uh vines
that have viruses already um but at the
same time certain Vineyard especially
this one that I was at in Thailand they
try to to take precautions to kind of
prevent or at least mitigate the risk so
as you can see on the top left this is
the fresh cuting that they got from The
Vines and the vineyard uh we
defoliated the branches and then prune
them
to lengths of about a foot maybe a
little longer as you can see in the
bottom left um this is when we were I
guess sterilizing the vine so after we
runed them we stuck them in a hot water
bath at I believe it 50°
C maybe it's 80° C for uh about 30
minutes and there's some papers about
using this method to kind of kill any
diseases that are present and try to
prevent the spreading of any uh trunk
diseases um once we finished that they
were stuck in pots with instead of like
cocoa they have a lot of rice down there
so it was that Rice hle um fine material
and the tops of the vines were painted
with paint mixed with fongicide to kind
of close the wound on the
top after a few months actually a couple
months then this picture here is what
the result was and you can see something
similar when I visited uh TR and Brazil
where they also propagated all of their
own Vines as
well for Vineyard to establishment it
was pretty standard um in Thailand or in
India they kind of just planted vines on
the ground of course you don't have to
wait for fall or spring you can just
plant whenever you feel like it um and
then in Thailand they did something a
little bit more unique instead of
grafting The Vines uh before planting
they actually planted the root stocks
and then field grafted their explanation
to me of why they did this is because
instead of having the Scion that has
your desired grape variety on top
immediately allowing the root stock to
take off and be as vigorous as I can to
really establish its root system is what
they were going for and then later we'd
go into grafting and that'll be the next
slide but I just thought this was a
little interesting on the right it's
nothing special it's just a great Vine
but instead of using a stick to pull it
up vertically they tie on like this
fishing line almost and tie it to the
top uh trellis and I just thought that
was different I hadn't seen it
previously but uh we'll move to the
graftings you comment just briefly on
the sparkling that
people where it's
from yeah
so so this is from that Brazil region
that I mentioned previously in
petrolina the variety is Muscatel which
is a type of Musk I guess and this is a
really common wine from the region that
uh dry semi arid
region primarily makes white wines and
sparkling wines for red wines it's just
not the best climate for it I guess
because there isn't enough fluctuation
in temperature between day night and
they also receive a lot of sun so they
said that whenever they get certain red
grapes it comes out very light and the
tannins break down and there's nothing
left in far as far as complexity in the
Reds so this is one of the most popular
wines this bottle I believe is under
five US dollars so the market is to the
local Brazilian wine drinkers who uh are
relatively new I guess to Wine because
they like their beers but yeah this is
Muscat where was I okay graph
ing so for
grafting this is field grafting we took
thean variety that was refrigerated from
the previous pruning in the monsoon
season it was taken out of the
refrigerator the root stock was split
down the middle and then the cane is
shaved to a flat point it was cleft
grafting and one butt is cut from that
cane and inserted into the the slot and
then wrap tightly with this plastic wrap
pretty standard cleft grafting um but
one of the things that they noticed here
is sometimes the plastic gets into the
graph Union which will cause the vine to
die after a few years so um that's one
of the downsides of this and it's also a
lot more labor intensive to go into the
field rather than bench crafting in a
room now move to training systems and
this is another very unique thing to the
tropical regions often the not for the
wine grapes you would see double Cordon
or single Cordon vssp systems as you see
on the top right this is the grand Monte
Winery in
Thailand and this typically works very
well for them but in addition to that
for the more vigorous varieties I think
the only variety that that Winery did
cane pruning was for their
muskat um otherwise it was all double
cord done spur pring um the training
system that you saw in Brazil was often
similar although sometimes you saw
Highwire cordons in this middle picture
and uh in Brazil because the region is
also known for their table grape
growing they had regular pergolas that
they also grew table grapes on but they
did this for wine grapes and it was
interesting I think this method
is unique but at the same time there's a
lot less control over how many buds you
have how many clusters you have unless
you go through and kind of go underneath
to really look at everything but because
this vineer didn't have too much
mechanical operations it wasn't a big
problem
um and this middle picture at the bottom
is in India where as you can see see
their training system is also
this y system just do you know the name
for the where they split it into a y
it's called the Y system y system there
we go and in Thailand they also use this
and this is actually where they saw the
best quality grapes and the highest
yields but Thailand didn't regularly use
this for all of their grapes because
they can't mechanize really anything in
that block so it makes it more
challenging uh the system on the bottom
right is in Thailand as well but they
use for root stock growth so that they
can propagate and it's just a really
easy method for them to grow The Grapes
so that's why they use
it so as far as pruning goes in Thailand
the first thing they did was count the
cluster so they split the buds to see
how many uh infloresence they're
expecting for the year to kind of
estimate how many uh buds to prune to
typically it's five to six Buds per spur
and they would only keep a couple on the
top um as you see they use diagonal
pruning some people say that it's better
some don't but that's what they use the
five to six Buds per spur is what they
said to be a better amount of Spurs to
keep
for yield rather than vegetative growth
at the lower buds um and then similar to
how we did the grafting they also sealed
the pruning wounds with a mix of funu
side with
paint so the growing cycle is something
that is very distinct from anywhere else
as I mentioned before in Thailand they
are able to have two growing Seasons but
they only harvest in one um so you can
kind of look at this and see they have
the rainfalls average between 2001 and
2011 um as well as temperatures they
have noticed that it has gotten warmer
um and the rain has been a little bit
more variable because of climate change
um but I thought this was a good chart
to show because it really covers and
highlights a lot of different things
happening in the vineyard um throughout
the growing season so you see pruning
number one happens in April through May
and that's all vegetative and then
pruning number two happens September
through October and then fruit set and
this is when they're looking to get
their quality grapes here um you can
also see a
distinct drop in rainfall in the season
24 millim versus between
120 and
220 so that's uh pretty distinct
difference in rainfall and is which is
why they go with this season to be the
Fring season the pest pressures is also
down here below I'm going to cover some
of these pests a little bit more later
but you can see at different points in
the season they experience these
diseases um and of course birds will
always be there but can't do too much
about that other than putting a net or
making some noise cannons or lasers
so so to be able to do what they do
here they induce dormany so prior to
pruning they spray ethon and what this
does is really kind of prep the plant
and induce it into Dy and we prune it
and we also defoliate they
go ahead and remove the leaves with a
like a hedger they have people going
through just taking off the bulk of the
vegetation there um but that is
generally how it's done about a couple
days later they will then apply hydrogen
cyanamide to the buds and I believe some
spray it but the vineyard I was
interning at particularly in Thailand
they would actually go and get the
mixture and then paint it onto the buds
rather than just spraying broadly
because I guess the buds is where it
needs this uh
application um you can see Bud burst
this is in Thailand maybe a week after
Bud burst a couple weeks and then this
is almost immediately after Bud burst in
Brazil so this does the Fon uh help to
defoliate the
plants at all or do they have to really
go in and kind of aggressively
defoliate you know so they sprayed this
about right before I got there so I'm
not exactly sure what it did um I did
notice that there were some less leaves
but there were still a significant
amount of leaves that needed to be
pulled off by hand so it wasn't 100%
no um Kobe everyone has s your second
wine which there yes so the second wine
here is from Thailand it's a shz
um because they're close to Australia
they use a lot of Australian terms for
these wines and this is from Monsoon
Valley it's the largest Winery in
Thailand
um trying to think a little bit about
this wine I
believe this Winery they hyper use hyper
oxidation in the beginning of the
fermentation process and then ferment it
more or less normally through the end
and blend it with the different blocks
to try to get something consistent from
year to year um and try to keep these in
mind because at the end I'd like to ask
your thoughts on these different wines
um
so okay so fruit
set fruit
set happen pretty normally as you would
expect so I'm going to go through this
slide pretty quickly but the biggest
problem that they experienced is dowy
mildo as we could really get to the
infloresence before it even sets causing
a big loss um something unique again
with these regions is because they don't
have a winter coming up they can't
afford to be a little late on the
Harvest and there was one block that we
visited that was I think contracted out
but we still went to check it out and
see how it was it had very very poor
fruits at it had almost nothing because
of Downey mildew and this was already a
month or two into the season but they
just pruned again and started all over
and I wasn't there for when they
harvested this block but uh I assume it
worked out because they like I said they
have a lot of time um to get the fruit
in so this is some of the canopy
management that they do in India I
notice probably the least canopy
management um they were generally the
Messier Vineyards that I visited um as
far as weed control and general
maintenance of the vineyard um and then
in Brazil you see them kind of just
taking a handheld hedging tool to cut
everything that's hanging out into the
rows and then in
Thailand this was probably the most
painful thing I did while I was there
they gave us lopping shears and we had
to go overhead and L all day for a
couple
days and we tried to keep it within the
trellis wies so that way the growth is
vertical whereas uh and then when we LED
we just took off the tops the tips
whereas in Brazil some of these were
hanging out of the side of the trellis
so they'd be cutting some branches very
short doing it this way but labor is
really cheap in Thailand so that's why
they had just a few of us going out
there and manually removing the the
top this is some of the other canopy
management that we did um we' remove all
the downward facing shoots as generally
you don't want those and then early in
the season before Bud burst we went
through and removed all the uh little
buds that were coming up across from the
future clusters and they really try to
keep the fruit Zone open for disease
reasons as well as uh ripening so we
went through before the vine got massive
and really uh vigorous and removed all
of these little shoots here um we also
removed this is shoot selection so like
I said we only select two shoots per
spur and that way you don't have too
much Vigor um across the vine because it
as you can see here it already gets
[Music]
pretty developed in terms of leaf
development and fruit development so we
go through and leaf pull um for better
air circulation and Sun uh sun exposure
we Leaf pulled only on one side and this
was the side that was facing
the west and that way in the morning it
would be kind of protected from the Sun
in midday the whole canopy will protect
it and then it'll get a little bit more
sun exposure in the afternoons
but you can see how much they Leaf pull
they pretty much remove all the leaves
from the lower part of the canopy and
then um a lot from the fruit Zone as
well so it's a lot
of vegetative Management in terms of
irrigation it was all water sources that
were available right on site so on the
left this is petrolina uh it's a big
lake the S Francisco River so this lake
is what they pull the water into through
this uh pump system and then what
irrigate their fields with it in
Thailand
similarly this is the vineyard the main
Vineyard site where they have this big
pond that they have this pump house that
would pump water through to the vineyard
and they would use this for fertigation
as well and in another site in Thailand
they also have water right there um I
don't have a picture of this but but in
the southern Vineyard in Thailand that
it's a little bit more Sandy of course
they have better drainage it's also a
little drier um so they need to be
watering it a little more frequently
because you know generally if there's
sandy soil the water just going to go
right through and you're not going to
have a lot of retention um but they also
had a water shortage for that year so
they had to determine which blocks they
would just kind of neglect for the year
and not water so there were certain
blocks because of water shortages that
just wouldn't water because there is no
County water it's not really feasible to
bring in water um so like many other
regions especially in California water
can be a problem but it's generally not
in a lot of tropical
regions now we can uh for this next SL I
guess before we get there let me just
see
okay so this next line is a
Justin how do you say
it bar Barbara Barbara
Barbara and this Barbara is
from Brazil as well um typically it's
known to be a little bit more tanic and
a bigger wine uh but in this region as I
said before it's also a region that is
known not to have great Reds and known
to have low
tannins so we will see what your
thoughts are because typic typically the
better wines that I tried were the ones
that were typically supposed to be
bolder because I guess when you have
that loss you still have a higher amount
to begin with so when you lose some of
the tanin then it's not as big of a
deal but again I didn't try this one so
love to hear your thoughts on
that so for the other side of it because
it is
so tropic coal sometimes you have a lot
of rain in Thailand you have the monsoon
season a lot of rain in Brazil generally
you don't have too much but when you do
it can be a problem and across all of
the regions I noticed Rays
grow uh like kind of mounded growing um
so on the left side this is India and
you can see that there's a hump where
the vines are planted in the row and
on this is also Brazil on the right and
I thought I'd put one of Highland in
here but I don't have it um so they did
that to kind of keep the water table a
little bit lower by having the vines
start off at a higher
point and then aside from that there
were also Vineyards in Brazil where they
had trenches that they dug to kind of
help instead of tile drainage where you
dig you set the tiles and then you kind
of cover it back up they just dug it and
left it open and they
have pipes or not pipes other trenches
going across this way in some rows that
drain into this main trench so this is a
way that they kind of either lowered the
water table or kept the root Zone a
little bit
drier so some of the major pests that
were there are worms caterpillars and
thrips as well as melee bugs so we
looking here can anybody def find or see
any
pest here
anybody yeah
okay
so it's right here on this Leaf you
can't really see I believe that's a Mee
bug this is for sure a melee bug uh
anyone know what this is
these are worm eggs so you'll see this
worm in the tropics quite a bit I'm not
sure if they're coming here or not um
but these are the egg nests for these
worms here they're also large
caterpillars in
Thailand so that is it's kind of freaky
when you came across one of these and
then there were these weird horn beetles
that would bore into some of these
Trunks and it basically ate into this
spur across part of this trunk and went
in this way and we kept cutting back
cutting back cutting back and then it
wasn't there but we ended up cutting off
this whole part of the Cordon because it
was eaten through it there was a big
hole not too common but it is there
aside from insect pests there are also
other animal predation pests such as bir
birds in Brazil you would have these big
birds and sometimes two cans come in
eating your grapes and in Thailand you
would have monkeys coming in from the
forest as well as once in a while you'd
have elephants marching into the
vineyard and they
had uh barbed wire or fencing all around
the place but there's one section where
the elephant didn't care you know they
just come right through and not much you
can do about
that um so it's kind of kind of a tough
situation there but luckily it's not too
common
uh for
viruses rupes stem pitting is a common
one leaf roll is another um because as I
mentioned they propagate their own Vines
and there's no virus free initiatives
there you know there will be more of
these viruses present I believe this is
some kind of virus I can't say exactly
what it is it could be possib role do
you have any idea Justine or
anybody yeah hard to say and then this
trunk with was also split could be virus
maybe not what virus I'm not sure and
there's buter Saria trunk disease as
well um and this is what I'm being shown
here by the vineyard manager in southern
Thailand and he is actually from Germany
he did an internship there and liked it
he was asked to stay so he stayed there
and he's been working there for about 12
years now but it's interesting because
this guy as well as the person I was
working with both were trained in the
more traditional regions he was trained
in Germany the person that I was uh
working under in Thailand she was
trained in Australia so they both have a
better idea of some of the scientific
developments and other good
practices weed management was another
thing as I mentioned people spray um
India didn't really have too much weed
management happening one Vineyard in
Thailand had sheep that they were
through their field this was a organic
Vineyard so they tried to not use too
many
things um but sheep and then in this
other veneer that I was interning at
they used hes these white base hes and
we kind of just dug up the weeds under
the vines again it took a lot of manual
effort but works I
guess um and diseases dowy mildew
powdery mildew and thos are common um
some anthos on these grapes here um noo
on this
Leaf um I think it's powdery on this
one just a lot of disease in here and
this is the organic Vineyard here so
that's probably
why and what they did for this is they
had their
typical
sprays um but as in addition to that
they would use some other things my
notes didn't transfer but they have
other
sprays such as
this type
of find
it yeah sorry this presentation was
supposed to be on my laptop here but
then it wasn't working so I put it here
and didn't share this other part but uh
it's some kind of biological control I
can look it up after and let you know
what it
was uh continuous harvesting in Brazil I
just wanted to touch on this I mentioned
it previously but unlike Thailand where
they have so much rain in one season and
no rain in the other they were just dry
year round so they could just
continuously Harvest as soon as you
prune the vine you could then go ahead
and start the next growing season um so
all of these pictures were all happening
within one month of each other and as
you can see they're all in very
different stages here you have recently
prune no bud burst at all and then here
you see vegetation I believe they're
just across the the aisle from each
other um but in very different stages
and then another Vineyard at the same
time is also almost ready to harvest
here so again a very unique opportunity
for these Vineyards and possibly a
unique opportunity to explore further um
as
well out side of that here are some
other interesting things that I didn't
really expect but can anybody see the
snake in this bottom picture
yeah yeah and then the snake head
here so and then this is when it came
out but I was actually stepping on this
snake when we were grafting I was
sitting down on a stool I was cutting
the vine and I felt my the ground moving
under me I didn't know what it was so I
stopped I kind of look and then I get
back to work and I feel it again and I
really wasn't sure what it was
and then I thought maybe I just
dehydrated because it was very hot it
was in the mid 90s with like 90%
humidity full sun it was brutal um but
it was a snake and what we ended up
doing for the next hour is catching the
snake and then we released it right
across the street so it probably came
right back the next hour but we CAU the
snake and this is a different snake this
is a tree snake and a little bit more
scary because when we're working in the
canopy you might accident accidentally
touch the snake or get too close and it
might bite you um luckily someone saw it
and then
we whacked it with a stick and this one
died so this one won't be coming
back and this is just another thing that
I wanted to bring up I wasn't really
sure what to make of it but air Roots
were very common you don't see it as
much I would say here um but they were
on a lot of the vines and
quite quite a bit of it too so I don't
know if anyone here has any experience
with why this might be the case in the
tropics just wanted to kind of see it a
lot in more human So Long Island for
example it's actually quite common
aerial Roots we don't see it very often
up here unless it's very humid
here okay so it's just the humidity
somehow the plant wants
to okay yeah this is very very typical
to see and these are just some of the
people that I worked with uh who hosted
me while I was there um this is one of
The Vineyards that they grew table
grapes but they also made wine this is
the third wine this last one that you
just had um was from this Vineyard that
they grew it on a overhead
pergola um this is another block of the
same
Vineyard in this picture it
is in another Petrina um Vineyard
I believe this is
[Music]
the okay this is a different one but
yeah this that's good thank
you I thought there was
one um this first one that you had the
sparkling was this Vineyard that I
visited and they make a lot of sparkling
they also make wine for a lot of
different labels it was just a huge
facility and then these are the people
that I interned worked with in
Thailand um
here and of course there has to be a
Vineyard dog Thailand had Vineyard five
dogs a lot of them are wild um but this
one was named
namt and yeah can move to question as
manushi pours this last wine that is
from Thailand this is the vineyard that
I internet I thought that they had the
best line overall that I tried so um
yeah what cultivar is this one this is a
petit s
dff Thailand what is the typical
timeline for production there do they
try to avoid the monsoon season or do
they figure out a way to work that in no
they they pretty much have a full
growing cycle during the Monson season
they just remove all the grapes um so
the plant can just have vegetative
growth uh because unfortunately
unfortunately I guess The Vines don't
experience any natural dorcy and because
of that it's going to keep growing and
you
can make it here you can make it
dormant but you can't make it stay
dormant for too long it's going to come
back sooner than later so rather than
just keep killing them everything that's
out there they just let it grow let it
uh just have vegetation and then prune
it before the season that they want um
as you can see here
between in September they prune fruit
sets going to be in October and it's
September through October because a lot
of different blocks um take time to go
through and they also start off with I
believe the Reds and then do the whites
because the whites have a shorter
growing season fruits set happens here
generally and then grows through
December January and then the sparkling
that will harvest in January typically
you can do an earlier Harvest and uh the
Reds February the bigger Reds like this
one maybe Cabernet San could be end of
March sometimes I think it can go
through maybe a early April but usually
by March that's the
end yeah yes how about the management
what kind ofer that they use and do they
use like organic
fertilizer organic isn't too big of a
thing so most of The Vineyards don't do
organic that one that I showed you with
the Sheep is the only one that I know of
who goes out of their way to use organic
management as far as the exact types of
a fertilizer I'm not sure this is a
discussion that I had with Justine
yesterday about some of the uh
pesticides and fdes that they use I
asked about it and they gave me this
sheet the their spray schedule and half
of it's in Thai and when you translate
it didn't exactly come out um so I'm not
exactly sure what they do but I do know
that they
ferate um across I think several of the
different Vineyards I went to they
ferate quite a bit so I'd assume it's
more or less standard and it's going to
kind of depend on uh the situation at
each Vineyard depending on what they
need in there for their
soil yes already mentioned this but
regarding the amount of like sunlight
cloud cover that you see throughout the
growing Seasons that people choose do
use find that some regions had more
consistent sunlight or is it
variable
so this this is for uh Thailand
specifically
um generally in September October it's
still the very edge or like end of
monsoon season so there's some rain and
cloud cover once you get to the end of
October November it is very very Sunny
very hot uh all the way through December
and then January so they get a lot of
sun if you go further south to the other
Vineyard it is also very sunny um hotter
too in India it can also be fairly Sunny
although there you know are clouds um in
Brazil it would also be very sunny as
well so all of these regions had a lot
of sun cloud cover occasionally but it
wasn't a regular thing and it's not to
be expected either too too
often continu
gr that's a great question
so I've heard that in the southern part
of Brazil they do have to do replants a
little more often or actually not the
southern the northern part of it they
need to do it more often that's what I
heard from some people who told me um I
outside of there but when I spoke to the
folks at one of The Vineyards there they
were saying it's so new that they're not
entirely sure how long the vines will
last they only really planted about 30
years ago and that's their oldest block
and they haven't had to do a replant yet
for that block um and that's one of the
most established longest you know
lasting Vineyards there so as far as
they know no it's not any shorter but at
the same time
we don't really know C for
certain yes so with the continuous har
so you mentioned spr Dy yes doing can
you get more gra to grow just by pring
or you always have to spray something to
force the vine dorcy first or can you
just print it and it'll grow more graes
you could prune it I think the idea
behind spraying is to kind of allow the
plant sometime to pull back some
nutrients back to its roots and like
kind of store um but in terms of being
able to just prune that's that's a
possibility I'd say the bigger bigger
thing is coming out of
dormy um applying the ethon or ethon no
the cyanamide yes the cyanamide is a
bigger thing uh because you will get Bud
bursts regardless of whether you apply
that or not
but this allows for more uniform Bud
burst otherwise what you may see is Bud
burst towards the edges because of
apical dominance whereas the middle
might not have very much or it might
be weaker
growth um and because the outer ones are
going to be a lot more developed by the
time the middle one even burst it's
going to have uneven ripening if you
have fruit and it could just over the
outer ones could overtake the middle and
the middle might not grow enough at all
so that's the big thing and um one of
The Vineyards in Brazil specifically
mentioned instead of using cyanamide
they use a garlic mix like it's garlic
in water and they put that on um and it
works I don't know if it works I I think
I heard a couple people using that and
the the organic Winery in Thailand also
said
that it's I think it needs to be looked
at a little more I did see one people
that kind of mentions that um if I find
it I can send it out but it
is supposedly
effective can take you with a grain of
salt Marin a question for just a
general so I assume you're not fluent
Portuguese or so how did it work you
know not being a speaker commun Growers
managers and so forth and would you
advise other students to go to places
even though they might not
Lang yeah yeah the experience was pretty
good with the places that I got more
from I would say were the ones that
spoke some English as I mentioned the
place I've interned at she spoke English
she studied in Australia she knew kind
of what she was doing as far as in
addition the one in the South he was in
Germany you know German speak English
more or less and he also had a good idea
of what he's doing so I think
it is a great thing to go out and meet
other people from other places and
there's almost always someone who can
speak English and if not like in uh
let's see Thailand some places nobody
spoke English some people only spoke
Portuguese and Brazil but I mean we live
in a good time when we have Google
translate and there's a transcribed
feature so I could just record and they
speak and I can just read exactly what
they're saying so there's a lot of great
opportunity now that you can do that
type of thing with people that you
wouldn't have been able to before but
now you can so yes I wouldn't say that
it's a limiting factor at
all
yes yeah yeah so after they prune some
of it is used for
propagation um and then the rest of it
is dumped into the forest or somewhere
because we're in a very rural area and
there's nobody around they just have a
big pile
generally and it gives a very nice I
don't want to
me yeah yeah I think in Thailand one of
The Vineyards did sell some of the
cuting they dried out cuting for that
but I don't think it's a tradition or
something that everyone regularly does
um in any of these countries so it's
mostly either composted or thrown off to
the side something like that yeah
you think you'll learn what do you think
you've learned that you'll apply to your
time in um or when you set
placeis a lot so one of the things I did
notice is certain varieties just don't
do well at all in Brazil they didn't
work in Thailand they didn't work and
one of those varieties is like pin Noir
in Thailand they could barely get the
plant to grow um it's there but it has
no fruit and it's been maybe four or
five years now and then in
Brazil there was a vineard that is
growing P
Noir but I think they're only getting
about
maybe one case of wine per acre or
something crazy low and they have to
charge a ridiculous amount for that
bottle because it just costs a lot to do
and yeah it's just certain varieties
don't work certain ones do peti SAR SAR
are very good um as well as the canopy
management another thing that I forgot
to mention in preventing disease is
whenever it rains to prevent Downey
mildew they will just take the sprayer
through the vineyard RS and they'll just
turn the fan on high and blow off the
water they won't spray anything and
that's just to dry out the flowers so
that they don't get dowy mildew that's
something that I would probably do
because it's from what I understand it
makes all the difference in preventing
dowy
maybe last question and then we got to
wrap up
yes I just was gonna ask the um Market
or how has Market change for these these
regions and I guess are they exporting a
lot or is just kind of stay in Thailand
the market is very small um their
religion I think it's Buddhism they
actually weren't supposed to drink I
think at one point the strict Buddhists
and the newer ones do um but a lot of
it's beer song beer and Chang are the
two most common wine is a very new thing
it's starting to grow you see some
domestic tourists coming to visit the
vineyard but generally it's the
wealthier ones because I mean the wages
in US Dollars would be like $10 a day so
it's barely anything um so they can't
really afford it so you're going to see
the higher income classes getting these
Wines in Brazil they're able to
mechanize a lot more um than Canon they
produce cheaper wines that are like
under $5 a bottle they make a little bit
more so you do see more of a domestic
Market Brazil isn't exporting too much
Thailand is to the neighboring countries
Singapore China these other countries
that have higher incomes maybe not
overall but higher income individuals
that can afford it um otherwise that's
about the extent I would
say right we need to wrap up please join
me in thanking Kobe
if you're interested in the Dreer watch
the horiculture
uh Andor reach out to Martin H who would
be happy to share some information I
think this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu