Um, what an honor uh to be here. It's
such exciting uh discussions and um I'm
humbled uh to to come from here in East
Hawaii Island, very rural uh
communities. I wanted to I think a lot
about uh human behavior. Again, my name
is Scott Larson. and I'm a climate uh
adaptation extension specialist with
PyASK and I have been for a little over
10 years and and and thinking about
human behavior and we've talked a little
bit about that already in the previous
discussions you'll see some linkages and
so I thought one way to to share that is
to talk about my behavior and uh one of
the uh the core to my professional path
has always been to be regularly immersed
in the natural world and um equal to
that has been to develop and and and um
foster genuine connection or meaningful
relationship ships and in doing that um
essentially I I really had focused on um
sustenance and when I say that I mean in
in remote locations and and deeply
connected to the natural world
connecting to our food, water, shelter
basics. Obviously that's heavily linked
ancestrally as well to to u health and
I'm going to really center on well-being
a little bit more. Uh but in doing that
I'm going to share um sort of North
America and my experience and research
and and leading outdoor expeditions
outdoor expeditions there and then
transition to um where I am now in in
middle of the Pacific Ocean and share
that transition again in a sense of of
human behavior and and um it's not at
all to diminish to to to to cue into
Sharon's talk. and you remember acutely
when you tear your ACL. Um, in remote
places, you value emergency rooms and
access to them and and hospital visits
and those things, but I'm really
focusing on well-being that transcends
some of that. Um, it doesn't mean it's
more important. It's just the sense of
well-being and um, and I'll get into
that next as far as connection and
relationships. And so, this is a biscom
pine in the upper left from uh, the
middle of Colorado. It's a it's a it's
an individual that I began to learn very
well its stories um through
dendrochronology and other other work
that I had done in this very remote area
at Treeline. Uh looking into the changes
in its stories or the way it tells its
story of change over more than 1200
years. Um this this this species this
individual has been alive and it put me
in a place of understanding my place how
small it is and how for me that's where
I felt most alive. So getting back to
that connection to nature and
sustenance, I followed it in a human
behavior way because it's where I felt
most alive and I'm doing that to this
day. And the bottom right um I should
say the linkage from the left to the
right is that's one of the best mentors
I've ever had. It's a black lab mut
again linking to Sharon's talk is um and
also the greatest hunter I've ever
known. And so the bottom right is my
work. The upper right was re researching
white pines in the Rockies and then the
bottom right is in northwest Wyoming
researching wolves. And um the linkage
there is it really was compelling to for
me to understand wolves better through
my dog, this this great friend of mine
and then vice versa. and particularly in
the sense of sustenance of food and
hunting and watching and being
particularly in the winter with wolves
uh trained me much more deeply and truly
to connect to place sure but
pragmatically to find food successfully.
And so um this is David Abram wrote a
book that was really powerful in 1996
called the um spell of the sensuous and
it really was a gamecher in literature
of um essentially he's saying we are
only human in as much as we are
connected to more than human. In other
words, if we're not connected to nature
we're missing our capacity uh in a
psyche sense the development of our
psyche. And so um going further at that
time, this is again all the about 2000s
um in in northwest Wyoming. And you
know, at the same time, I was I was
engaging outdoor education as research
in leading short um week-long small
group expeditions, but I was also
hunting and using my botanical skills
with a friend of mine, a non-blood
brother named Kevin. And we'd go up into
say 9 10,000 ft uh applying our
knowledge of ecosystems. And we start in
the low areas, you know, digging
Yampampaoot going up to a range of
berries up elevation in the fall and
then we transition to small game hunting
and and um deer and and we wouldn't we'd
stay out there uh in the sense of not
having refrigeration, not some we're not
packing out anything. We're preserving
the food in place. And that's Doug Doug
fur tea I'm drinking in the upper left.
And the idea here is is this is bear
country. So, it's a certain heightened
awareness in Northwest Wyoming when you
are doing these kinds of things. And um
I found that not only was I most alive
in these situations, I I saw my own
horizons much better in a way of
pursuing my professional development of
connection to place. And so, Whoops. I
think I Yeah. Whoops. Oh, so moving
north in Alaska, uh again the mid 2000s
by this point and late 2000s. Um it's
the relationships across the operators
in these week-long, in this case was two
week long expeditions across global
cultures. It was World Wildlife Funds
send their clientele across all kinds of
cultures and we would link up in these
small groups of say six to 10 people
that we build a team and that team was
embedded deeply within boat captains,
float planes. Um, and establishing trust
there is fundamental because when things
go south and they will, you got to be
ready and you have to have open
communication. And I don't mean just
with the human components. And so this
is a fascinating way to engage human
behavior at at more of an extreme as
you're furthering north in North America
and latitudes. Um, and at the same time,
the species that I was used to in in
northwest Wyoming were vastly different
and the same. They're the same species,
right? The coastal grizzly, the coastal
brown bear versus the grizzlies of
Yellowstone, but they function totally
differently. And if I'm an omnivore and
I'm thinking of sustenance, that's an
omnivore. and most everything they eat
seasonally, even though it's very
different from the the interior bears of
Alaska or the grizzlies in Yellowstone,
I can eat mostly what they can. It's an
amazing connection to to reconnect to in
these ways across species in different
uh ecosystems. But again, the human
element is where I found myself most
situated. And working with people that
generationally have been engaged in
these areas was amazing. That's a a very
rugged uh cabin of a very rugged woman
connected to place. It's Jod and Lucas
from the early 1900s. That's Kevin and I
again uh with some of the the clothes
that we tanned from their hunting
endeavors. But that's Peter and Mary,
good friends of mine from Rankin Inlet
on Hudson Bay. Um and that's Peter in
the right doing a drum dance while Mary
is chanting. And we're in a small
structure built of essentially bearded
seal seal skin hut. and uh amazing to
see much more deeply not only into
generational connection to place and
survival well-being etc and adaptation
but therein to find myself more deeply
and so as I go further north again the
bear ecology totally changes with polar
bears it's vast open expanses and these
bears unlike brown bears and black bears
that are gone within nine out of 10en
times before you even know they're you
are in their area these bears will come
right to you and It's it's also
extremely remote as far as resources. So
you need each other, you need these
relationships in place where you don't
have like aabaskan interior culture, say
in Alaska or across Canada, um all kinds
of wood and lots of resources. It's it's
driftwood here and except in the ocean.
And the the point is uh change is
paramount and as the the communities
change the the more than human so the
the human and the Dorset culture. Sorry,
we're missing one. Oh, there it is. The
Dorset culture uh was one that was used
to heavy ice and they would hunt and
fish from the ice hand lining
essentially two-tonon or one ton
animals, marine mammals, and that was
massive. And they were around for 1500
stable years and then the climate shifts
around 500 AD, the medieval warming era,
and you get a very quick transition to
the Tuli people. Um, and I leave those
upper left amulets indicating that
throughout that that era, the Tuli being
the predecessor of sort of Inuit,
Upupic, Inupia, uh, and certainly uh,
all across coastal communities. But that
deep connection, those are amulets that
are Dorset amulets that are maybe an
inch or two hyper accurate skull
structures of polar bears. And then
there's more stylized. They're really
getting at spiritual realms and and and
more swimming behaviors and and just a
fascinating connection. And by the time
the tulie take over, they're using open
ocean crafts to
harness right whales or um and and these
whales are so massive um that that
stabilizes the seasonality of of the
tuli culture um and and from again a
sustenance standpoint. Uh but I need to
quick go through there we go that all
those relationships by the time I'm in
Hawaii in 2010 I realized very quickly
that information data is not knowledge
um not very quickly I mean over that
time I came to Hawaii understanding that
information is is not knowledge nor do
we become any more knowledgeable through
information accumulation. it
knowledgeability rather sits is situated
in uh that information within the
context of direct perceptual engagements
with our environment. In other words,
experience. And this is a quote from Tim
Engold, one of the paramount um folks in
establishing environmental anthropology
as a as a new um discipline currently
since basically from the 80s to now. And
um you know through that time so if if
information is not knowledge, well what
is knowledge? Well, we just talked about
that as situated information through
experience. And then how come with all
the decades of applied science and
climate science have we not seen more
human behavior change? Well,
psychologists, cognitive e uh biologists
and certainly um a range of social
sciences have said, well, if you want to
engage behavior, engage affect emotion.
Um and what they're getting at is the
the type one and two knowledge forms or
knowledge systems. Type one is visceral,
quick acting, very impactual instinct,
intuition, emotion, uh unconscious.
Again, thinking about hunting and
fishing, that kind of thing. Uh
gardening as well. Um and the system two
is that long-term slower to react
reason, logic, analysis, etc. And it's
not saying one is better than the other,
but it is saying most of the research
suggests if these two diverge in one
person, the visceral knowledge forms are
going to dominate behavior. But the
point is we need them both. And it
really is not thinking of climate change
as some distant future or vast geography
and objectivity. It's really shifting uh
social sciences have made clear we need
to think about climate change as deeply
personal, deeply local and deeply uh
present in this moment. And so with that
in 2015, I had developed uh with a
number of uh leaders co-developed the
the the manager climate corps which is a
research program for graduate students
where they get two-year immersions into
community. And what I mean by community
is I had worked hard to find the
long-term relationships connected to
place in East Hawaii uh and Hawaii
Island. Um and that is people who uh
cultural practitioners, heritage uh
managers, uh natural resource managers,
policy professionals who are deeply
connected to not only the more than
human place but also the communities of
humans that utilize and engage that
area. And so when I show these
foundational elements, hopefully they
they of of the manager climate core
program, um hopefully they make sense a
little bit more and I don't really need
to go through them as you think about
the slides I've shared in my path, but
uh we've had 20 grad students go through
this over five cohorts and it's been a
hugely engaging way to drop graduate
students into long-term relationships
through practitioners of place. Um and
then before I have a little time um I
can I want to there you'll see in the
website that we're linked that that
those websites will show you about the
manager climate corps in detail but I'm
going to shift those same foundations of
that program that's been going on for
the last 10 year or yeah 10 years um and
show those same foundations applied in
new ways into new locations and this is
Kakua on the west Hawaii island is uh
known more so globally now as one of
those top coral reef snorkel
environments Very few of those folks
engaging the reef understand the huge
power of that area as far as the native
Hawaiian history and contemporary
culture and that's hika from the late
18th century in the in the artist
rendition practice there in in that ha
or or sacred place sacred structure has
been traditional practice has gone on
from then to the present moment without
interruption. Um, so if you think about
sustenance, connection to food, water,
shelter, particularly within more than
human, what a great place to consider.
And so the community action plan that
was developed was driven by traditional
that community itself. And it was
embedded into the state parks top down
kind of more conventional plan um to
really join those two to have at the
same time a community-driven plan united
with a a state parks plan. the first
kind of that sort that has has been
established in in Hawaii, the state of
Hawaii. And um importantly,
relationality or kinship modalities is
the only crosscutting theme of that
community action plan. Um and that so
another way to think of it is the goal
here is to root the practices in heia
that have again as far as relationality
or kinship have been uh handed down for
generations and root them much more
deeply in um in all the surrounding
activities whether that's tourism
experience industries uh certainly
research that has largely been
parachuted in and not really engaging
the community. shifting all as as we can
patiently slowly to engage heritage
management to engage natural resource
management through those very specific
practices in that area. Um and that's a
new five-year program that's being
developed uh currently. We're in our
first year with that um partnering with
Cornell for that uh from uh and so as an
example of a practice what in in the
area and of course Pacificwide and
actually globally this is a this
outrigger canoe paddling is a powerful
way to demonstrate this is an sort of an
introduction to outrigger canoe paddling
what has been handed down for
generations to obtain sustenance to to
survive whether it's fishing hunting uh
adaptation as far as war transportation
These are basics that have come down
through generations. Um and and and
really many spatial scales and temporal
scales are engaged here. Whether you're
talking about ground swells impacting
the canoe, how to navigate that at the
same time as wind chop. And then if we
take that notion of practice to a
broader scale, back to that manager
climate core. Again, those are two-year
research projects that graduate students
were driving. Well, what if each of the
islands here are stages or research
projects? So like the first five there
that are darker, those could be each a
research project. And if you're
maintaining the relationships as as sort
of embodied in in the canoe itself and
and the navigators within the canoe. Um
that final island, the sixth island is
where you engage for example through
Kellua Bay, the community action plan I
shared, deep kinship connection and
therein the capacity for gaining local
sustenance, food, water, shelter, but
also a way to adapt that's been intact
for centuries. Um, and if if if we don't
consider th those those tremendous
capacities just in the human condition,
we're missing a lot of what it is to not
only adapt, but actually to find our
deeper sense of self, our well-being,
and certainly um health as far as our
ability to survive. So, thanks very much
for your time. And that's what I got.
I'm just curious u and Sharon uh hop on
when you're ready for your concluding
statements, but I'm just curious, Scott,
uh you're you're you're taking in this
relationality.
Um it's a very organic relationality and
one that I personally can understand or
relate to. But we are entering into this
incredible abstract moment of artificial
intelligence
um which is still you know two degrees
of separation from whoever generated the
basis for which the AI is going at. But
um how are you thinking about
incorporating or or
informing that
trajectory in that direction? Right? How
how how are we going to sort of
integrate this massive ecosystem
thinking, corporeal thinking with these
databased AI based
[Music]
um formulas for understanding the bigger
picture, right? They're two different
ways. And I'm just curious how you're
thinking about how we can
I tried to give an example of how I
didn't mention too much of the research
I'm involved with and have been for
decades that I didn't focus on that as
much
as engaging that research and and
largely in place. And so that's one of
the things I'd say is, you know, I'm
talking about remote wilderness
experience, sustenance, and building
shelter in that way. But no less is this
applied with with local sustenance in a
garden at a backyard garden or a front
yard garden. And the more that we're in
it engaging the senses like in the sense
of I mentioned with um David Abrams
spell of the sensuous that's just as
paramount and particularly when global
supply chains are in question and and
we're talking about massively
unsustainable connectivity globally in
relation to to to carbon uh budgets and
it's it's unnatural to maintain those
pathways to connect to place more and
more. Um, that doesn't mean, you know,
that I know where this shirt was made
from, but I try to make clothing to to
grow food or to wild harvest food. And
the more that we're doing that, David
Abram would suggest that the more we're
capable of finding our own well-being,
our own sense of self instinctively um
that's been handed down for for
centuries to all cultures, to all
people. And that's kind of what I've
been on the path of and that's what I'd
sort of answer with is just say that
doesn't with all the things going on
none of that negates the need to connect
to place. In fact, it only emphasizes it
in my ru my zone and it doesn't suggest
that we shouldn't uh consider these
these large technologies. Um but as as
Sharon presented there are costs to a
lot of these whether it's AI she
mentioned some of the cooling that's
needed. Um the we need to think of all
the spectrum of impacts in in plus and
minus ways specifically towards
sustainability of all species, not just
our own. And the more we consider that,
the less we're not centered on humans,
the more I found that we'll become truly
human. This has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu. edu.