this is a production of Cornell
University all right good afternoon so
my name is Aaron mcken and it's great to
see so many familiar faces um for the
last year and a half i' have I've had
the pleasure of being a grad student in
the horiculture department and working
very closely also with Cornell
plantations and their
staff so I really gravitated to public
Horticulture because of a love of plants
and for me public Horticulture really
brings together how plants can be used
to serve ecological communities and
human communities alike um and so when I
Was preparing for this presentation I
was kind of asking myself why why
marketing why did you choose this topic
and what makes it exciting about public
Horticulture and you guys might be
wondering that as well but for me
basically um I felt that this there was
a kind of a gap in here um in terms of
the collaborative aspects of public of
public marketing um and I felt that by
gaining expertise in this um and
coupling that with my passion for plants
that I would be able to fill a niche
when I go and seek a career after this
master's program is over so today I'm
going to share with you um some of the
results from my research while I've been
a graduate student and so just to put it
in context kind of
increasingly um in an increasingly
competitive Marketplace public
Horticulture institutions have um
started joining together with other arts
and culture organizations in their area
to create what is called a public or a
collaborative Marketing Group which I'm
going to shorten and say CMG which I
think you guys will all enjoy hearing
better than the mouthful of
collaborative Marketing Group so
synonymously we'll use those so in this
increasingly competitive Marketplace um
um the collaborative marketing groups
have enabled Gardens and other
organizations to reduce their marketing
costs and also tap into customer
expertise um and furthermore this
collaboration is a strategy for
maximizing the potential of marketing
and better addressing um the concept of
destination
marketing so this project directly
addressed the knowledge Gap in the field
of public Horticulture related to these
strategies um collaborative Partnerships
are socially contrived mechanisms for
Collective action a CMG is a venture
shared between a group of associated
organizations that aims to um obtain
greater recognition resources and
results for those organizations when
compared to those individual
organizations working
alone so CMG efforts specifically aim to
increase the success of these
organizations as they engage in
collaborative problem solving and they
also create a platform for information
Exchange
so the core research question was are
collaborative marketing groups an
effective way for par Public Gardens to
Market their mission to Their audience
and then uh sequentially I also asked
what were the motivations in conditions
for that Garden to join what were some
of the Key activities and best
management practices being uh that were
outcomes of the CMG and then what were
the most valued outcomes both monetary
and non-monetary
the methods that I used to kind of
obtain this data were um in two sections
and the first was interviews with five
case study Gardens um and key marketing
staff at those
Gardens and the second was an electronic
survey and so of the 30 Gardens that I
sent the survey to 25 completed it so as
a return rate it was pretty good and it
was such a small sample size because
each of these Gardens were participating
in a collaborative Marketing Group so
that was kind of like the key factor in
them getting the survey to begin with so
the survey asked about the garden
satisfaction with their CMG performance
and it also designed to was designed to
answer the core research
questions the interviews were the
purpose of those W um were basically to
understand the current practices being
employed by these cmgs at Public Gardens
and um that interview was conducted in
two sections so the first section was
using the business model generation
canvas which I recognize that this you
may not be able to see each of the
headers but this is a visual way of
laying out a business model and I have
basically the experience of using this
is you bring a big like 6x5 version of
this into a a a room where you have
sharehold or stakeholders in the
conversation and then we use Post-it
notes and kind of dialogue to then
populate each area so it's a way of
visually representing the business
business model and outlining you know
what is the what is the value
proposition or the mission of the garden
who are their customers Their audience
and then what are the channels that they
reach reach that audience with so so on
and so forth and then when we got to the
section of key Partners we turned to the
conversation to ask how does the
CMG basically open up new channels or
provide Key activities or key resources
for them to achieve their mission which
in nonprofit horiculture is Paramount
achieving the missions so this is just
kind of here for um a visual aid but if
anybody's interested in learning more
about the canvas and the business model
generation handbook I'd talk to you
about that later and could provide more
resources so I'm going to go through
each of the five case study interviews
now and basically the second part of the
interview which I I failed to comment on
was a series of open-ended questions and
so the summary of each interview I'm
about to provide is the canvas and that
that the open-ended questions so really
it was obviously a qualitative analysis
and um we had a lot of fun while we were
doing it and it was reciprocal the
gardens gained a lot out of that process
of going through the canvas and then I
gained quite a bit of information as
well so my first interview was with
Cornell plantations right here in itha
and they are part of a collaborative
effort of local cultural institutions
called The Discovery Trail which many of
you hopefully are aware of Discovery
Trail partnership is a group of
nonprofit organizations based here that
promote the awareness and understanding
of connections of the connections
between art History Literature science
and the natural
world the goal of the discovery Trail is
to collectively Market the member
organizations to tourists that are over
90 miles away and so this is a region
which Cornell plant that that tourist
audience is a region that's a little bit
less attainable for Gardens specifically
Cornell plantations to put M valuable
marketing resources too so Discovery
Trail really AIDS in in um in
compensating for that in a way so
Discovery Trail is supported by annual
membership dues as well as through the
Strategic tourism the Tomkins County
strategic tourism board and again I'm
I'll mention its um main function is to
increase public awareness and positively
impact the visitation of each of the
member member organizations to Discovery
Trail so it one of the things that has
evolved out of this successful
partnership um over time is an
educational program called kids kids
discover the trail and so this was kind
of a learning moment in you know even
just the first interview where I
realized that the the longevity or the
age of a collaborative Marketing Group
influenced the level of their activity
so for example Discovery Trail once they
became more seasoned decided to create
and um evolve or basically
formalize this educational program
through their through their um shared
kind of
collaboration um and I'll come back to
that point later in the outcomes so
other non-m manitary B uh benefits of
the discovery Trail for plantations
include strengthening their branded
cultural identity of itha so really
creating more of a destination marketing
um brand here in itha for for people
that aren't living here to when they
come visit they can really identify
with what there is to do when you visit
and then top of Mind awareness in
potential customer audience's mind so
that goes for both Regional people that
live here and then people that are
visiting um creating that top of mine
awareness my second interview is with
Garden in the woods which is
headquartered which is the headquarters
for New England Wildflower society and
the Massachusetts Garden botanic garden
group was established in 2012 to better
leverage um the various Public Gardens
throughout the state of
Massachusetts and so this was created by
the recommendation of the Massachusetts
office of travel and tourism so there
was actually an outside you know body
saying you all you Gardens need to get
together and create this and they also
felt that strength and numbers would
really enable them to um increase
audience awareness of the 11
participating Gardens and make kind of a
viable and robust Partnership if they if
they join together so the CMG is still
in the early early stages of its
development but it's already impacted
how New England Wildflower Society
thinks about marketing um it's funded
through member dues
and as well as um they're able to gain
uh financial support from convention and
visitors bureaus and the Massachusetts
office of travel and tourism so that's
that's funding that they wouldn't have
access to if they weren't collaborating
it's another another kind of key
outcome so this this CMG provides a
really key marketing channel and the
vehicle for that is a shared website and
that's a that's been a common theme so
these cmgs create websites to
collectively tell what's going on so
whether that's through an events
calendar or just simply through creating
links to their websites this is a way to
achieve a more Dynamic marketing mix for
Gardens that a lot of times don't have a
very very substantial marketing budget
so furthermore the CMG strengthens New
England Wildflower society's
relationship with their peer Gardens and
it really does enfor reinforce that um
climate for knowledge sharing among
professionals um so much in nonprofit
Horticulture or you know any nonprofit
field there are various people working
in the same positions trying to achieve
the same goals and so if we can share
kind of day-to-day you know knowledge
about day-to-day activities about how to
best achieve you know the promotion of
these individual organizations that
basically is what the CMG is able to
formalize the process
of so Chicago Botanic Garden was my
third interview and destination
marketing is kind of an ever important
um strategy for nonprofit Gardens to use
so increasing in order to increase their
visitation and attendance du North is
the collaborative that Chicago um is a
part of and these
organizations have joined forces to kind
of like bring attention to the do the
North Shore region which is 40 minutes
north of downtown Chicago and so the
reason why this is significant is
because you know people go to Chicago to
go to downtown but they don't
necessarily know what's going on in that
in that neighborhood up there and so
there is a wealth of cultural
organizations there and they've decided
to join together to cross program and
cross market so the interview with
Chicago Botanic Garden revealed that du
North has not just an economic impact on
the garden but but also on the region as
a whole um by attracting tourists to
that area so in addition to this
destination marketing strategy um the
collaborative also impacts um their
bottom line by appealing to a few key
donors and this was also kind of a big
realization from this interview and the
one that I'll talk about next so people
that give large um large contributions
to Gardens then want to have some
involvement in in the decision- making
and kind of the the future of how that
is going to be portrayed to its audience
and so the staff at the Chicago Botanic
Garden really felt that they were
serving this key these key donor wishes
by demonstrating that they're using
their philanthropic um contributions in
a in an effective way by collaborating
with these other organizations and
basically creating a brand to promote
the whole area not just their Garden so
the public response also has been very
positive to the do North collaborative
because they like seeing the
organization in their area work
collaboratively so that brings me to
redb Garden in Salt Lake City which is
part of a a CMG called Foothill Cultural
District which is comprised of seven
destinations along Salt Lake City's B um
Foothill Boulevard the mission of this
Marketing Group is to provide visitors
with the opportunity to experience
Utah's fascinating art culture history
and stunning natural areas um in an
easily accessible way and using public
transportation so the Foothills Cultural
District also was really um created
because of the vision of a local
philanthropist Zeke dumpy who also gave
significant contributions to the Garden
um and has like you know like a building
named after him and things like this so
he's like one of their key donors and
really important and he said to them and
the other organizations he said hey I
give to all of you individually I really
want you all to work together and so
they you know they through they did some
trialing and some piloting of those that
program and then it it basically was
formalized in 2004 and some of their um
some of the key key resources that comes
out of this collaborative Marketing
Group is they really can Leverage The
collaboration when they're applying for
Grants um so they end up acquiring funds
because they state that they're in
collaboration with these other
organizations and they're also part of a
cultural tax District that you know
looks favorably upon their their
collaborative
efforts so this culture of collaboration
also creates the perception that redb
and the other member Gardens are
Community Players um and so again this
is kind of evolved in the direction of
more shared programming and it's not
just it's no longer just a marketing
platform so my final interview was um at
the Scott Arboretum in Media
Pennsylvania and if anybody's been to
the Philly area you know that that area
is rich in Botanical Gardens and
arborita and um the Scott ARB burum is
unique they're part of um two separate
collaborative marketing groups and the
first one I'm going to comment on is
called Greater Philadelphia Gardens and
that is the oldest collaborative that I
interviewed and it's comprised of 30
member Gardens in a 30 mile radius of
Philadelphia so that's a high density of
Gardens and that Regional proximity was
kind of the basic for why they created
the collaborative back in the 80s but it
also then evolved because um you know it
creates this knowledge sharing among
Gardens as as I've mentioned before so
some of the Key activities of Greater
Philadelphia Gardens is that they work
to promote the member
Gardens across the board so some of the
members in that CMG are like really
well-known Gardens for example Longwood
which probably many of you have heard of
but then there's other which are lesser
known um and so the benefit that each of
these members are afforded is that their
reputation is extended by way of being
associated with these other bigger
Gardens so another really key activity
is that um that the pooling of those
resources enables Greater Philadelphia
Gardens to Market to an
international audience and so what I
want to give um just a moment to recog
recognizes that like I didn't interview
them but the bartrums garden is really
small that has huge historic
significance and their visitation levels
are like low and just like every like
many nonprofit Gardens you know has
struggled financially but what they've
tracked through Google analytics and
through their attendance is that because
of Greater Philadelphia Gardens
marketing to an international audience
they get tons of international visitors
and it's they couldn't pay to Market the
way that Greater Philadelphia Gardens is
is marketing for them if that makes
sense so that was just a really key key
um learning from my interview with them
so the second partnership that I'd like
to just talk about briefly with the Scot
AR redom is one that's more web- based
it's called the Delaware County Arts
Consortium and they are focused on a web
platform and calendar events calendar
called greater uh the Philly fund guide
and basically it's it's a way for the
Scott Arboretum to Market to people
regionally because even though you're
seated in a community and you think have
a you have a good handle on how to best
access people in your community there's
always there's always um new ways to
reach them and so this website really
enables um Scott the Scott ARB burum to
reach a local audience that they
previously didn't know how to so the
conditions for joining um are we're kind
of really a big key Focus for this study
and by definition collaboration requires
that a certain amount of autonomy is
kind of is sacri is is sacrificed by the
garden so they have to work together in
order to and put their their own
objectives kind of on the side so what's
really key before starting to create a
collaborative or deciding if you want to
join one would be that you know you want
to understand the institutional factors
of the other organizations that you're
joining in you want to understand the
culture and the um organizational goals
and then secondarily a a major theme was
that nonprofit leaders whether they be
executive directors or key donors were a
huge influential motivation for why a
garden would join um existing n network
and Regional proximity also greatly
influenc the likelihood of a
collaborative um either being created or
someone deciding to
join so just to share some of the
results of the electronic survey um the
motivation to collaborate must be based
on the CM 's ability to kind of attain
outcomes that the garden couldn't
achieve on its own so the survey
respondents basically stated that this
was a strategic decision for them and
that um joining the collaboration was
really like Paramount was that they
wanted to join together with the other
arts and culture organizations to create
that strength and numbers
concept and then moving into audience
which we've talked about before but
really accessing a wider tourist
audience through shared marketing
activities was another major priority um
for these
Gardens cmgs helped to establish kind of
transactional relationships with
visitors but this the research was not
showing that anything beyond a
transactional relationship was created
so what I mean by that is people found
out about the Garden or the
organizations in the area and they went
and visited but they didn't necessarily
buy a membership or become donors um and
so that a way that when you deepen the
programmatic involvement by creating
something like kids discover the trail
you can start to draw in uh more of a
relational um relationship with that
audience so some of the Key activities
were shared visibility and the vehicle
for that was oftentimes a website and
then just creating an economy of scale
for these Gardens to promote their
Garden through a website and lessen the
individual marketing costs that was a
major driving force
and furthermore the um interviews backed
up that the CMG opened up new channels
so they were actually able to access new
customers or audience that wasn't
previously kind of available to them
through the
collaborative and lastly um from the
electronic survey the respondents
answered that the most valuable outcomes
was increased publicity and visibility
of their Garden um Gardens indicated
that the CMG had improved relations with
regional cultural in institutions
because it facilitated and formalized
Partnerships and collaborations that
were already happening and so they were
now given you know they were given
permission in a way to and given you
know a platform to stand on in order to
to collaborate with one
another so across all interviews the
larger the garden and the more
established the collaborative Marketing
Group the more concrete the contributors
or my interviewees were on why their
Garden was involved and so I guess that
kind of goes with without saying but it
was still interesting um to kind of look
at collaboratives that were anywhere
from devel starting founded in 1980s all
the way up to 2012 um and so each
interviewee really highly valued the
triple bottom line Theory which really
takes into account and adds value to
Social Capital reputation awareness
building as viable outcomes of the
collaborative um so more more
performance evaluation is needed uh you
can't just say yes we're you know we're
having we have these non-monetary
outcomes and they're really good I mean
it's good to have a solid understanding
of that but more benchmarking would
definitely benefit um leaders in terms
of decision-making and validating their
their involvement in
this and so in conclusion um
collaborative marketing groups proved to
be a really effective way for
organizations to work in concert to
achieve Lar larger scale advertising
while saving money and
resources um they provide a solution to
align media and publicity expenditures
and help to stretch individual budgets
while diversifying the marketing mix of
individual gu individual
organizations having a better
understanding of the benefits of a CMG
would enable public garden leaders to
comprehend the value of collaboration
and justify the resources and staff time
that they allocate to it furthermore um
in improved forecasting would definitely
help to help them to make informed um
decisions so ideally the findings from
this study will and the use of the BMG
canvas and future research will help to
um provide knowledge that is required to
successfully engage in these formal
collaborations so I just want to thank
the um professors my advisers and
committee members the fellow public
garden leadership student
students and all of you for listening
today thank you very
[Applause]
much question um well that's where
social reputation really comes into play
and as you know when the when community
members or members of these these
organizations view that large garden as
um being philanthropic themselves in
sharing their brand and sharing their um
reputation that's kind of where they
gain the benefit and so yeah it's really
in in the nonprofit field you can kind
of create things based on non-monetary I
don't I don't really know how to answer
this question but basically they gain a
an improved reputation from it and this
can this this happens more often in a
nonprofit scenario does that help to
answer any other questions
okay thank
you this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu