this is a production of Cornell
University
hello and welcome to common diseases in
the garden
so I just picked up about a dirty dozen
or so of diseases that you're likely to
find where if you work on the grow liner
in your own garden and
they represent an array of
diseases that were some you see the
signs of the disease and some you see
the symptoms of the disease
and so let's just run through them very
quickly you're certainly not expected to
memorize them but just to have a feeling
for the diversity of diseases that
you'll find in the landscape
the first disease I wanted to go over
was powdery mildew funny mildew is one
of the easier diseases to identify
because there's a rightist sized which
is actually part of the fungi
that
covers the leaves usually on the top of
the leaves and it's actually a group of
fungi it's not just one specific one but
they all have specific host ranges so
they're ones that hit lilacs crab
zinnias dogwoods roses they are they're
all susceptible to powdery mildew and if
we have a cool
spring and summer it's we're almost
assured of seeing this disease so the
fungal hyphae
infect the outermost leaves and then
insert essentially their mouth part as
it were although they don't have a mouth
but the feeding part into the cells and
they feed off of the
photosynthate that the plant makes
as I mentioned the disease is much more
prevalent when it there's periods of
high humidity and rainfall so in terms
of a management issue you want to keep
the foliage as dry as possible so
certainly if you think that you have a
plant that's likely to get powdery
mildew let's say like a bed of
try not to overhead water those plants
try to water them so that the leaves
don't get wet
most of the time party mode is an
aesthetic issue not not so much a plant
health issue but it can be quite quite
bad looking I have found that party
mother on dog woods can go into the
stems and and cause sort of a
physiological
problem for for dog woods but otherwise
it just it's just unsightly
okay if you are a small home footballer
and specifically apples you're likely to
be dealing with apple scab it's
certainly one of the main
diseases that
orchardists have to deal with and it
causes small
spots on the leaves no big deal but it
also
causes spots on the apples it was out a
call from my
pathology 101 class with dr. Sinclair
who literally wrote the book on diseases
it doesn't affect the taste of the apple
at all it's just a surface thing that of
course if you were looking to buy an
apple that looked like that on the right
you you wouldn't buy it so it makes them
unsellable the fungus overwinters on
leaves that have dropped to the ground
and and hang around and serve as the
inoculum source for the next year's
infection and
there's there's a whole there's actually
software that's written to healthy time
if you are a professional orchardist
when you have to spray your plants
to prevent apple scab but for the home
orchardist especially if you're starting
an orchard it's really great if you can
select a resistant varieties it's going
to help
reduce the amount of
management effort that you're going to
have to have to have good apples
and that if you you know have an apple
tree already and you don't want to have
apple scab where you want to limit it
there are fungicides that you can use
and basically there's not a
one-size-fits-all
prescription for fungicide because it
really depends on the weather and then
you might want to avail yourself of some
of the Cornell apple scab software
programs so that you know when to spray
this could because this is a major issue
for for apple apple growers
going right from apples to strawberries
gray mold botrytis is
like powdery mildew the many botrytis
fungi and that they are characterized by
having this sort of gray
mold that is that easily comes off the
plant you can see in the picture on the
right there's the straw there's two good
strawberry sort of one on top of each
other and then just to the right of it
is a great moral defective strawberry
and you can see that the pattern of
spores have just sort of fallen off and
landed on the leaf reinfect another part
of the plant and botrytis unfortunately
affects a lot of different herbaceous
plants and like powdery mildew is
favored and cool wet springs and cool
summers of course you'll find that
that's true with our diseases a hot dry
year might be tough for the plants from
a lot of point of view but it's much
easier on them from a disease point of
view because a lot of diseases are
spread by
raindrops hitting the fungus releasing
the spores and the spores move to a new
part of the plant so anytime we have a
crew wet spring and a clue and wet ish
summer look to see a lot of diseases and
again people manage botrytis by trying
to not do much overhead watering of
course mother nature is going to going
to rain on the plants but if your
on a regular basis you'd want to water
just the base of the plant not the
leaves
Turks pot this is one of my favorite
diseases because it's pretty hard to
miss diagnosed and the good news is even
though this looks really horrible it
actually has pretty much no effect on
the tree it hits maples and it hits the
maples in the late part of the growing
season and that's why it really doesn't
have that much effect it gets going and
it can be you know pretty amazingly
throughout the plant and you know these
vibrant tar-like spots all over the
leaves and these are actually small
sometimes they're even they're the size
of a quarter or larger
but because they hit the plant late in
the in the growing season there's really
no management and it's really no real
effect on the tree overall and that
would be true for a lot of the diseases
that hit late in the season you know yes
they don't it makes a plant unsightly
that it really doesn't have a
physiological effect on the plant the
diseases we worry about other ones that
had in the spring and so that they're
compromising the plant throughout the
growing season diseases that hit later
in the year that only you know hit the
tower spot hits and about a month later
the leaves are falling off anyway it's
not really a big problem
another one of my favorite diseases is
black not
black not hits proms Prue's and it's
especially cherries and it's this sort
of charcoal like swirling growth on the
twigs and the fungus infects the twigs
and then starts to sort of charcoal e
growth
and
it's really easy to see when the tree is
out of leaf it's actually harder to see
if you've got a decent-looking cherry
and it starts to get black not you might
not see it until the winter and when the
leaves drop out so there are resistance
variety so that would probably good idea
to do if you know you have a lot of
black knot in your area I certainly have
seen
in New York a lot more black not than I
see in Washington DC area I don't know
why but you seem to have a lot of black
not up here
you can prune out the affected twigs in
the winter although it might behoove you
to dip your pruners in some alcohol
between cuts just to make sure you're
not spreading it and
it can it can be just an aesthetic issue
but if it gets really going on the plant
it can take it out because essentially
the growth girdles the twig and
eventually that twig dies and so if
there are enough black mountain sections
throughout a cherry plum or prune it can
kill it so again always when you're
buying new plants look for disease
resistant varieties because diseases are
hard to manage I don't think that
there's really management for black not
least I'm not aware of it except for
just cutting it out when you when you
see it
Tomatoes Tomatoes get a lot of diseases
and none of them are good and one of
them is devastating so the three that I
wanted to touch on our early blight
septoria leaf spot and then late blight
starting at the top right that's
septoria at least in my experience just
about every tomato plant on the lower
leaves starts to get septoria and
depending on how you manage the
disease like some people I would just go
in there religiously and strip out the
lower
leaves when they start getting septoria
to keep the infection to a minimum some
people just say oh well
not to worry I'm going to get my
tomatoes and that's it so it's up to you
to decide whether you want to manage it
that way or if you want to spray a
fungicide to try to keep some toya to a
minimum but it seems to me that every
every tomato's gonna get it there are
bill resistant varieties but it seems
like it's ubiquitous and tomatoes
also somewhat ubiquitous is early blight
and early causes more of a necrosis with
septoria is spots or the bright has sort
of a motive that is more like margin
relief the closest and into necrosis of
the leaves and that can be pretty
serious and and really keep your tomato
harvest much smaller than it would be
without the early blight
but then there's the devastating late
blight and then late like ten ironically
come somewhat early in the season
but it tends to be a little bit later in
the season and it causes these like
dark anchors on the stems and then hits
the foliage and it can wipe out the
plant just a hundred percent dead
so there's pretty much no tolerance for
late blight where you can tolerate
septoria and you can tolerate a little
early light there's really no tolerance
for late right and unless you're a
hundred percent vigilant and taking out
and inspecting your plants on a regular
basis and removing the one that starts
to have late blight most look like it's
going it's gonna wipe out your your um
your crop so again resistant varieties
there's a list on the Cornell vegetable
website in what I've varieties that we
think are late flight resistant
using fungicides to keep it at bay but
it certainly is a bad problem that comes
a those each year sometimes it's a
really bad late bite season sometimes
it's not so bad so because tomatoes are
probably our most important vegetable
crop in the home garden it's important
to know each diseases and certainly
we'll have workshops all where we really
take a look at this because you you want
to see this up close and personal
okay so now let's talk about diseases
where you see the symptoms but not the
signs of the disease
cold injury a lot of times when people
come in and they show me samples like on
the the two leftmost pictures like
what's hid what disease is hitting my my
plants well it was really it was cold
injury so it's an abiotic disease
nonliving and it's it can be very hard
to diagnose partly because a lot
especially with evergreens the damage
isn't going to show up for a month or
two and so people by the time it's 70
degrees you forget how bad the winter
was or maybe not with this year
and they forget that that's that you
know these plants especially the other
green plants that were exposed all
winter long can have get this kind of
damage and on the right is a picture of
a tree Finbar tree probably of maple and
they can get cold injury to frost cracks
where especially on the south side where
the bark would warm up in this in the
winter and a close but sunny day and
then perhaps the Sun goes behind a cloud
and it's back to the very very cold
temperatures and the bark can't expand
and contract that fast and can cause a
frost crack so clove injury is something
that it's subtle you have to keep a
kind of an eye on the weather and and a
memory in terms of what the cold was
that winter and especially if plants are
susceptible to cold injury when it's not
only cold but it's so frozen that the
plants can't take up water so they they
actually desiccate and so you see more
like a drying out damage so that's close
injury
salt damage
on a year especially like the one we've
just had there's a lot of salt on Rhodes
and I love this picture on the top right
that's salt spray damage where you can
see they use
got hit directly with salt and the salt
actually desiccates the needles that
salt is saltier than inside the plant
and the plant tries to equivalent the
router potential and so what is drawn
out of the needles into the salt at
around that are coating the needles and
and kill the plant needle out writing
you can see some bearing on the pine
foliage on the bottom right and then my
my personal favorite salt damage is on
deciduous trees which you wouldn't think
would have a problem but under heavy
heavy heavy salt spray damage the buds
are killed but especially the terminal
buds they're repeatedly killed by the
salt and the plant keeps trying to shoot
shoot out new shoots to accommodate the
loss of that terminal twig and you get
this what we call witch's broom so in
without damage this you can get
salt spray damage and you can get
yourself goes into the soil and become
makes the roots actually lose water
because the roots become less salty than
the soil around it and water is drawn
out from the root into the soil
there's not a whole lot you can do this
for salts for damage if you know you're
going to have salt damage to the roots
you can leech this excess salt through
the soil profile south is
mobile earnest air doesn't get bound up
in the south profile so
usually we don't have to worry about it
too much because
usually a winter harsh winters followed
by a bunch of spring rains and those
rains flush the salt through the soil
profile but if you if you dumped a bag
of so I'm sorry dump the back of
de-icing salts on one of your favorite
plants by mistake you could obviously
try to remove as much salt as possible
and then flush it out on this spring
with water just keep watering that plant
in the early spring and hopefully the
soil salts will move through the soil
profile and away from your higgs
brought to 95 blossoms rod is a tomato
disease were and sometimes pepper where
you get our lesion or sort of that
yeah kind of a mushy black lesion on the
one side of the tomato on the end of the
tomato and
this is actually a calcium uptake
deficiency so in this case where most of
the diseases for tomatoes are worse when
it's wet this is a disease when it's
that's worse when it's dry because the
tomato is rapidly expanding that leaves
calcium is one of the main ingredients
in cell walls so as the plant is growing
if it doesn't get enough calcium it has
problems with the new growth and it
can't especially if it's dry just kick
in enough calcium up into the plant and
you start getting comes up blossom and
run there are resistant tolerant
varieties so you may want to do that in
somewhat rainy New York we don't seem to
have it so badly but just be careful if
you we are having a dry
summer to make sure your tomatoes are
well irrigated so that'll help keep
calcium uptake
going so you won't have the boss blossom
and rod
finally verticillium wilt verticillium
wilt effects some of our most beloved
plants it seems to be particularly harsh
on Japanese maples and on red buds but
it hits a number of plants certainly
automate those species and you can see
in the upper left-hand corner there's
some Japanese maples and they're just
really thinning out looking unthrifty
not very good aesthetically that's
probably verticillium wilt and then in
the bottom picture is a maple with some
bridge die back and
that again is probably verticillium wilt
it's a little bit hard to diagnose
sometimes because it's sort of a fading
back but it's early I'm often here to
one branch at a time so that can be a
clue and if you snip that branch off and
you peel away the bark in the upper
right corner you can see some Browns
streaking in the canyon it just subtle I
found it to be quite subtle
but that is
diagnostic for verticillium
the brown streaking in the cambium
not much you can do there's really no
spray for verticillium it's a sirloin
pathogen it's difficult to manage a
couple of things you'd want to do you
can remove the affected parts and hope
that you know that contains it I've
found that basically you start just
removing the plant on the installment
plant plan or your take off one branch
and next year take off another branch
alright next year take off another
branch
certainly if that tree dies you would
not want to plant resistant species back
into that site because it's sort of more
in persistence so
you wouldn't want to put another mate
though like you wouldn't want to replace
the Japanese maple that died of
verticillium with another maple you
might want to put there you know there
are a lot of plants that are resistant
to verticillium so you would want to use
those rather than susceptible diseases
susceptible species
okay well that is the
quick overview of some of the most
common diseases that we see in central
new york and
happy disease hunting this has been a
production of Cornell University on the
web at cornell edu