this is a production of Cornell
University all right and with that uh
what I'm actually going to be talking to
you about today is about the uh post
Harvest Apple
microbiome and summarizing uh the work
I've been doing for the last five years
at
Cornell right so just introduce one of
the things that uh I think we can
sometimes take for granted and I
certainly take took for granted before
starting
program at Cornell is how we can just
walk into a grocery store and see all
this amazing fresh produce months after
harvest in the case of uh something like
apples that right now apples have been
harvested harvested mostly in like
September with a little bit of like
August and October but you can walk into
a grocery store now and see New York
apples that were harvested from that
previous season uh right in the grocery
store and they uh look and taste great
so how do we actually uh
make that happen right and the answer is
with a variety of post Harvest
Technologies and the way we tend to
approach this in science is uh by
looking at okay what are the issues and
how and how do we solve them so there's
this big issue with fresh produce where
uh a large percentage that in some cases
this is like lowballing it um 24% of of
fruits and vegetables are lost before
reaching consumers right so big issue
and right again as I mentioned as
scientists we' like to think about why
why does this happen um and so there are
a lot of different ways that food can go
bad so uh there are sort of what what do
you think of as like food naturally um
going bad through uh ripening is
inessence which is based on cellular
respiration the fruit has metabolism it
go through all of its energy and then it
starts to break down uh and then water
loss is also a big deal especially in a
lot of leafy greens that even with a
little bit of water loss they'll shovel
up
um then we have uh molds and and
rots and and in these uh in horor
culture we call these post Harvest
pathogens that will infect the fruit and
of course these are very dangerous
because they'll spread and then we also
have a physiological disorders a common
example is something as simple as Apple
Browning so you bite into an apple and
it's kind of brown and gross it's not
moldy like it's not dangerous it's just
not what you really want uh from an
apple and so we have all these issues
that we have to deal
with right and so one of the the main
things that we want to do to preserve
the shelf life is to slow
respiration right because that slows
rping inessence uh process the most
effective thing we do for a lot of uh a
lot of these problems is Refrigeration
one of the things that I learned taking
uh po Harvest classes with uh Chris and
uh and and uh Dr uh suang Dan doing our
research is how important Refrigeration
is like refrigerate refrigerate
refrigerate and then there are some
other more specific Technologies we can
also use that if you reduce the
oxygen uh plants need oxygen to process
for their cellular respiration to
process energy like we do and then that
can limit respiration as long as it
doesn't get too low and you get
fermentation and then there's also this
plant hormone ethylene that mediates a
lot of this ripening inessence that we
can control right so apples are what is
known as a climacteric fruit that uh
through development through this
ripening phase you see that there's this
big burst of ethylene and then shortly
after you get this big burst of uh
respiration right which creates uh leads
to a lot of ripening inessence right and
in a fruit like strawberry which the
graph gives here for comparison we don't
see that right so some fruits do have
this climic some don't apples do and
that means that if we have this uh
showing this chemical pathway for
ethylene if we're able to inhibit it at
certain points
these two compounds uh one mCP and AVG
are ones that uh the Watkins lab very
commonly
uses and that are very commonly used in
the industry if we can inhibit ethylene
we can preserve the shelf
life right and then the other issue one
of the other issues I mentioned is water
loss um and so uh H how do we uh prevent
that the big way is when we uh
refrigerate in big storage rooms and we
try to keep it very humid for the
produce that uh 95% relative humidity is
the common Benchmark um but of course
there's a problem with humid conditions
and if anyone's a plant pathologist
seeing the water all over these apples
this might be a cause for a heart attack
um because uh when you get a lot of
moisture on apples that's just or or or
on anything as as you might expect
that's just inviting rots and molds in
right it's very intuitive if something
gets super wet mold will grow on it and
we don't want that on our food
right and so balancing all of these
approaches is
tricky um and we can control most of
these post haris pathogens with
fungicides which have some regulatory
concerns and even if you don't care
about that the one thing that really
struck me is that uh it's becoming more
and more difficult to develop new
fungicides you've already found all the
easy modes of action we're really
struggling to find new ones we need new
approaches in addition to the fungicides
we already use so one that's being
uh investigated is bio
control which the principle of it is to
use uh to simplify to use the good
microbes to fight off the Bad microbes
that you have a good like bacteria or a
yeast that will fight off and the the
bad uh postar
pathogens uh and and protect the fruit
and so there are some commercial
products available for these um but
they're less common than conventional
fdes for a couple of reasons that
they're a bit more expensive and they
can work as well but they're a bit more
uh that that you have to have the right
context for them so they're not quite as
consistent can apply to every situation
even though they have a lot of
potential um and so a lot of the uh
people who look at uh bio control when
when this uh microbiome concept started
were really interested because uh that
they had the
idea that instead of just using this bio
control antagonist to attack the
pathogen that there can be all these
interactions with the microbes that just
have to be on the fruit
surface right and so that leads to
developing theories of how can we
actually use the microbiome for
biocontrol and so that was uh where a
lot of the kind of early Theory early I
say as in like 10 years ago because this
field is very new um theory around
uh the the fruit
microbiome microbiome comes from and one
of the things that people have taken
from other microbiome studies is this
idea of the holom which originated from
the idea of the human microbiome which
and to be clear this is not the only way
people view the human microbiome but
it's one framework people use is that we
as humans
are a a sum of not just our own
physiology and not just our own actions
but of constant interactions between us
and the microbes in and on us so
everything we do is not just human
physiology it's human physiology
interacting with microbial phology and
microbial
ecology and so people have said why
don't we apply that to fruits as well
that there are all these microbes living
in and on fruits there have got to be
these constant
interactions there that that that can
shape all sorts of outcomes and if we
can just study these microbiomes maybe
we can then figure out more about the
fruits right and so that leads into my
work so we have this uh postar
physiology
element of trying to create to trying to
make sure that uh fruit lasts longer uh
deal with the issues that AR
and combining that with microbial
Ecology of we we know that there are
these microbes on surface of fruits what
are they what are they doing how can we
use those right so that's what I've
essentially been working on for the last
uh five years and then a couple years
ago I gave a presentation for the work I
did uh for Masters which is AVG as a
reminder this is one of the chemicals
that inhibits ethylene so all you need
to know is that it slows down ripening
and slows down sin
Essence um was so it was associated with
bacterial but not a fungal microbiome
variation in Gaya apples and so we
hypothesized that okay if we change if
we manipulate fruit
maturity um with this chemical that
should change what microbes we find on
there we found that it was true for
bacteria but they didn't find evidence
for uh fungi um
but one of the things about apples I
mentioned the clima Turk is that Gaya
apples don't have a very strong don't
have a very pronounced climac Turk that
its ethane goes up a little bit but uh
with this new variety uh Snap Dragon uh
which great apples if you live in the um
Northeast Us by the way highly recommend
um that that those have a much more
pronounced climic tur so we asked uh C
can we see
effects uh with this other cabar and
then with that we other we also wanted
to um
expand the
uh the the experimental design to look
at Harvest Time as well that here again
we have this very simplified pathway
where AVG chemical stops ethylene and
because ethylene leaves hering inessence
you can use AV to to create apples that
will last longer through
storage
um and we're also looking at at
manipulating aurity just through Harvest
times that we
harvested very early earlier than you
would typically Harvest apples and also
later then you would typically Harvest
apples right and so what were our
hypotheses
we predicted that this AVG this ethylene
inhibitor would uh affect microbiome due
to ethylene mediating some some uh
microbial interactions so ethylene
um we we're mostly concerned with it
because uh of its effect on ripening it
it also is known to have some effects on
uh plant defense right in addition for
to
uh to that we uh predicted Harvest Time
will influence the microbiome due to
some ecological principles Community
succession and turnover that the longer
the apples are there the more time the
mics have to colonize and that will
change the
community um and then we have we we
predict that the uh we also stored the
apples and predict that that would the
microbiomes due to this different
environment uh that they're
in right um so the sampling procedure
I'm not going to go through through this
for every experiment um
but uh essentially we had a few
different
treatments that we had our chemical
application that we
had this e inhibitor ABG we had uh two
Harvest times that were three weeks
apart so again like earlier and later
than you would typically Harvest
apples and then three storage
times uh with lot of application to get
a lot of good samples um and then the
process of actually sampling the
microbiome
it's kind of entertaining uh some people
when I explain it it's you put these
apples uh in a bag um you have a machine
it shakes them around a lot um with with
this uh solution and then you filter all
the liquid through onto this filter
paper and get this uh Grime which has
all the microbes in it and then you can
store it at the bottom of this tube and
then do typical DNA extractions and
sequencing right and again not going to
go through this for every experiment um
but we have our rdna extraction um and
then at this point point you shift the
samples off to a company who does the
sequencing and the way microbiome
sequencing is typically done is with
these small amplicons um so sequencing
entire big genomes of microbes is pretty
expensive but we can sequence a small
region of a ribosomal subunit to tell
what's what
essentially um and then we can do a
bunch of uh btics process the sequence
to get these feature table of we have a
sample and then these are all different
uh microbes and we get relative counts
of each to see how much of each microbe
is there that's the kind of
highle explanation and so here first I'm
going to show the ethylene data and it
looks about what we expect that when uh
we apply uh AVG we
see that the ethylene is greatly reduced
um and that the uh early Harvest apples
continue to get e after storage where
when we Harvest them late when they
already kind of hit especially for the
control ones they've hit that uh point
of the clima Turk the ethene
um production
decreases right and then going into the
actual uh
microbiome data uh I like to give a an
overview explanation of these uh
ordinations when I each time I do these
presentations because I know that
interpreting these multivariate data is
isn't something that everyone always
does their job so essentially for for
these each point is
a microbiome which for these sample is
for
apples um and the points that are
further apart have more different
microbiomes so the points that are
similar together have more similar
microbiomes the points that are further
apart have different microbiomes and
because uh we find hundreds of different
of microbes we're not able to make these
generalizations about like what's a good
microbiome or a bad microbiome all we
can say is that when we take all these
hundreds of microbes microbi microbes
together to form the microbiomes these
ones tend to look more similar to each
other and these ones look uh different
and so the main thing we see is that the
darker points that represent the later
storage time tend to Cluster differently
from the lighter points and then we see
that the late harvested ones these blue
ones also cluster a bit differently from
the uh early Harvest points and then we
can also do some statistics on this and
uh partially because it's is a
summarizing like PhD work as part of the
uh part part of the fence we're going to
have to get a little nitty-gritty into
the stats um and it's also like
important for the story of why I did
what but I'll try to not go like uh too
deep into it the main thing we were
really curious about um AVG and we did
find the uh the these initial ones are
are P
values um and so we did find a
significant P value that were the the
the chance of seeing these differences
is uh pretty low due to random chance
there's prob a treatment effect but
you'll notice the r squared for all of
these is pretty low so only uh in in
bacteria only 3% of the variation is
explained
by uh this the the this ethylene
inhibitor application and for people who
work on Univar data are probably
thinking uh 3% is like nothing for an r
squared that like how do you even get a
significant result and again the answer
is multivari data is very complicated
that 3% of the uh
microbiome of of differences in the
microbiome across hundreds or maybe even
thousands of different microbes if we
see it consistently enough that can give
us a significant result so it does look
like yeah it's doing something but the
actual variation it's
explaining uh is isn't the largest and
that was something that kind of kept me
thinking for a while
afterwards and we see pretty similar
things for uh fungi that Harvest Time
storage time and this chemical
application this ethylene inhibitor
significantly shift in the
microbiome here the r squ is 04 it's
explaining 4% of the
variation right and we were able to find
some uh cool results with this my
favorite one was uh doing this uh stats
analysis to look at the direction of the
shifts and we see that uh all all the
red ones are uh are factors that that
significantly predict microbiome
variation um and so what we see is when
we apply AV
G the microbiome shifts the opposite
direction as late Harvest so the same
direction as we would expect from early
Harvest right and so it's a little
complicated to work my head through like
it took me a while to think about this
but what that essentially means is
that uh when the fruit is less mature
either due to having an AVG application
or due to being early harvested and
going in this direction that shifts the
microbiome in a similar Direction so the
microbiome is really tied to this
physiology that if you're able to
manipulate the maturity by either
harvesting early or by using a chemical
to uh reduce ethylene uh production that
shifts the microbiome in the same way so
that was a cool
result um and we got a good paper out of
it with
the last thing we did with this study
being looking at uh shotgun metagenomics
so I mentioned that uh when we look at
uh when we do sequencing for microbiomes
we tend to just look at a small region
of the genome to tell what's what um but
that doesn't actually tell us what the
genes are that these microbiomes
have and so uh what what we did was uh
this shotgun magic sequencing which does
sequence at random the entire microbiome
which we can use to to predict what
genes are there and see what these
microbes are actually
doing um and we did find some
interesting results that I wish I had
time to dig into but there's already a
lot of of uh there are already a lot of
data here but the main thing is is in in
most in large part due to the fact that
we weren't able to sequence as many
samples
um uh because the sequencing is much
more expensive when when we look at the
overall uh functional differences from
the predicted genes most of these are
bacterial um that we see some
differences due to storage time looking
from at Harvest uh to six months uh
combining some other data sets that I
also don't have time to talk about but
Harvest Time and AVG applic
don't result in uh significant
differences right so in summary we found
that uh our according to our hypothesis
this AVG chemical does have have an
effect on the microbiome and it's
similar to harvesting early because both
uh create less mature apples um but the
the actual like r squar value the amount
of variation explained by this AG is not
super high right and we see that uh
storage time is really the important
factor of bacterial composition and
function which is something we know from
the literature a lot of Studies have
looked at this and a lot of Studies have
found the same thing that storage time
is very important so that got me
thinking of like we got uh a great paper
out of this and then um my advisor Chris
asked a very good question and S to me
about this saying that the uh for PhD
you don't want to just think about doing
these separate studies you want to think
about well how do I build off of these
previous results when I looked at this
of what we were doing with maturity and
it's a very cool finding that they were
able to manipulate uh maturity and shift
the microbiome but I was looking at the
r squ values the effect values and I'm
like I think we just got to try
something different to see if we can
find a bigger effect that was my
conclusion and so next thing I looked at
were uh fungicides like surely the
things that Target the actual fungi
maybe we'll see really big effects with
those um so in this case we're looking
at fungicides and this uh skull
inhibitor this different chemical that
I'll uh be talking about as well so uh
starting with the
fungicides we have these two different
ones we have flu oino which is a
conventional fun side it's kind of what
you think of where uh you spray UND side
post Harvest on these apples that's food
oxol is a very common one mam is a
natural product compound so it's uh less
commercially used but it's available for
Organics and the main difference the the
reason experimentally we think that this
would be different is that flu oxil is
specifically designed to Target
pathogens whereas mamy is more broadly
toxic to
microbes um so we expect potentially uh
differences from there from how those
two
uh how the microb reacts to those two
and
then uh another Factor here is we have
this scold inhibitor that they were
testing so superficial scold you can see
these kind of pictures of these apples
that you probably wouldn't want to eat
um that it's caused by a variety of
abiotic factors um so this isn't a rot
or a mold it is just the the Apple
doesn't have everything it needs and
it's developing uh these issues right
and so we have this uh antioxidant um
DPA that that's used uh to
treat um superficial scull because a lot
of
uh what creates these physiologically
are oxidation reactions um
there are some regulatory concerns
around DPA where it's banned in Europe
um because it's like effect is very
powerful um as an antioxidant so we're
thinking okay like does that ship shift
the
microbiome if if we uh really change the
surface environment with this
antioxidant right and as previously we
wanted a post Harvest component we this
time we decided to look more at
shortterm because we looked at longterm
previously so like just 28
days um and then a room temperature
shelf life afterwards to address if the
fungicides really hit the
microbiome does it recover
quickly right and so we hypothesize that
when we target pathogens uh with these
fungicides that it will kind of disrupt
the entire community and
then uh similar methods I'm not going to
go over everything before of of the
sequencing we
used okay and so when we looked at the
um fungal data we find that the main
factor that shapes uh fungal communities
is the DPA the scald
inhibitor you can see these 95%
confidence ellipses that are overlapping
but they're clearly not identical
they're they're not in the exact same
place um and we see that the uh it is a
highly significant result and that the r
squ is 0.15 so 15% of the
variation uh of of what we see of of the
fungi on on the Apple surface can be
explained by adding this uh antioxidant
scald inhibitor right and the fungicide
we found was barely significant and when
we did parb we found that natomy the
organic broadly toxic to um microbes uh
fungicide had a had a small effect that
was barely significant and the
conventional fungicide that specifically
targeted pathogens um had no observable
effect and then we looked at bacteria
all of our treatments we didn't find
significant results what we did find is
the storage time heavily impacted uh the
microbiome where between the 14 and 28
days there was a big shift as you can
see and then when we took it out of act
room temperature it shifted back what it
was before so that's kind of an
interesting result
wasn't really uh exactly what we were um
looking to test
um with without uh the fun sides being
significant but I was pretty happy with
this that that we see that there are
these shifts that occur at Cold Storage
which we already know but what we didn't
know is that at least in the short term
they're somewhat reversible that we see
this big shift 14 and 28 days and that
it goes back to looking like how it did
in early storage if you take it out at
room temperature which could imply that
kind of the cold the the the cold uh
storage room
environment really is a a factor that
again um is
reversible right and so then I decided
to dig
into uh we we found that the DPA like
the applications of the antioxidant
scull
inhibitor um were had a big effect on
the fungi so what fungi is this actually
affecting right and so we found a few
different ones that were uh
significantly uh affected it's possible
that it's affecting more but when you
test hundreds of fungi you have to do uh
pretty strict multiple testing
correction so we're only seeing the ones
that are very significant um because if
you test hundreds of things um with just
a p .05 caught up you're just you're
going to get a lot that happen to um
come across as as significant even if
they're not just due to random chance um
so we're using a lot more uh stringent
cut off here
and the main thing is that this
aridium uh genus is uh very common on
the surface of apples it's a a yeast
that's known to have certain biocontrol
properties um and the one thing I was
able to find in in the literature which
kind of tied this together is that part
of its biocontrol action um
um is through um oxidative exerting
oxidative stress on on pathogens so by
sping the antioxidant it's not able to
do that maybe that
explains uh why why it's a lower
abundance when you add add the DP it's
not able to actually enact that bio
control as much um so in conclusion uh
see I'm still doing okay on
time then we have uh fungal composition
as I mentioned was associated with this
uh scalon
uh antioxident DPA and then bacterial
composition was associated with storage
time and then the skull
inhibitor uh the the main important
genus fact we found was on aridium and
then actually going back a bit this
cladosporium people might also know that
uh see that Inc increases in abundance
when you have DPA it's known to uh be a
mold most of the uh post Harvest on it
is that it
causes uh rotten grapes I wasn't able to
find a of it in apples um but that's
another thing to
consider um a table grap specifically
there's been some work where it's been
found as a as a
RW um and then one of the things that uh
surprised me when I looked through was
not exactly what I found but what I
didn't find was that when we looked at
um the abundance of
pathogens we saw that the uh
fungicides uh didn't shift the abundance
at all even if we didn't do the big
multiple testing correction I talked
about and just looked at which do these
have like what are the raw P values none
of them were close to being significant
when when we applied the uh
fungicides designed to um to control
them so after this I did some more
thinking about okay what do I want my
next step to be um thinking about a few
things that we
found DPA this uh the the this
antioxidant a strong effect on a fungi
but we didn't observe any effect on on
bacteria and the spici
sides um didn't seem to have a big
effect on the microbiome and also didn't
seem to have substantially reduced the
abundance of both Harvest pathogens
we're looking at which were both
consistent with the literature because I
was surprised by this so I went to see
how other people found the same thing
and other people have and no one really
has an explanation for it um is what
I've seen um so I thinking
about again going back that that all
these things we apply to try and
manipulate
microbiomes we can find consistent
results and we also got a very good
paper out of this but for my next
project I was thinking about the the the
biggest um results we found were due to
things like changing a big Harvest time
or leaving it in storage for a long time
these factors through time looking at
the kind of large scale ecology and then
again thinking about well we don't see
these big effect of ferdes on the things
we know they
control of that these kind of this large
scale Community ecology approach of
looking down and looking at all these
microbes doesn't always let us pick out
very specific interactions on
um uh on on on specific microbes if
they're not already so abundant that it
shifts around the entire community so
then I got to thinking what actual
questions can I take with this like a
community ecology lens that uh I I I I
think is very important right and so
that led me to look at more of these
spatiotemporal factors of how do the
microbes actually get onto the apple
fruit to begin with um and how can that
be explained by where they are in space
and time
and um this was a a fairly substantial
shift from what I had done before um
because right as you may remember the
title of my uh presentation is about um
PR and post Harvest treatments this
really isn't either it's looking about
the at the spatial end ecology and how
that changes Through Time right but
again looking
through my results seeing low r squared
values and not not not always the
effects we were
seeing I thought like this is where I
think uh we're actually going to find
the most important biological results
right and so getting into the actual um
what I did for this one you may remember
uh I I talked about uh these data at
Grandfield review I decided to also
include them here because they
uh they're they're pretty important for
like the story of what I actually did
and why and we'll be able to pick out um
some interesting Trends from it so uh
Island biogeography theory is a
classical ecology theory that you can
see here with this picture of birds that
basically states that the further away
the island is the less dispersal there's
going to be the less things can make it
so you're to find fewer different types
of of species there's going to be less
diversity just kind of makes sense right
that here we can see these birds all are
all able to get over here but here on
this island only one type of bird is uh
and I wondered is that true for apples
as well that are apples lower to the
ground and in this different canopy area
do those have different uh composition
and diversity due to differences due to
potentially differences in
dispersal
right and so our research questions here
were looking at these different canopy
areas the lower canopy the inner
canopy and outer canopy and we're
looking at do these have different
microbiomes um and we looked at a couple
of harvest times to make sure it was
um consistent only uh one week apart
this time and tracking tracking changes
through storage um and because we're
interested in looking at uh temporal
effects as well uh we wanted to look at
to to do a multi-year study this time so
this was a pretty big
undertaking uh and and again a little
risky in the sense that like it's not
using the bread and butter like post
Harvest uh te technologies that I was
using earlier
on PhD and so our hypothesis this time
is that in in accordance with this
biogeography theory that each of these
zones should have a different mic a
different microbiome because different
microbes um Can colonize at different
rates and and potentially even just due
to random chance that that of of what
makes it there
they uh should be different and then we
think that uh the lower canopies should
have the highest diversity
because more microb should be able to
get to he from the soil right so this
hypothesis really
implicates the soil as being important
right and so the main thing we found is
that uh between the years there's a lot
of variation explained um that for fungi
you can see that these cluster are very
separately for fungi and bacteria um
highly
significant our squared for fungi is uh
0.54 so 54% of all the differences we
see across the microbiomes for all of
our our fungal samples can be explained
by which one was in 2022 which one was
in
23 uh for bacteria
they uh microbes a lot more complicated
so the r squs tend to be a bit lower in
general uh 23 which is still a lot
higher than we've seen
before and then when we look at uh the
canop area we found that previously when
we had uh experiments it was things like
storage time that had the biggest impact
but in this study it was actually canopy
area that had the biggest effect on the
microbiome composition and we see that
for our two years for fungi we see these
again these wouldn't be high R squares
by univariate measures with like one
treatment and one response but for
hundreds of different microbes
explaining 20% of the variation that's
quite
substantial um and then for bacteria we
see the same where we we we see a a good
deal of
Separation um with highly significant
results and higher R squar
values and so for me this was very
exciting and and looking at yes we can
uh try and manipulate the
microbiome through these Technologies
which is great
and I'm really glad I did those studies
and then it's also important to look at
okay there's a lot of variation even
within a single tree here of uh of of
where these these microbes are based on
uh presumably dispersal because any
physiological differences we tend to
find don't have uh big impacts on the
microbiome um and with our diversity we
find that
again it's a little complicated
and and messy but it uh but but the
brown lines for the lower canopy do tend
to be the highest in fungi overall and
then when we do the stats for the
overall trend it comes across as very
highly significant that the um lower
canopy consistently has the highest
diversity and then we see the same thing
for bacteria as well
um so this this uh I I make another note
on this the this uh confirms our
hypothesis about the island biogeography
theory that and at least acts in the way
that we would expect if
soil is the main source of uh microbes
and they are being dispersed from the
soil to the above ground apples as
if in the same way that like birds fly
from the mainlands to to
Islands um and
then we uh did uncover some potential
compositional differences as well
previously I mentioned for one of my
other studies we did kind this whole big
metagenome sing with shotgun
metagenomics what we did here is a
little different um because we didn't
have the the money to do full shock
metomic sequencing so used a tool that
predicts the metagenomes based on on
what bacteria there are are called py
crust um and the main result I got from
this that while you have to be a bit
more careful with P data because you're
not working with the actual metagenome
you're just working with what you think
the metag genome should be based on what
bacteria there are um that we see that
over half of the
um of of uh the genes or Kos these like
small genetic elements that we're not
technically sure if they're genes um
involved in uh secondary metabolite
biosynthesis so all these exra compounds
that could potentially be uh toxic to
other microbes but can serve of a
variety of purposes that over half of
them are increased in abundance in the
lower canopy and and to me my
interpretation of this was not
necessarily that all these microbes are
producing a ton of secondary metabolites
but just that there's a greater
diversity of of microbes a greater
diversity of
metabolism that that you see that this
is a more complicated a community that's
ends up
producing more compounds because of
that right so when we zoom out a bit and
look at the broader implications here um
so we think that most likely this comes
from a dispersal soil because of the
diversity uh patterns we see and the big
compositional differences that that is
most likely due to some sort of
dispersal and it matches what we would
expect from VI biogeography theory if
the source is the soil and microbes are
being dispersed to um above ground
apples and we also know that uh in
controlled environment experiments with
a rabid opsis this has been done and
it's been shown that yes like most
microbes from the soil
can uh
can colonize the uh the above ground
phosphere and when when you do that the
above ground phosphere it looks pretty
similar to uh what it would be outside
of a controlled environment uh so it
really does look like when you're
looking at these above ground uh uh
microbiomes dispersal from soil uh that
is my belief anyway is is this important
factor um and having more dispersal from
soil and the lower canopy it's a bit of
a mixed bag that The microbiome go study
microbiomes people like to take
the sort of positive look at it of like
yeah the microbes are here like
protecting the
apples uh protecting the fruit but the
these um microbes could also have a
greater risk for uh post haris pathogens
colonizing because of that uh greater
dispersal and again uh my main takeaway
is that when we look at uh which I guess
we'll see in these
conclusions the the the spa should uh to
temporal factors and this kind of
fundamental C ecology concepts are very
important for studying uh these
microbiomes that we can
manipulate uh with our our Technologies
and get some differences uh but what
really shapes the microbiome what's
there and what we can work with are
these fundamental spao temporal factors
right so overall yeah have our different
canopy areas have uh distinct
microbiomes the lower canopy has the
highest diversity
which we are suspecting is due to this
increased dispersal in accordance with
Island biogeography Theory and we found
some functional differences and then a
part
that I think is important too is that
like I said we see huge differences in
the communities between years but the
patterns the fact that we see
differences between these canopy areas
are the same and that the uh different
uh gener that
are uh different in the lower canopy
versus the upper canopies I I didn't
show all all these data but it it
remains prettyy consistent between the
two years uh that we looked at so it to
me it feels like this is really a a
fundamentally important force uh shaping
the
microbiome right so okay zooming even
further out to look at kind of what I've
accomplished in my PhD in two minutes um
that we found that uh ethline mediated
fruit maturity so either by applying an
uh an eth inhibitor or just harvesting
early uh is linked to microbiome
compositions and we found this in
Snapdragon which has pronounced climac
which we found results there than Ang
Gala which doesn't so that could
potentially be an important C ofir
effect as well um the skull inhibitor
DPA has a very notable effect on fungi
um and the fungi sides have a little to
no effect um which was kind of
surprising but is consistent with the
literature and looking at that I looked
at the spao temporal effects which I
found seem to be really important in
shaping the
microbiome um with these Dynamics
matching some of what we would expect
based on classical ecology Theory like
uh the theory of Island
biogeography all right and a lot of
people helped me through uh a lot of
this work a lot of people who are here
in this room and a lot of people who
have since moved on to uh bigger and
better things so I just wanted to say uh
thank thanks to everyone who helps me
out with this work um and I'm happy to
take any questions
Conor can you describe the uh the trees
that you were sampling from and how you
how you sampled and then also um whether
or not the Orchards that you were
sampling from were applied with any
fungicides or
maides all right so let
me go back so
um Mo the uh right for Zoom the question
was uh can I
describe basically what what the trees
look like how we sampled and how how
they're
treated um so this is specifically the
tree that we used for the um a set of
trees we used for this last experiment
on the different canopy
areas uh most of the trees that we
used look fairly similar with the second
experiment on funder sdes the the Fuji
the trees were a bit
larger um that it's this as most Apple
people probably know these more modern
kind of like smaller trees that are uh
easier to uh get to and the way I
sampled was because uh even back when I
was thinking about
um
uh even back in the earlier
experiments and when I wasn't directly
looking at the different canopy areas I
I was thinking and uh ysf who's in the
audience like even made a comment to me
about like oh you might not want to take
the apples that are like super low to
the ground because like those might just
like have more like dirt on them you
might get like a different microbiome
which um was one of the things that got
me thinking about this question actually
um that I tried to make sure that
um that I was pulling um each sample is
like a few different apples like four or
five and I was trying to pull them from
different areas on the same tree ideally
so um If This Were The Experiment I so
so so a sample would be like I would
take a few replicates um and each
replicate would be like let's say four
apples from here for the lower canopy
like four apples kind of from here for
the inner camp and four apples from here
for the outer campy trying to get uh
different areas as a result for some of
my early experiments um I was uh it was
pretty slowo uh Chris had the nickname
Speedy Gonzalez for me while I was
sampling because I would be very
meticulous in trying to uh pick out
different apples and uh it would take a
while as a result and I would not have
very many apples um did that fully
answer your question how is that tree
and like what's the canopy withd just
trying to get a sense of like what the
outer versus inner canopy is for yeah um
so the tree is
uh trying to about 10 feet tall yeah 10
feet tall I was trying to convert it in
into meters and I was like I probably
don't need to do that
um yeah so we we had uh
certain like guidelines for like what
constituted like lower outer and inner
canopy based on kind of rough distances
the the lower canopy was about
everything below kind of like waist
waist height upper canopy was like
everything above chest height and then
outer an in in our canopy
um we were able to
uh to just by trying to pick the ones
like really close and really uh far away
from the center of the tree and then I'm
also remembering the other part of the
question you asked was about how they
were treated um pretty much all these
trees were treated with fungicides
throughout the uh the growing season so
that was like
a what about have you thought about
reflective Fabric and like how that
could right your Harvest maybe there'll
be less soil spray or something yep that
is a great question so the question was
what about a reflective fabric so um in
case people don't know uh there will be
like reflective like I don't know what's
made out as like aluminum
uh there'll be this like fabric put down
um with the idea that if the sunlight
hits Rays on the ground they'll bounce
back up and hit the apples so because
light is important for developing the
color of the fruit that's why Growers
will uh put down this reflective like
shiny uh uh fabric Thing to get more red
looking apples generally and the
question was do we think that that would
affect the microbiome by potentially uh
reducing um the dispersal I think
absolutely would would be my guess um
that that would definitely be something
I'd be interested in looking into as a
followup from
this uh going into a bit more depth of
uh dispersal there are a couple ways
that uh people have shown that dispersal
from soil to the above ground can happen
one is uh through the air there are some
classical micro microbiological studies
on it um interestingly there was one
that found that it like mostly only
occurred on like sunny days during the
daytime was when this happened um
I don't exactly know why but that was
what they found and that I think that's
a lot of what we're getting because
we're looking at the outside of the
fruit that the other way microbs can get
into the apple is uh through the root
system through the xylem that microbes I
I didn't notice until I started looking
into it actually but that a lot of
microbes do go through the plant xylm in
in into the above ground as well so that
would probably not be affected by the
reflective fabric as much but the aerial
dispersal we get I'm seeing a lot of
when I do the Apple wash probably would
be effed would be my guess so out of
time one question of those
one yes that was a great talk thank you
my question is maybe this is kind of
alluded to with the light question too
so what we consider and I'm not sure if
you looked into this but it's sort of
like the spatial element of the apple
right so just looking at the single
fruit um and given off of what you were
saying based off of like the microbes
being uh transferred to the Apple
through the xylm are there differences
between the kaix end and the other side
of the fruit in terms of uh microbial
diversity at all or you know like just
uh know between the Sun and shaded side
or something like that y so uh the
question was what about differences like
biographical differences like within the
Apple itself like Kix end so the bottom
and then the stem end the top or sun and
shaded side um and so the answer is for
kend absolutely there's
um uh research group that's done a lot
of work on different experiments and
they find consistent differences between
stem and
KX um and they find that the middle like
like the peel middle tends to have the
lowest diversity and the lowest
microbial count because it's you might
imagine it's like harder for a microbe
to survive there but in the KX end and
in the sem end where there are those
kind of grooves for the microbes s in
they tend to find higher diversity and
uh
higher uh High higher uh microbial
counts
um sun and shaded side we're not
uh totally sure funny story about that
though there was actually like a little
miscommunication in this project where
that was what Chris originally wanted me
to test with this
study um but but when he was looking
at and then I took it more in a
direction of um outer versus inner
canopy because uh when I do the Apple
wash you get the entire Apple so you're
not able to look at Sun version shaded
they are um methods that can be used for
that the other group that I talked about
that
um does the uh KX versus stemon what
they do is they'll kind of take a bit of
fruit flesh from the peel stem and KX uh
they'll uh grind it up in in liquid
nitrogen and and just do the DNA
extraction from there so it's like it's
mostly Apple DNA but they get enough
microbes and then when they amplify a
small region of of bacterial or fungal
DNA they get enough bacterial or fungal
DNA uh to get some microbiome sequencing
and I did actually try those methods
very early on in my PhD um and part of
the
uh um and it didn't end up working for a
few reasons part of that being that like
it requires a lot more samples and a lot
more sequencing money and part of it
being the sequencing just didn't work as
well and I asked them about it over
email and they're like oh yeah like we
have this like fancy $20,000 like
homogenizer equipment thing I forget
exactly what it was I'm like well I
don't think I can get that so I'm going
to find a different way um and that was
part of the empis for why I developed
Apple wash solution but it also gives
higher quality DNA just in general so I
didn't just do it because it was easier
and I didn't have the money there were
scientific reasons but all sort of
positive not finish off thank you very
much this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu