this is a production of Cornell
University all right well it's such a
nice spring day out there and uh so I
want to reward you for staying inside
with me uh with some beautiful spring
flowers I'm going to talk about uh Ro
redend project that I've been working on
it's been a long-term project but that's
Woody plants for you they tend to be
long term uh the title is just meant to
convey uh my effort to really rejuvenate
a plant which has been popular for a
long time in gardens but has sort of
languished in in Commerce and sort of
has lost popularity in the public
imagination it's not for lack of of
Aesthetics it's an incredibly beautiful
plant and every new variety that comes
out seems more stunning than the one
before uh the difficulty
uh the problem really lies with the
culture of the plant it's biology it's
very difficult to
grow unless you're you know willing to a
knowledgeable Gardener that's willing to
make the effort to do so so for really
the vast majority of the gardening
public these are plants uh that fail in
the garden we call them in our cynical
moments bials you buy them in bloom at
the Garden Center and they die the next
year
well our depart research department at
Holden is consists of four principal
investigators so why this uh big
investment in radad dendrons well part
of that is because of uh really it's
happen stance it's a convergence of
like-minded people with the same
interests uh able to pull their
resources and and uh create what became
the David G leech research station so
David Leech was a uh influential
American
horticulturist president of the American
Rance Society for many years involved
heavily with the garden Conservancy but
also a passionate uh admirer of red
dendrons and very a world a world
Authority really he wrote his seminal
book called reders of the world which
really came out in the early 60s really
helped popularize the plant in the
American Consciousness and his niche as
a hybridizer was cold hearty hybrids so
his Target for
hardiness was zone five and in
ornamental plants the hardiness is
usually given for the buds the flower
buds that's the trait of Interest so
buds Hardy to about minus5 Fahrenheit
was was his uh threshold level and he
created these beautiful hybrids here the
Red Sea and the yellow
Capistrano uh which are plants they're
recombinant plants you don't find those
colors in a hearty background in nature
they're created by hybridizing different
species
species the other answer to why roted D
is why not they really are probably the
most uh one of the most ornamental Woody
shrubs available in terms of the
diversity of colors these are species
most of them from Asia showing the range
of colors everything except maybe a a
blue uh variety of types of infloresence
inflorescences tremendous variability of
Leaf morphology this is uh you have uh
low elevation tree species with leaves
that are 3 feet long up to small tiny
little small Lea Alpine plants at at
about 18,000 ft in the in the Asian
mountains often times I'll have these uh
kind of fuzzy undersides here different
colors that's a it's kind of a suede
type covering called indumentum don't
really know the function of it but it's
it's uh highly
Al so what I've been showing you so far
is just a slice of the total genus
renrin which worldwide consists of about
a thousand species and that includes
other
subgenera
um which uh are such as the Deciduous
aelas and the Evergreen aelas and the
small Leaf groad denance subgenus heanes
which is the focus of my talk are the
non-scaly Leaf large leaf rendin most of
them
Evergreen and the center of diversity
Center of origin for this genus is
Southwest China into the Himalayas so
those solid and hatched areas areas of
extreme topographical relief uh which
led to uh quite rapid
speciation and then outward from that
Center you'll find instances of other
species into Korea
Japan um Central Asia and Europe and
across the landbridge into North America
so there are a couple species on the uh
in the eastern mountains of of North
America that uh are very useful for
breeding cold hardiness so breeders like
David would
typically uh take a Hardy North American
species and cross it with a uh more
colorful but less hearty Asian species
and
as a rule you can intercross quite
freely at the subgeneric level and so
there's really no you don't have to go
to extremes to to try to for these wide
crosses uh and The Offspring themselves
are often fertile so hybridizers would
just cross species with species and
often times some of the the modern
varieties have as many as a dozen
different species in their
background where you don't find renrin
is in these
uh Continental areas of Asia or the us
such as Cleveland uh and that's the
areas where of extreme heat and cold Ro
ders like higher elevations in the
mountains or along
Maritime climates which are more
buffered uh in terms of
temperature all right well briefly uh
the interest in the west and renrin
really evolved out of that crazy
Victorian uh passion for for plants um a
lot of the
uh collections initial collections
coming into the into the West were were
in uh in England sponsored by uh landed
gentry who could fund Expeditions and in
return they would get seed uh so really
the from the GetGo the interest was
among hobbyists enthusiasts and that has
really continued into today's world most
of the Breeders are are just um what I
call backyard breeders I'm definitely an
exception to the
rule uh and some of the first hybrids
were made in England uh the Earl of
Caravan uh created some of the first
road enter hybrids and he was the U
owner of
um it was called uh hi highest Castle
which you know as um down Abbey there
you
go all right so 20 you know a century
and a half later there are over 25,000
registered hybrids not uncommon in
popular plants like like roses let's see
here
okay uh the style of breeding was was
done as pedigree breeding just like dogs
and horses uh breeders had their
favorite uh stud plants to use very
limited triing most things were
introduced commercially based on one
plant at one location and the emphasis
really was on flowers above all uh and
less on uh performance and
adaptability and that's been a problem
in terms of general public uh use of
these plants um particularly soil issues
the requirement for acid soils pH
optimum around five and very good
drainage is required uh and that
primarily has to do with avoidance of
root rot
disease and so many rotoden that are
planted by uh gardeners who are not
knowledgeable buying them at big box
stores and just sticking them into the
foundation next to their down spouts uh
involves improper site selection and
lack of proper soil amendment to try to
overcome those those restriction so
really out of that
25,000 uh group of named hybrids there's
fewer than 20 that are important
commercially on a national have a
national sales presence those are the
so-called Ironclad
roadeden uh which were developed over a
century ago in England uh but have
proven to be very versatile and so my
goal really is to try to expand that
ornamental pallet and create really the
modern
ironclads so I'm taking a collection
that David Leech created really a
50-year uh body of work that that he did
uh that developed these highly
ornamental cold hearty plants and we're
adding traits like root rot disease
resistance and heat tolerance to those
with the goal of getting a plant product
that people can grow more successfully
also one particularly with the addition
of heat tolerance that will broaden the
market renrin typically Fade Out of
culture as you go south around the Mason
Dixon line and um as you go south the
emphasis shifts to Evergreen and
deciduous as
alas so roted ERS are not considered to
be particularly heat tolerant and
disease resistance and heat tolerance
are not really uh coincidental traits
our source of resistance that we're
using happens also to be quite heat
tolerant and we feel that there's
probably a functional relationship
between these two our working hypothesis
in the breeding program is that uh
disease resistance is is important in
warm climates because disease pressure
increases as you get warmer and
wetter so the disease root rot disease
is caused main causal organism is phyto
camoni which uh I will sometimes refer
to as a fungus but truly it's not a true
fungus it's fungus like now classified
in the protstas
um it's a soil pathogen when it finds a
susceptible host it
colonizes right behind the root cap and
then begins to grow through the root
system uh eventually moving up to the
crown region you can see this section
here the the necrotic regions at that
point it's really disrupting the
vascular system of the plant and you see
this
Wilt uh symptom that's the classtic
indication in the choots and that's
irreversible at that point the plants uh
is good as
Dead uh the zoospores are the Infectious
agents shown here in the lower right and
they are motile they have
fella uh they can move a little bit
around in the soil and and under wet
conditions and so that's one of the
reasons why drainage is so important as
a disease avoidance
mechanism well phop there is a problem
for renin and many many other crops
because it's a it's a uh it's a global
invasive it's everywhere and few native
plants like uh many of our renin are
resistant so we early on we were looking
for sources of resistance and when I
started there already was a report uh
done by Pathologists at Ohio State uh in
the mid 70s and so we did another report
in 2002 looking at more contemporary
hybrids just to do screen means and
identify either cultivars or species
that would be useful for breeding only
6% of the hybrids prove resistant and
177% of the species out of these
Collective studies and that's uh that
number gets even smaller when you look
for plants that are not only resistant
but also have some measure of of cold
hardiness which is another one of our
key
criteria so doing resistance screens is
is uh where these are done in control
Greenhouse experiments where we culture
the pathogen in the lab and then make an
inoculum and give it to the plants so
we're either doing these uh like on the
left we're doing inoculations of single
plants and pots that's when we're
usually trying to identify resistance
level in specific genotypes where we
need a replicated trial or we're looking
at seedling population breeding
populations where we're screening
genetically variable um Offspring and uh
these are done when the plants are at
about 6 months of
age one of the key metrics that we use
are are disease root scores or root rot
disease scores which is a numerical
visual
rating uh where on a scale of 1 to five
so one is a healthy root nice quite um
fine Roots
here uh working up to a level of
intermediate level which is uh three
where you have necrotic fine Roots plus
some of these coarse Roots here are also
damaged and we use pruners to kind of
cut and and inspect cross-section as we
go it's a destructive
sample uh up into the crown rot area and
finally five which is a a dead plant
so not so it's important for a parent to
be resistant but also for it to be able
to transmit that resistance to offspring
effectively and not all plants do this
equally well it's based on really
breeding value which in turn is is a
measure of
heritability the resemblance that
Offspring Have to their
parents um and this is a key thing in
Woody plants especially you want a high
heritability value which is estimated on
a scale of 0 to one uh because you want
to make as much gain as possible in one
generation know the generation time in
Woody plants can be long and if you can
get good Pro you make good progress in
one generation that's that's really
valuable So based on uh this is uh these
are the parent scores on the scale of 1
to five versus Offspring on the same
scale and uh we're looking at open
pollinated offspring of all these
parents
and so the heritability estimate which
is a narrow sense heritability a measure
of additive genetic variability is 86
which is a a satisfactorily high number
uh that just suggests that we can make
pretty good gains in one breeding
cycle and that value comes in line with
some uh heritability studies down on
other Woody plants mostly uh these are
all threatened tree species where areas
from areas where pyur is actually
naturalized and is becoming an
ecological issue eucalyptus monter Pine
European Chestnut so the values there
vary from 05 up to about 86 do you have
any similar data about prunus root
stocks in that respect I prunus I
don't ultimately through some trial and
error uh we settled on a really one
species as our foundation for resistance
breeding it's called Roden hyperm it's
native to
Taiwan uh but it's and it it's so but
it's high enough elevation found between
1 and 2,000 MERS in the central
mountains of Taiwan so it has some
hardiness we can grow it it's probably a
zone six plant we can grow it outside uh
in Ohio it did survive this winter uh
but it got took a pretty hard hit um but
it other virtue is heat Taun so this is
a one of the few large leafed Evergreen
species that will grow in the Gulf South
in addition to those traits it has good
ornamental traits this compact bushy
growth glossy foliage nice thick thick
leaves and it's very floriferous
although the only comes in white uh and
the inflorescences or trusses as
gardeners call them are a little bit
open the the
typically the standard is for something
a little more Compact and
organized so from a B's perspective what
we're we're we're crossing this with
plants that we know have uh hardiness
have good saturated colors pinks Reds
yellows
purples and and so
forth so in a breeding experiments uh
again these are inoculated Greenhouse
studies we just this just gives you a
visual idea of of um what comes out of a
cross this is a susceptible cross in
fact most of the parents we're crossing
it with are
susceptible uh this is a variety called
calap open pollinated so there's about
100% mortality uh this is 7 weeks after
inoculation cross with the species no
mortality and the F1 shown here there's
a little there are few dead seedings but
otherwise things look pretty good so
there's a strong resemblance of of the
first generation to the resistant parent
and you can quantify that just by doing
disease progress plots this is using
another susceptible variety yellow one
called
Capistrano um this is the mortality rate
on the Y over days from inoculation so
this is the um open pollinated Offspring
from cap EST Strano a fast trajectory to
Extinction R is the hyperm resistant
parent so it levels off at about 20%
mortality among those seedlings there
seems to be some recombination where um
uh about 20% of The Offspring
are susceptible rather than resistant
and then the
F1 plotted here which levels off and it
tracks closely to the resistant parent
you measure the area under the disease
progress curves and just subtract and
divide and you can end up with a gain of
in this case 83% gain and resistance in
one
generation so with some of those
breeding experiments behind us we we set
off to to generate large numbers of
populations and progyny in in a in
Earnest and and uh this gives an an idea
of how we made those crosses we we
bulked different hyperm genotypes we
didn't want to use just one accession
because we wanted to avoid the
possibility of inbreeding depression in
later
generations and we'd cross those with uh
an array of of cifi in this case this is
the red group of varieties we're looking
for you know strong pinks or Reds out of
this cross we also used yellow purple
whites so forth um and we grew those out
in
quantities with the thought that we
could possibly make some of that first
generation material might be worthy of
introduction but then to take that to
the F2 Generation through siib mating
strategies either full or half
CIB and this shows uh the crosses were
made in 2005 and 2008 we had them
growing out in field rows they all have
kind of the same look pretty dense uh
this is in the open sun they do pretty
well you can see flower buds on them by
a year four most of them had produced
flowers to evaluate and of course they
were spending the winter
outside so we're getting a performance
and an ornamental
evaluation uh within four years uh by
2009 and here it shows you some of the
selections we made out of those thousand
based on ornamental value and
performance so we're reasonably
satisfied since one of the parents was
white and we're happy with what we were
seeing in terms of color saturation
often times too you get this nice
patterning gardeners call them blotches
but of course bees know them as
pollination guides and are any of those
that we're seeing now named CS uh
whoops on this list uh actually no but I
will finish up with
I'll show
you okay in fact this I'm going to peel
off from the breeding program at this
point and pick it up at the end of the
talk and Detour a bit on on some stress
testing we've done so uh I've been
talking so far really about you know uh
transferring resistance
genes
um to to progyny and in pathology the
operating principle is is called the
disease triangle
I know many of you have probably been
introduced to this uh so the disease
symptoms we
see uh under in outdoor conditions is
really the interaction between the host
plant the pathogen and the environment
and the environment can have a huge
effect on
moderating um the outcomes and typically
uh stress environmental conditions
reduce resistance that's a phenomena
that's called predisposition so if you
look at abiotic stresses like extremes
of moisture or temperature salinity
ozone those are all things that can
somehow change host physiology in a way
that
weakens uh its defense response and in
particular I was interested in looking
at flooding and heat because those are
two traits that deal immediately with
our desire to move these plants South
and also with uh really the heavy kind
of substandard soil conditions you find
in most most
Landscapes so in 2011 we conducted a
field flooding trial we put out an array
of genotypes um some unknowns as well as
some controls both susceptible and
resistant
checks and um this was an area where we
knew that we suspected the pathogen was
present in our Fields the idea initially
was to flood the area by pumping in
water from our pond but it it turned out
to be the wetest year on record in
Northeast Ohio so mother nature took
over our treatment plan and we had
conditions like shown there on the left
repeatedly throughout the season
probably on seven or eight occasions
where we would we would flood and then
over the course of a day or two it would
drain so by the end of one season then
there were clear you know most things
were looking pretty bad from outright
dead to often times a chosis is a sign
of of stress of of root Rod damage but
what really stood out was how well
hypertherm
performed uh under those conditions
that's shown
here so
it and when we did it so we we harvested
all the dead plants got root scores of
five and then we harvested the survivors
and and um calculated the values for
those
and this shows the breakdown we had
groups of susceptible plants resistant
benchmarks three of those are resistant
plants that don't have hyperm in them
some experimental hybrids with unknown
um resistance levels and then the
species itself at the bottom and on the
left here this column shows uh disease
scores under non-f flooded conditions
and these were determined in previous
experiments uh before the the field Tru
trial so um you know our resistant group
uh here and here had Roots values of
about two which is equivalent to uh just
damage to fine Roots but but nothing
further under flooded conditions um some
clear changes occurred everything was
more susceptible under stress but in
particular the the resistant benchmarks
almost doubled from uh their root scores
so that's equivalent to from going from
just having fine root damage to damage
up in the crown region so these plants
were nearly dead and contrast
hyperm uh although the values went up in
root scores only about
30% and the hybrids of hypertherm uh did
quite well overall they weren't
significantly different from the the
parent species in terms of root score
values
and you know we're attributing these
results not to flooding stress uh
directly but to um pathogens and I mean
hypoxia is a possibility uh typically
doesn't lead in to U plant
mortality uh and Road D are can handle
about 48 Hours of flooding with with no
issue um plus the plants really the
sequence are mortality in the field
really followed our expectations based
on our Benchmark so that the susceptible
plants died right away resistant plants
held on
longer and then to kind of close out
that that question we also um isolated
phytop from necrotic regions uh of the
field plants and so that's done by in
this case we took pieces of stem near
the crown region grew them out on
semi-elective media which will screen
for phyas but not at at the genus level
but not at the species level um phop
chinon though does have kind of an
unusual morphology uh it's Coral like or
coralloid so that's another indication
of a potential match and then finally uh
we had those samples sent to Ohio State
and they did a sequence
analysis against the there's a
diagnostic storage protein in in phyto
cinamon and the match was 96 to 100% so
we're fairly certain that um that uh
really
flood um the phyto was was causing the
symptoms and that it was uh that some of
the effects we were seeing were were
aided and eded by by the flooding
treatment uh so in conclusions from the
flooding trials that it's it's less um
predisposed to disease than other
resistant renrin the trait's heritable
because the
f1s um did almost add statistically they
did as well as the resistant parent and
this is good in the sense that uh in
terms of a a a product development
because we could potentially develop
Renren that can withstand uh sub those
poor soils heavy soils found around uh
in home
Landscapes we also looked at heat
stress and uh this this is another key
question the um being that are these
plants that are adapted to warm climates
like
hyperin uh less predisposed to disease
under high temperature stress and to do
these kinds of experiments we we um we
chose we we chose a a pulse treatment
method where you could expose tissue in
this case roots to
heat remove that stress then inoculate
it or and include
uninoculated controls and then
subsequently measure the level of
resistance in those treated
plants and we use large water baths such
as this one here to um apply heat we
grow either single plants or seedlings
and pots and then drop those pots into a
poly bag and immerse it in the water
bath for treatment and our treatment
temperatures range from s of room
temperature up to about 42 Celsius
typically the experiment was done one
hour to Target in the bath and then one
hour at the Target
temperature and these are some data we
just got uh this winter um comparing
Asian
species U for the response to heat
stress uh and I just have summary means
for these I don't I haven't run the
stats yet um but basically we have a red
so these are root Rod scores plotted
against days after inoculation and we're
comparing on the bars the
controls wither without heat but no
phyo and then wither without heat plus
phop being the green bars and the dark
green is the heat treatment so one thing
to point out in the controls is that
there's no lethal effect of this heat
stress on the
plants um and in this case this is a
species from Central Asia called ponum
it's a susceptible plant it was really
our control and it it uh we reached
almost complete mortality within a week
and a half of inoculation in both um the
nonstress and the heat treatment no
surprises there I mean it's hard to make
a very susceptible plant more
susceptible uh in contrast though we we
looked at two Asian species that are
resistant one from Japan called kisi
which is not considered to be heat
tolerant and then our heat tolerant
hyper
eum and in those cases the heat stress
in kisi the dark green clearly elevated
the disease scores uh especially in the
early part of the time course again I
don't have a test yet on significance
but it it looks like it could
be uh and hypertherm uh except for the
very first sampling date which could be
sampling error uh all subsequent dates
the heat stress plants showed uh the
same as or or lower uh root scores than
the non-stress one so seem to Su suggest
that hyperm is not
predisposed to Disease by higher soil
temperatures much in the way that it was
less predisposed um by flooding so those
are good two attributes in addition to
resistance per se
um another study
was uh more um ecological so we wanted
to know whether in natural populations
are warm adapted ecotypes more disease
tolerant uh following heat stress than
their uh cold tolerant relatives and and
do this we switch to a a species called
renin minus which is native to the
Eastern
us and it grows from high elevation
North Carolina down to within 50 miles
of the Gulf Coast so in the Florida
Panhandle and um Southern Alabama for
instance and we've been collecting those
over the years putting together a trying
to capture the really a rangewide
collection of this species and we have
compared
two um two populations so far uh the one
here at elevation 4,000 ft in North
Carolina
and one at low elevation in southern
Georgia um called Providence Canyon so
this is the shrub here at the top of
hawkville mountain and you'd find the
the road enter minus at the bottom of
this Canyon along the
riverbed in Providence
Canyon so we did the same kinds of um
disease progress plots same kind of heat
treatments that I described earlier um
temperatures were a little bit different
I'm showing you results at 26 and at 42
celus we also did them at 34 and 50
C um looking at mortality rates over
time so at
26 um and the blue is the northern high
elevation population and the red is the
southern low and these are the controls
down here so heat treated but not
inoculated again there's no that heat
treatment appears to be
sublethal and um at 26 they they're
basically the same statistically the
same uh response both species are highly
susceptible uh to phyo so there's I know
mortality within almost complete within
under two weeks from inoculation and
that you'd expect that uh in the case of
a natural population that's being
challenged with an invasive pathogen
it's never seen it
before uh at 42 Celsius I there's a high
degree of mortality and ultimately in
both populations but the the rate of
disease development or mortality in the
southern population is much slower and
looking at areas under the
curve here that turns out to be a
statistically significant difference
so there is a transient effect anyway
the heat stress appears to be initiating
some sort of Defense
response in the warm climate ecotypes
that's not found in the cold ones so
that I thought was a fairly novel result
and we want to uh see if we can
generalize that those data looking at a
larger sample of
populations still the question of root
damage is there you know it's sublethal
but you don't know if there is some
something going on at 42 Cel that's
pretty warm uh so we um and that could
confound the interpretation of results
so we did um some viability assays on
both populations using TTC staining a
vital stain that will turn cells Pink as
it as it's reduced by mitochondria and
you can elute that stain and you know
measure it spectrometer with a
spectrometer so here we're showing
absorbance uh standardized over dry
weight uh milligrams dry weight for both
Southern low Northern High populations
and there is no significant difference
in viability estimated that way so we
feel that at within that 26 to 42
Celsius window um root viability is not
an issue and that's a good range of
temperatures to continue working in
at 50 Celsius I mentioned we we had done
um we had done a screen there and there
actually was probably 50% loss of
viability in those tissues a bit too
extreme well we don't really understand
in Rod Dennis what's going on at the
physiological level but there are
reports there's increasingly reports
from other systems notably rabid opsis
and tomato of of how uh pred disos might
function and it really involves sort of
antagonistic me metabolisms so you start
with a resistant uh plant given it an
abiotic stress that kicks in the hormone
abscissic acid which is commonly it's a
very common uh upregulated stress
related hormone but ABA increased ABA
can cause a inhibition of Defense
signaling Pathways that are
specifically those mediated by jasmonic
acid or salicylic acid so if there is
then a pathogen challenge during or at
subsequent to that stress then the
defense system of the plant is lowered
and you can change phenotypes from
resistance to
susceptible that's um that's kind of a
consensus model there's certainly lots
of uh variations on that and we know and
what I feel from my work since we've
identified genotypes that are less
predisposed that clearly there's
probably involves some different uh uh
regulation at the gene level and with
the Advent of less expensive genomic
analyses
metabolomics comparative transcriptome
analysis uh these would be perhaps
fruitful studies uh for the future if
you were predisposed to
that all right well finally back to the
breeding program um since we wanted to
develop heat tolerant Lo of Denis the
obvious thing was to put them in the
South and see how they did uh for this
work uh we found a industry partner with
plant development services based in U
near Mobile Alabama uh they have a brand
called Southern Living plant collection
which is um quite popular and pdsi
really they're not a nursery person say
they they work between breeders like me
and the marketplace they they take care
of the the development aspects of the
plant um those are services that we
don't have in House at
Holden and uh the test site was in
Southern Louisiana Independence we put
had put in over 165 selections that we
made in Madison initially and and a put
out a replicated field trial the plants
were shaded I think for the first half
of the first summer and subsequently
have been out uh in the
open um in in this is now the beginning
of year three of the trial so they get
fairly strong afternoon sun
uh and based on the results so far there
are really about 20% or maybe 30 out of
the 165 select collections that we put
in have really performed well that is
we're um you know we're at 100% Survivor
ship and then the surviving plants
themselves are um vigorous Growers they
have good Leaf quality and they're
producing good flowers such as the one
shown
here and this past March I was down
there uh while they were in bloom the
first time I had been there in In Bloom
and we selected three for introdu ction
uh those are the ones shown here so uh
two pinks one kind of a clear pink the
other more of a rose pink some of these
patterns these flares and blotches this
one has a a frilled margin to the pedal
um as does this there's another nice
feature where the petals the backs of
the petals will be Darkly pigmented and
the face will be lighter so that creates
kind of a a by color effect and these
little nuances do make a difference it
makes the plant fancier and we're you
know we hope that these can compete with
what's already kind of been established
as the current standard for
renrin uh and of course in the South
they will have no competition because
there are no
rendin yet that um have been developed
there so these will go into tissue
culture one this one already is uh and
then subsequently out to uh Growers
we can glean some extra information from
that field trial by um we want to do the
confirm the presence of phyo just as we
did in in Madison Ohio by isolating and
sequencing the pathogen uh just to prove
that that's what's causing it it is an
old Nursery site uh and they apparently
grew a lot of aelas and Chamas there and
those are both host for phytop and
because nurseries are constantly moving
plants in and out of their in ventory
and phyo travels in soil it's quite
likely that it's there all the certainly
the symptoms are consistent with it and
then it would be good to go back and
look at both the top and bottom classes
of performers you know we have the
original mother plants still in Ohio and
um so we can go back to them and do uh
test for resistance under control
conditions and confirm that they are
respective resistant or susceptible and
that will really close the circle on
this notion that uh disease
resistance is is a key trait to um
surviving in a warm climate like that
with high disease
pressure well Holden we always talk
about being about more than just a
pretty plant uh because we're a serious
institution on a serious mission but the
and so I even though the scope of my
project is fairly narrow I've tried to
move it in a Direction that's topical
that addresses the issues that um you
know knowledgeable scientists are are
concerned about in these days and age
and so the issue of sustainability is
addressed because resistance will allow
probably result in reduced pesticide use
typically fungicide drenches that are
used in nurseries plants are broadly
adaptable uh I think my goal of covering
zones 5 to n has probably been modified
by the past two Winters and I think we
will release these marketed to zone six
to n although you can you know many zone
five winners it will do fine just as it
has done well in Ohio um up until
recently we'll call them climate change
ready certainly they're they're
positioned for um global warming and
warming is not just an issue in terms of
stress on Plants but most
predictions uh state that disease
pressure will also increase under those
conditions um and there's an increased
chance with warmer climats that
pathogens like phyto could
naturalize in in our Northern forests
and finally it's a good example of a you
know solution based use of
biodiversity um showing how uh we can
tap a species like hyperm to address a
real stubborn problematic issue like
root rot disease finally I'd just like
to
thank my some of my staff uh Jing Wong
is a research associate who works year
round with me and Hillary Wright is been
a seasonal it's one of our volunteers
Susan Hannah and Mike
collaboration with pdsi uh is through um
Buddy Lee shown here on the right who's
the director of plant Innovations for
pdsi and also an accomplished ornamental
breeder in his own right and finally a
few sources of
funding U not to mention our my major
underwriter which is the hold
arum that's okay we can have the lights
on
you had mentioned you had like maybe 10
genotypes of H used to prevent in
compression were those selected for
Superior performance in terms of
resistance from a
broader they were I
um although there is some structure
those they were I didn't have any H
plant when I started wasn't in our
collection uh but there's a u outfit in
on the west coast called the third end
of species Foundation ATA Washington and
they have a pretty good World collection
including several hyp region so they
made some crosses of those accession
their accession and sent me SE and then
I screen that for resistance and took
out really the survivors that were
really the
most um you didn't know about their
flower attributes
um the time we selected those pars most
these but there are some different some
you have larger flowers but maybe more
substance
others do any of the uh new varieties
have ornamentally interesting
grp no they're not really known for
showing food it's uh they're green
turning
brown yes I ask if you have any idea
what the resistance
is no um I don't really I it's it's a
it's
polygenic it's not an
AR so it's it's probably it's probably
multi could
invol
PHS we think that there's an age
responsibity I didn't show that on the
didn't discuss it on the her plot but
the The
Offspring um scores were the
whole they had shifted up and Val so
they were more susceptible in parents as
a group because we were measuring six
mon versus phys mature
parents yeah
so when you your D you R how are we
going to
know each had the
cities Geographic names right so what
are you going to do so car
we well I I guess a lot of it it may be
somewh out of my hands I think pdsi will
probably have their own ideas and
they're really you know they're the
marketeers they do a lot that and maybe
they have a sense of what
what so we haven't quite got to that
point of discussion but uh we sort of
have another we sort of do what I call
Leach classic hyds that we're
introducing uh we taking the name
gold solar
FL so you will know
those those wouldn't be for the South
they would be for the traditional
well I think we're out of time but again
I want to thank you Steve for traveling
to itha and sharing uh your research
with us you're welcome thank you
for this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu