this is a production of Cornell
University one of the great parts of
this gig here at Cornell is going in and
out of the city every once in a while
New York City is a fascinating place
where grass meets people and I got a
chance to walk on as the moodlight was
out the old Lincoln Center roof that I
worked on many years ago back in 2009
when they built this roof and put the
grass on it um a number of years ago it
was just a beautiful night and wandered
around Central Park with Zack Holmes on
Tuesday uh very interesting uh Landscape
Management there of which sports turf is
involved and you know Carl we can't
start out without something ridiculous
right who knows what happened you hope
nobody was hurt this guy looks like he
went off a off the road or off a
embankment or hit the wrong button and
the guy says maybe didn't like our pin
placements that day so you never know
what these kinds of things you know car
we've been talking a lot about putting
animals to work this has been a common
Trend this guy doesn't look so happy
Happ about it this time maybe he didn't
get a good night's sleep or whatever but
he's not thrilled about having to work
and then a big uh Melancholy shout out
to Tom Kaplan the current president of
nista just had to put his dog down this
is a big thing uh in our industry with
the connection between dogs and our work
life and our personal life and our
emotional well-being and when these
things happen it's always good to share
it with each other as a person who
didn't grow up with a dog but then had a
dog I sort of realized man this thing
hits pretty hard when it does and just
in case anybody was wondering whether I
won the pie in the face contest thanks
to everybody who contributed uh to this
Ridiculousness we raised uh $600 for the
farm neck group here at Cornell uh and
as a member of the a science faculty
here uh I was happy to do it with my
colleague Mike Amber Mike Van Amberg in
Dairy science all right Carl I'm gonna
do the weather quick we're gonna do the
rant and then we're going to get right
into a little bit of me to set up our
conversation with Trent uh with chent
with Trent with Chase sorry uh soils are
still pretty cool I gotta say uh you
know things are growing for sure but
when you look at our soil temperature
data you know just from a few days ago
you can see we're still in the upper 40s
mid-50s uh the 60s have moved down only
into the delm Marva Peninsula really and
last week of course was cooler than
normal right when you look at the
departure uh you see it very cool along
the coast but the big story this uh
spring has been the rain and I don't
know what's going on in in in the South
Chase but we are we are sort of
saturated we are half saturated here and
you know as we get the conversation this
has to be an element of a conversation
with the kind of field you choose to use
no matter what web of decision making
you have to uh navigate or map of
decision making you have to navigate uh
when it comes to uh climate change and I
know it's mentioned in your proposal
that we'll talk about later uh but but
this is of course something to consider
because you're In the Heat of the spring
Sports season now right up here where we
are we're in the heat of the spring
Sports season now the other thing is you
know we don't go crazy about this but
you know we're a few weeks behind last
year uh maybe only a week or so behind
normal but this is going to change
pretty quick and we'll talk about this
in a minute if you look at Carl's growth
model that he's built here on the
forecast website Carl I got to remember
to put the QR code up there so people
can see this but if you are listening on
the podcast the forecast website really
has this wonderful growth model that
picked up the little bit of blip and
growth we got last week and we saw it
really in the in the research plots as
well nice blip of growth but you see
that's returned to very slow growth and
it looks like forecasts for the next few
days are going to be slow as well now as
we heard this morning on our weekly
conference call uh it looks like it's
going to be warm and dry for a couple of
weeks this is a very interesting pattern
uh we went into a prolonged dry period
art wasn't willing to put his neck on
the line uh for going longer than 8 to
10 days but certainly a a a period where
you we're going to get some dry weather
now the other part I can't leave you
without uh thinking about our risk
assessment tool on the forecast website
uh it looks like as you get South the
red risk is growing and if you look
carefully at our weed control where we
recommend the 24d applications in the
spring based on degree day models you
can see it's also moving into that same
area
so this is exactly what we're talking
about and Carl you raised a really good
point uh uh over the week when we were
chatting about this you know you see
what happens when you get obsessed with
grass every place you walk and go you
see these things everywhere you take a
picture the people just finished mowing
uh this lawn by our botanic garden
probably at three and a half inches and
it still remains uh filled with flowers
now that's not really the topic of today
nor is this Ridiculousness at Real
Madrid stadium Chase I don't know if
you've had a chance to see this
craziness but this is some other level
hydraulic meeting of uh controlled
environment agriculture vertical
agriculture uh with sports turf of all
things and Carl as we uh sort of get to
you your rant that's the setup for today
uh we hear a lot about these surfaces
look at the lengths we go to to give
them a natural grass surface Carl what
else is involved here yeah right so we
we're always talking about field safety
right Frank and and how we can manage
the fields specifically to meet these
certain thresholds or or uh benchmarks
whether it's traction or firmness or
ball roll or ball bounce however you
choose to measure it uh but ultimately
the athlete is still interacting with
the surface with some sort of Footwear
on their foot right and and we talked
about this a bit with Andy mcnet in past
episodes but that selection of Footwear
is really important and how it pertains
to their performance and their safety on
the field uh so you can just it doesn't
take very long to figure out that people
have been trying to optimize Footwear
for athletes for a long time uh you look
at some of the research in running where
the the how the collar fits on your
ankle changes your gate and how you
decelerate and turn uh the midsole
thickness apparently is a big factor and
how thick that sort of s shoe sole is
influences how the energy transfers up
your leg while you're running so it can
have an injury risk it can also have uh
a performance aspect and then they also
look at hey when you're running on
concrete versus a rubber track you
should pick shoes that have different
sort of sole depths right if if you're
on a unforgiving Surface like concrete
you need a larger depth because you
don't want all that energy going back up
into your knee and your hip and and
elevating your injury risk so right
shoes matter for performance and for
safety Andy mcnet has looked at this a
bunch and we've talked about the the
sort of traction elements of Footwear
and he's looked at um you know studies
with this and now they have their
traction database basically saying hey
when you select a footwear that has a
certain traction sort of component it's
going to affect your injury risk
especially based on the field so they've
got this traction ba database at the
Penn State website Bermuda grass
Kentucky Bluegrass field Turf and they
will give you the traction values of
specific Footwear types and what they
say is hey the highest traction value
may be good for performance you can
stick your foot in the ground and and
change direction really quickly but that
also increases your injury risk right if
that shoe's not going to give something
in that system is going to give and it's
probably your ankle or or your knee
right if you're an athlete who can
generate a lot of force but can't then
move uh you don't want to select a
really high traction shoe so you got to
find something in the middle that
matches also the traction of the
surfaces you're playing on right so
there's the interaction between the
Surface and the Footwear we also know
people are different too right Frank and
and we've done a little bit of research
with uh Footwear and putting surfaces
and we find that different people cause
different amounts of disruption to
putting surfaces right you could see
here if you're watching uh subject a
creates a lot more visual disruption to
the putting surface than subject B
because they walk a little bit
differently right and how they apply
Force into the ground is different so
all this would say hey if I'm a
professional athlete uh and I want to
maximize performance but I also want to
minimize my injury risk I should
probably have a really sort of in-depth
detailed way to choose my shoes on Game
Day right at at the NFL level these are
organizations valued I don't know five
to 10 billion dollars surely there is
someone on staff who can select Footwear
based on the game day field and the
athletes that are in that field but uh I
saw this video a couple months ago this
is from Hard Knock a documentary series
uh they followed the the Miami Dolphins
last year and before the playoff game in
Kansas City here's our running backs
coach and in the video he's talking to
the running backs in the room he says
hey guys it's going to look like a green
field but it's painted dirt okay it's
painted dirt that's what it is so make
sure you take a couple pairs of shoes
there's there's two things that I don't
like about this FR one this is Arrowhead
Stadium Travis Hogan generally regarded
as the gold standard of of sports turf
managers right I think everybody in the
industry that that uh field that staff
is is sort of the level that we all
aspire to so that's that's one thing
calling this uh just painted grass or
painted dirt the second thing is he's
leaving this decision about what
footwear to choose up to the athletes
and they will always choose the highest
traction shoe because it maximizes
performance they shouldn't have to go
through a bunch of literature and figure
out okay which one's the best for injury
risk though and how should I measure the
field before there should be somebody on
staff who's making that decision uh
during the games and maybe there is and
maybe this quote is taken out of context
but man it feels like this is a coach
just saying hey guys you got some shoes
at home bring a couple run around a
little bit and and you'll figure it out
and and that man that does not seem like
a wise thing uh when you've got that
amount of stakes that amount of
competition that amount of money
involved uh in in sports yeah so and and
so there's the rant right the rant is
this should be safety equipment not
something a running back's coach is
advising unless he's got a brief uh to
to address this particular issue because
I think it's funny right when you think
about that Carl how little it appears
and of course we could be taking this
out of context it appears not much
thought seems to be given even though
I've heard from John sarakin and Andy
that they they put signs in the locker
rooms uh at these things about the kinds
of Footwear that they recommending
things now it seems odd to me when data
is such a part of the game right the
analytics of like just a soccer game uh
where on the field the action is taking
uh Chase has looked into this over the
years but there's also the strategy of
the way you want to play and where uh
the traffic winds up uh being
concentrated now chase this is
interesting right because you did a lot
of work in this area this is where I
want to start with we SED set up i s of
saw what Carl was going to do I like oh
this is a perfect setup for for for our
pal Chase okay the Footwear might be a
hidden risk we don't think about but
you've identified there's a lot of
variability in the field and in your
real great work right you basically said
listen there's a lot of things that vary
but the important stuff like soil
moisture and hardness don't really vary
much over the course of a tournament or
when you want something to perform it
depends on how what it is going in or
the existing variability in the field so
no matter how it happens there's going
to be some out there over a period of
Time how when if you had to reconcile
Footwear and
inconsistencies let's start at the
highest level where they strive to make
them uniform do you think those
inconsistencies are perceptible by the
athlete or in some ways also
contributing to the equation
yeah well thanks thanks for having me on
guys appreciate it always fun um yeah I
haven't seen these this figure in a long
time
yeah yeah this is some of my early work
you know you know it it depends Frank I
think when we talk professional sports
it's so different now with the lay
andplay side and how much they're
they're renovating the field so
frequently I don't know the degree of
within field variability at that level
you know but when you're talking about
some of the the the community level
fields that that I work on I mean even
Collegiate level Fields they're not
renovating as frequently as the
professionals I do think there's a
degree of of within field variability I
think as long as you have a 100% grass
cover that probably doesn't get into the
athletes head but if you're on a you
know High School level natural grass
natural soil native soil field um yeah
if the we've done research we've
interviewed athletes they recognize when
there's no grass cover or thin grass
cover and they actually do adjust the
way they behave and I would assume that
their Footwear and footing would would
do that too we haven't looked at that
specifically um but I would assume that
that it would interact differently all
right good okay sorry to be a blast from
the past but this no you're good yeah
yeah but but that variability that you
identified is exactly what we wanted to
say is at the highest level maybe this
isn't an issue and those guys really
need to think about Footwear because
every you know the fields are as good as
we can get them uh at that level one
would hope but this is a pretty good
example of what an average Community
Field will look like in in August uh
when the players get back and you've got
crab grass filling in there going to be
going a flower soon now over the years
Chase we've sort of tried to address
this on our sports turf website we have
this very simple tool that I've used
with school boards a couple of times and
gone around with the ground staff and
talked about sort of how would you rate
this have the guy ask a question make
sure they understood what the grounds
man new you know start to create this
community Dynamic and then Carl passes
along this and I know he passed it on to
you I want to start sort of with like
the gold standard we we're not entirely
sure who did this work So eventually
we'll just put it out there and see
where all this came from but a a School
District in California Fremont
California it looks like uh presented
something back in 2020 in the fall uh
about a Synthetic Turf versus natural
grass this is an incredibly elaborate
presentation of which the only thing
that immediately jumped out worthy of
our discussion here is not all traffic
is the same we don't really know how to
quantify it that's what this graph is
saying but an hour of baseball is
different than an hour of field hockey
an hour of softball is different than an
hour of rugby right when it comes to the
amount of wear and tear uh the fields
should be able to or you know are going
to have to handle and Carl we think
about this like with rounds of golf too
a much easier measure uh in some ways to
determine especially with nikolai's work
years ago that we're going to validate
this Summer that the majority of the
steps on a putting green happen right
around the the whole location so we know
not all traffic is the same and so you
have all these variables Chase here's
this great title of the proposal uh that
you're doing and in the background is
Joe Magle oa's uh field down in Elmyra
City School District uh exactly the
kinds of fields that you and I sort of
have to we work with all the time we
don't work at the highest levels where
they have where money's not an object
but it's not just about the money right
when you look at this proposal and I'm
putting this up here so everybody else
can glaze over at the amount of uh a
logic that's going into trying to
determine how to solve field problems
help communities answer the question is
natural turf or Synthetic Turf
a better option and in the meantime
navigate the web of communication this I
think Chase really depicts uh the
project here so let's let's start right
here with the conversation right we
think about Footwear we think about uh
field quality you've already passed the
comment just give me full Gras cover and
we when we three talk and the people
that might be listening think okay well
how hard is that that doesn't seem hard
you know Ben Palmer puts him on sneakers
in the spring right to not put as much
wear and tear okay uh so how why is this
so hard because Carl and I also know how
hard this is but talk a little bit about
navigating something that seems simple
like just get really good grass cover
and should be able to hold up to a
certain amount of wear and tear and
getting that executed on many of the
communities uh throughout the
country that's a loaded question get it
buddy that's that's why we paid a big
bucks to be here brother I I mean it it
all boils down to to funding and I and
that's going to be related to having
some professional sports field Turf
sports turf manager um to to hire
somebody who's knowledgeable and how to
do that is that the first step is that
is that it if you had to boil it down to
the key to making this happen is it
making sure they can attract somebody
who knows like they do what they're
doing just like they do for HVAC systems
and other systems in facility operations
how come we can't get it viewed as a
trade like that if that's the key is it
the key and how come yeah I think so and
it's because you have somebody
knowledgeable on how to and this is true
for Synthetic Turf maintenance too you
have somebody knowledge knowable on what
it takes to properly maintain the field
rather than somebody who doesn't and so
they're going to be the one who's
getting educated hopefully attending
things like this okay keeping up with
the industry and they're gonna they're
going to be the resource on okay how do
we provide the safe playable fields and
that's for all field okay so so um as I
said you know the weather's not so good
and we got a lot of kids want to play
sports and we got a lot of native soil
Fields uh up this neck of the woods um
I would say the uh uh frequency of
questions we're getting in New York
outside of New York nationally from
concerned people not necessarily people
in the management business that when we
deal with regularly but a different
level of sort of advocacy that um
they're against Synthetic Turf they've
sort of turned on Synthetic Turf now the
the preponderance some Synthetic Turf
system so when you try to navigate this
thing in your mind as you see this grant
unfolding what do you think are the keys
that you're going to develop in this
grant that are going to be important for
forming that decision that even if
somebody wanted to think about it now
what are some of the things that are
going to come out of this work and you
think people should be considering that
are keys in that discussion at the
community
level well I think one thing is you know
we're we're turf grass scientists right
the three of us um but at the same time
we're researchers and our job is to
provide un unbiased data to stakeholders
to benefit their job and so from with
that perspective we have to do a fair
assessment on natural grass versus
Synthetic Turf in all aspects of what
we're evaluating in that study and you
know so our initial submission was last
year and that was a knock on it as we
were to prograss and when I first got
that comment from a reviewer that we
need to be more unbiased I was like
really this is USDA yada yada and I was
kind of upset about it but after sitting
on it for a year and having to reformat
this this proposal you know I I get now
why they want that um they can't invest
a lot of money when our initial we have
an initial bias already uh that we want
to that grass is going to be the best we
it was obvious the way that we first
read it written it so we we we
reformatted it we've pulled in Industry
people from all from every side and we
we're truly coming at it from a more
unbiased approach and that's going to
benefit every body because we're going
to have we're going to have factual
information none of these numbers are
going to be leaning one way or the other
they are what they are right and we have
we have people now on board that's going
to help us balance that so I think that
that's that was top priority with the
resubmission um now within that I mean
all the factors that we're trying to
consider in the study I mean we're
looking at environmental factors uh
safety uh costs obviously and one field
type will probably be beneficial in one
scenario and another field type will be
beneficial in another so it's not going
to be so cut and dry um but nonetheless
we need to provide unbiased information
so that people can make the decisions
that's best for themselves I mean when
you talk about professional level Fields
um you know they they're a completely
different world than Community level
fields and all the the variability in
community level Fields is so extreme so
just to be able to provide large scale
unbiased information about all field
types covering all components of
community Level Sports Fields is our
goal so that they can make the decisions
for themselves it's not natural grass
versus Synthetic Turf it's just they
have they have the information they need
that's exactly right so so and here is
you know what a extension scientist who
doesn't do too much research in this
area generally tells people especially
with a spring like this with the amount
of kids that want to play you got two
options if you have natural grass and
you got you know 200 % normal rainfall
uh you better have a lot of extra Fields
where you're going to have to sacrifice
and move them around to a certain extent
even if they're built out of sand right
if if you don't rotate them or relign
them or move them around if you get this
kind of weather you're going to see
significant damage right so this is
where I'd say this is a time where
access to some Synthetic Turf is really
valuable in the summertime I'd say I
don't want the those kids on that Turf
that Turf even up here in Upstate New
York's going to get really hot never
mind what it's going to be down there in
Texas I mean there's some very simple
things involved here but what I I don't
know Carl what do you think too because
you've also interacted with these people
my sense is you get a lot of project
management people involved in these
communities as well and I was trying to
think you you know you got this web of
stakeholders and there's always going to
be somebody driving the bus and who's
sort of putting down the initi stuff and
I think they're very project management
engineering oriented like you Carl and I
think they're like how much can I use it
and how much does it cost me to maintain
it know I want to use it I want to Main
and these other things are more like
okay well like we'll figure that out
because everything else has to be
somewhere between that right Carl so do
is that what it boils down to in the
conversations you started to have with
folks there might be a bit of that but I
think the Nuance as long some people
like Frank you just explained synthetic
is great for the spring it's not great
for the summer and and that's sort of an
if then thing that that's not a zero or
one like okay we either need synthetic
or we need natural and that's where I
think just a little bit we poked around
with with sort of K through 12
facilities they want to make a decision
and then that's it like that's the the
last we have to think about fields we
can focus on the building and Pest
Control in the building and education of
our students and like Chase is saying
really you need somebody there who's a
professional and knows the day-to-day
and the week to week and the
month-to-month activities that will vary
based on the season or based on the use
um and and one thing we got from Chase's
proposal when you shared with us last
year Chase was like whoa we don't
understand who's making decisions at
Community levels like is it just a coach
who coaches football and it's just like
yeah I'll mow the fields and then I'll
make all the you know like baseball
fields I didn't realize a lot of the
baseball coaches end up mowing those
sort of high school level middle level
Fields they're making decisions they're
just a baseball coach and probably have
another full-time job right so we don't
even understand who's making decisions
and that's why it's really important to
get this work done Chase is like we know
the turf stuff that you should do it
should be easy but all those other
factors if it's parents if it's
administrators if it's facility people
who are really focused on HVAC or power
generators getting generators or
something like that and they're just
mowing the fields right like that's the
sort of but
but this is why but this is why they go
to Synthetic Turf right Chason you said
it the assumption is it's no maintenance
for Synthetic Turf that I can build it
and forget it it's Capital money it's
not annual operating dollars I signed a
warranty the company's going to come for
six years and make sure it's cared for
right and so you know it gets at least a
little bit of that but I I think the
critical point is it it's not no
maintenance especially the infills right
the various amount of infils you can
infils you can use the various sports
that move the stuff around but here's my
question since you're on the hot seat
here today brother Pro this might be the
last time we get you but when you sit
down okay so they said don't be so
progress so I'm assuming you reach out
to people with involved in Synthetic
Turf and I can tell you that when I've
sat in the same room giving a natural
Turf talk after a Synthetic Turf talk no
knock on the science of Synthetic Turf
but the guy before me sound like he was
selling a carpet for your living room
the various stitchings and weavings and
logos and things you could get on there
and when I brought up safety everybody
was like what's what's this guy talking
about wait wait there's something wrong
with Synthetic Turf that's the first
part of it a lot of those people
involved in helping inform the decision
they're looking even the guys at the
school grounds level they're looking to
influence that did the Synthetic Turf
guys get a little defensive are they a
little uh squirly when it comes to it
because I know the natural Turf guys are
a little squirly about Synthetic Turf
are the Synthetic Turf guys equally a
little defensive about it no no comment
no I'm
joking yeah yeah I mean they all are
right they all want to push their
product and they all want to push their
their their initiative and but to me the
the Synthetic Turf companies that were
really on board from the GGO for my
initial ask to be a part of this project
are the ones that truly do care about
putting out useful information and
unbiased information and so I I've I've
starting to internally identify who
those people are and to me I think
that's good I think they should do that
and they're all for it and they
understand that things might not benefit
them but they also understand things
probably could benefit them um and it's
not going to be beneficial to one
specific sector right there's going to
be benefits and disadvantages of
everything that we found in this St yeah
and so you might as well get used to
your success in this project likely with
both sides feeling a little bit upset
with you which is a space Carl and I
have inhabited for a number of years so
welcome to the club we're making up
shirts Carl we got any questions uh from
the audience on cha for Chase or any
more from you uh let's see no questions
one question I have uh Chase is uh have
you guys thought about you know like
we're talking about the decision- making
process and there's going to be a lot of
factors you guys want to just provide
the information for communities or or
school districts to to make a decis
ision any thought about including AI in
there like a decision making tool or
software that can help maybe they just
enter a couple things like we have this
much money we have you know these
weather conditions on a given year any
thoughts about a tool at the end that
can they can just sort of put stuff in
and it spits out a decision for them yep
absolutely so that's the end deliverable
that's that's like our big thing that
we're building towards all this data
feeds into a system they can go in with
their specific scenario their budget the
people they got hours of use whatever
and just spit out a recommendation
that's the end goal yep that's a home
run that well and then every so so
basically what's about to happen is uh
before you close the hood everybody's
going to get a chance to look under it
and have some uh influence in in what's
in there and then once the person are
you is it going to be something that
person using the tool is going to have
to self-identify it's like I'm an
administrator I'm a grounds manager or
it doesn't really matter you're just
have to enter in the logistics of the
district use and money and people and
stuff like that yeah the goal is to
identify through earlier objectives of
the project who those decision makers
are and honestly anybody can use the
tool but the the idea would be to
promote it to the actual to the decision
makers yeah all right because it's a
very contentious issue Chase of course
we know we like to fight about
everything up here New York we're
looking for a fight most Frank Frank
going back to your point though we don't
have data to support a lot of our things
right now any of these arguments so if I
have data and I'm the guy that has to be
in the middle of the back and forth I
can just be like look this isn't my
opinion this is the data so they might
hate that they might hate it but well
and that's and I tell you as we wrap up
that's ex probably why I formulated the
opinions that I have about this because
these are the things we have data about
right it's pretty good you can use these
synthetic surfaces uh pretty
consistently if you manage them they can
take more events than a natural grass
system maybe not by as much as people
think but there's some some data about
that there's data about heat right
there's uh there's data about the high
traction uh but that's it you know what
I mean I don't get into the cancer thing
I I I I I don't I don't get into the MCA
thing uh mean mer thing they sort of you
know most of the science refutes it but
there's some science that says there are
things that live in that thing now who
the hell knows when you got to put cork
or whatever stupid thing we're about to
put in there before we let you go one
more question have you as just a sports
turf guy uh from the old Kentucky days
with AJ Powell uh heard about the impact
microplastic uh issues in EU are going
to have on Synthetic Turf because maybe
our listeners are thinking about what
the next generation of synthetic turf's
going to be filled with if it's
infilled yeah I'm familiar I think it's
like second the the second largest
resource next to tires uh actual tires
in Europe they've identified as
microplastics or Synthetic Turf um I
don't I don't know to what degree though
I haven't I haven't read up on the
literature enough to not is it truly
impactful to you know humans or animals
or what not but it's it's something that
we're considering in the grant as well
too so I mean we're covering all aspects
okay all right all right Carl yeah y all
right Chase thanks for taking the time
really appreciate it yep thanks guys
Chase thanks everyone for for coming
today live and we'll see you guys next
Thursday 10 a thanks Chase take care see
you Carl Yep this has been a production
of Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu