this is a production of Cornell
University uh so next up are more
research briefs we are going to be
talking about weeds and then also the
farmer data lab so I'm going to be
introducing the next speakers first we
have Eric Youngerman and so Eric was
born and raised in the Rolling Hills of
the birkar Massachusetts okay western
Mass okay I'm assume everyone knows that
Eric Youngman joined the sustainable
cropping systems lab in uh 2022 where
he's a research support specialist and a
firste PhD student his work spans the
Northeast uh focusing on advancing
sustainable Pest and disease management
in organic cropping systems uh for the
past two years Eric has been invest
investigating the efficacy of inter
mowing for weed control in soybean and
dry bean he's particularly excited I am
too about its potential as a
supplemental uh strategy for managing
weeds in organic noil systems so he's
going to talk first I also just want to
take the opportunity to introduce the
next speaker as well there this is U
going to be done at the same time here
so Lou longchamps um earned his PhD at
Laval University working on sight
specific weed management he did his
postoral studies at Colorado State
University working on Precision nutrient
seed and Water Management as an
assistant professor of digital Agronomy
at Cornell University he explores the
potential of observational res research
and on Farm experimentation so Dr L
Champs is the current chair of the on
Farm experimentation community of the
international Society of precision
Agriculture and again he's going to be
talking about the farmer data lab right
after Eric so Eric take it
away okay cool wow that was a lot um
about me and Lou uh berkers did
everybody know that was in the
Massachusetts Matt did not so I'm just
pointing them out right now
I assumed everybody here would know that
okay so as Matt said I'm a a research
support specialist and first year
graduate student uh theable cropping
system PL I'm going to be highlighting
some of the work that I've been doing
with the inter Mower and also some of uh
the other students in L as well so um
I'm not going to go over the benefits of
cover cropping I don't think because we
already have our benefits of cover crop
based no till um but um primarily I I
guess we like it because uh it's great
for uh it's soil benefits um earlier
I've heard a lot of people asking about
uh what does it actually look like I
know we've seen some photos of roller
cing people also talk about uh I guess
do we roll or plant plant and roll in
our lab this works not here cool in our
lab we generally do it at the same
time um so we are rolling our our
material ride um and then we're we're
doing it all one path with a planter the
people in the back can't hear so you got
a s from
cool all right and so we really enjoyed
this system um to the point that our
Labs actually with with a lot of help of
people from in this room have developed
an organic noil planted soybean
production guide uh this guide is
available in the back for those of you
who are interested Matt's now standing
next to the pot um and although we've
highlighted a lot like benefits
of erosion control or soil Health um
what we haven't really talked about too
much is how effective these
are at weed
suppression so in this case we have
amazing weed suppression you essentially
see no weeds coming up through that M
layer does this always happen
though
no and so the question is are there
options available so we can
meet are are those options available I
don't like the stand mov voice are there
options available for us to maintain
that mul biomass layer
um without disturbing without disturbing
the
soil
so okay okay we
good excellent
so one option I think what a lot of
people do in this room typically which
it does involve some level of soil
disturbance this is high resid
cultivation
um how resid cultivation works it's kind
of great it works well especially it's
typically used for uh when we have too
many weeds and we go in at the end of
the season um I've heard that people
today talk about it um now one issue
though is you are disturbing that that
that mul layer you're also disturbing
your soil so this is kind of a funny
example because we don't really have
that many weeds here um but so you're
also ideally would be tearing up
those another option one that we are
especially excited about though is inoo
because down you can control your weeds
a mul system with literally no soil
disturbance yes you can point out oh
well what about oh it's also
really sweet video
too so we really like
this um there a couple other models out
there on the market but we've
collaborated with this group and what we
like about it is has 5 rotary
M um enable us to move pretty much
between anything that's 30in space and
we can adjust the cutting height from 26
in above the surface and you can use it
until you are are at risk of can
closure so we like this so much that a
few years back a graduate student of
ours who um have since moved on compar
the of M with two other management
options one the weed which VI was
talking about earlier as well as
increased seeding rate well this word
found this was in was that uh they
moment reduced we biomass by 60%
compared to the non-re control and there
was a increase by 14% in the
yield so this was pretty cool this was
quite
H but we want to know how does this
compare to more till based practices
like H res cultivated
um so we designed an experiment that's
the name of this the talk Ino is a
supplemental weed management tool in
organic soil to evaluate Intero weed
management and crop field in both F
based cultivation and organic sod where
not so I'm going be presenting our
results from the past three years for
three site years uh this all took place
up at M research New York some of you
might SE it if you came to our field
crop Bay um we had some pretty great
great soybeans out there um s was
planted at 185 pounds per acre sorry I
know I put three million of pure live
seeds per acre um and we developed
randomiz block design with five Tre roll
seral ride with no additional weed
management roll seral ride with intergro
mowing L with high residue cultivation
till witho and until with with inter
cultivation and the idea behind this
structure was we wanted to increase so
as we're going down we are increasing
soil disturbance so the goal here is how
can we manage our weeds by by with
minimal
disturbance so now just have a couple
pictures of each treatment so you're
like oh that's what it looked like so
roll with no additional weed management
pretty much we terminated our C at 70
approximately 75 in theses we just left
it and this you can see some gaps and
that has to do with some Ur
issues
damage for high resid cultivation um we
used a John
Deere Chris what was it 886 thank you
886 High residue cultivator
approximately 20 inle sweep you can see
on this side and we did it once per the
gr season
um we then also us our t r to treatments
um so occurrence happen twice per
growing season um it's kind of neat here
in this picture the top you can see um
pre Mowing and post mowing until you can
see quite reduction of the weeds within
the R zone and same on the bottom except
this is in our r Treat
and
thenation picture this John 900 standard
on the back um use finger weers as well
as standard inter cultivating I make UND
side and this occurred four
times so before I show the results I
want to emphasize a few things one is
that there was a lot of variation in the
biomass of the m three different
fields um quite a bit of variation with
actually enough I'll show you later but
well so we
with first so in the following so the
field that we had the most R biomass
which we anticipated or expected have
the greatest pressure or the least
pressure typically when we think about
what how much m is required you have a
standard gold which is about 8,000 kg
per
Hector pound per acre it's probably
about
9,000 about the same eight and half okay
so which field do you think
had the highest
am as as far as like
biom a
wish still kind of like really cool
because sometimes you can have a really
high M we biomass I didn't go over this
in the beginning I apologize but you can
also have really high SE density in your
weeds or sorry in your soil um and so
you can end up having really high
numbers we so that first picture that I
showed you really nice looking field
with no weat with field p and the second
but was still
eight and so another point to make is uh
with the result of show you we had
really low we weed pressure across site
years um and so uh it's hard to design
an
experiment just plant a ton of weeds um
and then Lo so there's some we
anticipate some of these results to be a
little bit more
uh
more we would expect more clearer
results with greater weeds
so here's the weed biomass this we
pulled across our site years on the
x-axis we have our R our treatments
going from least disturbance to greatest
disturbance and our we biomass
ACC um so the interesting thing about
these RH is primarily inter actually
increased come to that later
on and something else that I want to
highlight is how we actually sample
we um and this is just um you'll see
second um so typically when when most
researchers I
think s
Quant um we s our along the RO so the RO
be which have been removed these
pictures we
[Music]
that
report so the in row
mower uh as I pointed out earlier has a
22 in deck so right now when we're
including this we're kind of we're
including the we that not been touched
by
that
so quick
breakdown what we did in addition to uh
the the entire uh the half meter
quadrant is we divided also into two
inter row
zones combine those um so we're
excluding not make using the from
RS so when we do that we get something a
little bit different um and so now we
see inter
mowing is actually reducing it by 7%
when compared to our control we still
get really like hardly anything theyed
but it's quite
exciting
on there was no difference
between and that's okay interested hey
can we get these we out of here and once
you can figure out how to do that then
then we can really kind of start looking
at what we can do
to um
in conclusion in increase bi until to
the control we think that's because
primarily most of the weeds within that
area are going to
beeses but we essentially just causing
and grow and grow and grow so I would
not
necessarily in uh in
treatments
decrease compar to
the uh
[Music]
in
so can replace
cation effectiv effectively control
without
impacting so
quick at
this in organic noal
drivings um and what's interesting about
this is we also at how in can not only
uh control weeds but also can control
weed seat um and we noticed with the
late mowing so here no mowing early
mowing late Mowing and as dat mowing uh
and we notic that um the we seeds
reduced by up to 50% compared to the
Onre control so we're also removing
seeds which is pretty we don't have to
think about that but we're just focusing
on Le
control BL we also removing corn um and
so an organic Noto corn this is another
graduate student our Adam is in the
A and preliminary results from a large
experiment is demonstrated once again
that can remove biom we biomass the more
excitingly cor at least in this
experiment can also improve your use
[Music]
one question while we switch over to uh
Dr long so uh I should just say that
those were some really good soybean
yields that you were looking at earlier
right some high Bean yields those corn
yields that Eric was showing at the end
there those were quite low but those
were averaged over a bunch of treatments
some suboptimal treatments so um they
were lower than what we would like to
see here of course any question question
for Eric
Adam I'm curious about uh the ability of
the in
mower to Red reduce Che bang Che bang
can you talk a little bit more about
that we sure so in in the followup
experiment in our driving the idea is
that you're you're targeting weeds
before they are flowering and producing
seeds but to analyze that or to measure
that we put out pit traps that that
patch some mus we measured the
production of about s
ofine and so then we noce how many seeds
are being removed there's so many seeds
being added to the seed over here so
removing any biomass you would think
would be uh would be removing seeds but
actually
quantitated have Quan is
really
yeah the week continues to grow thepit
is going to REM SE again when when the
that's true yep yep um so one so I guess
one thing that be Target and try to
Target with the late mowing is do a
dominant assessment of what weeds are
out there so okay the most dominant weed
is going to be common raged you're going
to Target that common rag when it is
going into
flower yes there are cases where that
that common R can still grow back and
put off almost tiller put off little PES
but you're still reducing the number of
weeks by I don't think the exact ratio
by large number um yeah so I think it's
a NE option to explore and so just
prevent the production been going on and
trying to destroy them which is why B
project is so cool because it's going to
be preparing
all thank you Eric so Eric will be
around later you can talk with him about
in mowing
by farmer data
lab great you very much mat thank you
Christen for the
invitation yes it's my pleasure to be
here and I uh I see that this is a crowd
that is experimenting a lot conversation
we had and J and some of the the
discussion that happened today all come
forc me to see that this is this is this
is a great crowd for for for this topic
here um yeah so my background is PR and
agriculture um I've studied it over the
last maybe 20 years and and over those
those years I mean we developed ways to
capture the data organize the data and
look at uh and ways to interpret it to
to learn from the spatial variability
and all those layers of data and um
working with with
Farmers uh I kind of bought into the
idea of wondering what happen What would
happen if we put the the farmers
themselves in the driver seat and um use
all that technology to the service of
their own experimentation without
telling them what to do how to do and
what topic to experiment but just like
providing that that service and here in
this presentation that's what I will
explain try to to to show you what what
we are trying to do okay I want to start
here with a quote from the book The
Fifth Discipline from Peter and J it's a
little bit of a long text but from a
very young age we are taught to break
apart problems to fragment the world
this apparently makes complex tasks and
subjects more manageable but we pay an
enormous price um the idea here is that
if I have a research topic that I take
and I I isolate that very thing after
that when I try to put it together in
the big picture it's like trying to put
together a broken mirror it's never
going to look exactly like like the
entire thing see U so the idea here is
to try to see could we bring everything
together into a learning or organization
and another little piece here before I
start about the farmers that IAB is uh
there's a push here uh it's at the
bottom here of the the qu um sever 70
organizations are calling for Food
Systems approach so basically again
trying to sit down isolate thing but try
to see what happens if you think of it
as a system and uh going after or or
working directly with Farmers think
about it when you experiment something
it's something that will lead towards
the vision that you have for your farm
or something that makes sense this year
with your equipment the resources that
you have your soils so basically what
you try is an integration of all your
system rather than if I arrive comp my
life try to sell it to you then it's
there's just one chance out of many CH
that that it will fit in your operation
okay when we start thinking system in
Agronomy uh what I'm trying to do here
is to merge several disciplines okay the
first is obviously Agronomy because
we're looking for consistent
interpretation we need to understand how
things work to to know what we are
observing and understand it
but there is now data science that we
can use because everything that happens
generates a lot of data and if we are
able to capture that data now in our
conversation and exchange when we
discuss we have that data to increase a
certainty of of the conversation the
outcomes and what we observe and then
after that there is social science um
the idea here is to make sure that we
have an effective effective process
because if uh if we're not considering
the system as a whole considering the
humans that we are all uh the process
can be disconnected from reality okay
and at the center of this is on Farm
experimentation which is the the topic
that I'm working on in the in the
farmers that okay so why we decided to
focus on on Farm experimentation systems
approach it's real world we're working
with that from The Real World and we're
asking Farmers to change towards
sustainable agriculture well this is how
change happen you experiment with things
here and there and slowly you you uh you
progress towards your
vision okay so to support on Farm
experimentation what we are trying to do
is to say okay let's bring expertise
skills okay so we have students in the
lab that have skills and time to work on
the data
then we work with agronomist to be able
to uh to reach you where you are on the
ter on on the territory and then we have
researchers for in for instance last
year we did a project on Biologicals I'm
not a so microb biologist but at Cornell
I have access to all the best scientists
so I connected with so microbiologist
and you taught us like how to collect
the data how to transport it how to
process it and then when we get the
numbers how to interpret it you see
so this is a process that that is expert
enable so we have access to those
experts then after that I was talking
about prision we have all those tools
now we have uh tools on the web that
allows us to communicate easier then we
have a little bit of funding coming from
projects here and there that we can put
to the service of your experimentations
for instance we have a bunch of biomass
samples soil samples and then we have
equipment so we have a drone we have uh
things that we can provide and just fly
your field and learn more from the
experimentation that you are doing with
this we are hoping that it will help you
get validation so when you're trying
something you want to see if it works
then it will kind of increase a
certainty of your
experimentation also if we all work
together and we lift that data then we
can start learning from each other and
something that works on a farm that may
not have spread as fast now all of a
sudden we can share those Innovation and
find things that are
happening in the real world and not
necessarily just in in lasts basically
here what I'm trying to say is that I as
scientists we don't have the Monopoly of
innovation see so I'm very good at
quantifying stuff but I'm not better
than you to invent something new BBE
then after that we're hoping that this
way we can accelerate change because if
we capture and we uh increase the
learning potential of everything that
you're doing on your farm then we learn
faster so then we progress faster
B and then uh the idea here is to try to
say can we scale the speed and the
learning process rather than finding a
solution and try to scale that solution
see so what we are after is really the
way you learn and the way you uh you
progress towards your vision okay so in
the next few slides I was I will show
you how what we were doing to to go
towards like building that farmers that
okay the first thing we did is just get
our f w we just went and selected the
topic um that a lot of farmers were
experimenting with and then we just went
with it and work with with Farmers so in
this campaign here we covered 24
um so we were trying to do two things
okay the first thing was are we able to
get a conclusion for each site and each
year okay if as a scientist this is I've
never been after something like that
what I would do is that I would repeat
it in two three sites over two three
years and then get the conclusions but
here if I want to create value for the
farmers I don't want to ask you to
repeat whatever you do for three years I
want to be able to uh come to some
interpretation within one year because I
know that you guys how you work is that
whatever you learn this year you use it
to iterate for the following year and
you iterate like this until it works and
not necessarily repeating the same thing
over time okay so there's a there's a
little bit of adaptation from my side to
be able to to meet you with your meet
your
expectations okay so that's the first
thing we're trying to do to try to
conclude in one year okay so uh to do
this we consult with Farmers with people
in the network and with experts to uh to
identify um to better learn the process
of what we are doing because if we are
not using a replicated control trial
like we would do on a research Farm then
we need to rely on something else to
increase a certainty and what this is is
a agronomic logic we can call it this
way so the idea here is to say if I do
this I expect to have more yeld so now
we need to kind of backtrack and think
okay what would make this generate more
y so in this project here we that our
told was on biological so we said okay
you put those bacteries in the
soil then there will be something in
between before you you see more you
first will it survive so we went and
collected samples to see if um the
organiz organisms lived in the soil it
didn't live that means that it was
obviously not doing anything so if it
lives okay good first step we pass the
first step then we went and measured the
change the nitrogen status of the plant
and if there we didn't see any
difference like maybe it didn't do much
if it did then after that it's worth
looking at yes then it translated into
yield so now you see instead of relying
on an experimental design to draw our
conclusions
we do a little bit of a more detective
approach trying to put the the piece of
the puzzle together until we get a
conclusion okay um so this is the first
thing the other thing and I'm not going
into this but when we are working as a
network and we get data from all those
Farms all of a sudden we can start
seeing patterns and things so for
instance here uh my student did a an
analysis use using AI that allows to
identify Farms where it worked Farm
where it didn't work and now you look at
all those data that we collected for
each farm and then see what was the
driver to for the Farms where it worked
or didn't work you see so now we start
quickly understanding what are the
drivers and that allows to inform for
following iteration of your
experimentation maybe what could the
what are the success factors or the the
factor that could decrease your chances
okay okay then after that um we're
working on tools to make it easier EX
for the first iteration everything was
on paper and that was a mess that we had
to go back and forth trying to
understand and when we started talking
about rotations and trying to record all
the rotations for all those 24 sides
that was really a mess so now we are
trying to build tools that will make the
exchange a little bit easier okay so
here this is an experiment card and that
kind of takes you towards a path of
thinking your your experimental like a
scientific process so we believe that
this would be your hypothesis then to
verify that we will that will be like
what will you do in your field right
side by side and I will change the
nitrogen rate or I will put a biological
I will do this I do that then after that
and measure what will you measure what
will be the metric that you use to
interpret your your result and then we
are right if that's for you to start
thinking when I get those numbers how
will I interpret it to see it worked or
it didn't work and that will kind of
help you draw conclusions on your your
experiment but once we have access to
this so we have an online form that you
can f once we see this then that's kind
of the start of the conversation now we
can ask you will you need biomass sample
s so sample will you need to have a
contract uh applicator contract deal
mapping and things like that okay so so
that then we can engage after that we're
working on different web tool to uh to
find ways to to when we have all that
information to allow you to have access
to your data as well and to uh to
interact with your experimentation a
little bit more easier than if it's on
several different places this just
bringing everything
together um okay then we are working on
a survey so some of you may see this
it's going on right now um trying to see
what is the state of un Farm
experimentation there is one survey that
exists that was run in Australia on this
and 90% of farmers are experimenting and
actually I would think that it would
should be about the same
here then after that we're developing
the farmers that so they uh the the
website I me so here we are just
bringing all resources have a little bit
of material for you to learn but also to
to engage with us and that's becomes
like a platform where we can
communicate and uh I am also working on
the global unarm experimentation network
uh because there's Community around the
world in Australia UK South America
friends that are engaged in this process
and working on developing it and uh and
we're creating like a network of who is
who is doing what where to learn from
each other
basically okay the last slide here is
just to inform you that we have a new
project that is funded by the New York
corn and soybean Association grow
Association this means for adjusting
nitrogen rates in corn after cover crops
so if you are experiment thing with
nitrogen rates and corn after a covered
crop that qualifies you to to to work
with us on this one and basically we we
got some funding and we make all that
funding available for just to support
your your experimentation in terms of we
will visit your field collect samples
process samples and organize all that so
uh that's what I had and I just wanted
to uh to show to to talk to you about
the farmers that all we have a boot that
back there if you want to grab a card or
discuss it later thank you very
much this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu