this is a production of Cornell
University welcome to the show uh we
have a really interesting conversation
today about something that's literally
taken you know no commercial people want
to admit it but commercial people make
up less than 15% of all the money spent
uh in the turf grass industry you're
talking about homeowners uh and maybe
they're spending it on Commercial
Services for a little bit more but the
Home Lawn Market drives the majority of
how we value the turf grass industry so
we're going to talk a little bit uh
about Home Lawn stuff today but we have
some guests like I usually like to talk
about Mike fed danza's dog uh a pre a
previous guest on the show is doing well
sitting on the chair and here's Ralphie
and Leo from the Chicago district office
associations Derek settle uh who goes
out on Field tours with these two
Knuckleheads and then another passing
Ryan Gordon at T at the the the the uh
corset Snow kwami Ridge up in Seattle he
posted about a dog his doggy lost this
is again uh just connecting I just love
this dog thing uh that we've got going
and also po pet population has gone up
about 20 to 25% which is a big part of
the long conversation so let me do the
weather Carl quick and then I'm going to
set you guys up and get out of the way
uh things are warming up quick uh we
have really seen a rapid push uh in
warm-up so if you're making sprays for
uh root pathogens like fairy ring or
drenches for summer patch uh you're
going to be making those applications
relatively quickly in the New York
metropolitan area uh and all the way up
to Hudson Valley and even stretching
into here into Central New York um it
was a dry week last week and in fact I
think we had the first period of time uh
our our climatologist told us that we
were drying more than we had rainfall
for maybe the first time this season and
you can see the rainfall percentages are
uh generally 100% or more of normal with
a few dry patches smattered throughout
the region Cape Cod uh you know right
around New York City uh where you're
just a little bit short of normal just
for the month of April which has just
gotten
started what generally this means is
growth is unabated you know what they
sometimes say is listen if your grass
doesn't look good this time of year
maybe you should find another line of
work uh because it's pretty good easy to
grow grass in fact it grows you know you
can't stop it I think Carl you mentioned
you know you could mow multiple times in
a week I mow a mow an area for my wife
out at the house I mowed it on Sunday
and it needed to be mowed uh yesterday
uh on Wednesday so we know growth is
crazy uh but at the same time our little
poll Ator risk tool Carl is really
starting to show up what we're seeing uh
across uh the state with regard to
dandelion flowering right this is Sarah
this is a tool that Carl's developed
that's looking at dandelion and clover
blooming in the lawn to try to help
those people who might be making
applications to their lawns uh to maybe
recognize that there's risk and
potential pollinators vising it so we
are with Dr Sarah stria Sarah will uh is
the Outreach coordinator
from the G turf grass Institute one of
the great turf grass programs in the
world for many years um and that's
widely respected throughout the world
and of course is the source of
information in Canada and Sarah has been
very outspoken I love this there you
know we talked about this on my other
podcast I think you you guys have done
just a great job in getting out out into
the media and being uh thoughtful about
this I think your most recent uh
communication efforts uh on on Twitter
uh with lawn science and just trying to
teach people about how Lawns work what's
going on there citing the science uh
about these things I just you know this
is exactly you know we don't want to be
defensive even though we're like yeah I
don't think this is a good idea but at
the same time you know you want to sort
of embrace the idea that we're thinking
about lawns differently Carl and as I
get you in here you sent around this in
naturalist conversation
about uh this whole no thing happening
among Eco people and I can tell you
they're much more polite than the
general public in social media so big
shout out to in naturalist Forum
contributors it's the first time I've
ever heard
bashing so so look at this oh yeah this
you can't fix Lawns it no m is a
Band-Aid when Lawns need a tourniquet
this is just be watching I just love
this Carl so there you go brother yeah
so I think uh before we get Sarah in
here just sort of setting up the Noom
conversation right Frank so it's May 2nd
and I'll show some data here in a bit on
Google searches and how people start
searching for no now instead of in April
which is a little bit weird uh but
basically the idea is relatively new I I
didn't realize it was so new uh I guess
2019 over over in Britain uh UK
organization plant life started
promoting it uh as a way to promote uh
pollin in the lawn so basically the idea
is you treat your lawn like a lawn every
single month of the year except for
Maine which you just let it grow and the
idea is that there will be flowering
plants that will grow up uh as you don't
mow and that can be a pollinator sort of
foraging resource uh for them early in
the season especially when there's not a
whole lot around um if you look through
some literature this is the thing that
sort of pops up when you search it uh a
paper at of Appleton Wisconsin and they
said that hey we found no M Lawns
relative to traditional Lawns have high
higher pollinator richness and abundance
so the idea was uh they sort of survey
pollinators and oh wow we got more in
the no may maon this sort of supports
the idea that it it's good for
pollinators and then you started to see
certain municipalities uh Appleton
Wisconsin some places in Minnesota
around here Frank we're starting to hear
chatter especially when it comes to code
of of cities and towns where normally
you're supposed to keep vegetation lawn
type vegetation under 8 in and they're
saying ah we'll make an exemption for no
M because it's good for pollinators uh
the problem with that is that uh that
paper was retracted a couple years ago
uh and an entomologist entomologist
detailed sort of a lot of reasons why
the paper had some inconsistencies first
of all how they were identifying bees uh
by sight and not with a microscope which
you would need to identify the certain
uh species of bees and also that they
were reporting bees that just didn't
exist in Wisconsin during May and then
there's some other landscape context
things uh reasons why that the paper
probably wasn't so good uh and it turns
out when you look at some different
papers that haven't been
retracted you actually see these these
sort of bee abundances how many bees are
going on the lawn uh when you can cut
the lawn every two weeks even in may you
have more bees than a 3-week mowing
interval um and some there's some
evidence there that hey you know you
sort of got to cut the grass uh so that
it doesn't sort of shade out the the
dandelion uh flowers or the Clover
flowers so the bees can actually see
them and actually s ask he's got a
graduate student Frank who's looking at
UV light sort of how pollinators see and
if you have a Malon which has really
long grass that basically obscures the
the ability for the bees to see those
those foraging resources so hey maybe
that's actually preventing them from
getting uh to the flowers right and this
is just some some evidence from some
some pictures from my community where I
see a couple Nomo maons and it really
just doesn't go well at the end of it
right so the end you got to cut that
grass down right that's the idea of in
June and July you're going to treat it
like a a lawn and that seems to have
some bad consequences that I've seen
handling that vegetative material right
where do you put all th those clippings
which have nitrogen and phosphorus in
them how do you dispose of those off the
lawn um some damage to to long-term Turf
quality we'll ask Sarah actually you've
got some research there from a no M plot
last year you can maybe share with us uh
and then this idea of the other animals
that sort of inhabit that long
vegetation throughout May if you've got
some some small mammals some snakes and
then you sort of cut all that down they
were setting up shop all spring and then
you just shock in one shock uh event
disrupted that entire habitat so maybe
that's not such a good thing we're
focused on pollinators that might not be
good so this is a perfect time to talk
about no uh when I look at Google Trends
The Last Five Years in New York uh no
you see that first spike in
20121 uh more interest in 2022 and even
more interest last year we'll see what
we do this year uh but interesting to me
Frank that that the the surges peak in
the second week of May which if I were
going to imp imp no M I'd probably want
to know before May 1 that I was going to
do it not sort of like yeah well we're
two weeks into May should i m my lawn oh
maybe I don't need to M La so this
starts to to bring in some questions you
know who are we dealing with who is who
are I guess the audience of of n m uh
and this is what what Sarah's work and
everybody at at G turf turf craft
Institute has some really good resources
now note to moay this is a website uh
you guys have set up a lot of cool yeah
good visuals so good sort of snippet
posters you can send people to to get
some just really basic information on
what's good for pollinators is the stuff
in lawns good for pollinators how should
I treat my lawn if I want that and then
really good communication of the
literature too so you have these papers
and you sort of bring out the notes that
are key for people to know a really good
way to communicate sort of the primary
source literature to uh average people
who are going to start uh maybe
implementing this so that starts to get
us to our questions right Frank and I
think the first question Sarah is uh who
is the audience right we always as
extension people start with like you
know who are we trying to communicate
with I guess in in um your sort of
experience with people who are looking
at noo is there a general profile of of
people who want to do this or groups who
who want to adopt this
practice yeah um you've got a lot of
background on this and I totally totally
support this before I get in this I did
when you pulled up the paper um about
the Del Toro paper with the the Beast
they are going to republish it they did
do some restudies so there there is a
paper that has been pre-published and
it's uh available online now and so they
basically redid it but not only was the
issue that they were identifying bees
incorrectly they were comparing no mo
Lawns to moded Parks which are totally
different environments mode Lawns well
even mode Lawns are going to have more
pollinators than a park because there's
generally flowers around alwn right so
anyways that's that's one little caveat
but um what I'm finding with no is it's
it's mostly homeowners and it's people
who want to do good things and probably
the spike in that two we part is because
that they're seeing other people who
have put the Nomo signs out and so
they're on their smartphones on the
walking their dog be like what does this
mean actually um and some people get
really really upset about it there's
actually a paper in the Wall Street
Journal that people were citing each
other's neighbors and calling in and and
people get really really upset because
you said that you're making your
neighborhood look messy or bringing out
of property value or or or whatever so
it's generally homeowners but uh because
there has been this big
um virality of it on social media and
such um and then last year I think also
we were talking to a lot of news media
Outlets that also could have contributed
a bit to the spike um so that has
developed policies in certain
municipalities they've had to set a rule
on it and once the municipality sets a
rule then people are going to start to
Google it but it it's homeowners really
and really it's people who want to do a
good thing right they're not they're
just misinformed wait wait Sarah wait
Sarah we talk about people arguing in
virality that's normal business in New
York state so um um I asked a question
this morning of somebody ask it of you
can you separate out people trying to do
good from people who just hate
Lawns yeah no I I people who hate Lawns
hate them because they want to see more
biodiversity I think anyone you stop on
the street and ask them is biodiversity
a good thing they'll agree with you
right because that's that's what we've
all been taught right but the people who
hate Lawns they're
um not really understanding the
functional space that it is and that's
part of the website that I have that's
lawn science that also talks about what
are the functions of Lawns and the it's
it would be lovely in a world that we
could just say yeah everybody's lawn can
convert to a wildf flower
Meadow but then don't call me when your
cat goes missing because now you have
coyotes yeah
right like there are there are Pest
Control elements like yes there are
studies that uh fleas are not fleas and
ticks are not really that much more in
Long Grass unless you live next to
forests okay so if you live next to
forests you're going to have more fleas
and ticks and also if we're building
multiple neighborhood corridors of
everyone doing long grass then that's
going to create more larger animals like
deer and deer carry ticks and then
you're going to have ticks right so like
the studies that exist that say oh no
long grass doesn't actually carry ticks
they're small studies right they're
small plot studies and they cannot be
applied to how like it's common sense to
say you're going to find more ticks and
Long Grass the G turf grass Institute
actually just we moved um only about 500
met half a kilometer and our old
location we stopped mowing it for uh 4
months and if you walked in there with
white pants you'd come out with black
pants cuz how much tick you ticks you
had and there's no Forest there right
so anyways um there's also a home uh a
town in Ontario that they had a really
great initiative and it's a good
feel-good movement where they said that
they were going to completely naturalize
I think it was like 20% of the land mass
of their public parks they just said
they're going to naturalize them 12
months no cut well now this year they
had to add $3,000 back into their budget
to mow those all down because they have
rats yeah right um so it's it's tough
well we can agree a good idea yeah we we
can agree rats and snakes and coyotes
don't belong in lawn's Carl but what
about
pollinators right and and and so that's
the next question I think Sarah you're
bringing up a lot of good uh sort of
risks of no M and it's it's often build
as this is great for pollinators and
that's one potential function or
ecosystem service of Lawns uh but
there's other things that Lawns are good
for and it's not just Recreation it's
not just Aesthetics but things like uh
storm water controls soil erosion right
uh air temperature reduction and if
you're going to do maybe there's some
health and safety risks and just talking
to some extension folks this morning uh
uh downstate in New York they were
saying that can be something that moves
people off of n when you talk about
ticks when you talk about snakes or uh
mice that can get near foundations then
it all of a sudden is O you know is it
worth me having pollinators in the lawn
for that and I guess the next question
is does this really you know should we
be promoting pollinators in The Lawns
are there things like dandelion or
Clover or self-heal I guess how good are
those for pollinators and is it worth
sort of sacrificing some of our other
functions or ecosystem Services of the
lawn to get those uh
foraging um sort of Edibles for for
pollinators in the lawn
yeah well and you know we talk about the
obvious pests of the the rats and the
Snak and stuff what about bees bee
stings there are people who are
literally deathly allergic to bees so I
don't know if you were to go back 30
years and say oh how much I love bees
people would look at you like what
because it was the you know before the
popularization of the EpiPen um right so
I personally don't want bees in my
backyard because I like to play with my
dog and walk barefoot in my grass so no
thank you I don't want bees there but
pollinators are not just bees either
there are in bees alone there's over
there's hundreds of species of bees then
there's also moths and birds and uh
flies right so if you're going to say
you're going to support all of these
hundreds possibly thousands of
pollinator species that exist with one
flower a dandelion which is a not native
and B not a very good nutrition source
that doesn't seem right to me right it's
it's the Band-Aid when you need a
tourniquet you don't need Dan Alliance
you need uh Apple species you need the
uh flowering dogwoods you need the
Magnolia you need the willow species you
need all of these things like if I were
to have a a let's say a wedding and I'm
having aund 100 people over I'm not just
going to put out one bowl of
chips right I'm going to put out a
buffet because I know that not everybody
is going to like my favorite flavor of
dill pickle chips some people won't eat
it some people will be allergic right
now we're now we're somewhere else
listen listen here's something that I
hear often um and it was reiterated in
the ey naturalist thing Sarah I know you
guys have been playing around with this
and and I think maybe even measuring
pollinators correct me if I'm wrong
there but one of the things I hear is
when people want to help pollinators
they buy plants in the spring and then
they help the poll ators in the summer
and the fall or they buy plants in the
summer and they help them in the fall or
they buy them in the fall and maybe
maybe they'll come up in the spring but
T come up in the fall is the lawn from
your perspective actually potentially
useful for early spring visitors early
spring natives Specialists and would you
say that it's probably best to delay
mowing rather than to to necessar if you
mow as as the study showed relax it a
little bit but these spring ephemerals
I'm wondering it it can serve a real
purpose but it's sort of misaligned in
timing at least in my mind and it seems
like it's become something mostly
because of the alliteration you know
like you know mo No Shave November or
you know I think it took off on men not
shaving in November and men are lawn
people and so now it's no more may
because they don't shave in November and
they don't want to cut their grass in
May it could be a rebellion of the
entire male species who know Sarah but
can you talk a little bit about early
spring
stuff yeah absolutely so in my
neighborhood at least the crocuses have
already come and gone so I I strongly
believe at least in my ecosystem and I
cannot say a bled statement through
across all of North America plant
crocuses in your lawn to provide early
spring pollen because I I don't know
when the crocuses will pop in your
neighborhood versus my neighborhood but
for Ontario Southern Ontario
specifically you can incorporate
crocuses um or
um snow drops into a lawn and they will
flower and complete their entire life
cycle before you even need to mow and
that's usually in April um there you can
also incorporate uh white clover uh and
seed that intercede that white clover
actually works pretty well with lawn
grasses and can be mowed and the more
you mow it the smaller the plants can
get but they're not actually really
spring flowers they're actually late
summer flowers um so you could have
crocuses for the spring and clover for
later um and the other things that uh
you mentioned self heal and you can also
incorporate wild strawberry a lot of
these different species they can uh be
incorporated into a lawn you might have
to raise the height of cut and maybe cut
less frequently and also note that
you'll have to change your use habits of
that space as well because they're not
going to be as traffic tolerant right
you're not going to see crocuses and
self-heal and um Clover surviving very
well in let's say a commonly used soccer
field right we just don't see those we
see dandelions because they are able to
handle high traffic and compacted soils
right so yes you can incorporate and
then call that like your belon so I
would say I could do that to my front
lawn and then I'll leave my back lawn as
grass so that I can still enjoy that
with my dog and and my kids right yeah
so so what do you think Sarah of those
be mixes I know Minnesota a couple years
ago I I think uh had a mix there and it
has the things like white white clover
or self heel have you tried those out
and and that seems to me like you know
at least in myON a lot of people's lawn
they have high traffic areas or high
visibility areas and then peripheral
areas and if and if I can just take area
maybe plant some of those mixes maybe I
mow it once a month or something yeah
that's that's a a great idea right and
and so I guess have you seen the
efficacy of those mixes do they perform
well um and is that the alternative that
that people should be looking at as
opposed to just letting their lawn grow
in May and choing it back down yeah we
haven't seen any studies I haven't done
any studies on it but I've seen just
colloquially in my own neighborhood I've
seen a bunch of people have uh High
success with these things but in general
it I I would think that some of these
Lawns you just need to pay a little bit
more attention to them it's not as sort
of automatic like I'll cut my grass when
I want to you know whatever it's it's
you know lawn maintenance is in my
opinion the easiest least work for a
homeowner right whereas a beix you're
probably going to have to reced that
multiple times because Flowers and
flowering plants just generally don't
really like to be cut even if they're
mowing tolerant like you're going to
have to come back uh every 3 years or
something and and add some more seed
back into that uh you're going to have
to be cognizant of like you said hight
trffic areas the the it's not going to
be completely flower Meadow in the
backyard if you have a pathway that
you're going back and forth to your shed
that's not going to have flowers in it
right so just understanding um and
modifying your expectations of your
belong
it's not going to perform the same way
as a grass lawn and you're probably
going to have to be a little bit
more aware of the growth rates because
if you do let the the like even
microclover we have a plot back here and
we didn't mow it the microc Clover
turned into macroc Clover if you don't
mow it and then if you mow that down uh
it still applies to the oneir rule right
it's going to be really shocking to that
plant and even more so than a grass so
you you have to can just put it on a
calendar and say oh I'm just going to
mow every three weeks or something well
if you have like you saw showed in the
the beginning of this that extreme flush
of growth you're going to have to be
mowing it every week for that month
right just in general the whole no M May
and the hashtag and the cuteness we as
Turf managers and you talk to any farmer
also you can't do anything on a calendar
because this the weather changes year to
year climate is changing and also
ecosystems are totally different I could
do no mo may in Northern Ontario where
the polar bears live
yeah right I could do no mo all summer
or maybe in Britain maybe that's why it
worked in the UK right you know maybe
they have a cooler May and for us maybe
shifting like you said the Shifting the
timing Frank hey no mo April like I my
first Mo this year in in itha New York
was April 28th right so I could probably
I can get away and just by the nature of
how the Grass Grows with without mowing
in April so Sarah you you mentioned a
couple Alternatives here we're talking
about the beon okay maybe that's an
alternative but it's not quite as
minimal no mo M no maintenance as as we
might think um but you mentioned earlier
just planting other trees and shrubs in
the landscape is that the best way are
those the uh I guess the most nutritious
sources for pollinators early in the
year is that sort of the best way to
give them resources uh maybe Beyond you
know looking in the lawn for those
resources yeah I well it's essentially
don't do a popup shop for four weeks
plan for the entire growing season uh if
you can think of uh or visit your local
nursery and say what flowers in May what
flowers in June July August and plan for
that if you only have a small space just
even a hanging basket A Flower Basket
hanging off of your porch That's
providing pollen resources that would
otherwise not be there you can start
small even in my backyard I actually
started a little naturalized area where
I built a little fence and it's about 2
m squared that my dog won't go into and
I'm not going to mow it I'm not going to
cut it I throw a random packet of wild
flower seeds at it once in a while and I
don't manage that at all because
actually removing Garden resid residues
like those Hollow stems that come out of
like sunflowers and stuff those are
valuable nesting materials for bees and
sometimes the our best intentions are
saying yeah let's provide pollinator
support we don't also provide pollinator
habitat I like to say that the number
one hit to the carpenter bee was the
invention of the gas furnace because we
no longer have wood piles right so the
carpenter bee likes to live in Wood
piles so even just having three or four
logs in your backyard that you just
leave alone that's an amazing habitat
for snakes and pollinators and you could
just leave that in that space make sure
that it's an area that is safe from your
kids and your pets and everything else
yeah and you're supporting biodiversity
right start small yeah and Carl you got
love this show one week we're talking
about killing grass with with salts uh
you know and now we're talking about
snakes and rats and carpenter bees
because the the Landscapes that we
manage are are enormously complex and
one of the things Sarah that they
involve and you've touched on it a few
times and made the comment and I just
want to reiterate it and get more
thoughts on it when when you decide to
have something that's going to look at
your lawn as a different function than
traditional which is mostly you're
looking at it and you run around your
pets and your kids and you have lawn
parties and you walk on it and you know
it's all those things so once you make
the decision to help you know and use
this ecosystem service enhanced
pollinators you lose some of the
cultural stuff because you can't use
that space for the things you used to
use it for and I'm not even talking
about health reasons no one wants to
walk through 8 inch uh grass you're not
having a garden party with everybody
standing around in knee high grass so
when we're talking about importing these
trying to create some native or some
habitat or viewing these things
differently in the urban environment
ultimately it's going to change the way
you're going to be able to use that area
now when you've played around with this
a little bit you've mentioned a bunch of
plants there are plenty of plants that
will be low growing that you could mow
at three inches or four and 4 in have a
lawn that you can walk on and do
everything else on but also has these
you know incidental flowering plants as
we like to call them so talk a little
bit more about when when people talk to
you about this you actually say I'm sure
you say to them listen you can't have a
garden party in this thing uh when you
stop mowing it and make it a belon yeah
I the whole backyard wedding industry
will shut down if everybody has a beon
right I it Lawns have functions right
you said backyard barbecues social
events
even just me being able to hang my
laundry in the backyard I need to be
able to walk on the grass to be able to
pin my laundry to my line right so
understanding that maybe when you drive
past my lawn and I'm not physically out
there that on that moment it looks like
my lawn is a useless space but actually
it is doing a lot of functions even when
no one's physically walking on it right
it's holding that soil down it's uh
allowing water to percolate back down in
to refill our ground uh aquafers which
our our drinking system they act as a
natural filtration system and you know
what people don't think about this often
but it's also temporary parking
sometimes I know most people in the
winter will park on their lawns we have
it all the time here when we have field
days we park on the grass right there's
so many functions that you don't think
of and if I had a garden this entire
backyard I wouldn't be able to do those
things when I want to use them even if
I'm not using them all the time grass is
sort of the holding holding space for
future events right and the simplest and
easiest your point about being simple
and easy uh is well taken and Carl do we
have a question because we're at the uh
fastest 30 minute hour here we're we're
right at the end um just just a couple I
think Concepts uh Rich was talking about
uh bees and and pesticide use and how
that interacts with flowers and and I
think Frank what we're sort of starting
starting to think about and and maybe
promote is the idea that if you're going
to have pollinators in your lawn if
you're going to have some incidental
flowering plants that Clover the cell
fuels you probably shouldn't apply
insecticide applications we we would say
in one of the bmps is to mow flowers off
uh before you make those applications
and we're finding with Clover you can
run that mower over at two and a half
inches Hayden box data up in Geneva
there's still 50% of clover flowers that
didn't get cut right so oh and dandelion
flowers duck too y I've seen them go
they they duck back up yeah like they're
an inch and a half off the ground right
so so sort of uh you know aligning your
your pesticide use your IPM strategies
with the functions of the lawn I think
is one of the the big keys we're taking
away from today so Sarah thanks for
joining us Carl great job on this and
everybody appreciate you joining us for
the fastest 30 minutes in Turf um we'll
see you here oh one programming note we
will not be here next Thursday at 10: am
eastern time because my last kid is
graduating college so I will beat
standing there in tears as I'm enjoying
of happiness with the last tuition bill
I paid so for all of you Sarah thanks
for taking the time Carl take it easy
we'll talk to you guys again thanks
everybody thanks a bunch there
appreciate
it this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu