this is a production of Cornell
University I actually thought this was
really cool from a sort of I see people
investing a lot of money uh in dealing
with algae uh and and and weed
management vegetation management which
sort of starts with algal developments
in many ways right shading things out
and lot causing other issues um so the
use of barley straw is pretty common now
uh I know this was pioneered man many
years ago rockas swad did this work in
his younger years uh in Nebraska it
looks like when the water temperature
gets to about 55 degrees uh you put this
barley straw right at the inlet uh there
are chemicals that are eluded from the
straw I honestly haven't looked at the
science of this at all but I do know it
is pretty widely used and you know when
you consider what's involved in putting
one of those you know for lack of a
better term wedding venue fountains in
the mid middle of a golf course it more
guys are going to the bubblers that are
a little uh better I know there's lots
of solutions but this is a pretty simple
one that even gets used at a Swanky
place like Jim's got there at Fairview
Carl always thinking about fun things
around golf courses uh uh and really
love this sign I got to play a couple of
weeks ago and and I gotta tell you when
you play in a scramble and you're a
lousy golfer it gives you all these
feelings because you don't have to sweat
your crappy shots in fact as soon as you
hit a crappy shot you're happy to
support the other crappy golfer you're
playing with who might on the off chance
hit a good shot and I think when you
approach around a golf like that you
know I think it tends to be uh just a
little bit more fun and I and I think
we've talked about in previous episodes
uh the fun coming out of golf but I just
had this real uh thing about dogs and
wet dogs and dogs that are out in the
rain right so you know people want to
know why their cars smell like wet sappy
dogs I'm sure you know what this is Carl
and also uh Tim gra out in Iowa you know
everybody's in for rain and I want to go
out and I give you that look like what
are we doing here get me out of this
place and dogs have a way of
communicating those uh feelings just by
their looks so Carl you had something to
say about something I mentioned uh last
week on the show uh I actually thought
is pretty cool so why don't you take us
through this Urban nutrient management
stuff we've worked on yeah so wanted to
talk a little bit about backstory uh of
how this document came to be and and
sort of continue on from some of our
thoughts last week which is about you
know we talked about uh fertilization
soil test mlsn and and then we we
mentioned this Urban nutrient management
plan which sort of codifies some best
practices around um how we we use that
fertilizer uh and really what it comes
back to is is not so much turf grass
quality but water quality uh and that a
lot of these documents and best banag
practices are connected to to reducing
the amount of nutrients and sediment
that's getting into the water and
causing issues so uh one of the guests
this week we were trying to get was Mike
goatley and and I you know I read one of
his papers he was involved in which
talks about the history of of turf grass
nutrient management as it pertains uh to
the Chesapeake Bay Watershed and how the
regulatory environment has shaped um
sort of how we use turf grass
fertilizers in this Watershed uh and
this comes back to water quality right
so the the picture that people can see
on the screen
uh from this Watershed which is really
big stretches across Six States uh you
can see a lot of red on that image red
means there's not a lot of oxygen in the
water and that's because these nutrients
are are basically powering organisms
that are sucking up all the oxygen and
there's nothing left for the the plants
and animal life that are needed to
thrive in those situations so we know
that that nutrients are concern here how
do we fix this right what can we do uh
the sort of standard approach from an
environmental engineering perspective is
to V A A tmdl some folks may have heard
this before it stands for total maximum
daily load and and it's essentially a
process that um you go through to to
clean up water so first okay you
identify a problem and then you got to
figure out okay how much you how many
pollutants are getting into this water
body how do we quantify the amount of
nitrogen or phosphorus or sediment
that's getting in there and we need to
do a lot of assuming and we need to run
this through a bunch of models right
there's a lot of land in this this
watershed there's a there's a lot of
equations that go into that uh but they
try and make their best estimate then
they got to figure out okay how much do
we have to reduce that pollutant load so
that we get clean water um so they
develop those targets that's the tmdl
sort of targets actual numbers we have
to hit uh and then we got to figure out
ways to hit those best management
practices so that's where these sort of
plans come in hopefully you do that and
eventually the water gets clean so the
numbers for Chesapeake Bay Watershed are
are this uh 84.3 million kilog of
nitrogen we don't want any more than
that per year uh 5.7 million kilog of
phosphorus uh and 2.9 billion kilograms
of sediment so we don't want to exceed
those levels um and then we got to hit
those targets by 2025 so those are like
really big numbers again sort of
abstract like where do we get those and
that comes back to this modeling
component where there's a lot of
assumptions right we've got a
contributing we've got turf grass right
that's we're going to talk about there's
natural sort of secretion of of
nutrients that just sort of get out of
the water uh and one of the assumptions
we learned a couple years ago in a call
Frank with some folks in the New York
State DEC was that they assume every
piece of of turf grass in this Watershed
is
fertilized uh and we were sort of like
oh boy that's that's a red flag right
that's probably not a good assumption uh
and it was too late for us to sort of
change that assumption in the model but
we did sort of look up some numbers and
you know how much do do homeowners
fertilize maybe that's a good proxy
seems like 40 to 60% there's not great
data on that it probably is regional
it's probably breaking down by rural
suburban Urban there's probably
different amounts fertilizer fertilizer
uh going on there but but the bottom
line is that Assumption of 100% is is
wrong right that's not good um but
there's there's a famous quote from a
British statistician uh George box uh
and it says all models are wrong uh but
some are useful right so for us in turf
grass we get really defensive and and
you know part of those assumptions being
100% of turf is fertilized lead to hey
we got to do a lot of these best
practices to reduce our fertilizer and a
lot of times there's a regulatory aspect
to that you know we have phosphorus laws
across all these states there's uh
nitrogen sort of caps in some states um
but I think what it's accomplished is is
probably still pretty useful and part of
the accomplishment is codifying these
best management practices right uh there
is an expert Turf panel in the chesap
bay and they come up with these 10 core
uh practices that if if we do these
things we can you know estimate that we
reduce nitrogen leaking out of tur Turf
systems phosphorus leaking out uh and
the first one is how we came into
developing this Urban nutrient
management plan and it says basically
develop an urban nutrient management
plan for the property based on a soil
test and that's why we talk about mlsn
last week we talk about you know we
should probably use less fertilizer uh
having that plan codifying that uh helps
reduce the the excess fertilizer now two
of the other ones I think are really
important have nothing to do with
fertilizer but they sort of have
everything to do with what Turf does uh
in in sort of our Landscapes and how it
pertains to water quality uh the second
one is maintain a dense vegetation cover
of turf grass that reduces erosion uh it
reduces runoff and retains nutrients so
that is saying you know there's a reason
we have a lot of grass uh and it's
because it slows the water down or let's
slow that water down reduce errosion and
the turf grass is good at using
nutrients let's let all the nutrients
that are in that water seep into the
grass and the grass can use them and and
it takes it out of the water uh the
other thing uh that they mentioned one
of the bmps is make sure that your soil
in in turf grass systems has good
paracity and infiltration right so
that's sort of a reason if you have
compacted areas Especial where waterers
sort of on a steep slope it's going
really fast again we want that water to
go in and not across uh and again that
reduces our pollutant loads into the
into the chest Bay and these are good
things this is why we have grass and why
we have a lot of grass is because it
functions in these environments so part
of the bmps is like make sure you have
all grass and not bare area so that's a
good thing from from a turf management
perspective so so Carl listen and let's
let's go through a couple of things
right because each one of these things
uh has its own story to it let's start
out with soil testing right um we've
actually been as you mentioned last week
uh not necessarily support of soil
testing uh if it's interpreted in a way
we think is not consistent in fact we
even made the Asian turf grass programs
uh shout out this week from Micah Woods
uh commenting on our conversation uh
from last week that you that you led
right so so it isn't that you're soil
testing right that's not really the
issue it's the way you're interpreting
the numbers that you're getting and the
way you're calibrating those soil
nutrients to your observations and the
and your Turf performance in a
measurable way could be growth could be
disease resistance it could be traffic
tolerance whatever whatever that is okay
so that's the first thing the second
thing I want to say is I remember
driving by the golf course with the sort
of this environmental engineer was
visiting us one time and and you know we
just driving like we always do out to
from the campus which is very Urban out
to the turf plots and where the golf
course is and which is very you know
Suburban on the edge of suburban and
Rural uh and and first thing the
engineer says man it's so great this is
like a sponge for all this water you
know I don't know he actually says I
don't know why anybody gives golf
courses a hard time they're like perfect
for the storm water management needs so
some of it is Carl we don't always look
at things the way other people look at
them and what that's what you just
demonstrated in your point there the
engineers well it's grass it must be
fertilized in some ways now we do know
back to this point when you got a lot of
organic matter
and you got active soil life you are
releasing nutrients right but
theoretically one would hope that
wouldn't exceed what a plant and a
system could take up in a rizosphere but
there are times when just organic matter
levels build up and can leak and and
there could be just natural releases of
nitrogen now the last Point here I
actually got a picture uh to talk about
things we don't think about where I'm
going to talk about sports Fields a
little bit today Carl we the
intersection of these ecosystem services
and the functional use of this landscape
is very dramatic on these Sports fields
and I'll just ask you again to remind me
you read a paper or uh talked to us
about a paper that showed uh compacted
Sports fields are getting on the radar
of storm water management Engineers to
your Chesapeake pay point now this isn't
a chemical property car we're talking
about so physical properties which is
what your last core management thing was
there
uh can you talk a little bit about you
know what we mean when we say compacted
surface obviously there's no grass here
so that's not good but also the
compacted soils on these fields create
uh runoff problems as well yeah so uh
you know we talk a little bit about the
modeling that goes into figuring out
okay what pollutant loads getting into
the water um there was a thesis at a
temple and and they do a lot of
monitoring of okay when we have a rain
event how much water comes off of this
land and this Watershed and how fast
does it come off and you can do some
calculations based on the land use so if
you have a sports field that's sort of a
natural you know lawn turf grass
environment that's different from uh you
know a developed housing area that has a
lot of impermeable surface it's
different from a forest and they have
some estimates on how much water should
come off so they do those estimates and
then they're collecting data on how much
water is actually coming off and they're
like hm there's more water coming off
than we thought and it's coming off
faster than we thought and you know why
is it what assumptions are we getting
wrong and what they're sort of pointing
to is like know there's all these
athletic fields and we're assuming an
infiltration rate of X and it's coming
off faster than that and so what they're
figuring out is that if these these uh
athletic fields are compacted that that
water's not going in like it's supposed
to be and it's overloading there's
there's there's more water than they are
expecting coming off of this Watershed
and that affects how they design green
infrastructure water control structures
at the at the the outlet point so uh
they were sort of pointing to like hm
like that's maybe something we have to
consider either changing in our model or
it would be great if we manage these
Sports fields to have a certain amount
of infiltration and collect that water
like we think it should yeah all right
well since we're talking about the soil
let's start with soil temperature which
was surprisingly warm uh in the New York
metropolitan area well into the 60s
almost everywhere except the highest
elevations are pushing into the upper
50s but you've got temperatures well
into the 70s uh in the metropolitan New
York work area and this is a a pretty
big deal because you're now in the
throws of active growth active soil life
you want to make sure you've got your uh
summer patch sprays down your your soil
pathogen sprays uh because obviously the
infection period for these organisms is
well underway um it's been warmer right
uh the early part of last week uh before
it got cool most recently it was in the
40s today here in Upstate New York uh
but I can tell you uh War overall last
week uh a little more uh well above
normal last week uh and the interesting
thing is and this is I think and also a
very interesting point of discussion
Carl because this was like the second
week where I've observed some drying in
my eye tests of traveling around uh the
area right uh and when you look at
precipitation minus uh you know evapo
transpiration you see again the sort of
localized nature of precipitation
and again when we're talking about
runoff we got pockets of three and four
Ines of rain being dumped in some of
these areas in Scranton along the cape
uh on the North End Northshore of Long
Island you know into the Hudson Valley
and then not 10 miles 20 miles away
you're at a inch or two inch deficit
right and so it looks like the drying is
going to
continue uh now uh looking at the lawn
water model Carl the the model is
picking up the drying that's occurring
it picked up the rain that went through
this is for Long Island uh this is uh
for the farming Dale location so Sandy
areas now still have plenty of water
don't need to irrigate uh we're
definitely I think uh honing in on the
drying the growth estimates are also
showing that growth is pretty active
particularly when you're not irrigating
so in some of these locations you better
check these things because these
localized models are going to end
indicate whether growth is going to be
higher or or below normal but this is
where it gets funny to me Carl we talked
about this earlier the foler models have
been very active much earlier I think
even even art mentioned this morning the
brown patch model was flaring up soils
are drying but the foliage is wet right
and you look at sort of where we are
today and where we're going to be by the
end of the week would you spray Carl
where where would you if you're at the
end of a spray would you spray or would
you hold tell me where you where where
what you're thinking you got dry soils
you know you've got to maybe add some
water talk to me a little bit about
management decisions with your water
model your growth model and your disease
models all integrated together they're
all wrong right they're all wrong right
but they're all useful yeah I I think uh
the one thing with the dollar spot
models and we we talked about this a bit
last week is it spiked up uh and it
should be coming down now so if you were
to run the prediction on that to like
June 2 or something I think more of the
region is going to be in green uh we're
going to have these cool nights right so
from that perspective I think uh I would
hold off again and this is the the
perspective of like you know I'm a
course that has you know let's say five
I've accounted for five fungicide sprays
on my Fairways for the year and I
probably had to go out two weeks ago
when it sort of spiked up there and it
got really hot and humid so I've got
four left and I've got June July August
and we know the fall pressure has been
getting that's what I'm talking about we
we've been saving right we've been
saving these applications in the spring
because the whole thing shifted to the
fall yep so so I would save and the nice
part is that that growth potential is
going up we're getting into sort of
Ideal temperatures if you have the
ability to irrigate right and you have
soil moisture and it's not limiting
growth uh even if I got a little bit I
would expect uh the the turf to grow out
of it so if I'm thinking large areas
Fairways and I've got limited sprays I'm
I'm definitely holding off and I'm even
looking at the Smith Kerns model and
it's interesting it's very low the next
couple days because it doesn't look at
the leaf wetness like we rely on Leaf
wetness which considers ah did it rain a
little bit is there a lot of relative
humidity the Smith curs is only relative
humidity um so if I look at both of
those models and I sort of s centralize
the recommendations I'd say yeah I I I
would definitely hold off on Fairways if
if I had a limited amount yeah okay now
listen my phone's been ringing off the
hook about natural and Synthetic Turf
and one of the things that keeps coming
up is there's not transparency uh
between the governance and stewardship
of sports Fields Carl and you know we're
going to be talking about this a lot
over the next few years we just got a
grant to do some work in this area in
school grounds and I want to use the
example of some of the things we've
learned here at Cornell uh has a way of
uh helping people in the grounds area
the sports turf area especially uh and
maybe golf guys will have something to
learn here as well is how to
operationalize uh or or add some data to
their technical operation um this is a
story that started with me serving on a
governance board uh for our athletic
department I've been the chair I just
finished up my 17th year as the chair of
the faculty advisory committee and I am
now retired from this committee it has
been a long and and Story Journey that
included the renovation of the swim test
here at Cornell which fell under the
opes of this one of the things I was
responsible for doing every few years
was to give a presentation to the
faculty and one of the things the
faculty Senate was very interested in
listen the Cornell faculty Senate is the
largest collection of nerds in the world
it's it it's somewhere between a
nerdfest and the Roman senate you know
where we love to hear ourselves
pontificate so every once in a while
they invite a knucklehead like me to
come in and it and I always get a lot of
questions about concussion so I come
prepared to discuss our concussion
Management program let's face it you're
at a university your your brain is the
most active muscle in your body uh by
far at this place than every any other
muscle but our athletes have to be very
mindful of concussions right and this is
something that the NCAA has been all
over obviously this is something that
Sports in general has to pay attention
to and we have a collection of data that
over the years I've been presenting
looking at the various Sports you know
this is from 2013 through 2018 you can
see football in general is very high
men's ice hockey in some years could
have as much as football women's ice
hockey uh still gets a fair amount
lacrosse another sport we're fairly good
at can be above uh average many years
and even wrestling another sport we're
pretty darn good at trying to get all
those well-fed Western Pennsylvania boys
here here uh wrestling around so uh
obviously this is a significant concern
for governance right Carl when we talk
about governance versus stewardship and
of course the governance includes
playing the game different you know
maybe you're not going to have kickoffs
in high school anymore you know these
things that happen at the high levels
maybe impact us at a lower level but I
can tell you the game changed for us
here at Cornell when we hired the
assistant coach for the national
champion Stanford Soccer football soccer
team a number of years ago coach Smith
here he gets here he gets hired he walks
out on the natural grass field for the
first time and he says we can't play
soccer here I can't kick a ball in a
straight line and that led to uh
Investments of a fair amount of money uh
to get uh the fields up to shape and
what it did also is it thrust myself and
Carl and at the time my graduate student
Chris sitco who's now the director of
this whole operation with thrust us into
having to manage this work with the
coaches work with the the people that
were managing these fields work with the
players work with the maintenance staff
and they were all a bunch of disparate
groups that there was no centralized
Focus for the way this field was tended
to now the first thing that jumped out
at me and Carl you you probably heard me
say this is there's two kinds of coaches
when you're thinking about just
governance from a coaches perspective
you got two kinds of coaches you got a
coach who can say I want the ball to do
this I want to here's a a good picture
of a athlete deflecting the ball to the
side and then maybe advancing it and
there's that little bit of friction that
occurs there that some coaches will say
really I want it to behave this way
right good all right then we go figure
out how to do it then you got these
coaches oh you need to M lower you need
to roll more you need why don't you core
this field wait a minute stay in your
lane budddy you're the co coach we're
the grounds people I had to realize whoa
now I know why I'm an academic and why I
have so much respect for guys like Ben
Palmer and all you know Nicole Sherry
Dan Cunningham all these guys that are
managing fields on a regular basis
dealing with coaches so we became as you
might expected Carl you know very data
driven like if we're gonna if the coach
is going to tell us what he wants we're
going to have to use numbers in one way
shape or form to know how to make
adjustments in our maintenance program
that then results in measurable
differences in these devices be they for
hardness moisture traction ball roll
ball
bounce so we have two uh we have two uh
setups for our soccer fields our Burman
field was built in 1995 it's a beautiful
Sandy uh so uh engineered sand with
compost and soil in it it's about two
acres it was resided to Kentucky
Bluegrass in 2016 and is now being
renovated into a Ry grass surface
because the other operation that the
students uh practice on is an off-campus
location where they've got two practice
bills both for men and for women and
some training ground in between uh that
are primarily Ry grass annual Bluegrass
surfaces so one of the Testaments one of
the things that we've been able to do is
to use this data to make these two
different playing surfaces play the same
but the annual blue BL grass uh problem
has become so severe on the Burman field
uh that we've not been able to combat it
so we're going to be shifting more of it
over to Ry grass so one of the things I
want to say about this in general is I
believe cool seas and natural grass
fields are done best when there's a
Bluegrass base that provides you that
that stability for a cleat to dig in and
then whatever the hell you want to grow
on top of it if you want to intensely
seed Ry grass if you want to put more
tall Fescue on it I don't really care I
worry a little bit more with t Fescue
that it can get Bunch type but as you
heard from Cal Bigalow a couple of weeks
ago we can actually do T Fescue pretty
low well when we started this operation
with them it wasn't looking good we were
having all kinds of problems with
irrigation we started top dressing we
needed to raise the sprinkler heads we
had a lot of infrastructural things so
the first thing I'm going to tell
anybody if they're talking to me about
natural versus synthetic is do you know
what you're doing do you have an
infrastructure that can actually support
the goals that you're trying to achieve
and so what we did and Carl I believe
you and Chris LED this effort years ago
is we basically said okay the people
we're talking to only understand numbers
yes they only they don't understand
anything about biology they probably
weren't that interested in engineering
but they might be interested they're
very much interested in the numbers so
you guys did a great job saying saying
okay how much do we do this for this for
that the other thing we started to look
at the various fields and the amount of
time we were spending on them with
floating time and this is where we learn
the concept of wrench time right car how
much time people spend actually doing
the job so we give them reports on hey
here's what we did so if you're in a
school district if you're at a
municipality just track your hours what
does it take you to do these things and
then start beginning to communicate
these things in a way that say here's
what this takes here's the over seating
that we had to do here's the weeklong
practices where we dominated by mowing
maybe we did another 13-week period
where we did more top dressing uh out
there right again just putting in the
hours over a 13-week period we started
to talk to them and give them reports
about the data that we were finding and
the things that mattered we started to
get them to use covers in the hight
trffic area is where they'd see results
so we had been able to create an
environment over the last well
essentially seven years till then we
hired Chris sitco back to run the whole
operation where we you know had a
methodically work through the governance
and different parties involved here and
then even when you do that Carl the NC
the senior day comes along and you're
calling me on a Saturday it's like Frank
they got senior day what would they're
calling me me that they don't know what
to do we didn't have a real plan in
place right for what to do we didn't
have a person really that oversaw it so
they were calling us and we said I don't
know get out there and test it we tested
it and said don't play on that field the
darn thing is frozen even when you take
the snow off they took the snow off and
played anyway so even when you give them
the data sometimes they're going to do
what they're going to do here's where
I'd wrap this up Carl I think any
operation that manages Sports Fields
golf courses or grounds should have
established protocols for the way they
go about their business right it
shouldn't be centered in just what a
superintendent knows or a foreman knows
or the people who work there for 15
years knows there should be things
written down to say this is how we
operate this place and then we have to
use that as a way of communicating our
needs externally right we keep following
up with people we hire good people and
you treat them right I me that's pretty
much what it comes down to when we talk
to people about natural versus synthetic
right we know that there are competing
priorities right they're competing
priorities for use how safe it is the
environmental costs the money and the
sociology which is there are egos
associated with getting certain kinds of
surfaces in communities there's the way
you fund these things is it a capital
expense or is it an ongoing expense
right a capital expense like a athetic
field you don't have to worry about
maintaining it so to speak and versus a
natural grass fields which is going to
have ongoing expenses which includes
maintenance differences that you can
learn more about at our Sports field
website here's the QR code for that and
you can go to our safe Sports field
website and get some information and
this will be renovated as part of our uh
granting program and also the best
management practices that are available
from a variety of States I know the New
England guys did really wonderful job
with this and so Carl that seems to be
it for me it'll just be me and you are
there any questions that came up or
comments you want to make um so we don't
have any questions but I think the
comment Frank is is uh you know when
you're trying to affect change of that
governance structure and tell them hey
we need x amount of people for X number
of labor hours we need this equipment or
remember we we talked about mowers and
replacing mower blades and it took you
right uh professor in in the College of
agon light it took a graduate student at
the time Chris and then me so three
people I didn't know I'm not sure I
entirely knew what I was doing but two
people who knew what they were doing and
me who was trying to put all the Excel
stuff together uh to really communicate
those needs over several years uh to
start to see that change and then uh
finally now Chris taking over and having
that sort of Baseline being able to
continuously communicate those now we're
going to have an inter you know an
undergrad student who's going to go out
and take this playability you know a
couple times a week to again sort of you
know figure out when when coach Smith
says hey I don't like how the dividing
it is or I don't like how the ball's
reacting we can have numbers that say oh
that's when we see the sheer test look
like this or the firmness test look like
this it's it's it's tough for one person
to affect all that change so in the past
I've said you got to hire somebody and
they need to know what they're doing but
that person also needs support in
communicating those numbers and
collecting some data um so it's just not
as simp simple as a k through2 District
hiring a person who knows what they're
doing they need to empower them to have
other people and train other people
around them and be able to communicate
and work with the governance structure
to say listen uh we can't meet your
expectations with this uh I need other
people to support me and that's how
we're gonna ultimately and yeah and just
to review Carl in 30 minutes we did
Urban nutrient management and soil
management right then we did dollar spot
and digital tool modeling how to use
those models to make decisions and then
we talked about managing Sports fields
in an operational way to get sort of uh
be able to sort of know what you're
doing and then communicate it to other
people around the various surfaces that
we manage I can't imagine you're gonna
get more in 30 minutes anywhere
else uh and one quick question Vitas was
asking about uh the data from shear and
compaction tools is that sort of a good
way to um get a holistic uh sort of look
at the performance I think so right I
mean I think firmness is is sort of
number one I would go to and then that
traction component is the next one I'd
go to any comments from you Frank on
additional tools or if those are sort of
what you would start with I I think the
ones we use there are pretty good but I
think you have to realize this they're
all indirect measurements of things yeah
right they're not direct measurements of
things that's why it is important to
calibrate them whatever device you're
using the reason I think used them there
there's already a data set that a lot of
different sporting organizations have
provided feedback on and I know Fe FIFA
is really you know uh elucidated these
things uh to to no end so there really
isn't any end to it but I'd say those
are two good places to start because
number one you don't want these kids
cracking their heads open when they hit
their head on the ground so I if they
crack their heads open banging into each
other that's a different animal but it's
not uh something that you definitely
want them doing and traction is
something it's good to know if the
turf's going to slip out from them which
is bad uh and also that the turf is too
stiff for them which is also bad so
there's that sweet spot in there I'd say
those are the two best ones if I added
anything I would probably add the ball
uh the ball roll and the ball bounce uh
because that also tends to be something
that the the uh players and coaches can
really associate their performance with
yeah so yeah that'll that'll wrap it us
for wrap it up for us today yeah a lot
of lot of ground covered today lot
ground Carl ground cover Turf there's a
covered the pitch as the Europeans would
say we fully covered the pitch covered
the pitch so thank you all for for those
attending live uh you guys will see us
next week uh with Ben mcgr take
care this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu