this is a production of Cornell
University it was uh it was 22 years ago
this week we held the first US Open at
uh Beth Page black and I had the
pleasure of being on the crew as a much
younger man uh back then but of course
this was during the the height of the
Tiger Woods uh you know period of
dominance that you know Scotty Sheffer
may be uh uh going through so you start
him out young uh Ashley B Binky Binkley
is a golf course uh superintendent in
Canada and has these two love one lovely
kid who she's been showing on Twitter
forever and you know you just love
seeing this walking out there and of
course on a sad note there were a lot of
passings I you know I think for those of
us again that have dogs uh losing them
is really hard and I think it's great
that people share uh these things
especially for men who sometimes have a
tough time uh expressing emotions around
these things animals seemed to be a
place where uh men have figured out how
to at least express some emotions and
all of us that have dogs know that and
so Carl I'm going to take the weather
for a little bit and I'm going to set
you up for us to transition to Rich uh
uh so just a little bit about the
weather as we normally do soil's cool
right as we've seen a cooling pattern on
the weather we're also seeing some
cooling happening uh in the soils right
it was really pushing warm and really
the only places that are warm left are
down where riches and along the Metro
New York area uh along the coast oh let
me see sorry about that um and of course
that represents how much it was cooler
than normal last week uh we've been on a
warming Trend over in general and but
cooler than normal means it's been
cooler than we'd expect it to be over
the last 30 years particularly Inland
warmer to the north and a little bit
more to the South now this is allowing
us to still be ahead uh of last year and
I think for people that go year to year
uh seeing how far we are ahead of last
year um but also recognizing we're right
around normal most of the region based
on the 30-year average is normal and I
think climate change makes these things
a little bit more difficult to really
interpret and get a feel for right
because as as we've been warming so
significantly over the last two decades
you know what's normal is not as easy to
understand as maybe it used to be it's
very interesting we had our conference
call this morning and we had people
talking about how dry it was and then
all of a sudden boom we had people
talking about how wet it was uh and I
think uh you know what you see is
there's widespread drying if you drew a
line from Pittsburgh to Boston you'd see
in a couple hundred mile radi uh
diameter of that width of that you'd see
a really big dry Trend the last week but
other places almost everybody else got
about about an inch of rain so there was
a real split in in the moisture across
the region now Carl here's something I
want to talk to you about this is uh a
lomy soil uh this is the lawn watering
tool this is a lomy soil uh down in the
Metro New York area over over the last
month right so I think I put the pin in
Central Park or something like that
right so I'm looking at this thing and I
got a normal native soil like Zack Hol
would have at Central Park right so I'm
looking at this thing and my first
thought is I'm not sure I would have
watered once in the last month because
while I did have you know let me get the
pencil here for those watching us I did
have three days where I was in some
severe as we're defining it now stress
another day where it touched it maybe a
couple days we're in it couple of days
more I'm in it but what I've noticed
Carl is I'm always coming out of it
right I'm not really persistent in a way
and it looks like I'm going to come out
of it again uh this coming week now
moisture is the conversation as we reach
the summer solstice right when the soil
when the sun is highest in the sky and
we get the most ET when you're looking
at this are you seeing what I'm seeing
that maybe I wouldn't have irrigated my
lawn in the last month yeah I think I
agree with you Frank I haven't seen the
visible stress like that may be
indicated on on this model and part of
that is the model is based on these m
maximum allowable deficits so basically
you know you have your Field capacity
and then if you drop that down 70% in
theory that's when we might expect some
stress um but I think our model early in
the season doesn't is probably over
predicting that stress like uh we had a
nice amount of moisture this whole
spring like like you've said on our
conference call this morning man it's
it's felt wet right and maybe part of
that is the the root depth is really
deep too so we have we have our rooting
depth from the spring rooting uh so Our
Roots can access a larger column of
water and when we get into this you know
quote unquote severe plant stress phase
in the model hey maybe our Our Roots are
actually deeper than this model is is
estimating so we're not actually seeing
stress when we predict it now if we pick
up this this hot and dry spell that
we're going to have move it into late
August or September when we've lost
rooting depth that's when I think we'll
start to see this severe stress actually
play out versus
yeah and because you know the soil
moisture thing is the fascinating part
and it's not just soil moisture but it's
soil where that where that rooting is
okay so this is good to know because on
the model if you go to the website
you'll actually see if you were setting
it and forgetting it starting in May 1
you would have put a fair amount of
water down already four inches or so in
the last month and and really not needed
it and that's the kind of thing I think
we're trying to drive here with this
model now as as Carl mentioned and we
know the Heat is going to be building
this is the 18th so you can see it's
coming uh across the uh region uh next
week this is where we have high
temperatures that persist and high
humidity that persists in the evening
now soon as you start talking about high
temperature and high humidity uh Carl
we're talking about diseases but it
looks like brown patch in particular is
confined to the southern end uh of the
region now I know you've got a rant
about this uh with regard to pesticide
use and this will be a perfect setup for
our Our Guest today go ahead Carl yeah
so so one of the thing when I first
started working you with you Frank I'd
go to these conferences and I wanted to
learn about how we apply pesticides you
know disease life cycles and I was in a
seminar at the gcsaa show and um Bruce
Clark was going through all the cultural
practices for you know dollar spot
prevention or a brown patch or
anthracnose and spends a lot of time on
the cultural practices the irrigation
the
fertility and uh there were no questions
from the group and then finally at the
end where we get to chemical control ho
baby the chem the the questions come
flooding in and I was marking them down
like oh my God there's 20 questions on
chemicals and none on the cultural
control um and just I think that sort of
uh mentality is what people end up sort
of getting into in the turf industry and
and it makes sense right we need
pesticides Frank you you studied this at
Beth Page black when we manag golf
courses this is a picture of I think the
the blue or the green course here but we
need pesticides in some uh quantity to
manage golf courses that's just how it
is in in at least in in Long Island the
amount of pesticides we need that
changes based on our expectations right
and when we did some work with the guys
at Wisconsin that was the main question
was what drives overall pesticide use on
golf courses is it the soils is it the
turf grass varieties is it the growing
conditions and what we found was it's
the budget and in effect it's the
expectations when you expect more at a
golf course when your members $50,000 to
get initiated into that golf course they
are going to expect a blemish free golf
course and you will use more pesticides
so when you spend more you spray more
that's the governor of pesticide use and
specifically when we look at the parts
of the golf course that that make up so
the majority of that pesticide use it's
the large areas it's the fairways large
scale rough applications that will
really drive that overall total and it's
interesting when we look at pesticide
records from a mom and pop course the
greens are not a whole lot different
from some of the those high-end places
but they don't spray the fairways and a
high-end Place sprays the fairways 10
times or 12 times and that's really what
shoots up uh those pesticide numbers now
when we zoomed out we got pesticide
records from different areas of the
country we expected different sort of
levels of pesticide use and when you
look at Texas or Florida or the Midwest
compared to us up here in the Northeast
man pesticide use wasn't that different
across the United States and we expected
more from the climates right hey maybe
different climates different
temperatures different growing season
lengths would change pesticide use in
the US it's about the same uh but when
we got records from other countries
courses in Denmark or Norway or the UK
wow they use a lot less pesticides and
that's probably not because of climate
it's probably because of the regulatory
climate right they have access to way
fewer pesticides we're talking easily in
order of magnitude fewer pesticides and
that restricts their ability to apply
them and you and Ben talked on the show
last week about some of the regulations
here in New York the birds and bees Bill
uh and and Neo Nick band and yeah I
think our turf industry gets really sort
of defensive about those and and last
week you guys talked really well about
the science behind hey maybe in Turf
neoni aren't that bad but in seedco
treatments yeah there is there is a high
risk to pollinators and it's tough when
the science isn't sort of leading the
the legislative approach um but but
often we'll get defensive whether the
science is leading or not and you know
the Spider-Man meme you're pointing uh
our industry likes to point the fingers
at hey hey we're doing good what about
that one over there uh and so we've
looked at this a little bit you know the
a will you know we'll point to a a will
point to golf courses as excessive users
uh and we looked at some pesticide
records as part of that research a
couple years ago and man golf course
turf is is about uh equal with with
great production in terms of our
pesticide use uh apples see we see more
pesticide use in and apple orchards and
potatoes holy smokes paint it white
sleep at night we talk about that they
use chlorthal a bunch in in potato
production so we we can do some of that
but I think what I come back to is is
one of my mentors and Frank you spent a
lot of time with her Jennifer Grant
would really always just look inward
right and instead of pointing the finger
at other people really asking the
question she'd be very direct with
superintendent why do you do that do you
need that like why did you spray that
thing uh and if someone couldn't explain
themselves she like well what the heck
right why why did you do that if you
can't explain why you did it do you
really need that uh and I think this is
a good question to ask and I ask this
all the time of myself is you know do I
need to be doing this and if I can come
up with a good reason and I can
rationalize it when we talk about and
you guys will talk about Disease Control
probably here in a bit um you need to
sort of be able to diagnose the disease
maybe you send it to Rich and Rich says
yes you have X Y and Z you need to treat
this hey I need that but when you can't
really sort of rationalize that and
that's the great part about Chen and her
IPM background was was if you can't
rationalize it why why are you wasting
your time on it and was that time and
and and money better spent on on
something else well here yeah and I
think Carl this is really the perfect
transition to the conversation when we
talk about why because this just you
know everybody learns this in some form
of pathology that you have a pathogen a
susceptible host and all your waiting
for is the suitable environment unless
you know you expect something to blow in
like a cutworm an army worm or or a gray
leaf spot that blows in maybe it it's
waiting for the host too but in general
you're you're waiting for the conducive
environment and of course we talked
about this Carl as you said in the past
and Rich you were involved in this
research many years ago when we were
using your records and other diagnostic
records to just determine when are
samples coming in what kinds of Trends
are we seeing what does our model say uh
this was back in early days you know we
were again much younger men so we've
seen a shift in in seasonal things uh
for sure but just to bring you in Rich I
don't know everybody knows you're a
biker riding you're how many miles
thousand 10,000 miles a year how many
are you doing now a year uh yeah about
around 10,000 a year um and that's I'm
down now I'm old I need a little more
rest yeah
and of course you just attended the the
dead at the sphere which I know you're
you know you're avidly enjoying live
music but at the same time I notic is
also when you were a younger man you're
you're you're well uh supported by
Sabrina in the Diagnostic lab so big
shout out to all the diagnostic people
and here's our questions for today Rich
all right we've been to working together
a really long time right and I'm sort of
curious about the trends over the last
20 years and you you know uh you are
dependent on samples coming in so people
understand that and of course you know
your institution uh Murphy and and Clark
did that anthracnose work many years ago
and I'm sure you know you are getting a
lot more samples before they identified
you got to put a little bit more
nitrogen you got to watch your growth
Regulators you got to sand a little bit
do you get as many an anthros samples
how much have your Diagnostics changed
based on some of the research that's
been done to maybe help guys identify
things themselves a little bit better
let's talk about that well that's a
great it's a great question and anthros
is an excellent example of how uh uh
research can solve problems you know uh
uh we used to I guess it was
2001 um the number of anthros samples
that I would get was about 36 % of the
Total Turf
samples and you know it was
somewhere around 200 a year um last
season um we got 14 anthract no samples
you know so so it pretty it pretty much
wrecked the business for us as
diagnosticians because if you follow the
guidelines you know and it was a decade
or so of of research by a whole bunch of
really good Pathologists yeah um
uh it eliminates the the risk for that
particular disease and and we just don't
get the samples now okay okay so
research uh undermines your business
model which I think is a good uh point
to remember um but I'm also interested
maybe in what you see uh with the
superintendents that do submit samples
or that you speak with because you're on
the road chatting a fair amount and you
know Carl and I and you've been involved
in our forecast models here at Cornell
we we as Carl have said they're all
wrong but they're useful I'm wondering
how much you see about that and also how
much how much is there more spraying
going on than there used to be uh and is
that related to different products or is
it related to being a little bit more
averse to risk uh you know like what
we've talked about recently that how
people have decided they need to spray
preventatively eight times for pythium
root rot uh what kind of Behavioral
changes have you seen among super
tenants over the last bunch of years
well that that's a great question and uh
a lot of times I think that those of us
in this side of the business are more
like psychiatrists or psychologists than
uh
Pathologists um you know uh guys
depending on where they are and we talk
about the higher end and bigger budgets
mean more sprays are still spraying
quite a bit you know I remember in the
uh uh the Heyday of anthros that many
superintendant would spray on four or
five day intervals even you know not
knowing they needed to fertilize and
that would have solved their problem um
but but it's not uncommon to
see um weekly fungicide treatments on
greens and teas today um and and and it
it's interesting I don't think they
spray more um but the risk aversion is
higher you know moving from the high end
to the lowend even the mid-range and
lower end guys um are getting pressure
for higher quality grass so they spray
more and and and then you know to kind
of roll this in too there's a lot more
chemistry there's a lot of chemicals now
you know it's remarkable really what
I've seen come to Market in the last 30
years that we didn't have when I started
and and they're and they may be softer
and not as persistent and that might be
why we're spraying
weekly yeah maybe I but I still think
you know if you're spraying on 14 days
that's pretty darn good coverage you
know so you don't need a fungicide that
that knocks the crap out of a fungus you
know for maybe 21 or 28 days before it
recovers its growth you don't need to
spray it every seven days so even the
most risk averse person at 14 days is
still covering really well all right so
let's let's stay on the uh pythium root
rot thing because this has really been
in my craw and I know I I banter with
Carl all the time about this and I think
it's come up recently is there a thought
among Pathologists that maybe we
shouldn't be spraying for pythium root r
i mean listen let's let's make sure
everybody understands what we're talking
about when you have saturated root zones
and you have stress Turf to begin with
cut low you know you know a lot of
traffic um you get these wet conditions
uh it doesn't even have to be hot I
don't think right Rich you'll get
pythium root rod in those anerobic
conditions right yeah yeah and temp
temperature doesn't matter at all I mean
going back to Eric Nelson you know in in
1990 you know he was talking about
pathogenicity at 40 degrees you know and
causing root infections with some of the
same pathogens that cause iium blight on
the foliage you know at 80 degrees so so
uh you know super saturated soils poor
internal drainage extra rain all that
creates a condition for this or these
organisms because they're algae you know
they're not really true fungi but uh you
know I don't think everybody needs to be
spraying I think I think you need to be
fixing your drainage or your irrigation
protocol or you know something like that
I think you're going to get more Bang
from your buck from from that then
starting to spray at 50 degrees or 55
degrees and spraying all
season but you're seeing it more and
more we we yeah we see we see uh uh a
more preventive pythium root rot
applications and I think you know down
south you know uh North Carolina South
Carolina you know maybe there's more
call for it um and and some of the
programs that come out of the Southern
researchers um might work well down
there but may be excessive up here okay
okay so so I don't I I I'm gonna go I'm
gonna uh go a little bit further with
this um they are more risk averse uh
they seem every even at the mid and low
level they're expect everybody's
expecting higher quality conditions
right so they're having to spray more um
I'm
wondering just my sarc fastic view as
you know from working with me a long
time I was very surprised with the rash
of nematode concerns we had years ago
that seemed to be well timed with the
release of new nematicides from two big
chemical companies I thought that was a
very interesting correlation causation
uh situation going on and I'm wondering
about the the regular visits that our
distributor reps make to our clientele
uh maybe saying boy you should probably
get that uh pythium root Rod I'm not
suggesting impropriety but I'm
suggesting more is it you're thought
maybe superintendant are barged a little
bit with these things uh that might be a
concern and that drives their use a
little bit um yes yes
I I uh uh um be careful now because yeah
I know joh might be two people listening
I don't want to throw anybody under the
bus but uh yeah they're there's a lot
there's a lot of that look there's two
there's two things I see you know new
product and uh uh uh uh you know the the
marketing push for the new products
right um the other thing is
superintendant who are so busy with
multiple
tasks you know Personnel problems greens
Comm you know um basically saying to the
sales reps just sell me what you think I
need you know and and that way they
don't have to really think about it in
the way we would want them to from an
IPM you know from from Jennifer Grant's
standpoint you know uh uh and so so they
get into
program programs that may have been
worked out by a research scientist that
are picked up by the companies and they
might not need any of it you know
and okay all right so so so we'll end
this part with being thought F right and
as we're more thoughtful um there
appears to be some new things on the
horizon um what is this new pathogen
from uh John uad at Yukon that I know
you're talking about that you've been me
talking about and also this morning you
commented as you hang out with molecular
biologists like Ming ye your new uh turf
grass pathologist who replaced Dr Clark
uh they're sort of throwing a wrench in
the whole pathogen ID thing we so do we
really know what we thought we know or
we don't know what we don't know well
um yeah it's it's become more confusing
because you know now with with the
ability to to sequence the the genes of
these organisms were starting to see
differences you know and and so uh it
was just to start with a new pathogen uh
that John's looking at um and that's new
I can't even we can't name it John
suggest a name and mingi did some work
with the same pathogen and they said
that the matches they're getting are
aren't close enough to to know what this
is so it's something new you know okay
so so this is good because we don't have
a lot of time left and I know this can
be a very lengthy conversation is it
academic or are these species
potentially going to relate to the need
for different control measures well I
that there's two answers is for that
depending on which one it could be
academic you know uh uh the John John's
pathogen looks a lot like brown ring
patch you know or wadia patch and we
know DMI fungicides work really well for
wadia and uh DMI fungicides John said to
name one Max thema works really well you
know so maybe we're we're we don't we
just realize it's A New Path because
John looked a little closer one time you
know okay so so that's that um the other
the other issue is with these root
infecting patch diseases you know we
both know course that was having trouble
with their summer patch control that's
right that's right and I would always
suggest to them that it was timing um
but what we found was it was a closely
related pathogen that wasn't
magnaporthiopsis this uh um SL
slopes oh God and uh and so that
pathogen has been implicated as the
cause of take all and bent grass you
know in Canada and and so so what what
we're finding is um that pathogen grows
at a lower soil temperature right so so
we are missing the timing but we should
have started at 55 degrees not 65
degrees and so so so we're finding that
in POA we're finding it in bent grass
we're also finding this magnaporthiopsis
myai that's supposed to be in fine
fescues
in POA on putting greens that are
telling me the same story right so
so figuring out exactly which one of
these and M mingi says to me he says if
they get good control at 65 degrees then
it's magnaporthiopsis if they don't tell
them to start at 55
degrees okay so this is go we bantered
around just calling it like the summer
patch syndrome because there's multiple
pathogens here and we're we still have a
little bit to to learn this is great but
on the other hand coming back full
circle um it seems like Diagnostics are
still going to play an important role
because we're going to have new
pathogens right and if people become
thoughtful right and are interested um
you know they can take samples do I have
pythium root rot that I have to worry
about uh here you're going to find
pythium everywhere uh there is still a
role for people to send samples in no
one's sending you good Turf but if
they're having trouble with their root
pathogens uh this seems to be something
that remains difficult to diagnose that
it'd be really good to get it in
professional hands wouldn't you say I I
I would say and and you know uh uh we
can look at it and and you know I'm a
classically trained pathologist you know
I was trained 30 something years ago so
I look at morphology and all the old
school stuff and to partner with the
guys that have the new technology you
know uh uh so what we're trying to do is
bring in some of these these uh uh uh
newer uh uh Technologies in order to
separate this stuff and so we're going
to start offering molecular
characterization of these root patches
through the lab you know the problem is
you know I can tell you in like 20
minutes takes Ming a month you know to
get to isolate and do all that work so
so you know change right they'll develop
assays I would imagine over time won't
they yeah I think so I mean there's
there's stuff that's quicker you know
and and I think once they get get a
clear picture of what we're looking at
then they'll start working on speed and
you know in my lab it's always about
quick and dirty what can you do fast
right and and uh uh it'll get to that
you know because in other crop systems
and other pathogens they're already
there so so we're going to get there too
all right well Carl do we have anything
for our fine guest here we have no we
have no gifts this ain't the Price Is
Right so all we got is the gift is just
being here with you guys the points are
made up what is it the points are made
made up and the scores don't matter
that's right rich rich one question I
had was um I don't see a whole lot of
people testing things on their Nursery
areas or their um you know Skip areas
check plots I don't see a whole lot of
that and I wonder how often do you
recommend that for people who are
spraying a lot of things and maybe
you'll look at their program and go I
don't know if you need this do people
play around enough on areas to the side
that they have experimental areas Dan
denelli comes to mind as a guy who's
done this with varieties and root zones
yeah well you know what you see a little
bit of that but mostly the press the
risk aversion you know nobody's willing
to even throw down a piece of paper yeah
right it's like you know and and it's
we've been teaching this sort of stuff
you know uh uh treatment evaluations
forever you know we're treat we're
teaching modeling we're we're we're
teaching mindful decision PRI Precision
applications and uh Underneath It All I
think is this the the risk averse High
salary has to be perfect and it's still
driving everything guys in the field do
yeah top down stress is is certainly
what well it's a cultural thing I mean
what D what we're talking about here is
a cultural thing it's it's it's the
expectations are human derived science
and the climate don't determine
expectations it's not a first principle
it's it's humans deciding that needs to
be perfect and and their willingness to
pay for it I think that's the other part
of this none of this is happening if
there not willingness to pay for it so
it also is the economics that g is doing
pretty good especially golf these days
but I would see I even see it in school
grounds you know they're willing to
spend money on Synthetic Turf uh there
you know more more grounds and
Landscapes want to be manicured not just
uh groomed uh and and sometimes they
worry about chemicals sometimes
sometimes they don't all right Carl are
we there we're there the fastest season
five of the Cornell Turf Show is is in
the books and maybe next season we'll
focus on people and not grass because
that's what it always comes down to
right it always comes down people as
much as you don't like interacting with
people it ends up uh there so thank you
everyone for those who've listened live
who watch the videos who who listen on
the podcast thank you a bunch yeah we
will definitely be back thanks Carl see
you rich good see talk to you next week
see you this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu