this is a production of Cornell
University thank you
Don so obviously we're going to talk a
little bit about berries today that's
what I do and that's what I've been
doing at Cornell now for 17 years um so
I work in actually several different
species as you can see up here
raspberries strawberries and
blackberries so Cornell has a long
history of work in berries uh at the
station opened in 1882 and berries were
one of the first fields that were
planted that first year at the station
in Geneva uh of course at that time the
station was an independent unit was not
part of Cornell but did join Cornell in
1923 and that that uh program has been
maintained through that time we are the
oldest Berry breeding program in the
United States and as far as we
continuously uh active as far as I can
tell we're the oldest continuously
active program in the world but those
stats are a little hard to come by so
there may be some dispute there um over
that time our program has developed 41
different raspberry varieties three of
which I have named and and patented you
can see them there we've also developed
43 strawberry varieties over that time
uh the 43rd one coming out today being
announced today in in the chronicle um
we did plan that a little bit so uh but
so generally and then there has been
some some Blackberry varieties there's
been little work in blackberries mainly
because New York is generally too cold
to consistently grow blackberries but
that's changing with some new genetics
that we're using in
blackberries so my program and my
appointment is research and extension um
we have a very diverse set of of
clientele that we work for that we try
to help certainly the home gardeners
gardening is the number one um Hobby in
the United States of course can be done
by people of all ages and people
continue to do it through throughout
their lives and so our varieties are
certainly many of them are suitable for
home gardeners and they really love
berries there's nothing be nothing
better than a berry out of your backyard
it will be the best tasting Berry you'll
ever get that said you can't grow
berries in your backyard all the
time so we have the people that cater to
those home gardeners certainly the
retail nurseries these are companies
like Burpee Seed Company sell our
varieties uh the gardens alive company
which is gurny and Michigan Bulb Company
and uh some of those other catalog
companies that sell directly to the
retail Market uh generally small numbers
high price per
plant uh you get into the commercial
nurseries you might recognize nurseries
like Norse farms uh Crone farms in
Michigan there's a lot of berry
nurseries around the country um we work
directly with them uh with our varieties
licensing our varieties but also working
with them with new material they
propagate some of our material
to give out to Growers for grower trials
before they're released and so we have a
very good relationship with many of
these Growers around the
country and then the commercial
producers both domestic and
international we work directly with the
New York State Berry grows Association
they provide uh member Growers who will
test some of our material before it make
it to the marketplace um as well as
larger companies in California that want
to see things pre-commercialization so
they can be ahead of the game when it
when it comes out out we have
international cooperation as well so we
have we have exclusive contracts in
Mexico in Europe um and we're working on
a few other countries so that they can
see our material very quickly and if
there's something they like they can
bring it to the market before everybody
else and they can have it for their own
um for their own programs for their own
production so in the extension side of
things we do things like variety trials
generally and a lot of protect
production technology uh research um I
worked quite a bit with Marvin of course
on that Marvin pritz on that area this
was a project um that Marvin LED on low
Tunnels for strawberries uh with day
neutral to extend the season it's been
very very successful and the berries
look really good under the system
um and we really we think it's a very
good option for the New York grower so
right now there are strawberries
available underneath these low tunnels
people are still picking strawberries
where they have them and they can pick
strawberries through through generally
through the mid November is how we find
it um often we just run out of berries
as it cools down but the quality and the
and the uh the season extension is
really great using some of these things
uh of course we have we started using
High tunnels at the station in 2008 we
put up our first set of about a half an
acre of these are Hay grve High tunnels
you can see they're multe Bay they're
interconnected these are seasonal so the
plastic comes off in the winter time and
goes back up in the spring and for
raspberries these this step in
production technology has really changed
the raspberry industry all it does is
keep the rain off but a raspberry that
gets rained on in the field has a shelf
life of about two days takes four days
by truck to get from California to New
York so if they get rained on even
though it doesn't rain a lot in
California it does rain sometimes
although in the last few years not very
often um those fruit are
unsellable put them under tunnels where
they don't get wet you get a shelf life
of 10 to 12 days so there aren't very
many technology you can use to get a 5
to 600% increase in your shelf life so
it's really important for raspberries
because they're so perishable um we also
find the plants grow better the fruits
bigger and the yields are higher all
good things but you have to irate you do
have to irrigate um for the commercial
market for the supermarket in California
all raspberries are grown under high
tunnels there is no open field
production that's that way they can
guarantee the quality and they can Prov
provide a consistent product that we
expect to see in the supermarkets every
day
now doesn't always work out the way you
like this is Hurricane Ike in 2008 about
a day and a half after we finished
putting the plastic
on and uh it came right over the top of
us 70 mph winds and tore it up pretty
good um two weeks later we had it
rebuilt put back together so it looked
really bad that day we disassembled it
parts that were bent straightened some
of them out replace some of them and we
were back in business in a few days so
um it really did look bad Monday morning
though coming to work it was pretty
disheartening we hold field days then
some of the variety trials we have all
the fruit might as well bring people in
to taste it so we put you can see we put
all this fruit out so that people can
sample it see the difference between the
varieties Growers come in they see how
we're growing it it's just a way to get
direct Outreach and to get direct input
from the grower on what they like so um
some of you came early you saw in the
back I put out some raspberries you saw
there was a little score sheet too I
figured I have a captive audience I
might as well get some information out
of it um but that's the type of thing
we'll do we'll provide grower samples
let them taste them let them rate them
on what they think about raspberries or
strawberries too and it turns out people
don't all like the same thing um
generally the good tasting varieties do
separate out that most people like um
and then there's often the outliers
people who like tart berries the really
sour ones and that's fairly common in
raspberries to have acidic fruit that is
that is tart in flavor um but generally
the market has moved towards sweet um so
higher sugar um bigger and redder uh
hopefully Colin was able to bring some
fruit down in Geneva and they got some
to eat I don't I didn't put any score
sheets out for them but I didn't didn't
want to leave you out for fruit if
you're not seeing it it should be there
in a Colin didn't bring it then I'll
talk to him later uh Colin is my
technician so it's my how I get anything
done a little bit about the statistics
of berries since I've been at Cornell so
when I came to Cornell the strawberry
industry in the United States as a whole
was about a$1 billion industry on about
46,000 Acres the vast majority of those
acreages are in California that part has
not changed now there's about 59,000
Acres this was 2015 data um 40,000 of
those Acres
California the other 19,000 acres are
spread across the country about half of
that in Florida and the rest spread out
um around the country New York is is
fifth in production um in acreage in
Strawberry production in the US and that
is a very small fifth um $2.2 billion in
the US in Farmgate value 1.8 billion of
that comes out of California it gives
you an idea of the scope of the industry
there it is a yearr round industry there
they are producing strawberries pretty
much somewhere in California pretty much
year round
now raspberries is really where we've
seen the the real dramatic changes since
I've been here so in 2000 or in 1999 the
process industry has stayed the same
that's pretty much Washington a little
bit in Oregon um the values has gone up
a little bit you see 104 million uh in
2015 on a slightly fewer AC that is a
machine harvested industry for Frozen
primarily um it's very concentrated on
three or four varieties that they use um
summer produced in the summer with a
very spe specific training system for
the machine Harvest where we see the
real Advance is in the The Fresh Market
in 1999 California had about 1,800 acres
of raspberries in 2015 it was up to
8,800 acres for Fresh Market raspberries
the USDA only takes statistics on
California that tells you what the rest
of the country doesn't even register in
their statistics um and the value has
risen from 31 million in 1999 to 400
almost $500 million worth out of
California um and that's just California
if you think about where raspberries and
strawberries are grown we have Mexico
just to the South and there's a
tremendous amount of fruit that comes
from there as
well as far as New York the industry has
been flat for the pretty much um the
last 20 years worth of of Statistics uh
in 99 we had about 1,600 acres in 2015
they only registered 960 Acres across
the region that is the top states that
produce the varieties that we produce
here and that cold climate uh Michigan
Ohio Pennsylvania and such was about um
6,800 acres in 99 now only about 3,800
Acres as far as the statistics that
collects are concerned the value stayed
pretty much the
same so what's changed obviously
raspberries we have seen a five-fold
increase in acreage and a 15-fold
increase in value in fresh red
raspberries and it is specifically fresh
red raspberries we're talking about um
and now they are shipped you go to any
Supermarket pretty much any day of the
year you'll see raspberries of course
you know the names driscolls is the
biggest name in raspberries and they are
have driven that industry
tremendously uh there's uh increased
Berry production in Mexico as well the
vast majority of blackberries are coming
out of Mexico there's a particular
variety that works very well can be
manipulated to produce fruit most of the
year um of course labor is is very
affordable there and they can ship the
berries they hold very well and they're
shipping them into the us but in the US
Blackberry production has not increased
nearly as much as the other berries um
although we're starting to see that
change the thing that's changed for New
York is the locally grown movement um in
99 there were only about or in 2000
there was only about 230 farmers markets
only I say in New York now there's over
500 and that Trend continues Nationwide
that Trend continues as well over 7800
farmers markets you go to farmers
markets in this area there's almost
always berries locally grown but those
acreages are rarely caught in the
statistics because they're very small
acreages a half acre uh a quarter acre a
quarter acre of raspberries could be a
lot of raspberries to take care of and
so sometimes they don't even make it
into the statistics because when those
sheets come out that they have to fill
out and they're growing 14 different
crops because they've got green beans
and they've got pumpkins and they've got
sweet corn and they've got everything
else they're growing the berries don't
even register on their on their
statistics so we know people are growing
berries in New York our berry growing
beginning Berry growing workshops that
we hold are packed with people excited
about out growing berries you can do it
on a very small scale and still produce
enough berries to have some money to
make some money and so it's just one one
crop within a many crops that uh many of
these farmers are
growing so these small grower statistics
are really difficult to capture um in
the usda's overall statistic
picture the other thing that's changed
then with these farmers markets and the
locally grown movement is that people
are more interested in distinctive
variet ities for these
markets the supermarket has gone towards
one thing big and red that's what they
want big red raspberries big red
strawberries and that's pretty much
where the marketplace is when you go to
the supermarket you know they look great
in the container but sometimes the
eating quality is not where you'd really
like it when you go to a farmers market
you want a high quality Berry you want a
high FL flavor Berry and you don't want
what you can get in the supermarket if I
want a big red raspberry that doesn't
taste very good I can go to the
supermarket so when people go to farm
Market sometimes they want something a
little different so in my program and of
course we still want to produce a big
red raspberry because our California
collaborators they still want those for
the supermarket so this is a variety we
put out a few years ago big and red
flavors adequate ships very well um so
you got to balance what you're trying to
do with the variety you know with
strawberries this is Archer if you
haven't you'll see some pictures in it
in Crown it's a very large red berry
this one happens to be very high flavor
as well it's a little softer than what
you'll find in the supermarket so we're
hoping for the local market people will
enjoy this as well nice to pick fills
containers really fast people really
like that um both for upick and for uh
pre-picked but we also have some darker
berries that we've put out so here
you'll see on on my right is purple
Wonder that's being sold through Burpee
it's much darker than you an average
strawberry would be and that color
carries through all the way through the
flesh so it is a dark fleshed Berry as
well the juice comes out of it looking
like wine it's that that
dark um but the commercial Market really
doesn't know what to do with something
like that it doesn't fit into any of
their marketing schemes so you see
Burpee has a nice display on it at their
website as you'll notice over here
they're selling them for $10.95 a piece
per plant a commercial grower grows buys
strawberry plants for
about 13 to 15 15 cents a piece so it
gives you an idea what the retail Market
will bear when it comes to Specialty uh
varieties I had no part in deciding what
the cost of these would be Burpy did
that on their own but uh we get a very
small portion of that as royalties back
to the to the university Courtney I'm
sorry but why why can that not be
shipped to all of those states there
are regulations on shipping plants
sometimes
uh California certainly has a lot of
regulations on you can't ship certain
species I don't know about all of these
states um some of those are not
States so there must be some some uh
territories involved there as well and
it may be they don't want to ship some
of these places as well but uh certainly
California you have to inspect plants
for instance for um Japanese beetles
before you can ship plants there so
there are there are things like that
that would be my my guess there
we also have a white strawberry um so
that's one there there you see in the
catalog is listed as Pineberry um white
flesh red seeds tastes like a strawberry
really just a novelty but it's
interesting um really not something for
the commercial market for the for the
retail Market it fits something that
people like to do because they like to
Tinker in their Gardens they like to
pick stuff and show their neighbors look
what I did you know you've never seen
anything like this so it's very popular
in that kind of Market but again it's a
very small portion of what we
do some of the darker raspberries crims
of night that was the one I put over on
the table with the refreshments dark FL
dark fruited very sweet uh freezes very
well much darker than what you see in
the supermarket and then a peach colored
one double gold again novelty it's what
people like flavors very high it's a
little on the soft side if you had some
back there um so it doesn't ship
particularly well but it eats well and
people really like it and it in your
backyard it's very interesting um to
look at as well as
eat we work a little bit in purple
primarily we're working in purple
because we're trying to transfer traits
from Red into purple into black sorry
when you cross a black raspberry and a
red raspberry the fruit's
purple so we're trying to transfer
thornless which we have done and we're
trying to transfer fall bearing as well
which is in the middle stages for that
so some of the stuff we're looking at
but if we were to get get a purple that
was interesting we'd certainly be there
is some market for it in in the retail
Market yellow there's lesser interest in
yellow pretty much a novelty makes it
look interesting when you have a fruit
salad but they pretty much taste like
red raspberri so most people will choose
red when you give but we want to put out
a yellow one just to have a a complete
Suite of
varieties this is not one we're working
on this is what you'll find on the
internet people say oh I want blue
raspberry flavor it's like that's not a
real
flavor so these are not the kind of
berries we're growing and we really wish
that blue raspberry flavor would go away
but it is something I actually do get
asked about fairly
often so the breeding program today is
traditional breeding we cross breed we
choose parents transfer pollen collect
seed grow out plants it's a very
straightforward process that's been
going on for centuries um we work in
Strawberry both short day which are
their June bears we grow mostly in New
York and the day neutral that more
interest that will provide that ex
season extension in those low tunnels um
raspberry both black and red again
Floric cane is for summer production
start somewhere in June will produce
through most of July and primac Cane
starting in July and produce into the
fall through uh till it gets too cold
with Blackberry I mentioned traditional
blackberries fruit in the summer they
don't do well in New York because they
generally freeze the canes freeze you
don't get reliable crop so what John
John Clark at University of Arkansas
started this a number of years ago to
work with blackberries that would fruit
in the fall so you can avoid winter and
we've been doing some work with him and
now on our own to bring that flowering
time early enough into the season so
that we can flower in July and August
and have fruit in August September
October uh for blackberries and the
blackberries I brought back there today
were picked yesterday so we're uh some
of the new selections from the program
are in full Harvest and we're we're
getting a very nice product um yield is
still a little bit on the low side it's
something we're working on but some
yield is better than no yield which is
what we generally get with Summer
bearing types um so expect to see more
Blackberry production in the in the
northern climates in the coming in the
coming years and they're starting to
adapt this to these types of varieties
in California as well for Blackberry
production so they can time the
plantings to get fruit at a certain
number of days after planting on the
current Year's growth without a dormy
period and that's really the advance you
don't need
dormy uh we'll talk a little bit then
you very faint uh some of molecular
genetic projects is the other side of
the program so I thought I I I get asked
a lot about you know how long does it
take to get a variety out you know what
is the process so I thought I'd walk you
through what we did with archer my
newest strawberry uh and it is a it can
be a long process so the Archer was a
selection I made very early in my career
here at Cornell and it was done very
much in the traditional sense of things
and so you'll see every step was done
through the field on a year-by-year
basis and it takes a long time doing it
that way so we've got some strategies
we've worked on and we'll I'll talk
about how we've been speeding that up
but this is how Archer started so in 99
we made some some crosses made some
hybridizations I didn't have a lot of
information to go on I hadn't worked on
berries for very long but we had the
records from my P from the past breeder
and we made some crosses collected the
seed in 2000 that seed got treated and
got planted out into the
field and you just grow them in the
field so we planted them in rows and let
them grow those have to grow a year go
through winter the next spring we get to
see
fruit now we've cleaned that up a little
bit and we use plastic we put them on
plastic to help with weed control but
the process is generally the same we put
them in the ground one spring the next
spring we get to see fruit um helps as
well we use a little bit of raised beds
when you get a lot of water this year
that didn't happen but last year we had
water it was so high it went almost over
the beds so from some years we get a lot
of rain and some years you get none but
you can't know that in
advance um so in 2001 we made the
selection so this is a 2001 selection I
made some notes that day when I selected
it it's a huge King Berry often the
primary Berry that comes off of
strawberry in the industry they'll call
it the
kingberry um I put very large Q well I
use the term queenberry as well rather
than secondary because it's easier to
write but that's not generally used in
the
industry um and I wrote that it was firm
good interior color good flavor tart
that's what I had to go on I made some
notes that day and I picked three fruit
a primary Berry a ter a secondary Berry
and a tertiary Berry you add those up
it's almost 100 grams of fruit so I
calculated if you took 100 gram of fruit
which is only three berries per plant on
a per acre basis that's over 4,000 lb
each plant produces more than three
fruit um so this is the kind of thing
when we see this kind of thing we're
like wow we got yield right away because
we got a lot of fruit size it comes off
very quickly it comes off at once and
for us to have a tertiary Berry in the
16 G size is a very good Berry in the
marketplace 25 will get you about this
big 55 or 50 grams will be about the
size of a plum it's a very large Berry
that's larger than what you normally see
um and we like we'll pick berries down
to about 8 to 10 G is acceptable for a
commercial product um so that year we
had one plant that's all there is is one
plant from that one seed so whatever
Runners It produced we collected those
Runners rooted them and start and and
there's a picture from that first plant
they're not the prettiest thing CU I'm
out there holding them with one hand
taking a picture with the other so it's
really not I'm not a photographer but
it's for me it gets it in my head so I
can look back and say oh I remember that
one and that's what we do to have a
picture kind of a record as we
go you start a plot took a year to make
the runners then you plant them again
you got to wait another year before they
fruit again so that takes a year we
planted um and then we look at it for
two or three years because we want to
see is it going to live is it going to
have some disease that wipes it out in
the first second year is the fruit going
to grow are the plants going to grow are
they going to produce Runners so we
collect more Runners from the next plot
and then you plant another plot and you
do it again to make sure cuz you got to
plant it in different locations to make
sure you didn't plant it in the best
possible location and it was great but
in a bad location it's going to die very
quickly so we planted multiple plots in
different locations so that we can see
this over
time and then you have to evaluate it
for several years to see how it comes
through winter to see how the plants
grow will they persist in the field will
it have a good yield every year it takes
time to go through this and it can
really take a long time and during that
way most of the selection
get slued off they're found wanting for
whatever reason they're susceptible to
some disease they don't produce enough
Runners the fruit quality declines over
time these are things that you
see we take more pictures so we want to
make sure we're planting the same plant
every time and that when you it produces
fruit the fruit looks like what we think
it's supposed to look like so each time
you each cycle you're taking pictures to
make sure everything is the same at that
point we decided these are looking good
they're very consistent we're going to
move it into tissue culture
because to take it off the station we
need disease-free plants I can't collect
stuff from the field and send it out to
Growers or to a nursery and it could
have any kind of pathogen on it so we
move it into tissue culture to clean it
up make sure it doesn't have any viruses
make sure it doesn't have phyo uh
verticillium various fungal pathogens
and that takes can take it a few months
but it could take a year or more too
some some varieties don't uh tissue
culture
well so we got plants we have to check
them for virus we have to produce more
plants so we can put them back out in
the field make sure tissue culture
didn't screw it up sometimes you put
things in tissue culture what you get
out of tissue culture doesn't look like
what you put in um and so we have to
make sure that we grow plants make sure
they're true to type make sure they look
like what you expect them to look like
all this takes time and we of course
take more pictures we want to make sure
it looks like it's supposed to look like
you have to make sure you have the same
product that you in the end with of what
you started with so we confirmed tress
of type at that stage we're like okay we
got virus fre plants let's send it to
the nursery so they can propagate it in
large numbers that way we can get it to
some of the
Growers um so in 2014 we sent out 16,000
plus plants to different 11 Growers
across the state so they could grow it
in a large scale and give me some
feedback on how um how it looks for them
how does it look in a commercial setting
up to that point we had 25t plots at the
biggest you know so now they get a th000
plants or 2,000 plants and you can see
it on a eighth of an acre or a quarter
of an acre and actually see it in a
large scale um they evaluated the first
year they evaluate it again the second
year because you want to see most of the
Growers will grow it in a perennial
setting and they want to see it more
than one
year so all this takes 15 years we get
to this point and we finally okay it's
time to release it and
you're here today it's being released
today it's being announced so it is
available to Growers now they won't plan
it until next year but of course we're
taking pictures all along to make sure
that it's the same thing question you
send that out to the
yes so what the Growers will pay what
the Growers will do or what the nursery
will charge is a propagation fee so that
the cost of propagation is offset um so
it is not the same price that
is uh it's we're not selling the plants
they're offsetting the cost of
propagation it's a semantics but um it
is not available to commercial Growers
um in this Kate was only available to
Growers of the New York State Berry
grows Association through a Cooperative
agreement with Cornell University that
we have with the association um so we
didn't send it to just any Growers we
sent it to Growers who were part of this
organization ation that we had a
contract with um for doing the testing
and so this was this year this is fruit
I got from a commercial grower it looked
great he was happy with it we moved
forward so that it's now going to be
available and they will plant the first
commercial crop this coming spring in
2017 of course we won't see that fruit
until 2018 so again there's time every
time you have to grow the plants so it
can really uh take a long time to get
through it so how do we speed up the
process well protected agriculture is
one of those ways certainly the high and
low tunnels speed things up the plants
grow faster you get a better look at the
plants because every year you have a
good year because you can control the
environment much better this year in our
open field the raspberries are very very
short where they're not irrigated they
just didn't grow much because they
didn't get any rain in the tunnels where
it's irrigated and protected the plants
look just like they do every year
they're 8 ft tall and they're covered in
fruit and so we can really get a a
faster look at things and since we can
look at them quickly we can evaluate
them quickly and move things into the
commercial stream much faster because we
can make decisions based on better
information we can make that decision
quickly and get them into tissue culture
quickly and once we have them in tissue
culture there are commercial Labs we
work with who can propagate them and
propagate thousands of plants very
quickly from a few tissue cultures uh
both r raspberry and strawberry work
very well in tissue culture and so
propagation once you have the culture
started goes very rapidly um and in
raspberry it is commonly done in in the
commercial nurseries that people will
use tissue culture for
propagation we've what the other thing
we've done is sped up the grower
valuations rather than waiting until
that last stage to get it to Growers
we're really trying to get it to the
Growers much sooner so this year in New
York we sent some 2012 selections to a
couple of growers in really preliminary
trials but to get a commercial uh look
at them much earlier in the process only
four years from when it was selected
versus uh 10 or 12 years after it was
selected some of our commercial Growers
our larger Growers um so we do that with
the New York State Berry growers
association some of our other
Cooperators in larger locations larger
industry locations they want they want
new stuff as fast as they can get it so
sometimes one or two years after it's
selected they'll get to take a look at
it because they're really interested in
moving very quickly and they have the
infrastructure to give me feedback very
very rapidly and so that's one of the
things we're doing to try and speed
things up um long term we'd like to do
some marker assisted selection um using
genetics and and DNA technology to speed
up the process and make it more
efficient throw out the stuff that isn't
worthy before it ever makes it to the
field um but we're a long ways from that
so one of the things we're doing in the
tunnel is growing things in pots so in
the field when we plant a seed l it
usually has to grow at least 18 months
before we can see fruit the summer types
need to grow for 2 years before we can
see fruit these fall types in a high
tunnel in pots we can plant them in the
greenhouse in March bring them out in
the pots in May into the tunnels and
they're fruiting now so between March
and now we get to see fruit and we can
eliminate a lot of stuff that is
unsuitable now we can't make great
decisions on the stuff that looks best
but we can move it much faster and
eliminate a lot of the stuff that we're
not interested in and so this is one of
the things that we're we're starting to
do more of so in a high tunnel like this
it's uh 24 ft wide we can fit about 900
potted plants and so we can go through
900 plants a year in there and those in
the field those might be in the field
for three or four years for each cycle
to look at
them so traditional breeding which we
were doing before in the mure genetic
side of things uh we've done quite a bit
of genetic mapping um we've done some
marker assisted sele ction we've done
some RNA seek work and genome sequencing
to try and increase the level of
information that we have for uh the
genetics of raspberry and for the future
we'd like to to try the you know the
latest thing that everybody wants to try
is crisper um but we think there's some
really interesting things that could be
done in Colony propagated crops um with
this
technology and since raspberry works so
well in tissue culture it's a fairly
natural um thing to try it on on because
it is usually done in tissue culture so
we've done some genetic mapping in
raspberry primarily for phytop root rot
resistance so phyo is a disease of the
soil of the roots that's in the soil um
it's pretty devastating on raspberries
it's very persistent um there is good
resistance but most of the resistance
are in varieties that aren't
particularly useful for the commercial
market so we'd like to do breeding and
you can do
breeding um and you can do field of
analysis but if it doesn't rain you
don't get phytop so it's hard to green
stuff in the field for phytops
resistance if you have a dry climate um
or if you have a dry year like we did
this year we had lots of problems on
raspberries this year but phyter was not
one of them because we didn't have a lot
of
infection so how do you look at phyter
then in a in a in a way that is
consistent we developed a hydroponic
system so we could actually observe the
roots in the raspberry as the disease is
uh developing so that we could get an
accurate screen of resistance
uh and then we develop molecular markers
get a genetic map and then look for qtl
analysis the quantitative trait so uh
phyo resistance in raspberry is a
multi-e trait a quantitative trait and
you look for qtl's to try to figure out
where in the genome most of the
influence on that trade is coming from
so here's the hydroponic system you can
see when there is no pathogen raspberry
likes it very well it grows very well
the root systems are white and healthy
um but once you introduce the pathogen
very quickly apparent which ones are
susceptible and which ones are resistant
so it gives us an accurate screen to use
for our genetic mapping and we've been
able to use this as you'll see multiple
times in different aspects of this
project so this work was uh was done by
one of my graduate students Jeremy
Patterson uh who now works for Driscoll
strawberry Associates in
California um and so you can see the
genetic map there seven ha haid number
in in raspberry is seven we have seven
linkage groups we looked at the um the
disease in different ways we took a
qualitative score just one to five is it
diseased or not diseased and then we
looked at stem lesions so they they
develop stem lesions as the plant is
infected and you can measure how how big
those are um some of the pedals get
lesions so you can do a percentage of
the pedals that get lesions and then you
can take a root score as well since we
could observe the roots directly when
you do a pot study and the roots are
surrounded by soil you get dead or not
dead but it's very hard to tell what's
going on in the roots and so this way we
are able to look at the roots directly
and get a score there and we found that
all four of those traits map to two
regions so it turn tells us that when
we're measuring these things all of them
were a good measure of resistance and
that they were measuring essentially the
same thing that same level of disease
res uh disease development um and then
the perent percentage of the variation
that was explained by the various scores
so some of them quite a bit when you
combine the two locations 50% of the
variation was defined by that score um
only 25% with a stem Legion so it wasn't
as um as consistent you'll see 55 and so
on so what but these regions of the
genome very clearly have something to do
with um with resistance the problem is
that that it's when you start looking at
the sequence it's a very l large amount
of sequence and so there's quite a few
genes in that region um that you would
have to look at so we published some of
this work in tag some years ago um it
was it was later confirmed by another
group in Scotland that they published a
very similar uh work that uh came up
with the same conclusions which we are
very gratified to see since they are
competitors um we have done some marker
assisted selection with those markers in
those regions um we screened
varieties we put varieties in there
introduced it and and uh uh looked at
both the markers and the resistance
rating from this and it did pretty well
um when we did the mark it was about
76% accurate and what we found is that
when the resistance came from a
different background the markers kind of
broke down so the background the markers
we found followed a resistance from a
specific source and there are other
sources in The Germ plasm that are
probably not in the same area or at
least have different markers um
if they are in that
area when we looked at populations so
seedling populations was all over the
place so some of the seedling
populations that were of the same Source
very very accurate 90% are better but
some of the populations that came from
sources of resistance that we didn't
know that were not from the resistant
laam um some of them were worse than
flipping a coin so the markers didn't
always work across the populations and
that's one of the things we find very
commonly in Mark assistant selection
that they're very population specific
the markers um and so so what do we do
we want to find better markers that
would be a good thing we continue to do
Marker work or we can continue to look
at other populations or we could try to
use some other genomic tools um so the
marker assisted selection work we
presented some of this work at at
International conferences and and
published that there but we wanted to
look a little deeper into the question
of what is actually happening why What
gene are turned on why is resistance
happening um so we looked at uh we
wanted to use RNA seek or RNA
sequencing um we took root tissue from
laam which is a resistant variety and
Titan which is susceptible variety um
and we did it pre and post disease so we
wanted to look at what genes were turned
on before it had any disease and then
what happened when you introduced the
disease um into the plant if you're not
not um familiar with RNA seek RNA seek
is a way to capture the RNA at a
specific time point so it isn't really
you're not following it at over time but
you grab the RNA from a tissue and
isolate it and that tells you what's
going on at that moment and then in this
case we grabbed it at another moment as
well and compared the two moments so you
break them up into small pieces because
at the time the technology was we were
at 86 base pairs or nucleotides with
what could be sequenced using alumina
turn it into DNA sequence it and then
you have millions of little fragments
and they have to be all pieced together
there's quite a few computer programs
that they do this with um it helps if
you have a genome a reference genome
that's already there because you can
reference those sequences straight to
the genome but if you don't you can put
it together just like a jigaw puzzle
where you don't have the picture and
you're just trying to piece it together
bit by bit and of course it's done with
computers to look at every possible
combination to see what lines up um you
get more accurate when you have a genome
but sometimes you don't have that
especially with crops like raspberry
where there is no genome published it's
not a widely studied genome um or plant
so there really isn't quite the
resources you would have for arabidopsis
or rice or corn or one of the more
studied crops we actually did both with
that but so again we took the hydroponic
system we collected RNA from The Roots
which is very difficult to do when
they're in a pot covered with soil so
this hyro honic system came back into it
so we could collect fresh root tissue
and then diseased root tissue so you
could see the difference between the
susceptible ones and the resistant ones
in the at the RNA level at the gene
expression
level so we we uh reported on this at
pag and a few other uh and the rubis riy
Symposium so what did we do we had about
71 million reads of 86 nucleotides which
is fairly typical kind of number overall
once we looked at all the we we
identified approximately 177,000 genes
that were expressed in these tissues of
course all kinds of genes are expressed
they may or may not be related to
resistance um we we chook between the
two groups between Titan and laam and
there was a lot of overlap about 13,000
genes um and then we did an
alignment both uh to a diploid sorry
diploid
strawberry which was pretty much the
closest genome that we had as a
reference gen know and then we did
denovo as well just the one without a
picture when you just try and piece it
together based on the sequence you have
um this work was done by another
graduate student Jud Ward also works for
Driscoll strawberry associate he is
their ahead of their genome department
now um and then we did a differential
expression uh uh analysis look at the
genes between the two groups to see what
was
different this was that uh the assembly
was done
um how to do it in non model plants we
published that in the in the Journal of
botney um has been very well received
because there's a lot of crops that
people have very little genome data to
work with they don't have a reference
genome when it's like well how do we how
do we deal with this all this RNA seek
data um and so we put that out um so
what did we find we pretty much in both
of them you infect them with r with phyo
and all their defense genes turn on
everything they have um goes nuts but
there's some differential expressions
um so some of these things were turned
on um I won't get into this the details
of which what the genes are but these
are have to do with inting the pathogen
and turning on the defense mechanisms
um we saw differential Expressions so in
Titan they weren't turned on as much
they're susceptible one as they were in
in
laam so upregulation of very key
defensive genes uh the pr genes are
pathogenesis related
um these are genes that are often turned
on and expressed when a plant is trying
to fight off a pathogen of some sort and
there's a bunch of these genes um we
found uh 18 different ones that were uh
expressed in lean 10 of them were
upregulated in laam where only 10 were
upregulated in Titan and three of them
were actually down regulated in Titan
very different expression pattern of
these defense responsive genes uh
between the two types between the resist
istant and the susceptible but of course
we still the these are large numbers of
genes that we're looking at um we did a
blast search of the of the data just
using the terms uh salicylic acid
jasmonic acid systemic acquired
resistance defense def uh disease these
are all terms that are used to describe
genes and so when we did that we 99
different uh things came up 99's a lot
of things to choose from um this is the
kind of stuff you get from blast
so we could tell though these were genes
that were actually differentially
expressed in the resistant type so in
leam so in the control versus the
treatment you can see the number goes up
because it's expressed more great more
highly in uh in the resistant or when
the pathogen is actually present and you
see here then these are just the Search
terms that you use and and what pops up
from the blast searches and this table
went on for page after page after page
because of all the information so you
have to sort through all this figure out
what you what you what you're working
with so where do you go with this I mean
99's better than
177,000 but we still can't actually do
uh uh you know candidate Gene work on 99
different genes it's just not possible
with the the with the funding I have and
the technology that we have now it would
take a long time and a big team to do it
um so some of the things you can rule
out fairly quickly they're very specific
responses versus very broad responses so
some of them are about you know
producing ligant in the in the cells and
that may not have any direct response
but is a kind of a side response to this
so we can we can start to to um to rule
some of that stuff out and then we want
to align it to the G The genome to the
qtls that we have so that we can start
looking just in the region where the
qtls are rather than looking through all
the genome and focus on those first the
genes that might be um might be present
in those regions and that's at the stage
where we're at now analyzing The genome
data that we have with the RNA seek data
to try and narrow down our choices um
and then once we start figuring out what
might be there that's where the crisper
would come in now crisper is something
though that right now not a lot of
people don't have a lot of experience
with myself included um but we think
there's some Targets in raspberry that
we can use to learn how to use a
technique and make it possible useful in
the future if you're not familiar with
crisper it's a bacterial system that
they theorize is used uhu in protecting
the bacteria from viral infection
primarily um if you wondering what the
the acronym stands for they're clustered
regularly interpace short palindromic
repeats that's crisper tells you a lot
doesn't it um they are specific DNA
sequences in the bacterial genome that
the bacteria can use to Target um
alongside this crisper Associated
protein 9
it forms a
complex and it can find the foreign DNA
in its own genome and systematically or
U very specifically cut it out and get
rid of the pathogenic DN uh DNA that's
what we feel that's what scientists
think that the actual system does in in
in
nature uh what they've done is is
harmonis this to take this section here
which is that targeted DNA and put in
one that you you want to change yourself
so make a make this DNA molecule
yourself so that you can Target a very
specific DNA sequence that you want to
change now to do that though you have to
know the very specific DNA sequence that
you want to change and it's a very small
piece of DNA that you want to change so
it's really very challenging to get to
that point but my new student archa is
working on this project we're going to
do some of this work with uh thornless
because we think a simple trait that we
can very easily visually um work with
and and classify is what we're going to
work on so we have a population that's
uh that's segregating we'll do some
sequencing to try and find the gene for
thornless um and then try to use crisper
to work on the thornless gene because we
can do this in tissue culture we can
very rapidly uh phenotype them as the
process goes
forward I think we at the end of this uh
in the end then we want to transfer that
to to phyo work as we narrow down the
different genes that could possibly be
interested uh in phyo their
resistance with that you I mentioned my
couple of my former students both
working for driscolls um Bill Boone was
a technician in my program for many
years and uh Colin is my current
technician without him I don't have a
chance to get a whole lot done um and of
course archina will be working with me
for the next several years on this
crisper project we're very excited to
see where that go
go so in a nutshell there's the berry
breeding at Cornell and if there are any
questions I will be around for a few
minutes Oran a question about it me not
mentioning organic organic is very
challenging thing for berries because
they're very very perishable they have a
lot of things that like to uh eat them
besides humans um the orc is even more
difficult because of all the rain so
without the use of fungicides it's very
challenging to get
uh organic this new pest called spotted
PL gropo which is a little fruit fly is
causing even more trouble with it most
organic production right now is grown in
dry climate locations um and they are
using Organic pesticides to try to
control that fly but that is that's the
only approach we have right now um
nutrition is very difficult as well in
these tunnel systems with Organic
fertilizers because they don't work well
in the fertigation
systems um so we don't do a lot of uh
organic raspberry or strawberry
production in New York um just because
of the challenges of the
environment question I'm just curious if
you looked at the nutritional profiles
or any phytochemical profiles of the
different raspberry colors the question
was about looking at phytochemical and
nutritional um uh differences amongst
the varieties we had gotten a fair bit
of work in that area uh both here and
then in collaboration with uh North
Carolina State they have a that does a
lot of that work we find wide ranges of
certainly Advan content finic content
amongst the Beres they're all very high
though um even the yellow ones are very
high in phenolic compounds even though
they have no pigment um they're high in
vitamin A folic acid vitamin C host of
things in general berries are good for
you you want people to eat more of them
not necessarily specific ones so um but
there's a lot of published work on the
differences amongst the
varieties any questions in Geneva I kept
you there long
enough importantly Bruce here um how in
in your RNA SE work how did you choose a
Time point to analyze and
um a Time point that is a Time point
after inoculation to collect your
and um would there be any better plant
material if you were to do this
again so um in our studies I think you
all heard the question in our studies
before in doing the uh analysis of
inheritance we able to observe the root
systems as the pathogen was introduced
and the disease um progressed and so we
use our experience from that to choose a
Time Point well obviously we did zero
time point before the pathogen and then
um we actually took uh samples at at 2
days 6 days and 30 days and those were
very distinct time points um in the
inheritance study at two days there was
no symptoms yet but there was infection
and so we could measure that there was
infection in the plant at 6 days you
start seeing
symptoms and at 30 days you start seeing
grow back of the roots that are in the
resistant
plants so we didn't have that last time
point with the susceptible ones CU they
were all dead um but we were able to
then choose those points so that we
could see the progression of the disease
not only in the plant but in the
expression as far as a better
tissue it seems that for phyo that the
resistance is in the root system is
expressed in the root system so I think
that's the best tissue that to use
although it is somewhat challenging to
use actually I'm asking about the
varieties that you would use would you
use the same uh varieties um are these
varieties related to each other or are
there any others that you would consider
using at this point we want to stay with
the varieties that we've been using
because we have so much historical data
on those varieties um certainly there
are other sources of resistance that we
would like to look at in the future um
but
can only do so much because we know
there are sources that are not related
to this this source that we're using um
but at this point we don't have plans to
use other other genotypes so our time is
up I want to thank Professor Weber for
fascinating this has been a production
of Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu