this is a production of Cornell
University thanks yeah so we're I'm with
breeding Insight we're under biotech
we're just up Tower Road next to the
Boyce Thompson Institute uh in a small
building that that you probably haven't
noticed before but but we're on we're on
campus if you're looking for us um so
yeah super excited to share the work
that the team does at breeding Insight
borrowed a lot of SL from people and
we'll get to talk through these
activities say so overview uh definitely
spend a little bit of time explaining
what breeding Insight is why why we were
founded um what we're working on uh go
into some specific examples of genomics
projects and how we're assisting
breeders talk about some bioinformatics
results uh talk a little bit about some
of the image analysis projects that
we've worked on with breeders talk a
little bit about Delta breed which is
our database management platform and
then I've got a couple uh miscellaneous
topics at the end so breeding Insight
the mission that we were given was to
help transform breeding by enabling the
implementation of genomic insight and
selection as part of routine specialty
crop and livestock breeding across all
of USDA
ARS so I think what people at USDA AR
were seeing and what we've discovered
working with a lot of specialty species
is that a lot of the challenges in corn
and soybean a lot of the tools and items
that have been deployed aren't readily
transferable to Specialty species in a
one toone capacity and I think this uh
list kind of shows that with corn and
soybean you've got very clear full
mechanization um we're working looking
just at two annual species we've got
functional diploids we just have to deal
with seed components seed planting a lot
of commercial breeders are in the space
primarily focused on high yields and you
get to have dry Harvest if you try
transfer that list over to blueberry and
lettuce it falls apart pretty quick so
again trying to how do how do we create
tools how do we adapt these tools and
service breeders when this is not the
conventional list of things that have
been made for corn and
soybean all right so the Breeders that
we work with breeders are tasked and
asked to do a whole lot of things so to
have a successful program to make good
progress right you've got to have good
breeding program management a lot of
good field data collection tools store
your traits properly manage all your
samples whether that's DNA samples
tissue samples uh seed samples again can
you work within the USDA germ plasm
Banks to bring in new and novel genetic
diversity identify new traits that are
plaguing your Growers um storing your
genetic data perform genetic analyses
and then make all those decisions and
Report out so I know so breeding's not a
sole Enterprise I don't think any single
person can do all of this
so what we're really looking at doing is
how can you create a good team so I
think any breeder today would say I
would love to have a great
bioinformaticist I'd love to have
somebody who's knowledgeable of genomics
I'd love to have a good statistician and
I maybe I'd like to have a software
developer to help connect and build new
tools to serve my program so to provide
this for every species for every breeder
across USDA ARS would be extremely
challenging and extremely cost
prohibitive
right so where breeding Insight kind of
fits within this scheme um again there's
a lot of basic research that comes out
super new
techniques uh new research coming out
all the time plant and animal breeders
as I just showed on the list before
they're tasked with a whole bunch of
other things they don't always have time
to go figure out the newest software
figure out the newest genomic thing is
it going to disrupt their current
workflow so that's where we kind of uh
fit in is kind of looking over at the
basic research hearing directly from
plant and animal breeders what are their
needs what are their challenges and help
ease that technology adoption into their
program so if they say I want to start
using genetic markers in my program
that's great let's talk about what you
want to use them for how many do you
want to deploy how are you going to use
it all right now let's show you a suite
of genomic tools that might be a good
fit for you let's talk price let's just
kind of narrow down the search space for
you so you're not wasting your time
chasing a bunch of different different
things that disrupt your current
workflow let's give you a really high
probability of success for what you
want all right so a little bit more
about who we are so again we are a USDA
AAS funded initiative we're located at
Cornell University we are Cornell
employees so that's really nice at the
moment uh we're we connect and build
resources for specialty crop and
livestock breeders so we'll talk
examples for both um and as I just
mentioned we really picture ourselves as
a service and Technology transfer model
again just helping provide additional
support to USDA specialty breeding
programs um and I know I'll focus a lot
on science team developments but want to
highlight that we're a team made up of
scientists as well as software
developers all right so a little bit
about uh what our growth has been like
since 2018 so the idea of starting
breeding insight and the Inception came
in 2018 we got our first group of
species in 2019 so there's the six
species trout salmon alphalpha grape
blueberry and sweet potato that
represented about 15 breeding programs
across the USDA ARS in 2022 we got 10
new species pictured down at the bottom
and also the formation of reading
Insight so this is a a group doing
similar work to what we're doing but
they're primarily focused down in the
Southeast um and they have a slightly
different uh research model than we do
in 2024 we got got 11 new species
pictured on the right and that brings us
up to supporting around 51 breeders and
breeding programs across the
US
right so here's kind of what it looks
like uh where all those breeding
programs are located so you can see
we've got some high capacity over in the
Pacific Northwest in Corvalis Oregon as
well as proster Washington also quite a
bit of capacity in Madison Wisconsin a
number of species there and then a
decent number in Beltsville Maryland so
really the idea is build some capacity
at uh Cornell University and then we can
serve as kind of surge support for
bioinformatics genomics phenotyping
software development to these breeding
programs across the US um one of the
things that's really fun with working
with all these different species is
we'll hear of a solution or a challenge
in something like trout and then we'll
hear a similar thing in cranberry and
take a tool from trout and be able to
apply it in Cranberry where those those
two groups would never meet at a typical
conference or or discuss these ideas so
we sit at kind of an interesting spot
hearing a lot of uh just breeding
technology that's coming through and we
help funnel and distribute that
information out to other
groups all right so that was a little
bit about breeding Insight let's talk
about some of the other things that
we're working on um so one of the big
challenges that we are set out to do
with looking at our species portfolio is
we can't constantly be building one off
solutions for every species or every
program that we work with so talking
with breeders working with breeders a
lot of the challenges are the same but
trying to figure out what is a common
Solution that's going to work across all
those species is a challenge but that's
what we're working on and I think we're
making good progress uh identifying a
number of tools and services that work
in that capacity so again what we refer
to this is kind of creating species
agnostic tools can we identify something
that can help breeders perform their own
bioinformatics regardless of the pyy
level of the species regardless of the
marker platform that they're using if a
species says they want to use genotyping
can we find one good genotyping provider
that can fit the needs for all the
species that we're working with same
with phenotyping can we find something
that works on berries and also works on
leaves and also works on Roots kind of
simpler simpler Solutions and then the
database management that's the same
component can we find a way for breeders
to store data for annual
as well as perennials for things that
are um at the plot level things are at
the plant
level just really try to create species
agnostic tools across all of these
species right we'll go into some
specific genotyping Services tools and
projects um so here's what I talked
about the challenges with genetics
looking at all the species that we work
with so we're going all the way from Aid
diploid system in honey B through a lot
of diploids with some of them having sex
chromosomes and then we've also got some
in fish breeding they will change the
Sexes of the fish periodically so that's
that's a fun Challenge and then if you
can look across our polyploid species
we've got tetrols all the way up to 12x
species and not always 12x sometimes
other things so um I think as as we keep
looking at this stuff it it keeps
getting more complicated and some people
say more
fun all right so some additional
challenges with with polyploids is that
um you usually don't have a high quality
reference genome due to the complexity
of the genome it's hard to get accurate
dosage calling and it's hard to phase
the markers especially for polyplay
species so those are some of the
challenges that we're
facing right so kind of that species
agnostic tool that I talked
about we've identified Dart uh diversity
array technology as a company in
Australia that's working really well to
fit a lot of the needs and requests that
we have um so this is our current model
I'll talk about the marker technology
from them on the next slide but uh
breeders that come to us that say they
want to do genotyping we'll work with
them to create a species specific marker
panel and then the breeders in this
equation are they're doing the tissue
collection on site so we work with them
to provide best practices what's the
plastic where they need to do how do
they ship it how much to collect what
are they working with um we help them
with the shipping to Australia which um
again they've got strict borders for
bringing in outside material uh the Gen
the DNA extraction is also done at darts
that's about $2 a sample which is great
and the actual genotyping depending on
the species $9 to11 so pretty low cost
pretty high throughput um darts been
great to work with and that genotyping
data can come directly to us so we can
help the Breeders QC the data and
perform any early bioinformatics Anis
that they need and then we can push that
back to them and then they can make
direct breeding decisions with the
data right so just a little bit about
the dart tag um is the technology that
we're using that's the uh so it's a
targeted genotyping by sequencing
platform based on this padl technology
uh featured on the right so we can
Target any snip or smart small indel um
into the dart tag panel
um uh typically we're making the marker
panels to Target 3,000 Loi um that's
within a single primer pool um and
what's nice about the technologies that
were allowed to force in any major qtl
or markers used in markers assistance
selection that the Breeders are already
incorporated into their breeding program
so we can force those in and then we try
to round out the rest of the panel with
genome wide distribution of the markers
right so we're hitting the same 3,000
lowai every time so we get relatively
low missing data and we found that this
works plenty well for any genetic maps
that we want to create any qtl analysis
any gws and we're getting good genomic
prediction accuracies for most of our
species for most
traits right so yeah we've been busy
making a lot of marker panels um so
here's the list of species that we
currently have so we work with dart to
make these uh marker panels open source
and publicly available so if you're an
alphalpha breeder you can contact Dart
and use the same alphalpha marker panel
whether in industry or whether you're
USDA ARS so that data has a one to one
comparison um yeah so here's a number of
species that we've worked with here's
the ones that are currently in
development so yeah we'll have a new hot
marker panel coming out watermelon red
clover hemps being worked on with the
group up in Geneva and we've got uh
Blackberry being worked on out in the
Pacific Northwest um so again just to
reiterate what we've seen with the dark
tag marker technology is that we found
to be readily accessible um we get good
communication with dart the Breeders are
also able to easily send their samples
uh the data coming back is highly
reliable we're getting fast turnaround
time the price Point's quite affordable
High repeatability among the calls that
are being made and we like that it's a
targeted marker platform that you're
hitting the same 3,000
Loi right so little bit about the data
that you get when it comes back so I
mentioned that it's a you get targeted
sequencing so we're targeting a snip of
Interest so here we're looking at this G
to
a but because it's targeted sequencing
right now at 81 base pairs we'll also
pick up these off Target Snips that's
what we're calling them so for any uh
lowai we're getting additional what
we're calling micro types so instead of
just bolic snip calls at the locus we're
getting much more information so more
similar to SSR
markers all right so so some additional
information on why we like Dart tag for
genotyping for the species that we work
with again same set of lowai across all
projects and samples so just make
sharing information particularly when
there's multiple breeding programs for a
species um it works really well on low
quality DNA um we get low missing data
we get pretty good read depth at around
50 reads per Locus per sample um so this
really helps with
multi-state dosage calling especially
for autop polyploid species uh we like
the multi-c reads what we call
microhaplotypes across the target Losi
um and then yeah linkage Maps
constructed using Dart Snips can
identify some genome assembly mistakes
so we've seen this in cranberry and
lettuce all right so getting multiple
micro types per Locus means we've got a
whole lot of Loi and a whole lot of
genetic data that we need to keep track
of so here's some examples uh in
alphalpha on the upper left so again if
we were just looking at bolic Snips at
3,000 loai we would expect to see 6,000
Al okay we're we're identifying 32,000
unique microhaplotypes so coming at
around 10 microh types per Locus there's
just a lot of additional information at
those low side that we're targeting um
so we want to keep track of that we want
to work with our breeders keep uh
genotyping a number of samples see if we
can get kind of where do these stop um
how much can we capture enough diversity
with the single marker panel that these
kind of asot and we can say yeah we feel
like we're we've identified 90% 95% of
the genetic diversity for the low side
that we're looking at so across the
seven species that we've currently got
marker panels out for we've got
156,000
microhaplotypes
um yeah so we'll talk next about uh
setting up databases to keep track of
this information
right so again so here's the target
Snips the of Target Snips so again we're
working to establish the best workflows
for filtering and processing the Shino
type data as it comes in we want to
create file formats that work with other
applications for Downstream analyses so
we want readers to have flexibility if
they want to use tools that we're not
developing in house can we get them the
data file format so they can go run
their regular analysis that they've
already set
up um yeah and then we're trying to
create and test internal apps for
userfriendly pipelines so we're working
on something called hype
DB right so here's here's a picture of a
component of that hype DB so this is
called Hao search so this allows you to
query those micro types so if you find
if you want to look at a particular
Locus to see how many microhaplotypes
you have or if you've identified a
microtype associated with a major qtl
you can go in look further into that um
alil the microtype and look look at uh
other germ that might have that same Al
or qtl or you can also look across
projects and say um and I'm only seeing
a little bit of diversity at this one
low side that I have I'm seing a lot of
other projects have a whole lot of
diversity maybe I should reach out to my
collaborator and ask for some germ plasm
so I can increase diversity in this
targeted
region okay we'll shift
bioinformatics right so this this was a
fun one um alphalpha creeping rootedness
qtl
so the breeder that we were working with
had identified this as kind of classic
alphalpha kind of staying within its
planted row very nicely he was very
interested in what's going on with the
spreading alphalpha that he had
identified thinking that maybe this
would lead to increase tolerance for
biotic or abiotic stresses or maybe
there could be a niche market for
Growers who want to plant this and just
let the alphalpha spread in the field so
we genotyped an alphalpha population
segregating for the trait using the 3K
Dart tag marker panel for alphalpha uh
perform gwas poly within this uh big app
and I've got a slide I'll talk a little
bit more about that um but yeah we
identified a major qtl on chromosome 6
explaining this trait so we can share
that back to the breeder and and see
what he wants to do with
it all right next project uh genomic
prediction we're going to stick with
alphalpha here for another minute so
alphalpha when we started working with
them a few years ago they didn't have um
they really weren't using a lot of
genetic Tools in their analyses or in
their breeding programs and now that
they have a marker panel they're very
excited and they're talking about moving
into genomic selection um so they're
really interested they're kind of in the
testing phase right now like what
accuracies are we getting for our traits
how do we create a training uh uh panel
to do this and so we're we're working
with them to show kind of like what's
the diversity with with what they're
working with what they're starting with
with their training um group gr What
percentages do you need from all these
different uh subgroups to get the best
predictions that you have so I think
again a lot of other
species plenty of literature on this
alphaalpha is just coming to the table
now they trying trying to assist them
with this and we can see that we're
getting pretty good uh prediction
accuracies for things things like height
in their
program all right the next one so talked
a lot about microhaplotypes having these
multi multiple information per Loi so
thinking about can can we squeeze more
information using that data than just
bolic Snips so what kind of uh genomic
prediction accuracies can we get if we
actually use the micro types for
pedigree relatedness versus just the
bolic target steps so we're seeing
slight increases in there and we're
really interested in exploring that
more right so I talked to just alluded
to this big app so that stands for the
breeding Insight genomics app um so this
is a collaboration with the genomics and
bioinformatics team as well as uh other
key people so trying to make a our shiny
app just to make a a web-based
application to perform genomics and
bioinformatics Analysis that's easily
accessible somebody can use it with no
coding experience um it's got really
good integrated help we're working on
putting out tutorials there's help pages
online there's also click information
within the app to find more information
and hopefully you can feel confident
running your own analyses and then also
if you use the tool you've got the
citations for for what tools and and uh
additional applications were
Incorporated um and again broad support
we've got the ability to pick what Ploy
your species is within the app so
diploids polyploids should be able to
use the tool without any
issues okay yeah so the the basic analys
IES in there or again we can do dosage
calling uh from the files coming from
Dart you can look at your data using
pcas do some basic genetic diversity
analyses you can perform gws and you can
do genomic
prediction right let's talk image
phenotyping tools that we've had so this
was a sweet potato nematode project um
so this one was with the sweet potato
group down in Charleston South Carolina
so they
were doing root washes of potatoes to
look for which ones are most resistant
or most susceptible to nematodes um the
classic Model was to dilute these root
washes sit at the microscope for three
plus weeks hand counting uh the
nematodes on the screen um that that
seemed uh fairly inefficient uh they
reached out to us could we come up with
a better solution and so uh tears tears
in the audience and this was our first
application of doing machine learning
for image analysis um so it it worked
really well so you can see on this slide
there's still a lot of plant debris but
it's picking up the nematode eggs very
clearly from that plant debris in the
background um and looking down here at
the F1 scores so the models agree more
with uh humans per counts than one human
to another so pretty nice uh the
scalability of this again going from
single slides to now you can p IET 96
samples into a plate and then run it
through the machine and get get your
images really
quickly all right the next one uh this
was the trout image one I'm sure we've
got Edwin online we've also got AJ in
the audience so this came from the trout
breeder in uh Hagerman Idaho so he was
really interested in taking images of
the trout eggs following fertilization
to identify which ones had successful
fertilization versus which ones were
blank or aborted um this is you can see
the differences with your eye the
initial challenge was that the eggs are
quite glossy and shiny so we had to come
up with a Imaging system to reduce that
glare on those to get clear images so we
could actually categorize them so the
efficiency is that these trays with the
eggs sometimes have up to 7,000 eggs on
them and this uh machine learning model
will analyze it within seconds with
minimal handling um recording overnight
95% accuracy on dead vers viable um and
the scalability is that they worked very
nicely to create this very simple light
box and deploy that in a system that
needs to stay dry can't have a lot of
handling and just needs to be readily
deployed on
site I think this is the final one for
uh image projects this was potato growth
defects with boa so the this came out of
the max Feldman's potato breeding group
in prer Washington so he asks can we
segment and measure negative growth
traits on potato tubers so his system is
that he can Harvest them wash them put
them on a conveyor belt and then they
get automatically imaged and then the
potatoes are cropped out um so he wanted
to identify some negative growth traits
like this growth crack on the tuber and
then also these Sprouts that are on the
tuber um so again the efficiency is
hundreds to thousands of tubers can be
um individ evaluated in an automated run
and we're getting 90 to 94% accuracy
where this is now replacing the classic
1 to5 rating for negative growth
defects right talk a little bit about
the data management software called
Delta breed um so here's here's our logo
here's the name um yeah so we're we're
definitely trying to abide by Fair data
practices so make the data easily
findable accessible interoperable and
reusable
so we try to adhere to the community
standards set by brappy so that's the
breeding application programming
interface we talk extensively with Pete
Selby on that type of work and try to
stay up toate and and help uh provide
information back to the community when
we can um again the big challenge is
creating things that are General but
also can be specific to breeding
programs at the same time as we're
trying to manage a lot of different
species so we've recently released the
Delta breed version 1.0 we're
considering this our MVP or minimal
viable product so with that we know that
there's some we're working with pretty
basic features kind of data in data out
um there's know limitations and at the
moment we're trying to have a controlled
roll out to our breeders so we're really
just trying to support the USDA AR
breeders that are most engaged with us
and have the most immediate need for
data management
support um along with that again just
try to really help get documentation and
training resources in place so that they
can do additional learning and know best
practices right so with that some things
that that the system can do at the
moment is we can set privacy and
administration levels for each user
within the breeding program you can
upload germ plasm you can upload
ontology so that's the traits that
you're going to phenotype with you can
upload experiments and observation data
and then we've got the brappy connection
to to push data to field
book right so yeah users sign in using
their orc ID um so that your user
permission levels associated with that
information so here's an example of germ
plasm records so everything that comes
in gets a unique G the name of the germ
plasm and then you can track the
pedigree information and you can always
open and expand to see more details on
that
individual right uh pedigree viewer so
this was a bra coming out of the breed
base group um so this was an example of
zi so this was a ban release down here
and they wanted to track back and see
what were the parents and and how did
they get to
it right so ontology this is a again
phenotypes ontology what's the set
vocabulary that you're using to go and
collect phenotypes out in the field or
in the lab so again a shortened name
here you can include the full name um
what's the trait that you're measuring
what's the scale class what's the unit
that you're working with if you click
show more details you get a little bit
more information for what are each of
the values that you've set one to five
um so again the idea is that you're
providing enough information that if I
gave this to somebody to go out to the
field to score that you would feel
confident that they could go score
correctly that they're not going to
invert the scales or invent something
new so again something as simple as
plant height is well am I measuring it
in the middle of the Season am I
measuring it in the end of the season am
I measuring it to the top of the flower
to the flag leaf so just being very
clear on what's the defined vocabulary
and that's where we come in with the
trait method in
scale right experiments and observations
I think pretty classic your germ plasm
name there's the G that's associated
with that one um is this a test plot or
a check plot what environment are you
working in um what are your row and
column positions for that um you can set
Latin long if you're using a GPS to to
track where those are in the field
a unique observation unit ID this is
systemwide for that uh data row and then
fill in and and upload your phenotype
data for the experiment and then
downloading data again you can decide am
I pulling all environments associated
with that experiment and what's the file
format that I would like my data to come
out
in right so the connection to fieldbook
um via brappy this has worked nicely
we've got a QR code on the screen for
your reading program um which will push
push the data into field books that you
can indicate which field you want to go
collect data for and upload your
phenotype traits as well and select
those and then you can go out in the
field and digitally collect your
phenotype data so hopefully minimal um
downloading the files and re-uploading
the files you can just scan the QR code
and push that using
brappy right so an important component
not to be missed in creating all of
these tools is also the training that
needs to go into it so we have a
Learning Hub online so people can go and
find this information we can create
links provide Sops uh plenty of Zoom
instructions plenty of meetings with
breeders to hear what are the challenges
uh how can we better help and when we
can we love to go out and have in-person
site visits with our breeders to really
hear firsthand what are they faced with
and and establish a good connection with
our
collaborators right additional software
demo applications so we've got YouTube
videos coming in uh pretty consistently
now to help talk about um uh the Delta
breed software the big app and other
tools that we're
developing okay I think we've made it
almost to the end just a couple fun
miscellaneous things to finish up so we
have a long list of species that we work
with at breeding Insight but also just
taking a look at what CS already works
with and agch up in Geneva there's about
50% overlap between these groups and the
species that we support but we also have
our our own set of species that that
aren't common between the two so again I
think we hope that there's tools and
services at breeding ins sight and that
these can be transferred over to the
Cornell
Community right just also want to take a
moment to highlight that breed and
insight in bi onramp received the 2024
USDA secretary honor award um so this is
I think category four for providing all
Americans safe and nutritious food uh
this was on January 10 so dong Yen got
to go down uh Tim Reinhardt is our uh Pi
representing the office of national
programs at the USDA and uh Kio is with
B on RAM so they got to go down and
enjoy the celebration with Tim as we won
this
award right final slide just want to
highlight uh a number of Cornell trained
individuals on our team who were trained
at Cornell so thank you the people who
helped train these uh great great people
um glad to have them back in the Cornell
Community providing more tools and
services and and sticking sticking their
whole careers with plant breeding and
genetics or physiology so thank you so
much but I think that's a pretty good
number all right and definitely a lot of
people to thank you know we have a ton
of support at the bi onramp staff the uh
onp a lot of people on the breeding
Insight team at the moment and thanks to
our Advisory board for helping answer
questions when we have them thank
you this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu