this is a production of Cornell
University I'm going to be talking about
um Cutting Edge Technologies in the
Imaging facility uh so as you can see um
all the labels that are new are
instruments that have just arrived this
year or are um we're planning to get in
the uh near future so this is sort of a
Services overview we have stand
microscopes and fluorescent tools so
fluorimeters
spectrometers um missing we have uh
Advanced microscopies what we call
Advanced microscopies so comp focal
multif Photon we're expecting a super
resolution system in January we have a
laser capture micro dissection system uh
a fax a CT and a bunch of technologies
that we call inital Imaging and then
support for image analysis and
visualization and so how we normally
work um
is uh you know you make an appointment
we sit down we talk about what you want
to do and we try and put you on the tool
that will work out best for you if you
know what tool you want to use um we'll
get you trained in on it and um we
generally charge by the hour um but uh
the facts and the CT are full service so
you drop off your specimens and we image
them for
you um and of course um our staff is our
most important resource Mark richio runs
the CT he's going to be uh tag teaming
with me Carol Bales um right here runs
microscopy and fact Joanna delar Cruz
microscopy in the inital Imaging and
Teresa pory does CT super resolution and
some uh 3D printing
and I'm tangled on the system
here
um use that Arrow so our com focal
microscopes um serve probably the the
biggest number of users as you probably
know uh com focal microscopy was
developed for Imaging into thicker or
cloudy specimens um oh I do have no
that's not a pointer um it it enables
you to get a nice clear detailed section
into what would appear you know
optically blurry on a normal microscope
um
but so that's really um it's more kind
of a One-Stop shop now um people these
our comforable microscopes are
incredibly well engineered and intuitive
and people use them for thin samples and
thick samples basically you can choose
whatever exitation line you need um your
emission color um the bandwidth of your
emission color and depending on what
system you can use you can have up to 34
different colors they have automated
stages so if you want to image something
with a field of view that is larger than
what your objective provides it will
automatically tile for you or you can um
look at different positions and follow
them over time they have automated f
Focus um and of course they have
everything to keep your cells Happy on
the stage um temperature modulation or
gas modulation um if you need that and
this is our spinning disc system this is
for if you need speed um on the order of
100 images per second it also has a fast
Focus motor if you need that um and this
system is also good if you're having
phototoxicity issues so this system is
supposed to be gentler on your
specimens um and now so multiphoton
microscopy was developed here a couple
of decades ago in the web lab um here at
Cornell um there's always been lots of
user-built multiphoton systems around uh
not entirely user friendly um now we
actually as of last month we have a
lovely nicely engineered multiphoton
system that's easy to use so all you
have to do is type in the wavelength and
press go so it's actually easier to use
than some of the um standard linear
lasers so what multiphoton gives you is
deeper Imaging it's good for you know
thicker pieces of tissue or you know
live plants live mice that sort of thing
it gives you access to Second harmonic
generation and other nonlinear signals
I'm not going to talk about that um also
probably most importantly it gives you
axially restricted photo damage and
photo AC activation and I'll talk a
little bit about that so multiphoton
microscopy was really heavily um adopted
into the Neuroscience Community this is
an example Imaging probably the world
record um Imaging a millimeter down into
the vasculature um of mice now um
especially young brain is pretty
transparent probably this is kind of a
special thing most people get around 500
or 600 microns in but this is an example
of um some image images that have just
been taken recently on our new LSM 780
multif Photon system this is a cleared
pop Leaf um and I can't see it very well
from over here but you can essentially
um image all the way through the leaf um
into the you know from
um I'm going to get I don't know Leaf
terminology the Palisades into the mesop
here but you essentially get all the way
through and this was taken by Monica
carvalo from Carl Nicholas's lab um and
they're interested in the vein lits here
so this is a single image you know taken
out of this stack right here and you can
see that you can um image pretty well
all the way through the leaf um the
clear Leaf if you need to do that um so
multiphoton also gives you 3D resolve
photo
bleaching um photo destruction and photo
Activation so I want to talk a little
bit about this so this um if I um focus
a standard laser beam through a
fluorescent sample right here you see
that you get pretty much just as much
photo activation all along the line um
kocal what it does is basically just
image this part it throws out this part
and this part by using using a detector
aperture that is optically conjugate or
com focal how multiphoton works is it
actually just activates at the focal
volume right here so this is a zoom up
of this of this region and this enables
you to do things that are a little more
quantitative for example if you want to
know about the mobility in your sample
you may want to do some a standard photo
bleaching analysis so in in three
dimensions it turns out that that's very
difficult with normal um linear
excitation because um so you would go
along right here you would you would
park your laser beam and you get
fluoresence you you have a bleaching
pulse right here which bleaches down and
this recovery is due to unbleached
molecules that diffuse back into your
focal volume so this is dependent both
on your diffusion coefficient and your
focal volume single Photon it's a very
not very well defined focal volume two
Photon it's very well defined you can
get good numbers out of this single
Photon you can't get good numbers in
three dimensions so this is also um um
applicable
to uh
photoactivated um
gfp um molecules such as meos so in this
case you excite with purple light and
you turn the green molecule to red and
you can watch this um diffuse away and
you can quantitatively um determine what
the diffusion coefficient is so for
Mobility um you also for instance
targeted oblation if you want to do that
this is um an example from the laming
lab from Philip Eiserman uh what they
would like to do is Sever the actin
filaments um within a cell without
affecting the nucleus so right here
they're going to this is using normal
compal microscopy the image and they're
going to use
multiphoton to sever the actin filaments
which are above the nucleus in this case
um so you can see that they do that
without um damaging the nucleus and this
is the second place winner in our image
contest this year so get your images
ready for
spring
um so
um and I just wanted to harp on this for
a little bit um this this area right now
of optogenetics is really hot right now
um um being able to op optically
activate signaling molecules and you all
probably know more about these um
phytochrome B um and um as a light
sensing protein because it came from
plants and so the idea here
um is that if you um activate
phytochrome B at 650
nanm um it will bind this phytochrome
interaction factor or the blue triangle
right here and people have now um
engineered this into Maman systems um
where if you opt optically activate this
protein um it will bring an a a a a row
affector molecule to the membrane
surface and basically activate it and
this is an example of
that microscope PowerPoint has stopped
working very
interesting
um okay we'll see it might be that um
movie um we'll try it again
in okay doesn't like that movie but so
what you would have seen if you saw that
movie in that movie was just taken from
um from the nature paper but basically
you can see that if you opt optically
activate let me go back here
Escape
um so if you optically activate um this
um cell what you see is that pseudopod
extension in that direction and and
basically I just wanted to make the
point that the molecular biology is
really hard but the optical activation
is super easy um if you want to you know
we have um a microscope stage that will
keep your cells nice and happy if you
want to do any kind of optical
activation anywhere um for any amount of
time uh it's very easy to do and it's
very um um in intuitive how to do it on
these systems um and similar to that
this is the the laser capture micro
dissection system talking about moving
laser beams around um so basically the
idea here is um this is mostly made for
hystological type sections that you
place them um on in general mostly you
place them on these specialized slides
that have a little thin piece of plastic
on them and you identify regions of
Interest so in this case the breast
epithelial cells um and um you rest
press go and it will basically cut out
the region that you're interested in and
puff it into the endorf tube um for
further analysis so this is example from
js's Lab um his students are interested
in epithelial tissue um they cut those
regions this is actually Imaging the cap
right here of the endorf tube um you see
that they've picked out those regions
you close up the cap and you send it off
to
genomics um so this can be done at the
Single Cell level and even the single
nuclei level if you're patient enough um
so that being said all the all the
technologies that I talked about so far
are are limited by the fraction
essentially and the idea here um is if
you have an infinitely small point and
you image it you're going to get a point
spread function um and I had to get this
into a talk Lambda over 2 and a so
Lambda the wavelength that you're
working with two Divi divided by 2 and a
the numerical aperture of your objective
this is going to be the size of your
point spread function if you have a
couple of spots within that they will
not be able to be resolved
and just because it's a soap box of mine
um this is actually point spread
functions um in um
cross-section and you can see so Lambda
over 2 and a the width of the point
spread functions is here but it's
actually the length of the point sprad
functions that's really dependent on na
and that's really what changes as you go
to lower na so super resolution
microscopes are microscopes that break
the defraction limit um and this is an
example of um a lovely example of uh
chromosomes um from po coen's laboratory
and you can see with normal microscopy
you can't resolve the strands um and
this sort of thing whereas with super
resolution microscopy you can and this
sort of thing is really important to her
because she studies uh chromosome
crossover so where they cross over is uh
critical so uh super resolution
microscopy is actually a bunch of
microscopies with a bunch of very
different
Technologies um so and you know this
year's Nobel Prize to chemistry went to
bsig hell and mner for a lot of these um
Technologies bets and mner were Cornell
grads you probably a lot of you know
them maybe um
so the system that we're getting in
January um you uh can accommodate the
first two the localization based and um
the super resolution Sim structured
illumination um multiple objectives is
another way trying to put as many
objectives as you can close to the
sample that helps you instead I'm not
going to talk about correlative eem um
ay scan is another technology that we're
going to be getting uh in the spring
so localization based super resolution
microscopy is actually um so this is
goes by storm Palm um GSD um is actually
pretty
simple um so if you imagine that these
are molecules that you would like to be
able to resolve these little yellow
things if they're within the point
spread function which is indicated by
the red blur here you will not be able
to resolve them normally however
if you can get them to Blink so this
comes on and then off and you basically
look for the center of the point spread
function you can identify it this blinks
on you look for the center this blinks
on and off and you look for the center
now you have resolved your Flor fores to
greater than um the defraction limit and
this is an example of um of Alexa 647
labeled tubulin in a storm
buffer and this probably not going to
play but you know it's
actually um not very interesting they
just
blink
and so and this
is so this is the um the results a
standard image of microtubules would
look like this a a storm image then
looks like this so now you've resolved
the microtubules this is taken by
members of the um zipfel group this is
an example an onion bulb using this
technology psf stained
cellulose um so the the
blinking um super resolution
microscopies okay so these typically
result in 20 nanometer resolution 10
times better than the defraction limit
so that's great but they're difficult uh
they're thin samples you usually have to
use turf or evanescent illumination
which we'll have um they require the
tough part is really the buffers and the
flop for chemistry you can only use
certain Flores they generally cannot be
done live because the buffers are very
reducing um and it requires 10,000
images for each super resolution image
so that's sort of like 10 minutes of
blinking data which you guys all Miss
because I couldn't get it to run
so the other technology that we're going
to have um is super resolution
structured illumination microscopy so
the way that this works is that instead
of Illuminating uniformly you illuminate
um in a defraction um pattern and then
that pattern will beat with a spatial
frequencies in your sample they'll
create uh a beating pattern that's now
larger so you can pick it up with your
objective lens so this is how it's
implemented in the Zyra the system that
we're going to get so they this is
actually a three-dimensional D
defraction pattern right here what they
do is they basically mix orders of a
defraction
grading this is an example of an image
taken with that this is a polyene
chromosome um and basically looking at
heat shop factor and um it's in green
right here and polymerase is in Red so
you can see that you can really um
isolate complexes that you can't see in
the standard microscope
image so the super resolution structured
illumination microscopy Sr Sim um this
is easy so you basically can put your
sample on the stage and that's it uh you
can accommodate thicker samples not real
thick less than 20 microns it doesn't
require specialized Flor fores it only
requires around 15 images so that
corresponds to five rotations of this um
defraction pattern and three
translations um so it's relatively fast
um it can be done live and it results in
a resolution that's about two fold
better than defraction so there's no
such thing as a free lunch um so the
airies scan is going to be kind of
similar to that uh the structured
illumination microscopy so this uses a
detector array rather than a com focal
pinhole and a point scanning laser com
focal setup and this is expected to be
about the same as the SR Sim in terms of
resolution and ease of use um it's a
really new technology so there's not a
lot of data out there so we're kind of
excited to be getting this in the
spring so
the other thing that we have that's new
to us is the fluorescence activated cell
sorder or fax um so if you um have
suspension cells that you need to
separate by color or size um or if you
just need to analyze them this is an
instrument that you can use for laser
lines 12 emission colors specimen
cooling it sorts into tubes or plates um
and we can take biosafety level two
agents if that is of interest um and
then um other technologies that we have
are sort of loosely organized into
intravital Imaging and now this can
accommodate sort of bigger
specimens um they are noninvasive to
minimally invasive so the idea is um you
know a lot of them are set up for live
mice but you could do live plants as
well plants that are you know still in
their pot you image them take them back
then bring them back and image them
again if necessary so this would be
luminescence ultrasound CT and in some
cases
multiphoton this is an example of our
new uh high resolution ultrasound this
is a mouse heart beating um so it's good
at picking up motion and anatomical
structure it's not used a lot for plants
but I'm not really sure why this is an
image that my daughter took over the
weekend she's 10 years old so ultrasound
is really fast easy totally
noninvasive um and tissue can be sampled
or injected via uh image guided needle
placement if if you would need something
like that
um
yes it's
Doppler um or it can be depending on you
know how you use
it um so um visualization analysis we uh
support um a bunch of different image
analysis packages um we do some custom
written
algorithms um these are our winter
analysis uh image analysis workshops um
if you're interested in finally
analyzing all that data that you took or
interested in having your students
analyze all the data that you took um so
they going to be this um in between
break in break here so that's all I
have this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu