this is a production of Cornell
University so well uh welcome and um
let's see what we can say here this is
the title this talk is based on a paper
that's been published in geoderma U last
year and I want to First give credit to
my co-authors I should say before so you
won't be disappointed U I don't actually
have any citizen science data that I've
worked on myself self so the idea of
this paper was the second author is Miss
uh misso who's a PhD student at
Wisconsin under Professor aul who's an
old colleague of mine who I work with a
lot in China he's at Wisconsin and China
and her whole thesis her old PhD thesis
is on using volunteer Geographic data
which is a big issue and she came to
visit me here a couple of years ago a
year year and a half ago and we got
talking about could this be used for the
area that most interested in which is
digital soil mapping and uh we decided
Well let's sit down and and write a
concept paper about this which is what
we've done and the third author many of
you know Steve carile is a retired soil
surveyor lives up in Aurora and a very
keen Observer not only of the soil
landscape but a quite a thinker about
interacting with the different
stakeholders so he gave us a lot of
really good ideas and so we have him
together so it's based on this paper and
if you like to read the paper then
you'll learn more um to my great
amazement after a little bit of uh few
weeks it was then actually cited in an
nature editorial as an example of even
soil scientists are thinking about
citizen science so it was like citizen
science is a big deal which I'll explain
in a minute but wow even soil science is
getting involved and they kind of took
my abstract and put it here so that was
pretty cool but uh the paper has not
been cited too many times so I don't
know if anyone has done much with it but
anyway a mention in nature makes my
mother proud very
good anyway some of you may well know
about citizen science I want to give the
background in citizen science then talk
about how it's been used in soil science
more in general but then focus in on
could it be used in the more technical
aspect of soil mapping and that's my my
main interest but let's talk about
citizen science in a more General sense
uh this quote I can't remember where
that's from actually uh the idea here is
the citizen and we could maybe call The
non-sp Specialist might be the word they
act as either the Observer the
experimentalists but this is within a
structure that's set up by the
professional science that's why we don't
call it a hobby and you'll see in a
minute the difference between bird
watching as a hobby and bird watching as
citizen science for example there's a
structure that's been set up by the
scientists within which the citizen
works there really two main features for
this one of course is we we're greedy as
scientists if we can get people to make
observations or do things for us then
that amplifies our effort we don't have
to hire another uh graduate student
right you know that's good but a really
important e effort I think almost equal
is to build build a citizen support for
Science and scientific understanding
making a a literate uh scientifically
literate public is another main
objective and these are sometimes a
little bit in Conflict on the one hand
we want this rigorous scientific data
but on the other hand we don't want to
make it too difficult for the citizen to
get involved to get some feeling for
science uh there's a lot going
on your Scientific American has a whole
page with lots and lots of Citizen
science projects you can read about
that's an example U these are just some
of the citizen science projects that are
involved so the Connecticut Turtle Atlas
people are interested where are the
turtles and they try to get people
involved in this her and herpetology and
so forth but there lots and lots of
projects in Europe we have a uh whole
citizen science Association Network and
these are logos of various both
universities such as here we have
burnmouth University but also and
Aristotle University but also all kinds
of NOS so there's a whole movement uh in
China there's a whole page on this and
there's a lot of
projects that are listed so this is
getting more and more popular let's talk
about probably maybe the most successful
project and one that's very dear to our
hearts here at Cornell because it's a of
course a Cornell
example U eird is run by the Cornell lab
of orthology and their aim is to look at
the spaciotemporal distribution of bird
species and what's the advantage from
the point of view of the lab of
ornithology obviously a much denser
network of
observations then could be possible with
the
professionals their aim their scientific
aim in general of course is
understanding bird ecology you know this
is in in the broad sense that's what
they'd like to do and the idea is in
this case they're having the citizens
amplify their
efforts um this is their web page and I
didn't update this unfortunately for now
but as even a year ago there were
already almost 10 million observations
that were made and you can view and
explore their data you can contribute
data and so forth
um there are all kinds of incentives you
see you can make your totals and the
reason for this is so successful well
let's just look at this here are the
areas where they've received
observations so they would really like
someone to go up to Siberia which is VE
a very important area for Birds
obviously uh but I was really surprised
by the density in in Mongolia for
example so there must be some active
bird watchers there that's good but you
can see a bit of the problem here
spatially in that the distribution of
the observations is is not done by any
kind of sampling plan it's all
volunteered so it's not as if we an
example of Siberia is may be a good one
you'd say well look this is really
important for migratory bird ecology so
we're going to do a scientific
Expedition we're going to go to Siberia
we're going to set up a sampling plan
according to our protocols Etc you would
have a very different sampling uh you
can't really tell this in the United
States but I had a student a couple of
years ago in my uh my graduate course
here working on eird data from Chicago
and when you looked at the city of
Chicago uh the idea was what is a good
Urban bird habitat she was trying to
look at habitat that would be suitable
from these observations well you found a
huge observation uh along Lake Michigan
there were huge numbers of observations
everyone sits there with their Scopes
looking at the Ducks and the birds when
you got to the south side of Chicago
with a little bit more rougher
neighborhood there were no Birds now
this either means there are no birds
there because it's bad habitat or
because no bird watchers like to go
there or because the citizens who live
there aren't so interested in bird
watching but it's obviously I mean this
is a nice example of uh the danger and I
won't call it a danger but a limitation
of Citizen science is it's very
difficult for the scientist has to deal
with data that is not collected
According to some sampling plan you
might otherwise use U now why is this so
so important you know why is this
getting more important and one thing of
course is the technology um the GPS
mobile phone has has absolutely
revolutionized so many things um you
know the social interactions of
teenagers and things like that but also
for us the fact you can go take a
picture it's GE reference
um you data capture apps and you can
upload it very easily has has really
made it possible for uh for anybody
really with a very very modest
investment to get involved in this and
almost everywhere you have a these these
smartphones all over the world the other
part is this mentality
and the idea here is that we're getting
more the idea of the
specialist being different from from us
as an ordinary citizen is going away
quite a bit and examples for example of
of reviews I you remember you used to
have to buy you know the New York Review
of Books if you wanted to read a a book
review and a new book came out and what
do people think about it you read that
or you read the New York Times book book
review now you go on Amazon and everyone
can review the book and that's an
empowering thing and so many people are
used to now doing that and giving their
opinions Wikipedia is a very also a very
good example um let alone let alone
blogs everyone can give their opinion so
people are mentally more ready to do
this um so the professional scientists
how do they use this data one is the
massive databases the idea you can make
a much better model you have more
observations you have more points you
can make a better model and the example
for the eBird would be habitat
suitability something like that the
other thing that can be done is now
monitoring because people are out there
constantly and for example they can
report an event like the first skunk
cabbage they see or the or a certain
first bird or they can report a toxic a
toxic dump a dump site for example they
found someone that dumped a
refrigerators along the side of the road
they can just go report that and if
you're building an environmental
database or a hazards database you can
you can just do that so you have this
early warning and time series and these
are both very useful to the professional
scientist uh now that was a little bit
about in general and there are lots and
lots of examples of Citizen science some
more or less successful but I'd like to
now get to soil science um what is
different about soil science well the
first thing of course it's a resource
that's very underappreciated or
unappreciated in the in the common in
the popular uh culture I was interested
we had one one of the candidates for our
geospatial position come in and have
these very nice diagrams of the inter
sectioning spheres and the hydrosphere
and the and the and the atmosphere and
you know and the soils were absolutely
nowhere there that was okay soils were
implicitly there how's that and that was
interesting to me uh because the
position was of course in the soil
science
department anyway that was okay but but
uh that just illustrates and in the
popular knowledge then uh people don't
have much concept of of soils actually
maybe we have enough time I'll tell you
a nice little story about my my phda
exam and that was many years ago but I
had a minor in computer science so uh
they start to examine me and Tom Scott
who many of you know said okay well I'm
going to ask you some questions about
soils and see what you know so please
write down the orders of soil taxonomy
and then we'll talk about them so I'm
about to write on the board and the
computer science Professor interrupts he
says wait wait wait you just use the
word taxonomy is that like a
classification I said yes he said you
mean you can classify soils yes you mean
soils are are different I mean are there
differences luckily I knew where the
professor lived in KY Glenn and I could
specifically tell him about the differ
lustrin soils where his house was and
the Terrace soils right across the road
in the kyen Quarry so I could illustrate
to him there were some differences and
we had a nice a exam but but I always
thought was a nice example of a very
intelligent very very well informed
person about many things not
appreciating soils okay second point is
even people that know about soils I I
don't think we have any soil hobbyists
I've never heard of anyone who goes out
and looks at soils for a
hobby uh you could you could go around
you say I want to have seen every order
in soil taxonomy I mean that could be a
hobby but I've never heard of it so I
was on a pedology tour and there were
two students from the University of
Maryland who were like finally I saw
okay a tattoo of the texture triangle on
his
leg okay that's a good point that's a
good point you like
that but let's even if that is true how
many birders do you have and you
probably maybe some of you were birders
yourself they're they're fanatic they
they love their hobby they get out in
all weather in fact right now they're
these two burgers that have set up by
this the Stuart Avenue Bridge I've seen
them the last several days walking down
there're set up I think they're looking
for eagle or something I'm not sure what
they're looking for a falcon maybe a red
tail hawk I don't know but they're set
up there with their Scopes and they have
all their gear so they spend all day
there anyway so we don't have I guess
the point is in soils we don't have a
readymade group of people that already
go out in the field and like to look at
at soils uh a large group but I will
talk to Le about that another thing of
course Very is the surface soil is the
only one that's visible to the non-sp
specialist
and even if you would dig anyone who
hasn't been trained to look to
understand soil horizon soil structure
and so forth would not really know what
they're looking at or they they'd have a
very crude idea of what they would be
looking at um therefore and I also
mentioned this if you want to make a a
consistent observation even even of of
texturing you need some kind of training
uh maybe a few things like I can
estimate how many stones are on the
surface but even then you know if you've
ever done that
you get very fooled if you don't use
these grids to try to say really what is
the percentage of stones so it takes
some training um so it's also difficult
to have sort of repeat of similar
observations it's not like the birders
where you you go back to the same
location so there a lot of difficulties
there are some citizen soil projects and
these are the ones that um I I know
about um the first one and I'll I think
I have slides on each one yeah so the
first one is from the British Geological
Survey and this is the only attempt that
I know of to try to collect uh Point
soil data that might possibly be useful
for mapping it's a mobile phone
application uh displays on the
background the general soil type and it
allows people to upload their
observations but I'll explain the
problems with it in a minute opal is a
very impressive uh effort this is funded
by the UK lottery they have a lottery in
the UK and they take that money and they
can give it to different organizations
uh based with uh that make proposals and
so they have this Imperial College of
London has set this up and collaboration
with museums and they have all these
these these surveys and soil is one of
them they have six surveys and you'll
see they decided to make an earthworm
survey and you'll see how they did that
in collaboration with a lot of schools
then in the United States we have Globe
which several people in our section have
worked on before this was set up by NASA
but the main the interesting thing here
the main purpose was to educate school
children it it wasn't really set up by a
scientist to say I want to collect a lot
of data that I can now use in my
scientific project so it's very
important to educate school children in
in in methods of OBS observation of
atmosphere and soil but the main aim was
not to collect the data so here's my
soil and U it's uh it kind of promises a
lot more than it delivers um the
background in of of Europe is the
general soil map of Europe from the jrc
but the uh joint recharge Center in
Italy but the one in England is only a a
very very very general parent material
map now why is this the British
Geological Survey which controls the
soil survey data was the old soil survey
of England and Wales was privatized
under Margaret Thatcher and sold we give
you zero budget you have to make all
your money so they immediately even
though the data was completely collected
with rate payer money they completely
kept it to themselves they only sell it
you can't even buy it they only license
it and they don't want to give anything
away for free that's now been taken over
by the British Geological Survey but now
you see this extremely general map
saying we're on Chalk or on Triassic
rocks and that's all you can get as a
homeor you can't see the soil map even
though there is a soil map so you can't
go there and say Here's Where I Am this
is what the soil map say
when you upload your information all you
can say is well is it coarse medium or
fine and does it you know was it black
or white it's so it's not very useful
they are getting some U people uploading
things from their Garden but it's I I
find a really a lost uh lost opportunity
but you can maybe decide for
yourself this is opal and uh they have
of all these surveys I mentioned and
they they have a soil survey what
they've done here they've got a very
nicely worked out protocol for all their
surveys and the reason it's becoming
successful is because they're working
through the schools and have this they
work with the teachers and the schools
and they it's mainly school children as
you can see from the kind of publicity
picture but look what they're holding
see they have a nice worm here are they
very happy that they found a worm and
they learn how to describe tell the
different types of worms count worm
density and so forth so that's the main
thing about their their soil survey and
you can see all the things they've done
here enter your results results map
earthworm guide and so forth they've
decided to concentrate on the earthworms
and they've made really really a lot of
data and it very much more
consistent and Globe here is the globe
uh they collected data on soil
temperature moisture and so forth at
these various stations and then mainly
through schools and so you see this
teachers guide and so forth so these are
things they they tried to get the
students to to understand but it was
more a teaching effort and I don't think
they've really collected much data uh
that uh can be can be
used U okay now let's get to narrow down
even further into digital soil mapping
which is which is my interest and some
I'm sure you know about this others
maybe
not well soil mapping of course is we
would like to show spatially the
distribution of the different types of
soils either the properties directly so
we'd like to map the pH everywhere or
the soil texture or soil types According
to some class classification system for
example soil series or soil
orders uh the digital soil mapping just
means we use computer algorithms to
speed up or help this process and we
have this mapping Paradigm that goes
back that was that MC bratney uh and his
colleagues back in uh now it's already
13 years ago so systematized and
everyone uses this concept and how we
work it out as quite different but he
didn't like the clorpt he thought cped
didn't sound good if you know your Jenny
equation so he decided scorpan he wanted
to make scorpion but he couldn't think
of any ey to put in there so we have
scorpan and so he put the a in there
instead of time he used anom instead of
time so we get of a but there is
something new in here if you know your
Genny equation the point here is the
soil that we see is meant to be not
randomly distributed it's there for a
reason so it's based on the climate it's
found in the organisms that were work
both in and above of the soil the relief
so where it is in the topography the
parent material it developed from the
time it had to develop those are all in
the Jenny equation but here we have two
other factors we have S as a function of
s what is that supposed to mean that's
supposed to mean it's based on the
actual observations we've made that's
why he put it in there so you can't do
this abstractly you calibrate it based
on actual observations and then the N
here is there for geostatistics it's
meant to say neighborhood it means that
if you know if you know the soils you've
observed close by it tells you gives you
some idea of what soils you might find
after you've taken these others in
account so it's just a conceptual way
but what do we do when we now go to
actually use it we like to find a
covariant that covers the whole area we
want to map that each covariant
represents part of that equation and of
course it can be a very complicated I
have a colleague down in Flor University
of Florida Savina grunvald and she
throws 350 different covariants in a
great big data mining model to try to
figure things out I I'm not really an
advocate of that approach but that's
that's an idea but each of those
covariants are meant to represent
something that would affect soil
development so for example if you have
vegetation indices and you look at the
intensity of the vegetation or the
seasonality of the vegetation that might
tell you something about the the the
organic matter that kind of thing um so
anyway we we have we need the point
obser I said the S was then the point
observations for the soil and we need
Point observations I guess that's the
point we have lots of covariants we have
digital elevation models and derivatives
we have a huge number of remote sensing
products stream networks all kinds of
things like this geology Maps but what
we don't have or what are very expensive
are Mak Point observations of the soils
so the concept of how we might be liking
to use citizen soil science here would
be to try to find some observations we
could use either in our model building
or even if we built models with more
reliable information maybe for the model
evaluation which probably shouldn't be
called validation I I've been convinced
never to use this word that's why I put
it in quotes because I was convinced by
a colleague who I worked with in the
Netherlands that a model is never valid
you never say it's valid you can
evaluate it and
see how well it's performing and so
forth but to say it's valid is sort of
like you know you have a validated
driver's license or something so she
convinced me not to do that so I've ever
since been tried to be uh strict about
that so we can maybe get a philosophical
discussion about is a model ever valid I
don't think so anyway so this is the
question this is what we got our
motivation was to thinking about this I
just show an example digital soil map to
just if you have never seen one before
this is aroua in Tanzania and one is it
a one kilm resolution and one is it a
250 M resolution of the same area this
is the prediction of in this case the so
organic car carbon concentration in the
top uh 5
cm uh and I'm sorry I didn't show the
scale bar I should have shown that and
you can see so how are you doing this
you haven't been everywhere well youve
built some model and you can see what's
happening here is as we go up the
volcano first off we get more volcanic
parent material second we get higher
elevation where it's cooler organic
matter won't decompose as much and so
forth and there are other factors that
might might come in here but that's how
these maps are made but to certainly to
mild the model and possibly to evaluate
it we we need some observations we'd
like someone to go in a lot of these
places and and take a soil sample so why
involve citizens well for us
uh we'd like to increase the density uh
we think of course just like the bird
just like the bird watchers or the bird
ecologists we'd get better predictive
models if we had more
observations I'm going to get to this in
just a minute and Show an example we
would like maybe to correct mistakes on
published Maps because if you've seen a
soil map what you realize is they're
typically made now as polygons and the
surveyor has really not been everywhere
they've been every they've taken some
samples they have a mental model but
they could have made a mistake and if
you have an observation where it's
predicted to be one thing and you see
something else it allows a professional
mapper to say hm I didn't go there I
didn't take that observation but if
that's a true observation I better
rethink I better rethink my mental model
and would allow them to then improve the
map uh another way would be to take a
published map and and downscale it or
disaggregate it so you might have
especially a more General soil map where
it's been done maybe at a scale of
100,000 or 200,000 you know there are
several soil types in there but you
don't know where but if other people
have gone there that helps you to make a
more detailed map so that's what we'd
like to see now
Society well number one we'd like to
we'd like the citizens to have a good
idea appreciation for the soil geography
we'd like them to know there are
different soils that they have different
capabilities that they occur at
different places on the landscape and
the more people we could get out there
looking at soils and realizing this then
we would just be building support for
soil survey in a more General
sense uh so you know we'd like we'd like
people to do this and there's this
concept of the connectivity the soil the
people appreciating soils and thinking
as a citizen about the quality of their
soils the health of their soils in the
same way probably most citizens now were
quite aware of water quality for example
they they're clear if their lake is
getting polluted or if they're if they
have foul smelling water and so forth so
people have feel connected to their
Water Resource but often not to soil
resource okay now I what we did after
that my my co-authors and I we we were
really thinking who could be the citizen
scientist how could we categorize these
people of course some person might be in
different roles so I'll go through all
these different uh different types of
people that we might attract to be our
our citizen
scientists uh all of these groups the
interesting thing about this is these
all have a specific culture so if we
want to approach one of these groups
like if I go back here if we want to
I'll I'll talk to the greens or the
gardeners if they all have a culture
right so if you'd like to attract them
you'd have to meet them with the culture
the way they're thinking and making a a
project that's attractive to them and
what they do so these are probably very
different types of people and they would
call for a different type of
organization
I mentioned the national culture here
because we are interested of course in
doing this around the world and there's
a lot of difference between National
cultures uh both in terms of the
citizens mentality but also the way that
people would take to sharing data in
other words letting you on their land to
look at data or even if it's my own land
am I willing to share data what are my
cultural norms and so forth and we have
these these other things that are quite
different scientists and the public have
a different relation in different
countries so if you were thinking of
that okay so let's talk about the groups
one at a time the first one is yeah do I
call them citizens now I'm talking about
this is the closest to us and many
people in the room here would fit
certainly in this you're a research soil
scientist but you're not a soil mapper
you're an agronomist you're not a soil
mapper you're a professional in your
educ in your field of course um so we
call you an educated citizen uh
so you're to some degree familiar with
existing soil survey protocols and
products youve you're aware there's a
soil survey you of a if you don't know
exactly you have a general idea that
these exist and what can be done with
them uh you have an interest in these
Maps so you have an idea that if you're
interested in Agronomy or soil science
you you really have an interested in a
reliable soil map you have a
professional attitude towards soil
information so the concept that you
might get involved in in during your
routine your other work that you're
doing in making certain observations
that would help the soil mappers is not
doesn't seem like such a big stretch so
that would be uh one type of group this
would involve uh not so much uh more
just of figuring out a protocol that
would not be too hard for people to do
in the course of their other work so you
know plant breeder goes out they have
plant breeding plots they're out there
anyway what can you what could you ask
them to do as as they're out out there
that that might help you with your soil
mapping that kind of thing okay now the
next of course are farmers uh or we
might say land managers it might not be
the farmer themselves it might be the
Forester managing a forestry block or
DEC Forester for example these people
are familiar with their portion of the
landscape and mostly they're definitely
aware of the value of soil
information the motivation and we're
trying to think of the motivation here U
and the motivation for the first group
might have been in well you know science
is important and you know your colleague
is working to make a better soil map and
if you can contribute to that you feel
well you're
increasing the scientific project in
some sense here I think the they're more
interested in in a more detailed soil
map of their area it's maybe maybe the
other areas to compare Land Management
methods so maybe they'd like to have a
more detailed map of let's say the
county or a surrounding area but I think
the main interest is saying well if we
can convince them to supply data they
would get back a more reliable map
somehow I think that would be the
motivation to get uh Farmers
involved uh a big I should say a bit of
a problem with this of course is is the
Privacy issue in that in the United
States of course anyone can look at the
soil map and see in general how your
farm is mapped if I'm thinking of buying
your farm or I'm comparing but uh if
it's a more detailed map uh maybe maybe
I don't really want that information to
get out that's a bit of a
problem now civil engineers and others
involving construction are an
interesting group because they're the
ones who go and see the subsoil uh they
have Road Cuts service Mining
excavations and so forth so they're the
ones that are already making their own
geotechnical measurements so they're
they're used to this so we usually only
go to 2 m and you know the reason that
soil survey only goes to 2 m
this is a I don't know if it's a true
story but I heard back in
1899 when the Bureau of um agricultural
industry was set up Milton Whitney was
arguing with the head of the Geological
Survey and the Geological Survey said
you don't we don't need a soil survey we
already we already survey and he said no
no soils are different soils are the
it's this you know everything is
happening in the upper part of the soil
and you're only looking at the geology
and you just call it quaternary geology
and and we're looking at the we're
looking at the soil and they had a kind
of an argument and they decided that
since bodies were buried to six feet
that would be the
limit so okay you can call that the soil
down to 6 feet which we now call 2
meters so I don't know if that's a true
story but uh in fact there's been a
movement in recent years headed by the
Australians for obvious reasons because
they're in a very old weathered
landscape what they call whole regolith
pedology and there just been a special
issue in I think geoderma about this but
a lot of papers on this where they
saying oh look pedology is the entire
regali down to Hard Rock this is all a
continuous process and there's much more
conductivity much deeper in the soil
than soil scientists have have thought
in the past so uh we would actually and
USDA is behind this nrcs they'd like to
look deeper of course that's very
expensive uh you can't do it routinely
but these people uh look at quite some
depth so they could be a good source
and here's a picture of uh actually this
is a soil survey but I like this picture
because um it shows an excavation that
was done and we jumped in we we saw well
before they before they build the
buildings here uh we'll jump in there
and we'll take this opportunity uh to
see the the soil um and the nice thing
is here not only can we see the the soil
where we're taking the uh the the
observation here but you can see in the
back we get a very good idea of the very
of the variability which is very hard to
do if you don't have a trench or a pit
like this now I can ask you in this
picture which one is the professor head
of the
group the one in the chair
absolutely well he's taking no no he's
very active but he's taking the notes so
that's okay this is my my work group at
the Chinese academ the the soil Science
Institute the Chinese Academy of scien
Sciences take a lot of but this so it's
not a civil engineers but you see the
point that these these people doing the
excavation they have an opportunity
possibly for example just to take photos
for us that would be maybe just enough
if if if we already have a good idea
what the soil type is here and but we
don't have a real good idea of the
variability let's say of the horizons if
someone just takes a photo back here and
sends it to us that's that's really nice
so this is the kind of thing we we might
ask them to
do now gardeners a lot of people think
well the gardeners would be a good
choice but I don't I don't think so for
a couple of reasons first off the
gardeners are just managing one very
site very intensively and second they're
modifying the soil quite a bit so
Gardener an interesting group to work
with for many things but they don't
really help us with digital soil mapping
over over larger areas uh so I I think
they're enthusiastic people and they're
a ready-made group but I don't think
they're so useful for digital soil
mapping now people who go Outdoors
anyway hikers geocachers these people
who go out and they like to go out
anyway um I'm thinking they may be
interested in learning more about their
environment and you might be able to
convince them to do something as they're
going along in in their regular outdoor
activity we'll talk about what we might
ask them to do well we have the greens
and the organizers the greens these are
people that love the environment even if
they don't always get out in the
environment they they love it somehow uh
and the mo and the motivation well I'm
you know I'm today St Patrick's Day I
see we have one person wearing green so
this is
good the time I went down into Boston on
St Patrick's Day wearing my orange coat
was a bad idea that was a long time ago
anyway well Northern Irish are Irish too
right I I don't know anyway but um the
the idea with the greens in would be if
people are already involved I didn't we
didn't get to think too clearly about
what they might do the organizers are
are an interesting group a really
interesting group and some of you may be
in this group if you think about it
these are people that have a
psychological need to live in an
organized
world no
seriously let me ask you if you go look
at a Wikipedia entry about something you
know about and there's an incorrect
statement there what do you do do you
edit it or you just go on and say
someone else will edit it a lot of
people and I may include myself partly
in this description say I can't stand
that there's a wrong statement there now
why am I taking my my time no one's
paying me to do it to correct and it's
not a it's not a statement about me or
or someone I know it's just a wrong
statement I take my time to organize it
open street map is another really good
example of this why don't we just let
the professional mappers why are people
updating open street map well and I'm
thinking in terms of the soil map if
these same people can be motivated to go
look at the soil map and compare the
soil map that exists with what's really
there they might have a compulsive
interest in in sending information in
and I I don't I would not downplay this
because we see we see really good
examples of this the number of people
that every in the Netherlands you know
it's just unbelievable every bike path
with its width and and its surface is in
the open street map and someone is doing
all this too much time on their hands
too much you know they only work 36
hours a week so you got some time it's
not like
us but they work hard in the 36 hours
okay now let's turn the over to the
other side and say what information
could be provided to us and how hard
would this to be to get and I'll talk
about all of these one at a time that
and you can see the list here and let's
talk about them now the tacit knowledge
is what I might call the local knowledge
of the soil landscape it's not expressed
in really scientific language you don't
really make this is this is without
making a new observation but you make a
comment on a published map or a comment
uh maybe an even an unpublished map
where you say well I know over in this
area it's really really bouldery really
Rocky you could never use Machinery over
here and the bul this you know or here
it's been extremely high I I look at my
photo I say over there oh it's really
really eroded over there uh the gullies
are everywhere you the subsoil is coming
through and this kind of knowledge where
without making a new observation the
person who knows their land very well um
can either comment on a published map or
they could make a sketch um this is
difficult to translate into Point
observations but I can imagine it's it's
useful information because we haven't
looked at points we we've kind of made
observations then there's opportunistic
uh newly acquired information and you
know to see something say something
motto where is that used in New York
Subway maybe I don't know maybe here all
we need here is to say look if you're
out there and you see something that you
think is interesting and important to us
just send us a just tell us where you
were and send us a Geo a geotag
photo we can see a lots of things from
just a surface photo now we have an idea
already of what's there it's not a
detailed observation but this can help
us a lot um there's no protocol the
advantage here is we're not asking you
to fill in any form did you ever get
these things on the web where they say
please take a survey to improve our
website I just got one from the New York
Times this morning I I I subscribe to
New York Times I like it and I said okay
let me see and they came up and said
this will take 10 minutes to complete I
said forget it I don't want to answer
questions for 10 minutes I mean if
you're just asking me a couple questions
I might do it but in this case there's
no protocol and no
complication and here's an example
actually from me uh which I did uh out
one day for a bike ride and I see
they've done deep plowing on this field
and you can see these iron h Iron Stone
there's Iron Stone gravels here and then
big big chunks of Iron Stone there's a
TENS I there was one this big what is
this this is what we call bog iron
orstein in in Europe it's it's a it's a
concentration of iron that's been
concentrated by
groundwater and uh the farmer had
decided had this drainage problem in the
field and had decided to deep rip it for
some reason and brought all these stuff
up from maybe a meter deep and you see
all this stuff you wouldn't normally see
and I went back and look at the soil map
and U the you have sort of two units
coming in here this is in the 1 to
50,000 soil map but neither of them say
anything about bog iron now this unit
here the the uh this one with the
stipples does talk about bands of iron
of thin bands of non-continuous iron
that might be precipitating through the
spodic Horizon so you'd have a nice very
fine sand spodic Horizon with little
lines of iron but nothing about this
groundwater iron so this is definitely
wrong uh I don't know if the original
surveyor didn't dig that deep or what
but you see the soil type is quite a bit
here and so this is something that I
would if they were the if the mapping
project were active I would say here was
my point here's the photo figure out
what's going on and then they would be
presumably be reinterpreting the
landscape you also see here that the
Dutch don't think there are any soils in
urban areas so they're way behind other
European colleages the French and
Germans especially even the US so okay
here's an idea that came from Steve
carile and we worked it out a bit uh and
the idea is you'd have a map a project
called improve your soil survey and the
idea is you would the citizens access
the online map which you can always do
now anyway I'll show you that and
displaying it on their smartphone or
tablet and then they can check the soil
description that they see there with
what they're seeing on the ground and
they can then report things that don't
seem to match um certainly things on the
surface course fragments or Texture
things like that you can easily see uh
and if there's any discrepancies they
could either confirm or they could send
in they say went here and the idea here
is the professional surveyors in the
nrcs in the case of the US would review
this and here's actually an example from
Newfield uh this is a published soil
survey map which is online I I printed
it out very nicely uh this is all from
the our nrcs and I can print out the map
and show it on the on the on the the
background this is up on Irish Hill Road
in Newfield um you can also use I really
recommend this location at the
California soil resource lab they've
taken the whole Sergo database and
they've made it into something we'll
just show on Google Earth it's super
cool so you can show the soil map on
Google Earth you can see the perspective
and it's a really nice job and you'll
see they did a good job also in soil
survey so here's this area and if you
click on it you will see it's a Valia
Channer silt loone you will see a modal
profile and if you click on this you'll
get all the uh all the descriptions of
this but you'll see that this shows the
modal profile going down to almost 2
meters in the valua but when you get
there some of you may know this spot
this is a na the natural the Green
Springs natural Cemetery up on Irish
Hill Road uh just before the arnet
forest and when you get up there
you will see that there's no way the
soil is this deep and it's very
consistent in fact if you look at their
website and they ask one of the faq's is
can I dig my own grave or my own
relative grave because that would be a
really nice thing to do I could you know
it's very natural they say no because
after you get to about a meter you are
going to be stuck by this we need a back
ho because you are not going to be
digging this stuff out down to 2 m um so
they're clear on that and if you go and
look at any of these Graves that are
open you see here's the pile and huge
numbers of rocks have been excavated so
clearly uh the depth to the Bedrock here
is much shallower than mapped and I
think the solution here if if you would
uh if this nrcs would look at this would
be to re remap that I think the whole
everything they're calling the valua
there is is is probably not it's it's
because it's much much shallower and
there's another soil series I think well
it's not
what is it
Jonathan it's not it's not the Arn it's
the wetter it's the one it's the it's in
the arnet sequence but it's it's a
shallow is aret but it's it's the next
wetter
one yeah yeah so they could yeah no this
would be it's like arnet it's like arnet
but it's a little bit it's the little
one range class wetter but anyway the
Lords toown there would be remapped as
arnet and and I think the reason they
did this is when in the in the old days
when they when they mapped the counties
they didn't want to have too many soil
Series so if they had only a small area
of one series they'd correlate it to
another so these mappers May well have
known it was shallower because arnut is
mapped uh arnut series is mapped a lot
in the arnut forest and in in uh and in
in Shamong County for example but not
here because it's still Tomkins County
anyway okay almost finished here uh now
let's get to the more difficult part
which is the protocol guided
information this is much more difficult
than the opportunistic observation
uh you have to have a protocol you have
to get the uh observers you have to
train them and the quality control
though makes this a much more consistent
observation that you could really use
directly
um you need a protocol that's first off
safe that's a very important thing you
can't ask someone to do something unsafe
digging a deep pit maybe it'll fall in
on them or something like that or they
can make pull their back out digging you
know I various things you really have to
think about this we're professionals
we're all covered by well some of us are
covered by Cornell health insurance
others not I still have Dutch okay
anyway but um you have all this this is
all very fine but then I guess my
question here when you have this
protocol division you're asking them to
to get training and and to follow a
protocol and and really what's the
motivation for them there it's a little
bit unclear for me to see what that
would be um to be like being in the
volunteer fire department there's a lot
of training involved but the motivation
is clear you're you know you're helping
your community you're working in a nice
team and so there's a reason you go
through all this
training here's what they did in opal
and they have a 16-page field book just
for the earthworms they teach the kids
how to do this it's very nice but this
is the kind of material you would need
to develop this level of material if you
want a really consistent they have this
they have this survey step they you have
to measure a 20x 20 M square cenm square
and you have to do things just right so
the Sur surve is really consistent so
that's why they have high quality
data uh physical samples could be
submitted for analysis but I'm a little
reluctant about that because all of
these issues here finding a
representative site preparing the site
you know the surface soil sampling it
putting in the bag all that I just find
is uh probably uh maybe a bit
difficult the last thing I think is the
Precision Agriculture and this is
something that I thought about I don't
this is really citizen science as such
because the farmer the farmer is a
citizen of course but I think the
problem here is U there's a lot I mean a
lot has been done on this but I think
most of this data ends up being
proprietary that farmers do not want to
release this there might be a way to say
we will use your data to help us improve
our map but we won't show your data
directly there might be a ways to do
that but again this would take some time
to convince people okay okay so these
are my
conclusions we think that we could
increase our spatio temporal density
somehow with this so less glamorous but
there is a community of people us we
hope who like it um and maybe we were
we're imp you know we're very attractive
now our environmental science major more
and more people are interested in
environment and agriculture which is
good and maybe our numbers are
increasing so then the last thing is
that the citizen science relation we
have to think very closely about the
culture thank you this is me and one of
my
co-authors this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu