this is a production of Cornell
University thank you for inviting me to
talk today um I'll just give you a
little bit of background history so
branching out is the IPM newsletter for
trees and shrubs and it covers insects
and diseases of Woody plants so we
publish every two weeks from April
through June and every three weeks from
July through September so we Tred to
provide um timely information on all
aspects of Pest Management um on Woody
ornamentals the newsletter itself was
started by Dr George hudler in the Plant
Pathology Department at Cornell in 1994
as a master's project for one of his
graduate students um I came on board in
July of
1996 and for those of you who can do
math yes that is 20
years of writing branching out so um and
so you may have heard that George has
retired in January of this year but um
he is still working with me on the
branching out newsletter as the
co-editor and he says he will continue
to do that for as long as I'd like to
continue to do it
so um our target audience for the
newsletter is treat care uh
professionals so arborist and Golf
Course superintendent and urban
Foresters and that sort and and our goal
is to inform these pest managers on the
progress of insect and my diseases on
Woody ornamentals in uh the New York
state area and to a lesser degree we
cover uh concurrences of symptoms of
non-infectious plant problems too such
as freezing injury and winter drying and
drought so the way we do it was We
Gather all this information by a
combination of on-site scouting and
reports from other contributors to help
us prepare the articles about the um
pest so um and We Gather the all the
observations and we prepare them into a
uh commentary about the subsequent life
stages of the pest and then scouting
tips that might be helpful and um
preventative or Curative actions and
management Alternatives as well what do
is I drive down I have a mix of
different places that I go so I I drive
downstate to um Long Island and I visit
various sites and the County Extension
offices then I return back to itha and
but along the Route I make uh
predetermined stops at Orange
Westchester and NASA counties on each of
our trips so so this is our one of our
stops we stop at the at Farmingdale
College in Nassau County well I'm also I
also stop at hofra University when I'm
down there and planting fields are bitum
as well so it's not too terrible
Planting Fields you may recognize that's
a very famous uh site that's often taken
uh photos of at Planting
Fields um and then one of the other
sites we stop at was we I go to a
cemetery in Westchester County scouting
in the cemetery um some cemeteries are
very Barren but this particular one has
a nice mix of uh trees and shrubs and uh
luckily they don't treat anything so
that's good for me another day of the
week I go to the western part of New
York State I go to fingerlakes Community
College which has a nice little
Arboretum there and that's in Wayne
County and then I also go to uh Highland
Park in Monroe
County so and I revisit these specific
sites in this the state so that's the
same sites all the time so I have an
idea of what I'm looking for each spot
but um you know I get surprises all the
time you just keep an eye out for things
that aren't looking good if a little off
color u a little Browning or something
and or you know sometimes I'm looking
and I'm seeing a lot of maybe um ants or
flies or something and I'm like oh
there's a lot of honeydew over there
what's happening with that plant so um
so by revisiting these specific sites
and doing the on-site scouting I can
keep a good you know monitoring those
pest populations on a regular basis and
can keep a good eye out for that um and
then we then I also have several sites
in the itha area that I Scout on
including my own property which is an
abandoned Christmas tree farm so when my
husband and I bought that property eight
years ago um George asked me if we had
paid extra because of all the great
diseases I told him that we have on our
property so he was thrilled to hear that
we had a nice infection of pine pine G
rust and white pine blister rust and um
variety of other nice Conifer diseases
and insects as well I pretty much we
could do a scouting uh trip right to my
property so in addition to my own onsite
scouting I also have Cornell Cooperative
Extension agents that uh and some arur
that help contribute observations for
The Scouting Report section as well and
that helps kind of give a nice little
snapshot of pest populations in the
entire State at any given time so that's
that's how it's done so the newsletter
itself in each issue we in addition to
the scouting report we include a feature
article and that gives us an opportunity
to address a particular pest or other
topic in more detail than we can can in
the other columns
so uh in the last several years we've
been able to upgrade and include color
photos and the scouting reports as well
as the feature article thanks to some
generous donations from um arborist and
such and we also include Growing Degree
Days and phology in each
issue and we try to keep the the text
pretty easy to read and just the right
length to cover each topic we know the
um Tree Care Professionals out there are
really busy and they're just looking for
a quick snapshot they need to know what
do they need to look for this week you
know they don't they don't have a lot of
time to uh you know read a ton of text
and so we try to boil it down to just
the essentials okay this is what they
need and um they can just look at that
or share with their staff and go right
out there and use that information so
um let's see one of the things this
season we hope to do is something new
George would like to make some videos
which uh then we would link from a QR
code that we would include in the
newsletter so if any of you know George
you know that he's quite the
Entertainer this is Jen um I do want did
want to say that we take those those
Center folds so whatever you call them
and we post them in our our Diagnostic
lab they're great reading uh so when
volunte have you know a little bit of
time um they can peruse that you know
and it's very helpful because I think
that what comes in often reflects that
uh that that list so yeah that's what
we're kind of hoping is that's a
reflection of what's going on out there
and so and we and we go downstate um to
scout because really they're often a
week or more ahead of the the rest of
New York State especially up here in
central New York or a little F farther
north so we know it's it's well worth
our time to go down there and to get
that scouting information because
they're a bit ahead so often what we'll
see last week in Long Island is just
happening this week and uh and you know
Parts farther north than New York
State okay so here's a just quick look
at our website pretty simple basic but
it's got information um so about
subscription information you can also
look at back issues if you're not
familiar with the uh newsletter we've
got back issues
here uh idea of what the newsletter
includes it's that branching out
self-supporting through subscription
charges and donations and the normal
charge for the subscription is is $50
but as Cornell Cooperative Extension
Educators you can get the electronic
access to branching out for no charge so
you just have to send me an email and um
you can do that through the contact us
my email address is on there you can
send us an email and I would email you
the password information You' need for
the 2016 season and it changes every
year um and if you know if you if you're
willing to uh help spread the word about
branching out we can provide you with
subscription forms so you can have
available at your county offices to uh
share with to bring to the attention of
tre Care Professionals in your county so
right now we have about 400 subscribers
including some big names like the
Smithsonian and Longwood Gardens and pul
Smith's college um and they the majority
of our readers are from New York State
or the New England states but we have a
handful from other States including Ohio
and Michigan and Illinois in addition to
the newsletter we also published a book
so it's a 150 updated feature articles
it's about 300 Page book and that is $35
which is to kind of finish up I think
think some of the uh things that we were
really noticing this season that seem
some of the highlights are uh winter
injury we're seeing a lot of desiccation
on Spruce and true Furs this spring so
we had a nice article in the last um
issue and issue number three Sandra
Jensen from the Diagnostic lab wrote a
nice article all about the um
desiccation on conifers and so that we
are getting a bunch of questions on and
uh right now what we're seeing out in
the field is uh this is a Time season
for different rusts to be sporulating so
there's lots of Cedar rust are out there
and their full glory and white pine
blister R Us is kind of just finishing
up but we've got pine pine G Rus coming
and um from Don Gable down in uh the
botanic garden in New York said that he
thinks it's going to be a banner year
for or Cedar rust from what he was
seeing
so and then um the other interesting
tidbit was we got a report from um Long
Island that boxwood Leaf Miner was
emerging rather early this year so it's
it's really a couple weeks earlier than
we expected but it came from a very
reliable source and he even saw the
pupil cases so we're sure that he knows
what he's saying but so we um so I had a
conversation with Dan gillery and we
were both surprised that it was coming
out a little early but we so we've
included that in this week's scouting
report and that's the sort of stuff that
we like to put in things that are you
know maybe slightly unusual and and so
we do welcome anything that's um you
know happening in your county we'd love
to hear any information especially if
you've got outbreak situation of
something um we'd like to share that
with our readers so they know what's
going on in the state and it's nice for
us because we can't be everywhere though
I Scout in many places it's really just
a snapshot in time and um I can't I
can't go to all the sites in New York
state but so anything that if you know
if you're want if you'd like to share
with us we'd be uh willing to take any
information that um you have to share so
and I'm sure you've all seen the
problems with blue
spruce that continue
there are no there's no one answer
unfortunately on that one but so we're
we're kind of keeping an eye on seeing
what's happening with the the blue
spruce this season it's been kind of a a
problem for the last couple of years I
know many of you have seen that as well
and and we're seeing down in the lower
Hudson Valley a lot more is it Spruce
budall mge um then I suspect we've been
seeing it for a while and we didn't know
what we were looking at we were finding
all kinds of other things as well and
that was good enough you know what I
mean in a sense you're saying oh it's
got this and it's got that now that
we're looking for it we're finding it in
a lot of spruce samples Norway spruce
okay yeah yeah we you know we've put a
little bit of information about that in
the newsletter a couple for the last
couple of years Dan Gil's been very
helpful with that thank
you this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu