this is a production of Cornell
University hi this is Frank Rossy for
the Cornell turf grass video log and
this week we're talking about mowing now
in the springtime you get that surge of
growth because we know about 60 to 70%
of all the clippings produced for the
entire season are produced in the first
6 weeks of the growing season so it's
very typical that we're going to mow
more in the spring now for those of you
striving for a more sustainable approach
to your lawn maybe you're going to cut
back on mowing a little bit and so what
happens is you're left to have to cut
the grass when it's really high now of
course we don't want clippings clumping
up everywhere as that can be a problem
from a light shading of the turf so it
might be worthwhile to just sort of SC
scratch them around set the mower as
high as you can try to mow slowly so
that you're Distributing the clippings
and most importantly make sure you're
mowing when it's dry that'll allow for
the clippings to disperse and in the end
you may find if you just Skip One mowing
per month you're cutting your mowing 25%
for the entire year and that can have a
real benefit on fuel expenses as well as
improving the carbon emissions in the
environment thanks for joining me for
the Cornell turf grass video log this
has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu