this is a production of Cornell
University as johannas mentioned I've
been here for five years doing my PhD
and um this is sort of the culmination
of those five years and for the last
five years I've been working in looking
at biochar systems specifically at um
small cook Stow systems um in Kenya and
more specifically in this talk I'm going
to be talking about what happens to the
carbon and nitrogen within those systems
so just to give you a brief um look at
what I I've been doing um this is how
typically a cook stove system or
household Energy System can look in
Kenya where I've been working where we
have a traditional stove there is a lot
of wood Gathering From the trees to
combust in an O three stone fire which
is totally open air and there is a lot
of greenhouse gases and air pollutants
that are constantly going and being
emitted into the environment however if
we were to introduce a biochar cook
stove or I might actually call it a
pyrolysis stove throughout the course of
the talk um this system might look
totally different one of the main things
of this system is that um we are now
using um biomass residues or plant
residues and these are being used in
this pyrolysis stove um which I'll later
go into explaining how it works and it
still emits greenhouse gases and air
pollutants but those are going to be a
lot less and in this talk I'm going to
be um looking at um um nitrogen and
carbon
emissions um now you would ask well
where is this feed stock coming well
that's the chapter I'm not talking about
um today this is part of the the the
Dynamics that I look at but I'm not
going to be talking about today so today
I'll be talking about the biochar
production
with the stoves and then afterwards once
you have that biochar what happens to
the biochar when you actually want to
use it and put it back into soil and
what I'm going to be specifically
looking at is what happens to that
nitrogen in the plant residues um that
was not emitted into the air but
remained in the
biochar so to do this um I actually um
have a series of things that did and we
start with the initial residue n um and
we pyed these plant residues and I'm
going to be looking at the gashes CNN
losses um thereafter I took the biochar
and I um characterized it and
um we we realized that there was a
biochar enrichment and and and there was
and we want to look at how why there was
a uh a a nitrogen enrichment in the
biochar um we also look at different
parts of the biochar we actually
fractionated the biochar we extracted
some components from it and so we ended
up with some volatiles or what we call
volatiles but they're tan extracted
volatiles so take that in mind and then
we remained with also the extracted
biochar we wanted to see how those look
and finally in an incubation experiment
I look at the stability of it I look at
what happens to the carbon and nitrogen
how does the nitrogen actually affect
the carbon
stability um so just again um a little
bit uh of of the three things that I'm
going to talk about the influence of
small pyrolysis cook stoves um systems
on on gaseous C and N emissions the
characterization of the organic nitrogen
in biochar and the nitrogen's um role on
BioTrust
stability so moving right along let's
look at what happens when you have um a
a system where you have introduced a a a
biochar stove or a paralysis stove and
as you can see here we have this woman
that I actually did some research with
in Kenya and she's using one of our
stoves um to cook and and we are
actually measuring the emissions um that
are coming out of the
stove so the main thing to remember here
is that when you actually have the
original system the three F the three
stor fire there is carbon and nitrogen
oxidation and generally speaking what
happens is that there's not enough
oxygen in this process um to combust
fully the carbon and so what happens is
you have a lack of sto stoat air um
incomplete combustion and you have a lot
of carbon monoxide coming out um what
the features of of of the system or of
the stove actually affect is the amount
of oxygen the mixing of the oxygen with
the gases and also the time temper of
combustion actually affects those things
and then in nitrogen oxidation there
those things also happen um the um
oxygen mixing and temperature are part
of um the the variables that affect n no
emissions but more specifically we
wanted to look at what happens with the
nitrogen in the biomass what actually is
the effect of the nitrogen in the
biomass in the subsequent emissions that
we're going to see from the stove um and
in this specific case what we're looking
for is the still this geometry but also
the fuel con the fuel and
concentration um and why do we care like
why why would we even care to look at
these things well
from from from a from a climate change
perspective we all know emissions are
bad you know they affect um the
greenhouse gases in the environment but
I think that more importantly there's
actually an aspect to this which is
human health which is which Co actually
leads to 3.5 or sorry not Co indoor air
pollution actually which includes Co
leads to 3.5 million deaths worldwide
each year and that's actually a really
big deal so if you want to look at the
bigger picture that is why we're also
like trying to see how you can change
the Dynamics from combustion um to maybe
introducing a paralysis doove and see
what happens and also Africa in general
has 20% Global emissions of Co and nox
and now more importantly as wood um
stocks actually diminish in a lot of
these parts more and more people are
using higher nitrogen content plant
residues for cooking and that actually
has also some um implications in
emissions so our main objectives
initially were to measure the overall
performance of a paralysis cook stove
and compare those to the international
um standard organization cook stove
parameters um and also to understand the
mechanisms by which Co and no emissions
are formed in the paralysis stove and to
do this we designed a stove um which I
didn't um some um originally a an
engineer from um India did and we've
we've taken this this this um design um
on and and improved it from my masters
onto my dissertation and mechanical
engineers have worked with us for that
um but just to give you a little uh
brief uh brief
explanation inside here is actually a
pyrolysis chamber and this is the
pyrolysis chamber right over here where
you actually would put biomass and that
pyrolysis chamber is partially sealed so
it does not see as much it does not
actually have access to as much oxygen
and then in the middle over here we
actually have a combustion chamber which
you still have to feed some wood into
and the um the combustion chamber
actually is what generates the initial
heat both for the cooking and also for
the paralysis of the biomass however as
this biomass in the pyrolysis chamber
starts devolatilizing the gases come
into the combustion chamber and are
ignited so what happens is you kind of
switch over into using more of the fuel
from the from the volatiles that are
coming out from the pyrolysis chamber
and consequently what happens is you
have both the wood and the volatiles or
the gas from the pyrolysis forming part
of the flame that actually is um
generating heat for cooking um we
measured these emissions and the
performance of the stove in our lab um
just so we could have a standardized way
of comparing our stove to other stoves
in in that that are that are potentially
um available to make biochar as well and
this is our this is our system we have a
hood that was designed I bu some
students and we have the the the stove
in there um we use two different types
of biomass um to represent high and low
nitrogen um switch Gra pellets to be the
high nitrogen and hardwood pallets um to
be the low nitrogen uh content and we
use pellets just to keep the uniformity
of the of the of the biomass and not
introduce that as a variable um we did a
water boiling test which is sort of a
traditional way of measuring the
efficiency of or the performance of
stoves and basically what you do is you
boil water that is it but what you do is
while you're boiling water a specific
amount of water you are actually
measuring emissions temperature fuel use
and so on and so forth however this
stove um perform um operates a little
bit differently than your regular
combustion stove and we had to actually
to modify the the the original um test
and the only difference is that
generally you extinguish the this the
stove halfway once the the water boils
and in this case we did not in this case
we just Contin Contin to change um the
pots of water till the pyrolysis had
actually um been done so like till all
the fuel was used um and we were able to
measure real-time pyrolysis fuel loss
and fuel consumption and when I say fuel
consumption I'm referring to Wood fuel
consumption and we were measuring with a
real time um real time instantane or
instantaneous um gas emissions with a
gas analyzer herba to PG
um and right into the results so what
I'm going to show you first is what
traditionally everybody shows you I have
my stove in this case it's the pyrolysis
stove these are wood or wood pellets the
wood the wp is wood pellets and these
are three metrics that are not normally
used to measure what happens with
overall stove performance specifically
this one has to do with with um sort of
energy use um so it's co G per megga of
dry fuel used um Co in grams per minute
that's a rate of grams of of amount of
Co emitted and that's actually used as
an indicator for health and then the
modifi combustion efficiency which is
actually used to determine whether your
stove is actually combusting properly
the products that um the gases products
so if you have a high combustion
efficiency see your stove is performing
fairly well um and as you can see here's
the three stone fire the pyrolysis stove
of our study and then these are all
similar stoves in terms of what they
claim to do so some of them perform
these are more gasifiers but they do
claim to make biochar and they do they
do tend to operate in similar fashion so
we decided to compare them and the tier
ranking here
is um the standards the is the ISO
standards that I talked about where
basically they have set some standards
to see if your stove is performing
properly or not one being a poor
performance and four being the most
Optimum performance and for each of
these there might be individual rankings
so you you actually rank them
individually and tier one for Co it's
above 097 Grand per minute and tier four
is um less than 42 grams per minute and
as you can see fortunately enough our
stove actually performs fairly well in
that area and it also when compared to
um the three stone fire although it
doesn't perform as well as the stove
Tech teide which is actually the highest
performing stove that is out there right
now in terms of um emissions and that
also can actually um make paralysis but
you can see that we're actually in a
Range that is favorable for us and
that's great that's actually a really
good deal and then as far as nitrogen
because I said I was going to talk about
nitrogen too um we want to look at the
overall no emissions that we um got from
the stove and in this particular case
there isn't a lot of studies that
actually look at nitrogen emissions or
no emissions um from stoves because they
don't deem them as important as they are
and I don't have anything to compare
immediately but here what we wanted to
show is that as you have more nitrogen
in the fuel so in the x axis we have
nitrogen and in the content and in the y
axis we have n o you can see that as you
have more nitrogen you have more no
Evolution from the stove and so that was
sort of a given to us that that might
happen but there was a problem we we
weren't satisfied with those results so
you tell people great my stove performs
properly but what does that mean what
does that actually mean for the person
that's using the stove what does that
mean really in the context of how things
are evolving within the stove so then we
looked at answering two more questions
what are the key processes affecting the
formation of Co and no emissions in the
pyrolysis stove and we hypothesized that
there were the rate of fuel consumption
would consumption the rate of pyrolysis
fuel consumption and also the
temperature and that they would all be
positive Co correlated with um Co and no
emissions and the higher the nitrogen
imp plant residues it would lead to more
no production the other thing that we
wanted to look is well how does
paralysis affect the partitioning of N
and so we thought that most of it would
actually be going into the gas and I'm
going to show the results of that so in
order to actually look at the Dynamics
of what's happening with the emissions
you actually need to look at the
instantaneous emissions because that's
really what's meaningful here
and I'm if you look at over here in this
chart to the right hand side we have
time in the x-axis and N in grams per
second so the rate of production of
nitrogen um oxide you can see that the
higher the nitrogen you have the higher
the N you have so that sort of tells us
you know the same thing the same picture
as the prior um graph that I showed
you however when you look at Co which
looks so good in that table that we were
looking when you look at the peak levels
of Co in this graph this is 3.62 grams
per minute at the highest and over here
at the second highest maybe or around
there or the second Peak um um it's 2.1
grams per minute and what this means is
that we're actually um quite higher on
the the Dynamics of the co for um
evolving from the stove is actually high
and that actually has implications for
for exposures to human health people
that are exposed to that level of Co at
one particular time it actually can have
consequences on them so these are the
things that we want to look at
instantaneous emissions to be able to um
remediate later
on um now we wanted to also look at what
parameters of the stove or what
parameters of the chemistry um that were
happening inside the stove actually um
predicted these two variables so the
rate of production of o and n o and what
we actually found out is that the rate
of fuel consumption of the pyrolysis um
um fuel was actually
predominantly um uh
um influencing what was happening the
two emissions so here um overwhelming
overwhelmingly um C uh pyrolysis rate
was
actually um so fast that it doesn't
allow for proper mixing with the oxygen
and combustion of the co so then you
have a lot of Co forming and wood has
some contribution to that as well and
then when you look at the nitrogen
emissions um instead of being only the
nitrogen content it's actually the rate
at which the nitrogen is evolving
through the course of pyrolysis that
actually matters and also the
temperature at which the pyrolysis is
happening is is influencing the rate at
which the nitrogen is coming out of that
stove so that's really important because
those parameters are then later used to
go back and redesign or fix some things
of the stove that we would need to so we
can address these
situations um and
finally um we wanted to see well so we
know that we have an O coming out of the
of the of the stove but we also want to
know what proportion of that nitrogen
that's coming out is actually no o or
other species and and um these are the
three fuels that I actually used and I
know that I mentioned two before but we
had two of them that were um slightly
different in nitrogen of the hard woods
so we separated those and then here we
have fraction of the total nitrogen that
went actually into the stove and so
overwhelmingly the majority of the of
the of the nitrogen actually remains in
the Char and so um about 50% of it
remains in the Char and 10% of it is
only no the only issue is that we didn't
measure all the nitrogen species that
could be coming out of the out of the
stove so this is the other nend species
and that also accounts for about 40% of
the nitrogen so if we want to know the
overall n nitrogen budget we would have
to go back and measure those but for
this study we were measuring no o um and
so moving forward we once we have this
nitrogen in the biochar we want to see
well what does that mean why did it
remain there and to do so we actually
decided to look
at the forms of nitrogen that were
actually in the original biomass in the
biochar and look at the nitrogen um and
how it was formed with different
pyrolysis temperatures so we did this
using nitrogen kedge um NEX has
spectoscopy
and there were some interesting findings
um now why did we also do this it's
because like I said we we found that a
lot of the nitrogen was remaining in the
biochar so why is why is all that
nitrogen remaining and one of the things
is that one of the theories that we have
is that it's being incorporated into
heter istic like um compounds and a lot
of people have also said that that could
be true but um not they haven't really
been able to parcel out exactly what
kind of nitrogen and what the formation
of that nitrogen is with
temperature um so this is like I said
like the this is what led us to to look
at what type of what type of um Dynamics
was happening with the nitrogen in the
biochar because as temperature increases
we have a a enrichment of that nitrogen
and there's a Tipping Point after 350 in
this particular case we see that the
amount of nitrogen in the biochar is
actually diminishing but there's another
interesting qu um thing here and it's
that when you look at the low nitrogen
there is actually a much steeper um
enrichment there's a lot larger
enrichment in nitrogen um low nitrogen
containing biomass than there would be
if you had high nitrogen containing the
IMs so that actually led to
hypothesizing what could be happening
with the original nitrogen in the
biomass and so if we start with some
very nicely easily aliphatic um
compounds of nitrogen and then we
subject it to um higher temperatures
what we start seeing is that there are
either condensation there is lost of
water there is formation of cyclic rings
and so on and so forth as as carbon is
lost nitrogen gets more and more um
aromatic or
recalcitrant um and in this case it's a
little bit different it's more the
removal well it's also the removal of
water and and Co but oxygen being
removed can be can lead
to
uh aromatic nitrogen or um triple Bonds
in Nitro which are also very strong
bonds and so in order to um given this
we we decided to look at the following
questions and we decided to look at how
does pyrolysis temperature actually
affect the different forms of nitrogen
being formed and with increasing
paralysis temperature it will lead more
to to more stable forms of nitrogen so
stable I mean aromatic um and we had
another question which is can the amount
of nitrogen actually um in the biomass
lead to more formation of heterocycles
and the hypothesis being that increasing
amounts of nitrogen can lead to to more
and more um heterocycle aromatic
nitrogen um to do this study I grew
biomass at different levels of nitrogen
so everything was the same except the
nitrogen that we were actually um
fertilizing with we did uh Woody biomass
uh crop residue and grass and we pyed
them at three different temperatures 350
5700 and like as I mentioned before I
did a socks construction um to remove
the with holline to remove the
condensible
volatiles um we went to CLS which was
really cool and I totally geeked out and
use the syncron over there and um we so
this is um nitrogen um x-ray nitrogen
spectroscopy and what you need to take
away from this through the rest of when
I carry when I talk about my data is
that the energy level of the absorbing
atom actually decreases or increases
depending on the atoms that are adjacent
to it so whether it's carbon the
nitrogen uh the energy level decreases
if it's oxygen the uh energy level
increases and that should be sort of the
the way that I'm going to be explaining
what happened um and so this is one of
the many graphs that I have of the of my
of my um data but these are maze leaves
and these are low nitrogen I actually
have the pair of each of these which is
high nitrogen but you can't really see a
different in the squiggly lines and what
you're going to see here is all the
materials these are the the plant
residues the biochar and the
volatiles and first and foremost I'm
going to talk about the plant residues
and just so you know I didn't just like
make these up I actually de convoluted
those so I went through a very rigorous
process of two years of deconvoluting my
Spectra and this is what I have come out
with and what you need to look at is
that in biomass specifically which we're
looking at here the majority of this um
biomass it's actually aromatic um five
membered rings whether it's in whether
it has one or two nitrogens and this was
sort of surprising because the majority
of the people predict that it's amino
acids proteins well guess what amino
acids and proteins have heterocyclic
nitrogen so us finding this
actually is not that um
surprising um but overwhelmingly 50% of
biomass is actually um five membered
rings and probably due to some amino
acids that are constituents of the
biomass um now when we look at the
biochar what you're going to see is that
there has been a shift of energy so this
was the main peak in the biochar this in
the biomass this 401 .41 and as you can
see there's nothing there anymore but
now we have a new Peak at
398.36 membered rings and so not only do
we have this new Peak but as we move um
in increasing temperature which is
happening here we actually have a shift
to a lower um energy level so there's
more carbon surrounding that nitrogen um
atom those absorbing atoms most likely
so that was also very interesting and
not only that but we were also we
identified a nitrogen form that wasn't
quite or a nitrogen Peak specifically an
energy um that
wasn't explained in the literature
before so we are treating that guy as
sort of a little bit different because
it hasn't been described before so it
tends to to follow the the the trend
with biochar and pyrolysis temperature
and then finally when we look at um the
volatiles which are these and these are
volatiles and increasing temperature as
well so these are what we extracted from
the original biochar we see that that
398 Peak doesn't actually exist there
however we actually have this little
Peak over here which I didn't um um
label but it's at 4.74 which is actually
a cyclic um nitrogen and that cyclic
nitrogen tends to be very
um
um dis it actually it it's very common
for as a byproduct of paralysis um of
volatiles in the literature it's been
described as a byproduct for um um break
breakdowns of volatiles so it's actually
a distinctive from the biart and from
the boms so that is allowed us to
identify these different um components
of the biochar and in like I said in
this case
cyclic is one of the one of the um forms
of nitrogen that shows up but
overwhelmingly again the aromatic five
ring is what actually predominates in
the in the biomass in the volatiles
sorry um
so what does that all mean so what we
wanted to look at is who is being
affected or what is being affected with
um temperature and here in the in the
x-axis I have temperature and in the y
axis I have um two different functional
groups or what we are calling two
different functional groups in this case
the aromatic Six Ring um nitrogen and
that's percent of total that's that one
nitrogen um energy resonance level that
I've told you that hasn't described and
these are all the other aromatic
six-membered rings that um functional
groups and what we're seeing is that
with increasing temperature we actually
have an aold increase of that particular
nitrogen that um that we were looking at
that's six member ring and in the other
case what's happening is that all the
other um six-membered rings are actually
decreasing and they decrease by
half
now
um we also wanted to look at we we we
also looked at what happened with the
nitrogen level and fortunately enough we
actually found as well that as nitrogen
content increase which is in the x- axis
the total aromatic or the total heteros
in the chart actually increase and this
actually made sense because if you have
more nitrogen then you actually can
overcome that activation energy that you
need to make another to to make a bond
that's a lot stronger so you satisfy the
easier bonds and then you proceed to
make like a lot um harder bonds or bonds
that are more energetically
um uh that are that they require more
energy and on the other hand if you
actually have more nitrogen then easier
Bond um um or nitrogen bonded to
aromatics which are nitrogen which is
out of a cyclic ring then actually
diminish and that also makes
sense because of the same reason you
actually satisfy the amount of um
nitrogens that you can actually um
um uh nitrogen bonds that you can make
and then thereafter you cannot make
anymore so that was actually really
interesting because this is only
described in the literature once um
prior and it was a long time ago so this
is really cool to see again um so now
finally really
quick why do we care about the form of
nitrogen and so that leads to the last
part of my of my dissertation and it's
because we hypothesize that um if you
have more
nitrogen um then maybe the nitrogen is
actually maybe that makes um biochar
less stable but is it really and so we
all know that CN is used as a measure of
um of for biomass decomposing but is it
actually something that we can use for
biochar as well is it a metric that's
useful and um our hypothesis is that no
that it's not it is not a useful metric
um to measure the stability of of n of
biochar specifically um we actually
looked at what is the stability uh the
the Char look like does it increase or
decrease with nitrogen and also do any
of these forms of nitrogen that I just
talked about actually are responsible
for comparing some of the stability to
the
biochar and for that I did a
mineralization study with biochar only
and sand only um I took two of the
biochars and the plant residues um
without charring and I incubated those
at 30 um degrees C and I measured
respiration rates for CO2 and nitrogen
mineralization um for a very very long
time 200 days or so and this is what um
the resulting um cumulative
mineralization was in the upper graph we
have just the biomass in low nitrogen
and light n High nitrogen and when I
talk about low nitrogen think
about .5% and then when I talk about
high nitrogen think about 2% or higher
or 1 5% or higher there um about there
um and in the lower part we have the
biochars at 350 low and high at 700 low
and high and what we can see is that
overwhelmingly there is a lot more
mineralization of the carbon in the
biomass and a lot less in the biochars
and there are differences between the
biochars in terms of whether you have
more or less nitrogen but when we look
at the total commu uh Comm
cumulative um SE mineralization of all
these materials what we see is that
while the mineralization as the CN ratio
increases actually decreases for the for
the biomass and it is statistically
significant there are no differences
between the two biochars so there is
actually no meaning or not it's not as
meaningful to to use CN um to determine
the the stability of of
Char um and here's what happened with
nitrogen um basically nitrogen was
immobilized during the course of our
study and that might have been LED not
only to the fact that the nitrogen was
in a different form but we also weren't
providing any other sources of nitrogen
so the nitrogen that was available was
um
immobilized now this is the final part
and the final part was well what is
conferring stability to the Chart other
than the carbon what what role does
nitrogen actually play in the stability
of biochar so we fractionated the
biochar right so we actually took the
the volatiles which we hypothesized
would be the most easily mineralizable
POS possibly um form of nitrogen in the
CH and we took the functional groups of
that um um group and we correlated those
against the mineralization of the
biochar and saw if there was any
correlations and there was um we were
able to predict using the the functional
groups of the volatiles 75% of the of
the mineralization that occurred in our
biochars and these three groups or
functional groups were responsible or
these three group forms of nitrogen were
responsible or had something to do with
the uh stability or mineralization in
this case we have the highly aromatic
six-member Rings which was negatively um
correlated with mineralization and even
though this is an
aromatic um structure we are actually
looking at the proportion of this type
of nitrogen so the single bonded
nitrogen um and so it kind of makes
sense that it would be positively
correlated and significant with
mineralization and then in this case we
just have a nitrogen outside of the of a
cycle which if we hypothesize well am I
going to go for the easy thing or the
difficult thing to chew on a microb
might actually go for the easier thing
so it also makes sense that it would
have been the nitrogen outside of the
ring that had
um cor positive correlation with um
mineralization of the
biochar so when we put this all together
what is all
mean
um like I said when we look at
biochar when we look at biochars we can
no longer look at biochar by itself we
need to look at a part as a whole and we
need to look at what happens when you're
making biochar and in this
case figuring out what the parameters
that are affecting the the figuring out
the parameters that are affecting the
gashes emission um Dynamics it's really
important because then that allows us to
go back to the drawing board and improve
in in in designs that are you know
ultimately being used by women in Africa
and currently they are being used in
some households so that's a really big
deal that we need to pay attention that
sure we're we're really really
interested in reducing Co and no and
retention of nitrogen in the biochar for
maybe climate um impacts but we are also
very interested in doing that to reduce
um um impact on human health and when it
comes down to to to what you do now with
the biochar that you have or what what
what these farmers do with the N with
the with the biochar that they have it's
really important to know what happens to
that nitrogen because if you have a
farmer that is going to take a high
nitrogen containing residue and turning
into biochar is did that really worth it
it is is is locking that nitrogen into
these highly aromatic structures worth
it for them and so that's those are the
kind of things that we need to be
thinking about when we actually think
about making biochar when we actually
think about introducing
stoves that are um um going to make
biochar what what are the overall
implications to the people in the system
to the users in the system and so you
know we know that that that it changes
um um and the type of nitrogen
stabilizes the carbon but we also want
to know what are the implications for
Farmers along the way that actually
using these these um
materials that's it thank
you
Marathon this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu