this is a production of Cornell
University so welcome everyone um I hope
this is recording well
online uh this is a conceptual panel for
the live handson energy Expo that
happens tomorrow out in the a quad um
and what we're featuring today is about
electrifying new YK York how efficiency
and electrification opportunities are
available to us today so the great thing
about efficiency electrification is it
improves air quality it reduces
greenhouse gases and it conserves New
York State's natural resources and
that's the idea behind this panel and
it's to also in conjunction with the
climate leadership and Community
protection act or the clcpa in 2019 to
reduce our emissions 40% by 2030 and 85%
by
2050 this is only an umbrella policy
right it's a goal planning policy
there's lots of other little policies
that need to be built up underneath it
and we all need to start thinking about
what kinds of policies we want to build
up we will hear about one such idea
later but to give us a sense on how much
we are emitting as a state the gross
emissions in 2020 well the New York
State emitted 350 million metric tons of
carbon dioxide equivalents in in 2020
but notably it was 15% lower than 1990
so part of our work is already done you
can see right here where our current
levels are we're 15% below now what I
want to stress here is even though my
specialty is in this orange bar for
agriculture the blue bar is what we all
need to tackle this is our energy
consumption in the state and most of our
emissions come from the building sector
and the transportation
sector and that is the theme today that
we're focusing on um how do we take care
of this majority of
emissions doing this in our community
means we have improved air quality right
lower asthma lower particulate matter
lower cancer lower greenhouse gases and
lower extreme weather events lower
insurance and future crises lower
instability for farmers who depend on
the weather and notably if we reduce our
energy demand we also reduce our Demand
on the rural Landscapes to support
renewable energy projects so for example
this morning we heard from our
colleagues Ted uh cotch and Peter
Woodberry that we need about 75 to
125,000 hectares to meet our solar goals
in
2050 right so everything we do to reduce
our energy
consumption also helps our land base so
I want to just talk some some words
because I realized I uh decarbonization
is very familiar to me and it just means
reducing or eliminating carbon from the
fossil fuel emissions from a sector so
it could be from any sector like
Transportation buildings or power
electrification means replacing
technologies that run on fossil fuels
with Alternatives that run more
efficiently on electricity it also means
generating all that electricity from
clean energy rather than fossil fuels
right and this is a key point because
whenever you think about electrification
right it could be made from a fossil
fuel so we're trying to connect that in
and weatherization Home Improvements
that reduce energy use and make homes
more comfortable these include things
like moisture control air sealing
ventilation upgrades to insulation doors
and
windows I now want to segue to the role
of extension when extension was made in
the 1800s 64% of our Workforce was in
farming today only 10% of our Workforce
is in farming
yet everything we do as Urban or rural
citizens to reduce our greenhouse gas
emissions helps current and Future
Farmers have a more stable environment
to grow our food current and future
citizens have less damage to homes and
shared infrastructure and our land bases
can serve for other uses reducing our
community emissions is defense for
Agriculture and Forestry and it's
something that everybody in this room
can
do so I just want us to look at the
Cooperative Extension passage of the
Smith lever act in 1914 and see how much
it resonates in
2024 Cooperative Agricultural Extension
work shall consist of the development of
practical applications of research
knowledge instruction and practical
demonstrations of existing or improved
practices and Technologies in
agriculture uses of solar energy in
1914 with respect to agriculture home
economics and Rural energy I just think
this is really key right because our
landscape has changed but our mission to
work on behalf of each other um is the
same just for some reference I love
showing this rural electrification
Administration posters from
1937 right as we were looking to
Electrify then how can we make posters
that make these things pable
today same thing here
so how can we brand efficiency and
electric electrification for our
Century I want to just take a moment we
weren't able to get Stephen winter
Associates to come and talk about their
multifamily retrofit playbooks but I
recommend them for everyone they have
different typologies and I'm going to
focus on a post-war four to seven
stories because that's my apartment
building in New York City you can find
these at be exchange.org
and what these do is they target several
areas lighting the building envelope
ventilation heating cooling and hot
water they then break down the
proportion of energy by Heating and hot
water right and then there are some
other smaller sources um but this helps
you start honing in on where your energy
use is and therefore probably where your
um greenhouse gases are and then it sets
recommendations these are available to
anyone but it helps you go from having
to retrofit your entire house and being
overwhelmed by it to honing in on the
highest priorities or the easiest things
to do first or most costeffective things
to do first and they have it for all
different kinds of building types not
just New York City building types and
the other point I want to stress here is
um that New York City their emissions
are predominantly buildings and so this
is also Rob we're not going to talk
about it today this is a huge objective
in New York City um and that each time
you do something you can see how you're
moving towards your goal of En energy
reduction and greenhouse gas mitigation
so to make this all real we have
coordinated an energy Expo for you all
tomorrow um open on the ad quad from
10:00 a. to 5:00 P pm and so far no rain
is scheduled um and also in the man
Library Foy year in the Foye is mostly
incentives and job opportunities and um
some displays and outside um it it's all
equipment uh to to Electrify your lives
you can see some Maple how to make maple
sugaring more efficient how to build
affordable storm windows understanding
window science explore electric tract
tractors skid steers and Sawmills learn
about Precision AG drone features find
incentives to weatherize your home
explore electric landscaping equipment
and understand the next generation of
greenhouse light
efficiency it's really real the whole
point is that it's real so come join
us okay our land is 61% forested I
always like to bring us into our space
61% forested 20% agriculture 133% idle
and we also need to think about how to
activate those idle lands right as
extension we work with homeowners or we
work with farmers or Foresters how many
times do we work with an idle or former
AG land owner we generally don't and we
need to activate those in order to think
about the big picture
here and the goal here is the highest
and best use I would argue we should
activate those Idol lands for solar so
that we can continue growing high
quality products on our Agland but
fundamentally everything we do to
conserve energy conserves both our
climate and our our land
area so here we are uh launching into
today's panelists you're first going to
hear from Gabriel Gurley from CCE
Tomkins about Farm Energy Efficiency
then we're going to hear from Ken about
electrifying landscaping equipment then
we'll hear from Josh about weatherizing
homes Danielle will then present on some
efficiency Pilots that she's been doing
and then uh hopefully it's all going to
work out but at 3:45 Moren Ley from New
York State Department of Environmental
Conservation will come in and talk about
the New York State cap and invest or
Nikki program that is coming forward as
a way to fund these kinds of projects
and more as we move this process
along okay so which piece of this pie
are you going to eat of because it is
tasty work we have in front of us
Gabriel come on up
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu