this is a production of Cornell
University um hi everyone I'm Danielle
Eisman and I work here at Cornell in the
public health program but outside of my
normal day job I also lead a working
group that focuses on manufactured
housing issues um among many of those
issues is the aspect of Energy
Efficiency so that is what I'm here to
talk to you all a little bit about
today um so just for a little bit of
context manufactured homes um nationally
they are the largest source of
unsubsidized affordable housing um which
is something that we often forget
there's also roughly across the United
States 22 million people that live in
manufactured homes um some of you may be
more familiar with the term mobile homes
but usually these homes although they
are often built in a factory and
transported once they are installed and
put in place they rarely ever move again
so the term of mobile home is is no
longer uh accurate so we now use the
term manufactured homes um and according
to New York State executive law
616 manufactured homes are defined as
single family dwellings um and they are
supposed to be allowed in residential
districts um the state leaves it up to
individual municipalities in terms of
the Zoning for manufactured homes and uh
once you start digging down into some of
the zoning policies they don't outright
ban manufactured homes in Municipal
districts um but some of the language
around it uh prevents the installation
of some of these homes and although they
are not um always perceived to be the
most desirable form of affordable
housing the the changes that we've seen
in the development of manufactured homes
has really um allowed homes that are
built in factories and then transported
to be a very affordable energy efficient
um environmentally friendly form of
providing housing options for folks and
we all know in New York state affordable
housing is uh part of a crisis that
we're experiencing nationally um but
also in New York state
um so again for a little bit more
context um in New York state there's
just under 200,000 manufactured homes um
that makes up 2.4% of the state's total
housing stock um in rural areas that
percentage increases up to over 10% um
here in Tomkins County we're at roughly
6% for the number of manufactured homes
um that make up the housing stock um
roughly a third of them are are in
manufactured housing communities or what
we used to call mobile home parks um and
New York state has roughly 1,800 of
these 48 of its um 60 in 48 of its 62
counties and we can see that uh Saratoga
Duchess and olster Counties have the
highest concentration of manufactured
housing communities as well as
manufactured homes um although as I've
encountered with many of my students
very few people actually notice them um
so I don't know if anybody has driven
past a few of the communities just
outside of Ithaca um but they're they're
frequently ignored um and what we've
come to learn through my manufactured
housing working group is that the people
living in manufactured homes are just
filled with infinite need Energy
Efficiency is one of the topper our top
priorities in terms of the amount of
needs that homes or people residents
living in these homes need or have um
but just to give you a sense of the
energy burden by housing type um other
than a a boat or RV van mobile homes uh
manufactured homes are among the highest
in terms of energy burden um and energy
burden is referred to as or it means the
percentage of income that people are
spending on their energy um and we see
that you know one unit um or multi-units
tend to be a little bit more efficient
when it comes to energy usage and energy
consumption so it's a little bit more
affordable but um a lot of folks prefer
to have their own space right some
people um are quite accustomed to living
in the city and being you know sharing
walls with people um but a lot of people
still want their own four walls they
don't want to be living in apartment
buildings and so manufactured homes have
been able to offer that option to them
but as you can see it comes with higher
costs right um people are spending a lot
more of their income on energy when
they're living in a manufactured home
compared to a siteb built
home um to give you a sense of what
that's like here in Tomkins County where
I've been focusing most of my work um we
have roughly 11% of our housing stock um
that is for people living in
manufactured homes um 177% of our
existing housing stock in terms of
manufactured homes were built before
1976 and that's important because in
1976 HUD started to change the rules in
terms of Energy Efficiency for
manufactured homes um so to have you
know these 177% of those homes that are
19 from 1976 or before it means they're
probably in the worst shape in terms of
how efficient they are with energy
they're also poorly insulated and if
they haven't been wellmaintained then a
lot of those people are highly
vulnerable to extreme temperatures
whether it's extreme cold or extreme
heat um in additional 26% of the
manufactured homes in Tomkins County
were built um before 1990 so between
1976 and 1990
um and again HUD increased the Energy
Efficiency standards for manufactured
homes in
1995 um making slight improvements in
terms of how comfortable and how energy
efficient those homes were but if we
still compare them to siteb Built Homes
or regular um construction homes as you
saw in that previous graph um there's
still a lot of work to be done in terms
of ensuring people are are safe and
comfortable and able to uh keep
themselves alive when it's extremely
cold out or extremely hot out um an
additional factor to consider is that um
private investment companies are
starting to buy up manufactured housing
communities which are perceived to be
cash CS so we see these uh Property
Management investment companies buying
up communities um as an easy form of
investment they put very little
investment back into the community but
they end up raising rents for residents
living in those communities um and how
it often works is people either rent the
unit as well as the the land underneath
it or they rent the land and the slab
underneath the home and then they own
the home um and so that can present some
barriers if you're trying to introduce
Energy Efficiency um measures or
programs for residents in
manufactured um housing communities um
and what we have seen in our own County
we've seen it across other counties in
New York state is that more and more of
these communities are bought up by these
private investors currently in our
County um only 12 are still privately
owned by either a resident owner or um a
local owner one is owned by a nonprofit
and then the rest are owned by private
investor ERS and what we see is that
people are usually worse off in those
types of
situations and to give you a sense of
energy costs right um and this data was
it's a couple years old I think the
prices have changed slightly in terms of
the cost for using energy but um online
estimates suggests that um a large
manufactured home would use roughly 670
gallons of propane per year um and and
that if it's still at 325 a gallon um
that's roughly a little over $2,000 a
year um we've seen some projects locally
and I'll talk about that next um that
replacing this heating load with air
source heat pumps has reduced that
significantly to just under ,000 per
year for energy costs um and that you
know you get over 55% savings as well as
the reduction in carbon dioxide
emissions or carbon equip
thankfully um there's a lot of money
available to support these types of
efforts such as installing heat pumps in
manufactured homes um as well as
replacement so you recall I talked about
how some of these homes especially in
our County are older than when the
Energy Efficiency standards had changed
so 1976 as well as
1990 um
and so there's a lot of programs out
there to support the replacement of
these older less efficient homes um New
York state has its own um replacement
funds available but the application
process is somewhat difficult uh to
navigate especially for
individuals um in many cases the county
or municipality has to be able to apply
for these funds but there is a lot of
effort put out there for funding the
improve Improvement of manufactured
homes and this is just a small sampling
of the programs that are available to
help support and fund improved Energy
Efficiency projects so the USDA Rural
Development um section 502 Direct Loan
program will provide loans for the
replacement or the purchase of a new
energy efficient uh manufactured home
the IRA or infl inflation reduction act
will give $5,000 credit to new energy
efficient homes um and that also
includes Zero Energy modular homes or ZM
which are probably the most aggressive
in terms of Energy Efficiency and um low
uh low carbon emissions associated with
the use and the um placement of those
homes we also have HUD um which has been
providing Community Development block
grants um as well as loan guarantee
programs voice neighborhood grants home
program preservation and reinvestment
initiatives or the price program all
that are focused on the replacement or
Improvement or weatherization of
manufactured homes there's also the
department of energy weatherization
assistance program and sustainable
energy for consumers award which again
supports um and allows for these
improvements that you would apply to a
traditional siteb built home but can be
applied to a manufactured home um
there's also the EPA solar for solar for
all and the thriving communities funds
um in New York State this is available
via forom University so if anybody's
familiar with forom University and the
flourishing communities grants there's
three levels of grant funding available
for different types of projects aimed at
resilience and Energy Efficiency um and
they take a pretty wide scope with what
they're um willing to fund so it's it's
worth checking out two minutes okay I'm
going to skip all of those funding
projects and get to what I was supposed
to really focus on which is some of the
local Pilots um
so uh an organization that we have
locally called Ithaca Neighborhood
Housing Services received uh just under
$6 million from the state last year to
support infrastructure development for
the compass manufactured housing
community which is located in
Trumansburg just outside of ith
um the sustainable Finger Lakes Mobile
Home pilot project um heat pump pilot
program provided lowcost Heating and
Cooling options for manufactured housing
residents that qualified um the program
is wrapping up and unfortunately they
aren't going to be keeping that program
going because they weren't able to
secure additional funding but so far
they've been able to provide energy
audits um and installations of um coal
air air air heat Source pumps can't
remember all the acronyms um and one
example of that is where a woman um in
the summertime her bedroom was 108
degrees at night throughout the day
which is not healthy or safe for anybody
and because of this uh heat pump pilot
program her bedroom is now very
comfortable no matter how hot it is
outside we also have the town of dren
which is again nearby um they have been
doing some door knocking and handing out
information on weatherization programs
they are partnering with Empower to try
and help those residents with improving
the Energy Efficiency in their homes um
and then my group The manufactured
housing working group we are just an
informal group of local residents um
that are really trying to make a
difference in this
space um and then just a a couple of
examples I will be tabling tomorrow at
the energy Expo as well and I will have
a sample window insert um this is a
program based in Vermont um that
provides these lowcost window inserts
and you can see it makes quite a
difference for the comfort inside the
home so this is when it was 29 degrees
outside um a room without the window
insert was 47° inside and without the
window insert was 70° outside or sorry
70 degrees inside and then another
project we're trying to develop is to
build resilience hubs for manufactured
manufactured housing communities because
residents in these spaces often lose
power first and for the longest amount
of time um which puts them at a high
risk um whether or not they're
experiencing extreme temperatures or
other types of extreme weather
events and then if anybody's interested
in joining our working group or
attending of our meetings you can just
email me um and you're welcome to sit in
and um hear ideas share your ideas uh
talk to us contribute
Etc that's
it this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu