good morning everyone or good afternoon
depending on where in the world you
are uh I want to welcome you all to our
third uh webinar for the fall semester
for from nekki the national extension
climate initiative this is the
curriculum working groups webinar series
and today's theme is electrification and
climate and you can hear
from Brian Stewart Mark Pullman and
Sarah Brock from their various different
perspectives on
electrification I'm not going to read
bios um that's all in the registration
information um but we uh
uh we know these people are amazing and
I'm so excited you could join us today
um the
next slide so what is the national
extension climate initiative uh we are
uh serve as an anchor for extension
professionals researchers and partners
to collaborate on climate related issues
share resources discuss barriers and
opportunities for advancing climate
change programming and extension and
engage in professional development
opportunities we are 100% voluntary so
if you want to join one of our working
groups this is from the curriculum
working group but there's also the
communication s the Justice Equity
inclusion and diversity professional
development Partnerships and policy and
the evaluation committee you can find
more at National extension climate
initiative.
net um we this is the fourth of the
series we had one on Youth and climate
in September 1890 land grant
institutions in October and we have one
on resiliency in December you can find
more I'll put these into the link as
soon as I'm off for my part but you can
find it on our seminar series and on the
recordings on our YouTube channel so
that is to segue that this will be
recorded and uploaded to our web page
around 7 days after the event please use
the chat for Logistics and the Q&amp;A for
questions of the speakers we Endeavor to
start and stop on time we will not read
bio bios we aspire to be a resource of
many resources from which you can draw
upon for your own Regional work so we
hope you find at least one person today
that really resonates with you because
we advocate for a new kind of R&amp;D which
is research and
duplicate um just a heads up this is
what will be happening in December Kim
Davis will be talking about resil
building climate resiliency through
disaster preparedness Megan will talk
about preparing agents of change for
tomorrow in appala and Jack Voit who is
a undergraduate student will be uh
talking about some work that he's been
doing um for americor on filling gaps in
coastal communities I'll put those links
in the chat
uh and
then uh also there is a another webinar
about efficiency and electrification
that's happening in November 19th on
Cornell's campus which has similar and
different topics including um Pilots
working on uh mobile homes and farm
energy audits among other things okay I
think that's it um so I'm going to stop
share so Brian do you want to launch
sure thank you um hello everyone I'm
Brian Stewart and uh as it mentioned by
the one of the co-founders of Electrify
now and this whole topic about whether
climate act whether electrification is a
you can be thought of as a climate
action or a personal benefit is near and
dear to me because it's basically the
heart of what we try to do in our
Communications and of course the short
answer is both of these things but what
I'm going to try to do today is just
talk to you about you know my experience
with how of telling this story now for
over five years and what I've learned
and what I think is most effective ways
in ter in in terms of telling this story
um so but this this sort of like um
dichotomy between climate action and
personal benefit is at the heart of the
of the communications and one of the
things that we have that's fortunate
about this story is that because it's
both it makes means that there's
multiple motivations for people to get
involved in this once they understand it
there's another dichotomy involved in
this which I think is every bit as
important which is about the kind of
interplay between individual action and
systems change if you think back to the
um origins of the uh environmental
movement in the 70s if someone was
saying well what are you going to do
personally in order to kind of help
protect the planet most of the things
that we had available to us were about
using fewer resources kind of depriving
ourselves in some ways of things that we
wanted like you know turning your
thermostat down or taking a cold shower
or something like that it's about using
less of things that are bad but now we
have this whole different Paradigm with
electrification where your individual
actions are accomplishing that but more
importantly your sort of disassembling
the system that's at the heart of the
climate change problem and you are you
have the potential to be building parts
of this new system that should replace
it that promises a better future and
we'll talk about that all right the
other thing I would like to always keep
in mind as I'm having this conversation
is that that I want to supply a context
that's both Global because people this
is a big problem it's a global problem
but bring it back to a really personal
level um and realize that people have
different motivations they might be
really motivated by a problem that
they're trying to solve or they might
just really feel excited about embracing
a solution that looks attractive both
those things are important and then
although facts are maligned as a um as a
motivator for people to actually take
action I I think that they're it's
important to use facts to our advantage
and connect them to these more emotional
drivers like health and safety and
comfort that are equally important in
terms of the reasons why people might
actually take action but connecting
those things is helpful and it's a way
for us to myth bust which which is
important to do without giving too much
Credence to the myths and then finally
you know you can really understand this
but unless you have a good way of taking
action it's not that helpful so what I
like to remind myself is that we need to
be able to explain people what these
things are that you could do but also
remove barriers for people as much as
possible so that it's easy as possible
for people to do it because these things
can be can feel
complicated all right so just as a
starting point I've really changed my
thinking about how to begin this
conversation I used to start with a
picture of you know the kind of climate
change problem I don't really talk about
climate change that much I really mostly
talk assume people understand it and are
somewhat motivated because they of their
understanding but I really launch into
this from a standpoint of the benefits
and this kind of came from my work with
ARP where you know they were kind of
reluctant to to to go too hard on the
the carbon Mission standpoint because it
felt political to them but they were
comfortable if I talked about it as long
as I couch it in terms of these benefits
that were economic and health benefits
to their customers but I realize that
that's just a good way to talk about
this there are huge advantages to doing
this as a homeowner in particular which
is our kind of target audience because
it's going to reduce your bills and Make
a Better Living experience but it also
reduces air pollution in a really
dramatic way and carbon pollution so
depending on your point of view here all
those things are important I don't shy
away from this one fact though which is
so important to land because I don't
think people really get it in some ways
in fact when we started Electrify now it
was partly out of the frustration that I
felt that it seemed like all the popular
media just wanted to talk about plastic
straws and there was no conversation in
the public media sort of five years ago
about the importance of energy and the
fact that it's at the heart of this
problem I think that's really changed
which is encouraging but I think people
still need to be aware of the fact that
it's burning fossil fuels that are at
the heart of this problem of course
there are other issues land use food
production Etc I don't mean to downplay
them and Plastics waste again I'm not
poo pooing that it's just that if it
weren't for this fossil fuels problem we
wouldn't be here having this
conversation and it's also one of the
things that's most actionable as a
consumer I like to remind people that on
the heat side you know there's this
mythology that we've all grown up with
that natural gas is a clean burning fuel
but the truth is the more we learn about
it it's simp similar or potentially even
worse than coal in terms of its climate
impacts because of methane leaks it's a
major source of air pollution which is
virtually uh invisible to people and
it's also true that renewable natural
gas although it's getting a lot of
airPlay from the utilities is not going
to save the day here there's no such
thing as renewable methane and it's not
equivalent to renewable energy because
it's it still has massive environmental
consequences so the bad news is we have
to get off of this thing that we've
grown up with in which has been
important to building civilization for
the last 100 years but the good news is
there's an alternative that here that is
incredibly sustainable and is hugely
economically advantageous the cost of U
creating new energy with uh solar and
wind is now lower than any other source
and this is true all over the world to
varying degrees um because of local
economics but on a macro level this is
absolutely the case which is one of the
reasons why we are going to go here but
the of course we need to go here as fast
as possible but this is another story
that wouldn't have been true 20 or 30
years ago would have made this
conversation impossible to have the
other thing that's been having happening
sort of quietly behind the scenes is
that electric appliances have become
unbelievably more energy efficient in
our lifetime I like to point out these
minimum efficiency standards from the US
government so basically if you look at
this you'll see that gas furnaces and
water heaters and all gas technology
they're required by law to be 2% more
energy efficient than they were 30 years
ago this technology literally hasn't
changed since the time of your parents
buying these devices when we were
children but electric devices and
particularly those that can uh include
heat pumps are by law at least 30% more
energy efficient than they were 30 years
ago and in actual fact if you look at
the the devices that we buy they're more
like 50 or 60 or 70 or 100% more
efficient than the things that we would
have been buying 30 years ago and this
is true for anything that's electric um
the electric light bulb is kind of the
poster child for this um but these
devices that we'll talk about in terms
of homeowners in particular all have
massive efficiency benefits that are not
possible on the gas side that is one of
the reasons why if you look at energy
consumption in the United States at a
macro level it's essentially unchanged
in the last 20 years even though our
population is increased by 18% we have
51 million more people living here here
our homes are bigger they're almost
twice the size that were being built um
20 years ago there's 15 million heat
pumps that didn't exist two and a half
million EVS consuming electricity didn't
exist all these data centers that are
suck up huge amounts of electricity it
didn't exist 20 years ago and all all
these other devices like smartphones and
computers etc why is this that our
electricity consumption is flat even
though we've added all this these cons
these consumption it's because of the
effic Effy that we're seeing with the
electric devices and this has not played
itself out there is way more efficiency
to be gained which is why I'm not
concerned about this sound bite that
people say oh there's not not enough
electricity to go around we need more
supply for sure but it's not as dramatic
as people think and the other thing that
is important for people to realize is
that while our electricity supply has
been relatively constant the emissions
from electricity go down and down and
down as we add more Renewables all the
time and get rid of really um polluting
coal plants Etc this is why at a macro
level this story about electrification
is so compelling and why you hear this
sound by that we should be electrifying
everything and you know we've been sort
of talking about it primarily from a a a
climate change perspective but it has
these other benefits that are almost too
good to be true energy cost savings that
we'll talk about it is it think about
where air pollution comes from for the
most part it comes from burning fossil
fuels that's the the major source of air
pollution it's a huge consumer of water
so that fresh water so we'll have more
available flesh water if we get off of
fossil fuels production this all leads
to healthier people and a stronger
economy so lots of reasons that the
macro level to be excited about this but
I also think it's important to use this
context Framing and what it means
personally because you can be thinking
about that and go oh that's great well
what about me well in my home in most
people's homes 60 % of the carbon
emissions that we're responsible for as
individuals comes from burning fossil
fuels and it's actually very possible to
eliminate all that which we'll talk
about whereas the other 40% which comes
from the food you buy and the things
that you purchase that's harder to get
rid of I mean that is takes other people
to do that for us but we can take care
of this ourselves the four biggest ones
in most people's lives are their
electricity Supply their gas cars their
furnaces and their water heaters these
are the four biggest sources of uh
carbon pollution for any individual the
only thing that would be on part of this
is if you fly a lot um that would be up
there but for most people these things
make everything else pale in comparison
from a carbon emission standpoint and
the exciting thing is that when you
combine renewable energy and
electrification all these things can go
to zero and it's possible to do this
today you can get renewable en energy
into your home there's multiple ways to
do that you can get an EV and charge it
with that renew energy now you're
creating zero emissions for your
transportation same for your heating and
your water heating and there's economic
benefits to these two that we'll talk
about because when you roll this all up
what you see is that at a household
level the average in the US is about 20
tons of carbon emission if you Electrify
that home today with the grid as it is
no renewable energy more than we have
already you would slash those carbon
emissions
dramatically but if you
in add this renewable energy thing which
is possible to do at an individual level
and it's where we're headed as a country
a lot of states have laws now that
require this by very near future um this
is where we're headed that this home
would go from 20 to zero and along the
way save amazing amounts of money in
terms of energy costs it costs about
$7,000 a year to run a home on average
if you think about your electric bill
your gas bill and the gasoline
consumption for two cars which is
average that can be cut in half nearly
by electri
electrifying so of course it's important
to educate people about the technologies
that make that possible and we we're not
going to be spending as much time on
that today but this is one of the things
that I think is really important for my
work is just to make these things
familiar to people because while they're
not necessarily new most people are not
familiar with these technologies that
are fundamental to the electrification
movement and that each of them have
their own benefits which you can talk
about it's it can feel daunting we like
to try to keep it simple for people by
tell showing them how they can clean up
their electric supply and then thinking
about all the things in your home that
burn fossil fuels from your your
lawnmower which we'll hear more about
today I'm excited it's one of my pet
peeves all the way to um you know your
furnace Etc all those things can be
replaced with electric Alternatives that
are better you you can Electrify your
transportation and then of course
there's a Justice component to all this
we have to Electrify everyone we'll be
hearing more about that today from
another speaker which is I like to
remind people that's a certainly
important part of this okay so back to
this like climate action versus personal
benefit thing if you talk about heat
space heating for and heat pumps the
fact is that these devices are going to
make you more comfortable many homes
don't even have air conditioning it
comes along for the ride in this case if
you replace your furnace with a heat
pump but it also provides more
consistent air uh temperatures there are
more well spaced out in your home so you
don't have as many cold spots Etc
because it operates at a lower level of
energy but more continuously and that
also means you get better air quality
that more air through your filters Etc
that's noticeable in homes that are
heated with heat pumps but from an
economic standpoint it's the cheapest
way to heat your home there's just no
other technology that competes with this
you know you're the difference between a
gas furnace and the heat pump will vary
from place to place and home to home but
in general it is the lowest cost way to
um heat your home and by far the lowest
um carbon pollution I like to point out
to people because this is another myth
you do not need gas backup even in very
cold parts of the country it's possible
to Electrify homes Alaska Maine it's
happening um with these new efficient
versions of heat pumps that can operate
at very low temperatures and of course
if you have electric uh a renewable
energy unit home or this is what's going
to happen in the future these devices
that are electric will produce no carbon
emissions and that's just not possible
to do with the other
Technologies a lot of people may say
well this is a new thing you know like
am I going to be like the first person
doing this if I do this in my home and
the truth is that Americans are waking
up to the fact that electrification is a
good thing and heat pumps are just
better this is data about sales of heat
pumps in the US and you can see that
five years ago furnaces were massively
outs selling heat pumps and that's
completely turned around in 2024 it's
more like 60% sales are are heat pumps
so super exciting if you do this you're
not alone you're part of this trend
that's developing around embracing these
Technologies most people think that they
understand electric vehicles they they
they think they're just expensive um and
maybe a little bit better but the truth
is they're safer there's fewer
fatalities associated with electric
vehicles they perform better in every
way and they have these dramatic cost
savings that make the sticker price that
you might be um worried about pale when
you
or basically go away as an issue when
you look at total cost of ownership over
five years you'll save thousands of
dollars and it's because of this fact
these are two cars that are essentially
the same cars one's a gas and one the
other's electric and you can see you get
for $10 of fuel you can go three times
as far with the electric version that is
why over the lifetime of this car you're
going to save a ton of money as well as
massively reduce your carbon emissions
and of course all that can be zero if
you're charging R renewable en energy
and this is why again people are waking
up to this and so last year EVS were
about 8% of sales here in Oregon it's
more like 17 so you won't be alone if
you do this and I would just finally
like to end by saying I think it's
always important to give people idea
about resources they can turn to to help
them to do this in their own home these
are three really good ones that I use a
lot but of course it depends on where
you live and then finally you know
electrification is just better yes it's
a powerful climate action yes it's going
to give you personal benefits but it's
just better and that's why more and more
people are waking up to this and and by
doing this you can be building your part
of a better
future okay thank you um I think that's
uh all I have and I don't know if we
have a couple minutes for questions
here I I was trying to talk about to get
through that there's a lot of material
to cover but I hope Brian what is what
is the most exciting thing for from your
frame of reference about what
electrification can do for
us well I think the the most exciting
thing about it is this sort of no
compromise um aspect of it that you know
because I think people are used to this
idea that if you want to do something
that's good for the planet you have to
sacrifice somehow and I I think I I
applaud that idea of living smaller and
consuming fuel resources for sure but I
I you can I think it's fair to say that
that idea has not been successful in the
world in general as a as a as a solution
to our problems you know people don't
want to sacrifice so what I love about
electrification is it's a little bit of
a cake and eat it your cake and E it to
kind of solution from the standpoint
that it's it's the most powerful climate
action that people can take period there
is nothing else like it in terms of how
much impact it has and it doesn't really
come along with any kind of major
sacrifices and really not really any
Behavior change you know I think that
that's the other thing that I I I talk a
lot about is that people don't like to
change your behavior but you know an NA
isn't a behavior change you're still
driving the way you used to it's just
that now you're you're creating fewer
Problems by um having access to person
mobility and yes you can have this whole
conversation about should we be
transitioning to more public
transportation yes 100% but it it really
solves problems that people um have in
terms of just being able to kind of do
what you're doing but in a way that
produces fewer Downstream issues and so
there's a lot of questions now in the
chat and they're all about uh losing
incentives or changes incentives or
maybe an increase in incentives with a
new Administration um what are your
thoughts about uh how important so
there's many questions
um um thinking from the federal to the
state level and the personal uh and
business level what are your thoughts on
are the incentives necessary do we need
to rely on them do you think they might
get bigger what do you think yeah well
Ian I think I'm as fearful as anyone
that you know we're going to lose
momentum on this that we've sort of
gained over the last five years with um
under the Biden Administration I think
they just don't get credit for how much
they did in an amazing way that we are
we still won't see the effects of it for
years still but I would say this trend
towards electrification started and
really started picking up some momentum
well before these incentives were
available so I think I'm not fearful of
it changing I I'm fearful of it slowing
down because and we don't have time for
things to slow down but um I also feel
like this is a time where the states are
going to have to step up um and do as
much as they can um to to plug the gap
between what is may start to deteriorate
at the federal
level okay so we need to switch there
are some questions if you want to answer
them in the chat and could you also put
the links that you showed on that next
to your last slide into the chat as well
Mark will you please share a screen and
come on board and while Mark is doing
that I just want to comment that my
87-year-old mom just bought an EV car
cuz her
22-year-old Corolla was dying and she
was fearful and it was without
incentives it was a really
inexpensive used car Chevy bolt and I'm
not trying to advocate for it I'm just
saying there's so many benefits to it
it's one of the most inexpensive car is
out there right now and it happens to be
electric and it happens to run off of
the solar on her roof
so I don't know I'm just saying it's
it's not high tech scary or expensive
okay Mark take us away well thank you so
much for inviting me to uh speak on on
this topic um my name is Mark Pullman I
am a board member of the losn which is a
lake AO sustainability Network and I'm
going to speak today on our uh campaign
we're calling Electrify your Landscaping
healthy yard care it's clean it's quiet
it's
healthy uh a little bit about losn losn
is a community-based nonprofit volunteer
organization um and it uh we network
with nonprofits businesses in the area
local government and schools um and our
purpose we've been in uh in existence
for about 12 years and our purpose is to
promote sustainability in lake ofo lake
ofo is a small suburb of uh Portland
Oregon Portland is a has a population of
about 630,000 and our population is
about
40,000 um people are so surprised uh to
find that um the utilization of gas
powerered Lawn Lawn equipment or
landscape equipment is quite detrimental
to our uh to our community and to our
climate uh one hour of uh running a gas
powerered lawn mower is equivalent to
running 300 miles um uh of a car going
from like LA to Vegas um and one hour of
leaf blower use uh is the equivalent of
uh driving 1100 miles or from LA to
Denver that's just absolutely amazing
mindboggling to my to my mind but it
does come from the California air
quality management board and is quite
believable and this is smog uh forming
pollutants all all comers um one of the
uh main disadvantages to gas powerered
landscape equipment is the extreme noise
uh noise um created by gas powered
landscaping equipment is is um equ uh is
uh about four times louder than
electric and
um when we look at deciel levels of uh
in in the environment uh it is a um it
is a a
logarithmic uh measurement which means
for every 10 Deb that you go up it's
twice as loud uh most uh electric
landscaping equipment runs at a deciel
level of about 55 to 75 um most gas
powerered landscape equipment run at
about 75 and go up to as high as
120 um on top of which um the gas
powerered landscape equipment has um has
a low pitched uh hum or uh sound that
penetrates walls and windows much more
efficiently than the higher pitch sounds
do and um can affect up to 9
homes whereas electric equipment it does
have some uh low pitch sound but uh it
can affect maybe six six homes um a a
deciel level above 85 can be harmful uh
when exposed to that over approximately
15 minutes uh so so OSHA EPA have uh
have put uh levels of which unprotected
ears should not be exposed to decel
levels um uh and you can see that down
at the
bottom um gas powered landscape
equipment uh exude a lot of toxins um uh
volatile organic compounds like Benzene
butane form Malahide um and also a very
dangerous uh particulate matter uh small
particulates called hydrocarbon uh PM
2.5 that's the size electric landscaping
equipment doesn't exude any of that uh
when using the gas powered or blowers in
and of themselves they do stir up dust
and fecal matter and other stuff that's
on the on the ground and we'll talk a
little bit about how to avoid that in
the
future um looking at the comparing Gas
and Electric landscaping equipment uh
electric it's instant on and off uh gas
you got to pull a cord uh for starting
the engine you have to often we'll have
to prime it you have to refill the gas
and oil you got to you got to transport
the gas you got to fill the gas cans and
transport them often in your car uh so
it slushes around in the in the car and
with all the smell and uh in in there
whereas you don't have to do any of that
with electric you do have to charge
batteries and transport those batteries
uh but you don't have to winterize your
equipment with electric Landscaping
whereas if you don't winterize uh your
gas powered you're going to have a gummy
mess in the springtime and going to have
a and you're going to have a big Bill uh
cleaning it up uh annual maintenance of
spark plug changes air filter changes
fuel filter changes are all gone with
the electric landscape equipment um
multiple tools can be run on the same
battery so you don't have to buy
separate batteries for the different
equipment
um and batteries are becoming longer and
longer as far as the run times
go um I personally changed uh my gas-
powered G uh lawn uh equipment to
Electric several years ago and I
absolutely love my lawn it I it's
lighter it uh you turn it on you turn it
off there's no smell no no gases that
come out and and you have to deal with
uh and uh it's it's easier to push uh
it's all in all a plus uh to um uh for
your landscaping
equipment now you'll hear that they
aren't powerful enough for our
landscapers for our industrial
landscapers unfor fortunately many
companies are creating uh uh powerful
electric equipment uh anywhere from ego
to
Steel um to Makita and these have all
been field tested by AO which is the uh
which is the American green zone
Alliance U and are certified for our
landscapers for um uh for their
use now another another comment is that
uh the purchase price of the electric uh
the electric equipment is higher than
the gas and that is true um just like we
were talking about uh uh EVS being more
expensive than the the gas powered uh
models at this point although they are
going to be lower however um you'll note
that uh when looking at um uh the this
is just one brand steel uh the steel
br500 is a gas powerered blower and the
steel uh BGA 200 is a an electric and
you'll notice that the CFM is almost
identical uh you get little less uh uh
wind speed out of the electric than you
do from the gas but very very minimal
differences um and but again people say
that they are too expensive to replace
and operate uh when looking at the
economics of replacing gas uh gas
blowers with electric blowers we take
one example here of an electric blower
that cost about two grand
and we'll we'll give it we'll give the
landscaper the benefit of the doubt that
they have a gas powered blower now and
they're going to replace it with
electric so uh they they put out two
grand at the beginning um but in 10 and
a half months uh they you will find that
um the
electricity
um hold on one second here let me get my
pointer out yes you'll note here that
the steel 500 costs 5009 600 bucks and
the electric blower cost
$2200 oh my goodness okay but then you
look over the cost over five years
you're going to save a heck of a lot of
money with the electric um it costs
about
$113,000 to for your G gas El uh your
gas and your and your oil whereas the
electric
sorry about that um the electric uh this
includes your
electricity um so annualized cost is
about $500 for $600 for your electric
and $2,700 for your gas so over 10 10
and a half months you've actually paid
for your El your electric blower and uh
Savings of about $2,500 a year
another uh another uh penciling out of
uh costs we have a blower that costs
$2,500 here and we have a gas blower
that cost
$530 uh 2-year fuel cost um running at
1920 hours for um which is four days a
week four hours a day um uh with your
electricity cost about 384 bucks versus
the gas and the oil and the like uh 5600
so ultimately you're over two years
you're spending twice as much with your
gas blower than you are with your
electric so the next uh problem is that
they say is The Upfront costs are too
high so we're going to put our small
business owners out of
business so what we need to do is we
need to look at some sort of a financing
situ ation um we we know that equipment
is not paid for upfront all at once out
of pocket it's usually financed over
time so what we need to do is we need to
take a look at loans perhaps for our
small business people uh small business
administration has microloans we have in
Oregon we have a a new um a
new uh loaning situation where where we
are are making microloans to landscapers
and for individuals who are uh
winterizing their homes um and we're
we're looking to to use that in our
small community too we also need to look
at Community grants uh for the small
landscapers and we also know that large
re retailers such as steel um often will
give interest free purchases and
payments over the course of time and as
you can see uh you pay for it with the
savings but people say oh they're still
too expensive I can't do
that what is what is the cost of
inaction the human cost uh we it expel
these things expel um toxins which can
cause cancer pulmonary disease heart
disease uh the the the deciel level of
these things cause hearing loss
um and we just don't want to we just
don't want to tolerate that so what can
we do as individuals and as groups uh to
alleviate this problem one is that we
can simply not use blowers um we can use
brooms and rakes we can buy electric
tools which are affordable as you've
seen they're affordable clean and
effective we can hire landscapers in our
in our area a lot of people have
landscapers and so we can hire
landscapers that who use Electric Tools
one of those uh we have a list and we've
worked with um quiet clean PDX uh to
create a list of uh landscapers who use
only electric equipment and it's very
difficult to get into them because
they're uh they're filling up uh we can
also buy our own Electric Tools at our
home and loan them to the landscaper so
the landscaper gives us the the labor
and we give them the tools to do the
work in our particular home um we can
also uh purchase batteries to charge at
our home and then they can own the
equipment and just change out the
batteries as they
come we can also uh care for our care
for our plants the xeri society has a uh
campaign for uh leaving the leaves
because uh they care for our soil and
plants um uh they avoid uh we want to
avoid herbicides and pesticides which
can be harmful to our children pets and
Wildlife and we can leave these leaves
which actually builds the soil uh builds
mulch we clean the hardscapes but leave
the leaves in the
Planters you can also take action and
become involved in local and National
groups uh that are uh working toward um
a better cleaner uh home life um we have
the xeri society and the leave the
leaves we've talked about that uh you
can uh certified habitat uh backyard
habitat can certify your backyard uh for
um uh for renewable and sustainable uh
yard care and we've created uh a
gas-free landscape uh program here in
Lake aigo
we also um have electrification Fair we
had an electrification Fair um and um
encourag the use of uh rakes and brooms
uh we call it the sound of
silence and um we've also uh created a
community action uh group uh which join
uh we're doing letters to the editor on
an ongoing basis we're forwarding those
letters to the city council we um we
have an uh elect electrifica Electrify
your landscaping and healthy yard care
committee uh within losn and we ask for
donations uh from the local area and we
also have our signs that we would like
people to put
up we've also uh worked with other
groups in the area uh Watershed uh
Council uh Lake ofgo Watershed Council
has a uh Urban Forest tree Summit uh
that we just participated in uh we also
um invited to our electrification Fair
both landscapers who utilize um utilize
Electric Tools and also um and also uh
Electric Tool manufacturers we have a
sustainability Fair within Lake aigo
also and if you'd like to know more
information here's our here's our
website uh where Lake ofgo
sustainability Network
and any
questions that was wonderful
Mark um so I'm just curious Mark uh what
is your favorite difference from using
an electric landscaping equipment as
opposed to gas power like what is your
favorite like why what's the nicest
thing about
it I like the instant on and off uh and
the and not having to manage the gas
through the through the winter uh
we our usage drops at our home uh in the
wintertime of course and um even
utilizing stabil in in the gas U really
didn't help we always were we always
were all gummed up and it was always a
mess and it
smells um so Sarah will you start
sharing and I'll ask one more question
of you Mark um can you just talk about a
little bit how you're advocating for the
Landscaping businesses to uh to move
over to electric equipment because I
have to say I live in an apartment
building and I notice a big difference
between electric landscaping and gas
powerered landscaping equipment around
me well we're um we're actually going to
the end user we're going to people who
um who are hiring the landscapers and
encouraging them to go to electri
landscapers then we've reached out to
landscapers in general find out if they
have the option for electric and then we
put it on our website um we're also look
working we're also beginning to work
with seeds for soul which is which is a
a funding a a low low interest um
funding group um to and we're just
beginning that process and we'll
probably work on that next year um
bringing bringing the community together
to
um kind adopt a adopt a landscaper so to
speak we we'll uh donate some funds
we'll ask the city to donate funds and
then we'll get some uh uh micro loans
and between the three of us the three of
them be able to help the the lowincome
small landscapers uh uh weather the
storm okay I just want to say that I'm
going to put into the chat a cost
comparison uh that nerta has done for
greenhouse gas emissions and the cost
for different kinds of equipment you
kind of have to go onto the second tab
of of the first link like it's going to
download an Excel spreadsheet but it's
really
helpful very nice thank you thank you
Sarah thank you
Mark would you like me to take it away
Jenny please
great hi everyone um last speaker of the
session for you my name is Sarah Brock I
um run a program in New Hampshire that
we call the energy circuit writers
program and I'm going to explain what
that is it's a way through which we are
trying to help uh funds and action get
into our more rural communities in New
Hampshire we are fairly rural State um
and part of the reason I'm here is
because Jenny's mom is on one of the
energy committees I work with in veral
New Hampshire so happy to represent the
Northeast here just a
sec so um clean energy New Hampshire is
a nonprofit uh we are uh striving
towards a decarbonized Energy System for
New Hampshire for us that means that we
work on anything related to renewable
energy Energy Efficiency and
electrification we have a North star
that relates to equity um we haven't
talked a lot about that today but the
the three sentences that are run through
my mind all the time are these guiding
principles that um rates and costs must
be affordable for all that uh the system
should distribute the burdens and
benefits um economic and and
environmental burdens and benefits
fairly and that the Energy System should
be secure and resilient and
reliable um we have I run our education
Outreach technical assist
side that's our energy circuit writer
team we also do a lot in policy advocacy
and and stakeholder engagement and we
have a whole lot of members um across
the state individuals industry members
municipalities planners and we are you
know relatively small state and we we
sort of are the organization focused on
this we don't have many other
peers my team uh the circuit writer team
provides direct Hands-On technical
assistance to communities this is a
program that started in the North
country of New Hampshire you can see
Melissa here who's our original circuit
writer the concept was that a lot of the
the communities particularly in our
Northern um region are very small we're
talking like 500 residents or a thousand
or500 residents uh a thre member
volunteer select board running the town
and maybe a part-time administrator
opening the mail and you know processing
taxes so uh no capacity to help the Town
put LEDs in town hall or consider a
solar project or um or any of of those
other projects that we were seeing some
of the more populated towns be able to
tackle so we got some Grant finding we
hired someone to be a traveling staffer
who could provide some expertise and
some project management support and that
was incredibly successful we managed to
expand that to four municipally focused
circuit riders that are each live and
work in their regions so you can see the
North country we call the Sea Coast in
the Southeast and then a couple of those
counties in the southwest now each have
someone on the ground working out of
their home that is going to select board
meetings and planning board meetings and
um creating energy committees and trying
to get projects done that save money for
the town and therefore trickles down
into the tax base
um the concept here in in the work that
we do which started with municipalities
and you as you'll see has grown um
really has to do with the rural nature
of our state we experience some of the
highest energy burden in the nation
because we don't have access to natural
gas we're very reliant on Oil and
Propane to heat our homes um and cold
climates mean heat pumps were slow to
take off although we are certainly
seeing a lot more adoption of heat pumps
for primary heating now which I'm
thrilled about um we also just have very
small communities which means at the
municipal level very little capacity to
get projects done but also very little
capacity to get um the word out about
programs that could help residents to
take action and we see programs rolled
out in the state that just don't get
Beyond populated a couple of populated
centers in our
state so our team effectively is Bridge
um we identify what the programs are we
develop the the technical expertise and
capacity internally and then We're
translating and supporting our partners
through these
projects um briefly because you're not
you're not here to talk about Municipal
energy projects necessarily my team is
trained to do anything and everything
that's necessary to support a town
through the process of identifying and
then having the voters approve an energy
saving project and a lot of those
projects uh do have to do with
electrification some way whether we are
shifting um their electrical source to
solar and that happens a lot um putting
solar on the town hall or on the um the
you know covered landfill sort of thing
a lot of efficiency projects um a lot of
increasing number of electric vehicle
procurement and electric vehicle
charging projects um but a lot of talk
about
electrification that's I'll Breeze
through this but you can see sort of a
glimpse of the kinds of things that we
have
touched um we also work with small
business businesses this is relatively
new we got a grant from USDA to provide
technical assistance for businesses who
could be eligible for the um
renewable rural energy for America
program renewable energy for America
program one of those it's a program that
allows small businesses and a producers
in rural parts of the country which is
most of my state to access currently 50%
of project cost um for renewable energy
and Energy Efficiency projects so we are
out talking to business owners every day
helping them navigate the process both
of applying for the grant but then also
just putting the project together
generally and we deal with the same
capacity issues where these are small
business owners who who do not have the
time of day to go researching and
getting contracts with contractors and
we're able to hold their hand through
the
process and here's just another
spattering of the kinds of projects that
we've been working
on um when
it comes to helping so so the inflation
reduction Act was obviously um
gamechanging for a lot of reasons I'm
not going to talk about this but one of
the most impactful from our work has
been the elective pay program which for
those of you who don't work with
municipalities or nonprofits this
allowed um agencies like municipalities
and nonprofits that don't have tax
burden to still access the clean energy
tax credits through a direct payment
from the IR RS that has meant that our
communities and our nonprofits have have
access to an unlimited um funding source
that's non-competitive to help move
projects along and that has been
game-changing um there have been a
number of other programs and funding
often linking back to the IRA that um
part of my or my organization's mission
is to make sure those dollars land on
the ground in New Hampshire some of our
neighboring states have state agencies
and like Federal funding Zars whose job
it is to make sure that all federal
funding that could land in the state
does um we don't have that in New
Hampshire for various funny political
reasons so uh my organization sort of
tries to do that as best we can um when
these funding sources come across we're
we're analyzing what is it who's
eligible do they know they're eligible
what needs to happen and what kind of
technical assistance do we need to
deploy on the ground to make sure those
dollars land in the hands of of the
folks who are meant to receive them and
uh looking into the next year I I cannot
speak to whether this is going to change
her last week's election results but um
in New Hampshire we've been anxiously
awaiting our state department of
Energy's um program to deploy the home
electrification and Appliance rebates
this is something that's um a nationwide
program but every state has been asked
to to come up with their own plan to
deploy it in New Hampshire this was
going to mean I was just looking at the
dollars this is going to mean somewhere
around 7 million Landing in our state
which is a lot that will go directly to
Residents um individual and users and
some of that is specific to
electrification and I think the part
that my team is most excited about is
rebates that will help purchase heat
pumps um and other you know all the
appliances you heard Brian talking about
earlier there will be significant
rebates for on a level that we haven't
seen that combined with a couple of
other incentive programs that are coming
down the pike in New England should make
it possible for us to go out and be
delivering this electrification message
that we heard Brian share we don't
really have the um the structure to to
do that well in New Hampshire and these
rural communities so we have been
working with our energy committees and
our local Partners to think about when
this lands how do we make sure that
these programs which are designed to be
utilized by low-income residents
actually can we get those programs to
those low-income residents and and hold
through their hands through the process
of actually utilizing them because we
know from history that this these
programs are difficult to deploy
effectively in the populations that you
want them to reach so we're thinking a
lot about that proactively some of what
we are doing right now um we have a
funding tracker that we track with our
partners as these programs come up um we
are researching them and trying to
identify who needs to know about them
and who needs to go after them as a
coalition we um have worked with
Statewide Partners to make sure that
when the partners in the state go after
Federal funding that often it's it's
ending up that my program is being
tapped to as a wrin so that not only is
the program being applied for but
there's some money being set aside for
technical assistance as part of the
program rollout plan because we know
that that's necessary in New Hampshire
for these programs to be successful um
we are really advocating with our
communities to have shovel ready
projects to put together so that means
um figure out where in town the EV
charger is going to go because you don't
know when the grant program could land
that would make money available to help
you implement that but usually when
Grant programs are announced for
communities there's a six or eight week
turn around which is not enough time for
most small municipalities to come up
with the idea get a contract with a
vendor and put together a complicated
Federal grant proposal so we're
supporting communities and in developing
folders of shovel ready projects so that
they're ready to jump we are um forming
and strengthening local volunteer energy
committees and commissions which is a
model that's very common in the
Northeast where we have you know elected
um in in New England we have these uh
select boards that are elected in most
towns and the select boards can appoint
energy Committees of volunteers who then
can go off and do the the busy work of
putting together projects to then
present to the voters at an annual town
meeting so we create these committees we
support them we help them do their
homework for their select boards and
their voters um we help those committies
set up capital reserve funds so they
don't have to wait till the next town
meeting necessarily to take action on a
clean energy project uh these are all
somewhat unique veral New England
problems but uh we were actively working
um proactively to address them and then
we're also doing some kind of uh
creative organizing on the ground um
we've been uh working with some of our
local partners and a local utility here
to look at bringing batteries to local
emergency shelters in some of our
hilltowns where um where we can have
prolonged outages and we put solar on
these roofs and can we maybe rely on
batteries instead of diesel to to
provide back P backup power um we
started working with local libraries as
hubs for information around
electrification uh the libraries are
very interested they see this as a way
to to have more reasons for people to
come in the door um but they need
partners because they are not experts in
this so we're we're working with some
libraries right now to to see what kind
of programming we can help them run to
get the word out about programs and
electrification opportunities uh we've
got some towns piloting a coaches
project um rewiring America runs a
coaching training and we've got some
volunteers who have gone through that
training and we've got a growing list of
residents who have done some
electrification on their own and are
willing and excited about talking to
their neighbors about it so we're
standing up a program that's doing some
matchmaking in that regard and and if
that goes well that's something we're
hoping to scale um we've been doing
coordinated public Outreach campaigns in
various communities for years uh the
energy committee that Jenny's mom is
part of has done a lot of solariz and
weatherized campaigns with um my help in
the past and it's a model that we found
really successful and uh we've been
doing more work with resident owned
communities which are um mobile home
communities in New Hampshire we have a
lot of those communities that are owned
by their residents and um are
increasingly looking at Community solar
projects and electrification across
their communities and we've got some
grants to help with that so we're
getting creative um to get these
programs and these Solutions out into
the hands of people who need them takes
um a lot of coordination and effort and
thoughtfulness at the level in my
experience but uh there's a lot that can
be done I'll leave it at
that Sarah thank you so much I just
admire your program so so so so very
much you are connecting the dots in ways
that are so important and as we think
and especially for Rural communities
because New Hampshire like the whole
state is like a million people
so um you have a a specific kind of
place based learning collaboration and
integration to connect the dots for
funding and implementation
so how can other places think about what
you're doing how can they research and
duplicate what you're doing in order to
meet you know in Florida they'll have
different kinds of problems in Oregon
they'll have different problems in Iowa
they'll have different problems like I
just feel like you you're connecting the
dots in important ways how can we how
can we
follow or be inspired or like how has it
come together in your head to make these
kinds of things
connect me I think um everything that
I'm working on started with the question
of uh what do we want to see and why
isn't it happening the in circuit writer
program was created because someone
looked up at these little towns in the
North country and said none of these
towns has has switched out their street
lights for LEDs why because it makes
perfect Financial sense and it was just
the the capacity and so we we identified
the problem and we we tried it out we
plugged the hole in a teeny little pilot
it worked and so we expanded it um the
solariz and weatherized programs were
the same thing what why why is there a
we got data from the state and it said
that nobody on the coneticut river was
subscribing to the New Hampshire saves
program why and so we we put together a
program and we talk to the installers
who were wanting to do business there
and we talk to the NH saves folks and we
put together a program and we we changed
this The Narrative and I think wherever
you are in the country surely you have
one of those why isn't this happening
and get the people around the table
who've got perspective on it including
the folks you're trying to reach and
come up with a solution that's worth
trying at a scale that's possible to try
David will you come on and ask your
question sure thanks Jenny um and thank
you Sarah and also Brian and Mark my
question speaking as a member of the
national extension climate initiative
which uh is sponsoring this and
represents the resources of the l Grant
University system broadly speaking what
what can we in the sort of bridging
organization between community and
Academy and the academy what can we do
better that would help the work that
you're doing uh in places uh on the
ground more effectively and I'm also
just curious whether any of you already
have connections with Cooperative
Extension people in your
communities I'll just note briefly that
in New Hampshire our extension runs a a
nature groupy program that I just love
it's a um a volunteer
matchmaking program and I've talked to
them at length recently about whether
some of what they're doing to try to to
tap volunteerism toward the end of
conservation in their case um couldn't
be sort of mirrored or or dovetailed
with the idea of um developing some sort
of coaching program or volunteering
program around electrification and
helping people access electrification
resources and that I think there's
there's more to to be looked at there
that's one area where we're seeing
connection and L A sgo in losn we are uh
connecting with uh with State and
National groups uh we have a
electrification action committee that
we're um uh
we're connecting with Electrify now and
creating a a coaching uh electrification
coaching group uh to help people
Electrify yeah I mean I'm to be honest
this I'm pretty unfamiliar with this
extension um kind of concept and how how
we might work better with them but I I I
like the idea and I love the fact that
you know it feels like it's kind of
embedded in communities all over the
country which is such an important thing
I think everyone here has been touching
this speak speakers on this kind of
local action idea that and you know the
way local action works is by connecting
well with the communities like Sarah
spoke to that very eloquently I mean
without people on the ground you can
have the best programs in the world and
they won't get any traction so I I don't
know I would love to explore it more I'm
i' like to talk to you maybe and others
more about what that might look like
because I'm pretty unfamiliar with what
that extension program is this is I just
sent you I just sent you a chat with my
email address we can okay followall up
then and anybody else is welcome as well
so Colin has one question
uh um New York state has some similar
programs called the re Regional clean
energy hubs with a link um we have found
that there's generally good awareness
for various energy and cost savings
programs but low participation what has
been your program's best practices for
moving someone from awareness to action
what's more important education and
Outreach or program design and incentive
structure dot dot
dot um every time I've asked that
question uh
Colin I it tends to be in a room um and
I always like to have the contractors
there and the program leader people
design people there um and ideally some
some just humans uh who fit in that
category of of maybe the audience and
then we just map it out start to finish
um the path from awareness to action and
every little place on that path where
you could fall off or where something is
confusing and then um we we designed the
program to smooth that and have an
answer for every moment where it gets
confusing so I've run I mentioned the
solariz and weatherized campaigns but
where I've had most success in in in
getting uptick in an actual program it's
when we like hyper analyze the program
in that respect and pick a geography and
pick some partners and um and run and in
some of those cases we were we were
negotiating with the contractors to to
sweeten the deal a little bit uh and you
know have an extra incentive or some
discount and in some cases we were
simply just promoting the program and
and helping people feel better about
participating and giving them a sense of
now is the moment we're all doing it
together in my community here and that's
we're partnering with the energy
committees and doing it a couple
communities at a time was very effective
but that skill made sense at the level
that we were operating in rural New
Hampshire I will just add on that the
reason I know Sarah is because she
worked with my mom's town which is
Cornish New Hampshire to have a
competition with the neighboring town
which is planfield New Hampshire to see
who could weatherize more so there had
little tickers you know like who was
winning who was getting more and then
they did the same thing with solarizing
right like who had to who has more solar
panels and what happened was as they got
each Town had incentives because if the
town got to 10 participants the cost of
the weatherization or the solar panels
went down if they got to 20 participants
right the cost of the solar panels for
everybody and for the weatherization
went down and so not only did you get
everybody to sort of cajo everybody else
in but you also started getting
everybody talking about the issues and
finessing the problems and actually
making a better product for everyone and
it was fun I mean we're talking towns of
like 1400 people we're not talking about
some huge thing like one building in New
York City has 1400 people and I can't
get my building to like even put a solar
panel on our roof right I mean it's
really hard but um it was so joyful and
fun and silly and and real like I and I
say silly with most
endearing means I when I mean real like
it was just so real and I just I just
put that out there
because because like Brian said in the
beginning you know we we can take an
austerity politic as the only way of
getting through this or we can just
improve our air quality improve our our
our water quality improve our our
efficiency and savings all of these
things like like why are we resisting it
which is my
question ultimately for all of us but
does anybody else want to give their
perspective I totally went off and a
should of end we are overtime but I feel
like this group is Rich um well I I do I
would love to respond to that Jennifer
real quickly because I I I feel and
someone asked us in the one of the q&amp;as
you know it's the like a lot of things
in this space The Upfront cost is often
the thing that is the hurt um and that
that can that can take many different
forms you know The Upfront cost might be
scary when you're comparing it to a
lower cost fossil fuel piece of
equipment that's going to cost you more
over the life of the product but The
Upfront cost is lower that's one
impediment another impediment is
particularly if you're talking to more
of the um another version of that if
particularly for lower income folks it's
like
wow like the idea of a new water heater
is just like so not in the cards because
they're trying to keep food on the table
so those upfront costs just become like
completely showstoppers so I kind of
feel like the incentives were one take
at this the IRA the whole idea of the
IRA was that at the least it the um the
very least it would encourage people to
buy more efficient equipment um which is
going to be better in the long run but
in the best case scenarios you these
more efficient versions of heat pumps
and other devices are competitive with
gas equipment or or fairly close because
of those upfront incentives so that was
one way to get at it but the other way
that I just still scratch my head about
like why this isn't more of a thing is
financing because if you think about
nobody buys a car with cash you know I
mean almost everyone finances their cars
when they purchase them and that's why
it's relatively easy to buy these
expensive devices because you're
spreading the cost out over time and
it's just weird to me that there isn't
more like prevalent examples of that I
think that the number of people who
actually Finance their um HVAC equipment
is teeny it's really small um why is
that it's weird these things cost almost
as much as an automobile and yet people
have to pay cash for them it's crazy so
I I that's another Frontier I would love
to try to crack the code on somehow
Sarah you probably have more experience
with that um but yeah upfront cost
that's a big heard of just to underscore
the the weird aversion to financing I've
been seeing that for a decade and I
think until it can be as easy as on bill
um that's where I've started to see and
you know I used to do some work in
Vermont and Green Mountain Power over
there did did a great job building some
of this into their rate structure and
that's when they really started to see
the adoption but it was years of having
great programs through the local banks
just no
uptake yeah I can I just also mentioned
uh uh as a resource there's a really
Dynamic group of family consumer science
Educators in extension that pay
attention to household Finance they're
not going to solve the problem by
creating the new Financial tools but
they are a really good group to help
people understand what tools do exist
that might that might um from the
consumer side make it easier for people
to understand the benefits of going uh
this kind of Route
so Dave did you put a link on that did
you say I'm looking for it I don't have
it right here yet I have not put a link
but I will if if I can before Jenny
shuts us down
so and if not I'm gonna talk to you
anyway
yes I just want to say thank you all so
much this has been a really great uh tag
team of ideation and um and doing
uh I I hope everybody knows that you can
contact me with ideas of things that you
want to be presented next um because we
are trying very hard to get multiple
voices in order to cross fertilize and
and innovate as well as Implement so um
be sure to send me an email and you can
also join nekki we're all a volunteer
crew um uh and there's many different
ways to participate um but more
important than joining necki is figuring
out how to make this happen in your own
community so um I just want to say thank
you so much for our speakers today you
you have my heart this was great and um
I hope you all have a great rest of your
day the recordings will be online within
about seven days and um and I hope to
hear from you all soon thank you
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu