this is a production of Cornell
University I appreciate everyone uh my
name is Gabriel Gurley I'm the program
manager for a energy New York program um
we Statewide program working with uh
Cooperative Extension offices throughout
the state um but our offices uh are
located in the tokin county Cooperative
Extension Office
so I'm going to spend a few minutes
talking to you today about uh audit uh
Farm energy use um talk about a little
bit about the uh auditing process uh
energy auditing process for farms uh so
I'll give you a little bit of
description about that and uh also talk
about the technical supports and
grants so I'm going to first begin
talking a little bit about our the
energy auditing process What It Is What
It entails what kind of benefits um
someone can receive from an energy
audit um afterwards I'm going to spend a
little bit of uh time talking about
different energy grants financing
programs there's a wide away of programs
there's no way for me to cover it all in
this presentation today but I'm going to
hit the major ones and all the ones uh
that I'm going to present today is
related to agricultural production I'll
probably touch a little bit about
residential um but again mostly uh
because of the program I work in I'm
going to spend my time and focus on
those that particularly address
agricultural production and then finally
I'm going to kind of tie it all in and
um kind of point out some things that at
a energy New York we can assist with in
this in these endeavors
so first off what is an energy audit and
what are their
benefits an energy audit sometimes it's
also referred to as an energy assessment
it's basically just a detailed
examination of a building's energy use
um in the case of agricultural
production um it can entail the entire
agricultural production process on the
farm so buildings for example it may be
a poultry building or some sort of
livestock building a barn that uh the
energy audit process will go through and
evaluate but it could be other things
specifically on the farm um P specific
pieces of equipment for example um if
you're in value added production for
example it could itail Refrigeration
cooling uh ventilation for f stock
pretty much it covers everything across
the board so um I talk about buildings
often times folks think about an energy
assessment referring to the residential
home which those are available as well
um but when it comes to agricultural
production it covers the entire
agricultural production that's on the
farm and the purpose of an energy audit
is to uh identify energy saving
opportunities and improving performance
and that's both within the buildings and
for the agricultural production
operations
overall what's included in an energy
audit an energy audit or assessment of
how a building or a tire production uh
operation uses energy where it is being
wasted and any safety or health
issues um often times when you get the
report it's a very detailed report it
breaks everything down uh on the
operation um factoring in uh where the
energyy is being used where it's being
wasted safety or health
issues um often times in that energy
audit it'll also have what they have an
called an executive summary page it kind
of gives you the highlights of what the
entire report is um but it's looks like
an engine an engineering report it's
very
detailed um the report can be multiple
dozen pages long um so it really does
cover everything from a to z uh in terms
of the farm operation or in the case of
residential uh the homeowner as
well so those list of recommendations uh
recommended Energy Efficiency measur me
and Associated Energy savings po uh
potentials are listed in that
report um it'll break down equipment by
equipment uh when an energy auditor
comes out and performs an energy auditor
assessment on the farm they will
actually go through every piece of
equipment they'll pull the information
off the name plates off the equipment
they detail that they put it in the
report um and they have the ability to
measure and calculate based upon the
piece of equipment what potential energy
uses it's uh consuming on the farm and
also if there could be based upon uh the
production measures that the uh Farm is
using uh they could give recommendations
on where some Associated Energy savings
can
be one of the things about the energy
audit or energy assessment as well
particularly with Farm production is
that they don't give recommendations
just to say oh well you know you can go
Net Zero by doing this this and this
when the energy auditor uh comes out on
to the farm they have a conversation
with the farmer themselves and they will
listen to the farmer and try to figure
out what their goals and objectives are
and when they recommend make a
recommendation on the report
they try to make sure that that those
recommendations is something that the
farmer can actually
Implement um something that is within
the goals of what the farm is trying to
achieve and they certainly don't make
recommendations that's going to make the
farm the farmers's life harder so if
they don't come out and make
recommendations just to say well you do
this you can reduce the amount of energy
used by such and such if they know that
it's going to create more issues in the
production process for the
farmers then they're probably not going
to follow through with the
recommendations so they really try to
take a realistic approach when uh the
energy audits are uh performed and what
they put in the report in terms of those
energy saving
measures when is an energy audit useful
um
I've got two items here but there's
multiple reasons why energy audit is
useful uh for first before making any
energy saving improvements or adding a
renewable energy system it's important
to have
one also having a plan for equipment
Replacements that increase Energy
Efficiency when a component fails so one
of the benefits about an energy
assessment is often times it's usually
uh somebody requests one because they
want to see what they can do to save
energy of course that's what the energy
assessment report will produce but let's
say it's something on a major piece of
equipment the equipment hasn't failed
yet it was going to be a major
investment for the farmer so maybe the
farmer says I can't do it right now but
it's something I should look into well
any piece of equipment sooner or later
is going to fail so guess what if the
farmer has had an energy assessment or
AIT performed when that piece of
equipment fails the first thing they can
do is go grab that report and say yes I
can remember that the energy auditor
told me something about replacing this
with another piece of equipment they've
got a road map to to go by so they're
not just going out and making impulse
decisions they can go by that
recommendation replace it with a newer
piece of equipment it's more energ energ
efficient so it's really like having a
road map or a plan in place in case
something were to change or disent piece
of equipment were to
fail um sometimes an energy audit is
required um if a farmer for example is
either purchasing a new Farm or looking
at making some production
changes sometimes the lender may require
an energy assessment to be performed
so sometimes the farmer will call out
and request an energy assessment for
those purposes as
well energy a audits can help you
understand how much energy your
residence or agricultural op operation
uses it PRI prioritizes problem areas
and
fixes helps make your residents or
agricultural production areas more
efficient and comfortable able for the
workers livestock and you so it's not
just necessarily about trying to save
the energy you know that's one of the
goals but also it can help make the
operation more efficient and more
comfortable for everyone that's on the
farm uh learn how to uh you use your
energy sometimes that energy audit
sometimes folks don't even realize that
some pieces of equipment is consuming
that much of electricity so you learn a
lot of about the equipment and what may
be using energy on the farm to determine
where the energy is being wasted to make
personalized
recommendations and to help lower your
energy
bills so how do you apply for an energy
audit here in New York it's extremely
simple to get an energy audit performed
the energy audits are available at no
charge to customers of an invest your
own utility and what that means is uh
nice egg National Grid any of your major
utility companies they're considered to
be investor own utilities and the
easiest way to determine that is when uh
farmer can opens up their utility bill
if they look on their bill and they see
a systems benefit charge posted there on
their the utility bill that indicates
they're eligible for the energy audit
anyone who looking is looking for uh an
energy audit for
residents best way to do is reach out to
your Regional clean energy Hub you can
also contact participating local service
providers uh for those energy audits as
well a lot of HVAC companies and those
sorts of folks uh can come out and
provide an energy assessment as well for
agricultural operations it's very simple
as well
uh you go through nera's energy audit
program um if you don't you go to nera's
website look up their agricultural
program page there's a link posted there
um if you can't find it there then of
course go to the a energy New York
website uh we have the links posted
there we also have a contact us button
at the top where you can click and post
a message to myself and uh G in the
office and we can get you relay to the
appropriate person um for an energy
audit but the application itself there's
an online application that can fill out
and John you've helped walk through some
folks as well when they call into the
office uh through that process but
there's an online application folks who
are maybe a little intimidated on
filling out applications online that's
where John and has helped folks out
before through energy New York uh the
paper application it's literally one
page front and back basically all they
have to do is fill out their name a
telephone number email address what type
of Commodities they produce on the farm
and sign on the back um it's just about
as simple as anything that you can apply
for um again these audits are per uh
available at no charge to the customers
and these audits are also available
every two to three years so uh once you
get an energy audit performed it's not
one of those things where you just get
report you set it aside if your
production changes on the farm maybe
you're entering into some new crops or
uh maybe growing some different types of
or raising some different types of
livestock maybe you're getting into a
value added production on your farm at
any time there's changes happen to your
farm you can request to have another
free energy audit
performed okay so that covers a little
bit about the energy audit
process I'm going to touch a little bit
here on the various grants and financial
programs that are
available um so I'm going to cover in
three major areas the USDA re program uh
utility specific programs and I'm
highlighting National
grid uh just as an example because they
cover such a large area of the state but
the other utilities throughout the state
um offer various programs as well so
just because you're in NYSEG or rg&amp;
service area they have programs
available uh for agricultural producers
as well and then I'll touch on a few
other uh resources as well nrcs
programs uh USDA
and the nerta re technical assistance
program one of the things that you don't
see on here is that there's State
programs that New York state offers at
the state level as
well um so for the sake of time we
couldn't go into all those but they have
specific programs that may tie in to
some of these programs as well and one
of the questions that's always asked is
well can I apply for a reap Grant and
apply for a state grant program or
financing the answer is in many cases
yes you can stack incentives and grants
on top of one another to help reduce
those costs the barriers cost to
adopting energy
efficiencies so first up is the reap
program uh the re program or uh it's an
acronym for Rural energy for America
program it was first created back in
2008 in by Congress a new uh farm bill
and reap helps uh support Farmers
ranchers and Rural communities adopt en
Energy Efficiency measures and also
utilize renewable energy
sources so the
objectives for reap uh re facilitates
its Mission through two primary
objectives one it's a grant or loan
guarantee to agricultural producers
and Rural businesses for Energy
Efficiency improvements and the purchase
of renewable energy systems it also
provides grants to service providers to
assist farmers in getting energy Audits
and planning and development of
utilizing renewable energy
sources to qualify for reap Grant um
agricultural producers must receive at
least 50% of their gross income from
their agricultural office
operations uh reap qualified Energy
Efficiency improvements it covers a wide
range of areas uh that re funding can be
used for I just put a few bullet points
on here um but most of the things that
you could typically think of um in terms
of energy and uh efficiency improvements
it will cover so high efficiency heating
ventilation air conditioning systems
insulation lighting Cooling and
Refrigeration units energy efficient
equipment and
more reap loan guarantee
details uh loans guarantee are available
up to 75% of total eligible cost um for
a grant the amount is up to 50% of total
eligible project cost reap also combines
Grant and Loan guarantee funding up to
75% of of the total eligible costs based
upon the
eligibility um loan amounts and terms
are based upon the use of the funds but
you typically the funds loan terms can
go all the way up to 40
years couple links there uh for the USDA
re program and you can also visit AG
energy New York
website utility specific programs again
I'm just going to hit some of the
highlights for National Grid um they
have a agriculture program rebate that's
available to nonresidential customers
for Energy Efficiency upgrades to
facilities and Equipment there's two
types of rebates prescriptive rebates
and custom rebates prescriptive means
they already have a list of what rebates
they could provide on a fixed amount
basis predescribed custom rebates means
they can go in and evaluate the project
and base a custom rebate on based upon
an analysis and specific
calculations prescriptive rebates
include lighting hbac processed systems
commercial kitchen equipment
Refrigeration of course
agriculture programs open to all uh
non-residential use utility customers
but that includes agricultural
producers uh they have the residential
program that uh gives you a monthly
discount on the electric bill uh the
programs administered on on an annual
basis uh beginning September one you
must uh apply by January uh July 1st
excuse me to be eligible and all
National Grid agricultural customers
are um
eligible uh for the sake of time just uh
there's the agricultural productivity
program as well uh got a few details
there um what the capital Investments
are what the total funding is available
to
those um and what kind of prescriptions
they uh provide uh for that particular
program um if you have any questions
feel free to reach out to me um go to
the a energy New York website you can
click contact us button uh that's the
best way to reach out to us uh the other
incentive programs just very quickly uh
nrcs on Farm energy initiatives house
programs as well we have those listed on
our
website USDA Farm storage facility Loan
program provides low interest interest
loans uh that can help in energy
efficiencies and storage
facilities and our Nera re technical
assistance program provides free
assistance for those that are may be
applying for a re Grant um and that
assistance available throughout New York
State
so appreciate everyone um again anyone
that has any questions can always visit
our website at AG energy New York and uh
feel free to reach out to us if you have
any questions or need any
assistance this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu