this is a production of Cornell
University okay so hi everyone my name
is Elise tomaseski I'm really excited to
talk about my research where I've been
using chrisper cast 9 to Target fruit
obis related genes in filis graa and
I'll also go over an unexpected path
that my research has taken over the last
couple of years so fisus graa or ground
cherry is my model species it's a
species that I work on it is a solonus
fruit crop species and it produces small
sweet yellow berries however it is an
underutilized species that's not grown
on a large scale largely because it is a
semi-domesticated species as it has a
sprawling growth habit and high rates of
fruit drop PR the name ground
cherry the fruit are covered by an
inflated caix or a husk and the husk the
color does not always corate with the
ripeness of the fruit so on the left are
fruit that had dropped and I peeled back
the Kos all of these and there are a
there is a clear gradient of ripeness in
the fruit so even though they have
dropped they are not always rip not only
is that an issue but the fruit drop is
an issue because you can then introduce
soil born pests or pathogens to the
fruit and making them unsellable and
Farmers would lose and profit that
way therefore for my research I am using
frisper cast 9 and fistus graa as my
model species to explore the genetics
behind fruit exision as well as trying
to develop ground cherry lines with
reduced fruit drop
there are four main steps of fruit
excision or fruit drop however the
genetics behind each step is largely
unknown these four steps include the
formation of an obis Zone which are
small cytoplasmically dense cells this
is where the Detachment occurs and it
forms on the pedestal that connects the
fruit to the plate these obyan Zone
cells then become competent to external
signals that induce cell separation and
then CIS cence and Detachment occurs for
my research though I am interested in
aing the genetics behind the obis Zone
formation and how that
occurs a likely group of genes for me to
Target were Mbox transcription facets
these are largely known to upregulate or
induce floral organ development and
they're also known to work in groups of
four or a
Teter in tomato which I'm kind of
illustrating on the left here there are
three known Mbox transcription factors
that induce obis Zone development these
include jointless and what I'm showing
is a wild type pedestal on the top and a
jointless mutant pedestal on the bottom
there is no obis Zone this is also the
same for mutants of ma P where MC as my
diagram shows and jointless 2 however
interestingly the jointless 2 orthologue
does not exist in fesal fora and I'll
talk about that more at the end of my
presentation but for my work I'm using
crisper cast 9 to Target the orthologue
of ma cix which is npf3 and the
orthologue of jointless which is also
named jointless and I hypothesize that
That Knocking out these genes would also
inhibit or not have an exision Zone form
on the pedesto and that is exactly what
I found so on the left is a wild type BR
cherry fruit and zooming in it's very
clear where this exision zone is present
this is where the ccent stops on the
pedestal this is where the fruit will
detach however in my mutant in the
middle here this subcision Zone does not
exist it's not present by the naked eye
in fact these fruit will continue to
stay on the plant and actually Decay or
uh continue to ripen until a physical
force is applied however I do want to
note that it's not impossible to pull
these fruit off it's not harming the
plant like it would in a Pepper or a
golden
Berry similarly to my jointless mutants
my npf3 mutants also do not form an
exision Zone shown in the middle picture
here as
well another phenotype that I'm seeing
on these npf3 mutants only is that the
Kix does not coales to a single point uh
as it does in the wild headp you can
also see the berry in there it's
completely yellow so it's already ripen
which is a great phenotype that I like
to see and it's helping with the
uniformity of
ripening so just because I couldn't see
the Obion Zone by ey doesn't mean that
it didn't form and I wanted to see on a
microscopic level if the Obion Zone was
forming so what I did was I chose fruit
that the cix or the fruit was starting
to ripen I embedded those in parin wax
and sectioned those and what I saw was
an Obion Zone in my wild PPE so on the
very left what you can how to orient
yourself is that on the left would be
the pedestal connecting to the plant and
towards to the right would be connecting
to the fruit there is a clear zone of
obsidion Zone cells they're small and
Darkly stained however in my jointless
Mutant shown in the middle here this
Obion zone is not present I don't see
these small banding SS similarly in my
mpf 3 mutant this also doesn't exist
this is exactly what I wanted to
see zooming out we on a larger scale
this is also important both not only in
a large scale agricultural setting but
in the greenhouse so I grew up wild type
plants and my Mutant both jointless npf3
and these are going at the same time
everything's the same and you can see
there large accumulation of fruit
occurring on the the rakes that hold up
the pl not only does this cause more
time for me as a researcher to have to
go and clean my green houses but you're
increasing pressure of both diseases and
pests in the greenhouse similarly as
I've already stated on a large scale
this would be bad because You' be losing
profit due to fruit that are on the
ground so my mutants are holding up and
they're dropping maybe one or two fruit
likely because you're jumping into the
at that
point up until this point you guys have
kindly assumed that I have created
Knockouts however the last couple of
years I've had a lot of issues detecting
what edits I've made using crisper cast
I couldn't produce an amplion using PCR
despite many different methods and uh
attempts and what looking further I
found that my region is Rich in tandem
at repeats which makes PCR an awful
nightmare so I found a PCR protocol from
daughter wall and colleagues where they
use a two-step PCR method and they lower
the EXT extension temperature and
increase the amount of begging inpl
typically an extension temperature of 72
degrees is used and I couldn't get an
amplion shown by this gel here so when I
lower the extension temperature to 68
degrees I was able to get an amplion so
using that method and my optimized
protocol I finally got bands which I was
really excited for so it's clear the the
band on the very right is my wild type
and all of my meals are evidence of
deletions in the gene itself this re
jointless by the way however this was
also concerning to me because fos graa
is reported to be a diploid so at
maximum I should be getting two edited
alals and I'm seeing three bands in most
of my examples here this indicated to me
that these weren't actually diploid so I
had to figure this out and I did this
with two ways first with a pollen
germination screen that was adapted from
the Litman lab where they found that
diploid plants had one pollen tube per
pollen grain however non diploids would
have a mixture of two pollen tubes per
pollen grin what I'm showing on the left
here the picture of my wild type fist
grusa pollen and thankfully for me these
all have one pollen two per pollen grain
meaning that my stock is in fact
Diffy what I'm showing now are pictures
of my mutants from jointless so the top
two here they have these two pollen
tubes for pollen grain as well as this
bottom left one here indicating to me
that they're not diff also interestingly
my non-transformed control or my wild
type that went through regeneration also
had two pollen tubes for poll grade this
is actually good for me because now I
have a tetrol wild type that I can use
for
comparison I kind of already spoiled it
a little bit but I then needed to use
flow cytometry to kind of figure out
what was going on if I had an anupy A
hexaploid or a tetrol so I was using
Leaf tissue with the help of Lena Wilson
and essentially what you can do with uh
flow cytometry is estimate your Tetra or
your Ploy level based on the Nuclear
fluoresence So essentially a diploid
would have half the amount of
fluorescence as a tetr and this would be
shown by an increase on the x-axis so on
the left you have a diploid Peak at 50
and on the right we have a tou Peak at
100 for my samples this is exactly what
I saw so my on the left is my wild type
and I had a fluoresence level of 10,000
but my non-transformed control or the
Tetra wild type that I expected was at
20,000 doubling the fluoresence peak
indicating to me that it was a toucher
point this was also the case for my
jointless plants as well as my npf3
plant so before I go on to what's next I
also sympathize greatly with those who
work with poly deoy plants has been a
lot of work but I still have a lot more
to go um I'm planning I'm do in the
process of trying to identify other Mbox
transcription factors that interact with
jointless and npf3 seeing what might
have taken the place of joint list too I
then will once I get candidates I plan
to Target them using crisper and also
screen those for any obis Zone
prototypes and with that I'd like to
thank all of our committee members all
of the members from the van G Bon Labs
as well as the bti greenhouse staff for
keeping my plants healthy and happy uh
the flow citometry team especially Lena
Wilson and Jackie Mahoney as well as the
Litman lab members Sergey and MAA from
BCI for their help with the microscopy
work as well as Victoria and tisar who
were my Ru students Joseph Hill who
helped a lot with the PCR
troubleshooting and last but not least
Nathan re who was a former member of the
B Club who helped with the jointless
crisper construct design as well as
generating the mpf 3s and with that I'm
happy to take any
questions
yes very nice uh is it easier to look at
col to look at like group tips for or I
was also considering doing that um I
because the pro the protocol for bplus
in the pollen had already been figured
out it was a three hour protocol for me
so I could collect pollen germinate it
and then I was looking in the microscope
pretty like four three to four hours
later so it worked well for me I could
use the root tip
squash about three hours yeah three to
four yeah I don't want to be this person
here but we'll
see um so
while he's doing that I promise they do
um I what really started this off for me
was I was in the greenhouse and I
noticed that my flowers were incredibly
large I thought I was kind of going
crazy for a second there but the flowers
are very large and if he's able to get
this up I'll show you the other thing I
noticed in the flowers themselves was
deeper anti in pigmentation um but
you'll also have larger leaves they're a
lot Greener so I can pretty easily
detect a teslo versus a diploid in
my if it ever comes back you'll be able
to see it there we go so not only are
they larger but they're also more
pigmented um both in the petals and the
filaments I this isn't necessarily a
phenotype I think this is a jointless
phenotype but yeah I'm just showing the
darker pigmentation here and in the fils
you have an pigmentation
like we don't really have any other this
gr or ground cherry accessions that I
could screen I mean we've screened the
wild Ty for that that we have and it's
deploy um our goldenberry which is also
a fist L is a petri Floy that we know
and that people have reported on a
lature um but I've screen I have created
other knockout lines that I'm not
showing today I think three of them
almost all of them were touch employees
as well I know other people in the lab
have generated them as well and it's
about 80% you'll get that are touch or
touch the high
in I'll keep the ball moving here so
thank you hello everyone good afternoon
um as you said my name is Ain I'm a
third year PhD student in Mike G's lab
um and I'm excited to talk with you all
today about integration of different
proximal remote sensors for uh improved
characterization of ergonomically
important traits such as yield
so proximal remote sensors have
applications to both
highy and breeding programs and by
researchers for other projects as well
as Precision
agriculture so traditional phenotyping
methods are typically time and labor
intensive um and can be temporarily
constrained um high thut phenotyping on
the other hand may allow things like uh
early season prediction of end of season
traits um thereby uh decreasing the time
breeding cycle um can help with
phenotyping more individuals for uh Goos
or training populations for genomic
prediction um and uh being able to
phenti a greater temporal resolution uh
may help understanding of genotype by
environment interactions and uh
parameterizing prop growth
model and then um for Growers um the
ability to detect pest or disease and
allocate resources to different parts of
the
field however uh application of proxim
amount sensors to each of these things
relies on both the uh relevance and the
accuracy and different sensors capture
different Spectra um and different
platforms allow collection across
varying scales so um there may be unique
information contained within each of
these that may increase both the
relevance and accuracy um of using these
sensors
however because of the uh complex and
high dimensional nature of these uh of
the data streams collected from these uh
sensors integration is uncommon and
typically lacks
generalizability so I'm going to be
talking about two different platforms
and sensors first we have uh
multispectral images selected by unied
aerial
verticles um and then we also have blar
scans collected by unoccupied ground
Vehicles so um all of this data was
collected on genom to field maze hybrids
planted at musra research
for and these are U these are all two
row plot now the multispectral images
you can see here have five things we
have blue green and red which constitute
typical image um and then we have red
Edge and near infrared as
well so uh the multispectral camera is
mounted to the bottom of the Drone here
um and all of the raw images have about
80% overlap so these are cards stitched
together using a software called piix 4D
to create an orth
Mosaic that orth Mosaic is been uploaded
to platform called image free developed
in the robins
lab uh to take the orthomosaic and split
it into these thought level images
here so the uh lar scans are collected
by the ground Rover here the lighter
camera you can see uh on the back um the
Rover is uh driven in between the rows
of the two row plots um and the lighter
scans are converted into
three-dimensional Point plots so you can
see the the two rows here and some
additional points being picked up from
adjacent plots which are ultimately
propped out uh to give us this this spr
plot here now each of these uh points
has an X Y and Z coordinate uh denoting
its position in space so uh the lar
scans give us a 3D reconstruction of
each plot
so in order to achieve integration uh
we're using um machine learning models
called autoencoders so an autoencoder is
a deep unsupervised um machine learning
model which takes uh its input for
example our multispectral image um
passes it through a first neural network
the encoder to produce um what is called
the latent space here so this latent
space is a reduced representation of the
original
image this uh latent space has then
passed through a second neural network
the decoder which is analogous to the
first to reproduce that original image
and this model is optimized uh such that
the difference between the original and
the Reconstruction is
minimized um and in that way the uh
latent space or the latent phenotypes
um are we you know we hope the important
features reducing the noise of these
images so we first trained this model on
the um multi-spectral images um with an
original dimensionality of about 40,000
values um down to a single Vector that
is um 512 um
values so achieving um integration on
these images um will include will
involve taking training these models on
multispectral images um and again on
point clots extracting the latent space
from each of these and um concatenating
them into a single object which can then
be used for
prediction so to evaluate um training of
the auto on multispectral images and the
point pods which I'll show in a moment
um we uh looked at visualizations of the
original images and the uh
reconstruction so you can see here that
uh the latent space um was able to
effectively
reconstruct our original
image so we similarly trained a model on
the lier skin uh this involves a little
bit or a couple of additional
prepressing steps so we take the um
original point5 as you can see on the
left um kind of Stack the two rows
together um so taking this xais and
flipping it um and then compressing
along the time Dimension here to produce
um a
triangular uh single Dimension density
map and again you can see that the
latent space contained both the
sufficient and necessary information to
reconstruct this um High dimensional
image so the next thing that we wanted
to do was um investigate using
preliminary investigations of what kind
of information was contained within the
lane space so um this is showing a PCA
thoughts of the
512 Len codes extracted from each of
about
5,000 colored first by ndbi and again by
the
date um so this is signaling that there
is biologically relevant information
contained within the latent space and
similarly do the same thing for our
Point
CL
pattern so our next
steps are to uh take the the latent
spaces and use those to predict ground
truth phenotypes so we've done some
preliminary tests of this with um grain
yield which I've um not shown here um
taking some uh you know simple linear
models um we are seeing bi electrical
signal um
and in particular um we are looking at
different ways to account for the
temporal data um that we have here
so with that I'd like to thank my
committee might def Sun Margaret Smith
i' like to thank Liam um Nick leac Amy
Schultz and others um who have helped
collect all of this data and with that
I'll take
question how do you measure that the
reconstructed image is good
enough that's a great question so
um Ely we'd like to use the prediction
accuracy from that second step so once
you take in the L using those
toyp um but you know the initial tests
looking at the loss of these different
different um you know I wouldn't it's
it's possible that
uh more blurry or higher lck in the auto
and would actually be
greater prediction
accuracy
the over
model
timately are you planning on looking at
I guess I'm curious when it comes
to incorporating
this mod
The
drus
Beneficial other or it's
really that you think
it's yeah absolutely so um ultimately I
think that will depend on the trade info
um but for something like um you know
more complex like yields
or Lai or resource um
the you know 3D architecture that that
something we are hypothesizing will lend
additional information that will
increase that accuracy um that is
something that we're saying to test as
well so we just use the Rovers we just
use the Drone
together can you go back to the slide
with the PCA I guess I was there was
that the pc1 had explained 9 % Mar so
which suggest that all 52 are pretty
highly
correlated understand that
right so why not just represent this
with two values instead of 512 I mean
like that first PC is explaining almost
everything that you have in your
52 yeah yeah so I think the
the advantage of not using something
would be you don't have that linearity
constraint um on the looking at the
relationship between the
different
um the you know one
potential reason that that that first
value is
high really highly correlated with the
date or something so you're really able
to pick out like the brightness level so
even though that high percentage it
might be something that's not
biologically
but if you did the the auto process on
just one
dat so so that dat isn't a factor
causing variation
what would it look
like maybe thing is swamped by dat yeah
that's you
get yeah so um From Below you're going
to get through two reconstructions of
like the ears help for example where
it's from above um particularly later
days that Cy closure to to on that um
yeah like Dan count
um yeah other that below py that you
have
that wonder if you tried uh going Auto
ENC train it's looking for heritability
so what you do do you train not the same
row you get
aired replicated Row in
other and build the
space yeah that that's a great Point um
something that we have talked about Jing
but not doing yet is int introducing you
know like a secondary loss function for
genotype or a you know spatial location
in the field or something like that so
um yeah I actually just actually make a
result
opposite
replic
us just
so like in other words you want the
decoder to generate something that
resembles the
other you can also do this by running
the r opposite direction grows and other
sides grow so that's the other things
people doing like props they're trying
to they run out one
side okay yeah thank you yeah definitely
try yeah yeah thank you
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu