this is a production of Cornell
University all right well thank you so
much Jeff for the introduction I'm
really excited to be here with y'all
today um like Jeff said I'm Elizabeth
McCarthy my pronouns are she or hers and
yeah my um love affair with niiko Shana
Valentine's Day we're going to talk
about love of plants um started when I
was undergrad and I never want to leave
it um I took a little bit of a hatus
occasionally but not very much um so so
I'm excited to talk to you about how
poly and hybridization affect um flower
evolution in these awesome species there
all right so I'm going to start with an
introduction and then I'm going to tell
you two stories about flower color
evolution in polyploids one on a young
polyploid that's involving homeologue
bias and subgene abdomin and one on some
older polyploids that involves some
transgressive delin and production and
then I'm going to finish up with some of
the things that we're doing in the lab
right now so you can see what my awesome
undergrads soon Portland are
doing um so alop poly involves two
things both whole genome duplication um
and interspecific hybridization so as we
can see up here we have two different
diploid species here are um their sets
of chromosomes different colors um and
they come together um to create hybrids
that have um four sets of chromosomes
but two different diverg genomes back in
the same nucleus um and this leads to
this genomic shock where they have to
figure out how to work with each other
um and this leads leads to all sorts of
different changes but can also lead to
changes in phenotype like we can see um
in these poly plates here and so I'm
interested in how these phenomena lead
to differences um in flower
phenotypes poly is everywhere especially
in land plants um so we have ancient
poly at least in all seed plants another
in all flowering plants and when we have
so many genomes access that we have now
we can see that all of these red um
lineages are holding genome duplications
across land plants so we have ancient
poly
everywhere on the flower side of things
we know that morphology and color is
going to affect the type of pollinators
um that interact with these flowers so
here are just a subset of pollinators
and you can see that the flowers that
they're visiting have different colors
different shapes they open at different
times if we could smell them they would
smell different um so we have this
really exciting system where we can look
at differences not only in the plants
but see how they're interacting um with
animal
pollinators and we're going to see this
pathway a lot don't worry it's coming
back um and this is the flavonoid
biosynthetic pathway which is a branch
pathway with many enzymes working
together so the enzymes are in bolded by
the arrows and they produce all of these
different types of pigments that lead to
flower colors so on the bottom down here
we have our anthocyanins those are
colorful we have red ponin Pinker
magenta cyanidin and purple dadin and
then up here we have flavanol these are
colorless to humans but they absorb UV
so differences in flavanol can give
differences in signals to pollinators
that have UV receptors so all of them
are important for um the formations of
flower colors and how they interact with
pollinators and we also have some
understanding of some transcription
factors that are promoting um expression
of some of these flavonoid biosynthetic
pathway
genes so my overarching research
questions in my research program are
again how does this genome merger that
we get with hybridization yield the
novel and diverse phenotypes that we
observe in alop popoids and then how do
those phenotypes affect the evolution of
alop pooid
species um and nikana is a fantastic
system to study this in because we not
only have an amazing diversity of
flowers size shape color um but we also
have a ton of poly plates and they're
all different ages so we have some that
are young that have not undergone
speciation that are all less than a
million years old we have another
section that's about one or one and a
half million years old that has
speciated into a few species another
that is four million years old that is
speciated into a few more I ran out of
space on this slide there's yet another
one that is six million years old that
we think has maybe speciated into
potentially 90 different species what um
so there's a whole lot of stuff going on
here we have this really nice trajectory
of different age polypoid so we can ask
questions about the differences between
what's happening short-term and
long-term consequences of alop poly
boids as they
evolve today the stories I'm going to
tell you are involving Nico tobacum this
young polyploid and suction rande this
older one so we're going to get a flavor
of a couple of these
things all right so that first um story
I'm going to tell you about is about
niiko tobacum and home bias and subgene
OBD dominance and how it affects flower
color so Nicos tobacum is the product of
um nios sylvestris maternal progenitor
and Nikos tomoris paternal progenitor we
have these natural polyads like I showed
you already that are point6 million
years old and we have some different
exceptions that have some variation in
flower color we have these really bright
magenta ones and some light pink ones
but we also have synthetic polyploids
that we have create not me I use them
other folks have created in the lab um
where we have first generation polypoid
so we can get an idea of what's
Happening immediately following polypoid
to then compare that to what's happening
over evolution in our natural ones and
we again even in our synthetic lines see
some variation in flower color so we
have light pink ones and we have darker
pink ones so we have a great system that
we can
compare again flab by synthetic pathway
um the differences we see in these pinks
is mainly due to differences in cyanidin
pigments so that's the focus we're going
to think about um for this story at
least and we're also going to think
about homog expression bias so when we
have have Alo poly plates we have
homeologs two different progenitor
copies inside um our um genome and so
for example dfr which is one of our
genes in our pathway will have a
maternal copy and a paternal copy here
in purple and um teal and um we can have
either equal homeologue expression where
there's equal expression from both of
these um copies or we could have unequal
expression and then we call that homog
expression bias so for example Le down
here we have more copies um or more
transcript of our paternal copy than our
maternal copy so that would be an
expression bias towards the paternal
over the maternal and in the talk I'm
going to be reporting that homog
expression bias as the percent of our
maternal homologue um that is present so
the proportion of sylvestris um in these
popoids that's at the gene level so
we're thinking about how are the um
what's the ratio of our two progenitor
copies if we build that up to the whole
transcripton level we can see whether we
have um a a skew in the bias do we have
more um sylvestris bias genes than
tomoris bias genes or do we have an
equal number of each so if we do have a
bias we call that sub genome dominance
where one um progenitor genome has more
um expression overall um than the
other okay so my questions for this
story are what's the genetic base is of
the pigment and flower color differences
that we observe in these tobacco Alo
poly plates and do those correlate with
homeologue bias differences um in the
polyplay so do we see that these flower
color differences are associated with
homog bias
differences so to answer this question
um this is part of my postto work um
with Amy lit at UC rever side um we did
a developmental series for all of our
different um accessions so we have um we
corrected collected Corolla tissue from
early buds mid Buds and late floral buds
um across all of our different um our
progenitors our natural poly ples and
our synthetic polyes um and this work
was um um done by um two undergrads
amber Lorn and amilda cty um at UC
Riverside with
me um we did a transcriptive analysis
from these accessions um with an
illuminum platform and a 1x 85 reads um
we used a jovo approach to um to analyze
that data but we found that these short
reads made it really difficult to
distinguish between our two progenitor
copies and so when I got here um y'all
might recognize him Jacob Landis you'll
see his face a couple times um so in
collaboration with Jacob um we added
some long raid Oxford nanapur sequencing
to our progenitors to be able to
increase the quality of our assemblies
we create um made those Diplo assemblies
put them together in silico to create
our Alo poly assembly and with that long
read data we were able to distinguish
between our two copies so doing
great so um we are looking at our
different biosynthetic pathway genes I
told you you were going to see this
pathway a lot um I've colorcoded it so
we can have an idea of where the
different genes are so the colors in the
pathway are related to the colors in our
points um the points on these graphs are
flavonoid biosynthetic pathway genes the
violin plots behind them are the
transcription overall so in this graph
we're looking at differentially
expressed genes so on our x-axis we have
our different pairwise comparisons so
between our progenitors between our um
polyploids and our two different
progenitors and among our different
polyploids and then on our y- AIS we
have our log toold change of our
differentially expressed genes another
thing to notice is that our bold color
points are our tomoris Hogs and our um
transparent points are sylvestris looks
um so if we look and this is in our
early development so our early Bud
seeing what's going on there if we look
at our comparison between our
progenitors we see that most of our
genes are differentially expressed just
what we want to see um so our Sylvester
homeologs are upregulated in sylvestris
our tomoris Hogs are upregulated in
tomoris when we compare our tobacum or
polyploids to our maternal progenitor
unsurprisingly we see that our Eternal
Hogs are upregulated in the poly boids
compared to the maternal progenitor um
but we also see that we have some um
maternal Hogs that are upregulated in
the poly plates um compared to their um
progenitor similarly to our when we
compare to our paternal progenitor we
again see that the maternal copies are
upregulated in our polyploids but in
this case when we think about the
paternal hoges they're tend to be more
highly um expressed in the progenitor
compared to the polypoid and then when
we compare among our different types of
polyes um we are starting to really
tease out differences um that might be
involved in the differences in flower
color we see when we look at comparisons
between light pink and magenta flowers
we're starting to see genes that are
involved in producing anthocyanins um we
have the um black pig um points here our
FS Gene which gives us towards flavanols
and we see differences among our um
sessions here so we're starting to get
some of these pieces that might be
important in creating these differences
in flower
phenotype and so we looked at that a
little further we took these different
comparisons where we had light pink and
dark pink polyploids compared to each
other and we saw um whether there were
any commonly differentially expressed
genes to those comparisons um and so we
found a few um at least two comparisons
had an upregulation of dfr which is
again again this one that is the first
Gene towards making at the cyanin that
was upregulated in the dark pink um
phenotype whereas fls which is towards
making flavanols um is upregulated in
our light pink things and then we had a
handful of other genes that were single
tens but again they seem to be
concentrated in the genes they're um
producing um at the cyanin and they're
upregulated in our dark pink things um
or flavo were at the beginning of our
pathway for um our light pink um
types so let me took a step back and
we're asking this question about do
changes in homog bias in these genes
correlate with the differences in flower
color that we observe and so for these
plots um on our x-axis we have our
developmental time points so these are
our early mid and late um tissues and
then we're looking at our percent
sylvestris so that's our home bias so if
it's 0.5 that's equal if it's above 0.5
that's Sylvester's bias if it's below
0.5 that's tomoris biest um and our
sylvesters and toosi foris um are
behaving excellent we like to see that
um but in this case in LS we see that we
have pretty equal expression between our
two progenitors and that seems to be the
case for all of the accessions that we
looked
at um we did see some differences in
homeologue um expression bias but they
did not correlate with phenotype like we
hypothesized Iz they instead correlated
with the polyploid age so our synthetic
polyploids which are here in these um
pink and purple points um tended to be
more equally expressed whereas our
natural poly ples here in cyan and
orange are further away from that equal
expression so those are more biased um
and we saw that both in um Chi at the
beginning of the pathway and in dfr
towards making
epins um and we we found this overall we
found that natural polyploids tended to
display a stronger homog bias more
different than equal um both on our
flavonoid biosynthe pathway genes that
we can see here so we have an um
increased distance from equal in our
natural polyploids compared to our
synthetics and that also held across the
entire transcript so we're seeing we
have stronger bias in our natural poly
blades compared to our synthetic
polys so then we can ask this question
we looked at in individual genes what
about overall do we see sub genome
dominance where we have more sylvest
bias or more Tomos formis bias genes
than the other um and in this plot we
have our progenitor ratio on the x-axis
and our polypoid home ratio on our y-
axis then we have a lot of points in
here so I also put these um histogram
curves along the sides to give us an
idea of the distribution of those points
and
we can see that our progenitor
ratios and most of the ratios of our
polypoides are pretty balanced um we
have a relatively symmetrical curve here
um but we see this pink one we have this
line that is a little bit higher on one
side than the other so qm24 seems to
have a little bit of a bias towards
sylvestris um biased Hogs over
tomoris and if we look at their floral
phenotypes here's qm24 here's are the
two parents you can see that um q24
shares some things with sylvestris um
that maybe a little bit further away
from tomoris it has a pillar color it
has a smaller tube opening um it's more
star-shaped and so maybe um that is
reflected in the morphology that we
observe okay so to really answer that
question of whether we have sub genome
dominance what I did is I partitioned um
or grouped these genes into either
a sylvestris bias group or a tomoris
bias group um and then did a kisare test
to see whether we had um a a skew in
where um those genes fell but we did
this in several different thresholds so
first naively I think um I just split it
down the middle and if it was bigger
than 50% I put it in Sylvester's bias if
it was smaller than 50% I put it in to
toop foris bias but that gives us no um
no equal um expression and so we created
this buffer zone where we have equal
expression so we have a threshold where
it was considered Sylvester's bias if it
was 55% or above and tomoris biased if
it was 45% or below and then also
another threshold where it was 60%
versus 40 less than 40% everybody
feeling good about that can you tell
that I'm an undergrad person yes awesome
and then we took the
um the the numbers that are falling in
those categories to do the CH test to
see if we actually had sub genome
dominance um and what we found so here
on our x axis we have our progenitors we
have our different polyploids and then
on our y AIS we have bias so um our um
dotted line in the middle is no bias and
um above the line is atonement to sorus
bias and below the line is a sastrous
bias so what we see is we have a slight
bias across the Gen toward tomoris in
our progenitor ratio um a slight bias
toward sylvestris in qm24 like we saw in
our other plot but no bias in qm25 or
our natural poly blades so a little bit
of sub genome dominance here but not a
whole
lot okay but that's the whole genome
let's look at our at our flavo
biosynthetic pathway genes so we've seen
this um type of graph before we have our
pren ratio on the x-axis our polyploid
homog ratio on our y AIS um the gray
points are across the genome or trans
cryptum excuse me like we saw before but
now we're highlighting where our flavo
biosynthetic pathway genes are falling
out again they're colorcoded based on
our pathway um and what we can see is
that especially in our progenitor ratio
we have um a huge bias towards
tomoris we also have one in our poly
blades but it seems to be a little bit
less
but let's look at that in a slightly
easier way um we can see that our bias
has shifted a lot here right so we have
a huge bias towards Tomos foris in our
progenitors in our floid biosynthetic
pathway genes um but that is still
present but greatly reduced in our
polyads so we still see the stos foris
bias but it is way less present um
mostly our our synthetic poly voids are
unbiased um but we do see that
sylvestris um the whole genome um of
sylvestris is playing a role in
determining the flower color um of these
polyploids since we have that reduction
in the bias so even though sylvest does
not make pink colors it is involved in
making pink that its genome is involved
in making pink colors and
polyploids um so both of these genomes
are working together um to create our
differences that we see in
polys okay
again with these plots so a new thing
that we can think about um where Things
fall in these plots gives us an idea of
their regulation so if things fall out
in this horizontal line then they are
likely trans regulated because they're
in the same environment and so they're
going to have equal expression our
diagonal line represents our cyst
regulatory differences because those
cyst regulatory differences should track
with what we see in the progenitors to
what we see in the polyes giving us that
diagonal line and then anywhere else in
the plot is likely some sort of cyr
interaction um and what we can see from
this again we have our flavonoid
biosynthetic pathway genes pulled out
here here they're colorcoded by Gene
here they're colorcoded by our excession
so again our pink and our purple are our
synthetic ones and our cyan and our
orange are the natural ones um and what
we see is that often when we see
differences the um the synthetic poly
seem to have more equal expression and
then our natural polyploids have more
deviation and so this seems to suggest
that our natural polys are evolving cyst
regulatory differences um and cyst
regulatory changes as they're aging
based on what we're seeing in the
synthetics which I thought was pretty
cool when we were looking at the
sequences of these genes we also found
that a few of our tobac mix sessions had
a frame shift mutation in dfr which
again is that first Gene towards making
at the cyanin um and we have a one Bas
pair delation leading to this frame
shift um other folks um found this also
and did some um functional work on it
and they found that that frame shift led
to a non-functional gene um so when we
have the frame shift and we bombard
those um constructs into a white tobacco
mutant um the gene that does have a
frame shift is able to create um anth
thein you can see that in this cell
there's our control because our yfp is
there we know that our constructs are in
there um but when we have a frame shift
again we know this cell has that
construct but it can't produce any at
the sinin and so we know that this frame
shift is
nonfunctional so um we seem to see that
this dfr homologue and the Sylvester's
copy might be becoming Aude even in
young poly blades um and also because of
this we know it's nonfunctional we did
not include the that transcript in our
overall transcript analyses which I'm
going to show you
next because we found that our
homeologue bias did not correlate with
flower color but when we pull our um po
um expression together we do see that
overall expression of these genes does
correlate with flower color so you've
heard about fls which is making
flavanols and dfr which is making at the
cyanin we're looking at those um
expression of those genes across
development in these plots but we can
also look at the ratio here um because
um they're competing for the same
substrates in the pathway um and so what
we noticed when we looked at that ratio
is that we have an elevated fls to dfr
ratio early on in development in our two
polypoides that have a light pink
phenotype which you can see
here um and so we think that that is um
driving the flux of the p way towards
making flavanols at the expense of
making it the cyanin um and it also
seems to be because dfr um isn't
expressed as much early in development
it's being turned on later that's giving
us that um elevated fls dfr ratio but
because we have this
competition having more fls means that
we're going to have more of our pathway
going towards making flavonols less
going towards e thein giving us that
light pink phenotype
we also looked at the sequence variation
in this Gene um so this is work that has
been done by um Abigail McCoy who just
graduated last semester um she worked
with me for seven semesters at Portland
um and she was doing another project
that I'll tell you little bit about at
the end um but what we could see from
that is that we do have some variation
especially in regions that are important
in which substrates this Gene um is
interacting with um because it works on
several different ones um and so
sequence um variation may also affect
how these enzymes are functioning um and
so it seems like there's both a
transcription um an expression story to
this story and potentially um a sequence
Evolution story to this
story okay so conclude on this story we
found that homog bias does not correlate
with the differences in flower color
that we
observe we do see that we have a
stronger homeologue bias in our natural
poly plates compared to our synthetic
ones we have a slight sub genome
dominance in tm24 but not the
others we have a reduction of tomoris
bias in our flavonoid biosynthetic
pathog and popoids compared to their
progenitors and the transregulatory
differences are important early on in
polypoid evolution but perhaps our
natural popoids are evolving more s
regulatory differences as they
age we've got this um potential
pseudogene popping up and that our high
fls to dfr ratio is potentially driving
um our L Pig flower phenotype and that
our pigments that we see that are
different across these species are
probably due both to transcript levels
and also um the efficiency of these
enzymes all right so let's shift gears
we're going to talk about transgressive
delin in in these older poly poids so
here's nikana section Renda you've seen
sylvestris before she gets around um and
then obus aolia is our um paternal
parent here um and this is a single
event that happened four million years
ago that has speciated into a few
different poly
plates and we also see again flavonoids
we're going to talk about our pathway
this one is going to be um a flavanol so
campol and cotin and a delphinidin story
because you can see these purple
arrowheads here nudis and Randa have
delphinidin
the purple pigment but soest obus FIA
don't so that's a transgressive
character because it is outside the
range that we see in the prors which
just makes me really excited that's why
I love poly because what where is it
coming from we're gonna find
out so we have that transgressive
delphinidin which is here we also have
transgressive levels of Cam forall in
two of our species Randa and stoni
compared to our parents um and if I
didn't convince you before even though
the look white we do have that delin in
um in the tubes of these two
flowers um and so my questions here are
is this delin in coming because of
differences in sequence evolution in
differential expression or a combination
of
both and if sequence evolution is
important then is it because we have
complementation from our progenitors
where coming together in the same genome
um means that they can then produce that
pigment they couldn't before or has
there been some sort of Resurrection
of function during polyploid
Evolution told you You' see his face
again um so we did another transcript
analysis um again with a um early mid
and late floral buds um this time we had
a little bit of better um alumina um 2x
150 reads that did allow us to do um a
denovo assembly for our two progenitors
which we again combined into our um Alo
polyplay transcriptome um and then Abby
who you've seen before or also maed
these to a specific um just the the
reads of known flavonoid biosynthetic
pathway genes so we can pull out the
sequences of these genes to look at
whether they're functional or
not um so we found that they tend to not
have any non-sensor frame shift
mutations there are no stock coant or
frame shifts in any of our genes in
thean sylvestris the maternal
progenitor we did find that
obtusifolia has some either two or three
premature stop codons in ANS which is
our last um enzyme in our towards making
an thein um but we went and looked at
our homog copies of obtusa folio and our
poly blades and we didn't see those stop
codons we looked at another um younger
polyl that also has obtusifolia as a
parent and its obtusifolia homog also
doesn't have these stop codons so that
makes me think that these probably arose
in the lineage after it um created the
poly plates so it's not really playing a
role in the poly plates but maybe it's
playing a role in why um obtusifolia
cannot make any
antis um so because of a different
project one of my undergrads um who also
has graduated um Trinity Tobin found
that the ANS copy um of nikoa sylvestris
retains an intron in its transcripts so
here we have some gels here's our
genomic DNA from sylvestris um here's
cdna from another diploid so we can see
that we can definitely get
differentiation where we have with an
intron without an intron but in the cdna
from sylvestris we tend to have both so
we have some transcripts that have the
intron some that don't and this also
changes over time so early on in
development we have more transcript that
retain this Inon and less that don't
this is not DNA
contamination um if we do those same
samples in a different Gene we can see
that we only have um transcripts without
the Inon in our cdna samples so
something is going on here we looked at
the sequence um and if you leave that
intron in you get a stop Cod on pretty
much right away so likely these
transcripts with the intron in are
non-functional um and so this
potentially is playing a role in the
lack of anthocyanins in the maternal
progenitor so like we're going to look
into more about this because it's just
like what is happening here
okay if we look at our overall
expression of our flavonoid biosynthetic
pathway genes in our polyes we see good
correlation so our transgressive
flavanols um we have that those two that
have higher flavanols they have higher
expression of fls which is towards
making and the cyanin and two of these
genes that are early on in the pathway
which are going to give more flux
through the pathway overall so they're
increasing the amount of pigments that
are produced we also see really nice um
correlation between
um increased expression of Anin based
genes so at the bottom of the pathway or
the um transcription factors involved in
the two species the orange one and the
cyan one um that produce that
transgressive doin so it looks like we
have really good correlation between the
transcript differences and our pigment
differences in this
story um which we can see here right so
if we look and apologies for the um
quality of these graphs I'm not sure
what happened there um if we look at dfr
transcripts and correlate it to dadin we
have a really nice correlation similar
to F3 prime5 frame H which branch brings
this the pathway to our delphinidin
Branch we see that there's an increase
um in delphinidin with an increase in
transcript
accumulation um similar with fls if we
have an increase in fls we have an
increase in flavonol and then we also
looked at the the ratio between fls
which brings us towards flavanol and F3
Prime H which is going to differentiate
towards whether we're making cerol or
cotin flavanol and we see a correlation
between that fls to F3 Prim a ratio and
our um camper altic coration ratio so
we're seeing really good correlation
between what we are expressing and what
pigments we are
producing so to conclude this story um
our ANS Gene in both of our diploid
progenitors may be nonfunctional or have
reduced function um which may explain
why they don't make anthocyanins but it
seems like those mutations happened
later after they produce our poly plates
so it's not telling us why our
polypoides can produce um or influencing
why our polypoides can or cannot produce
fles um we do have increased expression
of early and fls genes um correlating
with increased flavanol production um
and increased expression of anthocyanin
based genes correlating with the
transgressive
delphinidin so seems like this story is
an expression difference story and less
so um a sequence Evolution
story all right I have a little bit of
time yes just want to highlight a few
things that are going on with the
students that either have just graduated
or still working in my lab because I get
really excited about the work that my
undergrads well excuse me undergrads
that work with me do um so um Lan Jensen
graduated a little bit ago she um
they're actually doing um a PhD at the
University univers of Buffalo now they
worked on um evolutionary simulations of
the biosynthetic pathway we modified um
a simulations by wheer Smith um and
changed it so that we could evolve
towards having multiple Optima to
reflect the pigment data we have and so
we can ask questions about what are the
mutations that are necessary for flower
color shifts to happen and are some
shifts harder to evolve to than
others um you've seen Abby's face before
um Abby was working on um a positive
weather positive selection is connected
with floral pigment shifts um and so she
used gnds um ratio analyses to
investigate whether we see differences
um between Anin and no Anin producing
species and also cyanidin versus
delphinidin producing
species so Trinity was working on this
other project that then led to us
figuring out that we had that intron um
retained in an ANS she was looking to
develop a digit droplet digital PCR
protocol such that we could distinguish
between expression of our two hogs in a
single reaction so more bank for your
buck we made some progress unfortunately
it didn't really come to pass that it
was going to be feasible for what we're
doing but we still learned some really
cool stuff along the way um so we've
kind of shifted that project with some
new folks um I'm G to move this so we
can see Alissa's name um some new folks
who are using ddpcr but now we're
developing two different primers um to
still get the expression data out two
different um reactions this time um but
Elisa Pino and Brooke tillon are working
on this project and we're getting into a
different we're taking that those um one
million yearo polyploids and seeing
what's happening with home bias in
them um we have another set of folks
Edie Russo has been working with me for
about a year and a half looking at how
cellular Dynamics um changing over um
development are affecting the um flower
sizes that we have in poly ples um and
Tim MRA just joined the lab this
semester um so we're excited to see what
they're going to come up
with and then finally um I got a a grant
to go to um Q Gardens um in the summer
so full circle Jeff talked about how
that's how my story started and I got to
sorry I get excited um I got to take one
of my undergrads um to the place where I
started underg love of niiko Shana so it
was fantastic so Marissa mle and I went
and collected a flower morphology
photographic data set of a lot of these
really old polyploids that have exploded
um and we're actually right now they did
it um yesterday and this week um and I
did it last semester my intro biolab
students are measuring tube length and
width um from the photographs we brought
back which is super fun I'm having a
great time with it and then Kendra
Moscato joined the lab this semester and
so we're excited to see where we're
going to take that um um project so lots
of stuff going on um I'd like to
acknowledge a ton of people who have
made this niiko sheny journey possible
including my PhD and postto supervisors
collaborators from all of those places
and especially my undergraduates um
because mentoring them is really
valuable and really exciting for me and
that's why I do what I do so I'm excited
to see where they go and what they do
ALS o some funding sources and
computational resources um and with that
thank you for your attention and I'll
happily answer any
questions for
Elizabeth how do
I yeah I'm trying to figure out how I
can make it pop
up um maybe I can get some technical
assistance on the zoom while I answer
Rob's question me but I'll
try thanks Chelsea we made it disappear
and then um put it back Rock question
first of all thank you that was quite a
to force sorry I get excited and talk
real fast it's a nice lineage for so
many reasons
biogeographically you have a lot of
repeated Evolution gain and loss of
night blooming and color versus white
and scent um as you know and so
sylvestris is a major player in in
everything you've shown us today if I
remember correctly sylvestris is a
problem file genetically um that's off
on a limb on its own
right and and it the the cladistics are
are misleading because because of the
hybrids that it makes it looks like it's
closely related to things that it's
actually the progenitor of um so what
came be for sylvestris um thinking about
the stop codons and why it's white did
it have ancest so the stop codons are in
obtusifolia oh sorry it's the intron
retained that seems to be my Okay but
well so let's take a step back further
than that then is the ancestral
condition in the to be white and scented
or be
colored I can't tell you it's a um I I
wish I knew the answer the way the way
the nikana um um or the nikana sections
are connected it means that we have a
bifurcation at the the base and that
could be white or
colorful pretty much yeah right and so
we we do see a lot of um shifts in
whether things are colored or white
in the genus and so I don't know the
answer I guess let me follow back with a
kind of Stacy Smith question um when is
White not white you know so many of us
thought about white as null mutants but
obviously you were showing us the
flavanols can give you white flowers
they're very strongly pigmented and
they're antifungal but they're not nulls
yeah right so if you looked at the the
tree for the
genus um do you think there are many
different sources of whiteness o
that's a great question so something I
didn't talk about today um and so
sylvestris and many of these do have
flavonols and they um absorb UV instead
of reflecting UV up to
aolia um does not have very many
flavonols and it reflects UV so even
within our white flowers we have
phenotypic differences um I haven't um
manage to do those things with every
single um it's my goal to do this with
every single species of nikana totally
not feasible um but just one more the
Australian ones that you finished with
yeah those have a single origin and they
radiated yeah so they should all have
the same white so um they at least in
terms of UV absorption and reflection we
were able to do that I brought my spec
with me to London it was great um and so
those all seem to absorb clols um or
excuse me absorb UV we haven't done any
pigment data on them yet but hopefully
soon at least a handful um
so in terms of the ones that do absorb
UV and produce
flavanols I think those are probably the
same white but then we have some that
have a ton of flavanol and some that
don't so like the um the two popoids
that have that really high levels of
flos that is that a different
phenotype I don't know how do we I don't
know so I guess again my answer to your
question is I don't know
yes yes thank you really interesed so
how did you calculate the age of this
6.5 million it would put you in the myos
um so that was not data I did but um
they used um molecular data um and um
some sort of non-parametric test if I'm
remembering correctly um to estimate
times
um we we don't have any within theana um
off the top of my head I don't have the
specifics but it's definitely um earlier
than so I think so in AC but I I don't
have a good I'm doing great on questions
I don't know is the answer to your
question also um but definitely a good
point that that's um maybe we don't have
um specifics like maybe our exact dates
aren't great but I think our relative
dates are certainly good so um even if
we don't have the exact dates we still
have that trajectory of understanding
which ones are younger and which ones
are older um so that still kind of fits
with my um I wish we had more fossils is
again the answer I saw hand over here
and then you're on
Deck it's a naive question a lot of
these pigments that You' talked about
appear in vegetative organs as well as
floral orans is it a fair supposition
that what you found in the
petals is also happening in the
vegetative orans I think yes and no for
the flavanol I would assume yes I think
it's way more likely that those
vegetative tissues have flavonol
compared to the anthocyanins um just by
looking at the vegetative tissue in some
of these plants as I've worked with them
there are some that I I I call them they
have purple leaves people are like no
that's green I'm like yes but it's
purpler than these ones so I think that
maybe some of them have some antoin in
them um but I would certainly guess
flavonol the levels and the ratios of
those things I'm not sure um but
even hold the phone um even within the
the flower tissue can I find that yeah
so even in the flower tissue we have
differences so the the the pigments are
really concentrated in the limb and not
in the tube um so I do think that for
the anthocyanins at least we have um
really specific um expression of when
we're turning those pigments on um which
is not happening in the vegetative
tissue that answer your question I got
one okay yes no um you see um sub genome
dominance in the older like natural
polyploids is is sub genome dominant
it's we see a more expression bias okay
so at the gene by Gene basis we see a um
greater um deviation from equal
expression but if we look at it overall
we don't actually see sub genome
dominance is that is that a function of
um the age of the polypoid if you could
look at that gradient of the ages of
those polypoid events you see with older
polypoid events more of that bias that's
a great question and it's part of like
I'm trying to piece this together right
I'm working in all these different age
polyploids and hopefully at some point
I'm going to be able to put all of that
together I gu to follow up to that is
there is a logical conclusion of that
sub genome dominance and maybe a
contraction that you see potentially
yeah definitely um at least in um we
don't have full genomes of all of these
polyes um but for um the sequences that
people have used phog gentically we do
seem to have both copies of things in
most of these poly voids maybe the
oldest ones were starting to lose some
things so maybe that's when
fractionation is starting to happen but
we don't have a answer to that yet
either but definitely a great question
and kind of fits with this idea of how
can we use this trajectory to really
answer cool
questions yeah what about flower size
and
shape what about it tell me yeah I also
care about those things
I out interesting ways I guess say yeah
and I we're trying to get at that in in
some of the things that um that Edie and
Tim are working on with the cell stuff
um also the Suave lentes project we have
we have more differences in shape size
um than color and those so those are
things that we're we're getting into
then again I don't have good answers to
your questions but I would love to find
out um I guess I can tell you a little
bit right we do see that um we tend to
have wider tubes in really young
polypoides and that seems to be because
the width of the cells are bigger with
poly so polypoid increases the the width
of the cells and increases the tube
might influence pollination so maybe
we're poly potentially is giving us more
generalized pollination um but what
we're what eating and Tim are looking at
is the cell size in the older polypoides
and preliminary data it looks like we
lose that in our older ones so we're
reducing the size in our older polys
potentially like we're reducing genome
size I'm excited to find out more about
that Jeff and then Rob what's the link
with pollinators in the sizes and the
pigments
um you know the amount of flavonoids for
reflection for B's C versus bats not c
yeah we we have some pollinator data um
we have pollinator data more for
diploids than we do for polyploids so
that's another um whole trajectory that
I would love to take my research program
in the future is to look and see how
these morphological and and phenotypic
differences affect pollinators but
unfortunately we don't know a whole lot
about what's pollinating our poly plates
so again I don't know the answer to that
question but that's great I have so much
to work on Rob Back Adrian's question um
you also have a symmetry issue right
like tophia and and oora are zygomorphic
we know what genes are responsible in a
lot of my families py morphy um are they
um segregating between between the
hybrids because sylvest does not look py
morphic to me no sylvest is not I would
say that most neosan are not there are a
handful um a lot of the alatte are also
um
zygomorphic um trying to just think
about all the poly poids in my head for
a
second I think most of them are radial
at least in the limb um there are some
in the older poly blades that we were
just investigating where they do start
to have those um so again really great
questions that we can investigate we
know those genes um hopefully with more
data we can again start answering those
questions really great ones that get to
just question too because certain kinds
of pollinators like flowers that have an
up and down yeah
definitely yeah size question it'd be
cool with more data to see if there's a
relationship between polyploid and end
maybe you can that if in these
polyploids that um maybe you see less or
if it's compensating or they're going to
get their genomes one way or another
yeah I I don't know again really cool
things um that hopefully be able to
investigate at some point but yeah
there's so many cool
things other questions folks yeah go for
it um because you made your owna
transcripts were you able to see any
bias when you took that same data and
I'm assuming you did a concatenated
transcript
down in the mapping so were there any um
reads that maps to one or the other
incorrectly yeah and that's um part of
why I didn't tell you a story about
homog bias and rande um because we have
um I need two hands for this um I need
two hands for everything um we we have a
threshold um for when we're looking at
those um hom log bias where um less we
can um have to have a less than 10%
mismatch between our two copies and for
many genes we reached that um for some
we didn't luckily for the tacum story We
reached that for Oliver flavonoid
biosynthetic pathway gen we didn't hit
that for um R um which is unfortunate
I'm hoping maybe and maybe Jacob has a
better um answer to this question like
if we add more long reads um to those
progenitors we didn't have that for this
one whether we might be able to pull out
um the differences we also have the
added difficulty of there's four million
years of evolution in the polyploids and
in the Diplo lineages in that system and
so being able to really figure out
homes because the homes within the
polypoides have diverged in sequence
from the progenitors we see that way
less inbam it happens sometimes but
they're pretty tight so that's way
easier um so so yes um and then we just
can't ask those kind of questions for
those genes does that answer your
question a other questions folks I go
quick so real quick that gets into like
the next I keep thinking about as in the
longterm one right got this 90 species
or whatever it is thinking about copy
them right whether you get retain
retention of hogs over time and how that
might lead to either sub or
neofunctionalization yeah can you see
how that you might attack that across
those different time scales yeah um I
think it'll probably have to be on a
like candidate Gene basis more likely um
um maybe not all the
things um but at least like I said
before folks have used some um um genes
to look at phog gentics and we sometimes
don't see the the second copy in some of
those faules the old ones um it's
certainly interesting I mean we're
already seeing some puden in young
polypoid sometimes um and I didn't talk
about it today but when we looked at all
of those flavonoid biosynthetic pathway
genes in the rande there are a few more
like some of the um Hogs within the poly
plates have um um frame shifts and so
we're starting to see some of those
things um but yes again all of you have
really great ideas um these are really
good questions that um with more data
will definitely be interesting to
investigate right well let's thank right
thanks this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu