this is a production of Cornell
University
so I want to start right at the very
beginning so as the name of our lab
suggests we study fungi as model
organisms really to try and understand
um evolutionary processes and to try and
understand how organisms adapt to ever
shifting environments so I'd like to
start with just a brief overview of the
fungal Kingdom because not all not
everyone is always so familiar with them
or thinking about them all the time so
fungi of course are um the largest
Kingdom of microbial ukar and as a group
they've been diversifying for just over
1.5 billion years and as you might
imagine over this amount of time fungi
have radiated out into basically all
environments on Earth both terrestrial
and Aquatic and they've evolved a
variety of different strategies for
survival across all these different
environments and in my lab we take a
comparative approach to try and
understand how fungal diversity is
generated so rather than focus on just
one model system on one branch of the
tree we try and leverage multiple model
systems across the fungal Tree of Life
in a comparative framework to try and
understand what strategies are shared
across different lineages what what
strategies might be more Innovations
particular particular to a specific
lineage and in this way we really try
and understand some of the foundational
principles of fungal adaptation and
fungal
Evolution and one of the types of
variations that we're most interested in
studying in our lab are fungal
interactions and this is because sure
come no surprise in a Plant Pathology
and plant microbiology Department that
fungal interactions literally shape our
world right so fungal fungi have evolved
to to interact with humans with animals
with plants with bacteria and with other
fungi and the outcomes of these
interactions are really essential for
the continued functioning of ecosystem
processes and maybe more um visibly the
interactions really impact very
important aspects of human society in
terms of human health and also Global
Food security and
so the goal in our is really to
understand fungal interactions as a
process where a process is really
something that is continually unfolding
over time so we're interested both both
in the ecological Dynamics and also
evolutionary Dynamics and Eco Evo
dynamics that are driving fungal
adaptations um on in on the interaction
stage and so there are two main
questions that we're really interested
in understanding in my lab you can boil
them down to first one when do good
fungi turn bad so we're really
interested in understanding genetic
drivers and environmental drivers that
can um lead to pathogen emergence for
example from a mutualist or commensal to
a path to a disease-causing organism and
on the other hand and kind of related
we're also interested in how to fungi
learn new tricks so how to establish
pathogens for example um pick up new
traits or evolve new traits that allow
them to expand and infect other hosts or
how do pathogens evolve new strategies
for overcoming host defenses or in some
cases some of the control mechanisms or
control strategies that we try and
deploy out in the field to control their
um their
impacts there's of course a major
challenge when studying fungal
interactions and you can boil these down
to a question of genotypic and
phenotypic variation right so as many
plant Pathologists in the room will know
getting disease to happen or trying to
uh induce a disease isn't really always
as simple as mixing together one
pathogenic strain with one particular
host there's a lot of variation
certainly between species but also
within species and across different
populations and lineages within the
species level there's a lot of variation
in how these fungi are actually
interacting with their hosts and as an
evolutionary biologists I think it's
really important to understand where
this variation comes from so how is it
generated
and what are the outcomes of this
variation um in a very practical sense
and I think by understanding where
variation comes from and what the
outcomes are we really position
ourselves um much better to actually
being able to get one step closer to
being able to predict the outcomes of
different interactions um as they're
happening out in the field or even
within our own bodies so that's really
another reason why a lot of the
questions that we ask in the lab span
from the Within species level to between
species level so as was briefly
mentioned in the introduction my lab
takes a three-pronged approach to try
and Tackle this question of um how is
variation generated in fungal
interactions so First We Take a
computational biology perspective and
this really allows us to discover
patterns that are unfolding in large
omix data sets then we take an
evolutionary genomics approach to
actually try and characterize some of
the processes that are responsible for
generating these patterns that we see um
in in these data sets and across
different species and in this way
generate some sort of comparative
insight into how these processes are
unfolding across different fungal
species and
populations and then finally we try and
tie it all together with a molecular
genetics approach um trying to actually
conduct some functional characterization
experiments to actually test the
hypotheses that computational biology
and evolutionary genomics are really so
good at generating and also conduct some
manipulative experiments in the lab
along those same lines and over the past
couple of years and hopefully uh into
the future we've been applying this
approach to a new and emerging concept
within the field of fungal biology and
fungal genetics and that's the concept
of starships and unlike this picture
might suggest or unlike what chat GPT
thinks a Starship is these are not the
star sh that are spacecrafts that you
might have heard um uh or seen in
science fiction shows but rather these
starships that we study in the lab are a
newly described super family of
transposable elements
and I don't think this scientist needs
any introduction in this room in fact
I'm looking at a picture of her right
now in the back right corner but of
course um transposons are these really
interesting features and entities
genetic entities that live within
organismal genomes and they were
discovered just over 80 years ago by
Barbara mclintoch including some of her
pioneering work done here at
Cornell and essentially through Dr
mcclint Talk's work she showed that
there are particular regions of the
genome that are capable of transposing
themselves from one location to another
and she was finding that the
consequences or outcomes of these
interactions that are happening at the
genetic level can have very important
phenotypic outcomes so in the The Case
of Dr mclin's model organism maze she
was of course finding that this great
variation in pigmentation patterns could
be traced back to the activity of just a
single transposon and these effects were
largely resulting from where that
transposon ended up as it moved itself
um between different positions within
the
genomes and as a consequence of her
pioneering
work scientists quickly be began to
realize that a lot of the cases of
adaptation that we observe out in nature
and in some cases have been observing
for decades and even over hundreds of
years a lot of these cases of adaptation
could ultimately be traced back to the
activity of these poorly understood and
previously hidden features of organismal
genomes so the classic case of course
being the peppered moth so a lot of
students learn about this example in
biology 101 it is the classic case of
adaptation where during the Industrial
Revolution in
England these this particular moth
species underwent a shift to a darker
pigmentation pattern that was better
able to camouflage it against trees that
were accumulating soot from the
Industrial Revolution it was only a
couple of years ago that researchers
went back sequenced these genomes and
realized that this change in
pigmentation phenotype just like what Dr
mlin was seeing was actually being
driven by the activity of transposable
elements so really if we want to learn
more about organismal adaptation we
really need to start paying attention to
these often hidden parts of the genome
that can have these out sized phenotypic
consequences but in the 80 or so years
since Dr mcclint first described a
transposable element the definition of a
eukariotic transposable element has
essentially remained unchanged and the
definition is a relatively short piece
of DNA that can just move itself from
one location of the genome to the other
but here's where things start to get a
little bit different when it comes to
Starship transposons
so like their name
suggests first thing you need to know
about a Starship transposon is that it
is much larger than any other eukariotic
transposon described to date in fact it
can often be one to two orders of
magnitude larger than anything else you
would find in a fungal genome or really
in any other eukariotic genome and
actually towards the upper range of uh
the Starship size Spectrum you can get
starships that are actually approaching
the size of small fungal chromosomes
just to give you a sense of perspective
there like other transposable elements
Starships have a recones that we call
the captain which is actually the only
Gene that's both sufficient and
necessary for moving the entire element
for transposing the entire element and
some really elegant work was done by
Andrew urkhart to show that this is the
case beyond the captain and here's where
things again start to get a little bit
more more interesting the these
Starships actually carry many other
protein coding genes as genetic cargo
right as you might expect from such a
gigantic transposon there's a lot of
room for other cargo to actually begin
accumulate within the boundaries of the
transposon and really at a fundamental
level this is why starships are so
special because the ability to carry
genetic cargo gives them this ability to
make complex contributions two
organismal phenotypes so over here's
small little schematic just placing
Starships within the broader context of
eukaryotic transposon
diversity at the bottom we see the
canonical transposons like the one Dr
mcclint was working with these
transposons are not capable of carrying
any genetic cargo beyond the romines
that's responsible for movement and so
all of their phenotypic impacts are
largely going to largely going to um
result from where they end up inserting
in the genome right if they insert
themselves in a promoter region this can
lead to a change in gene regulation if
they insert themselves into a protein
coating sequence that can lead to the
generation of a natural knockout so
really their impacts are limited to
their transposition but as you increase
the size of the transposon moving up
this spectrum to the point where you
have
Starships because Starships can carry
dozens of genes at one time this gives
them much greater ability to impact
phenotypic uh phenotypes of their of
their fungal hosts so in the example of
the Starship here hus which is one of
the first Starships to be
characterized this Starship actually
carries many different genes that are
each involved in detoxifying a different
type of heavy of heavy metal right so in
this way the Starship is not just
contributing to a phenotype based on
where it ends up in the genome although
it certainly can do that as well but
rather it's able to impact the
generation of phenotypic
diversity and so what do we know about
Starships so far so from one of our
early systematic studies we were able to
um categorize the diversity of Starships
into 11 major
families and here's just a philogenetic
tree showing how all of those different
sequences have evolved over time and in
general this is a very
diverse um Gene family so even both even
within particular families but certainly
between families the different Captain
recombinases show very very little
similarity to each other indicating that
through some combination of Rapid
Evolution but also Evolution over long
periods of times these elements have
been diversifying in fungal genomes for
quite some time and we estimate just
close to 400 million years of evolution
based on how they're
distributed we also know that Starships
they're not a kingdom wide phenomenon
but rather they're concentrated within a
particular subm of filamentous fungi
called the
Poma this was really lucky for us
because many of the fungi that caused
diseases on humans and also on plants
are found within the Poma we see some
evidence of Starships in some bidio
lineages but um we're not really quite
sure how they have ended up there and
we're trying to figure that out right
now and then as I was saying the ability
to carry
cargo has resulted in many different
Starships encoding very diverse traits
so since we first described the Starship
super
family people have been other groups
have been coming out with many different
papers and our groups as well showing
that different starships are
contributing in different ways to some
of the phenotypes that we really care
about studying so for example phenotypes
like veillance evolution plant
pathogenic fungi um and also heavy metal
resistance I mentioned before and so um
and as you might notice a lot of these
papers are currently still in the
pre-print stage so we really still are
at the beginning of understanding just
how broad the impact of starships are on
fungal adaptation and fungal Evolution
and so in my lab right now what we're
doing is framing this question of fungal
interactions through the lens of
starships and we're asking now how are
Starships actually mediating fungal
interactions with both plant and animal
hosts and essentially trying to
understand what are the parameters of
this newly described mechanism of fungal
Evolution so the takeaway from today's
talk I'll be sharing two recent stories
that have um come out of some of the
work we've been doing over the past year
uh with many different collaborators
just showing everyone here how Starships
really provide fuel for fungal Evolution
and I'm going to show you how they do
this on two different levels first is
through generating genotypic variation
at the level of genome structure but
also at the level of genome content and
then second we'll start getting into
what I think is really going to be the
next Frontier of Starship biology
understanding the role of these elements
as a mechanism of fungal horizontal Gene
transfer so for this first part over
here understanding contributions of
Starships to genome structure and genome
content we were working with a large
genomic data set of the opportunistic
human pathogen aspila
Godus there's a lot of there's a lot of
interest in understanding the genetic
mechanisms of strain heterogenity in
this particular opportunity gentic
pathogen just because it is one of the
number one killers of imuno compromised
patients and so we were working with
just over 500 short read genomes we also
went ahead and sequenced 12 new longer
read genomes which would give us this
ability to actually be able to more uh
precisely resolve the Dynamics that were
happening at the population level so
what we did was we essentially applied
this new tool that I developed for
annotating Starship elements to this
data set and ended up with this
compendium of starships that are active
within this particular species so I'm
just going to walk you through how we
then interrogated this data set or
interrogated this compendium to try and
understand now some of the rules and
foundational biology of these
elements so first things first once we
had all the Starships what we did was we
tried to classify them into different
unique types because one Starship even
though they're part of the same super
family can actually be quite distinct
from one another at a sequence level so
when we did that we found that there are
at least 20 distinct starships that are
actively transposing within this
particular species over here you'll see
just a heat map about how these 20
different Starships Are distributed
across the population that we worked
with you can see like as you might
expect from a mobile element and we know
this from bacterial mobile elements very
often these genetic entities has have
very patchy distributions across
different populations so you can see
that recapitulated over
here also mentioned that many of these
Starships really share little to no
sequence identity with each other
indicating that many of them are
carrying different combinations of cargo
genes and something that I like to point
out is that unlike a canonical
transposon you will only ever find these
Starships in a single copy within a
particular genome so there appears to be
some mechanism controlling copy number
within this particular species we
already know that that mechanism can
break down because other species can
accumulate multiple copies um but we're
really still not quite sure what that
mechanism might be and whether it's host
controlled or Starship
controlled uh right uh one of the
benefits with working with fuma Godus is
that people have sampled this fungus
from literally everywhere on Earth but
also from outside Earth in space on the
International Space Station so a couple
of our isolates were indeed sampled from
the space station so I can confirm that
Starships have made it to space because
we can find them up there as well
looking down on us so after we try to
understand where these starships are
found at between different individuals
we then wanted to understand where
they're found within the genome itself
so what I've done here
is okay what I've done here is map out
the eight chromosomes of the reference
FEMA goddess string we have 293 and
along the perimeter I've indicated all
of the segregating Starship insertion
sites so these are sites in Black over
here where Starship is present in some
other individual in the population but
absent from this one particular
reference string and then in red over
here you can see the uh eight starships
that are present in this one particular
individual if you add up all the
sequence that's contained within this
mobile
compartment we get upwards of 2 and a
half% of genome content actually being
located within these mobile elements and
when we add up all of the different
insertion sites across the entire
population there just over 150 unique
insertion sites where Starships Are
generating this genomewide structural
variation just to give you a sense of
the upward bounds of Starship mediated
structural VAR iation over here I'm
showing the single Locus with the
highest concentration of Starship
activity so all so this is a Cy plot so
regions of similarity are indicated in
Gray over here each line is a different
isolet and this is just obviously a
subsample of the isets in our
collection in red outlined in red are
all of the different starships that are
found at this one particular Locus and
in uh different colors over here here
might be of interest to some people in
the room these are all different
biosynthetic Gene clusters that are
encoded in this one Locus so what I
think is really interesting about this
example it really shows how much
variation can accumulate in just a
particular region due solely to Starship
transposition activity right so in some
cases we have Starships actually
introducing a biosynthetic gene cluster
to this BGC hotspot in other cases we
have starships that are coming in and
inserting themselves within a particular
cluster like over here or just Upstream
of different clusters we don't know what
the phenotypic consequences of these
insertion events are yet but now we
actually have a hypothesis that we can
go back to the lab and actually
interrogate um in more detail but
essentially the takeaway here is that
really nowhere is safe in The genome
from Starships actually being able to
insert themselves something I also like
to point out I get this question a lot
is how Faithful is transposition so over
here I've pulled out the same Starship
across a dozen or so
isolates and the Starship is found
across different genomic locations so
that's why you see synony only between
the different Starship copies but not
between the flanking regions in this
particular plot and as you can tell the
boundaries of the star ship are pretty
Faithfully maintained across
transposition events there is some
variation some inp specific variation in
what this Starship actually looks like
and so we know that's the answer to this
question of whether or not content is
maintained between transposition events
or between different isolates it's both
a a yes and question it is maintained
but then also these sequences are part
of the genome and of course are
experiencing the same types of
mutational events that other sequence in
the genome is experiencing and so they
are also changing over time although we
don't really quite know if they're
changing in the same way or if they're
changing in slightly different
ways so that was looking at Starships
across the genome now we wanted to
understand what impact Starships might
be having on the pangenome so the
pangenome is the complete set of genes
or genetic sequences found across all
individuals in a population
so I was saying within any one
particular genome around 2 and a half%
of the genetic content is located on a
Starship but when you try and scale that
up to now look at how much genetic
variation is contained on Starships
within the Pang genome across all these
isolates we see that around 3 to 5% of
all of the genes in the Pang genome are
found at least once on a Starship and in
particular the genes that tend to be
enriched on Starships no surprise are
so-called accessory genes and accessory
genes are genes whose presence and
absence differs across individuals
within a population so upwards of 16% of
accessory genes are Starship mobilized
and we're really really excited about
this finding because for a long time we
didn't really quite understand what
contributed to variation in gene
presence absence outside of canonical
genetic mechanisms now we have some
really good evidence that it is the
mobility of the starships that could be
contributing to the presence absence
variation in these accessory genes thus
generating variation in genomic content
and the reason for this we'll get into
aspects of horizontal transfer Gene gain
a little bit later but something that's
important to know is that being located
on a transposable element also
predisposes genes on that element to
being lost because not every
transposition event is ultimately
successful and it's been shown in the
lab that
occasionally a Starship will fail to
reintegrate into the genome during a
transposition event leading to the loss
of that Gene of all of the genes located
on that particular element so in this
way starships are both mediating Gene
gain through horizontal transfer and
also Gene loss through just failed
transposition
events so because fagus is this model
organism there's been a lot of work done
to try and understand the functions of
genes involved in inter in different
host interactions within Godus and
something that became very quickly clear
was that their Starships in this species
carry Loi carry genes that people have
been studying for
decades because of their involvement in
particular interactions so the best case
of that is here with the biofilm
architecture
Factor this particular Gene bath is
shared across actually um six or seven
different types of Starships so there
seems to be this very strong association
between this B architecture factor and
mobile
Starships we're interested in this
particular Gene because it's been shown
by some of our collaborators that it is
responsible for
mediating biofilm morphology so the
ability to form uh biofilms which is
important from a human health standpoint
and also more importantly it's able to
increase and affect how this fungus row
under low hypoxic conditions which
ultimately impact the virence of this
fungus so here we have a really cool
example of a trait actually being
localized to one of these mobile
elements so if you want to understand
how this trait evolves how this trait
gets disseminated or spread throughout
different pathogen
lineages first step is actually
realizing that it is located on a mobile
element and that opens up some new
avenues for understanding how these
phenotypes evolve over time we also
noticed that there are a couple of
biosynthetic Gene clusters located on
Starships which again gives us some
insight into how these metabolic
phenotypes are evolving and changing
over time these two examples over here
were actually identified just over eight
years ago by ant Antonis rus' group they
were the first to realize that these
clusters were actually found in
different parts of the genome depending
on what strain you looked at they named
this phenomenon a mobile Gene cluster
and here we're actually showing that the
Starships Are the mechanism that's
resulted in these clusters ending up in
different locations of the genome and
since that paper came out there's been
some functional work done to
characterize the products of these bgc's
and interestingly one of them the fuma
German is involved in mediating fungal
bacterial interaction so this molecule
actually suppresses bacterial Spore
germination so it could be important
from a competitive sample we're looking
to dive a little bit deeper into exactly
how that works and also a molecule fah
hopeside a which is involved in
increasing Thermo tolerance and also
tolerance to UV stresses so over here
again a really great indication of how
Starships how their genotypes could
ultimately impact the phenotypes of the
funi that we're studying and how
mobilization in particular could impact
the evolution of these phenotypes
and so over here um just to this is just
kind of one side story just to show like
just how many hypotheses and new
directions this data set has opened up
for us so one of the um findings of the
analysis was that Starship Starships
carry not not only enzyme encoding genes
but they also carry transcription
factors and using some of the tools
developed by our collaborators in the
Keller lab we can see that in many cases
the transcription factors carried by the
starships are embedded into larger Gene
regulatory networks in the cell so over
here I've just colorcoded all of the uh
transcription factors found in Starships
as these colored um diamonds over here
and each connection between a node in
this network is indicating a significant
correlation in gene expression between
these two different loide so you can see
that these Starship transcription
factors some of them are only associated
with the regulation of other genes on
the Starship like in this case over here
but in some cases you have these
Starships which tend to be associated
with the expression of many other genes
across the genome so yes the C on the
screen is not track curs on oh thank you
I think yes thank you so these
transcriptions factors over here are the
ones that we're finding in Starships is
that clear for
everyone so over here we're trying to
use this now as a model for
understanding who is regulating who in
this interaction that's happening
between the transposon and the fungal
genome at large are these interactions
that we're seeing these hypothetical
interactions that we're seeing in the
network evidence that the host is
somehow controlling expression of
Starships
or conversely is it some evidence that
the transcription factors being carried
as cargo are somehow manipulating other
potentially other phenotypes that are
encoded elsewhere in the fungal cell and
postto in the lab right now is trying to
dive in knock out some of these
transcription factors and try and
understand what their phenotypic impacts
are so that wraps up the first section
of the talk just looking at what these
elements are doing at a population level
now we're going to shift to a more
between species approach to try and
understand the role of Starships in
actually mediating Gene transfer between
different species and this work is a
collaboration with Andrew urkhart and
Andrew and Aaron vogan um a lot of the
lab work I'll say all of the lab work
was done by Andrew he's just started up
his own lab U Down in Melbourne
Australia where he's going to be looking
into this a lot more
so to start off with our
interest in Starship horizontal Gene
transfer begins with this particular
Gene cluster called the ssf cluster
which encodes a pathway for f Malahide
degradation now all three of us
initially became really interested in
this um in this Gene cluster because it
was found on a couple of the starships
that we were studying at the time and
just because it seemed to really
exquisitly encode
the complete pathway for formaly
degradation I would say we were
initially a little bit confused why
would fungi have evolved this really
sophisticated genetic architecture for
deating form Malahide and I would say
our confusion was really just a result
of our own ignorance we didn't quite
realize how pervasive for Malahide is in
natural environments we were thinking
that it might only be linked to human
activities but in fact formaly is
produced usually as a byproduct of a lot
of different plant metabolic pathways
and in these cases in some cases it's
been shown that the production of
formaly acts as this antimicrobial agent
that can protect particularly fruits
from fungal colonization or bacterial
colonization so this got us really
interested in understanding this cluster
because potentially it could be
providing adaptive uh benefits to fungi
that are encountering form Malahide out
in their environment especially a lot of
fungi that are interacting with plant
material so I said we were interested in
the cluster primarily because it was
found on a Starship and as we dug into
it a little bit more we came to realize
that actually it's not just found on a
single Starship but this cluster is
actually shared across four very
distantly related Starships so I've
aligned those Starships over
here so you can see in most cases only
the formaly degrading cluster which is
outlined in blue over here is shared
among these vastly Divergent elements
and in some cases the cluster itself
shares relatively High nucleotide
similarities certainly higher than you
would expect just given uh given the um
element wide
comparisons so we were of course really
interested in trying to identify the
process that was responsible for
producing this particular pattern so we
took a phenetics approach to
understand during what time in The
evolutionary history of these Starships
did they acire the cluster and so when
we did that we found that this in each
of these cases these Starships seem to
have independently acquired the cluster
from somewhere so over here we have a a
tree of the captain romines that acts as
a proxy for understanding the evolution
of the element as a whole and over here
we've just mapped out the presence
absence of the various genes that are
found within this cluster so you can see
on the tree over here we have these four
spots within the tree where the cluster
just suddenly appears to now be
associated with a particular Starship so
I think this is pretty good evidence
that this process was a process of
convergent acquisition and not a process
of inheritance um through vertical
descent and what was really interesting
was that in each of the cases where the
Starship appeared to have acquired the
formaly degrading cluster each of these
events coincides with a horizontal
transfer event between different fungal
species so in this case over here
between four different species we saw
evidence over here between two here
three and here two again so in each of
the cases it seems like the convergent
acquisition of this cluster is priming
fungi to adapt via horizontal Gene
transfer that's mediated by The
Starships themselves and you can just
get a sense over here from what that
horizontal transfer looks like at a
genetic level so here we're comparing
two species putative donors and putative
recipients from different fungal species
all these dots represent a gene that's
been um that's been blasted essentially
from one genome to the other so you'll
see for the most part A lot of these
comparisons the median Gene identity at
the nucleotide level is just around 70%
or maybe a little bit higher up here in
red are all of those Starship Associated
genes in Red so in many cases these
genes are showing 100% nucleotide
identity across different species much
more than you would expect most simple
explanation in this case is one of
horizontal Gene transfer and so we of
course wanted to understand what effect
horizontal acquisition of the star
might have on a recipient fungus and we
were lucky enough that we found uh one
of the PA very often working with
genomic sequences the isels are
typically not always available but in
this one particular case we were able to
acquire isets from both the donor PES
asilis and also the recipient peses over
here so we had a nice collection of both
Starship positive and Starship negative
strings that we could
test and as predicted by the genotype by
the Starship genotype
the fungi that had the
Starship had a phenotype of increased
form Malahide resistance so over here we
see increasing formaly concentration
over here we have the different isolates
either Starship positive or Starship
negative it's really only those isolet
that have the Starship with the formaly
degrading cluster thank you these isolet
over here
positive and negative only the isolates
with the cluster that actually have the
predicted phenotype of increased formaly
resistance this is really exciting
because it suggests that we might
actually be able to predict phenotypes
remember that's one of our ultimate
goals is trying to predict the outcomes
of fungal interactions with their
environment and with host here we're
showing that it is actually possible to
predict in some cases the phenotype of
the fungus based on what its Starship
genotype might
be so now we're going to shift
perspectives a little bit try and
understand some of the broad broader
consequences or broader context of
Starship activity within fungal genomes
so before I was showing you Evolution
from the perspective of the Starship
itself so how the Starship is evolving
over time here we're taking a different
perspective and trying to understand
Evolution from the perspective of the
formaly degrading cluster so over here
we have a biogenetic tree of uh one of
the genes within the cluster that's
acting as a proxy for understanding
evolution of the cluster as a whole and
we see a very interesting evolutionary
pattern playing out here we see that
there are some
clades in within this tree where this
formaly cluster appears to be so
associated with Starships as expected
right that's what we went into this
analysis knowing but in other cases we
see examples where the
cluster is associated with a degraded
Starship
so we have this scenario where the cargo
in the cluster becomes mobile when it's
acquired by the Starship and can be
shared between different species but
then the flip side of that is we also
see the consequences of what happens
when the Starship begins to degrade and
in these cases the cargo once again
becomes part of the non-mobile
compartment of the genome but by this
time it could have ended up in a
different species for example or in a
different genomic location in the cases
of up here and so this was really
interesting because one of the mysteries
of fungal genomics has always been how
do why are we finding genes in different
places in the genome all the time why
are we finding what look to be near
identical copies of the same gene across
different species and before we didn't
really have a satisfying mechanism for
being able to explain that but I think
what we're seeing here is that Starships
do provide now a very convincing
explanation for why we might be ending
up with very diverse patterns in gene
location um and also Gene distributions
both within species and also uh across
species and this isn't to say that there
aren't other genetic mechanisms that are
also responsible for producing these
patterns canonical mechanisms like
recombination either parasexual
recombination or sexual recombination
but here in this particular case we're
just seeing just what the impact that
Starships can have on this one
particular J family providing a very
satisfying explanation for how this
particular cluster has ended up so
widely distributed even when all
evidence of Starship associations might
have been
erased so with that getting back to this
main question over here and just
wrapping up how are Starships mediating
fungal interactions with their
environment and with their
hosts the two stories that I've shared
today I Hope they've demonstrated that
Starships really are fueling variation
in genome structure and genome content
and also we now have very convincing
evidence also some laboratory
experiments that Andrew has been running
that we didn't have a chance to get into
right now we have very convincing
evidence that starships are indeed a
mechanism of fungal horizontal Gene
transfer and over here try to create a
model that summarizes everything that
youve just heard over here what we're
really advocating now is a shift in how
we conceive of fungal genome space so
current theory in fungal genomics will
divide up the genome into two different
types of compartments you have dynamic
or accessory compartments that are
changing rapidly and then we have core
compartments which are more conserved
within species and also um between
species what we're seeing now is that
actually there is a third type of
compartment and and that's the Starship
compartment which consists of the mobile
fraction of the genome and this is
really important for a number of reasons
but fundamentally the ability to
transpose or the ability to be
mobile puts the genes in this
compartment on a different evolutionary
trajectory compared to genes in other
genomic compartments and this is
because through Starship mediated
movement these genetic cargo can end up
new individuals through horizontal
transfer
events they can also end up at new sites
within the same
species or can ultimately lead to loss
of that mobile cargo through failed
transposition then over time eventually
it seems like many Starships can keep
going for some time but one possible
outcome is that those Mobility features
are
lost the cargo then reintegrates back
into either dynamic or accessory
compartments or sometimes even into core
compartments over here so really by just
proposing Starships as this new genomic
compartment we're hoping that this can
now provide more mechanistic
explanations for genome Evolution across
different Poma fungi and so now the next
steps really in this process are to
continue charting the Starship genotype
to fungal phenotype map try and now
understands understand not only fungal
interactions with their environment and
with host posts but also understand how
fungi are interacting with these genetic
entities that are actually embedded
within their
genomes so I'd like to thank some of the
folks involved in supporting me and also
supporting this work all the folks um in
the fungal interactions lab as well as
some collaborators um both across the US
and also in Europe and
Australia um and always like to mention
that this process of actually
discovering Starships as a feature of
fungal genomes certainly not something I
did by myself this was really a
collaborative
approach through that really resulted in
us being able to really rapidly move
forward in our knowledge of these
elements over a period of just four
years now um to really try and more
quickly and effectively understand what
their role is in fungal biology and so
I'll just highlight some of um my
collaborators that have been involved in
this process and recently we just wrote
a little chapter in uh fungal genomics
um textbook over here kind of
documenting the timeline of this
particular Discovery really just
highlighting how processes like openness
transparency and data sharing really
resulted in a lot of different groups
independently semi-independently coming
up with this concept at the same time so
I would encourage you to maybe um take a
peek at this chapter if you're
interested in understanding how this
process of discovery unfolded um over
the past couple of years and so with
that I'd be happy to take any
questions um we do specifically want to
um ask students uh for questions first
and give students particularly an
opportunity to ask questions first so
okay great and I'll also be looking for
questions on
Zoom yes in the back what it is about
the genetic structure of these transpl
elements that allow them to carry these
Gene groups with them in a way that
other trans developments can if you know
yeah we don't know and I think that's
going to be my answer to probably a lot
of questions today like we still we
really still don't understand how these
things work we don't really understand
how those boundaries are maintained
across different transposition events um
definitely something we're interested in
figur out
yeah yes so I know there are other Comin
elements that don't carry around cargo
genes like this so if you make a
philogyny of all the Starship tyrosine
recombinations and the tyrosine
recombinations of those other elements
do you see that they seem to have like a
monoptic origin and there's one type of
this element that can gain this ability
or it happening all the time that's a
great question and that was that is
actually a question we could answer um
and really question oh yes thank you so
the question was are Starship tyrosine
recommon ases monoptic or have they
appeared multiple times over
evolutionary history the answer to that
question is that they are monoptic so in
this philogenetic tree over here all of
the at least fungal and even bacterial
tyros recommen that we were able to fit
into this tree all of them appear um uh
external to this particular sorry all of
them appear external to the Starship
tyros comod so they do share one single
common origin something interesting
about just tyrosine or common ases in
general some of them like fungal
cryptons for example they don't carry
cargo but there are other tyrosine
recombinases in bacteria that are like
bacterial analogs of Starships they're
called integrative and conjugative
elements and so so in those cases those
tyrosinases also appear to be capable of
carrying cargo we don't know if it's
something particular about a tyros Romas
some convergence in protein function or
structure yeah I'm not sure
why yes uh excellent talk I really
enjoyed your figures and and diagrams
and things like that my question was I
was really interested in how um you were
looking at the Fahy biosythesis pathway
and how a whole biosythesis pathway
could fit onto a transposable element
it's pretty cool are there any other
um like biosynthetic Pathways or things
that you guys are pursuing now after
looking at the mahide one yeah
definitely yeah the I I've been studying
metabolic Gene clusters for a long time
just starting in my PhD actually and
when you think about it it really makes
a lot of sense from a selection
perspective that entire Pathways would
be located on mobile element and in fact
some of the earliest
hypotheses um in particular put out by
John
Walton he was he was one of the first to
suggest that maybe the actual selection
to form a biosynthetic gene cluster came
from this selection pressure to actually
be maintained to have the pathway
maintained after a transfer EV so from
the very beginning there's been this
connection between horizontal transfer
and the formation of metabolic Gene
clusters I think is really
interesting um short answer is yes we
are really interested in other metabolic
Gene clusters that are found on uh on
Starships these are two that we know the
products of in aspila Godus you can
see those they're actually outlined here
in white over here all these different
fopid so you can see that there's
actually a lot of other cargo that's
included in addition to these particular
clusters but certainly there's been a
lot of interest in the fungal genomics
World in understanding how different
clusters end up different places know
that they're frequently horizontally
transferred now we can actually begin to
understand a little bit more
mechanistically why they're horizontally
transferred or what conditions induce
transfer right is it related to the
actual function of the cluster itself
for example um yeah questions like
that yes um so regarding the 11 Gene
families that you found star chips in
yeah uh to this point how much of that
result do you think think is due to the
fact that those are heavily annotated
Gene families or that are particularly
relevant and we have a lot of genomic
sequences yes that's a really great
question so like any any so the question
sorry I have a lot of things to keep
track here between the cursor and
repeating the the question
stff think you're quickly seeing how I'm
very bad at multitasking but so the
question is how much might um bias in
our genomic databases be impacting our
assessments of tyrosine recom diversity
um I will say so very quickly one of the
more frustrating aspects of one of the
roadblocks in studying these elements
was that the tirene recombinase itself
is often quartly annotated in a lot of
automated pipelines so the first step of
the tool that I
developed just takes a denovo approach
to just annotating them and not relying
on a priori information so I would say
we have a really good sense of the tyros
or common ases themselves but then there
is still that question of bias in the
genomes that are available for us to
look at I will say that um that's
certainly something we're thinking about
when it comes to trying to understand
where starships are found in what fungal
lineages because yes they're found
mostly in Poma but also most fungal
genome sequences are from the Poma as
well right so I am going to be really
interested to see whether or not this
pattern holds true as more genomes are
sequenced what I can say for sure is
that starships are not in yeast we have
a lot of really great East genomes and
there's just no evidence of Starships in
yeast it seem to mostly just be in
filamentous
fungi yeah you have sense of the
mechanism by which Starships acquire
their cargo and how uh like like is it
usually like a like single cenic block
of genes that corresponds to a segment
of like a fungal genome or there
multiple CTIC segments that type thing
yeah so the question is how do Starships
acquire new cargo how does the cow get
Its Spots right so the
question kind of answered here I think
when you start aligning starships that
maybe share different um parts of their
cargo with each other in some cases like
between myate and Prometheus there's
evidence that maybe it was some sort of
intra element Rec combination event that
happened um possibly resulting in the
exchange of a larger segment of cargo
over time though with selection If there
really is just selection you know for
this particular phenotype you might
expect other parts of that to have been
lost so maybe that's why we see really
the only regions being shared in some
cases here just being really kind of
restricted to the cluster itself um
we know that Starships can Nest within
each other so that appears to be maybe
one way that car cargo could be
exchanged between different elements we
think recombination is
important um but beyond that we really
don't know whether there are particular
genetic features associated with
starships that maybe predispose them to
acquiring cargo from other parts of the
genome or from other Starships as well
but we know that those types of
sequences or is elements um in bacteria
exist so we would predict that maybe
something similar is going
on yes question you mentioned that uh
stash typically have more copy
number although You observe like some
have multip copy number so I Wasing plan
to investigate what mechanism cop number
how does that
affect yeah so the question is uh do we
have any plans to understand how copy
number control is enforced in fungal
genomes and we have no plans to do it
but we're really interested in in
understanding how that might happen
right whether it's host controlled or
whether it's through some mechanism that
might be encoded on the Starship so over
time you might have you might expect
there would be selection for elements
that maybe minimize the detrimental
impact they have on their particular
host kind of like thinking about host
parasite or host viral coevolution over
time you get a less you get you get the
evolution of a virus or sequence that's
just more able to persist within a host
um don't know if that's something
similar going on
here question in the back so if I if I
caught this right there's subset of
genes on the mobile elements that are
core genes from the p analysis and I'm
wondering are there does that tend to be
a common theme between
Starships um and do those genes are any
of them known to be essential and if so
is that like a mechanism of kind of
vertical uh stability for it through
about propagation the question is in
some cases there are core genes that are
located on Starships and is there any
evidence that their core presence
absence pattern PS are somehow Rel
linked to an essential
function no I have no yeah I have no
idea um uh I will say you know like any
analysis certainly a Pang genome
analysis what is core um in one
particular data set could ultimately end
up to be you know accessory as you add
more and more genomes not sure if that's
the case with these particular genes but
when we look at their functions we have
no idea what they're doing or whether or
not they are essential
I think maybe have any questions on the
zoom none that I can see okay um so
let's thank our speaker again and we're
gonna have the uh student and po launch
up okay great
thank this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu