this is a production of Cornell
University um yeah thanks yourself for
the words um so yeah today I'll be
talking about pre- and post Harvest
Management in apple focusing on a
Norwegian perspective um kind of giving
some insight into the fact that yes we
can grow apples in Norway and how we
grow them um so and there will be a
sufficient amount of um beautiful
pictures um to just show off a little
bit so just so you're
aware um this is like right outside my
office really or pretty close to yeah
it's in my
town it's pretty epic um so just a kind
of General brief overview I'll give a
overall background of a little bit about
Norway and my um Institute in general
and then um fruit growing in Norway um
tie it into explaining a little bit
about the climate of Norway and how that
impacts growing and then specifically
how it impacts post Harvest um certain
disorders since that's what I focus on
um and then tying in some new cultivars
that we've just had and how that impacts
post Harvest research how that impacts
my research and leading that into my PhD
and essentially why am I even at
Cornell um
so I was going to talk about me but
Yousef pretty much did that so I'm from
Maine I want that to be said I'm not
Norwegian fullon
American went to undergrad here worked
for a couple years in Western New York
and then decided I needed to learn how
to do research properly so I did a
master's also in Norway because I wanted
more cold and um more winter so I was
like let's go to Norway um and then I
found out they had fruit they had apples
and I decided to stay so I did my thesis
um at nibio The Institute that I work at
now um and now as part of my um position
as a scientist I am doing a PhD um in
partnership with nio my university in
Norway and now with Carnell as well so
that's kind of the overall
connection um so I don't I also don't
expect everyone to have a grasp of where
Norway is and why this is impactful but
basically Norway is like way up here way
at the tippity top it's about the same
I'm about the same latitude as ankorage
Alaska um but because of the Gulf Stream
we it's warmer than an Anchorage so we
can grow more things and we can grow
apples commercially whereas in Alaska
they couldn't necessarily so that's just
the general context of why why I can
even be working on apples in
Norway um
generally my Institute
is um it's kind of this combination of
extension
and
USDA and all this
different culminations of Applied um
agricultural research so it's a fairly
large Institute it's the 750 employees
over 15 different stations positioned in
different spots to focus on whatever
commodity is grown or produced there so
we have a lot of aquaculture up north
and Arctic
Sciences um we have a lot of grasslands
and Forestry in the middle and then the
Big Apple near me is my research station
which focuses just on
fruit um and as you can see Norway is
super long um there's a lot of it's
really ragged Jagged coastline um
there's very little aable land only 3%
of the country can is aable so there's
some unique challenges just based on the
geography um if we zoom in on my station
so this is um these are some of our
Orchards this big um long
building right here is our office
building and then down here we have a
lab building with Windows facing over
the
Fjord um so our station has been around
for 7 5 years um it was um created to
support Fruit Growers in the region um
and we are right in the middle of one of
the largest growing regions for apples
in Norway um so it's a pretty strategic
placement um we are 10 researchers and
eight technicians that work with every
aspect of fruit research from cultivar
and root stock selection all the way
through post Harvest and CER production
um we have a lot of collaboration both
nationally and internationally with
business and researchers other
researchers and especially given the
scale of Norwegian fruit production I
think we have pretty good infrastructure
overall for free
research um if we dig more into Fruit
industry in Norway in general um here in
Norway we classify as fruit and berries
so fruit is like all tree fruit um so we
do work on berries a lot too because
there is a lot of berry growth growing
but that's a different station I don't
work with it at all so I'm just going to
talk on about tree fruit um so Norway
it's primarily Apple Plum Cherry and
pear it's pretty small acreage 4,000
Acres of Apple total but it's also a
small country with five million people
so it doesn't need to be a ton and
there's this other impact of the um
northern latitude obviously affecting
the growing season and where we can grow
the fruit so if we look at the southern
part of Norway which is the only part of
nor where it's warm enough to grow fruit
we have three major growing region
regions one right near Oslo
um one in Telemark right in the middle
here which if you ski is where telmark
skiing was
originated um on one on the west coast
um and I work right here so right in the
middle of this session section and if if
you notice on the map the Big connector
piece here is uh fjords or lakes bodies
of water so as this picture shows it's
you're gr right up to the fiord or the
lake because you really need to take
advantage of um the moderated climate
from the bodies of water to even be able
to grow
anything um but because it's all in
fjords fjords tend to be mountains that
go straight very steeply down into
water so that means we are often growing
un really Steep gradients and you're
growing wherever you can in whatever
amount of space you can right so this is
not uncommon where you see like a
hundred trees planted in between
somebody's house and another house um
because you're just using all the space
that you can possibly
get uh but given that I still think we
have a fairly modern production system
right we use normal trellis system um we
try to plant north south but that's
really directed by the slope if
sometimes you just have to plant however
you can plant it um and even with that
sometimes you can't get a tractor up it
so you have to use an ATV or we have
these special sleds with h treads on
them that can hold one bin of apples so
it gets
interesting um everything is planted on
M9 root stocks um we import all our
trees from the Netherlands for the most
part um so
that we also have been producing trees
in the city or apples in the same region
since the
1200s so obviously they haven't been on
M9
forever but the same areas have been
used for growing apples for 800 years so
the fact that we're all using the same
root stock is kind of fascinating to
me
um there are a few chemical thinners
used
um and it's mostly hand thinning or no
thinning there's a couple reasons for
this it's often too cold to use for
chemical thinners to be effective but
then it's also our largest our um the
Apple that yeah our largest volume um
Apple often gets too large if you thin
it is what the Growers say so we then go
into biannual year but at least or B
annual bearing but at least you have
sellable
fruit uh we also have limited pesticides
especially cons uh compared to the US um
it's similar to in the rest of the EU um
but some pesticides there's just not
enough of a market of people who want
them so the companies don't want to
register them in
Norway um what I do think is kind of
unique is that all our cherries are
grown in tunnels um to prevent rain
cracking so from June to July half our
fields are just covered in white plastic
um because there's so much rain that
it's easy for the cherries to crack so
to commercially produce cherries they
have to be under tunnels we don't use
reflective Fabric or tunnels or anything
or hail nets for anything else but for
Cherries we exclusively use tunnels is
that the single use plastic for That
season no we try to reuse it a couple
times the plastic uh usually lasts like
five to 10 years is it left on the whole
time or is it on and off no we we take
we take off the fabric in the winter or
a in August really so it's only a couple
months out of the year um
but and we obviously have it off for
pollination as
well um overall if we talk closer to
harvest um we produce about 20,000
metric tons of apples per
year um generally from small Orchards
and Family Farms again because we have
this long history sometimes they've been
in the same family for 600
years
um and it's mostly Co-op uh packing
houses where the grower like a
number of Growers deliver to the same um
packing house and own the packing house
um because of the small scale of farming
it's often part-time farming so they The
Growers will have another job on top of
farming as well which complicates
things and um as I guess I pre
previously mentioned there's a lot of
rain so it often means that we're
harvesting in the rain um in New York if
it rains one day you're like oh well
I'll wait until the next day when the
Apple's dry to pick if we did that in
September in Norway you would never pick
a single Apple because it rains every
single
day so it's just something that we have
to deal with you learn to love the rain
um and you know it affects the
apples uh in the past 30 years the
strategy for um Apple production has
been to sell it as fast as possible
basically get everything out before the
end uh the beginning of December um we
have taxes on imported apples until
December 1st so that's the only time
that Norwegian apples have historically
been competitive in the
market uh however Norway wants to be
more self- sustainable right now it is
currently one of the least self-
sustainable countries in the world uh
and fruit is one of the ways it can be
sustain it can be self- sustainable in
Fruit um at least in apples so there's a
bigger focus on trying to increase both
the quality during the current season
selling season of Norwegian apples and
extend the season so there's this uh
renowned or renewed interest in post
Harvest all of a sudden in
Norway at the same time there's also
Resurgence in The Cider industry it it
seems to me like a very similar Trend to
what's been happening in New York the
past 105 years with lots of onale on
Farm sales um lots of marketing lots of
like look at how lovely this product is
and it really is quite great um I it's
it's a similar style I think um to New
York's cider so it it's really helped
the industry a
lot but I said I'd talk specifically
about the weather so we'll go into that
and this is just the reminder again that
everything is due to the Gulf
Stream So I want to directly compare
itha and my region of Norway so for the
next few graphs um Norway will be in
green and Ithaca will be in purple so
the graph on the left is the average
temperature throughout the year and what
I think is interesting here is the high
temperature in Norway during the growing
season is about the same a couple
degrees warmer than the low temperature
in
itha so it just it never gets warm in
Norway the sun makes it feel warm but
degrees wise it never gets very warm so
obviously this impacts Growing Degree
Days so this is uh Growing Degree Days
based on a 10 degree scale and here here
Norway gets about half The Growing
Degree Days in a season as itha
gets that has a big impact on what we
can grow and this is right on a f too
right like the most optimal conditions
that you can get for growing in
Norway but one of the things everybody
knows about Norway if you know something
about Norway is the Midnight Sun the
long daylight hours and the long night
hours in the winter right so OB so if
there's so much light maybe that has an
impact on
um or it can help increase the
growing season even if the temperatures
are
low right and based on this graph on the
left which is the hours of daylight
there's four hours more Daylight during
most of the growing season in Norway
than in
itha but the graph on the right is the
incid incident radiation right so what
actually would hit the tree what you
know is is it is always lower in Norway
than in itha even though we have four
hours more Daylight per day in Norway
and the question there my question
immediately was why and that brings me
back to the oh it's always raining in
Norway and it really is so this is
average monthly
precipitation and what you can see is
the lowest month for precipitation in
Norway still has more precipitation than
the most you'll get in itha on average
so it really is always raining in Norway
uh and then during the Norwegian growing
season which is May 1st to September
30th itha gets 64 days of rain Norway
gets 104 So within a f Monon period we
have more than a month more days of
precipitation
so it really is always raining that has
to affect fruit
quality the plus side is we got awesome
rainbows and we get our own tanic Falls
look alike in my town so some
perks but we're focusing on apples so if
we then go into what apples we actually
grow uh we primarily have five different
cultivars um Aroma uh being this one
being the main variety uh but we also
grow Discovery red Gravenstein summered
and Ruben step um and we harvest in late
August through early October
these were completely unknown varieties
to me um before I moved to Norway and
there's a reason for that is that
they're all really summer varieties um
so for context we have a root stock
planting of galum that ripens in early
to mid
October in New York that's early to mid
September right so there's a month
difference um so it's really debatable
if we can even commercially grow Gayla
because it's on the edge of our growing
season so that's why we only have summer
varieties for the rest of the world and
why our varieties aren't necessarily
relevant historically to the rest of the
world uh as for
storage as stated our late season
storing varieties really aren't late
season they're mid-season at best
they're Gaya comparatives um Gaya can
generally be stored for like eight nine
months in optimal conditions and that's
what we're seeing with our storage
varieties as
well we also see because a lot of them
are early season varieties that they
lose firmness really quickly which is
typical of Summer varieties right you
pick them and they're soft if you look
at them uh and then to complicate
everything 1 mCP which is super common
ethylene inhibitor um right used in the
US commercially for 25 years was just
approved last year in Norway so we're
we're catching up at a rapid Pace to the
trends but it's we have some setbacks
that we've been working with and another
setback there is that we generally
harvest the fruit to write for long-term
storage um in part because of the
tradition of just sell the fruit as fast
as possible and you want the nicest
fruit if you're selling it right away so
you harvest it
late however we still pick or we still
sell the earliest pick fruit
first and that's the best fruit for
storage and then we end up storing the
late harvested fruit and that's the
worst fruit for storage so there needs
to be this like reconstruction of how
people think about how to store fruit um
we also have Harvest requirements that
aren't based on storage they're B based
on Direct sale and then we have this
really long Harvest window where Growers
are allowed to harvest for three to four
weeks um and we have the compounding
factor of gruit being in the
rain uh we also don't have internal
defect orders on packing lines we have
external ones so anything on the outside
we can sort out but if there's any
Browning or anything wrong inside we
can't see it so we don't actually know
how big of a problem internal disorders
are um and just really quickly to
emphasize the loss of firmness this is
in Aroma our main
cultivar um which is a midseason Variety
in Norway but according to the um Gan
bank or the
um yeah according to Geneva it ripens in
August August 21st 25th so pretty early
season um it this green line is the
requirement it needs to be at um at
packing for firmness
level um which is five kilos at Harvest
is usually six to seven and it loses
that by about six weeks of storage and
we're trying to store it for nine weeks
optimally with some firmness left during
shelf life which it clearly doesn't have
um so 1 mCP application and CI help but
we don't know for how long it it's never
going to be a six month storage variety
so complicate that bringing in the
disorders finally we also get soft scald
on it which is a really common chilling
injury common on honey crisp as well um
and we have ways to mitigate it that are
similar to how you mitigate in honey
crisp but in honey crisp you can
condition it for 10 day or seven days at
10 degrees um and then bring it down to
a cooler temperature but with Aroma it
gets soft so fast that you can't do it
so you have to debate if you want soft
scald or you want soft fruit and that's
kind of what we have to that's the
constant debate we have to work with um
and there is some evidence that growing
season seems so affect it and weather
seems so affect it but there's no
consistent
um indications of
that the other common disorder of honey
crisp so honey crisp it's often soft
scalled bitter pit um are talked about
so we do have bitter pit um but it's not
at significant levels you see it in also
in Aroma as you do soft scald and
calcium sprays generally work but um
it's hard to find scientific proof that
they work and there is variation between
Seasons which is what we see in New York
but it's just never at high amounts it's
like 5% is your like is a high year for
bitter pit so my question is I think
it's just not warm enough in Norway it
it could also be cul of our
susceptibility but I think it's just the
temperatures are never warm the calcium
can be distributed into the fruit for a
longer portion of the growing season
it's not as much of an issue that's my I
I don't have hard evidence for this but
this is just my general enal train of
thought and some positive to the cold
growing season
perhaps um we have also seen a rise in
other lenil disorders um that are not
bitter pit this is a variety we it's
hard to decide what is what um but
generally we've seen more in recent
years um which could be linked to
climate change and a slightly warming
climate and a wetter
climate um but it's just a general
observation right
now uh like yeah Norway has decided to
follow the trends of the rest of the
world recently um in that because we
have no variety that's really really
good at for storage we need something
that's better that can be stored better
and we also need something that's
crispier juicier sweeter attractive to
the like new consumers right so we need
a honey crisp type of apple in Norway so
the largest distributor decided to um
choose a choose two crossings from the
Netherlands and start planting those so
they both have the same two parents sq1
159 which is a Dutch variety and honey
crust and um one of them is called Eden
in Norway it's red and orange pretty
firm crunchy super sweet um like that
that's the one thing you taste is sweet
and then the second is freed which is
your more classic looking variety firm
crunchy sweet but more balanced flavor
you taste it or I tast and think this
tastes like Cy
crisp uh so it's great that we have new
varieties that can attract a different
consumer base however following the
trend can have
consequences as we might be aware of
so there seems to be this equation where
if you breed a new variety that has
honey Cris parentage it's of not tested
enough and it often has problems once
it's commercially planted Norway has
followed that same Trend where you have
a honey Cris parent you have commercial
planting um started without prior
research so for context the oldest trees
in Norway are six years old um the first
commercial production year was 2020 and
that was the first year we could start
research on these trees so that has led
to biannual bearing unsurprised Uris
inly this is this picture is Extreme I
wanted to show it but it it does happen
um and also lots of disorders so the the
two common things that you get with this
equation so that's been great for my
research at least because it gives me
two things that are relevant across the
at least the post Harvest industry um
across the world so the two things I'm
looking at in my research are core
Browning and water core so core
Browning just super briefly um is often
worse in cold climate it's not yeah um
so that might be part of why we see it
here um we see it in both Eden and free
but it's also seen in honey crisp and
everris which is another that's a honey
crisp and Fuji
Offspring um and so what I think is
really interesting here is that Eden and
freed seem to have different causes of
core Browning despite being so similarly
related so Eden it seems to be very
ccent related and freed it seems to be a
variety of factors influencing it not
one factor directly caused with it and
that's the same with honey crisp and
ever crisp is that that's this
interesting like combination of factors
all adding up to disorder
incidents
so I think the um discrepancies within
similar Cult of Art is fascinating to
me and then water core um
is technically a pre Harvest disorder
but
it's uh excess orbital accumulation in
the um intercellular space and we have
seen it historically in Norway but it's
only been very stress related water core
which is very externally visible so you
can pick it out on packing lines so it's
not really a big problem necessarily
um ironically it's related to heat waves
and warm growing seasons in Norway um
even though it never gets really hot but
it's warm enough that um if it's warm
near Harvest it will cause water
core um however Eden one of the new
varieties gets a different type of water
core called maturity water core um that
happens mostly in the core um and is not
externally
visible and it is some sometimes related
to cool temperatures near Harvest aka
the whole growing season in Norway um
and increases with later uh ripening and
later
harvesty and as the current marketing is
that they want to pick this fruit really
late and when it's an orange background
color we get up to
76% watercore at harvest in commercially
picked fruit so it's this big issue um
and we see it also in everris one of the
honey crisp or honey Cris and Fuji cross
but in
contrast Eden um is more problematic
because the water core can turn brown
within two to three weeks after
harvest so we really need to figure out
how to prevent water core from the start
in
Eden um but I also want to see why it
acts so differently in Eden and evercast
even though they're related so that
brings me quickly to my
thesis which is a similar title to um my
talk today um pre and post Harvest
factors in relation to physiological
disorder development for sustainable
Apple
production um so and it's in
collaboration with nibio Cornell and
nmbu so what that means is I'm looking
mostly at cor Browning and water core
and trying to dig into the causes a
little bit and the growing season and
growing region factors that could impact
disorder development um I won't
necessarily go into all these points um
but if I briefly go over the general
methods just so it's understandable why
I'm doing it here and why it's could be
applied here so I'm for core Browning
I'm looking at different storage
temperatures different storage
treatments in all three
varieties um over multiple
years um to compare how the same
treatments affect the fruit
differently um and I'll look at I'll dig
into ethylene receptor gene expression
as well but it's mostly a applied
storage trial um to really try to
understand why core Browning in Eden is
ccent and related and why it's not in
ever Crispen freed um and how variety
and growing season differences and
growing region differences affect that
for water core there's a couple
different sections of this um I'm
looking at Water core development on the
tree and near Harvest at different
Harvest times in both Eden and evercrisp
and trying to see if pattern development
like if incident development is similar
across the two and
um yeah if that affects different a
certain PA part of the sorbital um
metabolism pathway in the same way or in
different ways in the two
varieties uh and then I'm also doing
kind of the reverse in storage because
water core can go away in storage it can
the sorbitol can be taken up by the
fruit um so then I want to see if this
process happens similarly in the two
cultivars in Eden and ever crisp um and
then also if um the gene expression in
the metabolism pathway is kind of the
reverse of at Harvest and on top of that
I want to look and see if you can while
here at Cornell um use um some of the
Nano x-ray uh technology to see if you
can um track the same fruit through
storage to watch the dissipation in one
fruit over time and watch the orbital
kind of go away in a way or be
absorbed and then the final part that's
relevant to Cornell is I want to look at
the effect of root stock on water core
incidents in development so this will be
done at the two um root stock planting
Trials of everris and Geneva and Hudson
Valley um ideally with a couple
different Harvest timings and looking at
differences in sorbital accumulation
water core development and then because
it's in the two locations looking at
growing region differences with the
ultimate goal of eventually maybe this
can be then applied in Norway um with
eventual root stock plant things
there
um yes so that's what I had to say
really about basically why I'm here why
I my research could be at all
relevant um and just wanted to end with
my actual office
views um I have a corner office
so I look out on these two views um and
then this is my field office
uh and just a plug is we have a post
Harvest pathology conference happening
hopefully in Spring 2026 in Norway um so
if you want to see these views in person
you're welcome to come for
them that's what I have guess one
one there any
questions SE
questions what whe the soil is
like it seems me there's not a whole lot
of weathering so yeah
it's yeah so Marvin's asking about the
different soils um so they're very
organic actually uh because it's so cold
that there is a lot of erosion at times
because you can have landslides and
avalanches and everything um but nothing
decomposes really
fast so it's a really high organic
matter soil
I I don't know the other basis for the
soils actually um and I maybe
should but they relatively deep I mean
you have trage issues yeah they are I
think they are relatively deep
um there yeah they
work well enough that's
yeah
um yeah there's one question in the chat
from Thomas saying is there any
potential for newer varieties used in
central Sweden um like Ren Silva and
Frederick they're not known for storage
um I haven't heard of any of those
varieties actually
um but we do often most of our varieties
actually come from Sweden
um and we tend to grow the same things
as in Sweden
so there is potential that we could use
those as
well yeah about your boot stock so you
said in Norway it's 800 years
cultivation yeah okay so how is it that
in 2014 it seems like there's one root
stock that seems to be what replacing it
seems pretty dangerous to have one root
stock you would think over 800 years
there would be some resistance that
build up and and so is there any effort
to try to look for that and put that
into the breeding line
in future yeah yeah so the question is
about um why we still use the same root
stock after or yeah why we everything
has grown on M9 even though we've been
growing for 800 years
and how that impacts different
resistance to diseases and such and I
would say and if we're looking into it
so we do have root stock plantings we're
part of the Euro fin um Network and so
we do look into different um root stocks
but the problem really is that
commercially because we have such low
volumes it's hard
to um ask for very specific varieties on
very specific root
stocks so I think that's a large part of
why we're forc why we all have M9 is
because we just can't get anything else
other than just M9 because the root the
uh nurseries don't want to offer us
anything other than just M9
um but hopefully we can um steer away
from that and
towards a more more variation in the
root stocks because it is dangerous to
plan on the same ground for so long for
sure
yeah yeah so my question has a little
bit of background and it's that uh I'm
from Ontario Canada where in the 1980s
the provincial government spent many
millions of dollars paying great Growers
to pull out Cult of virs that didn't
work anymore and then they gave them
money to put in cultivars that work so
if there's 5,000 Acres of apple trees in
Norway and all of these problems such as
the cultiv bars aren't right and there's
one root stock and that sort of thing uh
has Norway I it would never happen here
in the States but is Norway considered
just paying the Growers to pull them all
out and put in some robust
cultivars yeah so the question is about
why don't we just take out the ones that
don't the cultivars that don't work and
put in new ones and government yeah
exactly yeah government grer dollars as
well struggling with these cultivars
that that don't seem to that's what the
two new cultivars were supposed to do so
that was there's there was this big push
um Eden and Fred have been the two most
highly planted cultivars ever
potentially like it's a for Norway it's
a lot of trees planted um right they
were supposed to bring along the like
new Revolution and it's not working so
far so because they didn't they didn't
do enough testing um so I I think that
might go along eventually but there's
also this push back where some people
want the traditional varieties even
though they don't store well or anything
right because that's a Norwegian Apple a
Norwegian apple is supposed to be soft
Norwegian apples supposed to smell like
raw because that's just the smell of
Norwegian apples
um so
there's there's some back and forth um
but I I think in some ways it could be
good to just kind
of reset but you have to have enough
knowledge about the varieties that
you're going to plan and that's that was
the key problem that we've learned
now so yeah oh yeah great presentation I
guess my question is in regards to the
uh banal bearing habits so
um from what I gathered from the
presentation that seems to be kind of
the the trend in the way the orchard is
managed there's very little thinning and
if it all is hand thinning do you think
that's going to be kind of an issue is
climate change kind ofes more prominent
in the future right with like they
spring Frost I'm just thinking like you
know if you're managing the orchard by
any Elite you have a frost event right
then your crop's going by by right so
that was a like a crop insurance plan
the grower couldn't bu into for that
like how that work yeah so the question
was about different biannual or like how
biannual bearing system essentially is
going to be impacted by climate change
and
in there is crop insurance we do have
that um but I I think there's a there's
definitely a push
towards uh preventing B anual bearing
and there's a push towards more annual
bearing and I think that's going to be
the solution frankly to B annual bearing
and climate change is annual
production um so it's just and with the
warming climate chemical thinners will
work better so then it'll be easier um
hopefully to have an annual production
system um so but I I think it's also
just getting Growers to understand the
economic benefits of thinning and some
people get it and some
people don't or or don't
care enough like they're fine with what
they have right now and it works for
them thank so yeah yeah you clarify the
roock issue what was the rostock used by
the Norwegian Apple industry before 2014
yeah so before 2019 it was or 2014 it
was also still M9 that was used so since
since we've been doing um dwarfing root
Sox has been
M9 um for time yeah yeah it was just
before 2014 we weren't allowed to buy um
trees from other countries we had to
produce everything internally and it was
really
expensive so from 2014 it was allowed
for us to buy it elsewhere and looking
at the temperature sort of the seasonal
change of temperature average
temperatures the uh area where apples
are grown in Norway actually the
temperatures are higher than EA right
during the winter oh during the winter
yes yes yeah it's a much more stable
climate yeah so cold damage or winter
freezing damage is rarely an issue yeah
it it happens but it's not a big problem
for sure okay
yeah yeah just wondering a little bit
more about the The Cider industry are
they using these culinary varieties or
do they have different traditional
varieties that they've been using for
cider or they bringing in varieties from
from other parts of Europe or what's
happening yeah so the cider industry is
mostly based off of the dessert apples
um so it's really big on single varietal
cers actually uh you you do have Blends
uh but there's also like marketing for
like a specific ARA cider and a specific
Gravenstein
cider um they are bringing in British uh
CER varieties as well uh and bringing
back some old traditional varieties but
most of it is leftover from um from
industry like it's industry fruit um
with some people growing specifically
for cider it'll solve your post Harvest
issue right there yeah it helps a lot
yeah there there it definitely does a
lot for it
yeah what do you mean by culinary
varieties I thought those are fresh
Apple apples for Fresh Markets culinary
means for
cooking right for kitchen use well I
don't know the term culinary can mean
Fresh Market or fresh eating but I guess
that's what I meant the the the VAR The
Fresh Market varieties
yeah yeah I kind had a related question
how would you describe the average
consumer there in nor way compared to
like the US like are they more
sophisticated they know BR they ask for
varieties you know here they're you know
are they and how much do they eat
relative to to like say a typical
American yeah so the average consumer in
Norway does not know different varieties
um sometimes they know Norwegian variety
like one or two Norwegian varieties but
it's still like red green yellow apple a
lot of the time um they also generally
um
have because we're at the end of the
supply chain the quality in general of
our fruits and vegetables are lower I
would say than in the
US um so generally they're less picky
perhaps in some ways um at least I've
had to become less picky when I'm there
but I'm not a traditional consumer
either I will
qualify um but it's a very meat and
potatoes
country um so you have meat and potatoes
for dinner with a side of
vegetables um so it's also very like
like traditional um crops still right
like very root vegetable
based um but it it's expanding um the
consumer base is definitely getting more
adventurous and trying more things and
demanding more so we're we're getting
there I think we're just like 10 years
behind the US in Trends it's my
guesss I presume there are Imports and
or not yeah there's there are where they
coming from so our Imports mostly come
from Italy and
Poland um but we also get stuff from New
Zealand and Chile depending on the
season obviously um but when possible it
tries to be we try to be in
Europe but you know the question was do
consumers know their apples are they all
La by variet
though sometimes okay um normally when
you have Norwegian apples it's Norwegian
red apples this much per Kil
so the grocery stores aren't helping
either right and like sometimes they
separate out the Norwegian apples and
they'll put like Norwegian flags up and
sometimes they don't um so there there
needs to be more work at the grocery
store side of it too right and the
distributor side of it to like really
sell but import apples are so cheap so
it just makes it easier to just sell
import
apples so
yeah yeah I me was the restrict
regulation for using pesticide and
fungicide in Europe and Norway right how
you overcome the wet weather there and
what's also like during the preh Harvest
and post Harvest and what's the impact
of the total amount of the production
which can be consumed or go to the
storage yeah
so we don't really have a great way to
overcome the impact of limited
pesticides and the growing season in the
wetness um so we get a lot of fruit
rot um and we also can apply pesticide
or uh fungicides post Harvest we can't
apply anything post Harvest we can't
apply wax and like nothing um so there's
a lot of we try to use cultural methods
right and try to be good about sorting
pre- sorting fruit when we can um and
right now the big um thing we've
realized is that a lot of Growers Don't
Spray fungicides after
July so now we're trying to push for a
spray of fundra sdes in August so that
they actually work post Harvest so I I
think that's the The Next Step that will
increase our storability a lot and
increase our marketable
fruit okay good then thank you yeah
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu