this is a production of Cornell
University engaged learning is a key
component of our mission at Cornell
University as we prepare students to be
creative collaborative and critically
reflective leaders we take that really
seriously in horiculture where we engage
students in three important ways we
provide students with direct hands-on
experience es we also give students
chances to apply what they've learned in
communities from the community of the
classroom to local and global settings
and we provide students with
opportunities to reflect on their
learning to consider and articulate how
they will use what they've learned to
make the world a better place as they
grow to become leaders in horiculture so
what does engage AG learning look like
in horiculture let's look at some
examples students in creating the urban
Eden serve the Campus Community while
they learn they design and install
landscape plantings as part of their
intensive study of more than 300 species
of trees shrubs and Vines including this
runoff filtering bios Swale along Tower
Road we all enjoy the visual impact of
their work while walking across this
beautiful campus in Horticultural
science and systems students delve into
many Hands-On activities from planting
trees to harvesting Peppers to donating
to a local food bank they sample food
remove invasive plants from natural
areas and create Textile Art with
plant-based dyes every fall students in
restoration ecology take on a real world
project in the local community
working together to gather data analyze
the issues and Report their findings one
year they investigated coste effective
options for using sediment from future
dredging in the kuga lake Inlet to
promote ecosystem Services the
experiential learning students gain in
the field is not separate from their
classroom experience rather it builds on
it Agricultural Science majors and many
plants science Majors complete a summer
internship to explore career interests
they apply coursework to real world
problems and network with Growers and
agricultural professionals as well as K
through2 audiences Master Gardener
volunteers and others some create blogs
to reflect on their experiences both
what they learned and then how it
changed them viticulture and enology
majors are also engaged in all phases of
growing grapes and making wine from
planting pruning and managing a 500 Vine
organic Vineyard near campus to
harvesting the grapes and bottling the
fruits of their
labor in my course the art of
horiculture students get firsthand
experience with a range of plant-based
materials and media choosing one for an
intensive creative project inclass
experiences strengthen the link to
learning and exercise exercises and
writing encourages students to reflect
on the impact of Nature and Gardens on
their well-being we create public art
which may range from a sad sofa on
campus to special installations such as
the large scale stickwork Willow
sculpture at the Ithaca Children's
Garden budding student researchers
frequently are guided in individual
studies of their own design by faculty
mentors students have worked with with
one Professor to grow vegetable
transplants for distribution to
lowincome families to encourage home
gardening and healthy diets others have
worked in communities through
Cooperative Extension programs ranging
from school garden Partnerships with the
elementary schools to working with
farmers and Commercial Growers Hands-On
horiculture instills non- Majors with a
lifelong appreciation for plants and
teaches them basic Horticultural skills
s they apply techniques such as pruning
to campus Landscapes and fruit trees at
the Cornell Orchards and students in a
freshman seminar have gotten their hands
dirty partnering with Habitat for
Humanity to see Lawns for low income
housing but Cornell is a global
University and the communities in which
our students work extend far beyond Etha
in my course experiential garden-based
learning and bise the students spend
their entire spring break creating
School Gardens and teaching lessons that
tie the garden to the curriculum in
southern bise so by focusing on those
three things direct experience
reflection and Community engagement
we're preparing our students to become
leaders in their field in their
communities and all around the world
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu