this is a production of Cornell
University so it's a real pleasure to be
here at Cornell and I'm glad that Alan
arranged it so that the snow cleared
just before my arrival um okay so I'm
going to be talking about uh the the
nitrogen problem in food production it's
a it's a very familiar problem and this
is a very familiar site in most of our
uh food production in in both the US and
in Europe the heavy use of nitrogenous
fertilizers that promote crop growth and
really without that use of nitrogenous
fertilizers we couldn't support the
population that we currently support on
the planet and we certainly couldn't
support an expanding population going up
to 10 billion so it's very difficult to
see a uh a society that that weans
itself off this use of fertilizers I
would say we're very dependent on it's
been estimated that the natural uh
nitrogen cycle can support about 3
billion people on the planet so you
could imagine that 4 billion people are
currently dependent on Harbor Bosch and
by 2050 we'll about have about 7 billion
people dependent on the Harbor Bosch
process so it it's it's really hard to
imagine how we get away from this uh
heavy use of nitro nitrogenous
fertilizers now this is one of the
results of those nitrogenous fertilizers
this is a lake in China heavily uh utro
um heavy uh um contamination from uh
nitrogen uh pollution causing these
algal blooms
and certainly uh nitrogen fertilizers
are one of the major agricultural
pollutants that we get uh on our planet
uh and most of the nitrogen most of the
reactive nitrogen that is polluting both
our aquatic systems and also our
atmosphere is is originating from the
use of nitrogenous fertilizers but
actually today I'm not really going to
talk too much about the environmental
degradation that we get from our
nitrogen fertilizers it's it's much more
a focus on the inequality of the
availability of nitrogen fertilizers so
on this map I'm showing you the global
nitrogen consumption around the planet
and and you can see that places I don't
know whether this I don't think these
these don't work do their pointers on
the on a screen like this but the the
the dark green areas like here in the US
and Western Europe and China and India
heavy uses of nitrogen fertilizers um
and as I said um with all the the uh
consequent environmental degradation
but I think in some ways a tragedy on
this is when you look at subsaharan
Africa it's almost a blank on this slide
very very limited use of nitrogenous
fertilizers in in African Agriculture
and that's because most farmers in
Africa in subsaharan Africa are small
holder Farmers less than a hectare of of
land very little financial resources
available to them and simply not the
capability to purchase a nitrogenous
fertilizers or financial capabilities
available to purchase a nitrogenous
fertilizers and as a result of that if
we look at this analysis that was um
published in nature a few years ago here
they were asking what is limiting maze
productivity around the planet so this
is only looking at maze but if you look
at you can go to this paper and you can
see also all the other serial crops
wheat and rice um but if it's in green
then it's already 50% above the yield
potential so that's out of the analysis
so it's only the regions that are not
achieving a yield potential so well
below the 50% yield potential and the
the areas that are not achieving their
yield potential they ask is it the
availability of nutrients or is it the
availability of water and I think this
is actually a very surprising result so
blue means it's both nutrients and water
and red means it's just nutrients so
it's only parts of AR the Arid areas of
Eastern Africa where if you you have to
if you want to increase your
productivity you have to irrigate and
add fertilizers but most of the uh maze
growing areas uh in the world
particularly in subsaharan Africa it's
really not water liit limitation that's
restricting growth it's the availability
of nutrients and those nutrients are
nitrogen and phosphorus the the pr
dominant ingredients of
fertilizers so if we are going to
increase productivity in these areas of
subsaharan Africa and in particular
increase productivity for small holder
Farmers you have to tackle this issue if
you don't tackle this issue then you
cannot raise the yield potential in
those uh in those regions of subsaharan
Africa for where for small holder
farmers are suffering from the inab
ability to produce enough prod
productivity now I would say there's
really two scenarios that by which we
can achieve this you could follow the
China model and in China they
essentially subsidize fertilizer
production by building fertilizer
factories producing L vast amounts of
fertilizer that essentially brought the
cost of fertilizers down to the point
where small holder Farmers could afford
those fertilizers and and that's been a
very successful strategy in China the
consequences of it is massive excess use
of nitren fertilizers and the picture I
showed you is not surprisingly from
China where uh massive use of
fertilizers have led to huge scales of
putrification
I would say that scenario is very
unlikely at least at the moment in
Africa most governments in Africa cannot
afford to build uh large um f fertilizer
factories to support their agricultural
base and you know I would say the
countries that could have AFF it like
Nigeria they've got a lot of oil wealth
they're producing a lot of oil wealth
there seems to be very little desire to
use that oil wealth to support their
agricultural base so it seems I would
say unlikely that we're going to solve
this issue of nitrogen
availability um in subsaharan Africa by
just waiting for fertilizer prices to
come down to a point that small holder
farmers can afford them
so that's why the Gates Foundation is
funding a program uh that I had we call
it engineering the nitrogen symbiosis
for Africa and this is essentially
asking can we utilize biological
nitrogen fixation so plants around the
uh through the evolution of plants
they've really many organism many times
they've struggled with the availability
of nitrogen the availability of nitrogen
is not just a limitation in agriculture
it's also a limitation in some
environments in a number of environments
in the natural world and to succeed in
those environments the plant has to find
a way to acquire nitrogen by other means
and one example of that uh of of solving
that problem is shown here which is
legumes peas and beans that are able to
interact with nitrogen fixing bacteria
resulting in the formation of these
nitrogen fixing nodules that are
essentially nitrogen factories on the
roots that can deliver the full need the
full nitrogen needs of those plants now
the question is how can we use this
nitrogen fixing availability to address
the problems in nitrogen availability in
subsaharan Africa certainly if we can
use biological nitrogen fixation it
provides a much more sustainable Avenue
for delivering
nitrogen but that is a hugely complex
process to engineer what I'm showing you
here are all the nodules on a p route
and moving that transferring that
capability the complexity of producing a
completely novel organ into a Serial
rout it's it's a a big Challenge and I
accept of it's a big challenge so just
to demonstrate the opportunities in this
area I've mocked up this graph and it's
a mockup of a graph but it is based on
real data so on the x-axis is looking at
nitrogen fertilizer application rates on
the y- axis we're looking at yields so
it's a familiar site as you increase
fertilizer use you increase yields um
and the uh World average for fertilizer
uses around 130 kg of nitren per hectare
um here in the US you're somewhat above
that and in China we're actually off the
graph it's around 220 kg of nitrogen per
Hector the in contrast small holder
farmers are right at the Other Extreme
here small holder farmers in subsaharan
Africa using 3 to 5 kilog of nitrogen
per Hector extraordinarily low levels
and that includes not that's not just
nitrogen fertilizers that includes all
the manures that they have access to as
well so they're putting very very small
levels of nitrogen onto their fields and
as a result they're getting these
extremely low levels and I in this graph
I'm showing you the region that's
highlighted in blue I would say is a
region of greatest opportunity so
legumes actually fix nitrogen around 110
around 110 kilogram of nitrogen per
hectare so that's that's pretty well at
the top of this graph uh where where
you're getting pretty well getting close
to the maximum potential yields so if I
want to replace nitrogen fertilizers
here in the US or anywhere else in the
developing World agriculture I need to
move in totality the complexity of a
nitrogen fixing P nodule to a Serial
route but in in a context of small
holder Farmers there they're at the
Other Extreme of this graph and in fact
relatively modest levels of nitrogen
fixation in small holder farming systems
can double or triple yields so in that
blue window of just around 25 to kog of
nitrogen if we can get 25 to 50 kg of
fixed nitrogen into the crops of small
holder Farmers then we're looking at
doubling or tripling the yields real
great opportunities there and in that
regard getting to that level of fixed
nitrogen I think is much more
achievable so the process of making a
nodule is pretty complex definitely
we've got the um it's a bit dark on here
but the uh on the left you're seeing the
mechanisms by which the bacteria infect
The legum Roots so they do so through uh
root hair Cur root hairs that curl
around the bacteria the ATT bacteria
that attached to the root air um and uh
they form infection threads that grow
down into the root air and you can see
the blue staining as the bacteria inside
the root hair uh which will ultimately
grow down all the way in on the right
you see a the nodule that's been
initiated and the light blue staining at
the top is the infection thread growing
down into the nodule and ultimately the
bacteria released into as infection
droplets into uh compartments within the
cells where they fix nitrogen so a lot
of complexity there and transferring all
of that complexity I would say is pretty
challenging but when you look in the
legume uh diversity of legumes you see
actually see a the degree of diversity
in the complexity of these nodule
structures so on the right is a a nodule
in medic cargot trun catula which I
would say is the iCal of this
evolutionary process but we see much
simpler modes of bacterial infection so
on the left here is a a crack entry is a
it's a different mode it's not it's not
going through root airs much simpler
mode of bacterial infection that goes
through where root where where lateral
Roots break through the epidermis and
allow the invasion of the bacteria and
in the middle are stem nodules on Asom
and those if you actually look at these
on a surface of a of an Asom SHO
you would never say they're nodules
they're swellings on the surface that
have leg hemoglobin present in them they
they certainly do not reflect the
complexity that we see say in medic
cargo trun capsula and I think while the
complexity that we see in say P or medic
cargo supports the high levels of
nitrogen fixation much of that
complexity is really about increasing
efficiency increasing the efficiency of
the nitrogen fixation process and if
we're really talking about trying to get
lower levels of nitrogen fixation so say
in a 25 to 50 kg of fixed nitrogen into
small holder farming systems I think we
don't need all of that complexity we can
get away with some of the much more
simpler processes that we see say in
Asom or in Tania and they will deliver
they won't deliver I don't think we'll
be able to replace nitrogen fertilizers
in totality with those kind of systems
but we can certainly deliver very useful
levels of fixed nitrogen to uh to small
holder farmers in Africa and in time
time I would say in time we will get to
the point I think it's just a matter I I
truly believe we can move nitrogen
fixing nodules into cereals the problem
is just the complexity of the process to
deal with 20 years ago I I would have
shocked you if IID said we can I can
sequence your genome in a couple of days
time for a mere1 or
$2,000 and that's become possible just
in the last sort of 10 or 15 years
technology is advancing it's advancing
very quickly what we can't do now we
will be able to do in the future so I
hope that over time we can be providing
some level of fixed nitrogen that's
useful in a small holder farming system
and gradually getting to the level of
complexity that we see in say a p or
metac cargo nodule to really deliver
truly replacing nitrogenous fertilizers
also here in the developed world but in
the shorter stage I think we can
actually probably deliver something much
more useful in the developing world than
perhaps what we might Envision as in
replacing fertilizers here in the US
okay so in order to achieve that I I've
broken it down into I think there's four
main steps that we have to transfer into
cereals or four main processes that we
have to transfer into cereals to get
nitrogen fixing nodules into a seral
crop one is to engineer the recognition
of the RIS obial bacteria that's the
very first step that happens when a
legume uh legum perceives the nitrogen
fixing bacteria and then initiates the
processes associated with accommodating
those bacteria second stage is initiate
the formation of a nodule so transfer
the nodul organogenesis the capability
to make this new structure third process
and probably I think one of the most
complex is engineering the bacterial
infection processes and lastly uh but
not least is engineering within the
context of the nodule and the back where
the bacteria present the suitable
environment for nitrogen fixation so I
would say that those those four steps
there four quite different steps four
quite different processes that we need
to consider and in the in the the gates
funded program that we're initiating
it's really at this stage a proof of
concept I'm certainly not expecting to
deliver nitrogen fixing Cals in two and
a half years which will be the end of
the first round of funding what we're
focusing on is a very first step
engineering Ryobi recognition into
serials and putting aside at the moment
the second third and fourth steps
something to worry about for the future
rounds in the first round we need to
something that's achievable which is
engineering roval recognition in Cals
and we know that that Rial recognition
sorry it's so dark but we know that that
Rial recognition is really the key step
I wonder if I can just if I increase the
brightness on my computer no I'm at the
max on my computer so it's not my comp
not me okay so the um the processes of
recognition that are the way the means
by which a a plant recognizes Ryobi
bacteria every time a seed germinates it
has to find the rise ofial bacteria in
the soil and it does so through this
chemical communication it's been known
for a number of years the plant is
releasing flavonoids those are
recognized by the Ryobi bacteria and
that in turn uh initiates the production
of Nod factors which are diffusible
signals coming from the roval bacteria
that are perceived by the plant and Nod
factors are the structure of Nod factors
has been very well uh characterized has
been known for almost 20 years now it's
a kiteen backbone with an asile tail and
then we have a number of other
decorations around the molecules so this
is the noao Cobian meloi and um which is
the symb of medicago species and it's
sulfated on the reducing terminal sugar
and it's
isolated on the non-reducing terminal
sugar um and those modifications that
differ between the different roral
species and that to a degree defines The
Host range and in fact when you look
across the diversity of Ria we see quite
a wide diversity in these signaling
molecules they always have the k in
backbone they always have the asile tail
but they have a variety of modifications
sulfation carbom fuc cellation
acetalation Etc around this basic
structure and the other thing that
differs is the length and degree of
saturation of the asile tail and those
absolutely Define The Host range of the
different Rial bacteria which roval
bacteria interacts with which uh legume
species so in order to understand how
the plant was perceiving those
uh that no Factor signaling molecule we
undertook a relative a pretty
straightforward genetic screen where we
were just simply asking for mutants of
medic cargo that were incapable to
activate nodu formation in the response
to Ryobi bacteria and this is
essentially the basis of the screen so
the dark spot on the roote indicates a
place where the Ryobi were inoculated on
the root and you can see in a wild Tye
plant you get nodules forming at that
site and in a mutant in this case an np2
mutant you the plant is completely blind
to to the Ryobi bacteria and does is
completely unable to initiate nodule
formation as a result of that genetic
screen we identified a signal signal
transduction pathway that was
responsible for perception of Nod factor
and transmission of that signal down to
uh the a suite of transcription factors
that are involved in uh coordinating
gene expression associated with
nodulation now at the core of the
signaling pathway oscillations in
calcium and I'll just I can just play
you this movie so this is a root air
cell of medarot truncatula that we've
micro injected with a calcium responsive
dye and then what you're seeing at the
moment is just the dye relocalizing
around the cell but once we treat this
root with nod Factor you can see that
the region of the nucleus begins to
oscillate its calcium those oscillations
are always in the are predominantly in
the nucleoplasm but they're also
occurring in the nuclear Associated
cytoplasm we know that the store of the
calcium is the is the Endo reticulum but
particularly the region around the
nuclear envelope where the channels and
pumps associated with this response are
localized and that calcium oscillations
will continue for up to 24 hours while
over no factor is present and it's
essentially transmitting the signal
saying that nod factor is recognized at
the plasma membrane and transmitting
that signal into the nucleus to activate
the the the ultimately activate the
production of the transcription factors
in the nuc
now uh the molecular view of that
pathway essentially we've got three main
complexes associated with this signaling
process firstly we've got the receptor
like kinases that are involved in
perceiving the no factor and there's a
suite of receptor like kinases that form
a complex on the plasma membrane that we
are now known to actually bind the no
Factor molecule Downstream of that there
are a suite of channels and pumps on the
nuclear membranes that are associated
with producing the calcium oscillations
and then Downstream with the calcium
oscillations we have the calcium
decoding complexes this protein calci
cam K calls calcium and Cal modu
independent protein cyas and it
interacts with a transcription factor
and in conjunction with a suite of other
transcription factors or ultimately
coordinate the gene expression that's
necessary to initiate this Pro the
processes of nodulation and bacterial
infection so we know that those calcium
oscillations are Central not only is a
signaling pathway Central but the
calcium oscillations themselves are
Central and we know that because the
gain of fun because gain of functions in
the protein cam k um which is the
decoding the calcium oscillation so this
is a protein that sits immediately
Downstream with the calcium oscillations
it's a it's a it's a kise with the
capability to bind both calcium on its
own and then calcium in complex with
calmodulin almost certainly we know is
the Protein that's decoding those
calcium oscillations we can create gain
of functions in that protein and when we
transform those gain of functions into
the legume Roots we get spontaneous
induction of nodules in the absence of
rise obia or nod Factor so we know that
just switching on this protein alone is
sufficient to coordinate the whole
process of generating a nodule and uh uh
the whole developmental process is
associated with the formation of a
nodule so that's telling us that the
calcium oscillations alone are
sufficient to to activate those those
processes and once you turn on this
signaling pathway it can coordinate all
of the complexity of development that's
necessary to produce this new structure
of the
nodule now if we look at the evolution
of this process nodulation we most
people think of nodulation in legumes
and that's very familiar there is most
legumes the majority of legumes can
nodulate but nodulation is not actually
restricted to legumes uh it's evolved
multiple times so the red indicates that
s of groups where nodulation has evolved
and all there's multiple origins of the
evolution of nodulation but all
nodulating species are restricted to the
to the R osds so there there's a
suggestion that a predisposition event
facilitated the emergence or the
evolution of nodulation but but
importantly nodulation has emerged
multiple times and not only that
nodulation has emerged multiple times in
the legume species so there is not a
single as far as we can tell either
there's many many thousands of plants
that have lost the capability to
nodulate or more simply probably a few
upwards of 10 12 origins of nodul the
emergence of nodulation in the osds so
one question we had was is this
signaling process and the capability to
activate calcium oscillations is that
limited to legumes or is it more broadly
and broadly occurring in the uh in also
non nodulating um sorry non- legum
nodulating species and these are the
actin arisal species like older trees
that form nodules not with Rial bacteria
but with frankia a filamentous nitrogen
fixing bacteria so for that we wanted to
look to at a number of different species
not only in the legumes so all the work
that have been done in the past on
calcium and and the signaling pathway
have been restricted essentially to
medic cargo truncatula um and Lotus
japonicas which are the main uh uh model
legumes and very not no work have been
done on the more s much more primitive
legumes like cers like Ci Christa which
is a nodulating species or looking for
instance at cers which is a non-
nodulating legume uh that that diverged
before the evolution of nodulation also
we wanted to ask in the the non the
nodulating non legumes such as in the
canabas the parasponia and is is a a
tree a tropical tree that can interact
with rise obia and form nodules or for
instance older alus glutinosa which is a
non- legume that can interact with
frankia bacteria so how common was this
capability to coordin to respond to
nitrogen fixing bacteria and activate
calcium oscillations and for that we
chose this diversity of species and
looked at their capability to activate
calcium spiking and what we found
perhaps not surprisingly in all the
legumes that the capability to activate
nodulation is is is Broad within the
legumes it doesn't occur as far as we
can tell in cus which is a
non-nodulating legume importantly
parasponia which is the only non- legum
that can interact with ryia is also
activating calcium oscillations in
response to its rise obial symbion and
similarly older species which interact
not with ryia with with a frankia and we
know that these frankia bacteria not
producing nod Factor molecules they're
producing a completely different
signaling molecule they are also
activating calcium oscillation so it's
telling us that even though ulation
evolved multiple times as far as we can
tell as as far as we've looked in all
the times where nodulation evolved it's
recruited this signaling pathway and
utilize the same signaling mechanisms to
activate the processes so it's clear
that if we want to transfer this
capability into serials this signaling
pathway is Central to that process
because it's been Central to every case
where nodulation has evolved I can't say
every case because there's some
cucurbits where we haven't been able to
look at yet but all the cases that we've
been able to look at the the capability
to uh perceive the rise obial bacteria
and activate the symbiosis signaling
pathway is a common feature and so
clearly we need to be able to transfer
this signaling capability into Cals if
we're going to be able to transfer
nitrogen fixing
nodulation so if so so I would say I
have to recapitulate the signaling
pathway in Cals now that is a daunting
challenge especially if you think of the
complexity of activating an oscillatory
calcium behavior in your nucleus I would
not like to be able to have to engineer
that thankfully I don't have to do that
and the reason is because actually the
signaling pathway that we had
genetically dissected in medic cargo was
actually not really a nodulation
signaling pathway it's actually a micro
isal signaling pathway at the core of
this signaling path the core of the
signaling pathway is what we call the
common symbiosis signaling pathway it's
duly required not only for uh the the
perception of Ryobi bacteria but it's
also required for recognition of our
vascular micro isal fungi now the
capability to perceive our vascular
micro isal fungi goes L goes way back um
and sorry I'm a little bit ahead of
myself so if we look at the molecular
Viewpoint the the common signaling
components are all shaded in in blue
here or the components that we know are
common to the to nodulation and micro
isal signaling and the red components
are the unique components so so the the
the receptor complexes it's only the nod
Factor receptors that are specific to
the Ryobi recognition there is a
co-receptor called simar that's already
duly required for nodulation and Rise
obial recognition all of the components
that are required for the generation of
the calcium oscillations and the
components that are required for the
perception of calcium oscillations are
duly required for micis and nodulation
and it's only really when we start to
get to the transcription factors where
we get the specificity uh in this uh
process where the the transcription
factors have specific functions in
nodulation and do not appear to be
predominantly involved in the micro isal
Association so the micro isal
Association has many parallels to to
nodulation the signaling processes
similar regard to nodulation the
perception of RIS obial bacteria the
plant is releas in signaling molecules
in this case stacton and they activate
the production of diffusible signaling
molecules coming from the micro isal
fungi we call MC factors very similar
parallels to how Ryobi bacteria are
perceived and those parallels go uh even
greater but if we look at how this these
processes are evolved well nodulation
emerged around 60 million years ago and
was restricted to a number of groups of
uh uh plants in the uroid arbuscular
mization is much more ancient it dates
back at least 450 million years ago
right to the root of the plant kingdom
so all plants this is what the blue is
indicating all plants at least at one
time had the capability to form a
vascular micro isal fungi and we know
that at least about 80% of higher plants
can form the oscular micro isal
symbiosis the plants that can't like
arabidopsis have lost that capability
but their ancestors their pre pre their
ancestors certainly had that capability
so importantly all the monocots that are
the targets for our Engineering Process
have the capability to form the oscular
micro isal Association and therefore we
would predict have the symbiosis
signaling pathway so therefore this
signaling pathway should in theory be in
serial crops and I don't actually have
to re-engineer all of that complexity of
of producing and decoding calcium
oscillations I simply have to follow the
evolutionary trajectory that's happened
in legumes that is essentially has
converted what is a monofunctional
siging pathway into a bifunctional
signaling pathway where we got one
signaling pathway involved in the
recognition of micro isal fungi and ryia
whereas in serials it's only the the
recognition of micro isal fungi where
this pathway is
functioning okay so um work from utap
Paskowski lab has shown that this
signaling pathway is indeed present in
serials and that's shown here with
genetics so on the top is a wild type
rice root that's been colonized by micro
or fungi and all the dark blue staining
is the fungus it gets very heavily The
Roots get very heavily colonized by the
fungus and if we make mutations in any
components of the common symbiosis
signaling pathway in rice then the
fungus can form the initial infection
structures on the surface but it's
unable to colonize the root so and
that's exactly the same phenotypes that
we see in legumes so we can recapitulate
the mutant phenotypes in cereals that we
see in legumes indicating that this
signaling pathway is certainly present
not only present but it's fulfilling
equivalent role in the recognition of
micro isal fungi but more than that we
can actually do uh the the parallels
between the signaling pathway go go more
significant than that because we can
take the genes from rice and trans
complement them in a meta into the metac
cargo mutants and on the bottom panel
here is a metac cargo mutant of ccam K
it's a calcium decoder that mutant
cannot normally form nodules but when we
transform it with Cam K from Rice then
complements not only for mization but it
also complements for nodulation
indicating that this signaling pathway
in the evolution of this siging pathway
there's nothing that's changed in the
core processes of the siging pathway
that has allowed the siging pathway to
be bifunctional the common simus
signaling pathway is there and
functional as functional in in cereals
as it is in legumes so I would argue
then that serials have the innate but as
yet unrecognized capability to perceive
even respond to rise obial bacteria and
Engineering that process is actually
because of these evolutionary history is
much simpler than perhaps we would have
thought a decade ago and therefore for
the engineering components of our grant
we're really focusing just on the
receptor complexes what we really need
to do is to get the receptor complexes
present and functional and then the
transcription Factor comp transcription
Factor complexes present and functional
to transfer the cap capability for this
this signaling pathway to be
bifunctional it doesn't tell us we're
going to make a nodule I accept there's
a long Arrow going to not to generating
the complexity of a nitrogen fixing
nodule but as I said at the moment I've
parked all that complexity at the moment
all we're trying to do is transfer
recognition of r obia as a first step
towards engineering nitrogen fixing
cials okay so if we really want to
understand this the signaling pathway in
serials in fact what we need to do is to
understand it's context as shown here
where the the this is a plant root in a
so in close proximity to micro isal
fungi and it's at this early stages
where the fungus is growing down towards
the root where this signaling pathway is
functioning or at least the first stages
where the signaling pathway is
functioning where diffusible signaling
molecules produced by the the micro isal
fungus are being recognized by the root
activating that symbiosis signaling and
then promoting the the processes that
are necessary to accommodate the micro
isal fungi
and the first one of the first steps
that we've taken in the gates funded
program is to understand what cials are
actually recognizing from micro isal
fungi to activate that that signaling
pathway so in the last few years it was
shown that micro isal fungi produce
lipooa acarid that are structurally very
similar to Ryobi nod factors so it's
very clear that the parallels going of
signaling and the signaling processes
are going continuously all the way from
the the signaling molecule through to
the the signaling Pathways and probably
all the way through to the colonization
of the root by the by the rise obial
bacteria so micro isal fundi producing
lipo keolo saccharides structurally very
similar to rise obial nod factors and it
was proposed that those were the mick
factors that were being recognized by
the plant but a second group also from
too was arguing an alternative
hypothesis which was that micro isal
fungi produce also much simpler Kito
oligosaccharides are completely
undecorated so no atal tail none of the
sulfation or acetalation that you see uh
in in some of the lcos and that it was
actually those short chain kyos
sacharidy molecules those were the
things that were activating the the the
the the symbiosis signaling pathway uh
implants so we took both of these
classes of signaling molecules and ask
what what are serials recognizing and
what is activating the syus at signaling
pathway so for that we generated rice
lines that had calcium reporters the
chameleon uh which allows us to measure
calcium and tested an array of different
signaling molecules different lcos both
at the top is the micro isal produced
lcos and then we're testing lcos from
broad spectrum risia that produce a
whole spectrum of different lco
signaling molecules and you can see that
we really do not see any responses to
the LC signaling molecules but we do see
responses to the to the the kit ola
saccharides and that's just shown here
just in graph form where we're looking
at the percentage of cells that can
activate calcium oscillations and you
can see really no response whatsoever to
the lcos but very good responses to the
kittool acarid I want to highlight here
that we're looking at very high
concentrations of these sigal molecules
10 to the5 molar that's very high
concentration so uh we re re chose those
concentrations simply so that if we got
a negative result we can be very very
confident that the plant is not
responding to those
lcos so if we compare on the top here
are two different species of legumes
medac cargo and Lotus that are showing
their responses to lcos and cosos and
the bottom are two non- legumes tomato
and rice and really the main differences
that we see between legumes and
non-legumes is a capability to respond
to lco signaling molecules so both
non-legumes and legumes can respond to
kyos acarid and activate the symbios a
signaling pathway but the ability to
perceive L seems to be an innovation
that's happened in in the leg
and probably strongly associated with
the capability to respond to rise obial
bacteria so I would argue that this
Innovation that's happened in legumes
it's clearly important for the cap for
the for the for the uh capability to
activate nitrogen fixing uh nodulation
and something that we really need to be
able to transfer into non- legumes uh to
allow recognition of roval bacteria so
in our project we have as I said two two
main focuses firstly um the engineering
the perception of the no factor which is
the uh transferring The receptors from
legumes into Cals uh to allow nod Factor
recognition and in the second half we're
using the gain of functions I showed you
we have gain of functions in our ccam K
there's also gain of functions in its
interacting partner Cyclops those gain
of functions can coordinate the whole
processes of nodulation in legumes so
using those gain of functions in
combination with the transcription
factors to activate reporters and I I
it's very modest my expectations at this
stage are very very modest can we
transfer no Factor activation of calcium
spiking into cials and can using the
gain of functions in ccam K in
combination with the transcription
factors activate reporters simply legume
reporters that are reporters nodulation
specific reporters simp it's a very
simple question can we recapitulate the
signaling capability in serials and it's
important I think at this stage that we
keep our expectations modest I don't
expect to be able to trans transer this
this process and get a nodule but I do
keep a relatively open mind about what
will happen if we transfer the
capability for serials to recognize rise
obial bacteria and importantly activate
the symbiosa signaling pathway that
coordinates the processes that are
necessary for a mutualistic symbiosis
with a with a microorganism it might be
that it will facilitate improved
colonization of seral roots by Rise
obial bacteria but I doubt we'll get
nodules now unfortunately Ely it's just
the nature of having to go and give
seminars I wish I could wait a couple of
years and give this seminar because it's
too early to say what what the results
are we're doing a lot of transformation
at the moment we've got an awful lot of
transgenic lines coming from barley we
have some promising preliminary results
but it's just too early to really say
definitively whether this approach has
been successful so I just wanted to
highlight some of the challenges that we
have in engine in this Engineering
Process this is really one of the most
complex engineering processes that there
is in in the uh in in the public sector
it's certainly comparable to
transferring C4 photosynthesis which is
another of the gates funded programs so
what are the challenges that we face in
in in in engineering something of this
level of complexity so so firstly I I
just want to reiterate we we're working
on the different complexes so one of the
complexes is The receptors and I just
want to highlight again that the
co-receptor simr which we know is
involved in transmitting the signal to
activation of the nuclear calcium
oscillations that co-receptor is already
present in Cals it's already there
because it's a micro isal specific
component presumably it's a co-receptor
with mfactor receptors which
unfortunately we currently still don't
know what they are but all we really
need to do is to get the no Factor
receptors in a stable form we presume
they'll form a complex with that
co-receptor and therefore they should
activate the nuclear calcium
oscillations and the other signaling
processes that we need to transfer not
with the gain of function we can just
use the gain of functions to autoa
activate the pathway serials already
have ccam K but we we can use the gain
of functions as a way to switch on the
pathway and the important thing is
whether we can get these different
transcription Factor complexes to
activate their appropriate uh promoters
in serial Roots okay so one of the
biggest challenges in transferring those
processes I would say is what promoters
you
use so do we just use 35s we can't use
we've got many genes to transfer we
can't really just keep using the same PR
again and again we need multiple
promoters to drive the different
proteins and exactly when we look at
this we've got quite a few proteins to
get stably present in the serial route
what level of expression of say ccam k
relative to the transcription factors
into necessary should we just put them
all on constitutive promoters and pray
it's a it's a a difficult thing and
especially when you don't know what the
out if if we get a negative result is
that because the promoters we're not got
the right level of expression or is it
because there's assumptions in our
process are that there's actually
missing components that we don't know
about in the legume system so it's very
important particularly when you're
setting up a large serial transformation
process that if you get a negative
result that that negative result can be
informative you've at least try we I
feel like we have to stack our cards as
much as possible to get a positive
outcome and we can overcome any
technological difficulties so uh I would
say this is just looking at the
expression of ccam K it's expression is
normally restricted to epidermal cells
but then when you get Ryobi colonization
and the arrow indicates the point where
Ryobi colonizing the root that you can
see that CM K is expressed in a region
of the root around that rise obial
colonization so how do we recapitulate
that because serials they've never seen
rise obia before they don't have a the
transcription factors that coordinate
this expression pattern when we're
moving if you want to just change root
development obviously you just use a
root promoter but here we're trans
transferring a new capability into
serials a capability they never had
before so there aren't any serial
promoters that will do that for us so
what promoters should we use and I think
that this is one of our biggest
challenges at this stage and you know we
can do something like this and this is a
whole panel of different promoters we've
hooked up to Gus and then expressed in
Roots and perhaps should I just use the
strongest expresses is that the right
thing to do I don't know what level of
expression should a transcription Factor
B to give us the relative to other
transcription factors so I find
personally find this sort of analysis
really uninformative it's how we started
this process it's like okay we just need
to make a lot of promoter gust reporters
put them into serial roots and the ones
that are blue are the ones we're going
to
use yeah it's not I find that very
dissatisfying and not particularly
informative we've done it but all we
have is some roots that are blue and
some roots that
aren't so um I would say this is
probably the most informative analysis
we can get on telling us which promoters
we use and here we've text with these
are mostly serial promoters we've used a
variety of different serial promoters
constitutive promoters root specific
promoters and then promoters that drive
serial promoters that drive say ccam k
or Cyclops so they should be already
symbiotically relevant promoters and
what we've done is we've driven the ccam
K protein but with these promoters and
transform those into the ccamk mutant
and ask how well we can complement a
medic cargo ccamk mutant using serial
promoters and uh right here is the
control because that's the medic cargo
Gene driven by its native promoter so
that's a level of complementation that
we can get just from the Native promoter
and you can see there's actually quite a
few serial promoters that do just as
well if not better than the native
promoter and those are promoter were
actually taken from cials which
transform them into a a legume and they
are activating the appropriate
expression of ccam K so I would say that
that's as good as we can get we now also
recapitulating this by trans using those
same promoters to test complementation
of the rice mutants for mization so at
least it tells us that those promoters
work in a in a symbiotically relevant
context and they're expressing these
genes and I think I think we we're
currently doing this for all of the
genes that we're engineering testing
finding out which promoters are best for
which genes at least in a legum context
which will then I think at least stack
our cards we can't guarantee we're going
to get exactly the same expression when
we go back into a seral but at least
we're starting with serial promoters and
if they work in a legum in a symbiotic
context I'm optimistic that they'll work
in a serial in a symbiotic context but I
think we're still shooting in the dark a
little bit and um I I don't think that
this is really I think we're still in a
somewhat imperfect
scenario so the in an from an
engineering perspective this is a very
familiar cycle from an engineering
perspective if you want to design a jet
engine you go through this process of
design build test and then use the test
to inform the next design and then build
and always improving and that's how we
get these perfect jet engines that can
FES across the Atlantic and this is a
sort of process in this sort of
essentially it's a synthetic biology
approach we have to move something new
from from legumes into cereals and and
create a new functionality in Cals that
cereals do not yet have so the on the
left hand end the design end essentially
if we in an engineering perspective you
move through this cycle many times
before you release a jet engine that you
sell to Boeing and I think we have to do
exactly the same I can't just go through
this cycle once and while hour I'm going
to have a nitrogen fixing cereal it's
not how it's going to work I need to
move through this process many times we
we might in this first round of
Transformations get nothing it might all
be negative results in which case we
have to scratch our heads and say okay
what does that tell us go back redesign
rebuild retest so the left hand side
which is of the design and build side
we've really tackled that very well we
got um sorry we've got Golden Gate
cloning which is a modular mode of
cloning you you synthesize the modules
you stit stitch them together to make
Gene modules those themselves became
modules that you can stitch together
into complex binary vectors and using
Golden Gate cloning we can produce
hundreds of constructs within a week
it's trivialized the production of
constructs so we can make many
constructs and this modularity is
actually very important because we're
testing different promoters with
different genes even what we're finding
when we do the same promoter testing if
we do the same with Terminators we find
some Terminators work and some
Terminators don't work for
complementation so you really need to
mix and match promoters open reading
frames and Terminators and then mix and
Max the genes that go into your binary
vectors in order to uh test as many
iterations and many possibilities as you
can in this engineering strategy so the
Golden Gate modularity has really
trivialized the production of the
constructs but getting those constructs
into serials is a huge headache so we
have maximized our throughput into
cereals and we putting 150 constructs
into cereals this year and we'll do the
same again next year another 150
constructs that's actually pretty good
in the public sector in a couple of
years getting 300 constructs into
cereals but when you look at what's been
done in synthetic biology in bacteria so
I take an example Chris voy just down
the road at MIT he's moved nitrogenase
from uh nitrogen fixing bacteria into
non- nitrogen fixing bacteria and to do
so he removed all the regulatory
elements he created his own regulatory
circuits and then he transformed that
into uh into non non nitrogen fixing
bacteria and looked for the capability
to trans to initiate nitrogen fixation
to optimize to get to a level where he's
getting back to the original levels of
nitrogen fixation that the starting the
starting bacteria had he had to test
880,000
constructs and so to do that he
roboticize the whole process he he made
liquid handling robots that make the
constructs liquid handling robots that
do the transformation liquid handeling
mod dos that do the measurements of the
nitrogenase there's no point when any
person is actually doing any of that the
person is the one the person is doing is
is feeding it into a computer and it's
designing all the constructs or
designing the principles that then the
computer designed the constructs 880,000
constructs and I'm doing something much
more complex than moving nitrogenate
from one bacteria to another I think
moving nitrogen fixation from legs to
Cals is pretty damn complex so I am not
tackling this at anything close to the
level of complexity that we currently
need to do and the ability to move
through this cycle I can do it at 150
constructs a year oh that's pretty
painful going so I think that one of the
big problems for us in dealing with this
complexity is that synthetic biology
plant synthetic biology is just not good
enough yet we don't yet have the tools
and one of the biggest bottlenecks for
us is transformation so one area that I
think can be useful for us and is an
area we're now putting into place I said
micro isal the micro isal symbiosis is
ubiquitous in the plank Kingdom and that
means even mosses and liver WS do the
micro isal symbiosis so this guy which
is a liver work mtia it's a organism
that's hloy very simple genetics you can
transform it just by grinding it up in a
t in a tube putting it in a liid with
agrobacterium you plate it out two weeks
later you have a fully functional liver
work so this is sort of as close as I
think we're ever going to get imp plants
to synthetic biology and the sort of
capability where we can start to
roboticize the processes and get
probably not 80,000 constructs but at
least in the thousands of constructs
that we can test in a reasonable amount
of time to actually test the complexity
problem is manania doesn't have Roots so
the likelihood that I'm ever going to
get get a nitrogen fixing nodule onto
manania is very low but it does have the
symbiosis signaling pathway so at least
a framework for engineering symbiosis
signaling I think manania is a very good
framework at least for this first stage
and so we're now in the process of
putting manania as a complement to the
work that we do in cials to really start
to make this throughput much greater and
to to tackle it I think at the level
that we really need to do but I I think
just just ending here on the on I just
want to reiterate that we're really just
tackling the first stages here and while
the this evolutionary trajectory and The
evolutionary trajectory makes the first
stages much simpler it actually probably
is also very clear that bacterial
infection is also reusing the same
processes that mical fungi use so I
think it's very clear that the whole
process of nitrogen fixation has assured
has piggybacked on the micro isal
symbiosis and that evolutionary
trajectory means that I think it's much
simpler for us to engineer nitrogen
fixation into cereals because we're not
having to really re-engineer anything
new in Cals we assert the existing
biology that's present there even so the
complexity of the process is such that I
think we need much better plant
synthetic biology tools and in some ways
I think I have to build the bridge in
plant synthetic biology before we can
truly tackle this and that's for me
that's the what the next round of gates
funding is going to be about not just
pushing into these other four areas but
also putting in place a synthetic
biology tools that allow us to really
tackle something of this
complexity okay I'd just like to
acknowledge the people involved in the
work this is an international program of
research my collaborators Jean Den
Aria's group in too were have been
working on the lcos and cosos and
helping us to understand what what
signaling molecules serials recognize um
the um Joyce Van who's at bti here in
here in Etha is helping us with some of
the
transformation um Tom brutnell is also
helping us with the Maze and the serial
and Ma and teria work and then both
myself and Yen star are the real
engineering Labs who are pushing the
production of the uh receptors and uh
the the downstream calcium decoding
complex and these are just the members
of my own group who are part of the ENA
program and I would also just like
before I finished just really
acknowledge the Gates Foundation because
nobody else has been willing to take the
risk it's a high risk High reward
project there's no way I'm going to be
delivering nitren fixing cereals anytime
soon Gates Foundation absolutely
recognizes a long-term program and are
willing to put the funds up in the
beginning uh and I think a lot of people
will say it's not possible it's too
complex you can't possibly do it and my
answer is if you don't start now you
certainly will never achieve it if you
start now maybe there's a chance of
achieving it so I I really acknowledge
the Gates Foundation for taking that
risk thank you
yes I can repeat the question yes so the
question is can you do it a different
way are simpler ways like can for
instance put a nitrogen fixing plastic
create a nitrogen fixing plaster and the
obvious thing is to move nitrogenase
from bacteria into a plased uh where
it's functioning already as a provide
nit fixation in in a plant cell and
there is actually a second Gates fund
program that's run by L gubio in Madrid
doing exactly that so they're trying to
move nitrogenate actually into the
mitochondria the reason they're doing
the mitochondria is it's a low oxygen
environment already because of
respiration means that oxygen is being
utilized um it's also has a lot of
reductive power is very important for
nitrogen B and in the first instance of
just trying to get that into the the
yeast mitochondria as a stepping stone
into
plants that there I would say there's a
perception that that's simpler I would
argue with that perception that that's
simpler nitrogenases a hugely complex
enzyme probably the most complex enzyme
on the planet it has these unique
co-actors I Sul centers and co-actors
that are unique to nitrogen so you're
not just got to get the components of
nitrogenase there but you also need to
get those co-actors produced as well so
it's not straightforward just to move
nitrogen over and I I argue that I have
the Prototype I know it works leing are
beautiful they fix all their nitrogen
themselves not only but many different
species of plants that this capability
and works beautifully completely
independent mat fertilizes so I would
argue that I have the advantage I have
the Prototype and it's a matter I know
it works and I know if I transfer that
to serials it works it transferring
nitrogen it's a viable approach but I
wouldn't say it's simpler or less highis
it's just as much
RIS but I think it's a legitimate the
nitrogen problem is a huge problem and I
think it's totally legitimate multiple
multiple Avenues to try to
solve yes so so that's a big that's very
important question and um sorry I I
repeat the question so um the question
is on specificity so we have a b
functional signaling pathway yet
specific output and I actually showed
you that the gain of function in cam K
alone can activate a modle And yet when
Miz come along they activate the same
protein with ulations and you don't get
clearly specificity is there in the
leing context that the leing must know
it's recognizing not Factor even though
it's activating the signal so um we I
say we've been working on specificity
for years and I really thought it was
encoded in the structure of the
oscillations because we saw initially
with the micro isal fungi we saw what
looked like different calcium
oscillations but actually now when we're
working with the signaling molecules and
cells there exactly the same the
structure of the oscillations is
identical between non factor signals and
the signals coming from micis fun um
even so we do see different gene
expression patterns to n factor and
micro bungi that are dependent on
components of the symbiotic signaling
paway so it's clear that it's not the
specificity is not because there's other
signaling molecules being produced by
the micro organs that my argument at the
moment it's still that the signals
themselves are being recognized and the
specificities in the recognition of
those signals so I would say there's
probably some parallel signaling just go
back to the
pathway okay I would say that it's
there's probably not much more than this
but there might very well be parallel
signaling if you notice the grass
proteins which are nsp1 and nsp2 and r
one those are grass proteins that we
know are important for this we actually
don't know how they're activated and
possibly one possibility is that there's
parallel sign go sectors straight to
those grass proteins and the combination
of the activation of those proteins in
combination with sinus is Sign Factory
that means that you only get ulation in
one context or infection but
mechanistics yes yes so that's a very
legitimate question so the question is
can we can we just get R living theing
molecules that micro and Fung producing
that is actually part of our strategy we
have that in that's one of the main
reasons for working out exactly what
cials are recognizing because and the
fact that the C2 recognizing just a
simpler version of the no Factor I'm a
little wary to say it's just kit saiz
it's clear that K sa will activate
signal inact way but we still have to
use quite high concentrations of those
molecules to get a response much higher
concentrations that used there and we're
currently testing we have some evidence
that it might be de at K sa not
decorated with a asile tail but perhaps
decorated with sulfation or carbonation
or whatever some of the other
decorations that you see
on so we have evidence it might be a
decorated K sa opponent tested now so
that's very much part of the reason for
understanding exactly what it is that
Cals recognized for micro Rizal fungi
because a much simpler strategy would be
to ENT near only just to make a lot of
that signal and therefore presumably be
able to colonize the
do you have
any actually I have two sort of related
questions if you had a guess at a
timeline as to how long you think this
might take you I'd be curious to know
and the second question is do you
envision that you would have to co-
inoculate with a rodium species or do
you think the engineered uh cereals
could make use of the natural Rovia in
the soil yeah both both very good
questions I I I think everybody heard
those questions right repe um so the
first question i' say I hate that first
question and I get it all the time how
long is when are we going to get n fix
and cereal and that is an incredibly
difficult question to answer because
we're really moving into the Unown we
don't quite know how much of the
complexity that's present in L we need
to transfer into Cals and exactly
whether we can do that so it's very
difficult to judge but but my point for
highlighting in the beginning I think
there's
opportunities in um in the along the
process that perhaps we can deliver
useful levels of fixed nitrogen that
could be hugely beneficial to smallhold
Farmers well before we're kind of
replacing fertilizers here in the
develop world so I'm optimistic that we
can be there at least within my career I
hope it's not M I'm waiting for many
future generations to solve this problem
but I'm optimistic that we can at least
be delivering some level of useful fixed
night within the next 20 years whether
that's in the context of having a fully
functional P nodule on a Serial rout I
think that that's optimistic to say we
can do that in 20 years but I also would
say technolog is moving very quickly and
particularly in synthetic biology
synthetic biolog tools are coming into
place that I think make it much more
feasible so I think we have to be
reasonably open mind how long this is
really going to take and the second
question is would we have to go in I
guess within a nocular or can we just
get them to use the native risod I would
be very hard to imagine how we could
engineer it for the native R over
present of a serial at least at this
stage I think we'd have to know what the
sing molecules are produced by the ryia
and probably in the first instance it
would probably require theum I would say
because at least then you've got control
both on the plant side and the bacterial
side that you know the bacteria are
producing the signal that you've
engineered the plant to
perceive I I I don't think problem so
the question is that do
this a little bit so I just hold it um
the question is do we have is there
something intrinsic to syrial that stops
them from being able to be invol in that
process and why do Cal not have this
capability I I think it's not that I
mean if you look at the evolution Cals
are just diverged well before modulation
emerged I think that's the simplest
reason to say why seral don't have the
capability they weren't didn't evolve
early enough um and I think the the we
in agriculture we've created a situation
where plant productivity is highly
dependent
on and is an annual system where we
strip everything all the plant material
off the soil and then come back the next
year and plant new seeds and expect to
get high
productivity there's there's no system
natural systems that are like that so
we've created a system that's hugely
dependent on on always adding back the
nutrients a natural system has a much
more natural nutrient cyes so in many
many environments fixing nitrogen is not
the v and end there not the competitive
Advantage so in fact when you look at
Lees where they succeed are tend to be
the places where nitrogen is limited so
chalk grasslands uh acidic soils
tropical soils that are very low
nutrients so I think I would say that in
the natural world nitrogen in some
context is is the major factor but in
many contexts it's not so so you don't
necessarily have to solve that problem
and there are and there across the pl
Kingdom many different examples where
different plants have found different
ways of solving this problem and I think
for cereals probably in a natural
context it's not to be all an end for a
competitive Advantage cereals tend to
grow in areas where nitrogen is not that
Li so I I would say it's not that
there's something intrinsic to seral of
sof being able to modulate just that it
just didn't happen in their lifestyle
but we've created a false environment
where nitrogen is the key factor
to I think if I was going to work on
anything if I had the choice i' work on
caronia because it's probably the most
recently
evolved example of neration and it's
also probably the most simple it's crack
entry infection the bacteria get in by
infection threads they don't get
released into they stay in infection
threads they fix nitrogen inside the
infection threads so it's as as far as I
can it's also very clearly a modified
Lal root it's not a complex molecule so
I would say if I was going to try to
recate anything in ponia but genetic
bsection modulation piston a tropical
tree that takes years to it's just not
realistic so I think I have to work with
a system by which I can genetically
prect this process and that is the model
Ling there is yet to be an aiz species
that's been developed where you can by
although it is not an
area trying to develop a model species
but I think I'm too far away I can't
wait for that to start the enging
process I think we can we've got enough
information right now and it's clear at
least for the signaling pathway it's the
same signaling pathway I think we can
pretty well say probably similar things
that happen intive species Happ allow do
function so that's a very good question
and I would say that that that so the
question is how is there is there a
yield penalty when you get nitr fixing
seral and that is a really easy answer
for small holder Farmers they're right
at the bottom of that curtain if you
look at a field of Base in Africa it's
yellow most of the time so their
photosynthetic capacity is being limited
by the availability of nutrients so I
think that there they so far down on the
levels of nitrogen that are available
that there's no way
even if you're having to fix your own
nitrogen you are pushing productivity up
significantly because you're starting
from such a low L that argument becomes
important when you're starting to can we
totally replace nitrogen fertilizers
with biological nit fixation and in that
regard yes I'm I'm sure there is a yield
penalty but you have to think about both
the environmental sustainability and the
economic sustainability of the current
model where we're using vast amount of
fertilizers and the average farmer is
spending certainly in the UK about 40%
weak production costs are the the
purchase and application of nitr
fertilizers so I would argue you take a
40% yield penalty and it's still
economically viable and it's a lot more
sustainable so yes there is a yield
penalty there will I suspect there will
be a Yi penalty but you're probably not
going to get that yield penalty until
you get upwards of 70 80 kg of fixed
nitrogen rather than the sort of more
modest 25 50 kg that that would be my
arum certainly in a situation where you
find
first oh it's wonderful there's three L
receptor oh sorry two Lys receptores all
of back here only two yes there's
there's a few other Lys proteins that
have just but
not so we're in the process of getting
generating mutant there's
two I'm guessing they're
well it took us a while to actually get
unfortunately MTI poly which is the
model that's being developed is a non
mized
species some some Trend everybody
developed a model plant seems to manag
to find
one one of the few 20% plants that don't
mic
sy so um the we had to develop a new
micro mean model which we've chosen that
hcia which is a close relative for micro
and then we have to set up all the
transformation Tools in that so we now
transformation working so we're now
getting chis working that in order to
them to start but the S pathway is all
there we have it all synthesized we're
in the process of testing transation
with cargo I'm guessing it's going to be
the same all the other we already know
that the sway coming from this
Trail at
least so let's continue discussion over
refresh and
thanks this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu