good afternoon um my name is Laura
mcdermit I'm working with Kathy Heiden
Reich and Marvin pritz and Dr Harold
vanesse on this um management uh soil
management and Berry crops Grant and I'm
happy to have you here uh I hope that
there'll be a few other folks joining us
here as we get going um I do want to I
think probably most of you have already
um taken the time to fill out the S
demographics questionnaire and the
educator preest which is in the file box
on the lower uh right hand corner of
your screen but if this is your first
time visiting us for one of the webinars
and you have not done it um please take
a few moments either uh right now or at
the end of this um presentation to fill
that out and send that to Kathy
heidenrich um it's very important for
the grant and while we're on that topic
I might um also remind folks that uh we
are in the Final Phase the last three
webinars um today then March 2nd and
then the final one will be on March 9th
um and at that time we're going to have
a post test of um all the Educators
hopefully we're going to have a really
good showing for that final um webinar
because that's a very important
consideration and how effective the
webinars
are um for relaying uh educational
information that uh extension folks can
use out in the field with
Growers um we also want to remind
those of you who have been in attendance
for a number of these webinars that we
are hopeful that you'll take the
opportunity to make the next step so
using all of the materials that will be
available to you as um participants in
this first portion of the grant um we'd
like to have you take those educational
materials out into the field and host
some grower um grower workshops uh
grower field days whatever and then kind
of report back to us and Kathy has some
formats and if you have any questions
you can contact her or her or myself
about that but we'd love you to start to
get your head around that and plan for
something this uh this growing
season all right um before we get going
also I'd like to make sure folks know a
little bit about the webinar I think
most of you have done this but you can
type into the chat box a long narrow box
at the bottom in the center that that's
where you enter your comments and
questions and I will try to keep track
of them uh please go ahead and introduce
yourself if you haven't done that yet
even though you may feel like you do it
every single time it's helpful for the
presenter to kind of get to know where
everyone's from um Additionally the web
links which is in the lower left corner
uh you can click on that and then you
can actually browse to that uh right now
or at the end we're going to go back to
the this kind of format at the very end
um uh so they'll be there and they'll
also be accessible as the recorded
webinar all right um today with this is
the 10th in a series of 12 um Berry crop
nutrition and soil man Management
training
webinars and um our speaker today is Dr
Harold vaness who's the professor and
chair of the Department of crop and soil
Sciences at Cornell University um um and
I will now switch into that presentation
mode um Dr Vanessa's current research
and extension interests are in Precision
management of nitrogen soil health and
space and time
statistics um he teaches an
undergraduate course in soil management
for sustainability and a graduate course
in that space and time
statistics um he has off authored over
100 refereed Publications and four books
and advised 45 graduate students
and I'm exhausted for him so I'm really
glad that he's here um hey Harold hello
can you hear
me sounds
good okay well thank you Laura and uh
it's a pleasure to be uh joining this
group again um I looked at my my
calendar and it was uh almost exactly
four months ago when I did the uh the
first webinar um uh one of the early
ones on U on basic so information and
and soal management principles and uh
since then um we've discussed uh as a
group at least you know nutrient
management and seral Health Management
and uh doing that mostly from a uh
production perspective today we're going
to be talking more about uh some of the
environmental impacts and um and how uh
we can reduce that um let's see I'm
having a little bit of a problem there
we go um going to the next slide okay um
the the outline for today and by the way
I just put my picture uh up there it's a
slightly different picture than the
other one uh just to make it a little
bit more uh more personal for you uh but
we'll uh we'll start today with a
discussion of uh environmental loss
processes then uh erosion and runoff
prevention then we'll talk about
managing phosphorus and then managing
nitrogen do a summary and then we'll go
into the question and and answer session
and I I try to organize uh the my slides
and and my presentation in a way I think
that will will allow you to uh take some
Concepts that you can use with your
stakeholders that will help you I think
in in your educational pro
programs um so we'll we'll start at
looking at environmental losses um the
primary ones that we might be concerned
about with uh with berry production is
uh is sediment nitrogen phosphorus and
pesticides and I should say say up front
that that most uh most of the the berry
production is done in a way that that is
is uh relatively sustainable has
relatively little environmental impact
say compared to corn production uh which
is more large scale uh it's an annual
crop uh it's a lot of these soils are
being tilled on an annual basis and so
when we compare that to to most Berry
crops uh we're dealing with perennials
and um and not as much tillet and and
typically not as much uh nutrient inputs
either so um so often the environmental
impact may be may be smaller yet we we
we do need to be concerned about that
and we need to take that
serious so in the picture here you see
the um uh basically the the basic
hydrologic cycle and and the main point
is that these environmental losses uh
occur when we have u a lot of water in
the system that water of course comes
more mostly As precipitation some cases
a little bit as as uh as irrigation but
but really it's the it's the uh extreme
precipitation events when we get you
know an inch two or even more we uh
that's when we tend to have uh the the
problems and um so an important concept
to consider is is what happens at the
precipitation when it reaches the land
surface and it can basically go in two
directions it can either infiltrate or
uh the water that does not infiltrate
then runs off and creates all kinds of
problems because it will take with it
these uh contaminants like sediment
nitrogen and phosphorus and if it takes
sediment then we refer to it that as as
erosion um and uh that may readily of
course reach uh streams or other water
bodies like lakes and naries and uh that
is uh in general very
undesirable but uh if we're lucky that
the water infiltrates and then it's
being held in the in the soil I like to
refer to the soil as a sponge and uh and
the soil holds on to that water and then
makes that available to the plants um
through evapo transpiration if there's
excess water in the soil then it will
percolate further down either to deeper
groundw or maybe shallow ground water
that might eventually reach a stream so
those are are are the processes and so
if chemicals go with the percolating
water then we refer to that as as
leeching so if we think about these lost
Pathways the um uh the ones that we're
concerned about are are runoff with
mostly with phosphorus to a lesser
extent with nitrogen and then maybe with
pesticides uh for uh erosion which means
that runoff that takes with it all the
sentiments and the siment in turn may
have a lot of phosphorus with it or some
nitrogen and pesticides um so all of
these contaminants are concerned when we
have
erosion erosion is a really bad thing um
when we have leeching we're concerned uh
mostly with nitrates and pesticides
phosphorus uh basically doesn't leech
except in some very unusual
circumstances and then we finally we
have a concern about gaseous losses um
and that is typically not directly
driven by by water but indirectly
especially when it comes to uh nitrous o
oide which is generated when the soil
becomes anerobic and so when it's
saturated there's no air in the soil and
then the nitrogen is
transformed uh from say nitrate to
nitrous oxide and of course uh this is a
big concern because it's a serious
greenhouse gas it's 300 times more
potent than um than carbon
dioxide um and we may have some gaseous
losses of pesticides which is really um
unrelated to to water typically that has
to to do with the properties of the
pesticide
itself and uh I'm not going to discuss P
pesticides in detail uh today it's a
little bit beyond the scope of uh of
what we wanted to talk about so we're
going to focus on sediment nitrogen and
phosphorus so the environmental loss
potential in in general is is affected
by a number of factors so one obviously
the weather we discussed that if you
have a lot of intensive uh rainfall you
have higher potential for runoff and
erosion and excess water also generates
leeching secondarily we have these
inherent Cil properties like texture and
organic matter which also affect you
know basically where the water goes and
what it takes with it and then we we'll
discuss that in a little bit more detail
thirdly soil health and we've talked
about that Bob shinel Beck mentioned uh
that in the previous webinars so if we
build up our soil and we make it healthy
with say good aggregation then we can
reduce the environmental loss potential
significantly and then um finally
perhaps the what we might call the more
real-time soil management practices uh
such as whether we cultivate the soil uh
which may expose it to the elements
whether we have soil cover like mulch uh
whether we traffic the soil causing
compaction and those kind of things and
then of course last and not least is um
is you know how much fertilizer we apply
either or organic or inorganic
fertilizer and where we where we place
it uh because of in principle the more
fertilizer or other organic uh um
materials that we put out there the
higher the potential that we have losses
so we'll we'll come back to these
individually um but first let's let's
let's discuss you know the the basic
inherent properties of soils and how
that affects potential environmental
impacts uh you know texture or or the
distribution of particle sizes in terms
of sand silt and Clay is uh is probably
the most fundamental property and you
know we're all familiar uh with the the
textural
triangle um and it it provides the basis
for a lot of these environmental loss
considerations I like to talk to my
students or to stakeholders uh as as the
the soil particles and the the texture
of the soil sort of defining what we
might call the house uh the basic
structure of of the soil and I like to
use the analogy of a of of a house in
that you know the uh you have the
structure of the house which is the the
walls and the the roof and the basement
and all that and that's the most visible
part of the of a house and and in
particles for the soil that's what you
see uh the most interesting part however
is what's what happens in the
spaces um between the soil particles or
with the house analogy what happens in
the rooms because that's where uh all
the processes take place that's where uh
the organisms are that's where the life
is and that's where the interesting
things happen so in soils there's
there's bacteria fungi all kinds of
organisms that live in the pores and
that's also where all the important
processes of water and air movement
occur so I'd like to have people farmers
and students to to think in soil in
terms of soil not just in terms of the
particles but have them think in terms
of the spaces between the particles
so um when we think about a sandy soil
then most of those pores are relatively
large um although in general terms we're
still talking about less than 2
millimeters in in most cases um but by
by S standards those are very large uh
pores and those pores will lose their
water very quickly because the capillary
force that we see in large pores is is
relatively weak conversely when we talk
about clay soils
we mostly have small pores the capillary
force is really really strong and they
retain the water very
tightly okay uh but if we have a clay
soil that actually has good aggregation
then uh we may have a few larger pores
that are are between the Aggregates so
then we maybe have both small and large
pores so this is an example of of of an
aggregate that uh has the the range of
of pores so it has the the larger pores
um and those facilitate infiltration and
drainage eras and rooting because they
lose the water very quickly because of
the weak capillary Force the small pores
um they retain the water very well and
so they facilitate both water and and
nutrient retention so when we're
concerned for example about leeching we
like to see these nutrients being
retained in in the
soil so I have a question for you here
um actually two questions first one is
uh which soil has a higher leeching
potential a sand a silt or a clay and
the second question is which soil has a
higher runoff and denitrification
potential the gaseous losses of nitrogen
the sand the silt or the
clay and I'm sure you all got this
question uh just right um it's the of
course the sand that has the highest
leeching potential because it's mostly
large pores doesn't retain the water in
the nutrients very well so they easily
wash out with the percolating water and
for two uh it's of course the clay that
has a higher runoff potential mostly
small pores so not very good
infiltration capacity and uh because it
is mostly small pores the irration can
often become a problem when you get a
lot of water and so you have higher
denitrification so I I'm sure you all
got those answers correct so when we go
back to our textural triangle um again
so we're talking about the more Sandy
soils like a sand the lomy sand Sandy
LOM lot of large pores high leeching
potential uh when we have higher clay
contents we tend to have higher runoff
and denitrification
potential now let's look at thinks a
little bit more in in a landscape uh
perspective and uh we often use the term
hydrologically sensitive areas for for
uh parts of the landscape that have a
high potential for pollutant losses and
uh in some cases we're concerned about
runoff uh surface losses in other cases
it's leeching and subsurface recharge
losses um so when we uh where where do
we in the landscape have high runoff
losses in flood planes and this is kind
of an interesting uh scenario because
most flood planes actually uh tend to
have relatively coarse textured soils
like gravels or kind of Sandy soils um
that uh that you might say well they
have high infiltration capacity but
because they are located near stream uh
basically if you get uh heavy rains you
get flooding then uh basically
everything goes uh so you have not a lot
of nutrients uh on the soil or the soil
is very poorly protect ected then a lot
of that gets lost and in the Northeast
we certainly experienced that this year
with h with a hurricane and and uh and a
followup in parts of the Northeast with
the with some other heavy uh rainfall
events so similarly areas that are
adjacent to flowing or standing water uh
bodies are hydrologically sensitive
primarily because they tend to be wetter
areas in the landscape and because they
are close to these water bodies so
there's very little buffer very little
opportunity to filter out some of these
these contaminants areas with low
infiltration capacity are concerned
maybe because the soil has become
compacted or sometimes it's even when
it's adjacent to uh say a road or um or
or or some other you know compacted area
where the runoff that comes off that
area then goes onto a field and may uh
reduce runoff and erosion on the field
and then areas generally that are
saturated that are already wet have a
high runoff potential as
well okay so let's then think about uh
about the leeching and subservice
recharge areas um the ones that we're
mostly concerned about are are areas
that are close to either Wells or
Springs these are are typically areas
that have very permeable soils and when
you're very close to these water sources
that people use for drinking water we
need to be extra careful and so that's
uh those those are sensitive areas and
in general areas with very permeable
soils are also of concern so we have to
think a little bit in terms of uh of the
of the location that uh that a field or
Farm might have in the
landscape and so you know going back to
my earlier presentation from a few
months ago uh we talked about soil
survey reports and and how useful that
information is whether you're using the
the the paper copies uh with the
traditional Maps or whether you go to
the uh online version the so-called web
seral survey which is just a fantastic
Tool uh it provides you with information
on basic s properties on suitability for
use and uh in this case also the
environmental loss potential so the S
survey can be a very good sort of first
source of information to uh to start
thinking about these problems and how to
address
them okay so let's um let's look at at
one of the concerns that we have and
that's that's erosion and there's two
aspects of erosion that are undesirable
one it removes the good soil it it
removes the soil right from the surface
um it uh it's typically uh the soil
that's the highest in organic matter and
that's the most
desirable and um and what it leaves
behind typically is the uh kind of the
grally material the coarse fragments
that don't get washed away as easily
by the runoff water so uh with many
years of erosion we basically lose our
our best soil the other aspect of course
is that uh this soil ends up somewhere
else as as sediment and this pollutes
Water Resources with it streams or
eventually going into lakes or estuaries
or or rivers and uh this uh this covers
uh aquatic habitat um it makes it less
suitable for uh drinking water or even
navigation so uh both of these aspects
of course are highly undesirable and
erosion really remains uh a large
problem uh here in the in the United
States we we still have a lot of
concerns about it so there's a number of
factors that that affect that soil type
and slope so uh typically soils that
have a high runoff potential also have
higher erosion potential steeper slopes
of course are of Greater
concern uh so Health can be a big factor
as well if we if we basically build the
soil up with a good aggregation uh good
plant rooting that you know pumps the
water out very well uh we are going to
be reducing the erosion potential and
then also surface management you know
whether we keep the soil covered or
whether it's exposed using pets or you
know herbici sites or something like
that that can greatly in influence the
erosion potential
so here's a quick illustration of that
that uh that shows these uh these four
graphs in different stages of the
development of of erosion so uh on the
the top left uh we see a raindrop uh and
a raindrop actually has a uh has a
certain amount of energy basically from
its mass and its
velocity uh it then reaches the land
surface and that is basically uh what
initially you know creates the concern
when the soil is dry it is relatively
hard and initially uh resilient and can
absorb the energy over that that
raindrop but as the soil starts to wet
up it becomes soft and it becomes
weaker um and the Raindrop uh energy is
cannot be absorbed quite as well to the
point where that surface layer becomes
very soft and uh very susceptible to the
energy of the raindrop up which may
cause then the Aggregates or the soil
itself to be uh smashed and uh and
dispersed and you see that here in the
in the the picture you see the very soft
soil and you can actually see the impact
of the addition the the individual
raindrops that basically destroy the
soil you start to see water accumulating
at the surface and if this is on even a
even a modest slope you start to
initiate runoff and then erosion
um now one thing we could do is um is of
course we could try to cover that soil
um with say mulch or you know some other
type of of uh uh say organic compound
maybe even uh even some compost and uh
and that uh that material that surface
cover can
then absorb the energy of the raindrops
so instead of it falling directly onto
the soil it's being absorbed by say The
Mulch and this greatly greatly reduces
the erosion potential so one of the best
things we can do to reduce erosion is to
uh have the soil
covered and that's depicted here in this
you know rather famous graph that shows
the relative erosion or soil loss from 0
to
100% And the uh percentage service
residue so if we have bare soil we have
uh losses at
100% um but we see down a fairly rapid
decrease in the erosion losses uh with
even with modest um modest amounts of
service residue so if we have about 30%
service residue we reduce the erosion
losses by about 60% from 100 to 40 and
then if we increase the amount of
service residue in the end we end up
with relatively low erosion losses so
one of the best things we can do uh in
terms of reducing erosion losses is to
cover the soil and the good thing is
this also has a lot of benefits in terms
of uh building uh healthy soils to
reduce the effects of you know extreme
water and temperature conditions at the
surface to promote biological activities
so to some extent uh it is a no-brainer
to put U mulch or other materials on the
surface so uh in terms of erosion and
runoff then what are sort of the main
strategies you know in
summary avoid fields that are prone to
flooding or have high runoff potential
if at all
possible keep the soil covered with
mulch or residue or even compost build
and maintain soal Health especially
aggregation to increase infiltration
capacity and reduce the runoff potential
and then uh use grass Alleyways
preferably along the Contour so there's
some pictures here this this shows of
course the the surface mulch this is
also soil that has received uh compost
and so it's in really good shape kind of
like the soil that you see here uh this
is a picture that shows um these
Alleyways that in the winter time will
have a a rye C crop and this can then be
mowed onto the rows this in this case we
have grapes here uh in South Africa but
we can use that then as a mulch to go
into the into the rose uh of course you
can bring in external sources of mulch
as well and then the the bottom picture
shows you a a grass Alleyway especially
if it's along the Contour that's good
because it will infiltrate water quite
well it will filter out any sediment
that might come from the rows if they
are unprotected so those are uh some
some good management approaches that are
really not difficult to implement and in
fact are being implemented by most Berry
Growers
okay so let's um continue on and now
talk about
nutrients in the early seminar we
discussed the the nine what we call
macro elements the elements that plants
need in relatively large uh quantities
so the the the carbon oxygen and
hydrogen are uh are available plentiful
uh in the natural world and uh it's
primarily the nitrogen and the
phosphorus that are the ones that are
are applied in large quantities but are
also of environmental concerns uh so
that's what we'll be focusing
on so this uh this pictograph shows uh
the difference in loss Pathways between
nitrogen here on the top versus
phosphorus on on the bottom and although
they are both nutrients they behave very
differently in the soil and they have
very different impacts so we'll we'll
discuss those in some more detail
so nitrogen can be in the soil in in
both organic or inorganic form as
nitrate and
ammonium um most of the nitrogen we hope
will be taken up by the crop I mean
that's that's our objective and that's
uh that promotes good
growth um it may run off or erode but
typically with nitrogen those are that's
a relatively insignificant loss pathway
it's mostly the leeching and the
volatilization and denitrification that
are the primary loss
Pathways and so those are the ones that
we are are concerned about they are both
uh initiated by very wet soil conditions
now phosphorus on the other hand can uh
be in the soil also in organic and
mineral form again the uh desired
pathway is crop
uptake U leeching uh is only a problem
in some very rare cases where there's
just excessive amounts hugely excessive
amounts of phosphorus in the soil uh
where we're dealing with very sandy soil
with shallow water tables but in most
cases it's really the runoff and the
erosion that's a primary concern with
phosphorus so let's look at each of
these in a little bit more detail
starting with phosphorus so here's our
pictograph again um so it's primarily
the runoff and the erosion that's of of
concern here's a picture uh from a lake
in Canada with with a barrier in between
that shows uh the area that received
phosphorus inputs and then the area that
did not um most of the freshwater lakes
in the in the in North America are
phosphorus limited and it actually takes
relatively little phosphorus to induce
utr fication or algae growth or even
acatic vegetation and uh this is to some
extent the natural process but it gets
accelerated by phosphorus that comes
from from farms again Berry Farms are
probably not a huge contributor but uh
but they could contribute um with poor
management
practices well one thing we need to keep
in mind because erosion and runoff are
the primary uh processes for phosphorous
losses then you know from that of course
it's a logical conclusion to say
practices that reduce runoff and erosion
also reduce phospherous losses and so
you know having uh surface mulch uh
improving infiltration capacity through
good soil Health Management Etc these
are all practices that also reduce
phosphorus
losses but there's another dimension to
that and that's basically the the the
the accumulation of phosphorus in in the
soil if we end up with lots and lots of
phosphorus in the soil then we increase
the loss potential and that's uh an
additional concern so if we just think
about uh phosphorus levels in terms of a
a seral test level which we of course
measure on a regular basis uh we know
that if the seral test levels are are
very low that we have uh reductions in
yield and uh that there is sort of a
point where you say well um uh there's
sufficient phosphorus in the soil for
good Crop Production we have sort of an
Optimum range but then if we really get
too much phosph in the soil then um then
we have excess and this excess
phosphorus is much more susceptible to
losses through runoff and
erosion um and that's that's a concern
so the above graph is basically kind of
a hypothetical uh case on the bottom
here I'm showing you some some real data
of relative yield this is for corn and
alphalpha and grass but it shows you
that uh in this case for uh for a Morgan
extractable p that if you're sort of in
this range of four to six uh that's sort
of where the cut off is between going
from below Optimum to to Optimum and so
you don't have any yield increase beyond
that uh but in at some point in time
you're starting to get into excessive
levels and even though um this the the
response to soal P levels is often quite
somewhat variable and low Precision uh
there is really strong agreement that
these levels U that there is a certain
level where you really have an an
Optimum amount of phosphorus in the soil
not deficient and and not
excessive and so I just wanted to show
you as a comparison because many of you
may be using different extractants you
know here in the Northeast uh we mostly
use um um modified Morgan or which is
just like Morgan certainly in terms of
phosphorus uh some of you may be using
Olen or Bray or or mic one or mic 3 and
um and this here shows the different
ranges because the extractants uh are
are slightly different and they uh end
end up with extracting a little bit more
a little bit less phosphorus um
depending on the method and uh so they
each have their ranges in terms of low
Optimum high and very high and it's
under the very high where we get to be
concerned about excessive phosphorus
level losses and so we would like to be
able to to prevent that from happening
we don't want to have too much
phosphorus in the soil um that will
possibly cause environmental
concerns uh now in most cases if uh if a
farmer uh regularly soil tests and um
and is very careful about how much they
apply uh you don't really see any
problems with that the cases where you
do see that uh occurring is typically
with a lot of organic inputs so we see
that with manure especially say on a
dairy farm that has a lot of excess
nutrients then uh that builds up the
phosphorus or we also see it sometimes
uh with uh uh you know repeated compost
applications sometimes with with even
with Organic Farms um because uh both
manure and compost are not as well
balanced in terms of nitrogen and
phosphorus uh that is that uh you
typically uh apply too much phosphorus
for what the crop needs if you apply the
right amount of nitrogen so you do this
year after year and then you start to
build up your phosphorus levels so these
are some some real uh Cal samples of um
cases where there's been an increasing
amount of organic uh phosphorus applied
and uh these are then for mic or for
margar the um the F the soal test levels
and you can see that they really build
up and they are really highly excessive
which is really what we would like to
like to prevent from happening so uh if
you have a situation like that when you
have too much phosphorus in the soil
then you need to um to make sure that
you uh that you change the the diet you
might say of of the soil where you add
your nitrogen in in a different way
perhaps you can do that by adding say
Clover um residues or or Alfalfa or or a
um if you're not an organic grower then
perhaps you can simply apply some
nitrogen fertilizer and a smaller amount
of compost so that uh that you can start
reducing those phosphorus levels in in
the
soil so and we account for that in the
cornal Cal Health test in in terms of
the scoring curve that we use for
phosphorus analysis and uh that was
discussed in in the previous webinars by
Bob schindelbeck
so the scoring curve basically the idea
is that we uh we interpret an actually
measured value of a soal health
indicator in this case phosphorus and uh
we interpret that in on a scale from
basically 0 to 100 so if we have very
low phosphorus levels then uh we give it
a very low
score and uh as the phosphorous level
increased then we increase the score as
well so and this is then where we around
four to six where we reach the optimum
level but then we start to downcore it
basically uh when we start to reach
excessive levels of phosphorus so uh it
is important that uh that you try to
keep your phosphorus level sort of in
this Optimum range so sort of between
about four or five and about 20 and that
you don't want to go into excessive
levels so to summarize uh the phosphorus
management what are the main strategies
well the first four that we see here are
the same as we used for runoff and
erosion prevention okay uh because if
you don't get any runoff then you don't
have any any problems with losses so the
same one avoid High flooding locations
keep the soil covered maintain soil
health and maintain grass Alleyways but
now we have this fifth consideration is
monitor the soil phosphorus levels and
try to avoid excessive
phosphorus so these five uh management
strategies uh are very effective in
reducing P
losses Okay so we've talked about
erosion we've talked about phosphorus
now let's talk about nitrogen and
nitrogen is a very kind of complex
element in in in the
soil um and both in terms of how it
behaves in the soil but also in terms of
the larger um considerations around
nitrogen and there's a there's a number
of concerns that we have about around
nitrogen these days one is the is the
high energy consumption that's
associated with the habos process that
basically is the industrial process that
takes atmospheric nitrogen to reactive
nitrogen um it requires a lot of uh
natural gas a lot of energy and it
generates a lot of carbon
dioxide secondly you know we have a a
persistent concern about groundwater
nitrate levels we haven't really seen a
lot of improvement in general over the
past couple of decades in in nitrate
levels which is the result of excessive
nitrogen applications especially in
these more Sandy areas or even urban
areas the other one that we're concerned
about is is the losses of nitrogen uh
into streams and rivers and then into
estuaries and this map here on the
bottom shows the the about 300 locations
around the world where there are a lot
of concerns with uh High uh levels of
nitrogen in estuaries causing uh hypoxia
or low oxygen levels and fish kills and
all that uh one area that's really quite
well known is is Northwestern Europe
where there's a lot of nitrogen use a
lot of intensive uh dairying this is the
original area of where where the dairy
systems were developed and then of
course on in North America uh the area
along the east Co Coast starting sort of
with Southern New England uh going down
to Florida and then of course along uh
the Gulf Coast where we have probably
the largest problem as a result of all
the nitrogen that comes out of the
Mississippi River Basin primarily
associated with uh with corn
production um but these are uh often
very important estuaries uh like for
example the bonic Bay on Long Island uh
where there's a lot of concern even from
Horticultural Farms about trying to
reduce nitrogen
losses so the fourth area of concern is
is greenhouse gases uh primarily nitrous
oxide n2o which is the result of
denitrification and uh again Berry
production may not be a huge contributor
uh but uh agriculture overall has a very
large footprint in terms of of
greenhouse gas impact uh actually very
disproportionate to the uh share of the
gross domestic product about 7 to 8% of
greenhouse gases are associated with
Agriculture and most of that is nitrous
oxide losses because nitrous oxide is
about 300 times more potent than carbon
dioxide and um and so we need to try to
reduce that through prudent and
judicious nitrogen
management so let's go to our pictograph
here about about nitrogen again crop
uptake is desirable we may have a little
runoff and erosion uh but most of the
losses will be leeching or
denitrification if we have you know a
more sandy grally soil most of it will
be through leeching and this is as
nitrate because nitrate is negatively
charged and the soil is negatively
charged as well so therefore it very
easily percolates down and washes down
with uh with the with the water in the
soil the uh volatilization and
denitrification losses are primarily um
uh N2 which is the nitrogen gas that's
also in the atmosphere which is not at
all a concern uh because 78% of the
atmosphere is already D nitrogen gas uh
but it's the nitrous oxide that's the
primary concern now when we have a
denitrification event from say a heavy
rain we may actually lose quite a bit of
of of of nitrogen we may easily use 30
40 pounds of nitrogen uh per acre uh
either through the nitrification or to
leeching with a a heavy rainfall event
of say an inch and a
half the other component that I should
mention is volatilization of ammonia
that is is also a concern primarily with
uh
acidification so the the the nitogen
cycle of course is is relatively complex
and I won't go into detail about that
it's I think the main point is that
there's a lot of these uh these
Transformations that occur in the soil
that are in part driven by all these
sources of nitrogen that come you know
from Agriculture and uh when it moves
from one state to the other state it may
be become subject to leeching or
denitrification and gaseous losses and
and all that so I'm going to simplify
that by uh using this graph here so this
uh First shows the sources of soil
nitrogen one of them is we get a little
bit of nitrogen from the atmosphere
typically about about maybe 6 or 8 lbs
per acre it's free nitrogen basically
but a relatively small quantity in most
uh field conditions we get a significant
amount of the nitrogen from uh the the
mineralization or the basically the
decomposition of uh soil organic matter
that may be native in the soil uh other
organic materials that may have been
applied like manure or compost or uh
residues um and then uh cover crops
especially leguminous cover crops like
Clover or alphalpha and these all get uh
get decomposed and the organic nitrogen
is mineralized to inorganic nitrogen uh
primarily as a result of uh of uh uh you
know biologically biological processes
which are in turn affected by
temperature the other source of nitrogen
of course is is mineral nitrogen which
is uh which is fertilizer it could be
ammonia type fertilizers it could be uh
nitrate type
fertilizers so we have all these
different sources uh of variation that
are associated with nitrogen
availability um and that makes it
actually a little bit more difficult to
manage nitrogen uh we uh different soil
types have different uh sources uh if
you're looking at the midwestern soil uh
they have a lot of organic matter and
it's very deep and they have um have
good structure they provide a lot more
nitrogen than say a uh a a soil in the
Northeast that's very Sandy and um a pot
soil type uh type soil that has
relatively little organic matter and
nitrogen
mineralization of course the amount of
organic matter in the soil uh affects
the nitrogen availability and we have
seen soils you know build up organic
matter when they're very well managed or
lose organic matter when they are say
have a history of intensive tillage or
erosion of course how much you add in
addition in terms of organic amendments
like compost and Manor whether you have
cover crops and what types of cover
crops leguminous versus uh grass cover
crops for example uh soil and crop
management you know how intensively you
till and things like that uh whether you
have drainage or not and if you have
poor drainage then you may get a lot of
uh losses especially of nitrogen
temperature is a factor
because a lot of the mineralization is
temperature mediated because it's a
biological process and then of course
last but not least
precipitation um because uh a soil
that's say very dry will not uh
mineralize nitrogen or soil that's too
wet won't mineralize
nitrogen and uh all these things in a
way interact in very complex ways and
that's what makes it very difficult to
precisely predict how much nitrogen uh
needs to be added to your soil to
adequately feed the crop but there are
really some some guidelines that we have
if we understand the system a little bit
better um so this is this picture here
shows the the nitrogen
mineralization uh as part of the
incubation time this is from an an
earlier paper by cman and
muns and what it shows you here uh that
the most of the nitrogen comes from the
surface soil this is the 0 to8 18 cm
which about uh 0 to 7
in and we see the uh an increasing
amount of nit being mineralized over
incubation time up to 100 days this is
the square root it's 100 days and then
we see that as we go deeper into the
soil less and less nitrogen is
mineralized and becomes available so
it's the surface soil that's the most
important that provides the majority of
the
nitrogen so in the field this is a
laboratory study but in the field
nitrogen release will be affected by
weather conditions like temperature uh
soil organic minor content so types uh
Etc so let's now consider the the losses
so we looked at the sources of N and
these are the primary losses one of them
is is ammonia volatilization and that
can be the result of of um uh the
application of ammonia type fertilizers
especially if they're left right at the
C surface so that they can
volatilize and you can reduce that by
basically incorporating it or injecting
it into the
soil uh also manure can often have
ammonia fertilization so if you apply
manure even some compost and you leave
it on the surface then you might lose
some of that through
volatilization uh we talked a little bit
about runoff and erosion tends to be not
that big of a problem the primary losses
of ntion from runoff and erosion is when
you leave
the uh organic or inorganic surf uh
fertilizer on the surface and it gets
gets removed in a heavy rainfall
event um the other losses the major
losses are denitrification and nitrate
leeching as we as we mentioned again the
primary objective of course remains
getting the nitrogen into the
crop um so again it's management soil
Health precipitation and temperature
that are all critical factors in terms
of the losses it's always if you get a
lot of water you get a lot of
precipitation that creates most of the
problems that can create the leeching
the nitrification is affected by both
precipitation and by temperature because
it's an indirect loss and it's a
biologically mediated loss so if you
have actually very cold soil you may
have quite a bit of nitrogen in that
soil um but you won't get much
denitrification losses because uh the
soil is cold and the boss iCal activity
is low so when you really do see a lot
of denitrification losses is is sort of
you know a little bit further into the
growing season when the soil has become
warm and then you got a lot of rain and
you can lose easily 30 to 50 pounds per
acre in a heavy rainfall event and so in
a way you'd like to be able to account
for
that so when we go back to our basic
properties in terms of pore sizes um we
can think of the loss potential again in
terms of large pores uh good ation so it
reduces denitrification losses small
pores reduces leeching losses and
ideally you have some of both because
that provides a well balanced soil which
you tend to get from a well aggregated
soil another uh concern related to nen
is is poor internal drainage um so if
you uh have uh barriers deep in the soil
and you have uh water tables that are um
at um you know relatively shallow depths
that promotes of course denitrification
losses you can remediate that through
insulation of subsurface drain lines and
of course uh race beds also reduce the
susceptibility to imperfect drainage so
it's an it's an component that's often
forgotten but um you know poor drainage
creates uh problems especially with
nitrogen losses but even with runoff and
erosion and phosphorus losses because uh
CS that have poor drainage tend to have
higher potential for runoff because the
soil remains wet and
saturated so what are the main
strategies then for reducing nitrogen
losses do not over apply nitrogen by
accounting for all sources of nitrogen
inputs like the soil organic matter
compost manure fertilizer Etc
ideally provide nitrogen in multiple
applications and account for weather
factors we're actually uh on the
scientific front making a lot of
progress in this area we now have for uh
field corn and sweet corn we have a tool
that we developed the adapt end tool
that allows for um for prediction of how
much nitrogen he needs using model
simulations accounting for all these
weather effects that we discussed uh but
I think for uh uh for uh even for Berry
producers where you may not have a tool
like that uh you can have basic rules
rules of of thumb if you have um say a
very wet spring then you probably lost
some of that nitrogen through
denitrification and leeching depending
on your soil type and you may need to
make up for that and apply a little bit
of extra nitrogen say in your second
application but if you have a relatively
dry spring you may want to do the
opposite uh because you didn't have any
losses so you don't want to over apply
so you can uh can even you know without
really using sophisticated sophisticated
methods you can make some adjustments to
your nitrogen based on the weather
conditions uh next one build and
maintain soil Health aggregation organic
matter Etc uh that especially on the
medium Define textured soils will help
with irration and with water and
nutrient uh retention so soil Health
Management
um again it's important not only from a
production perspective but also in terms
of reducing the environmental losses and
then finally as I mentioned facilitate
good
drainage um so I wanted to to show you
um these two soil Health
reports and uh to look at that sort of
in the context of the environmental loss
potential so these are two very similar
soils but one had a history uh of uh no
manure inputs and the other one had a
history with manure inputs and uh even
though these soils inherently are are
very similar they're medium textured
soils you can see that the aggregate
stability without manure was
53% but it became 78% with multiple
manure inputs so we have actually uh
make the soil more made the soil more
desirable by allowing for better
irration reduced um reduced potential
for denitrification l mes the available
water capacity went from uh 0.1 to. 26
so we've increased the ability of the
soil to
retain the nutrients as well so we've
both uh reduced the denitrification
losses in principle and we've reduced
the leeching losses because we have
better water and nutrient
retention also notice that the organic
matter content without manure was 2.6
and with manure it's been built up to
over six%
so that has a lot of benefits uh similar
with the active carbon and potentially
mineralizable nitrogen that's an
indicator of the amount of nitrogen that
we can expect from
mineralization that went from about six
to about
203 and so this uh this soil on the
right of course can provide a lot more
nitrogen from natural sources than the
one on the left so all in all the one on
the right with the manure inputs is of
higher Health higher quality and uh and
presumably reduced environmental input
uh
impacts okay so this is then my last
slide where I want to put everything
together that we've discussed in the
past
hour um and I think first and foremost
most Berry production systems have low
environmental impacts from nutrients and
sediments and part of that is because
they uh that is inherent with the
production practice and the fact that
you're using a a perennial plant so
there's not a lot of tillage going on
there's not very large amounts of
nutrients that normally get uh get
applied and so it's not as big of a
concern as perhaps you know corn
production or some of these other major
crops side characteristics like soil
type location Etc can affect potential
losses like for example when you're on a
flood plane or whether you have very
clay soils um and uh you know naturally
soils that have high runoff and erosion
potential
in addition to that through management
we can increase or decrease the um
potential for these losses leeching or
runoff and erosion so when we build up
the soil uh through good soil Health
Management we can increase productivity
and reduce the environmental impact so
it's a win-win
situation and then in addition we need
to make sure that we don't put too many
nutrients out there that we that we that
we are careful about what we apply so
prudent nutrient management can prevent
most of these
losses and with that I will hand it over
or back to Laura to our moderator and uh
be happy to entertain
questions thank you Harold um I know
that Tom has a question about whether or
not the soil Health test that you showed
second to the last slide was with manure
from a corn silage field and then I
actually had some questions about that
um same slide so I don't know would it
be possible to go back to that yes we
can go back to that um yes I mean the uh
the the the soil on the on the right
there they were both soils that were in
corn production and uh the one on the on
the left was primarily corn for grain
and the one on the right was uh part of
a dairy system so it was corn silage
with manure
inputs
okay um hopefully that answer here's
Tom's question and my question may be a
little bit off topic from the Barry
example but I'm I'm just wondering about
the um root health rating I struggle a
little bit with these soil Health tests
trying to understand what's happening
and definitely I can see the positive um
impact the manure has but why is the
soil the root health rating lower do you
think um I would have to go back to all
the details about the particular Farm
which I don't really have with me um uh
it probably has to do with with with
with the fact that the uh um the field
that was that received the manure inputs
uh also had rotations with Al Alpha and
we uh used the Bean bioassay for uh to
look at the uh so let me just put the
arrow there we use a bean bi bioassay so
uh which is also a legume so we may have
increased the uh the the root uh disease
pressure a little bit simply by the
rotation it's typically the the the
rotation and the types of crops that are
part of the rotation that are the
primary concern uh but keep in mind that
we use a uh uh for the root health uh
rating we use a sensitive uh indicator
crop which is which is uh snap Bean
basically that um and that's what we use
in comparison now if you're if you're
not growing snap beans of course then
you need to understand that you know
your crop might have slightly different
susceptibility but we we selected snap
Bean because you know it is the best
indicator typically that you can use for
vegetable
production okay great thank you um it
looks like there's a couple of other
folks typing and maybe we can get some
other questions
here um Kathy wonders how long does the
effect of a heavy downpour persist in
terms of nitrogen losses to soil is it
an hour or so after the event or a day
or more okay good good question that
Kathy um yeah so if you uh it it it
takes a little bit longer it takes
several days um what um when we have a
more finer textured soils like a like a
silt LOM down to a clay LOM you know
when we get a lot of rainfall the soil
becomes saturated and if it doesn't
drain well then uh the C remains
saturated and then it takes about 2 Days
in fact we've done a lot of research on
that and taken a lot of measurements um
it takes about 48 to 72 hours then for
these Anor robic conditions to occur and
that's when you get most of the lossess
so it's not
immediate because the soil needs to
remain saturated for about 2 days for
the E8 or the Redux potential to go down
and that's when you get most of the
losses
and similarly with leeching losses it
takes about a day or so day or two for
the water to move down through the soil
and then to wash out most of the
nitrogen I hope that answers your
question okay great and then um there is
another question from Glenn he's
wondering if the additional traffic from
manure applications increased the
surface and subsurface hardness I think
he's referring to that very slide that
right right
yes yeah absolutely and we we we do see
this a lot on on Dairy Farms where the
soal health indicators are all looking
great you know it's all in the green and
the ratings are are very high in the 90s
and then we see that the hardness uh is
typically uh uh the soil is very hard
and and so the score is very low on that
and that's because on on these uh fields
that receive manure a lot of the manure
gets applied with very heavy uh manure
spreaders uh often times under very
marginal conditions you know the the
farmers want to get to manure onto the
land early in the season because they
want to get to planting and so a lot of
these uh these soils actually show a lot
of compaction problems yeah that's very
observant of
you and then um again from Glenn he's
wondering if there's relationships
between temperature and precipitation
have been condensed into interpretive
Rules by which one could apply observed
and forecasted weather data into adapt
and recommend
ations uh let's see now I need I need to
look at that uh really quickly myself
should
I I've been condensed into interpretive
forecast uh yes so um if you're
interested in in in adopt n uh I would
encourage you to just go to our website
if you just Google adapt n uh you will
get there um but the the adapt in system
is is basically uh it it involves a d
damic simulation model which which
simulates soil and crop processes like
water movement through the soil and
nitrogen transformation and it also
accesses a highresolution uh weather
database that was developed here at the
Northeast climate center right here uh
in in the same building where I am now
Bradfield Hall and so the adapt end Tool
uh basically simulates all these
conditions for the early part of the
growing season it estimates the uh
nitrogen additions through
mineralization and and all that and it
estimates the losses and then it comes
up with a recommendation for Sight
dressing in this case corn um in
principle you know we could also get
into other crops uh so but that that's
what it does it's it's very Dynamic and
it takes all of those temperature and
precipitation factors into account and
it does it in a kind of a daily time
step okay and then there's a question
from Tom he's wondering if there's any
new research on remediating compact
mechanical ripping or biod drilling with
a deep rooted crop like forage radish or
alala uh well yeah Tom I mean those are
of course some of the uh some of the
things that more recently uh have have
been uh developed uh I I think the um
the the biod drilling is is is very
exciting this is um um for those of you
not familiar with it um Ray wild um at
the University of Maryland has done a
lot of work uh on that uh often in
collaboration with Steve gra who's a
very Progressive farmer in Southeastern
Pennsylvania uh the idea is to to use um
you know radishes especially you can
plant them in in September typically for
uh most of the uh the areas that we're
concerned of and um and they uh they
establish very strong and fat Roots I
mean they radishes and that basically
kind of loosens up the soil we call it
biod drilling um and um yeah so if you
have compaction uh the best way to
address that is is is to find some way
to decompact and it could be through
biod drilling it could also be simply
through you know some limited and
targeted uh tillage and then uh to try
to prevent that from happening uh
through you know soil Health management
practices and organic matter additions
and and all that you the soil becomes
more resilient to to compaction and more
resistant if you have you know better
aggregation and better exchange and all
those kind of things yeah so those are
uh some of the areas you know we uh
we've talked in the past about you know
using Frost uh tillet as well that you
know wouldn't be that appropriate for
Berry production but it's um you know
you basically till the soil when it when
it has a a very shallow Frozen uh
surface and uh that can be a you know if
there's been a lot of compaction that
occurred in the fall that can be a way
to alleviate the compaction that way you
do that uh at you know particular time
Windows uh during the
winter okay and then Kathy has two
related questions she's wondering if
there is then a short-term and or
long-term residual effect on nitrogen
availability after the Heavy Rain event
she's going back to that question
initially that she asked and then if
nitrogen is applied after the Heavy Rain
event is it more susceptible to loss if
another event follows
um there's not necessarily a residual
effect that that that I'm aware of and
so if you have such a heavy rainfall
event you you lose a certain amount of
of the nitrogen um you know so if if
most of the nitrogen that's in the soil
is in a nitrate form so the most
reactive form uh then you will lose a
significant amount of that uh with a
with a big rainfall event either through
leeching or through
denitrification uh and then it's gone
and you won't get it back basically um
then there's no necessarily not a
residual uh effect per se other than
that the soil is at that point in time
quite wet so if you get another rainfall
event you know say 4 days later and the
soil is already wet then of course you
can go into another leeching or
denitrification event but if you apply
the nitrogen you know subsequent to
these events and not immediately but say
you know a week later or something like
that then in principle that's not being
impacted by what happened to the to the
to the previous nitrogen and that is a
way to make up for some of these
losses all right I think does anyone
else have any questions for Dr
vaness all right they're pretty quiet um
I'll just move into the exit uh screen I
want to thank um Dr Harold vaness for
being with with us today um and I want
to remind the the group that remains
that the speaker for the next webinar is
Dr balinsky Santos who is the assistant
professor of horiculture um at the
University of Florida and the topic will
be fertigation and hydroponics of
strawberries he'll talk about new
diagnostic tools and Precision Precision
agriculture for Berry crops um again if
you have not completed the demographics
questionnaire or the pretest please take
an opportunity to do that right now and
um I want to thank all of you for
joining us and we will see you the next
webinar is March 2nd so we have a couple
of weeks break and then we'll be back on
March 2nd and March 9th finishing again
with um Dr vaness and uh thank
you
e e