it's recording
okay
all right
um greetings everybody uh we are this is
the recorded version of the equipment
webinar for the beginning Farmers 120 uh
if you are listening to it that means
that um Charles Bourne and his wife Meg
are in the process of having their first
child and we wish them luck so I'm
really happy that he spent some time
um in advance to tape this presentation
I'm going to move us into the classroom
and I just want to introduce chuck chuck
is the team leader for the Capital
District vegetable and Berry
extension program in the greater Capital
District of New York State and he spent
the first four years of extent his
extension career in the Eden Valley and
then has been in the Capital District
for a little more than eight years
um he is the person that we Crystal and
I turn to all the time for
information about equipment he's also a
specialist with Vine crops and potatoes
and he has his own small farm
so I'm going to just let Chuck take it
from here and I really appreciate his
effort on this
thank you Laura I appreciate it thanks
for having me on the webinar tonight
sorry that I could not be with you live
but as Laura said my wife and I are
expecting our first child uh at any
moment now so I had a a pre-existing uh
I guess
thing to get to so anyway uh Crystal and
Laura asked me to kind of go over some
of the basics on what a beginning or
small farmer might need for equipment
and as you can see equipment comes in
all shapes and sizes and colors and I
just wanted to take a little bit of time
tonight to just go through some of the
things that I think are important when
you start to look at purchasing
equipment and whatnot so we're just
gonna
started here
so where do we start I think the first
question that we all have to ask
ourselves is
what kind of scale are we looking at to
farm are you going to be a half acre
five acres you know 25 acres it all
makes a difference
especially as you start to increase your
acreage your your equipment needs are
going to change and it's meant mostly
for an efficiency Factor
um you know where
that's just for example and we'll talk
about this in a little bit but you know
a two bottom plow worked great for two
acres it may not work as well for five
acres it just takes you so much longer
to so you may need to go to a four
bottom
I think the other thing we have to ask
ourselves is how much labor do you have
and not only how much labor or time do
you have but also what quality
do you have uh if you have
you know in my case I have a an ant
that's 83 years old that you know Works
quite a bit with me but
um obviously she can't do as much as
let's say a 33 year old so I think you
have to kind of keep that in mind as
well
uh you know
back to that scale of size do you have a
lot of hand labor crops you know things
like greens that that may take a little
bit longer or you're going to rely on
more mechanization more equipment
uh long ago it was drummed into me by my
dad to work smarter and not harder
so again you know if you can mechanize
something and it's not going to cost you
an outrageous amount of money why not do
it it just makes your life a lot easier
improves your quality of life and it
could also improve the quality of your
product as well
uh and then I think you have to ask
yourself what do you already have for
equipment uh you know did you inherit
equipment or are you starting from
scratch and if you are in a neighborhood
where there's other Farms close to you
what might you be able to hire out or
you know to have somebody else do for
you
and you know things like getting Fields
ready for planning and things like that
if you don't have the equipment it might
be as easy for someone to just come and
do it for you and pay them or rent
Machinery from those folks especially if
you know if they're local enough and
they don't mind doing that
the other thought that I like to think
about is is have a system
um
it
it just makes your life a lot easier and
really it's on all ends whether it's
preparing ground whether it's planting
if you for for example know that you
want to take this three acre field and
break it into three one acre blocks
and within those blocks you know how
many beds or how many rows you're going
to have at certain spacing
um this really allows you to make some
decisions about equipment size of
equipment
spacing of equipment things like that
and I think for me I'm I'm kind of one
of those guys that likes to learn
visually
and so I put this little kind of this
little diagram together
you know if this was a a One Hole Field
so this whole Big Blue Block is one feel
but within those within that one big
field you know that you want
to have eight rows in each one of those
blocks
that are
or eight beds I guess is the best way to
say it so if each one of these black
lines represents a bed
that's 48 inches wide and from the
center of this bed to the center of this
bed is exactly eight feet every time
you know exactly how many row feet you
have or how many bed feet you have in
that block so that you can
do a lot of things you can you know make
sure that you have the right number of
plants the right uh spacing all of those
things can be answered
I also like the idea of putting in
permanent driveways between my fields
um
it helps not only just to get product in
and out and and field work but
actually it keeps a lot of soil
compaction out of your your actual
fields too because if you can Harvest
from these four rows and bring it to the
driveway and put it on a trailer
obviously that is one less tractor pass
across that field it puts all the the
traffic right in that driveway
the other thing too that you need to
keep in mind that and this goes back to
equipment is if this bed is is
too wide you may not find a tractor that
can go wide enough
and for example there are a lot of
tractors will not go any wider the wheel
spacing any wider than 60 inches
and that that can actually
play into a certain bed spacing that you
might not be able to use
if you want to go wider than 60 inches
then you have to find somebody that can
a good machinist that can actually weld
things for you
okay so the the question I think that
probably comes up first is is what size
tractor
um especially for a small farmer
beginning farmer and as I said earlier
they come in all different shapes all
different sizes uh all different colors
um I I think that predominantly my my
two favorites are probably
the John Deere series and also the
Kubota series and not that I'm
promoting either one but I just think
that in terms of Versatility I think
they have the widest range of of
tractors that you can select from
so there there are there are a couple
thoughts on tractors
um and keep in mind that this is is a
little bit of my opinion in this as well
but most Growers that start off would
probably recommend
well one tractor that can do a lot of
things but two two tractors that are are
very different
um one tractor would be the one that
performs the what we call the manual
labor okay so it's a tractor that does a
lot of the plowing and field fitting and
hauls a lot of the heavy implements and
whatnot and the second one is more of
the what I call the Finesse tractor so
once things are established this might
be used to to cultivate or it might be
used to hill or somewhere along those
lines not every Farm needs two tractors
the other nice thing about having
multiple tractors is that you might be
able to leave uh you know a certain
Implement that you use a lot you might
be able to leave right on one tractor
for a long time and instead of having to
take it on and off all the time
so
um the utility tractor
which is going to be the bigger tractor
or what I call the grunt
um
again you need to know what you're going
to do with it are you going to be mobile
or plowing rototilling are you going to
be carrying a disc over it and we'll
talk all about those pieces of
implements here in a few minutes but
I just wanted to give you an idea of
what we're talking about I think in
general you know anybody that's probably
an acre to 10 acres we'll do fine with a
35 to 40 horsepower tractor especially
if it's four-wheel drive
and there's a lot of reasons why I like
a four-wheel drive tractor as opposed to
a two-wheel drive tractor one of the one
is that it takes a lot less horsepower
to do the same job as a two-wheel
tractor
so four-wheel drive tractors just make
work a lot easier doesn't take as much
out on that on that tractor if it it's
four wheel compared to two wheel
for certain equipment like bed Shapers
and other things you have more control
the you're able to actually steer when
you have a Implement on the back rather
than just kind of hoping that you're
going in the right direction
um
and really what it also boils down to is
you need to know what kind of horsepower
is needed for those implements that
you're purchasing
and you know the the best thing to do is
you really need to talk to
if you're buying it from you know a
dealership you talk to the dealership
and and they have all the specs on on
how many horsepower a certain unit takes
and if you tell them what tractor they
have usually they can find you that
Implement to match it if you're looking
to buy it
um used and you're going through a want
to digest or something you may still
want to talk to a dealer and just get
his thoughts on whether or not your
tractor can pull that Implement that
you're interested in
okay and and the the best example I can
give you uh again is
if you have a 30 horsepower tractor and
you buy a five bottom plow
um you're not going to pull that five
bottom plow with a 30 horsepower tractor
whether it's four-wheel drive or
two-wheel drive it's not going to happen
and we'll we're going to go into that
here in a minute when I talk about more
board plows
the other thing that I'd like to have on
on one of those tractors is a loader
frame
um and you know that's that's for
a a bucket loader or a set of pallet
Forks either one become very very useful
on any farm and it's even better if it
can be what we call a quick touch bucket
or frame
where these frames have their own
stands for the most part and you pull
this pin right here and then you can
unhook the hoses and back right off of
the whole loader makes it pretty
convenient and then pull right back in
and hook right back up if you need to
and again these pallet Forks can be very
useful especially if you start doing
some um
growing of some Vine crops or other
things like that
um that you can actually just put a
cardboard tub on here with a pallet and
move it right through the field and and
load it onto a wagon or unload it when
you get back to the shop
so the pallet Forks come in very very
handy
the other thing is with any of this
Machinery inevitably it will break down
more than likely it'll break down when
you probably need it at the most
um so what I I tell guys is to find a a
good local mechanic if you can
uh and this goes for especially used
equipment that you purchase so that
there may not be any support there from
a dealer or you just don't know how that
equipment was used and
you know if the if the grower that had
it before you took good care of it you
might not have a problem but more likely
you're going to end up with something
breaking at some point in time and the
other thing is if if that that mechanic
or if you can find somebody else that's
a machinist
there are certain certain pieces of
equipment that may need some tweaking
just to fit your certain operation and
if you can find a good machinist early
on in your farming career and a good
mechanic you're going to be a lot
happier because they can really
um
Make It or Break It sometimes uh
when it comes to fixing equipment
so I'm gonna just start going over just
a couple Basics uh components of
tractors that that are pretty important
in my opinion
um you're going to hear the term
three-point hitch used an awful lot and
when you're you're talking about smaller
acreages most of your equipment is going
to be three-point hitched and what a
three-point hitch is really it's just
primarily used for lifting implements
that are pulled behind the tractor
uh
there are three main what I call three
main pieces okay uh there's these two
lift arms right here
okay and then there is this top link
piece right here
and if you're you if you purchase an
older tractor you may be required to add
something called sway bars or stabilizer
bars as they're sometimes called
which again they they
predominantly mount underneath right
here
and and are the same length as your lift
arm but it just keeps the
uh two lift arms from from wanting to
separate and wobble for the most part
a lot of the newer tractors have this
turnbuckle system
or they have a pin system which is a lot
so they don't need a standalone set of
sway bars which is kind of nice
um so just a this is a very detailed
schematic of all the different
components of the of a three-point hitch
and I think it's also important that I
point out that there are several
different
sizes of three-point hitches uh and this
correlates to
um equipment so something like a small
lawn tractor that has a three-point
hitch would be considered a category
zero
and something that is really large a big
piece of heavy machinery takes a larger
because it's heavier it takes a larger
set of arms and what not to lift it has
a completely different uh set of pins
and whatnot so that it's a lot larger
most of the Machinery that we deal with
Falls between the category one and two
especially if you for for smaller
Growers
now so a typical again and and I just
wanted to give you another little bit of
a schematic and and how these things fit
but
this is a brush hog
so you have these uh what they call link
pins on either side okay of of your
three-point hitch implement
and what happens is
these well let me go back to the next
one
these arms right here
slip right over those pins
and then you have another what we call a
little linchpin that goes right through
and secures
that
link pin within that lift arm so it
can't slide off okay and then that top
link arm slips right in there and you go
ahead and you put a a pin right through
there and lock that in
and what that top link does is it's on a
uh it
it's on threads so it helps you
adjust the
pitch so to speak of your Implement so
whether you want to tip it forward or
backwards it it lets you adjust your um
your pitch that way and these draw arms
uh
are what really help you raise and lower
that piece of equipment and set your
depth for the most part
oop going the wrong way
one of the things that I really like uh
and they're not very expensive they've
gotten a lot cheaper over over the last
couple years is called a quick hitch
and so this uh piece of machine this
little piece of Machinery right here
hooks on to your three-point hitch
okay and it's permanent it stays right
on there so it's hooked right onto your
tractor all the time
and what's really nice is that as you go
to hook up a piece of three-point hitch
equipment
essentially you just back rate to it you
back under it and those link pins fall
right into place there
and your top link you leave a bolt in
the piece of Machinery so your your top
link fits right in there and then you
just get in and you you lock these
handles down and it keeps that Implement
from from coming off so it's it's it's a
really convenient and Safe Way of
hooking up a piece of three-point hitch
equipment
I'm going to tell you that it is can be
very frustrating sometimes hooking up
three-point hitch implements because no
matter what you do you just can't seem
to get things lined up and you're on and
off that tractor
um
five or six different times sometimes
just to finally get that thing lined up
and get it hooked on and what's nice
again about this three-point hitch is
that takes all of that right out of the
equation lets you hook right up back
right up get onto it and and take rate
off again
so the other piece um especially if
you're going to use a
a lot of different Machinery will take
what we call a power takeoff or a PTO
Shaft or drive and that is what makes
things work it makes makes
rototiller blades go around it makes
brush eye blades blades turn
makes Baler Motors run the whole nine
yards but
they are very dangerous
this so this is what this is the spline
end of your tractor
and this is the shaft from your piece of
equipment which slips right over that
spline so it looks something like this
right here is your PTO shaft
and then this spins at a pretty high
speed
and you have to be very careful when
you're working around a PTO that's it's
engaged or running
because loose clothing can get caught on
this and it can wrap around that shaft
and literally spin you right into
um
the spin you right into the PTO shaft
and you do not want that
so
what we're going to just kind of start
from from scratch here we'll talk about
what I call primary tillage or it's the
very first tillage that that you may
have to do to prepare a field and in
this case I'm going to refer mostly to
what we call moldboard plowing
and again primary tillage is done to
prepare that seed bed or prepare ground
for shaping and trans for transplanting
later on we may want to incorporate
residue whether it's crop residue a
cover crop or even compost in some cases
uh it may be used to help level out a
field uh and then also we use it as a
means of disease and insect control as
well
so there's a lot of reasons why we do
primary tillage
um so you've heard me talk about this a
couple times but this is what we call a
moldboard plow
and when we say moldboard this is what
we refer to right here as a mole board
okay they come in all color shapes sizes
um
and
widths and this is pretty important
because depending on on how much of a
what we call a swath or
um
how wide this this portion is right here
it it's going to vary on how many
horsepower so it takes a lot less
horsepower to pull a 14 inch wide
moldboard than it does compared to a 20
inch mole board okay again as I said
they come in all shapes and sizes you
can get them in from one bottom and this
whole thing right here is considered a
one bottom or a two bottom which this is
or three bottoms all the way up to 20
bottoms so there's uh they can get very
big
um
I tend to recommend sets that have these
Trash Wheels or sod cutters
it just makes a much cleaner cut when
you go into the soil
doesn't it and it lets that in this case
over here if you look it lets this sod
roll under really nicely and and get
Incorporated
the other thing too is they can come in
manual or automatic resets
so as you're going along and if you hit
a big rock these things don't if these
these these mobile boards didn't have
any give to them they would just snap
off or they would stall your tractor so
what happens lots of times is that um a
manual reset these will just there's a
big spring in here these will come up
uh
and then you have to get over whatever
it was a rock or hard pan or tree stump
you get over it and then you just back
up and it just resets this uh moldboard
to where it was supposed to be
the fancier ones uh are and more
expensive ones are these automatic
resets where you just don't stop you
these are again two big compression
springs the whole thing just kind of
pushes up and then the Springs force it
right back down into the ground
okay where the rest of these are all
manual resets
so just some terminology that you may
hear again
that's your moldboard
that is your plow point and that's what
takes most of the abuse it's very
abrasive when you're pulling through
that soil
here's your side cutter
and then on the back side
is something that we call a landslide
and there's also a shin what we call a
shin there too but it's these landslides
and these plow points that we end up
replacing
depending on how many acres you do and
depending on your soil type but usually
they need to be replaced every one or
two years if you let these
um
these shins this upper piece here or you
let these landslides or the plow points
get wore down
then it starts to erode into your mole
board and I would much rather pay the
fifteen dollars to replace this little
piece here as opposed to the 150 it
costs to replace this big moleboard
piece
so just keep that in in the back your
mind as we go as you you think about
plows
it it takes a real knack to learn how to
moldboard plow
um
it's taken me probably a lot of hours
sitting on the tractor with my father
and my brothers to learn how to how to
move board and some days I'm not even
sure I'm still doing it correctly but
um I think it's important
just to to think about again it goes
back to what kind of system or develop a
system for for your fields and I think
the easiest system is to just break
those fields into smaller blocks
um and then plow moldboard plow in One
Direction
um
and what that does is it it just kind of
keeps the field on a on a Level Playing
uh over as you keep going
um and again I'm going to tell you that
your first pass is your most important
because that sets the tone for the rest
of your passes try to keep it as
straight as possible
because once you get a little cockeyed
whether
um
you know yeah yeah don't pay attention
and you start steering away around
something or you get off a little bit
once you get crooked it's hard to
straighten that pass up until you're all
done and then you might be able to clean
it up later with some other tillage
um
and so what happens is
um so this this guy has has made his
first pass on this field
um so he's driving this way coming
towards you
and he's flipping soil uh this side so
what he's going to do is he's going to
pick this plow up he is gonna then just
drive all the way back down here with
the up
and he's going to put his front tire
right here
and he's going to drop that plow in the
ground so he's got one tire his front
one front tires in this furrow
okay and his other tires up here on the
grass he's going to drop the plow and
then he's just gonna make us next pass
and he's just going to keep making that
until he is all the way over to the
other side
so again
um
this this guy right here you can see
he's going right along and it may not
look like it but his front tire is
actually right here in the pass that he
made previously
um so he's gonna go right along so that
same front tire right there will be
right here when he comes back through
um now
so over here he threw soil on the side
but when he gets over to the end of this
field he's going to have something that
looks like this which we call a dead
furrow and
you really it's it's important and this
is the other reason why I like to plow
one way is that
every time you plow whether it's once a
year or twice a year
um
move this dead Furrow so if this year
the dead furrows on this side
next year you're going to start to plow
you're going to actually start on this
side and what happens is it helps fill
this in a little bit and leave the dead
Furrow on the other side and then the
year after that you're going to reverse
it and just and just keep going back and
forth and that will
um keep you from from really making any
ditches on either side of your field it
keeps it nice and level
so secondary tillage so after you get
through and you you go ahead and you
moldboard plow I guess I should mention
too I'll just go back here real quick
excuse me
these moldboards can cost
um
they're all over the place depending on
on how War they are how many bottoms
there are
um I would say on average you're
probably going to end up about 100 to
150 dollars a bottom for manual resets
and probably more in the range of two
two fifty three hundred dollars for
those that are automatic resets
so they can be uh they can become quite
costly and again you know depends on
what kind of shape the the whole frame
and whatnot is in
um so just an idea of what it might cost
you for a mole board
so again secondary secondary tillage as
I started
um so once we go through with our mobile
boards
um we still don't really have
a seed bed that that we could plan into
so we come through with some type of
secondary tillage where we break up
those clods and clumps level it a little
bit and then and then that allows for
our Cedars and transplanters to move
through or are betters for that matter
uh to move through a lot easier and
there are lots and lots of tools out
there
probably the most
um
widely or common uh secondary tillage
tool is a is a what we call a disk or
disc arrow and again it's just these
Round Disc that they as they go through
the soil they chew up and they level out
a little bit and they break up all those
clods
uh and what's really nice is that these
are they're easy to use they come in a a
lot of different widths so you can you
know find them anywhere like right here
which is about a four footer you know up
to this one which is a 14-footer
but just keep in mind that with that
extra width you have to keep increasing
your horsepower every time
so you know something like this
three-point hitch one right here you can
pull with as little as you know 30
horsepower without really making the
tractor work
whereas this one up here you know you're
looking at really a 90 horsepower
tractor to pull that comfortably uh the
other thing too is is you get bigger
they no longer become three-point hitch
but they become hydraulic so where the
Z2 or three point hitch
so it needs those that lift arms that we
talked about in the back earlier this
one does not it actually
has a hydraulic cylinder right here
and there's hoses that hook to the back
of your tractor and it actually lifts on
these uh this set of wheels right here
but again that's uh you're talking about
a much larger piece of machinery
and these disc arrows again price ranges
all over the place depending on if
they're new or used and with and what
kind of shape they're in
my favorite secondary tillage tool is
something called a perfecta Harrow
I think it it pulls a little easier than
disk so it's it's this toolbar and it's
got these what we call Danish s times
and then these sweeps on on the end of
them so as this goes through the field
it it actually kind of starts to fill in
those um
uh
voids made by the the discs or made by
the moldboards that you went through
with
and breaks up some of the clumps and
then this right here is a leveler bar
and then this is a rolling Basket in the
back which really helps break up those
clouds and clumps
and really just does a super nice job of
preparing a seed bed
and as you see right here anywhere
between uh one and a half to three and a
half horsepower per s-tine and that it
varies because of um
the width of these sweeps that you put
on there it takes a lot more horsepower
to pull a a three inch wide sweep than
it does just a one inch sweep as you can
imagine
and again what's nice is they come in
varying
widths you can go anywhere from six to
thirty six feet to 30 feet wide
um and just a very good tool and a tool
that I think at some point in time every
Farm
does need
another one is are these three-point
hitch rototillers and they are fine for
growing very fine seeded crops they
prepare a really super fine seed bed
however uh there are some issues
they they can be very slow
uh because if you are into something
that's got a lot of sod
um it it may actually take you two or
three passes to get a bed
like you want it
um they are not really made to go very
deep so they're really just like a you
know that three inch tillage depth which
for some crops is fine but for others
they like it a little deeper
they can require a fair amount of
horsepower again because you are
you know not using three-point hitch but
also the PTO the power takeoff which is
going to draw some extra power
and they can be expensive
um you know nine 9 900 for a very narrow
one that's probably about a four footer
up to three thousand dollars on a six
footer and again there are many
manufacturers out there
um which is the guy on the bottom
here probably being one of the higher
end
rototillers in my opinion one a very
nice unit
the other thing that uh I don't
particularly care for about rototillers
is that they pretty much destroy
a good chunk of your soil structure
they break this this this soil up so
fine
um that uh you can run into some
problems with some soil tilt later later
on
um
but uh I think that's a whole nother
talk discussion for another time
this is a piece of Machinery which I
don't expect a lot of new Farmers to
have it's grown in popularity the last
couple years it's called a Spader
and as you can see it's got these what
we call while they call them Spader
teeth
but they look like giant tines with big
sweeps at them or points
and essentially what they do is they
um
They Don't Really till soil but they
just kind of mix it up and stir it and
then there's there's this kind of this
leveler unit here in the back which
helps break up some clumps push clumps
down in the ground and also just kind of
give you a little bit of a level
um
they again are they're quite slow
because you need to take your time to in
order to to get uh enough of those
Spader knives to go down into the soil
and they are expensive and you need a
large horsepower tractor uh to run it
comfortably
but if you want to see how these work uh
there's a good website with some good
videos right here that you can go ahead
and take a look at and see how those
units work again I think for beginning
Farmers this is a little bit of Overkill
um
and as I said they had gained popularity
but um
there are a couple folks that I know
that have them that actually have parked
them
um because they were just taking too
much time to prepare their fields with
them
the the advantage again is that they are
not as hard on your soil as a rototiller
so they maintain a little bit of your
soil structure for you
um and they are actually very good
incorporators of organic matter too
which is which is kind of convenient
again for smaller acreage I love this
unit this is a what they call a BCS
tiller
um and they don't even call they they
they call these units tractors
um as you can see right here this is the
base unit right here
and what I love about it uh is the
handle and this is what this
is supposed to be depicting but those
handles rotate uh essentially 180
degrees
so that you can have either rear mounted
equipment attachments or front mounted
attachments depending on what it might
be
and the price range you know for the
versatility of these units is not bad
as you can see
the uh the price for these base units
and probably one accessory
um can vary quite widely is depending on
what what you're looking for horsepower
wise
and just to show you the versatility of
these units
these are just all of the different
attachments that they make
for these tractor units and again that
you know things can be rear mounted or
front mounted depending on how you
swivel the the handles
and one other feature that I like about
this unit is this is actually what they
call their power healer attachment
and I think in circumstances where you
guys might have high tunnels or unheated
greenhouses and you want to make some
raised beds and you don't want to do it
by hand
I think these power healer attachment
units on the BCS tractors could actually
do a very good job so again you know
these are very versatile they'd be great
for smaller acreages
and especially if you're you're going to
have some high tunnels
I think if you're going to be a
vegetable or small fruit grower
especially vegetables I think you're
gonna you're gonna wanna look at using
plastic mulches
and in order to really get the benefit
out of a plastic mulch you're going to
want a a really good
bed
shaper or actually a mulch layer
okay and here's just a couple different
models now these are what we call
flatbed mulch layers okay are they
pretty much
just lay
that piece of plastic
rate on a level pretty much with the
soil surface maybe just a little tiny
bit of a bed but for the most part it is
um just going to be
right on the soil surface
um
there this is a buckeye tractor unit uh
where is my pointer
that's right here so this is one without
plastic and here you can see them laying
this nice row of plastic
this green unit right here is a rain
flow unit
and
four I think the larger operations the
rain flow unit is where I would steer
you
for a couple acres these Buckeye units
really do a nice job and they're they're
a little less expensive
than uh than some of the rain flow
models again rain flow is a company out
of Pennsylvania that makes a lot of
different equipment a lot of nice
vegetable equipment it's it's built well
it's heavy duty and rugged and I highly
would would recommend you talking to
those folks if you're interested in some
of these
bed shapers
the other option is you can do it by
hand however I'm going to tell you that
to get the biggest benefit out of out of
this plastic mulch you want a nice tight
bed as tight as you can get it otherwise
if it's if it's loose and floppy you
don't you don't get the maximum benefit
out of a piece of plastic
so but if if it's all you've got for the
first couple years it can be done
this is just another flatbed model this
is um one made by mechanical
transplanter company
and again you know all of these models
most of them I should say can come in
various widths anywhere from as you see
here a three foot wide to a six foot
wide
um
plastic roll it can accommodate so again
you can have beds that are you know 28
inches wide to you know almost almost
five feet depending on on how big you
want your beds to be
I as you
continue to expand maybe your farm uh I
really think it it starts to make sense
to look at what we call raised bed
plastic mulch layers okay and again
um I would steer you to rain flow
um probably they're they're model 2550
is one of their most popular models or
and these units they look big and they
and fairly aggressive and they are
so you're looking at um you know
comfortably probably a 70 horsepower
tractor
um preferably with four-wheel drive
to really do a good job at at
using this Machinery so what you see
right here this is what actually gathers
the soil
to make the bed
this particular unit is set up to
actually apply a liquid fertilizer
underneath and also drip irrigation tape
or drip tape
okay so you can see that you know right
here these units can make anywhere from
a two inch to a six inch high raised bed
um and again depending on what
attachments and accessories that you get
they can be anywhere from thirty three
hundred to five thousand dollars
um so again something that you're you're
probably going to think about once you
get established and uh and start to
increase your acreage and these raised
beds are where you really start to gain
um
some of your production you know your
yield increases earliness
um and drainage too especially if you're
going to be on heavy heavy soils that
tend to stay wet
um you you may definitely want to think
about one of these raised bed Shapers at
some point in time
once you get everything made you get
your Fields plowed and fitted and you if
you're using plastic you get your
plastic lid you need to get your plants
planted
and again I I gotta tell you that rain
flow irrigation makes what we call a
water wheel transplanter
and what this does essentially is
I've got a better picture of it here in
a second but I'll just explain it these
two tanks are full of water
um and there is a hose that comes down
into what we call a wheel which has
these spikes onto it
and as you travel down the field
these spikes roll and they punch holes
in the plastic at whatever spacing you
choose you know the wheels all come in
different spacing so you choose what
size wheel fits the crop needs for that
particular crop
and as that that little steel Spike goes
into the soil it actually fills it up
with water
and so when you take these plants and
you put them in the hole they are being
put right into
um
a transplant hole that's full of water
so here's a this is a different unit
this again is is Buckeye and I Buckeye
makes a great piece of Machinery
um don't don't get me wrong rain flow is
not the only ones on the market these
guys do a very nice job and they
actually do a very nice job for smaller
scale Growers so these pieces of
Machinery from Buckeye are they're heavy
duty but they are not
um
tremendously overbuilt but they're very
durable and here again this is a good
picture of that water wheel that I just
talked about and you can see these
spikes right here are what makes the
holes
and
uh this doesn't have a spike on it but
underneath this Spike if you were to see
it would be this hole right there which
lets the water Escape into the hole
so that's a complete water wheel unit
right there
they also you can also just purchase
from Buckeye
just the dry wheel punch so after your
beds are all made or even in bare soil
they don't have to have plastic on them
you can actually take and run this unit
over and it'll punch the holes into the
plastic or into your soil at your
desired spacing and then you come back
through and you can plant it by hand
so again you know pretty economical for
you know 600 bucks or so to uh to
purchase this unit and the other thing
too is that this is a pretty nice
toolbar
that you can actually hang some other
stuff off of
um later on as well
again um
mechanical transplanter they also have
their version of a raised bed maker
right here as you can see it's a lot
simpler not as many parts
but and not as heavy but
you need very very light soils for this
kind of unit to work really well and
that's another reason why I like the
rain flow units is they work in just
about every soil type
and do a very consistent job in in all
those soil types
mechanical also makes a transplanting
unit
um
this is a mulch planner or pop planner
model 900 that you see right here uh and
essentially what happens is as you drive
through this is ground driven
these spikes that you see right here
these yellow ones rotate around
and the guy that's sitting here just
puts the plant right there in that Spike
and then as it comes around
it pushes into the plastic the the spike
or the cup actually opens up
lets the plan out and then right here
there are what we call pack wheels and
that pushes the plant into the ground
this is dry so there's no water or
anything involved they do make them with
water attachments
um
very expensive
lots of moving parts
Nana is forgiving on transplant height
they have to be just the right those
transplants have to be the right size if
they're too big what happens is this cup
actually
that's that little hinge unit right
there will close back onto it before
it's off of the plant and it pulls it
right back out
um
I see where they actually tear plastic
more I think and and end up you end up
with more problems later in in later on
um so you know you can find these out
there fairly inexpensive used ones that
are in decent shape and again you know
is a good place to start although
um I think you can buy a water wheel for
probably still less money and and it's
much more versatile than one of these
mulch planners
so we've talked about transplants
um
probably one of the things you'll do
first before you do a lot of
transplanting is some direct seeding so
in terms of
direct seeding units for smaller Growers
there's there's a fair amount of them
out there this particular unit right
here is what we call an earth way uh
it's made by the company called earthway
um you really need a a good seed bed so
that the unit pushes easily this is what
we call plate planner so you can see
that
um there's all these different inserts
that go into this Hopper right here
which determines what what you plant and
these push seeders are really good for
beans
corn and squash
they are knotted on so on the larger
sheeted stuff they do a good job but
when you get to the finer seated things
like beets and carrots and lettuces they
don't do as good a job
you get uh
you get a they're either too thick or
they're they're too far apart it's hard
to fine tune where
you want those seeds to drop
uh cold Planet Junior they have been
around for a very very long time
they are very durable again this is a
hand seeder but you can also purchase
these units to go on a toolbar
so this is a
three row bed that that they're planning
and it could be to lettuce or carrots or
beets they do a much better job
more accurate job than the earth way I
just showed you and they they actually
don't have plates in there there's
actually a little Sizer gauge
um and right on the side there you kind
of dial in what your crop is
and it sets that little trapdoor to let
just the right amount of seed through so
they do a good job again they're a
little more durable a little they you
need a good seed bed but probably not as
good as a seed bed you need for that
Earth way
um as you start to increase uh in the
amount of uh what you want to pay you
know they The Cedars get better
these are what we call Belt seaters and
you can see that uh all these
different belts are all made for
different size seed different spacings
um
they can be Standalone push units like
this or again mounted on a toolbar
they are very precise they're very good
um but again they are fairly expensive
you know fifteen hundred dollars
um
just for the base unit and then you have
to buy all the individual belts as well
but again you know if you're looking at
doing a lot of greens a lot of small
fine seeded things carrots beets onions
direct seeded onions these do a very
nice job very precise job on those crops
this is a fairly new Cedar it's only
been on the market for a couple years
it's called a Yang clean Cedar
again it's sold by mechanical
transplanter company so the same guys
that made those transplanters I talked
about a few minutes ago
uh it doesn't use plates or belts but
instead uses this roller design right
here or right here as you see and what
happens is that they just take these
rollers they drill them out to the
appropriate seed size and spacing that
you wish for
um
and again you know they can be
individual mounted push seaters like
this
mounted in a gang like that
um
and you know moderately priced you know
for a single unit push unit
um you know 400 bucks is not bad they
are fairly accurate and fairly easy to
to change as well and that that's
another key component of some of these
units is how long does it take you to
clean seed out and and switch out if
you're doing multiple varieties of
something
so these do a very good job
um
I know Johnny selected seeds is a is a
local distributor here of this of these
units so you can find them in your in
the Johnny selected Seed Catalog
I think um these are always pretty neat
um
this is a company out of uh Pennsylvania
that builds this what they call two
different versions of a stand-in plant
um so this is uh
essentially what you could use for
transplanting uh Peppers
um they have to be fairly small of
course tomatoes eggplant things like
that
um you know not a lot it's just by hand
it's there's not a lot of moving parts
you know you slip the plant in
push it into the ground pull the handle
and and pull it out and there's your
transplant right there
and then they have this planet stick
which you can use for direct seeded
stuff
essentially you uh you jab it in the
ground and you drop your seeds in right
in the top and pulled out and um keep
walking right on down the row so it's
inexpensive
um
and uh and can do quite a bit of work
talk a little tiny bit about um
some other implements that will probably
be used or could be used especially if
you're thinking about doing a lot of um
not as much mechanization but a lot of
hand labor
um
and I'm going to tell you I have done an
awful lot of hoeing in my life and
there's a couple units that come in
pretty handy this is um part of a what
we call a wheel hoe and I'll talk a
little bit about a wheel hoe in a minute
an earlier version was again
Planet Junior used to make they were the
first ones to really come out with this
type of wheel hoe you won't find this
anymore unless you go to an antique
place but you will find these new
versions right here
and then of course there's your hand
hose
stir pose
sometimes they call these potatoes and a
prong ho and
of course your old-fashioned Spade hoe
so again talk a little bit about wheel
hose for cultivating uh you know weeding
right here these work well even to do a
little bit of hilling or if you want to
you know make a Furrow to plant
something into
these are pretty versatile units
um and again that price range is three
to four hundred dollars and you know you
can get down through some tight places
so if you're putting you know a couple
beds of something
a couple rows of of lettuce or carrots
or something on a on a one bed
um if you space it right you might be
able to get right down through there
with one of these um with a wheel hoe
with one of these
um
stir pose right on it do a very good job
of uh cultivating
I think crop sprayers is something that
we sometimes Overlook and there's a lot
of a lot of variations if you want to
have the highest quality product whether
it's conventionally grown organically
grown you know there are some some
uh
pesticides out there that are you know
things like copper so fungicide which
has been around for a long time still
does a good job
um
and just to to be able to improve that
crop quality I think is very important
and there's a lot of versions you can go
very simple with a backpack or handheld
sprayer like the solo unit right here
or you can get a you know 15 20 gallon
um ATV mounted unit that's got an
electric pump or even Mount this in a in
the trailer of a small you know pull
behind lawn tractor
or you can as you get bigger and you
need to cover a little more territory a
little quicker you can go to a
three-point hitch unit
um that usually has a PTO driven pump
but you can also stay with an electric
pump uh and that are anywhere between
three and 200 gallons and again you know
the prices range all over the place
90 bucks for this little solo backpack
sprayer
100 150 for the ATV sprayers and then
um
you know you can spend
upwards of three four thousand dollars
on a three-point hitch unit you know a
unit like you see right here in this
picture is probably going to cost you
about 450 bucks
um and then uh probably another 80 90
bucks for the PTO pump or an electric
pump if you decide to go with that
version
oh
so you when I talked earlier I talked
about a second tractor
and this is kind of the Finesse tractor
or the the
and these are just a couple models
there's there's a fair amount of
um
models that are out there
all three that you see here are what we
call off set
um so you are not looking you're not
seated right in the center of the
tractor but you are actually offset so
that you get a good view of the crop
that you're trying to cultivate so it's
right down there
there's various types of
um cultivators uh all three of these
happen to be what we call Sweep
cultivators
um
and mounted in all different
configurations the the key with um that
second cultivating tractor or any
tractor that you want to use for
cultivating
is the clearance or or the
the amount of space that's between the
belly of the tractor and the crop that
you're trying to cultivate as you can
see these are what these three right
here what we call High clear instructors
so there is a lot of distance between
your crop
and also the belly of your tractor and
and you want that because you don't want
to be really bending that crop over if
you can avoid it
so again you know these these are our
older units
um you can find them out there they
range all over in prices
um you can find a a cub High boy you may
find one
with cultivators for 1500 bucks that's
in decent shape
up to this 274 diesel unit which you're
looking at you know closer to four
thousand forty five hundred dollars for
um
uh but uh they are still out there and
and still available
this is a little more of a a specialty
item we tend to see these a lot on
Organic Farms where
um
you know cultivation especially for weed
control is is pretty important and these
are Alice chamber G Series
um
they are
very they've been around for a very long
time so that uh if you're looking for a
newer version
um there is a newer version out there
called the stockville
uh and they do make um you know you can
find those those are newer units they
look very similar to this but of course
have all the updates of power steering
and hydraulics uh and whatnot
but you can still find these G units
around again uh very versatile you know
here's one that's set up with cultivator
sweeps two different styles here's a
unit that's been set up for hilling to
make uh probably raised beds or to even
make raised beds to lay plastic on and
here's a unit that's even been set up
for mobile board plowing
um
probably the the most
sought after
Implement for this for these G Series
are this what we call a basket weeder
and these are really good for
um
closely planted rows of things like
lettuce beets carrots things like that
they do a really nice job they don't
move a lot of soil but they disturb
enough to uh
to do a good job of cultivating as long
as the weeds are really really tiny
and that's the key with really any of
the cultivators that you may see or hear
about is
the weeds need to be small to do to do a
really good job
this is another one um it's based on
an older implement
um
but uh they so they've updated it this
is called the Hillside Cultivator
and these units have become popular in
the last few years because as you can
see here they are able to be used for
cultivating between rows of plastic
mulch
and these things are their three-point
hitch but they are hydraulic uh
they have two cylinders up here which
allow the operator to actually move
these units in and out depending on on
how wide they need to go for to get
across that row
so very versatile very
um very useful not only for you know
plastic but also for Bare ground crops
too they do a very good job of
cultivating
you know something else that um you may
you may need especially if you are
thinking about having some animals on
your farm or if you're going to be
more on the organic side of things and
you're going to be needing to spread
compost our manure spreaders
uh and again you know the key here is to
match
um the size of the Manure Spreader to
your tractor to make sure that you're
not going to have a manure spreader
that's way too big when you get it
filled up uh to be able to pull and
here's another example too of
um a tractor having a tractor that's got
a loader on it so that you can actually
load
these spreaders if you have a you know
bulk load of compost delivered to your
farm
uh this is a drop spreader so we can use
these for lime or fertilizer and they
still make these units uh Market farm
implements which uh is a website for you
here at the end makes a lot of these
fertilizer drop units and they're really
good uh if you only want to fertilize
um you know certain widths of beds for
example they do a pretty good job pretty
accurate
you know I'm not sure if you call this
equipment I considered equipment I
consider it a very important piece of
equipment on your farm and that are
Harvest containers
if you've spent all your time and a lot
of money to get a crop to harvest
um
I I think you want to maintain that that
quality as as far as you can and and
having uh good harvest containers but
also uh containers that maybe can double
for for marketing purposes like these
shallow gray containers right here you
know for putting um you know a single
layer of tomatoes in especially if
you're growing some softer heirloom
types
um or even these larger gray green units
these are great for greens especially if
you've got a harvest and then put them
in the cooler to cool them down they do
a great job but they're durable they're
reusable just as long as you keep them
clean and I think they just help provide
a much higher quality crop in the end
again you know these are that motto of
of work smarter not harder uh and you
know if if you only have a small you
know Market Garden you know these little
pull hand carts are great they got those
big flotation tires so they move easy
um the ones with sides are great because
you can put some of those Harvest
containers in there and not have to
worry about them falling out
um but then also even just having a hand
truck to move stuff around is very
useful especially if you're going to do
some farmers markets and and you may
have to walk aways
I think every Farm probably should also
have some kind of
um
we call I call it a whirly gig spreader
there's a lot of different names out
there but uh you can use them to spread
fertilizer or cover crops you know or
in some instances even crop seed we
actually use a cedar like this right
here
uh to plant turnips uh purple top
turnips for root harvest in the fall and
again it works pretty well and there's
all different versions again here's a
pull type but then again you know here's
a a hand seeder it's a sling type to a
push type so there's there's all
different levels of
um of these spreaders that you can go
with
you know flame leaders again uh if if
you're growing crops that there are not
a lot of uh herbicides labeled on or if
you're going to be organic
um having a flame weeder and this is a
homemade unit
um made by Michael Kilpatrick who's a
grower up in Granville so here's his
here's his little heat shield unit so
all of his flame is coming out of these
four ports right here and then he's got
the propane tank right there on his back
does a very good job so again you know
he's got this bed ready uh it's probably
been ready for a couple days maybe he's
got some seeds that have germinated some
weed seeds so he's going to go through
um hit it with the flame weeder uh
if he's done it a couple times and maybe
he'll plant right into it or he may go
through and stir this up a little bit
again and come back through the weed uh
with the flamer in a couple days just to
kill any more weeds that may have
started
so just another little
um interesting piece of equipment that
could be useful
uh you know irrigation
um if you're going to be a vegetable or
small fruit grower you are going to at
some point in time need an irrigation
system whether it is an overhead system
like these two okay
um where you're pumping it out to a reel
here or if you're using drip irrigation
you still need a pump to be able to get
the water to those to those lines so
again
it may not be the very first thing that
you think of but within the within a
couple years you're really going to need
to think about some type of irrigation
system
so I this is obviously not a complete
list but this is a list of
um places to look for Machinery that I
often use
um you know I think again I think a good
spot to start might be with a local
agricultural dealer you know like a John
Deere New Holland or there there's a
bunch of them out there
um
it's a good place to find tractors good
used tractors too but then also to have
some support there
in terms of finding you know matching
equipment with your tractor needs and
whatnot
um want to digest or Craigslist uh could
be a place to find some machinery
going to auctions in the fall or spring
there's a publication out there called
Fastline
which I really like I subscribe to the
Northeast Regional Edition you can get
it either
hard copy comes like well depends on if
you want to pay for it or not
You Can Get It Free and it comes once a
month or you can get it you can pay for
it and it comes on a weekly but it's
essentially all the or a lot of the
Agricultural equipment dealers
everywhere from Maine all the way down
to I think Virginia for the north
Northeast Edition anyway
so it could be a good place to at least
locate some dealers maybe in your area
of course there's websites
tractorhouse.com is another good place
wengers is a used equipment dealership
in Pennsylvania they do a nice job good
support same with rotors farm equipment
out of Michigan and then I I mentioned
them once already and that's Market Farm
Company
and the one that I did not put here
would be rain flow but I've talked about
them several times
um and the other one is Buckeye
equipment company
um especially for those mulch layers or
those transplanters water wheel in
particular
you know other places uh country folks
grower and actually not just to look for
equipment but maybe to get you
accustomed to some of the industry in
your area
they do a very good job with a diverse
uh agricultural publication
of course vegetable Growers news is
another good way you can look in the
classified ads for equipment but also
get a good idea of what's going on in
the the world of vegetables and then the
other thing too is just get to meetings
and talk to other Growers they're going
to be one of your best sources of
information I think
um so again you know we've said this I
think I think we've
gone over this a little bit
but I think you need to really have a
good idea of what scale you want to farm
and then put a system into place to make
your life easier in determining um you
know what what's going to be going in a
particular field for example
I think you need to think about your
labor uh and mechanize where you can
uh when you purchase equipment make sure
that
it's appropriate for your size operation
and also for your your current tractor
that you have very important
um you know don't don't purchase those
implements that obviously can't be
handled um by your tractor if they're
just way too big or too small for that
matter and we have seen that happen
where
um you know you just that for whatever
reason
um it's just a piece of Machinery you
bought it's too small for your tractor
um so you've got you know Tire hangover
marks or could be a lot of different
things
and I think more importantly or most
important is don't be afraid to ask
questions about the equipment you're
thinking of purchasing
you know though the the dealers
um
in my experience most of them are very
good they know their equipment if they
don't know it they can find out more
information about it and I I really do
think that a good equipment salesman
will follow through from start to finish
and and even to the degree where if you
buy that Machinery from somewhere else
especially used
um
you might be or you should be able to
still ask him questions
um
and you know the other thing and we
didn't put it back in here but make sure
you find a good mechanic and a machinist
if you need one uh to to make your life
a lot easier when it comes to repairs on
this equipment
that's that's all I have Laura
um and
I hope it was somewhat useful for you if
you have questions
um obviously this is a recorded version
so you won't be able to ask me
directly but you know in this but you
are more than welcome to drop me an
email
at Sears and Charles d as in David B as
in boy 13. so cdb 1 3 13 at Cornell
.edu or you can also ask those questions
to Crystal or and Laura and they can
forward them to me and I can answer them
back for you so thank you very much I
hope you enjoy the rest of your evening
and take care