this is a production of Cornell
University well thank you so much for
coming out and it's really a pleasure to
be back here at Cornell and um I'm
presenting on a topic that's really
special to me so um I'll start off with
um just an introduction to
um why um why this topic is important um
and and then some of the research that I
did for my thesis and then Don will give
you an overview of what's Happening Here
at Cornell um with an exciting new
initiative um for me uh the topic of how
nature affects well-being um started
more in the Arts than it did in the
Sciences I I studied art history for a
while and um I've always loved this
painting by Van go and he wrote in a
letter to his brother how much looking
at nature um was a comfort to him and
his fin years when he was confined to an
asylum um he um continued to paint and
it was really uh the connection to for
his sanity um but what what he was
painting was nature and this beautiful
picture came out in one of the last
years of his
life uh also literature um i' the The
Secret Garden was one of my favorite
books and I really delved into it um a
few years ago and uh again the theme of
how working in a garden restores uh
well-being is is very powerful in that
story and then of course Cornell this is
a picture of the 80 White House Gardens
um and that among all the other Gardens
and Cornell plantations um there's just
so much Beauty on this campus and not
only as a grad student but as an
undergrad I found so much Solace finding
these places and little places to uh
hide away and get away from
the pressures of academic
life okay so there's really three um
core issues at the heart of my research
um first the statistics for mental
health among College age students are
very shocking um there are 57% who feel
overwhelming anxiety um and also
35% um who have felt so depressed that
it was difficult to function I found
that statistic very very troubling um so
some of these numbers are really high
and
um here are some numbers for what causes
the most stress academics being the top
um but a whole bunch of other issues as
well but um it's definitely a problem
among
students so one in three really has
faces of some kind of mental health
issue in addition to all the
overwhelming stress uh of being a
student so that is another number that
is really amazing to
me the other issue uh for me was uh
Public Gardens at colleges and
universities there are a specific kind
of public garden they work with the
university by having a mission that
coincides with that the university and
they are often fighting for their
existence um trying to show that they're
relevant um to the university and often
that leads to some issues um there was
an article that it was discussed that um
why should these resources be going to
this organization within the university
that maybe is not always clearly
academic um so the issue of
relevance uh is a key um part of the
equation
uh and then finally the literature on
these subjects there's certainly a broad
amount of literature on nature and
well-being and and also within each of
the areas of health and with mental
health and and colleges and universities
but where they intersect um it's not uh
as much and it's certainly not as much
when you get into to the study of public
gardens particularly um there are many
of these Gardens at colleges and
universities and yet they're not really
being thought of in terms of how are
they helping students um beyond the
academic part of their
lives um so I'm just arguing the public
gardens are um they very well could hold
the keys to a Rejuvenation of student
well-being on on these campuses
and what I wanted to try to answer was
um whether psychological well-being um
whether it's a priority at college and
university Gardens and whether they can
do a better job at appropriating that
role so before I um get into the the
more the research part of I had to
really dig into literature and um I just
want to give an overview of the way I
thought of this was um
kind of going from a broad amount of
literature down to a point um starting
off with the the breadth of literature
on nature and well-being but then going
down and getting closer to the college
and university experience um so just so
oops okay so these are some of the key
thinkers that I wanted to introduce to
um ol who wrote an essay on um the power
of a view um through Hospital Windows
um that patients actually had um a very
uh a better chance of recovery and a
reaction to pain
medications and um also fewer negative
comments from from nurses uh for when
they actually had a view of nature as
opposed to a brick
wall another um set of authors the
Kaplin
uh wrote about particularly this concept
of restorative environments and it's
based on this notion that there is
attention um D directed attention which
is a voluntary type of attention and it
requires effort and when that becomes
fatigued uh that is the the the core of
the problem is directed attention
fatigue and environments natural
environments particularly have been
known to soothe this actually restore um
directed attention fatigue uh for
different reasons um but particularly
because often they create a feeling of
being away um setting being set apart
they have a feeling of of an extent um
of space uh they create Fascination and
all these features contribute to an
environment being restorative
and our these authors actually right
here at Cornell um did a really neat
essay about school children and how
access to Nature uh really worked as a
buffer for
stress so they their concept of nearby
nature um the value of having it close
by um it was a function of how well
these students responded and how they um
it reduced their amount of
stress um Richard Lou uh his classic
concept of nature deficit disorder um
kind of close to um attention deficit
disorder or other mental disorders but
he puts this in the mix and says that
there is a lack of uh interaction with
nature among children and he recommends
vitamin n for vitamin nature
and then the question of the dose of
nature how much is enough um there was a
study that was done that said that even
a minimal amount of um of exposure to
Nature and and activity in nature just
five minutes was considered the most
effective of any of the other amounts
that were experimented with so uh a
small amount of time also low intensity
was found to be in effective
and um also the difference in
environments um between urban and more
natural it didn't seem to make a
difference they were all helpful as long
as they had some kind of green
element okay so now going just from that
broad amount of literature that's those
are just samples um with mental health
literature uh common themes are that
disorders appear in the first three
decades of life and because these are
the ages that our college students this
is there's a high percentage on these
campuses of of students who suffer with
these illnesses um and then other
there's so many other factors that
affect mental well-being as well and all
of them are are certainly represented on
diverse
campuses um the one that I found
interesting was the issue of help
seeking
is it's something that students are
notorious for not reaching out for help
um and often treatment is delayed
because of that and so it's a challenge
that needs to be
considered
um in looking for a way into how I was
going to approach Public Gardens with
this topic I I looked for other studies
that were done on campuses and there
were a few um University of
Massachusetts ammer um they they tried a
Horticultural therapy intervention um
students went in uh and interacted with
plants they um did different techniques
with a Horticultural therapist and then
took a survey and found that there are
some glitches in the study but um
predominantly it was showing how stress
was significantly relieved by this
experience um at this University in Hong
Kong uh views of green spaces and also
just the use patterns of different green
spaces were analyzed and recommendations
were made um based on those results and
this university in England also um was
interesting because it it looked at
different spaces on campus and found
that certain spaces closer to buildings
uh usually more formal uh environments
were really much more preferred than
than further away uh sometimes more wild
or natural
environments um and also that as th
though many students knew about these
spaces only about 50% really used
them and then getting into Gardens as a
sort of a subset of nature um why what
what is special about the garden
particularly and often um Gardens are
described as a series of of rooms and
there's a feeling of of Escape or
getting away that they promote
um there was an article done in for the
public garden magazine that talked about
how Gardens are this Refuge from our
difficult time that we live in with so
much information and um technology and
and access to problems worldwide and
that the garden is a safe
place and this was um after 911 um this
uh statement was made saying that at the
Brooklyn botanic garden there um had
never been such a overflow of people who
just needed that Garden right after that
devastating day um
so how they open their doors to people
and and people really needed that
space and then in discussing Gardens
there's also a some literature about why
we prefer Gardens um and for some it's
goes back to an evolutionary perspective
of that we were designed to our program
to really want to be in an environment
that feels safe usually an open one with
trees um and it it takes away from the
from the stress of that fighter flight
response um the other view is especially
over most of History was just the
creation view um of the story the
history of the Garden of Eden and just
that we were made for Gardens um we were
made to be gardeners and a man named
Benjamin Rush who was one of our
founding fathers and a physician and
psych early psychiatrist he wrote about
gardening as an effective means for
treating mentally ill in his day and
Horticultural therapy actually owes um
owes its creation to to Benjamin
rash um university
Gardens have a history of their own um
they really developed in about the 13th
century in England um Oxford and
Cambridge were the result of monasteries
and uh that dissolved and they had
cloistered Gardens these uh spaces that
were very private and um meant to be uh
places of healing and Escape for people
and these became places of institutions
of learning and then later on um in
Europe and especially Italy um in the
16th
century Gardens at universities started
to become more incorporated into the
intellectual um life of the University
they became great collections and they
were studied for their plants for their
qualities and so the concept of the
garden as a living classroom um really
started to develop and I think is what
is predominant today and this is our
lovely Cornell plantations and just had
to get that in
there
um my study had two parts I did a series
of interviews with nine Public Gardens
at colleges and universities and I
wanted to ask a variety of
questions um these are the institutions
so Arnold at Harvard um Smith college uh
Cornell of course Garvin is a beautiful
garden that's 175 miles apart from its
campus in Arkansas and just gave another
an interesting um insight into its
challenges that it has in reaching
students um Ralston in North Carolina
Mai at University of Michigan Morris
arum University of Pennsylvania Scott
arum at swore and UC
Davis
um it was a broad different kinds of
gardens uh so it gave me a lot of
different
perspectives um key to what I was
looking for uh from these Gardens was
the mission that um not only the mission
of the garden but of the university and
how how they c um complimented each
other um so this quotation is one that
is often that was posed to Public
Gardens as saying to stay relevant be
sure that your mission is in the vein of
the mission of your overarching
organization the the university
um and then this was
another uh thought that came out of
these interviews was the concern about
being not academic enough um some one at
least one Garden uh voiced this concern
uh that it wasn't it was afraid of not
of embracing other types of initiatives
because it might not appear academic
enough um that it was just seen as a
beautiful place um which is an
interesting uh way of looking at it that
it's somehow bad but um so this is
something I wanted to think about more
uh throughout the process um my
questions were very basic questions
about just access to the garden and how
they Market themselves but also more
questions related to well-being um how
it's stated in mission statements uh
what types of spaces they
offer um if they have any involvement
with Health Services those types of
question
questions and so a a large area of what
I was looking at were statements of
mission and vision and I just put up
Cornell for instance just a couple
Snippets that show how they're very much
related um Cornell with enhancing lives
and livelihoods of students and Cornell
Cornell plantations with enhancing
collections for the enrichment of
students so there's definitely a um an
interplay and I looked at the text of
these statements for all these these
Gardens and their their universities and
looked for how they might um introduce
the topic of well-being or uh reaching
students um my observations from the
from the um mission statements part of
the research was few had really direct
references but there were a couple uh
that actually talked about how Gardens
are how Gardens and how the university
is reaching out to benefit student lives
um and particularly actually making
reference to well-being um but those
were few uh otherwise there was I I
believe there was more of a perception
that they were helping helping students
in this way but not so much actually
making this an an explicit uh Mission um
I I identifi different types of of
references that were indirect things
that referenced um sustainability or um
other aspects that gestured towards
well-being and there were many of these
um and I I saw them as opportunities for
um the garden to embrace as ways of
getting into the topic of well-being and
um promoting
well-being
um when I looked at uh when I asked the
gardens for um spaces that they
considered restorative and that promoted
this feeling of getting away that was
that I found in the literature um
usually um highly designed areas were
mentioned um natural areas
too um a couple times uh Asian theme
Gardens were referenced as being
considered
restorative um and sometimes those that
were at a distance from the campus or
that contained a structure within it
were referenced as being considered
restorative
um so there's these are some images from
some of these Gardens including
plantations but also um spaces that have
been considered by the the people that I
spoke with as being
restorative um in terms of
programming uh five of the Guard
had programs that were about addressing
well-being um often or most all of them
were an exercise program or more of
physical health um two of those Gardens
had programs specifically for student
well-being um and plantations being one
of them and so I think there's
definitely something going on just
hasn't actually filtered down to student
students specifically yet um but there
are some developments that are happening
um The Escape program at Morris
Arboretum is is an exciting one to watch
um they have the issue of being about 10
miles away from downtown Philadelphia
the campus so enticing students to get
away and to get away from the the busy
downtown um environment um the mor are
Freedom has really um taken advantage of
different types of media to Market to
students um that this notion through the
notion of escape and it's been very
successful and offering um
transportation particularly um but this
has been a successful U example of
trying to get students out in
nature and then with working together
with Health Services only a few are have
had active conversations um again
plantations is in there and two two of
these Gardens are have had that
relationship started as a result of
student suicides that was just an
interesting one to keep aware of that
often these calamities actually promote
these conversations and would it be the
other way around that would that would
be really wonderful um that they would
be approached before these types of
events happen
um I wanted to get a more a narrower
picture besides what was happening in
public gardens in across the board so I
had a ready sample here at Cornell and I
wanted to just get some student
perspectives as opposed to
administrators of public ardens is what
I was speaking with um so I I did a few
surveys of of a variety of students I
wanted to compare um two types of
students uh ones that are focused more
on nature such as in horiculture and
then students who are notoriously not
focused on nature um engineering
students and um who actually have a
reputation at Cornell as being the most
stressed of all students um but I don't
know if that's true um so my survey um
was just a simple paper survey with
asking a variety of questions about
their level of stress uh for for one
thing and what was interesting was the
Horticulture students and
Engineers although I had about some
different numbers of how many students I
interviewed the same percentages um had
a high level of um of frequent stress so
it was basically proportional on the
kinds of stress that they were reporting
um so most of them had several times a
week uh and then another large chunk was
those who said all the time and taken
together those are about
74% and it was equal to the
engineers as well so it that was
interesting um for me to find and also I
asked about coping
strategies um eating more um sleeping
more as far as activities evolving
nature going outside spending time in
nature um these activities tended to be
more
um more likely done by horiculture
students as opposed to the engineers um
I don't know why horiculture students
were two times more likely to consume or
drink drugs and that's a little
troubling but um but it was also
interesting that they were more likely
to spend time in nature
um the I the notion of um whether nature
prescriptions I I asked students whether
they would they thought nature
prescriptions such as being prescribed
to take a walk in nature um whether that
would be an effective treatment um for
stress and for other illnesses um and
those who said that it would be very
effective um tended to rate
the the benefits of Nature and to
well-being and also the the value that
they placed on on green things on campus
they rated those areas the highest um
those who
rated uh the connection between nature
and well-being lower and also who valued
nature less actually did did not like
the idea of nature prescriptions as much
so there was a connection there um
I asked about what prevents you from
spending more time outside um Engineers
were more likely in certain areas not to
know where places were um it wasn't what
their friends were doing and just a
preference for being
indoors and then what I wanted to get
across here was that those who been who
reported that nature was was beneficial
to well-being and that campus green was
important to them um who WR when they WR
it the highest um they also that
coincided with the number of times that
they visit visited a public garden or
Cornell plantations in this case um the
ones who voted who go to plantations
every day they also valued nature the
most um and then the ones who never or
only once once a year would go into any
of the areas of
plantations uh they rated the value of
nature to well-being very low or um also
the value of of green and plants um was
rated lower the fewer times that they uh
would spend at
plantations um I wanted to find out what
might entice students to come to plant
ations more
and top being more um transportation
being offered events and activities uh
Wi-Fi um some were just you just can't
get to them so
they're and I at the end I just had
recommendations
um one being that
identifying making a case for well-being
and often getting it down and writing is
very helpful um having it in a mission
and and if it's not try to see if you
can get it in there because it it's
something everybody can work from
um trying to make a link between
academic performance and well-being um
might help this cause be uh promoted
more um because there is that concern of
being uh relevant and and often for
universities it's the academic
achievement is is the top so um showing
the the connection between how
well-being um often and how nature
experiences can really boost your
concentration and your ability to
perform um that might be a way for
Gardens to say um look at us and this is
an important thing we can do for the
organization for the University
um not only just being a garden but
coming at it with others such as health
services um Don will be telling you
about an initiative here at Cornell that
is doing this very thing um looking at
the Garden and seeing what types of
spaces it has that could be considered
restorative and really marketing those
to students
um getting ideas from other Gardens like
the Escape program at Morris or um just
taking a step um there's a Grassroots
organization called active Minds that
was started at upen um in the wake of a
student suicide and uh this group has
just grown and they do uh awareness
events at universities and it would be
interesting to have maybe host one of
those events at a public garden and get
involved in um that
conversation and just staying
open-minded um as just as a way
of being a living classroom but also um
promoting other other issues and student
well-being is a pretty important one
so um I'm gonna hand this over to Don
who will talk about nature
RX thank you Erica and I'm really
pleased to have this opportunity to talk
about an initiative with which we've
been involved for a couple of years now
in fact it was a meeting of the land
subcommittee of the president's
sustainable campus committee where
Maryann krne a professor in natural
resources David cutter the university
landscape architect and I got together
on the side and we were collectively
boning the fact that there were so few
efforts on campus to really really
encourage students to spend time
outdoors and one of us and actually I'm
not even sure at this point who it
was um had heard about an effort that a
group of progressive physicians in the
Washington DC area had started in
conjunction with the National Park
Service and that partnership led to
something called nature prescriptions in
which these Physicians were for patients
who were suffering from anxiety or
extreme stress or obesity related issues
they were actually writing prescriptions
for those individuals to spend time out
in the local national parks the
contribution by the park service was to
develop very detailed descriptions of
each of their Holdings in the greater DC
area what types of natural features were
present um how difficult the paths were
to walk on how you can access them by
car or public
transportation and this seemed to us
like a great model for transferring to
Cornell so it was at that that point
that we started to organize a group of
Faculty staff clinicians from ganette
and graduate and undergraduate students
under the theme of nature RX at Cornell
and as you can see our very simple goal
is to reduce stress and thereby increase
physical and mental health in students
through their engagement with nature and
hopefully through that engagement to
cultivate in students an increased
depreciation for nature so in the two
intervening years since we first created
this group uh we have achieved a number
of goals we've done a lot of research
we've discovered that there's a national
group that calls itself nature RX Tera
mat and um if you Google RX you will see
that they have very very funny videos
that are intended for a youth audience
when you see something beautiful and all
you can think about is Instagram filters
you may need to spend more time out in
nature and um both of the videos that
that group has developed thus far are in
that sort of light-hearted vein but with
a very serious message that we all need
to spend more time at out in
nature so we feel that in promoting
nature to students we need to focus on
some easily
graspable benefits that the time in
nature will
provide so we are talking about the need
to be active are you worried about
sluggishness time Outdoors is one of the
best predictors of being Physically
Active which can help to maintain
healthy heart healthy
weight get smarter this is something
that appeals to students are you
preparing for an exam time that you
spend in nature enhances cognitive
functioning and attention sometimes time
out in nature can be better than an hour
of cramming before a
prelim get engaged are you feeling
isolated which is as Erica was
explaining a very common cause of Stress
and Anxiety among students so find a
walking running or hiking Club research
suggests that nature is a social magnet
that draws people together and fosters
social interaction and get well and this
really is the essence of what we are
focusing on if you're feeling bad just
take a short daily walk to improve your
feeling of
well-being so in what ways are we
carrying out this nature RX approach one
that was very interesting and very
successful this past fall is that Sonia
Skelly led a firste student class called
Take It Outside in which each week uh
the student enroles were led by a
different Cornell expert
to explore one of Cornell's magnificent
natural areas in a different way we've
been working for several months on a CU
in nature app and website and very
recently we were really gratified that
the IT team at student services has
taken over the further development of
this app and website and we're going to
be very actively and heavily promoting
those and I'll talk a bit more about
that in a moment something that we're
quite excited about is that in following
up on that Washington DC model the
clinicians at Cornell Health what we
have known as ganette in the past are
now actually writing paper prescriptions
that they hand out to students that say
nature is beneficial to you we want you
to go out in nature and then they can
check boxes once a week twice a week
four times a week and um the clinicians
at ganette are very interested in
conducting a study of those students who
have received these prescriptions to see
what impact it has on them over
time we are starting to promote the
benefits of time and nature in the ways
that I was just explaining
through various media um you know I'm an
old faculty member so I don't really
know what students follow these days but
we've discovered there's something
called slope media which has both a
paper publication and an online
constantly changing website and blog so
we have an interview set up later this
week with one of the editors at slope
media we're also working with members
of the student assembly uh to get an
article in the Daily
Sun um one of the undergraduate students
that marshia IM shely worked with last
fall did a comprehensive study of every
course offered at Cornell to see which
ones are currently utilizing nature to
enhance their teaching which ones could
benefit from greater use of time
outdoors and which ones are never going
to get
outside um we are in early discussions
with faculty in the department of
communications about building a research
project around messaging of encouraging
students to spend time Outdoors to see
how different forms of messaging
different messages themselves will have
impact and uh we have a meeting this
coming Saturday in which we've invited
student representatives from
organizations across campus to come
together and to advise us on how we can
make the nature RX efforts more
effective more impactful for all of
them so one of the earliest things that
or earliest efforts in our nature RX
initiative was the development of a
campus map by David cutter our
University landscape architect in which
he pointed out some of excuse me some of
the key um natural areas on campus like
BB Lake and both uh cascadilla and Fall
Creek
Gorges that was sort of the jumping off
point for us to work with a graduate
student in information Sciences to
develop an app called CU in nature that
includes many of the natural areas that
are managed by Cornell plantations as
well as natural areas in the center of
Campus like we stinky Glenn uh tiger
Glenn and as of last week the Liberty
hiy Bailey
conservatory and here you can see uh a
couple of the pages from that app and
this IT specialist from student services
who I was mentioning is now working on
the further development of that and a
companion website so the idea here is
not to have students be studying this
app or website on their iPhones while
they're out in nature but rather to have
them become familiar with the
spectacular natural sites that exist
here at Cornell and to learn how far it
is from their dorm there's going to be a
new feature on the website in which um a
user can say how far am I from the
closest uh Natural Area right now and it
will tell how many minutes the walk is
to that site and how to get
there an effort we were involved with
this past November with president
president Beth Garrett who is in our
thoughts was also called Take It Outside
and it was a walk around BB Lake and to
the plantation's um Winter Garden for
students and members of both the Cornell
and local community and through nature
RX we anticipate running more and more
events like this simple events to just
get people at out in nature and to find
how close and how attractive and how
enjoyable it
is and this is a shot from the Take It
Outside class um that Sonia Skelly ran
this past fall here is another shot and
one of the things about getting out in
nature is that you need to do it in all
types of weather um and as you can see
the students were going down the gorge
with Sarah fiello and were uh mostly uh
prepared for that in terms of their
clothing so what I'd like to say in
wrapping this up is that we have
simultaneously both a very very highly
stressed and anxious student body and
the statistics that Erica was sharing
earlier bear those out um um the
counselors from the Caps program at
Cornell Health um counseling and
Psychological Services indicate that
between 18 and 20% of all undergraduates
seek their support each year that's an
enormous number so at the same time we
have this very stressed student body we
also have one of the most beautiful
campuses in the world I mean look at
this that that's right next to the
engineering quad so we feel that we have
this incredible opportunity to use the
natural beauty of our campus of Cornell
plantations to entice students outside
and to contribute to their overall
well-being so thank
you any questions for Erica or myself I
this kind of a weird question um so if
the the uh the stress is created under a
natural environment would pursuing
nature still be a way to release her
stress like for example this may might
not be unfamiliar to horiculture student
because sometimes we work in the in the
field or collecting s hole in the forest
for a very long that creates the
[Music]
stress you want to handle that one I
never expected that question I think
it's a great question and I think that
time in nature can um have certain
stresses associated with it one as you
point out is if you're there really
doing work in order to get that work
completed can be stressful um another is
that if you're not certain of the route
that you're following it's easy to
become stressed about finding your way
back to the starting point um and I
recall that when I was in Costa Rica
several years ago there was a program to
get um kids from within San Jose the
capital city who had spent no time in
nature to just step into woods and that
in itself was very stressful for them
because it was such an unfamiliar
environment so just becoming familiar
and comfortable with nature is often the
first step I think it's a matter of
mindfulness of what you're choosing to
focus on or moving your your attention
off of the research onto the less uh
demanding uh environment around you um
so it's a it's a choice I guess
of um letting yourself get off of one
thing the
other taking a five minute break from
data
to it seems like I mean like you were
saying it's stressful for people
sometimes who are famili you just step
into
it with it um I always I've often
thought that like incorporating kind of
identification
skills like just go hand in hand because
I always say you walk in any Urban
person or any person who doesn't spend
time walk into the kitchen and identify
everything in the kitchen and know
something's out of place yet in nature
they don't know what's safe what's not
safe the environment is safer you know
so like do you think about how maybe
to incorporate or you think that's
important
inor I think definitely the case one
study was that the natural areas the
more wild areas were not approached
because they were afraid of them or just
didn't know about them um and I think
they were trying to get at the idea of
interpretation is the answer these were
actually people took time to describe
these places to
um to actually um make them more
familiar um it would be used more and uh
also in the survey that students were
many raised that concern that they
wouldn't be safe um or they had many
different types of concern that's when
come outside so I think taking that time
to to speak to the students and and
interpret what these places are and what
they're going to find there and also
teaching them about nature learning
about what plants are the more you more
you know the more you see the more you
enjoy
so yes yeah so um it from your survey
data it seemed like there was a pretty
strong correlation between uh time spent
out the words and appreciation of nature
is that causational is it a chick of the
neck thing like do you love nature
because you spend time Outdoors or the
other way around or do they both kind of
feed back into each other that's a
really good question I I to think about
that a lot um I I think what I was
trying to at least argue was that um the
more
of if if a love of nature can be
established then there'll be a greater
use of it um and so as far as which
causes which I don't know sometimes for
some it might be greater knowledge and
hence be more familiar with something um
creates that that love and enjoyment of
nature um for others it might be that
love draws them to to want to learn more
about it um so I think it is a give and
take and I I don't don't know the answer
to that
question yes yes Geneva any
questions
Al no question from okay thanks take one
more yeah we'll take one more question
Phil um Erica do do you think that
getting getting back to the question
that being out in in a Wilder area might
be stressful do you think that that
could be an example of how important it
is having smaller uh more control old
Gardens on a campus could be truly
beneficial a small garden where you're
not going to get lost a small garden
that is
obviously manmade construction close to
your building but still would have the
benefit of being around trees being
around pants for this 5 P absolutely and
I think there really isn't at least some
of the data was trying to show that it
didn't matter if it was Urban nature or
more rural nature just any amount of
green really was beneficial so
taking it in more bite-sized pieces
definitely places right around building
seem to be very popular and so easy to
get to that um I think the ease of
access is a huge Factor so
um yeah definitely there's a value to
these smaller spaces and hopefully
campuses can maybe U keep cultivating
them and
yeah thank you America
[Applause]
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu