this is a production of Cornell
University um as Matt said um I'm a
professor at the University of Wisconsin
Madison um I've been working with um
organic agriculture for over 20 years
now I actually started my career down in
Mexico State University um and uh really
struck me the the role of organic in
terms of building um regenerative act
systems and and addressing many of the
challenges we face not only as a nation
but globally in terms of um having a
healthy nutritious food supply um
supporting Farmers U supporting small
family Farmers supporting beginning
farmers and supporting soil Health um
organic is all about soil Health um it's
all about um building our soil uh
improving our soil resources and truly
is the first regen of Agriculture um so
as we look at at uh maintaining and and
forwarding uh organic practices it's
it's all grounded in regenerative
agriculture um so I've been working in
organic no tail since that first time in
New Mexico um looking at how we create
systems that can help preserve our soil
build our soil so that's been over um 20
years now and have learned a lot in the
process uh still a lot to learn very
exciting to continue to do the research
um Matt said a lot of the research that
we have been doing is in partnership
with Cornell University here in New York
and for those of you that don't know
Wisconsin um T to be considered a Fly
Over States I don't know how many of you
familiar with Wisconsin versus the
Cornel there's a lot of similarities to
the agriculture in New York um we we
have hiler Landscapes uh a lot of
organic farmers are farming Bridges and
valleys a very diverse agiculture
smaller Farms I have organic daies and
organic vegetables organic gra Farms and
New York and Wisconsin always tend to be
competing for that second place or first
place position in terms of number of
organic farms and number of dollars from
organic ring and dairy farms we always
joging for that leadership position we
won't talk about California you don't
know
but so the that I presented um I think
it's really relevant to York as well and
that certainly good context
talk I think the biggest difference in
Wisconsin fing rocks like you guys
so we don't have many rocks but in terms
of size of arm resources we have and
even environment really really um have
to give credit this presentation was
actually made by my research scientist
Ben Rock so super grateful to Ben and
all the work he's done with data
analysis and just want to give them a
huge amount of credit for Ping together
um all right so starting with uh organic
no till soy and just want to stress as
well um a lot of my work is in organic
noil I think it has a really strong
place as we look forward not only to
organic grains but looking at other
organic feeds uh and livestock
production as well as organic vegetables
but I I certainly am not promoting
organic no as with silver bullet um many
many long-term studies that have
compared organic and conventional side
by side and as I mentioned organic truly
is is um regenerate agiculture the first
regenerate agriculture even with um
judicious tillage that integration of
crop diversity and cover crops Organic
Farms still are building soil organic
matter so I don't want to demonize
tillage I think there's a place for
tillage I think strategic tillage is
important I think we can have very very
good um Organic Farms that are
stewarding the soil with tillage it's
all tillage is part of the system and
organic no till should be considered as
part of system um and when you look at
designing rotations and how do you build
these different ecological tools
together to create a system that we can
lower inputs um we can be building
nitrogen on the farm we can be um
lowering our need for um different
insecticides or other aspects even
organic certified it's all about
building the system so thinking about
organic noil that is part of the system
so I first started working in organic
noil soybeans
um yeah it's SP about 20 years ago now
um and had the opportunity to work with
Jeff Moyer so learned a lot from The
rodale Institute and but they have been
doing in terms of pioneering this Techni
um over the past 20 years I think we
have a lot of success in the organic
soybean system I think I wouldn't say we
haven't dialed in I don't know if
anything organic can be dialed in
because the eological nature of the
system but this is a system that's
workable and we do have more and more
examples of farms that are making this
work as part of their uh soybean
approach on their farm and looking at
Market opportunities in terms of organic
grains we're still importing um the
majority of organic soy beans and I know
that in Wisconsin at least Farmers AR
organic farmers aren't thrilled about
organic soybeans but it is a sector of
the organic grain market that there is
opportunity for grow there is
opportunity for more domestic production
so looking at these different tools to
make organic SBE production more
feasible um is also important so the
system with Organic um noil sway beans
the first step is Ry establishment so we
typically are using a winter anual
serial grain as the tool for me
management winter Annual Ride tends to
be um the most consistent performer in
terms of winterial bra it produces a lot
of biomass um over Winters well and
tends to I I think a bit more AL C in
system that can also help with
Le one of the the key aspects of this
system is this planting date for the and
as we see how this system has failed on
farms where farmers are seeing issues
often times it is tied to this first
step if you look at that first step
right that the system is is going to um
have a high risk of failure so this
first step of planting that ride on time
um in Wisconsin and New York I would
push it past mid-september so this
really requires to be successful of
redesign of the system more broadly
often times in Wisconsin organic grain
farmers are planted to after corn maybe
you could get a ro planed day
mid-september if you're coming in after
corn silage but typically to get that
early planting day you need to think
about redesigning the system including
winter annuals are summer cere summer
cereal grains other lero cereal grains
and finding something that can be
harvested so that we can Target this
mid-september planning date um the other
key um two other keys in terms of what
to look for to make this system
successful at this early step is to go
into a field that has the right weed
pressure so um this is not a clean up
method in fields so it's not a way that
we can clean up Le fields and it also is
not the best method for suppressing FAL
we so thisle quack WS so targeting which
field you're going to try organic noil
and choosing fields that don't have
excessively High be pressure and that
aren't struggling with uh perennial GS
the other part in this uh First Step
that is key is a seeding rate so we're
not using a seeding rate for a typical
Ry cover CR coming in after corn which
is maybe a bushel Bush and a half foot
acre we needed to bump this up to get
the ground cover and the biomass needed
to suppress we that's usually around the
three B an acre range so investing in
that higher seating rate is going to pay
off in terms of weed suppression later
so three key aspects of this early step
that's going to set you up for Success
the ride winter start growing again May
and we want to terminate at the stage so
you can see where the the flowers are
coming off the r heads um you can run
your hand across the RADS and see the
yellow pollen sometimes when you're
roller thing there's clouds of pollen
that will come tractor driving over the
field heard stories about it actually
clogging the tractor um but that's the
stage we're targeting going into early
you're not going to be able to get the
mechanical termination of Ry that's
going to for that Ry at going into late
um you're going to potentially have
issues with viable rice seed which
especially is an issue of you're growing
other serial grains within the rotation
especially food Great Grains but I've
even heard of feed grade grains having
issues with some of that bi will rise
causing contamination in
that so typically um this stage in
thesis we seeing the ride flower heads
um that's going to occur on Memorial Day
um June 4th um so that's we're targeting
for mechanical termination of the ride
and the planting dat of soy so early
June um and this is not an uncommon
photo this is a photo of our um research
field at Arlington Wisconsin so South
Central
that Ryan mat does an excellent job
suppressing weeds so we don't have to go
through and do
cultivation uh the ride takes care of
the weed management we can roll the ride
plant it and then let it go for the
season um and then um harvest in October
this system does push back maturity so
um it does require to be ready to
harvest in late October early November
be able to reach um right stage of SoBe
so different sorts of roller we've tried
we've tried the roil model which many of
you may have seen and associated with
this this is a model that is
manufactured by more local machine
manufacturer in sou Central Wisconsin
but lots of different options in terms
of r as well we haven't seen a huge
difference in terms of performance I
think it um really there's there's
options that that work
Parkers so why organic noil um it is
something as we're seeing more extreme
weather seeing more heavy rain events um
it's important as a mitigation tool for
soil loss so um in the Upper Midwest the
corn Bel on average we've lost a third
of our top soil and that top soil is is
very very difficult to regain um we
certainly can build soil organic matter
within organic systems but to regain
this degree of top soil will take um
decades if not centuries so it's an
important resource that we need to very
aware in terms of our management is
affecting the maintenance of that
resource um and how we can protect
it uh so these are some pictures that
we've seen in terms of some Top Soil
loss with some recent Heavy Rain events
you can see without that soil covered
how that um this surface erosion of the
soil versus if you have that dry mat how
that protects and mitigates impacts of
those heavy rains keeps that soil in
place and also help maintain soil
moisture through throughout the growing
season by um essentially acting as a
barrier prevent evaporation improving
the soil as well um some other examples
um within our uh in our field of where
there's the open ground um seeing where
there's visible signs of erosion versus
in organic noil where you um have that
so protected so you can see the
treatment side by side and how that soil
is actually washing and being stopped by
the organic
treatments uh so it does also help from
a labor perspective and from the grand
Farmers I work with that utilize this
technique it's often not all their
organic soybean Acres but some of their
organic soybean Acres because it helps
spread out the labor and especially in
Seasons like this past season in
Wisconsin where just we were hammered
with rain so to find those windows you
can get out and cultivate was near
impossible and by having a certain
degree of a that you don't have to
cultivate it allows you to more
effectively manage those Acres that you
do need to cultivate so in a typical
tillage base system in Wisconsin we
typically have two to three pre-plant
Sage passes and then up to three to five
U weed management passes after planting
with our blind cultivation time meeting
and rotary hoing and our road
cultivation this uh cover mul system
this organic no system basically cuts
out all that for um pre-plant tillage as
well
so a lot of trips off across the field
and this is where a lot of the economics
um pay off is less labor um less lar and
tear on your equipment less passes over
the field um so less fuel costs um and
timly think about
mitigating by eliminating that degree of
passes over the Feld also beneficial
that way so again you know look at the
cost of the system and how the economics
play off by having the labor and fuel
cost reduced by 50% um that that
definitely shows up in POS
book uh so yields and this is where
again there's risk in the system that I
think when we look at how this is
actually executed on farms to have it
more Diversified in terms of the
approach and maybe not having all your
agas of organic noil is smart as we see
more unpredictable weather patterns Happ
year so um this is over the past decade
that we've been doing organic noil 've
been doing it longer just showing the
last few years of data um these are the
yields per acre green bars are no till
um blue bars are killed so you can see
we're typically averaging between 40 and
65 which an acre um in those two systems
and when we look at this um black line
that is precipitation the amount of
rainfall in inches um that is uh we're
seeing during the growing season um you
you can see that when we have less
rainfall when this bar is is lower
that's where you see more of a
difference between those two lines so in
years we have sufficient precipitation
like in 2024 we can actually exceed the
uh yield of traditional conventional
organic soybeans because we have that
weed management tool in place we're not
struggling with getting up and
cultivating during the um the wet
weather
um and we're we're having a system where
we can better manage weeds so when you
see as when these flat bars at its uh
high points there's very little yield
difference but where the system breaks
down where there RIS is in those
extremely dry years because the Ry
essentially acts like a straw and sucks
up a lot of that soil soil moisture and
planting into a dry situation within the
r Ry soy definitely struggle so by
having some Acres in traditional organic
soybeans that are cultivated and some in
organic noil you can kind of buffer
against some of this uncertainty in
terms of weather
patterns so profitability um looking at
profitability system these are some um
kind of badly envelope numbers that have
been put together comparing the organic
noil system some the costs in terms of
the different field operations as well
as different inputs in terms of seed
assuming that even an organic F
operation typically going to be putting
in some R cover crop but at that lower
seaing rate so because of the fact we do
field passes and lower variable costs um
particularly in terms of um some of the
SE costs and some of the passes over the
field that uh we can see that although
there's tight margins that if we can
close that yeld Gap that organic no til
perform organic based systems with
respect to the economics of this system
uh so looking at um you know where does
that pay off if we can get the uh yield
um within about uh five bu an acre we
typically see the economics of the
system paying
off so um one of the things I've ended
this summer which was super exciting is
to see how the practices that we've been
researching at our research station
actually translate onto Farms often
times we do at the research station I
criticized of working in a little bit of
a bubble uh we might not be seeing the
realities of of what's happening in
organic farm so B went out to organic
farms that were using organic noil to
try to understand what farmers were
doing with Organic noil what challenges
that farmers were facing with the um
implementation of the system and to see
if there's any trends that we're seeing
across the farm sites that are using
this system so he did this across a mul
state area um in the other West he
looked at Ry management s Management the
equipment that farmers were using and
collected arrang of data looking at soil
nutrients biomass weed biomass and soil
standing y or so standing
yield um so what he found um so farmers
that were using this he he uh went to
about 14 Farms so proceeding prop like I
mentioned prop rotation is one of the
trickier aspects of the system of dial
in you have to think of as a system and
what you're going to be planting before
the soybeans what he was Finding was
that most of the Farms were using some
sort of Cal brain that they were
harvesting as a cash FR many of them
were coming in following theat barley
was another one o um in Wisconsin where
we can get some really high yelding porn
varieties for silage that we can get off
earlier one Farm was using um porn
silage as a proceeding prop and only one
was using porn for brain but having the
serial grains as a proceeding propop
allow for the Farms that were using the
system to get and hit that early
planting day for the ride so the vast
majority with this rotation were hitting
that early September planting date um a
couple of them were pushing out further
uh but also um they were also able to
get that higher VI rate to make the
system work the r varieties they were
using and Gardener and arusip are both
some earlier um maturing varieties so
varieties that are a little bit more
adapted to the system so they can get
that earlier termination date and many
of them were also applying manure before
Ry and I think this is also an important
part of the success is having adequate
fertility for that Ry cover prop to get
the biomass youed for we supression so
the vast majority were treating that rye
as a CR and adding some fertility um
prior to
planting um many of them were planed
before um crimping so this doesn't mean
planting weeks earlier before crimping
but instead essentially going over the
field twice going through the standing
ride to plant the soybeans which helps
facilitate with seed to soil contact
because you're not having to get the
planter through that thick Ry Mulch and
then coming in and crimping right
afterwards there were a couple that were
crimping first and trying to plant
through that mul the vast majority were
planting first and then crimping so
planting da um kind of that range in
that late latter part of um May to the
early part of June um those that were
doing in mid May probably were using the
technique where they're planting around
the boot stage of Ry and then letting
the soybeans germinate and then cring
over that s speeding rates and this is
reflective of some really great research
coming out of Cornell is that in this
system going to the heavier s seeding
race is also important for the success
and resilience of the system to even
going up to about 240,000 seats per acre
many of them most of them were on 30ish
rows a couple of them were on narrow
roow spacing um and and about half of
them or more we're doing some inseason
weed management to help manage some exag
in
sy so looking at the performance
um many of them were targeting the B
majority we targeting um or being able
to achieve the the Ry biomass that we
need to make the system work which is
about 8,000 pounds per acre so having
those earli your planting days that
fertility uh and that heavier Ry seeding
rate was working in their favor and they
getting the Ry VI expression um some of
the Farms were struggling with um weed
suppression as evidenced by this higher
number but most of them were getting
decent weed suppression uh and a range
of different swaying stands so some of
them were struggling a bit with getting
that good seat to so contact and getting
so stand but the so yields 46 Bush an
acre we can that a pretty decent soy
yield in respon so uh farmers were
having success in this system the
farmers that were serving Farmers that
were visited um we're having um success
in terms of getting good biomas getting
good meat suppression and getting good
soybean so it's really exciting to see
that the systems that we've been working
so hard to research at Wisconsin and and
Corell
we we're seen in terms of success in the
FI so photograph of the differences so
here we can see a high biomass R feel
and just you know what a difference
having that heavy Ry biomass where you
can't see any soil vers inadequate
biomass and just how many weeds are
breaking through so visual demonstration
of how important setting up the system
for the high biomasses and then looking
at the inconsistencies and stands so
having this excellent sing stand um
paying attention to planting a planter
set up paying attention to being able to
get that seed in the ground versus the
inconsist
plant so Ry biomass and this is
something we see in our research as well
was the most important predictor for
Success so dialing in the system getting
choosing your Fields getting the riding
early um getting that rideing rate
correct that's what the most important
as ECT of having this work on your farm
um increases in Ry biomass tended to
decrease weed biomass if Ry biomass
increased soybean yield increased and
the soybean yield was strongly
correlated to weed biomass um and this
we see in the tilled system as well if
we don't get our weed management dialed
in that's when our geals are going to
suffer weed biomass was dominated by a
few species so these are species that we
struggle with in the Upper Midwest giant
rag weed giant fox tail um that's been a
really persistent issue in recent years
for a lot of grain Farmers as well as
yellil PL set up um really keyed in this
system to make it work um soybean
emergence is a challenge with increasing
Ry biomass we need that Ry biomass to
get the weed suppression does make
planting a
challenge so this is what we might see
if we PR first and don't have a plum set
up we have seeds that are resting on
that Ry bio mass and those seeds are
going to not germinate and contribute to
those stands so some setup
considerations if you're going to do
this um want to have the ability to cut
and navigate through the Rye residue to
open the furrow and reduce that hair
pinning where that um Rye is essentially
just put pushed into the planum row have
sufficient down pressure to push through
the M layer and place seed in the probia
depth and we want to have the ability to
to close us throw so we've done a lot of
research with a engineer Ryan luck and
see how we can overcome these issues so
looked at different um down pressures
different seaing rates still on a little
bit on the low side but a range of
seating rates as well as different Cults
and buring wheels and from what we've
seen um how that translates into yield
again to remind you if there's different
letters following values it means that
there uh statistically significantly
different um so that we can have
confidence that yes these treatments are
uh having effect on what we're measuring
and what we saw was that again when
we're looking at what to do with the
soybean planting phase to make this work
bumping up your seeding rates will um
translate into higher yields a down
pressure we did see a numerical
difference but not a significant
difference between the down pressures um
and as well as filter versus no filter
in this study um as been as closing whe
as well so the higher seaing rate is
improving plant stand and grain yield
higher down pressure and colding use
seem to um improve this plant stand but
that didn't translate into
yield um some relationship between
soybean emerges and grain yield from our
research stations um the research
stations uh at Arlington research
station in Arlington we can get really
high wi bi Ms um and that is
um it's it's a definitely a challenge in
terms of getting the soybean established
so soyum convergence translated into
brain yield Within These locations R
biomasses exceeding 10,000 pounds per
acre had lower sood emergence stronger
relationship to grain yield so this
indicates potentially that the yield Gap
could be overcome by
Emer so this pter style matter this is
some of the research we were doing with
uh Dr lock looking at what the waviness
how that W SE placement soing um plant
down so looked at several different
pters straight versus Ripple versus 13
wave versus eight wve versus no fter um
and what we found was that the results
differed per year so having U the
environmental conditions um that's going
to affect the degree of difference you
see with these different fers uh in um
2023 versus 224 you can see 2023 was an
extremely dry year versus last year we
had more steady rainfall particularly
early in the
season what we did find overall though
was that in with the planting set
planter set up in this system using
Straight cters um was was beneficial in
terms of being able to get um a good c
contact and plant stand um and that hair
pitting was significantly reduced so
setting up your plant of these systems
using Straight Edge cters is beneficial
we also found that the straight edge
culturs were beneficial in terms of um
uh having um reduced we pressure within
that Landing row so strage cultures have
several benefits with respect to the
system and how this translates into
brain yield um we did not see a
difference in terms of brain yield um
but in terms of again the weak
suppression and the
stand so I'm going to turn now for the
rest of my um talk and talk about some
of the research with reduced kill core
whereas and again we saw this translated
into the with the um on Farm study we
did organic no till soybeans is
definitely a system that can work if
you're planning how to plant this the
the ride how do you design a rotation
getting the planter set up um dialed in
organic noil soybeans are a viable and
profitable system for GRE Farmers
organic produced tot corn is something
that um I would say is not quite ready
for prime time at this point there's a
lot of exciting research a lot of
exciting promise and we're hearing more
stories of farmers that are seeing some
degree of success um if anyone would
want to try organic noil corn I would
recommend doing it on a very very small
scale just see how it works on your farm
two to 10 acres this is absolutely not
something that would do over a
significant number of Acres uh we've
tried a couple different approaches to
organic noil corn um roller crimping and
a living M system so roll pring more
mirroring what we're doing with the
soybeans using a winter annual cover CR
planted in the fall and then terminating
that mechanically in the spring living
mold systems um looking into using a
legume whether it be bread Clover other
clovers around F and using different
ways of suppressing that living mulch
that that um leg you that's been planted
um previous year or previous years
before the POR phase um and uh
essentially manage ing um that mulch to
limit competition with the
corn so in the roller G system we're
typically using R and VCH both winter
annuals um the benefits um these systems
tend to be more weed suppressive so we
get um more of that weed control aspect
of the system that we're looking for the
cover crop terminates so we can
mechanically terminate this and will
stay as a killed mulch so there's no
competition with nutrients and water
while the soy beans are growing a vet if
we can over winter vet consistently get
the bounts we need ve can supply a
significant amount of nitrogen to the
system which is a limiting factor in
terms of cor productivity Within These
noell systems um and higher yield
potential so far um as evidenced in a
research trial so it's it's a bit more
consistent in terms of the performance
of the syone um risks they do require a
later plan dat of the Corn um Ry can be
a a reservoir for um or a host for army
worms so there's more insect pressure
Within These systems um hardiness of veg
seed uh so that seed can have um
persistence across multiple Seasons so
it doesn't all germinate the first year
of planting and if there's Escapes in
terms of the V seed that can be
persistent in subsequent phas of the
prop ration and whereas the V can
produce a lot of nitrogen it's not
necessarily available when the corn
needs it so that can be a challenge as
well um the living M system uh planting
dates are not as dependent so
potentially because we're not waiting
for a stage of crop maturity for
mechanical termination so flowering for
both um Andis for rye as well as a
flowering early qus at for vet we can
theoretically come in as early as early
May and plant into these living Mo
systems are is less of a concern our is
not as attracted to legumes as it is to
grasses um less hard seediness uh have
that as concerned of persistence into
subsequent phases and an opportunity to
utilize that cover crop as of forage so
in our Dairy systems this could be a
very attractive option as a way to raise
or develop alternative forages or even
come in after not f stand risks um there
a lot more competition in these symptoms
because that are prods acely growing um
not as much contribution because that
nitrogen that's being fixed by the legum
is being used by the legum itself more
variability in yield um and inro control
can be an
issue uh some of the yields that we've
seen so we've been trying these from uh
less years
than so we have a good five or six years
under our B systems some of the light of
be we used um r Clover and aala and
yellow Blossom Sweet Clover so this is
where um there's promise but there's
still work to be done so if you see the
yield on that y AIS um you can have
yields as low as 50 bu in AC but in some
years in some systems we can see yields
reaching 150 and we've even gotten
closer to 180 in some of these systems
so in certain spots in the field so
there is evidence that there's potential
to these systems we can understand how
to dial it in what we need in terms of
reducing competition and management I
still hold that there is a way to to
utilize these systems to reduce form the
roller Qui systems um kind of see that
similar variability in Yi r v next we
can see yields of porn anywhere from
about 60 bu an acre up to 150 and even a
little bit higher if we're using just
straight hairy Veges the RO
so is this ready for on Farm adoption
not sure but really looking forward to
continuing this research in partnership
with farmers and cover crop breeders to
see how can we make that yield of 150 to
180 um so some of our experiments I know
I'm getting very very close to time um
looking at comparing different
management tools and management
intensities of the cover CRS um so a
baseline uh using a free man applic
planting red clover in mid August um we
are doing different ways of kind of
strip tilling or modified strip toing so
Trying to minimize competition within
the planting Road form and getting good
stand establishment and one of the
things in the system that I think we can
also look at more closely is the
genetics I think genetics adaptation
genetics to these systems are going to
be key I want to you know just have that
point out that with that 150 bu and acre
yield we using very very short season
varieties of porn so maybe it's not
surprising that yield potential is less
um for in season management looking at
fertility applications at planting
making sure there's adequate nitrogen
and then some management of cover prop
uh so different tools we're using under
Cutters to make those rows um different
ways suppressing through flame weeding
roller pring High cultivation so um just
looking at some yield of these systems
undercutting looking at strip tilling or
clearing a planting Ro for the corn I
think that's going to be key these uh
yields are in B per hect there but you
can see with the um undercutting we do
see a significantly higher yield um
plane meeting um we did see a trend
towards um higher yields with the plane
weeding as well um that we supression
and looking at um Indo ging high res
cultivation um seeing a less of a um
impact those
[Music]
tools um but we did see a Trends towards
lower plant P cultivation so risk of
impacting the stand there um this is
some newer research we've done I'll wrap
up with this um using a forage Harvester
to manage alala um and using some other
strip tillage tools as well as the in
mower so crop management here R Clover
seeded in August um we do some Harvest
utilizing that um as a as a crop um as
well as a living mulch strip tilling in
late May planing that short season corn
doing some inner row mowing to help with
mitigated competition um at a couple
different stages V2 and4 so what we're
finding here um is that using some of
these um competition mitigation tools uh
we are seeing some benefit particular
IND um looking at what the potential
nitrogen competition is or an uptake of
the porn so it does look like if we can
mitigate some of that competition it
could be valuable um both within the red
clover and Al ala systems um looking at
cord yields so this is where um
particularly um you know looking at the
in R mower as a way to um help improve
some of the corn yields by mitigating
that competition so yields here not
great um but we are seeing some impacts
on management and definitely some
promising results terms of getting the
yields that that would be considered um
acceptable so um just want to thank the
organizers of the event thank you all
for uh coming to our event want to point
out our website we have a great website
with a lot of tools um lots of past
videos lots of different resources case
studies um we also have a link to a list
serve that we have that facilitates
farmer to Farmer communication um just
again a huge thank you to Ben Brock
Miller putting together um this slide
said and to just the the Silva and Ryan
lab team members in general for all
their work with u developing these
research This research over the last
several decades so thank you uh question
in the back there yes what's
theing when you plant do this standing
right yeah so planting it's the so with
the standing rise system there's two
ways that farmers are doing it one is
essentially planting into the standing
Ry at anesis and crimping right over it
so it's done on the same day or within
24 hours um it's just planting into the
standing ride to get better seed disil
contact in some of our research that we
did with trying to um boost the uh
earliness of the soybean planting date
what we're typically targeting in that
system is is getting the soybeans uh
planted and then to um about the um the
the the first true Lea stage so about
the V1 so we don't want to plant in
there too early so we're usually coming
in um around May 15th which is is
usually around the boot stage of Ry um
and we don't crimp right away so we'll
go into the standing Rye plant that boot
stage um that rye will continue to
mature the soybeans will come up in that
standing rye and then will roll over the
soybeans at that that early stage of
maturity if we push it too much earlier
into May the soybeans um they're kind of
star for sunlight under that rye canopy
and they can get really leggy and
damaged but if we do it about two weeks
before an thesis um we do see some stand
loss uh but we have had years where
where that is advantageous in terms of
the final yield um Farmers have had
mixed success we've had mixed success I
don't necessarily see enough benefit of
that earlier planting date and criming
over the soybeans to justify that I
think it's a lower risk system to just
plant it and and crimp it in a thesis
but it isn't it is an
option is that curiosity what is your
plan rate on your soybeans that you ran
for these tests here and what was the
size of the soybeans yes that's the size
of the soyan I am not sure um we're
going at a lower seaing rate that I
think is ideal particularly with some of
the research that's been done at Cornell
University so in these trials we're
we're usually I think at about 225 but I
think bumping it up and Matt can give
his opinion to 240 is probably a sound
of recommendation 225 is already much
better than um what's recommended in
conventional production I think you know
we've seen uh that yeah higher rates do
pay but yeah 225 to 240 is kind of where
we're seeing our uh the maximum or the
uh greatest economic return then yeah
we're usually like at a 1.6 1.8 maturity
group but I'm not sure what the seed
that's like really but that's I think
variety trialing these systems and
understanding the impacts of seed size
and canopy and um other factors is
something we haven't touched upon yet
thank
you was there any assessments on on the
Cosmetic nature of the soybeans they're
suitable for their Island Market I have
not heard and in CL might have more
experience there I have not heard issues
with well you sorry Peter take me a
while to connect there we haven't seen
an issue um we haven't seen an issue
with staining but good point sorry for
that just it took me a while to CLI
there so you've had seen you guys have
seen issues with uh yeah okay
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu