this is a production of Cornell
[Applause]
University all right well good morning
uh it's great to be back uh again after
almost a year away uh this morning uh
I'll be sharing some of the highlights
of the work uh that I've done as a PhD
student over the last six years uh these
are I'll be covering three different
projects that uh are fairly unrelated uh
the first two in a little more depth
than the last one just very briefly um
specifically I'll be talking about the
progress that we've done to uh develop
cucumbers with resistance to Downey
mildew which is the uh most widespread
and devastating disease on cucumbers uh
in the US and around the world uh then
I'll be sharing some of the work we've
been we've done to uh map the major
powdery mildew resistance Locus and
squash which is one of the most widely
used genes uh in squash breeding but uh
which to date uh didn't have any markers
available for it uh and last lastly uh
I'll briefly talk about a collaborative
effort we've been doing with the USDA uh
to develop some genomic resources for an
important USDA uh PE core collection
that's used by uh PE breeders not only
uh in North America but around the
world so uh first off I'll talk about uh
the work we've done in cucumbers uh I
was really got involved in this project
from day one uh and this project was
started uh in response to an urgent need
from the Cucumber industry uh to solve a
new disease crisis and I say new not
because Downey milde is new in cucumbers
because uh it had been around since the
1800s but uh for many decades Growers
had never really had to worry about dowy
Milo at all uh and that's in large part
thanks to the efforts of breeders here
at Cornell and um Wisconsin and Clemson
and some other places at really
developing uh robust disease resistance
packages in cucumber uh including to
Downey
mildew well that all Came Crashing Down
uh right around 2000 6 uh and you can
see from this headline in the American
vegetable grower magazine an old enemy
reemerges uh suddenly Growers were
seeing what to many of them was almost a
new disease uh many were not uh really
sure what it was um but it came in a
very quick and dramatic fashion uh so
here you can see some of the symptoms of
Downey mildew on cucumbers uh Downey
milu uh you'll often see Downey Milo
first uh characterized by angular
chlorotic lesions it's a folar disease
so you see it on the leaves and and
those uh chlorotic areas eventually
coales and turn necrotic until you have
total plant death and the time that you
first see a chotic lesion on one leaf of
a plant to the time it's completely dead
and crispy uh can be as little as 3
weeks without any sort of intervention
so uh it happens uh really really really
quickly and uh in 2006 alone uh it it
was just caused devastating production
losses individual states were reporting
losses and tens of millions of dollars
and you know that's a pretty big deal
considering the total production value
uh in the US is around $350
million so uh another reason this was uh
such uh a bad disease was that uh Donnie
Milo was present is is aerially
dispersed uh by asexual zoospores it's
an old my seat and uh it can travel for
hundreds of miles so uh in the time in
the 3-we span that your plant is dying
uh the pathogen can uh reproduce from an
initial Spore Landing to to producing
millions of spores in 10 days those can
travel to nearby plants nearby farms and
uh if the wind is Right hundreds or even
thousands of miles away in some cases
and it's not a pathogen that over
winners um in cold places but it will
over winter in um Southern Florida where
they don't have a frost and it marches
up the coast uh as spring temperatures
get warmer uh which also happens to
coincide when people are planting their
cucumbers and uh 90% of cucumber
production is in eastern states in kind
of this area where you see um the Downey
Milo and and to give you an idea all of
these green and blue spots are uh areas
that at one time or another throughout
the season uh reported dowy mil do and
these are just the areas where it's
reported uh pretty much you can fill in
that whole map in the eastern US of
where the disease actually was but um
for uh 90% of production in eastern
states of pickling cucumbers Michigan is
a big place uh in Florida North Carolina
and Wisconsin are important and for
slicers Florida Georgia and North
Carolina so these places get dowy M do
extremely early in the season uh in the
in the North Atlantic area and the Great
Lakes region uh where we are uh we also
have a onew punch not only from disease
coming up from the South but also from
green houses and hot houses that have
cucumber production all year
round so there's really no escaping this
disease if you grow cucumbers you will
have Donnie mildew on your
cucumbers so not surprisingly uh in 2008
there was a survey uh from basically for
basically everybody involved in the
Cucumber industry and one of the
questions was what can public research
institutions do and not surprisingly uh
Downey M do research was ranked the
number one priority um we need to find
fungicides we need to develop resistance
we need to develop forecasting protocols
anything related to Downey mildew so in
response to that uh we started a
breeding program uh the first thing we
had to figure out was is there any sort
of acceptable resistance out there right
now so uh and and this was the year
before I joined so I can't take credit
for this but um Michael and company
started this uh effort with uh looking
at USDA accessions looking at heirlooms
uh going back into the Cornell seed
voles pulling out old lines that at one
time uh were reported to have dowy maer
resistance and just growing really as
many things as we could uh with as many
tips and as much data as we could um uh
dig up and what we found was that there
were no Cult of ours that had uh
what would even approach acceptable
levels of resistance but we did find a
few um old varieties air looms and some
of the lines that had been developed at
Cornell in the past that had um more
resistance than none they might hold on
a week two weeks three weeks longer than
the most susceptible cultivar so we
decided that was the point where we were
going to start we were going to start
Crossing some of those together and see
uh if we could develop anything with
Superior
resistance and as as 2010 uh we had
great promise so this is an F2
population of a cross between two of
those uh moderately resistant lines and
most things out in the field were dead
but every once in a while we came across
a plant that uh looked pretty good now
in this season uh we weren't to a point
yet where we had great resistance
everything died by the end of the season
but uh you can you can clearly see
there's there's a difference there and
uh when we grew out the parents uh
individuals did much better than the
parents which indicated to us that we
were actually combining genes from these
various sources so uh we were on the
right
track so our general breeding strategy
from that point forward was basically to
plant large populations into heavy
pathogen pressure in this area Downey
mildew comes in or the dowy mildew
pathogen I should say comes in uh Late
July early August so that's when we
wanted to plant um and we wanted to
plant young plants in the field so that
when we were doing disease ratings we
didn't have to worry about any
complicating effects from natural plants
in essence you know if a plant was
turning necrotic dying we knew it was
from Downey
mildew uh we harvested fruit regularly
uh so that we didn't have any fruit load
effects compounding uh resistance we
piled them by the plant so that we could
get you know a rough plant-by-plant
yield estimate uh we would flag early
selections we had harsh selection
intensity at the beginning of the
program uh the pathogen really did all
the the work for us you know there
wasn't there weren't many things alive
at the end of the season as we uh
increased the frequency of resistance LS
in our population we got to the point
where everything was surviving to the
end of the season so we uh continued to
select the best of the best and we we
did all phenotypic selection uh and
found that the Downey M resistance was
highly heritable and that our phenotypic
values were very predictive of the
breeding value uh and the performance of
the uh line in future
years we took cuttings uh there was
simply no time for pollinations in the
field before Frost so we would take uh
cuting from the field and bring them
into the greenhouse to advance the
generations uh which was very easily
done with cucumbers you just slice off a
growing tip stick it in some media make
sure it stays warm and moist and you can
have 90% rooting uh or even
better and at first we did uh a pedigree
selection approach as is very common in
cuc C breeding programs but then added a
recurrent selection approach with some
intermating in the greenhouse which uh
we needed to capture and retain all of
the resistance alals that we were
bringing in together um because there
was just too many to capture with
moderate size populations uh in the
field so by 2012 we had some lines that
we were ready to trial uh up top is DMR
n264 which was our uh top uh breeding
line and below it are the two parents so
uh 264 stayed green uh all the way till
Frost produced fruit all the way till
Frost uh you can see here that it was
doing better than its parents which
would eventually die uh in the course of
the season and all this compared with
one of our susceptible checks uh
piccalino which uh died almost right out
of the gate and this is very uh typical
of a lot of cultivars that Growers were
growing you just whisper the words dowy
mil do and they you know
Wilt um here is 264 again with uh two
cultivars that were identified in um the
late 2000s so uh some folks at North
Carolina did some trials to figure out
uh were was there any resistance in
cultivars they included over 80
cultivars that uh Growers were commonly
using at the time or were historically
important and these two
uh made it to the top of the list so uh
this was the most resistant single-ear
multi-state cultivar and this was the
most resistant multi-year multi-state
cultivar so uh as you can see they're
not very good uh to to Really highlight
that uh there were no uh options for
Growers uh at this time so and I should
say in the trial these were not reported
to be very good either they were just
the best of the worst um you know they
they acknowledg that yeah these aren't
very good but you know they might
survive a week
longer we also included uh they did
another study uh looking at all the USDA
accessions and there was one that stood
out uh this Pi 19788 that we also
included in our trial and it it held up
pretty well uh it had very similar
levels of resistance to some of our top
lines um but resistance is about the
only thing you can say for it uh it's a
wild accession that was collected in
India um as far as I know nobody really
eats it or would want to it's this very
uh netted Hollow bitter fruit that is on
a plant that has a lot of sticky sap and
is highly male and is late to flower so
um it has a lot of really negative uh
agronomic and Horticultural
characteristics that uh we didn't have
to deal with by not using it uh right
the
gate so one thing we were really
interested in is uh do we have high
enough level of resistance to uh reduce
or even avoid the use of fungicides
because this was a huge deal for Growers
um I have a case example here Michigan
grows uh 30,000 Acres of
cucumber they were spending uh Growers
collectively were spending $6.4 million
a year on fungicide on cucurbits most of
that was for uh fungicides for Downey
mildew on cucumber and uh this was
costing Growers up to $600 an acre which
was uh completely eliminating the
profitability for a lot of them and they
really had no choice on the fungicides
they used uh because Downey mildew uh
had overcome so many fungicides they
were forced to use the latest and
greatest most expensive and because it
uh reproduces so quickly and is so
virulent they were spraying on a weekly
basis and spraying even before the
pathogen uh came into the area because
once you see it you know it's game over
and even with uh fungicides you know
they were gaining uh or they are I
should say you know uh fungicides are
still important they gained some time
and often it is enough time to to get a
harvest but uh Growers really want uh
something resistance that they can add
to their fungicide
programs so what we did was we did a
split plot trial where we had four uh
cultigens we had two cultivars uh a
slicer and a Pickler that are very
common in production uh and then we had
two of our breeding lines including 264
which is our was our Top
Line in one of the plots we had a no
treatment uh trial we didn't spray
fungicide at all and the other one we
used what is a standard uh grower
application of fungicides so we we
sprayed weekly alternated between two of
the most effective fungicides at the
time and what we found not surprisingly
was uh this is a measure of uh area
under disease progress curve uh a
measure of a total amount of disease
that the plants have the higher numbers
are worse you want a lower number uh
without uh any sort of treatment uh
dashu and Eureka uh died pretty quickly
um they accumulated a lot of disease
very quickly
um and we we still saw some effect of
using fungicide with our lines but this
Top Line uh was statistically not
different between the uh Fungicide and
no fungicide applications which
indicated to us that uh Growers could
use this line without in in areas of
moderate pressure uh could use this line
without fungicide or with uh reduced
fungicide applications so uh this was a
a really significant finding for us so
we released uh this line and it was
immediately picked up by uh small Seed
Company in the South where it really
gained traction because of the heavy
disease pressure there and uh the lack
of any time at all to grow cucumbers
before the disease moves into the area
uh but it still had some some flaws that
we needed to work on um we wanted to
improve earliness we were about 10 to 15
264 is about 10 to 15 days later than uh
commercial cultivars which uh with
cucumbers when you're talking about a
crop that uh usually starts producing
fruit in about uh 55 days that's that's
pretty
significant uh we wanted to improve
yield it's always a goal uh reduce the
male flowering um it it had a little bit
skewed ratio that we wanted to change
and improve the fruit size so 264 really
was a uh Slicer in a pickler's body um
it was a small four to six inch fruit
but had uh the skin of a slicer so we
wanted to change that so we started
Crossing uh you know went back to
Crossing uh 264 with some Elite lines
and cultivars using the same approach
that uh I described earlier
so as of last year we had some new lines
that uh we again trial and this is
courtesy of uh Lauren who uh I worked
with last year to set up uh the trial
and she took all this data after I had
left um and our most promising line 401
did extremely well in the field here's a
picture of it um that uh we took for a
publication uh we now have an 8 to 10 in
Fruit as opposed to 5 to six uh it has a
similar disease resistance in this First
Column as 264
and much better than everything else we
compared it to and I should point out
that um this SV line Darlington and
centella are cultivars that have been
released by uh seed companies with
purported dowy M tolerance or um
resistance so we wanted to compare our
material with what was considered the
best on the market at the time and uh
there was really no comparison uh for
the
resistance the uh fruit under disease
pressure was much higher than everything
else and like I said it was bigger fruit
uh not only more but bigger and days to
harvest was right where we wanted it to
be right in line with the other
commercial Cult of ours so um and here
you can see um the plants growing out in
the field uh our two lines here the
marmore 97 which kind of represents this
B group here and then straight 8 which
is another very susceptible variety uh
was completely dead at the time all
these pictures were
taken so um we've released uh
401 uh and look forward to it being uh
trialed by seed companies as a line uh
to be sold by itself or in a hybrid uh
and one question I get a lot is how
durable do you think the resistance is
and that's a good question it's a hard
question to answer um there's some
anxiety about any new uh line that is
produced because
uh this this is a really nasty pathogen
in terms of its ability to to mutate and
overcome uh plant host resistance and
and uh develop resistance to fungicides
so here's just a couple uh articles that
have been uh released uh since this new
strain came on board uh showing new
avenues for uh pseudo peros cubensis the
the pathogen to uh mutate change and uh
cause infection so uh mostly the
pathogen is spread via asexual zoospores
but uh a new mating type has been found
in the US which could open the door for
sexual reproduction and recombination
that comes with that uh there's
different populations of the pathogen uh
there's a lot of genetic variability out
there uh which if it starts recombining
could uh be very problematic we've now
found evidence of seed transmission so
this is extremely important because
before you know we could predict where
it was going to be based on wind
currents
now it just depends on where seed is
moving potentially um and also there's
been some new host discovered uh that
might actually allow the pathogen to
overwinter so uh it's a problem that we
still have to work on there's still a
lot of unknowns but one of the great
things about the line that we've
developed or the lines that we've
developed is that they're really a
combination of resistance genes from
different sources uh we don't know
exactly how many we know it's more than
can be easily determined by uh
segregation ratios in in um Family
populations but we don't know how many
it is but it's my hope that it's enough
that uh if we keep working on this we
can stay ahead of the
pathogen so the next steps obviously are
to continue triing these lines in
numerous locations um uh development of
more commercial cultivars with the
Cornell material in it uh we need to
incorporate resistance into other Market
types so the the pickling sector is
actually larger than the slicing
cucumber sector in the US and um uh we
they are also desperate for some Downey
M do resistant material and and I know
that's one thing that Lauren is working
on um that you might hear about in the
future we need to continue to improve
resistance um maybe by identifying new
sources of
resistance um such as 19788 could we use
that does it have different resistance
genes that could be combined with the
Cornell resistance genes um to to really
produce almost immunity and then uh
depending on uh how many genes are
involved you know the development of
markers and either a marker say
selection or even a genomic selection
approach could help us more easily move
these genes into new material
so uh that was cucumbers now I'm going
to switch gears a little bit and uh talk
about the work we've done to map the
powdery milde resistance uh Gene pm0 and
cucurbita and cucurbita is the genus of
squash and
pumpkins first a look at the disease
powdery mildew uh so powdery mildew uh
is a disease that can occur on uh a lot
of very taxonomically diverse plant
species uh the disease is caused by a
number of different pathogens all from
the same fungal family so we're dealing
with a fungal disease instead of an old
my SE and this is pretty common symptoms
you know it'll range depending on the
pathogen and the host but often times
you'll see these white fuzzy spots on
leaves uh poter m a folar pathogen and
those fuzzy spots are the signs of the
pathogen they're the colonies of uh
canidia fores which are the reproductive
structure
eventually uh these colonies will coales
so that you have a a fuzzy mat on the
upper Leaf surface and potentially the
lower Leaf surface and uh in the course
of infection you can often get chlorotic
areas at the point of or nearby the
colonies um which is a sign of the the
pathogen uh using the plants resources
so it's um the most prevalent disease on
squash and pumpkins like the dowy milu
pathogen it's dispersed aerially so it's
pretty much everywhere that squash and
pumpkins are
grown uh unlike Donnie milw it typically
results in slow plant death um but can
definitely reduce uh fruit quantity
quality and storability uh so it's it's
really uh the number one disease that
squash pumpkin Growers are asking about
and talking
about so uh Potter mildew can occur on
uh all of the
cultivated uh species uh that we use and
I just wanted to introduce them because
you'll hear me talking about these
different species uh a little bit later
on so uh one of the species that uh is
common in the US is cucur aipo and that
includes your Jackal lantern pumpkins
your spaghetti squash acorn squash uh
zucchini summer squash uh then there's
cucur mosada which includes your
butternuts uh some sometimes your cheese
type pumpkins and also uh processing
type pumpkins so uh there's the
Dickenson variety among others that uh
are typically used to make canned
pumpkin pie filling um and then there's
uh cucurbita Maxima uh which includes
the Buttercup
types and your giant award-winning
pumpkins uh modeled by Chris and Kyle
right here you're going for a number
that beats that this year
right and uh once again most squash and
pumpkins are produced in eastern states
about 80% of the production is east of
the Mississippi River and a production
value of about $335
million so as you can imagine uh this is
such an important disease in squash and
pumpkins that breeders and geneticists
have been looking for a long time for
sources of resistance uh unfortunately
there's no known resistance native
resistance in cucurbit aipo back in the
early 1970s some uh researchers grew out
the whole USDA collection of all three
of these species and found nothing that
even approached acceptable resistance in
cucurbit aipo they found some moderate
resistance in both uh urb mosada and
Maxima but it wasn't really robust it it
it wasn't what uh would even approach
what was desired by the industry and
Marketplace
however
there is known to be powdery M
resistance in several wild cucurbita
species and uh here are some of the
cucurbita species shown here and with
this is a a Crossing polygon showing
what things are sparingly compatible a
line doesn't mean it's readily
compatible but it means that if you work
hard enough at it and long enough you
can often get a few seeds from the cross
so one of these species hurb okobi Enis
here uh is resistant and uh was
collected in Mexico uh a long time ago
and sent to Cornell uh with the hope
that it could be crossed with uh mosada
and pipo to to bring resistance in and
that was ultimately very successful uh
after a lot of effort uh resistance was
transferred from this wild gourd-like
plant to cucur mosada and then
eventually into cucurbit aipo through a
mosada bridge so it needed a little help
there but but they made it and uh it
wasn't complete resistance that was
transferred because we've never seen any
powdery mildew on this plant in the
field it's completely
resistant in cucur mosada and pipo
um we don't see that and the reason for
that is that a single Gene was
transferred uh we we now know that this
has many genes that contribute but a
very important Gene was transferred pm0
and that Gene confers enough resistance
that uh Growers often need reduced uh
Growers use reduced fungicide
applications and in a moderate year of
pathogen pressure don't need any at all
so it's it's adequate to get them to the
end of the season and the single Gene
was confirmed back in the 1970s using
segregating
populations so from there um at Cornell
this Gene was transferred into a lot of
different materials it was transferred
into to both subspecies of cucurbit aipo
uh into pumpkin uh and these varieties
are all names uh of varieties developed
at Cornell uh into zucchini including
Romulus here which has been uh the
source of resistance for uh a lot of the
things we've done historically in in the
breeding
program uh it was transferred into the
other subspecies of cucur aipo into
straight neck squash and acorn and
delicata it was moved into different
butternuts in cucur mosada a large
butternut and a smaller Butternut bugle
which is uh you can find in a number of
seed catalogs and one interesting
cultivar that lost resistance it was
transferred into uh a cucurbita poipo
cocelli which is is kind of like a
zucchini but later uh we found lost the
resistance so that'll be important in
just a
minute so from from here
uh these were disseminated to seed
companies that use these as sources of
the PMZ Gene uh use these or their
progenitors uh as we shared uh as the
Cornell program shared along the way and
uh continue to be extremely important
pretty much every uh variety that is
powdery mil resistant today uh has its
roots in these efforts uh and has the PM
Z
Gene um it's an incredibly widely used
Gene but a problem to date is that there
are no markers for it uh and one of the
reasons for that is a lot of the squash
and breeding squash and pumpkin breeding
efforts are done by small to mediumsized
companies that just don't have the
resources for mapping and Market
development uh and actually we have uh
many of you might know that we host the
vegetable breeding Institute Field Days
every year where Seed Company
Representatives will come in and see the
resources that uh the Cornell breeding
programs have developed and and kind of
pitch their ideas and what they want to
see in the future and one of my favorite
things to ask them every year was if you
could pick one thing for a public
research institution to develop that
would have utility for your breeding
program what would it be and without
fail every year uh for squash the two
answers were markers for powdery Miler
resistance and markers for virus
resistance so it was it was a huge
need uh that we wanted to to solve right
away so we got to
thinking what can we um how can how can
we we map this Gene uh quickly without
developing new populations without um
waiting additional seasons and using uh
The Germ plasm that we already have
available we have uh what we termed a
shared trait ingression panel they were
things that were very diverse in very
different species uh subspecies and
Market classes but they all had one
thing in common and that was a single
Gene from a wild species
so what we decided to do was um we
sequenced uh cucurbita uh okobi
subspecies Martini the original source
of the pm0 gene uh using genotyping by
sequencing and um we
also uh got together a bunch of heirloom
varieties in cucuro and one in um kcur
mosada things that were around before
the ingression event took PL took place
uh things that had no chance of having
any of the wild species in them and uh
we genotyped these also with GBS and
then we filtered all of the markers uh
so that we only kept the set that had
one Al for Martin E ey and one Al for
all of the heirlooms uh together and
then we sequenced quite a large number
of
heirlooms um
and uh we anchored all of these markers
using uh an F2 population that was being
grown at the time the study was done at
rup seeds so we we partnered with them
on this project uh and they they shared
some of their data this was an inner
specific population so it was really a
great for uh developing lots of
markers from there uh we genotyped uh
the Cornell shared inra ingression panel
that I was uh referring to e earlier
uh all of these uh inbred lines inbred
cultivars that were diverse but shared
something in common and we looked across
the genome uh each one of these bars
represents a chromosome from 1 to 20 and
uh we looked at whether they had the
heirloom alil or whether they had the
maresi or opensis alil so gray is
heirloom and blue is um
martini and you can see
uh the chunk of cucura Martini just
lights right up right on linkage group
10 so we were pretty confident uh that
we had found something there when we
zoomed in on the region so this is a
zoomed in uh
pictograph uh on linguage group 10 once
again we have uh the wild species up top
we found that uh there was some
recombination around the area uh not
surprisingly
you remember me talking about the line
that had resistance that lost
it uh was right here still had part of
the Martin easi ingression it just
didn't have the resistance and all of
these up here had resistance so we were
able to use that to identify a
relatively small 500 kilobase region uh
that we were pretty confident had the
resistance Gene it had to be somewhere
in here because these had it and it
couldn't be here because this one um
didn't have the
resistance so uh once we had this
interval we uh followed up with uh a
pretty small jwas study but um there's
only so many cultivars that are out
there right now you know since uh the
first cultivar started appearing in the
late
1990s um but we found about 81 cucuro
cultivars many with the pm0 resistance
um in both subspecies and all
morphotypes so here you have the Texana
subspecies here is the pipo
subspecies and we had pumpkins uh
zucchini acorns delicata uh anything
that we could find any Market type that
had the resistance Gene and uh where we
had heirlooms that lacked
it we uh grew them all out in the field
in uh replicated plots and we use pedial
ratings as our phenotype and one thing
we've learned over many years is that
pedial ratings are the easiest way to
determine if something is carrying the
pm0 gene
um leaf leaves can vary a little bit but
almost invariably uh something that is
homozygous for the resistance alil will
not have any colonies on its pedal
something that is homozygous for the
susceptibility alal will be just covered
and usually something that heterozygous
will have colonies at its base and taper
off and the tips will be clean and and
then we added two other classes just to
um be able to represent some sort of
intermediate phenotypes that we saw in
the
field what we found uh was uh pretty
clear uh on linkage group
10 uh right over the interval we had our
Peak uh so for those of you not familiar
with these types of plots this is called
a Manhattan plot where the linkage
groups are uh on bottom and the negative
log of the P value which represents the
significance of the AL relating
to the trait or the
phenotype um and so we had very
significant uh hit right at the interval
um where where we assumed the locus was
at as one more confirmation um we teamed
up with rup again who uh did a simple
binary rating on their F2 population
this was the same F2 that we use to
Anchor our Snips and um we took four uh
markers these uh two inside the interval
and these two flanking the interval to
see if uh they used a different
excession of okobi Enis if if the PMZ
Gene was in that one as well and what we
see is uh very much what we expected uh
we see an additive or incompletely
dominant gene action here uh where the
plants the group of plants that had uh
were homozygous with the susceptibility
levs had higher disease ratings the ones
that uh were homozygous for the
resistance Le had signif statistically
significant lower ratings and as we
moved outside of that interval um the
difference in PM scores uh was
reduced so uh we did some fine mapping
uh and narrowed that 500 KB region to
about uh a little less than 80 K uh
KB and we found a number of interesting
candidate genes so uh I've highlighted
four of them here uh we found a
predicted peroxid days which uh is known
to uh contribute to powdered mildew
resistance in uh barley uh there's the
salicylic acid binding protein uh which
contributes to powdery M resistance in
arabidopsis uh this one I think is
particularly interesting this is a uh an
NBS lrr that uh is a powdery mildew
resistance protein in
arabidopsis and then uh zinc finger
there's a zinc finger protein here um
and those are involved in a lot of
biotrophic pathogen resistances
so it could be any number of these uh
this is as far as we are at to date uh
it presents a lot of interesting
questions moving forward for someone to
follow up on uh and we definitely don't
rule out the possibility that's a number
of these genes acting in tandem um it
could be uh multiple of these or um you
know in the case of the r genene it's a
very big r genene maybe it's actually a
raft of R genes uh connected to each
other and so the last thing we did um
and this credit goes to Kyle uh was to
take some of our markers and and or take
some of the the Snips and develop
markers into them
uh we released the sequence information
so that those can be adapted to any
platform that the Breeders want and uh
ran some caps here where we had perfect
segregation between uh the phenotype and
the
marker so the next steps um evaluate
candidates to identify the causal Gene I
think that will be a very uh interesting
exercise uh we need to continue to
improve powdered milde resistance and
Commercial cultivars this isn't directly
related to what I was talking about but
it's very important uh as I said the pm0
gene doesn't confer immunity into
uh into the tolerant um
genotypes uh and there has been more
reports in recent years that the
resistance isn't holding up as well as
it had in the past and that's not at all
surprising we're talking about a single
Gene resistance eventually that's going
to break down so we need to be on top of
uh finding other sources of resistance
um using recurrent selection approaches
to combine these small effect alals that
might be natively in cucur pipo or
especially cucura mosada uh we could
also revisit some of these wild species
to pick up uh the genes that were left
behind in the beginning and we have a
lot more tools and Technologies now to
do that than they had in the
1970s so uh really briefly I'm going to
uh talk
about um a collaborative effort with the
USDA on uh doing some genetic
characterization of uh what we term the
USDA pisome diversity collection and
this collection really has its roots in
a core collection uh developed in the
early
1990s that was assembled to maximize
geographical and morphological diversity
within the collection uh in accessions
were collected all around the world and
this map shows uh the 238 accessions of
the updc as we call it uh that were
collected in addition uh there's almost
200 accessions that were uh developed by
breeding programs or donated by
institutions but have unknown collection
Origins and um one thing one thing in
particular to note is that this
collection includes uh breeding material
from uh the USDA and Washington State
breeding programs and uh field peas and
uh snap peas uh developed by uh Jim
Myers and his predecessors at Oregon
State so um oh I should I should say
that this
collection uh is used widely by pe
breeders to find uh new traits so uh the
collection's been grown out the core
collection and its derivatives including
the updc have been grown out in various
permutations uh many times by um
breeders looking for new traits and uh
there's been a lot of uh traits that
have been uh phenotypes that have been
recorded in our publicly available one
big thing that was missing was any sort
of highdensity molecular data um and
this was needed to be able to map those
traits a lot of the traits that are
important in P are single Gene tra traes
that would be relatively simple to map
with enough markers and enough
individuals um the phenotype data is
already there and another thing we
wanted to do was be able to um get a
genetic snapshot uh of what the
collection looked like uh often times um
morph uh the phenotypes could look
similar but they could be very
genetically unrelated so this would help
us to to tease out where uh diversity is
for breeding
programs so one of the first things we
did was look at the structure of the
collection and
um here we have a principal components
uh diagram showing uh each one of these
dots represents an accession uh that was
genotyped uh here are the Oregon State
snap peas snap and snow peas here are
the Washington State field peas and then
these other colors um were used based on
previous studies that included these
materials so this uh study or this color
here yellow represents uh the cultivated
type P uh pism sativum subspecies
sativum here are uh in blue are the two
recognized subspecies of pism sativum
elus and
absum and what is perhaps the most
interesting is this area of green here
so these P's here come from Central Asia
and and really all of these do too um
these were just the ones that were
included in in previous
studies uh and these are not recognized
as a separate uh
subspecies uh many people have noticed
that peas from Central Asia seem to be
different than cultivated peas but no
one has really looked too much into it
so one of the things we were interested
in doing with the genetic data is trying
to see if we could uncover anything
about this this very different group of
peas and it should be said that um these
peas are often found in mountainous
regions in Central Asia so if you think
of the mountainous areas in Iran and
Afghanistan India Nepal um they tend to
be more cold tolerant they have
different uh uh they tend to be low
growing basil branching so there's a lot
of um phenotypic differences as well one
of the questions we had and which um
hasn't really been addressed is um is it
possible that that these uh
accessions had some ancient or maybe
more recent uh ingression from pison
fulam which is the only other sister
species of pism sativum so we went to
the USDA collection and and genotyped uh
with GBS some Pyon fuls to see if they
clustered nearby these Central Asian
peas and those included at Red at the
top and we found out that they don't uh
and one of the reasons we thought they
might was because there are some
phenotypic similarities so uh there
still is work that needs to be done to
figure out where do these peas come from
and
um these these peas have a lot of
genetic diversity we looked at
um how much diversity they have to offer
to breeding programs and so on on the
left we have uh each group Pym fulum the
subspecies elus the cultivated types the
sativum and um the Central Asian piece
and we looked at how many Snips they
have that are unique to each of those
groups versus these groups here so we
found uh and and we corrected for
different um population sizes within
each each of these groups we found that
the Central Asian piece had over 6,000
Snips uh and this is
uh out of uh around 68,000 Snips total
that were different than anything else
and when we compared that to the
breeding program P's Washington State
and Oregon State we found that they
actually had more unique alals than even
the pison fulam and
one very important key here is that
these Central Asian PS have not really
been used in breeding efforts uh as far
as I know anywhere but they are fully
compatible with cultivated sativum
whereas pison fulum is a different
species and there's a lot of Crossing
barriers that exist there to bring in
that
diversity so uh in
conclusion uh We've developed the first
slicing cucumber with high resistance to
a new strain of Downey
mildew we have uh resistance genes in uh
very diverse moderately resistant uh
material that we know can be combined to
provide high levels of
resistance with resistance we can reduce
or eliminate the need for uh
fungicides we found that this shared
trait integration panel mapping approach
is very effective and we think it can be
used a lot in vegetable crops where this
whole model of bringing in a single Gene
from wild species is very common there's
been a lot of disease resistance genes
that have been introduced um from a
single
wild species and we think this approach
uh could really illuminate those in in
short order we now have markers for pm0
which is the most widely used Gene in
squash and pumpkin breeding and which a
lot of uh seed companies have already
started implementing into their uh
breeding pipelines we have a highdensity
snip data set that's now available for
genetic characterization and hopefully
trait mapping uh in a very diverse
collection of P
and uh were particularly interested in
um the application of this data to use
this group of peas from Central Asia for
bringing in additional diversity to to
breeding
programs so uh there's lots of people to
acknowledge for all of these different
projects I want to uh say special thanks
to my graduate committee um Michael and
Mike Gore and Susan and Chris smart um
they've been tremendously supportive uh
throughout the time I've been here and
I've uh you know I've been able to
bounce a lot of ideas off of them and um
special thanks to uh all the current and
former members of the Missour lab group
um you know as we were figuring things
out uh we really helped each other uh
with various uh skills and expertise uh
co- these are a list of co-authors uh
who have been very instrumental in in
all of these different studies um in
cucumber squash
andp uh the Cornell farm and uh
Greenhouse uh research teams uh Can't
Get Enough thanks for everything they do
to keep things going throughout the year
in the season um Mary kinger at the
vegetable breeding Institute uh has been
very helpful all the time uh has
answered a lot of questions over the
years um when we first got started in
genotyping Sharon Mitchell and Charlotte
uh charia spent a lot of time helping us
get going uh in those directions uh we
had some collaborators at other
institutions as well uh yesun and John
Murphy and rup seeds uh that donated
seeds or uh uh resources along the way
and also um thanks and large part to all
of the funding that allowed us to be
able to do all of these things so with
that that I'll take
questions this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu