this is a production of Cornell
University um my goal today is to to
share a few things with you to get you
thinking about your teaching um and I
know that some of you are faculty and
are currently in teaching roles and some
of you are graduate students and
probably will be in teaching roles at
some point so I hope to to get you
thinking about some things um I'm
probably not going to go as deep as some
of you might like to think but I can
certainly recommend some resources if
you want to look at some of these topics
at a little bit deeper level um I do
plan to have some interactivity built in
and so hopefully you came prepared with
the mindset of at least being open to
some discussion and some questioning and
so we'll see where that
leads so first I want to pose a question
to you and we're going to do a think
pair share and I think that if I
understand from Travis that you guys
learned about some of these active
learning strategies a little while ago
um but we'll pose the question to you
I'll let you think about it for a second
then you can pair up with someone around
you and then uh we'll have a few of you
share some of those so the question is
in your classes what does it look like
when students are getting it and so
think about that for a
second okay so let's go ahead and pair
up and and share what you think with
someone around
you okay let's let's rejoin let's come
back together
and so what were what were some of the
things that you guys were discussing
what does it look like when students are
getting it if you can I have a few
volunteers to to
share yes yeah students are volunteering
and asking questions okay so the
students are volunteering they're asking
their own questions they're you can tell
it because they're they're really
engaged okay what
else
physically oh okay I get
it yeah body language also communicating
that they're getting it moving forward
and eye contact yeah so you're kind of
reading their their body language and
and their the psychological signs that
they're they're giving good and so I I
won't ask this question but you can
probably as you were thinking about that
we're also thinking what's it look like
when they're not getting it well
hopefully today I'm going to give you
some things to think about so that we
can really generate this more in your
classes as opposed to the frustrating
times when students aren't getting and
so um I'm going to frame my my
discussion this morning around five
principles and there are a few handouts
out and around and and so you can feel
free to jot down a few extra things if
you want um but five principles that I
think will help you create meaningful
learning experiences uh in your classes
so my objectives for today are we're
going to describe the principles of
experiential learning and then
ultimately uh I'm going to encourage you
guys at the end to think about your own
teaching whether it's your teaching now
or whether you'll have a teaching role
in the future about what are some things
things that you can do in your own
teaching to to make it more meaningful
for your
students so principle one learning
begins with the existing knowledge and
experiences of the learner learning
begins with the existing knowledges and
experiences of the learn and so I'll let
you read this a little
bit
so is this what we think about our our
students they're just a brain on a stick
and nothing else
matters no not really I mean really it's
it's this stuff this is what makes us
uniquely human are those individual
experiences and aspirations and goals
and and so I would contend that one of
the things we ought to be doing as as
instructors is getting to know this
student I mean we still want to care
about this one at least this part of
this one but getting to getting to know
this student so we know who are our
students where do they want to go where
what do they want to be what are what do
they already know what are the
experiences they
have second thing I want to bring up
is there is no such thing as a blank
slate there's no such thing as a blank
slate so whether no matter what you're
teaching your students are coming to you
with some level of understanding or
perhaps misunderstanding of the concepts
that you're trying to teach there is no
blank slate and so if if we go into the
learning environment thinking that
there's a blank slate we're starting at
a disadvantage it's really about trying
to figure out what is on their slate and
building off of that as opposed to
starting from scratch so principle
number one learning begins with the
existing knowledge and
experiences of the learner and so let me
pose a question to you so based on
principle number one what are some
things you might think about trying to
do in your classes to to capture
principle number
one do some kind of assessment at the
beginning of class to see what students
know already already excellent idea so
do some sort of an assessment whether
it's formal or informal to kind of
gather what the students know okay one
more idea you might do in your
classes try to relate material to what
they know yeah so have them try to
connect with the new stuff you're giving
had them try to connect with what they
already know and that will help you do
that I do an activity with some of my
classes called a concept map any of you
guys familiar with a concept map it's
kind of a a a way to organize thoughts
and so um actually The Graduate course I
teach on experiential learning I do this
very activity at the very beginning of
the semester I had them create their
concept map about how people learn and
then at the end of the semester I have
them recreate that concept map and then
I give them back the first one that they
did so they can see the growth in their
own understanding of how people learn so
it's all all about what they know and
what they bring to the environment okay
so there are no blank slates that was
principle number
one principle number two learning is a
cyclical process it's a cyclical process
and I'm going to walk you through a a
series of little videos to kind of help
us think about maybe a learning cycle
that we might share in common that we
have been
through and so I'll pose this question
to you how did you learn to ride a bike
and so I want you to think about that
for a sec and kind of recreate some
memories or pull some memories out of of
the file storage to think about what it
was like when you learned to ride a bike
and then I've got a series of short
video clips that I think might
demonstrate what some of us have
experienced okay so I would propose that
step one for many of us well let me ask
before I give you what I think let me
ask you guys what you think so what was
what what was step one for you guys in
learning how to ride a
bike I have no rec no recollection could
you could you creating the wheel in some
people's well that would that would be a
precursor um because the wheel is is a
critical component of a bicycle other
thoughts yeah getting beautiful purple
bike that I wanted to learn how to ride
so getting that first bike that you
really wanted to ride other
memories so seeing other people ride
bikes okay any other ideas yeah my dad
holding the back of the seat yeah yep I
think many of us have similar memories
to that and so all great and and you're
going to see most of those things maybe
with the exception of creating the wheel
in these video clips that I'm going to
to show you and so let me start with
this one and I think we've got this
where it's going to work out
right I know it's hard was
helping what you
say can I help you a little bit you need
to use your legs you got to push with
your
leg okay you do it you got to push hard
push be like there very good very
good okay and so I would propose that
that might have been step one and that
might have been when we got that first
tricycle okay and we probably did see
someone ride the bike before we got to
this stage so maybe this is step two
really other than step one but what are
some things that we probably had to
learn about riding a bike when we are at
this
stage coordination coordination okay
Travis how muscle tone yeah I mean the
pedal it's it's a little bit different
motion it's not walking it's a little
bit different motion okay what else
might we have learned at this
stage yeah a little bit of balance I
mean the tricycle has a little bit more
balance than a two whe bike but still
you can't lean way over or way back
because you'll fall off okay what about
stopping on the tricycle how do you stop
on a
tricycle either yeah you pedal revers or
just stop pedaling or you put your feet
down okay so that I would propose that
might be step one and so now I'll bring
you to step
two
maybe TR to bre okay show me how you
ped
I okay and so step two is when we got
that that new bike that it was a two
wheel bike but it had training wheels on
it and so what are some things that we
probably had to learn when we were at
step
two steering yeah steering's a little
bit different on on that you know on the
tricycle the pedals are on the front
wheel whereas the pedals are back
further on those bikes what else do we
have to learn at at step
two the brakes right and what kind of
brakes do the those kind of bikes have
pedal yeah right you push back on the
pedal and when you get good you can
leave the skid marks on the
driveway okay what else do we have to
learn at that
stage how get on AER yeah it's bigger
it's up a little bit higher how to get
on okay what else maybe one more
thing this side of the room this side of
the room hasn't been as
as where where you can ride you might be
able to go yeah so you might get a
little bit more freedom particularly as
you get a little bit older mom or dad or
whoever lets you get a little bit more
freedom okay so our our our travel
through the bicycle riding Academy is
continuing this is
not keep going keep
going I'll
restart okay and so step three
was the day that the training wheels
came off and of course when I ask that
question that's usually where the people
go is the you know Mom or Dad holding on
to the back so what what what did we
have to learn the day that the training
wheels came
off balance balance right and balance is
really critical when you don't have the
training wheels okay what else do we
have to learn at that stage you have to
maintain a certain speed you do you have
to maintain a certain speed because even
if you've got well there's a few people
that can bounce standing still but I'm
not one of them but yeah you got to
maintain some level of speed
or you fall over what else we have to
learn at that one yeah tipping over
doesn't me you're not cut off yeah
because most of us were there right most
of us tipped over a time or two and of
course we had some trust issues with Mom
or Dad hanging on to the back because
you know they and you know those of you
with children probably went through this
with your own children is you know they
make you promise to not let go of course
what do we do we let go every time and
then I promise I won't let go this time
and we let go again and so so it's kind
of where we're working through that
cycle and we're getting better and
better so now I say we move on to step
four so so step
four step four we we we were a little
bit braver and those boundaries are a
little bit further out so what do what
we have to lose lose what do we have to
learn at at step four wear a helmet
safety yeah wear a helmet safety what
else we're probably getting faster
what's that look out for other yeah look
out for our surroundings we're probably
getting faster we're probably getting a
little bit older so Mom or Dad probably
gave us a little bit more room to
stretch out you let us take a few more
risks of course sometimes with the rist
comes those sorts of things and so you
know we after we run into our friend and
we get up and we get a bandaid on our
elbow or whatever else and then we get
back on the bike and we learn to well
next time maybe we need to look out
where we're
going okay so now let's see what's on
step
five ah what happens at step
five now that one that one was stag
because I have not found a great video
for this yet but step five was when we
got that first bigger bike right and and
what did the what do the bigger bikes
have that the smaller bikes don't have
yeah everyone's handlebar brakes right
and what did we learn is a critical
piece of information related to
handlebar breakes apply both at the same
apply both at the same time or if you're
only going to apply one which one do you
apply the rear because what happens if
you apply only the
front yeah and how did we learn that
either intentionally or unintentionally
we did something like that right we
flipped off and we said ah oh okay okay
I better not do that again let me just
work on the back breakes cool thing
about that is learning
to yeah yeah that one that you you could
tell that kid had practiced a little bit
he is he was he was there now I would
contend that our our journey through
bike riding is still
[Music]
growing
okay a lot of wind noise on that one so
that was that was just a person riding a
bike on a leisurely thing now how many
of you would say that even if you
haven't been on a bike in a couple of
years that you could probably handle
that today at least on level ground
maybe not on some of the hills you guys
have around here but on level ground so
most of us would say we can we can do
that with reasonable thing we we've
reached that level um although I don't
know about this campus our campus the
bicyclists are crazy you about have to
chase them around to you know I had a
professor when I was an undergrad used
to carry a golf club and he was Infamous
for carrying this golf club around
campus and anytime someone got close to
me start swinging this golf club because
he he wanted the bikes to stay away from
him because they will zoom up right
behind him but so most of
us most of us probably have skill levels
similar to that we could with a moderate
amount of success get on a bike and and
travel across campus now would is that
the Pinnacle of bike riding
skill I see some head shaking those so
what might be a next level of bike
riding skill what are some examples
riding up oh riding up the hill
yeah P oh yeah clip-in pedals I I I'm
too scared to do that have you guys seen
those where your feet actually like
attached to the pedal and there's like a
trick to get your foot out that's not
for me what other kinds of bike riding
might be the next level my little
brother
used yeah the jumps and the ramps and
and then you know the the guys that do
the racing and such anybody here do like
BMX racing or the the mountain biking or
the the like the tour to France sorts of
stuff
racing so but yeah so there is a level
and
so um this next one I found this video
by a kid named Spencer and so I want you
to look at some of the stuff that
Spencer can do and think about how he
got to that
point
[Music]
and so any we have any Spencers in here
no I you know I I think as a kid i'
probably in accidentally did some of
those moves you know flipping off or
doing some of stuff I'm I always look
back at my I've got two brothers and it
it's amazing that none of us have brain
damage considering the stuff that we did
as kids so but how do you think Spencer
got to the point where he's at do you
think it just happened
overnight no he had a lot of practice do
you think every one of his flips he
worked perfect the first time no he
probably had a lot of bumps a lot of
bruises and he you know he' tried to do
a flip and he'd land on his head or his
butt or his back or whatever and he
figur out okay what do I need to do
different he kept practicing so he was
working through and and trying to learn
each time he tried something so now I
propose that one more
step in our bicycle
Academy I know it's hard see I was
helping what do you
say can I help you a little bit you need
to use your legs you got to push with
your leg
so obviously that's where we started so
why are we back at that point now why
why are we back at that stage are we is
it kind of we're going to be old and
have to get back on a tricycle one
day yeah how how to teach someone so now
when we're back at that stage we're not
the little guy with the helmet on the on
the tricycle we're the parent behind the
tricycle um trying to teach our child to
do that and so what I've tried to
demonstrate with those videos and and
getting you guys to think back to your
own experiences say I was trying to
connect to your experiences with riding
a bike to think about how you went
through that process and it was you know
if we went all the way to where Spencer
is I mean that might be a 10 or 12 year
development cycle in terms of of bike
riding and so learning is a process that
we go through that we might call the
Learning Cycle and I wish I could have a
good way to demonstrate this
three-dimensionally the best way I can
describe it is a slinky you guys know
what a slinky looks like and so think of
this as as a slinky with with multiple
revolutions and so we you know somewhere
in in our being we've had a very initial
focus with the concept and we'll stick
with our bicycle example here so then we
we have an experience with that bicycle
you know we got that that first tricycle
we had to learn about balance and so you
know we leaned too far and we fell off
well down here in the reflection phase
we think about what can I do differently
what does that mean why does this hurt
and we think okay well next time maybe I
should shouldn't lean quite so far and
we try it again and we keep going
through this cycle over and over and
over then we get that bike with
handlebar breakes and we hit the front
brake and we flip off and as we're
laying on the ground we reflect and say
dang that hurts what don't I want to do
again okay I won't hit the front break
and let me try that again so it's just a
constant ongoing process and so thinking
now to your own current uh and future uh
practices in in your own
teaching what can take away from about
the Learning Cycle relative to how you
create learning experiences for your
students what are some things you can
take away to help you with
that failure Lear okay so it's not
always going to go successful and and we
can learn from the unsuccessful attempts
at things okay good what
else yeah breaking it down into
steps yeah break it down into steps we
can to get to the final you get yeah
that's an excellent thing and sometimes
we forget that we all have advanced
degrees in our respective areas many
times the students that we're working
with especially the undergrads and even
some of the grad students they don't
have near the the frame of reference
that we do okay what
else Travis I me a note of remembering
the the pieces of the puzzle that we had
forgotten you know the little mistakes
we made in learning about Concepts or
that now as experts we just kind of
forget that we knew that we don't slow
down and teach that to
students they won't learn yep that's a
good point and I would contend and this
comes from my own personal experiences
and as well as in the work that I do at
the University of Florida I get the
opportunity to do a lot of pure
observation of other faculty all over
the college and so one of my
observations is that as faculty and as
instructors we can get to be pretty good
at providing a lot of creative
experiences for our students I mean we
can come up with lots of cool
experiences for them and we invest a lot
of effort up here but we probably don't
place near enough emphasis down here so
we might create a very cool uh
experience in the greenhouse where the
students are are are growing out a crop
of of whatever and we'll talk to them
about that but then we don't help them
reflect and generalize based on that
experience we just jump right to the
next experience and so some of your
students are probably fairly
self-reflective and are themselves
hitting these steps but I would contend
that some of your students probably
they're just sticking up here they're
not really learning from it and they're
jumping to the next experience so you
know I would suggest that one thing you
can do is is intentionally design
activities to help your students reflect
about what you're doing figure out what
the next step is and work through the
learning cycle okay so principle two
learning is a cyclical
process principle number three learning
is about transforming the experiences
and so we talked a minute about creating
those experiences learning actually
happens about with the transformation of
those
experiences and so what I mean by this
is as as Educators one of our goals or
our goal is to help take things that
exist out here in the wide wide world
and help put them here in the brains of
our students now on my campus two today
I got to go into the psych the
psychology department actually saw a
bunch of human brains in jars which was
kind of interesting um but it's about
it's about transforming those
experiences and it's not as simple as
checking into a hospital and having a
surgical procedure where they you know
Stitch you open and dump it in and
Stitch it closed if they could do that
we'd be out of a job because they
wouldn't need us to help our students
learn but it's about
transforming those experiences for our
students now and this might sound like a
very simple question but I think it's an
important one as we think about what we
do as Educators and what we think about
as far as the the types of experiences
that we create but What mechanisms does
the human brain use to get
information how does our brain get
information our senses right our eyes
and nose and ears and and mouth and so
so so we our brain receives information
through sensory inputs from our five
senses and so as we are thinking about
creating experiences for our students to
transform we're really thinking about
creating opportunities for our students
to use their senses to grasp the the
information the concept that we want
them to do
now I'm not going to pass judgment on
Corell but I'll point right at the
University of Florida I travel around
and look in many of our College
classrooms and which two senses do you
think that we probably over
use in the way that we teach them at
least on our
campus eyes and ears eyes and ears and
sometimes it's not even the eye
sometimes it's a lecture with no
illustration but it's eyes and ears and
so we we really rely on the eyes and the
ears and you know that for some Concepts
that's not a bad way to go about it but
I would contend that there are probably
plenty of opportunities where we might
think about taste and smell and touch
and what can we do to provide a more
sensory Rich experience um for our
students I mean some of the stuff that
you guys do with the fruits and the
vegetables and stuff I mean shoot let
them taste it let them touch it let them
do whatever they smell it whatever they
need to do to really get that and it's
about as the information is traveling
into our brain the more ways and the
more modalities that we can get it in
there the deeper it's going to be
embedded and the the learning is going
to be even stronger so schematically
what might that look like this is a
model of of cognition called the
information processing model and this
was uh has some parallels to the way a
computer works it's actually in in
educational psychology during the time
when they were developing this model it
was in the early ages of the the
computer age and so they drew some
parallels from it but to me it makes
pretty decent sense about um how that
works and so we have some sort of an
input through our
senses through our senses transformed
into working memory or short-term memory
and then stored into long-term memory
and then when we need use it it's pulled
back into into working memory okay so
that intuitively makes sense probably to
to most of you but I want to put a
couple other layers on that relative to
the things we've been talking about so
if we think about this in terms of where
these things are
happening I would contend that these
things are happening outside of the
person so we're providing these
experiences so on a daily basis in your
classes when you create learning
activities for your students you're your
creating these sensory input
opportunities for the students okay this
half is what's happening inside up here
this is the part we can see pretty
easily this is the part that we hope
that it's happening and when students
are getting it we think we see evidence
that this is happening but but not
always then to put it one more layer on
it if we think about our learning cycle
model that we just saw this is providing
the
experience this is providing the
reflection and generalization and so I
would contend that if we only focus on
this
part this part may or may not be
happening as well as we would like and
so I think it's important to to Really
complete that cycle to where we're
providing opportunities for the students
to to Really internalize that at a
cognitive
level so our principle number three was
that learning is about transforming
experiences and so thinking the few
things that we just talked about what
are some things that you might think
about well I can do this different in my
classes that might make a difference few
ideas I going to ask a question
what the reflection and generalization I
I we I have a lot of experiences but to
get students to stop and reflect and
generalize what have you seen to work is
that the question you're asked us what's
worked effectiv well yeah what's worked
effectively for you why I'm
here I know you I know you well enough
to know that journaling is used quite a
lot and students you say okay we're
going to do a little bit of a a
journaling class students like I do that
all the time in all my other class it
might be journaling it might just be
some discussion it might just be some
thought-provoking questions I just
wanted to
comment last fall she the thing care
Share exercise and then I and Marvin as
part of you I was student that we were
asked to teach
at class and I used things share and I
it helped to communicate the topic that
we were discussing and trying to teach
the class so I think it was good because
it was a short like sound bite and stud
took the information in and then
projected it back out and got an
opportunity to learn from each other
yeah good you had a different one I was
going to say um have them teach it have
them teach it yeah so anything to really
just pause for a few minutes and have
the students do something that forces
them to think about it whether it's a
think pair share there's a little
activity called a minute paper where
they just exactly 60 seconds they write
down what they just learned or U you
know anything to get them discuss with
with a a colleague
journaling um anything just to pause and
so you know if if you are accustomed to
lecturing for 50 minutes straight if you
want to make an immediate change one
thing might be lecture for 10 minutes
then do a quick little activity to get
them allow them to think lecture for
another 10 minutes then give them a
little activity to think about what
you've done just to to break it up a
little bit um and so one of the things
that we really want to do and suggest is
that Implement Variety in what you do
and so you know you might like think
pair share and it might make sense to
you but that doesn't mean it's going to
make sense to all your students and so
you want to have Implement some variety
in what you do so that your students can
you can reach a greater number of
students yeah um I had an internship
over the summer and like what we did
ucal um you had end of the day note you
pretty much recap everything that you
learn during the day and then at the end
of you work with like say your
supervisor and you talk about like what
you learned and that was like a great
way to tie everything together because
you get so caught up in everything and
it's just really good to go back and
like see what you actually learned yeah
yeah that's a good
thing generalizing you're reflecting
that's kind of a good yep yep that
that's an not yeah so there there's no
magic bullet um just you know whatever
figure out what's going to work for you
and your situation your students and and
occasionally pause and let your students
actually think about what it is that
you're doing okay so we'll move
on principle four learning is about
building connections learning is about
building
connections and so I want to introduce a
a term to you called brain
plasticity um and it it's the the cool
thing about learning is that learning
actually causes a physical change
in the human brain and so if we think
about what we do as
Educators we we think about imparting
knowledge to our students helping them
learn things we are actually hopefully
causing some physical changes in the
human brain and so that was a pretty P
when I first learned that it was a
pretty powerful thing to me as an
educator to think about you know the the
efforts that I'm making even though I
may not be able to see them is causing a
physical change in uh in the human brain
now if we were
wanted to be at a scientific level and
you want to inject a bunch of dye in
somebody's brain and put it under a very
powerful microscope you could see it
it's about uh building and breaking
brain synapses and those are the natural
electrical connections in the human
brain and so if you're interested in
this sort of stuff you can go Google it
and look it up in the in the biomedical
literature but it really causes a
physical change in the human
brain now some of you might be
comfortable at the microscopic level I'm
certainly not comfortable at the micros
opic level so I like to think at at more
the theoretical and what can I what can
I see and what can I do and so there's a
concept called cognitive schema that to
me makes a lot of sense in how to think
about how people learn if we think about
cognitive schema it it's I visualized it
as kind of a Web of Knowledge with each
one of these nodules being a discret
piece of information and so if we go
back to our bicycle riding example um
this one might be pedaling and this one
might be balance and this one might be
turning and this one might be handlebar
breakes and so forth so we've got this
existing Web of Knowledge now let me
pose a question to you thinking about a
novice versus an expert how do you think
these schema might
differ more interconnections with the
expert yeah so the expert is going to
have more connections between here and
the expert will probably also have more
nodules and so it'll be much more
connected and so you all in your
respective areas in probably have a very
welldeveloped cognitive schema around
whatever it is that that you do um I
would contend that your students when
they come to you probably have a very
skeletal one with either some missing
connections or maybe some connections
that are actually wrong and need to be
broken um and so the the challenge is
then so as an educator we present that
new piece of knowledge and we are very
good at this we can create a lecture we
can create an experiment we can create a
reading we can do this very well we can
give lots of new knowledge but what's
what's the problem with what we see
right
here it's not connected right it's not
connected and so this is where you guys
get very frustrated and I've been there
myself where you say dang it I taught
them that how come they can't figure
this out well it's because they have
this piece of knowledge they just never
made the connection that it fits out
here and so it's just laying out there
by itself and so if you ask them to give
you back that information in the exact
same way that you gave them that
information they can probably do that
but if you ask them to use that
information in a different way they're
like it doesn't make sense it's it's not
connected and so it's all about building
these connections and that comes back to
the notion of building those the the
opportunities for reflection and
generalization to help your students
figure out how does this new piece of
knowledge connect with with the existing
knowledge now the challenging thing is
you get that brand new class at the
beginning of the semester and you've got
30 students in it or whatever and so
they're in your class and each one of
your students has an existing cognitive
schema how many of those 30 students are
going to have the same cognitive
schema
zero zero now they might have some
shared experiences if you teach a senior
level course in the major and your
students taken pretty similar courses to
get to that point there's probably some
similarities in their schema but they're
never going to be the same the the
challenging part and also sometimes the
exciting part is teaching those
introductory classes when you don't have
a clue what they know um but they bring
in a lot of interesting experiences in
there so again it's all
about building connections and so that's
principle
four and I'm getting close on time
aren't I Neil you're doing good am I
okay 15 minutes left okay I want to save
a little bit of time for questions
so as we help the students process so we
give them that new that new piece of
information we introduce that New
Concept there there's really two general
ways that we can think about that new
piece of knowledge either the they're
going to assimilate it so if that New
Concept that new experience fits with
their existing schema they're going to
kind of say okay that makes sense it
fits or they might have to accommodate
that new experience if it's different or
if it's inconsistent or contradicts what
they already know and so they can
probably process these sorts of things a
little bit quicker than they can these
sorts of things and so it's all about
providing opportunities to to help your
students figure out how does this new
piece of information fit and that's
where that reflection and that
generalization can help kind of to tie
that loop back
around so that's principle four it's all
about building connection and so in your
own teaching what are some things that
you might be able to do to help your
students build those
connections okay yeah so give them
different opportunities to to kind of
experience that help build those
connections good what
else conceptual framework yeah it can
and it it's very nice if you can
organize your your course or whatever
around a broader conceptual framework
and keep tying back to that framework to
help the student see where it fits
because it might be crystal clear to you
that a plus b plus C equals D to
students it it may not be and so having
that larger graphic organizer will help
do that good I want to take a quick in
my when I teach my classes I say we'll
take a quick time out earlier that was
demonstrating weight time so when you
ask a question and you just wait until
it's awkwardly silent and then someone
is willing to give you an answer and so
when you ask a question don't feel
afraid to have the awkward silence
because sooner or later someone will
will give you a good answer so other
ideas about providing that helping
students make those
connections for me like teaching
chemistry if I'm teaching the sh Le's
principal in stress readjust to minimize
the stress I ask them in their personal
lives where have they been in stress and
what did they do they readjust so I I
tie it back to personal experience Ah
that's that's an excellent way so
connecting it with connecting a A New
Concept to a different kind of
experience that has some similarities to
it good good okay so principle
five teaching is about creating
meaningful learning
experiences
teaching is about creating meaningful
learning experience and we talked about
the Learning Cycle and we talked about
that we are are very good at creating
learning experiences and so I want to
throw a couple ideas out at you about
creating meaningful learning experiences
things that are really going to engage
your students and and drive things
home the first thing I want to do is is
talk to you about just a couple of
differences between teaching and
facilitation and sometimes we like to
throw those words around a little bit
but I would argue that most most of the
time the meaningful learning experiences
are happening when we are facilitating
the learning process as opposed to
teaching and so in teaching the teaching
the teacher delivers the knowledge in
facilitation the learner constructs the
knowledge okay so a subtle
difference teaching instruction is
rigidly
planned facilitation it's more flexible
and spontaneous and we're open to those
anomalies that happen that we weren't
expecting in teaching the teacher has
very strict control over the
environment in facilitation the teacher
and the learner share the control of the
environment and teaching the Learners
are
passive in facilitation the Learners are
active and so I would encourage you to
think about your own teaching right now
and figure out okay where do I where do
I fit on this Continuum and and are
there some things that you can change to
maybe inch over this way now it's a
little bit intimidating sometimes to to
go into a class session and have a rough
idea about what you think is going to
happen in that class session but based
on the interactions with the students it
might go a slightly different direction
than you were you were planning and so
it's U you know it's it's tough
sometimes as the instructor to give up a
little bit of that of control to say
okay we're going to we're in this
together and I'm going to help
facilitate this process but you're not
getting off easy you got to contribute
as well so I'd encourage you to think
about that the other idea I want to
present to you is called Dale's cone of
experience how many of you have heard of
Dale's cone okay so a couple and so
Dale's con and this really it's actually
pretty dated but it's a pretty it's a
seminar work from from Edgar D and it
comes out of the educational media
literature but it's really about as we
think about creating those experiences
for our students we have choices to make
in how we choose to present that
everything from up here which is all
symbolized which is very abstract to
things that are down here which are very
concrete and very direct and so an
example might be if if we were going to
teach uh how many of you teach some sort
of plant identification okay so I
figured in this department there' be a
handful of you guys that teach those
sort of courses and so as we're teaching
those sorts of courses we can make some
choices about how do we how how do we
want to teach that well we might be up
here and talk about what plants look
like or we might be up here and show
drawings about what plants look like we
might show pictures of plants we might
come down here but when possible and
practical let them see the real thing
and so I would encourage you to think
about as you are teaching Concepts in
your
classes when it's possible and when it's
practical to think about what can I do
to provide direct personal interaction
of the with the students with the
concepts now
logistically and sometimes it's just
impractical to do those sorts of things
but I would contend you know if if if
you can let them see the real thing and
do the real thing and touch the real
thing then give them the real thing
let's let's not come up here um so I
would encourage you to think down there
where we are really in the doing phase
as opposed to the observing or the
symbolizing next thing I want you to
think about is what I call let's add
some real world experiences to to what
we do and so I would propose that in a
class you might add some things like
guest speakers I know you guys have have
world class faculty here but let's hypo
Hy uh hypothesize for a minute that
maybe there is an expert that knows
something better than someone here does
why not invite that person in or Skype
that person and that's the beautiful
thing now with technology is is you can
bring
anybody you can bring anybody into into
the classroom pretty easy field trips
again it's about going to see the real
thing um get your students involved in
in research uh do service learning
projects do outdoor adventure learning
sorts of things where you're getting the
students some direct purposeful
experience with those things now
activities outside of a course that are
more at the program level might be
things like internships study abroad
experiences or broader research projects
and um I don't know about on this campus
but uh I suspect you guys are similar to
us that we've got a lot of bright
energetic students that are are begging
for opportunities and on our campus we
probably don't make good enough use of
all these energetic bright young people
in the other work that we do in in the
research and extension activities that
we do I would contend that there are
probably some great opportunities um to
get those students actively engaged in a
variety of things so principal five
was creating those meaningful learning
experiences so now we're going to talk
about let's take this home what can you
do and so we're going to go back to
another think pair share and so I want
to ask you guys two very specific very
concrete things that you could take away
from my discussion today to immediately
at least in cases of the faculty
immediately for the grad students at
some point in the future two things that
you can immediately take away to make an
impact on your teaching so think about
that for a sec and then pair up with
with someone around you and share your
ideas let's reconvene we'll get a few
ideas shared and then we'll save a few
minutes for
questions and so let's let's hear a few
examples and and Geneva I'll give you
guys a heads up I'm going to call on you
guys in just a minute so you guys can be
thinking too but what are a few examples
of things that uh that you could
immediately Implement in your teaching
for the faculty or for the grad students
something that you could uh to do in the
future so a few
examples not lecture as much okay not
lecture as
mucha if you have a guest speaker
providing some context so that they
don't helping them draw that connection
why is person okay yeah help help your
students draw the connections out of a
guest speaker so it's not just this
anomaly with this strange person was
here for a day and now they're gone to
have pull some meaning out of that good
another example yeah after a fill trip
the experimential learning
part encourage students to yes yeah so
after we've had that experience helped
the students kind of draw some so it
wasn't just a cool day outside the
classroom it was actually there was some
meaning ad it helped the students pull
that out so Geneva what about you guys
what's something that some of you guys
might choose to
implement I have a
suggestion teaching a a co-taught course
with you know three sections and
different instructors sort of U struggle
with the integration I think maybe at
the beginning use the that schema as a
way to show interactions within the
components where we have different
people talking about it doesn't always
integrate as well as one person might
great idea how about one more example
from
Geneva this is just like
mik I guess I use a professional
audience instead of a student audience
okay passing around something physical
for them to play with with their hands
demonstrates the principle yeah that
that's an ex you know you you know you
you guys are going to have a lot of
kinesthetic Learners and just having
them of course the danger is sometimes
that can be a distraction where they
might be playing with it and not
listening to you but at least they're
they're getting some that any other
examples in here or maybe we can shift
over to questions yeah um take take your
students outside on campus public school
there yeah I mean the the the world is
our campus and then particularly now
with Technologies we can you know we can
travel around the world in a very easy
way where in the past it hasn't been
quite so easy so I think we've got a few
minutes for questions and so I'll take a
few questions so in terms of that
reflection oftentimes it's a lot
morei you know set of questions to take
home and read and write and respond and
yeah how obviously that's probably
better than nothing but how much better
than nothing is it well it is assuming
that the students actually do it it is
better than nothing but there there's a
concept now and I'm actually playing
around with it in one of my undergrad
classes it's called the flipped
classroom have you guys heard of that
terminology before it's the whole notion
of of let's take the basic knowledge
level stuff and do that as homework in
the form of online lectures and readings
and let's use class time then for the
deeper discussions and the reflections
on that and so you might think about you
know are there some ways that I can do
some things are there some things that I
can take out of the face Toof face time
to provide more opportunities for the
face Toof face time because I mean let's
face it I mean how many of you carry
around something that looks like this
most of you probably do and I hate to
break it to you but everything that
every one of us knows is available on
this little device and so the the
benefit our students get from us is not
the knowledge they can get the knowledge
anywhere they get the benefit of
interacting with us so that we can think
like a plant breeder or think like a
weed scientist or think like an educator
or think like a whatever you are think
like so the students can learn and
interact with us so that they can learn
to think like whatever it is we want
them to think like good yeah I'm think
about that first video with the young
mom saying very good very good very good
and I think it's Carol D who um had some
groundbreaking research that looked at
the impact of all of this positive uh
judgment essentially all of this praise
you're so smart you're so beautiful
you're so great is creating a generation
of risk averse Learners who are really
afraid to make mistakes and I think you
know we're seeing an impact of that in
our classes what are some very concrete
ways in which you have fostered um a
healthy risk taking in your teaching
yeah and so
the that's a a little bit expertise but
I can share some personal examples and
it's it's about creating an environment
where being unsuccessful is okay and
it's about learning from those mistakes
and and I teach classes on teaching
methods and so I teach all day about how
to teach and then conversely at the end
of the semester I ask my students to
evaluate my teaching so it's a little
bit intimidating to talk about the
entire semester about this is how you
teach good oh by the way evaluate my
teaching but I I will periodically throw
myself out there and say okay I just did
this activity let's critique it and so I
I model the behavior that I hope that
they can see and I also in the way that
I evaluate student work um I tend to be
very proactive in providing constructive
feedback and I try not to be penalizing
in the way
that I provide that feedback that you
know did you think about this what could
you do to make it better and to provide
some constructive feedback and and and I
also try to provide very quick feedback
to my students because if if we're
teaching a course where the concepts
build on each other and you T concept
one and then tested it and then you're
on concept before before you get
feedback from concept one the students
might have some misconceptions they
don't even know that they have by the
time that they get there um so that
that's our students at at Florida are
like that I mean they they've gotten
Straight A's their entire life and so
anything less than a straight A is
failure to them even though they haven't
earned a straight A
yeah you talked about being more
spontaneous sort of makes you a little
bit more vulnerable and that's okay
you're taking a
risk so doesn't make you less smart
obviously so you might get
respected in that situation see
that yeah that's it's it's the the
classroom comes a very fun and dynamic
Place although it can be a little bit
intimidating at times too because you
don't know what's coming
next yeah go
ahead uh yes in terms of giving
information uh students in many cases
you can say give a relationship between
two two factors in a uh table of numbers
or in a graph at least personally I gain
so much more and it sticks with me a lot
better if it's a a graph form I can see
the shape I can see the spacing between
effects or whatever uh get me comments
on that well and actually so and and for
a lot of people that is the way that
they like to receive information um I I
would encourage you to think about in a
given class of any size you're going to
have different kinds of students in that
class and and as instructors we tend to
be most comfortable teaching the way
that we like to have been taught when we
were students but to recognize that all
of your students aren't exactly the same
and so it's about presenting things with
some variety in the way that you do that
so that you present those those graphs
and those charts and and that's going to
reach those kinds of a student and then
you're going to you know deliver that
that fabulous lecture that's very
engaging and you're going to reach those
kind of students and then you're going
to do an activity that involves the
students out in the greenhouse house or
whatever and you're going to engage
those kind of students so it's really
about providing that variety of
different kinds of experiences um for
the students um but I would uh I would
look for opportunities and tying it back
to when we talked about the sensory
inputs look for opportunities to engage
all five senses when practical and and
when appropriate as opposed to to just
the visual and auditory that we often
do other question question yeah so we're
being uced to the muks where you have
10,000 students none of whom you can see
um and from what I understand in now and
the reflection and generalization part
of the uh learning process is really
done by small groups of students with
each other so that's about the end of my
knowledge right there but could you uh
touch on how this process works in that
giant
setting shipped into the online
environment it does create some
different challenges and it also creates
some opportunities and and um reflection
does not have to be just in small groups
it can be but you've got you're going to
have some Learners that are very social
in the way that they learn and and
they're going to they're going to want
to share with their peers but you're
also going to have some Learners that
are very introspective and like to think
things through themselves and so just
providing that pause time for them to be
able to do that and so in an online
environment it might be through uh some
sort of a discussion board where you
know maybe you're not forcing them to
respond to anybody else's thoughts
you're just giving them an opportunity
to put their own thoughts down or maybe
it's a uh a a guided reflective
reflective Journal where over the course
of of the class they've got to do an
entry once a day once a week once a
however that is structured um and so
it's it's you know there's as I said
earlier there's not a Magic Bullet that
is going to fit everybody which is is
challenging um but it also can be can be
fun because it gives us as the Educators
the opportunity to try out some
different things and to experiment a
little bit and and one of the things
that and I I try to model this in in my
own professional life too is it's about
not being satisfied with the status quo
and it's about trying out new things I
mentioned earlier I'm trying out the
flipped classroom and this is the second
semester now I've done that and I I went
through the learning cycle myself the
first semester and figured out some
things that worked and some things that
didn't work and so now I'll do that but
uh you know I'm I'm tenured so it's a
little bit easier for me to be a little
bit more flexible and spontaneous the
untenured faculty probably have to be a
little bit more focused and a little bit
more Norm reference yeah so are you
saying the flip
or FP what does it mean it means that
you so the has been that the face Toof
face time is the the instructor
lecturing and giving information and
then the students then outside of class
time take that information and apply it
through some sort of a problem set
homework project Etc the flipped
classroom does that 180 and so you
create a way to deliver the lecture part
outside a classroom perhaps through some
online recorded lectures readings those
sorts of things then you use the class
time the face Toof face time for uh
problem activities inquiry
activities uh those sorts of things to
where if we think about are you guys
familiar with Bloom's taxonomy and and
the levels of cognition so delivering
the lecture part that's often times at
lower levels of Bloom STX on
the problem sets are at the upper levels
of Bloom's taxonomy so we when they're
with us under expert supervision we're
doing a low level stuff we send them
home by themselves to work on the upper
level stuff they reach a problem where
they're struggling and they're stuck and
so the flip classroom you do that just
180 to where they're doing the higher
level stuff with you to where you're
helping them work through issues and
challenges and things um and so it's
again it it uh it has not been a perfect
switch for me I I'm knocking on wood
that this second iteration will go a
little bit smoother than the first
iteration um but it's and it's a
different model for the students because
the students aren't used to that and so
it takes a little bit of training on
their part to get them prepared for
thats like to get them not less focused
on grades yeah yeah you have to get them
focused on actual learning as opposed to
just getting the grade which that can be
challenging on some of these
students so are we how are we doing all
right
good than thank
you thank you
Geneva this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu