this is a production of Cornell
University thanks it's a great pleasure
to be here can you hear me okay yeah
good okay so yeah I'm really fascinated
by
size size is really important and it's
deeply fascinating question size is
fundamental to everything and it's
really important for yield but size is
not trivially important to yield you
might think we want things to be bigger
but we only want the right part of the
plant to be bigger we want the brain for
instance or the part of the plant we're
going to eat to be bigger but we want
the rest of the plant often to be
smaller to fit into a more plants into
the same field or the same growing space
and so if you think back to the Green
Revolution one of the key things was
making smaller plants with bigger grains
and here you can see prepr Evolution
wheat is larger plants smaller grains
postre evolution you got smaller pants
plants bigger grains so we need to
understand size breeders are very good
at achieving this but I think that if we
actually understand how size and shape
are controlled we can do even better and
size is one of the things we really
still don't understand that's so
basic so my lab studies this in
arabidopsis we like the arabidopsis seil
and the leaves for studying this um so
our sees are green um outermost floral
organ they enclose and protect the
flower bud so they're really defensive
organs and one of the reasons sees are
cool is that they have this amazing
pattern of different cell sizes in them
in a rops so they've got these giant
cells false colored here in red
interpers between smaller cells another
reason we chose seil is just that
they're on the outside of the flower so
they're really accessible for Imaging
and
manipulation another reason is that
there's four seil in each arabidopsis
flower so we can look at their size with
in a flower and say are all the seils
the same size or not and that's actually
important for their function the seils
need to be the same size to keep that
flower Bud close and keep all the uh
environment insects everything out while
the reproductive organs are
developing so seil are a great model
system we've now gone on to leaves which
are totally not a great model system but
a lot of people care about leaves and
guess what seil are like little leaves
so that makes me
happy okay so what we love to do in the
lab is actually image the plants as
they're growing and try to understand
how the growth and division of the cells
is giving rise to the size and shape of
the organ and so here we've got living
plants um and this this is one I did
back in the day taped onto a slide and I
image it every six hours and watch those
sequels grow so this is a flower bud you
can see here's one sequel here's one SQL
here's one Sequel and what you're seeing
is the fluorescent uh plasma membrane
marker outlining the cells and
fluorescent nuclear marker
you can see there's all kinds of
complexity going on here these cells are
not doing Simple Things uh some cells
are getting really big nuclei and
growing a lot other cells are dividing
and making a ton of smaller cells and
all of this is coming together to
coordinate so the seals are growing at
basically the same right despite the
cells doing all kinds of
things now I'm going to continue the
theme of image
analysis and say that we love to
understand this computationally through
computational image analysis this is
done in collaboration uh with Richard
Smith La with their amazing
morphographic software and I'll play
that again
hopefully so we've colored each
cell and all of its daughter
cells with the same color it doesn't
want to
play and so you can see that okay there
it jumped um one green cell gave rise to
this whole patch of green cells and one
red cell gave rise to this whole giant
red cell and so that's how giant cells
are forming they're growing and not
dividing the whole time whereas other
cells are
dividing so we can measure the growth
rates we can measure the growth
directions we can measure all kinds of
things from these images and that's and
also gene expression patterns so so
we're trying to put all of this together
to understand how this organ is
growing now we do a lot of molecular
genetic work that I can't possibly show
you in this eight minutes and come up
with Gene regulatory networks and I
don't expect you to understand anything
about this except that there's genes
interacting with each other giving rise
to something on that
something uh we like to model and we so
we collaborate this is with P fosa
Jordan and his post. Nicholas Russell to
model the growth and division of these
cells with their decision- making
process based on this Gene regulatory
Network about whether they divide or
grow and you can see we've got proteins
fluctuating up and down and what's
coming out of this model is a pattern of
different cell sizes bit like a seel
where we've got giant cells see here in
purple interspersed between smaller
cells in brown so you can see it's a
model give it credit it's not quite like
a seil but we're still getting that
pattern out of our Gene regulatory
Network one of the reasons I really love
modeling is not when it works like this
does but when it doesn't work when it
doesn't work it tells us what we're
missing we're like oh wait we hadn't
thought about this part or we don't have
it quite right yet those never get
published but they're the most important
models
actually so my lab is really focused
around two major questions three two
major questions one is how cells of
different sizes created during
development and we're really looking at
this how do you form giant cells in the
sea and the leaf both have giant cells
and we found this really interesting
role for stochasticity or Randomness in
this process we think about development
as being deterministic every
everything's programmed in but actually
the plant in this Cas is using
Randomness to generate this pattern so
that's exciting to us the second
question sort of the flip side of this
you've got all the cellular variability
how are organs made with reproducible
size and shape Des spite variability in
the cell growth the cell size cell
division gene expression all of these
things and so if you look at across
these rabitos flowers you can see they
all have four seal all the four seals in
each flower are the same size
and they're the same across flowers so
how does the plant do this how does it
make this reproducible structure from
this mess um and then we want to apply
this to engineering living
materials so we have um recently got a
grant from the National Science
Foundation in a big collaborative
biology integration Institute 12.5
million over six years with a huge
collaboration of people led by Pam suus
at University of Florida to study poly
because our giant cells are polyploid
they have more than one copy of the DNA
so we want to look across organisms and
understand what does having more copies
of the DNA do to the cells how does it
make them bigger what other properties
does it
have and then we also are very
interested in applying this to
engineering living materials our
materials are not sustainable and we'd
like to actually use the properties of
living organisms specifically bacteria
fungi and plants uh they have amazing
properties and can we incorporate them
into our materials into our buildings
into our even our Chairs into our
clothing to make them better and think
about what all of these organisms are
good at they use non-petroleum based
energy sources they can sense they can
adapt they can repair uh think about our
roads what do we hate about our roads
all these potholes roads cannot
self-repair but what if we incorporated
living materials into to them so that
they can self-repair how awesome would
that be okay that's a dream at this
point but it's a dream we've been
talking about uh Lori hberman is part of
this engineered living materials
Institute as
well and so there's a bunch of
challenges and speaking to the plant
path group I think one of the big
challenges is how do we incorporate
different organisms interacting with
each other because we know we're going
to have to have many ecosystems to do
this the challenge that uh most
fascinates me is how do we engineer this
shape and structure
and mechanical properties and growth of
these
organisms and we're starting this with a
buch of datom because they have silic
based frustules and they're
self-organized nanomaterials so look how
cool these little structures are how
they can make them at room temperature
this is worked by my postop Trevor cross
and that's it I'd like to thank my lab
for all of this inspirational work we
could not do this without amazing
collaborators both at Cornell and Beyond
and thank the ni and NSF for lots of
funding so happy to take
any thanks Adrian any
questions uh you showed some models and
I wonder how many parameters do the
models that you play with
have how many parameters models we play
with have um we try to keep the
parameter number as low as possible
because you know you can get anything to
happen in a model if you add enough
parameters so we're really trying to
limit it down to things where we have
some kind of biological basis that said
um there is some level of parameters you
have to have and most of the time we
have no biological information for those
parameters so we do a lot of parameter
optimization and look at in what regime
do we get the behavior we expect what
regime do we get other things and so
there's there's a lot to be done there
but yeah we're trying to keep the
parameter number
low
adamant giant is a consequence of
pooing our giant cell pooid
consquence
of that is a question I've been
wondering about for years and I um they
go hand in hand and we so far cannot
separate those two things and I think U
that's one of the things I would love to
do is separate we need something that
actually separates Floy from size and we
don't have it which tells you what a
universal principle that is so the
question is what's cause and effect and
it's totally unclear at this point
follow here so anything we learn
feature
from tests that create giant
cells in root yeah so those giant cells
are unrelated to these giant cells we
actually sent the molecular marker for
these giant cells to a group that was
working on that and yeah it didn't show
up so that was disappointing slightly
one of the things I should say
about these giant cells is that they are
little bios synthetic factories for a
lot of defensive compounds and our
plants that overexpress giant cells are
actually more resistant things like
powdery mildew and our plants without
giant cells are Little Farms of powdery
mildew um so there is some defense
response going on here that's really
interesting so thank
you hi everyone um my name is Holly tuon
I'm an associate professor in plant
breeding and genetics and just like
Justine even though she didn't mention
it I started with lightening with an E
so okay I'll just use lights in my title
slides so I'm going to give you a
lightning talk about our work and it's a
bit strange to be here because I
actually did my PhD in molecular plant
pathogen interactions and what I do now
is very different so in a parallel
universe this would be my department so
it's nice to be home so I'm going to
start with a premise this is very busy
but I'm going to give you the bottom
line and that is our aggra food systems
are driven by structural gender
inequality what that means is from value
chains reducing Distributing to the food
environment to Consumer Behavior are all
shaped by societal structural
inequalities okay this is pretty well
established at this point what we also
know is how women specifically engage in
these Agri Food Systems globally is
shaped by their agency social norms
their access and control over resources
and so on and so forth right so this
schematically tells you there's a
problem right there's a Global Gender
inequality Advocate systems which then
shapes outcomes from how people engage
in those Advocate
systems okay bear with me I'm giving
more intro slides because it's going to
be a little bit different from what
you've
watched so the most recent thinking in
the space says then if there is a
problem how do we Rectify it how do we
change it how do we what are the levers
of change towards more Equitable Agra
Food Systems tells us that we can look
at individuals engaging in Agri Food
Systems households community and so on
and so forth right there's different
layers where you can affect change to
really rectify the inequalities and
these look at institutional inequalities
power relationships agencies and social
institutions okay so we're going to come
back to this it's like a crash course in
gender inequality and Food
Systems within that system of Agra Food
Systems Innovations agricultural
Innovations are sub component right we
innovate we create new varieties we do
mechanization so that we make Farmers
lives easier right but what we know now
is again the latest thinking is
Innovations don't exist in a vacuum you
don't just develop a tractor and air
drop it right there has to be more give
and take with the communities who are
going to adopt it so the latest thinking
is around context dependent soci
technical Innovation bundle say that
three times very quickly what that
basically means means is as you're
innovating for an agricultural
technology you must know where that
technology will take place right where
will it how in people's lives will it
enter how will they use it how will they
interact with so you really need that
context
dependency and that's where we
are so by we I mean the equal lab we
call ourselves the Equitable
agricultural research lab we just set up
last year and really we take an
agricultural Innovation which is CR
Improvement that end to end from a
design of a plant variety all the way to
the release and Seed systems and we say
how can we really look at gender
equality and social inclusion in that
whole process okay now because these are
complex problems we can't just do it
unilaterally we need a group of people
from very different backgrounds so our
lab is kind of a hodge podge of
different disciplines and we all kind of
spend half our time trying to
communicate with each other but that's
the only way we can solve these complex
problems right so we have people who are
have plant reading backgrounds
economists anthropologists and we all
come together and I'll give you examples
of what that looks like we're not teed
to a geography we engage in a lot of
different projects so the sites of the
research tend to be very different as
well as crops we work on because it's
agnostic to a degree these inequalities
are pervasive right they're not in one
context but what brings us together is
how we research right using feminist
research networks uh Frameworks and
approaches and a lot of transer
interdisciplinary methods there's not
one solution to these problems and we do
a lot of collaborative research none of
this happens on our own we're constantly
communicating working with programs
globally so to sit this on some sort of
organizational principle Like You Justin
it's not a mess it's just range so the
way I look at it is we do work on data
generation which basically means we want
to understand what people in different
parts of the world and different social
heterogen 0 look for in prop varieties
right that's what I call data collection
traits varal preferences how do we
collect that we also do methodological
work that says how do you collect data
in a way that's more inclusive I'll talk
about that a little bit we try to
synthesize that up so we're giving the
right messages to the plant breeding
programs to say you should care about
this or that and then we do more
analysis of the research itself that's
the more fun part in my personal
opinion I don't have fancy videos so I'm
feeling a little disadvantage but I'll
show you some examples of our research
this may be very new and you're probably
thinking okay what does this look like
what what kind of research does this
culminate too so I'll give examples of
each on the left both of these graphs
are on casava in Nigeria so we do a lot
of work with breeding programs there and
the question the Breeders often ask is
who wants what what traits matter to
whom and why what varieties matter to
whom and why it seems easy very
difficult right so in years and years of
day have accumulated on what Farmers
want from traits but what we also know
is that farmers are not homogeneous
groups right they're very different
where they are what kind of households
they're living in matters so on this
rather busy plot on the left we're
trying to pull apart trait preferences
for these traits on the bottom through a
heat map here that we're showing it if
you're a woman or a man living in a poor
non-p poor household food secure
insecure four different regions you may
get different patterns of trait
preferences right readers don't like to
see this but we like to tell them it
matters context matters social heterogen
matters and this is for tray preferences
what you see here is What's called the
placket loose tree and all this is
telling you is these are varieties in
rank order depending on if the farmer is
a man or a woman and if they're
interacting with a man or a woman to
process you get different Bridal
preferences what does that mean we don't
know but what we know is it happens
because again people don't live in
bubbles right they interact with each
other and they may have different
preferences because of those social
interactions so the bottom line is we're
trying to move away from like these
homogeneous trait buckets and really try
to understand social heterogeneity right
at the individual
level moving a little bit up one thing
that I've become really interested in is
methods so what this means so imagine
you're going to a household you want to
ask people what kind of cassaba do you
like how do you do that right that
itself is a big question often it's
surveys but then you have to ask
yourself who's responding to the survey
there's a lot of power in politics and
who takes that survey so on the left
here you see a colel density plot where
we're asking husbands and wives from the
same household the same question what
how many cassava varieties do you grow
that are improved and then we go to the
field and we take the leash samples and
we compare them right what you see is
nobody's consistent right the husband's
responses and the wife's responses
differ from each other and they both
differ from the actual wi tissue now
here I don't want to say anyone's right
or wrong because when we go and do this
and we ask people at the plot level you
get a different picture my point here is
who you ask and how matters hugely for
adoption rates our assumptions around a
variety is adopted or not may be based
on wrong assumptions who you ask matters
hug right this is work in sagol and
kelpy where we had five different TRS
and we ask again husbands and wives for
their relative preferences up here
classic we separate men and women look
at the relative importance the I more
important but then what we did was we
took the same couples and we classified
them by agreement and disagreement on
who makes decisions in the household
right so then we're saying are there
some households that are more kind of
together and are there more households
where there's more disagreement does
that matter for the choices they're make
it readers don't like us when they see
this because it does matter right but
again we're trying to tease apart to say
how can we ask these questions so you
get good information oh I ran out of
time okay this is a scoping review we
did last year just to tell you looked
across all tra preference papers
globally for all crops and we ask the
question how are people collecting
information and what you see is it's
often direct questions so when someone
gets asked what do you like or not and
often we don't have data from women
that's the gender bias in the tot it of
the data is significant so we don't
actually have data on women's trade
preferences J is staring at me so I'm
going to wrap up here this is the
highest level work that I think is
really exciting where we turn the lens
back on the researchers themselves a
little bit and we say we are social
beings engaging in research we're not
robots right we have characters we have
histories we have social identities how
does that shape how we're actually doing
research there's a lot of theory out
there that shows that's true in other
fields so we have two sets of work
coming here looking at care
responsibilities of Faculty how do
faculty balance care responsibilities
and their social identities how does
that play out and the second one is
management leadership what does it mean
to be a woman in an international
agricultural research ecosystem and for
their management abilities and
perceptions so this is a much higher
level thing so I want to thank my lab
there's too many names to name here and
I try to put them on this spectrum of
work that we do um and thank you for
your
attention uh any
questions starting point in terms of
like what are
or interesting
um that would be good to look at we
don't often look at soil nutrient stat
and this is I think where disciplinary
practice comes in often these questions
are asked by economists if you look at
globally how the data is collect us
economists do these surveys a lot and
often it's just I ask you the question I
have a box and I ticket and I walk away
what we do control for is you're running
kind of like a regression you look to
see if there's any covariants that are
actually explaining some of that
variability so we do check if there's
things that are bigger than the actual
trade preference itself if that makes
sense so yes we do check that as much as
we can
I have a quick question so you're
generating data for trck preference as a
snapshot right contemporary do you have
any way of generating data on a
trajectory historically and forward for
the scoping review we tried to do that
for 50 years all crops to see what are
the trends and trade preferences the
biggest problem is
ontologies every study will Define a
trait in a different way and so
extracting that and relating them to one
another is hugely difficult because
there's no standard for social research
on traits you say yield I say Lo size
someone has to decide those are
equivalent to look at the totality of
the data set is something we're working
on right now to be able to synthesize
it hey everybody uh it's great to be
here I am happy to tell you a little bit
about my research and what I do today I
wanted to start off with a first slide
let's see let's get there here we are um
this is a photo taken outside uh just
yesterday um in this
uh photo you can see the Tower Road
lined with trees and and I spend a lot
of time thinking about how we interact
with plants in this kind of day-to-day
level outside of these agricultural
systems and in particular I focus on the
health relevant interactions that we
have with these plants uh this can
include everything from the uh the
services that these trees provide in
terms of cooling on a hot day through
both uh uh shading and transpiration
through to the removal of air pollution
such as particulate matter from the air
there's also a lot of work that shows uh
really extensive mental health benefits
uh through exposure to Green spaces uh
and all sorts of other ecosystem
services that are also Health relevant
at the same time we have all of these
negative interactions with plants
everything from the release of
allergenic pollen to the release of
volatile organic compounds like isoprene
which is a precursor to Ozone
formation even in the most urban areas
we still have
uh Landscapes that are filled with
plants for example New York City is
currently 22% of it is
forested about a year ago now there's
was some local legislation pass to try
and uh increased New York City's canopy
coverage of trees up to
30% um and one of the the major
justifications for this was people said
hey trees really improve public health
so let's have more of
that this is not just isolated toic City
and we're living at a time when cities
across the United States and the rest of
the world too are also channeling
resources into planting trees uh and a
little bit less into maintaining the
trees that they already have uh much to
the srin of urban Foresters and other
Urban free professionals U but it is uh
right now there's about2 billion do
being put into uh urban forestry in the
US through the inflation reduction
act however even though one of the major
motivations for this is improving Public
Health through making there be more
trees we don't really have a good
understanding of how uh many of these
trees how the individual trees interact
with individual people and so we have uh
a lot of these large scale patterns like
hey if a neighborhood has a lot more
green space in it it tends to be cooler
but when you get down to the level of
how is this individual tree transpiring
how is it providing shade uh we just we
don't have very good information at that
granular scale which is a problem
because those are the scales at which we
make decisions uh we don't uh tend to
say like oh we're going to change this
neighborhood we say no we're going to
plant a tree right here and then we make
decisions about where that tree is what
type of tree it is and so on and so my
goal and the work that's being done in
my lab focuses on quantifying these
interactions with plants in order to
improve the decisions that we make uh
often around uh Tree Management and so
on but also around uh our behaviors as
people too in order to improve uh the
health of uh people as individ uals and
as a broader group as well so I'm just
going to walk you through uh what this
looks like um I although you'll have to
excuse me because um this is a little
bit of a listicle right now sorry
everybody so focus on me not the boring
text um so one of the the major projects
that I have right now is looking at
allergenic pollen concentrations and
I'll tell you a little bit more about
that in a moment another major project
uh that uh I'm working on is trying to
uh understand the cooling effects of uh
trees in New York City on an individual
uh tree scale uh in order to understand
uh what heat exposure is like uh what
the health consequences are in other
words um how does that affect the number
of people who are going to the emergency
department during heat waves and
ultimately to to be able to um inform
decisions as like as we're making all of
these doing all of these Urban Greening
campaigns like when you plant a tree uh
it lasts for a long time and and so we
really should be figuring this out now
because the consequences of today's
decisions are going to last with us for
decades as part of this uh project um
I'm doing a lot of work with a post in
my lab uh Dave Miller trying to
um use remote sensing to identify
individual trees and because you can't
do a good uh a job of managing what you
don't know and so uh we're using some
new approaches uh uh incorporating the
the timing of uh various um life history
events for trees uh things like when is
it leaing out what color does it look
like in the to to try and untangle this
a little bit better so really using the
ecology to inform some of the remote
sensing
analyses now some of the other projects
that are happening in the lab now um uh
and touch a little bit on some of the
the associations between things like
neighborhood income or uh race and
ethnicity and uh how that is associated
with what trees are where uh and there
end up being uh it seems large Health
consequences for some of these things as
different types of trees provide
different Services uh so those are a few
of the projects that are happening in
the lab right now and for the last
little bit I just want to walk you
through uh an example of what one of
these projects looks like and so come
with me to Texas now uh and take a look
at Ash Juniper which is uh one of the
most common trees in Central Texas
as you can the uh gray things you see
here um are not clouds in the sky those
that is pollen being released from this
tree uh just to give you a some context
here uh people begin to experience
allergic reactions to this pollen at
concentrations as low as uh 10 or 20
pollen grains per cubic meter of air
uh one a single pollen cone on one of
these trees has about half a million
pollen grains in it and you might see up
to a million pollen grains uh a million
pollen cones excuse me on one of these
trees um and so what we're trying to do
is uh to understand uh both what the
health consequences are through
epidemiological analyses um as well as
to create operational pollen forecasts
it it turns out that uh most of the
pollen forecasts that you might find
through your weather app they're total
garbage they're just like unvalidated
like completely um well I'll pause for
right now on it but there's a lot to be
said I'll hold myself back um and so
some of the approaches that we take are
uh doing field work so uh field
campaigns to take manual measurements uh
we also work uh with uh citizen science
organizations especially the national
technology Network to enlist people to
help us take these measurements um then
we also do a lot of scaling up uh to to
try and understand um what is happening
with individual plants and then to take
that up to uh a site level and
ultimately to Regions or across an
entire State and someday I hope across
the entire country uh so uh some of the
processes that we try and understand are
fairly simple like how much pollen is a
plant producing uh and so Justin I'm
really excited to uh think with you
about some of the methods that you've
been using because um we too hate
counting and trying to avoid it as much
as possible um other types of things we
try and understand are when uh pollen is
being released or how it moves through
the air uh I think that's uh most of
that project there's a lot of cool
things about uh the the intricacies of
the remote sensing we are using but if
you want to know more about it you'll
have to uh come stop by my lab uh say hi
we're up in Bradfield looking forward to
talking with you all more
thanks question well I I will make an
observation so I think it's what's
exciting is to see some of this
wonderful work and urban plant science
right and we've just hiring a new Urban
plant ecologist AR SE will'll be joining
us very shortly and I can see already
all sorts of threads that connect him
with you and also Justine and Z so we're
sitting here and uh listening to these
talks
right just a question do you also have
models with a bunch of
parameters um sometimes it it depends on
the type of model uh we try and do some
model uh so basically a lot of this is
trying to create predictions and so uh
we are often okay with throwing a lot of
things and seeing what sticks generally
we do try and you know like think about
like what is most biologically
meaningful and take the things that
don't have much predictive
value okay thanks thanks
yall this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu