this is a production of Cornell
University have you seen any local
effects of extreme weather and and
climate change in in the years
especially that especially because you
you're native here to Duchess County uh
yes I have it seems like the uh
winterers are getting much milder uh
we're getting more I think think more
severe weather as we head south seems to
be getting more snow more cold uh
Winters are not nearly as bad
uh we've had three major weather events
in the last couple years one two years
ago the excessive snow throughout the
winter uh last fall with the uh you know
being hit by tremendous amounts of rain
the hurricane and then this winter with
I don't ever recall a winter of this
uh as easy as it was I've gone through
snowless Winters but never with as mild
as it's been we didn't have a winter
actually and we didn't have a winter and
I see uh a lot less hay was fed a lot
less hay was used
uh which is you know a double-edged
sword it's good for those that didn't
have to buy high but it's poor for those
of us that sell high or it's it's an
issue uh what the insect population or
and
the bad bugs that weren't killed uh in
today's paper there was a major thing
about uh you know lime disease being you
know perhaps the banner year for Lyme
disease so I'm I'm really concerned over
what's coming down the road even though
I
can't predict I can only hope things
won't be as dire as they may be what
happened to your farm during the extreme
weather events and how much money you
think you lost how did it affect
you uh of course it started in in April
last year with the fact that we had so
much trouble getting the crops in uh
just you know we got them seated and we
couldn't go even go back and roll them
roll them pick up Rock uh which in turn
we probably got a poorer catch of seed
than we should have so that that
bothered us you know just little little
things that you know don't always add up
the fact that you have to
send people again and again back to the
field because there's big wet spot you
had to go around and stuff like that it
takes a lot more time we lost probably
half our oat crop because we couldn't
get it we couldn't Harvest it in the
window that we had it went down we lost
a lot of it uh
uh the biggest thing that's bothering me
right today is that we left probably
$115,000 worth of
hay uh second cutting grass hay in the
field that we could not Harvest last
fall we made many attempts we got some
in but we do a lot of hay so we we left
$15,000 worth a hay in the field which
is really financially bothering me right
now strap me uh we lost a field of corn
uh uh that was you know a lot of it was
management fault for not chopping that
field we left it for grain thought we
could get it and we got the late
snowstorm and it was very tall corn and
it took it down so we lost we lost a lot
of corn over there so we probably lost a
minimum of 40,000 or so in crops you can
as a farmer you can
you can weather the
storm but you can't weather continuous
storms uh you can you can take it on the
chin you can uh you know you you come
back spring brings Eternal hope and
that's as a farmer that's what's that's
what fuels me that's what you know as I
as I become alive I mean this winter you
know as the warm weather comes you we
all feel like doing more and as the
farmer it's it's just so much easier you
know we we think again this year I have
this probably skewed Vision that this is
going to be the best year
ever this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu