this is a production of Cornell
University so uh we're gonna shift over
to our our our farmer panel so we have
uh Jay goldmark and Dean James who will
be talking about reducing tillage in a
diverse propop rotation so uh really um
grateful to have uh Dean James and Jay
up uh so uh Dean is coming from
Pennsylvania Jay is coming from uh yeah
Central New York so Jay goldmark from
Stonehouse grain in Livingston New York
Jay manages Stonehouse grain a 2500 acre
organic grain Farm outside of Hudson New
York the farm grows a diverse rotation
of grains legumes hay and cover crops
while finishing several hundred
grass-fed beef each year Stonehouse
grain also runs an on-farm Mill that
processes grains uh that they grow as
well as grains from The Wider Community
uh they make animal feed and also um uh
do some food grade grains as well so uh
really uh grateful again to have Jay
here to share with us what they're doing
down at Stonehouse and then I'm also
going to introduce Dean James at the
same time the other panel member so Dean
James U from uh don Cotner farms uh in
Danville Pennsylvania so really uh
wonderful to have a Pennsylvania farmer
come up to New York and uh share with us
so Dean James manages um yeah the farm I
mentioned a fourth generation Farm
consisting of 1700 Acres cot Farm Farms
started their organic journey in Spring
of 2020 so somewhat new to organic
farming but a long and deep history of
noil and uh and so uh Dean James has U
Been no tilling um for on the farm for
over 50 years they now have um but in
terms of organic production they now
have 200 Acres from what I understand in
certified organic production and they
grow uh corn soybean Rye oat oats uh
spring wheat hay and sunflowers I'm sure
Dean will tell you a little bit more
about that when he he speaks the farm is
also affiliated with boy station a
processor for organic soybeans and
canola so really happy to have these
guys here so why don't we welcome them
with a round of
applause all right Jay okay hi good
morning everybody can you hear
me all right um it is a pleasure to be
here somewhat intimidating so bear with
me um it's so good to see many of you in
person I talked to a lot of you on the
phone more than I see you in person so
really great to to be here um I manage
ston housee grain we also call it ston
housee Farm uh we Farm down in h outside
H just north of pipy and south of Al
that springs on the east side of the
river
um a little bit about the farm um we
grow a lot of the typical organic grains
for feed like corn soy beans in food
great stuff like Black beans penil beans
um spring peas winter peas then the
medle of small grains um and we do some
experimental stuff with sunflowers and
flats and oats um we get the idea um the
cool thing is we brought a nonfarm
animal feed mill and a balanced uh P Tre
diet calls for a lot of cool stuff that
we can grow in a diverse crop rotation
like uh soybeans corn peas wheat trale
barley too so by having the market on
our farm that calls for diverse set of
grains it makes us grow a diverse set of
grains that's probably really good for
our soil um we've been Organics since
practicing Organics since 2013 we just
celebrated being 10 years old still
pretty new um and certified in
2017 um most of our grains like I said
we we mill on the farm it's really
simple we run a Arts way grinder mixer
and then you know make different animal
feed products um poultry layers is
probably our biggest seller uh followed
by soyf free poultry layer and then hog
feed uh here's a look at the overview of
the farm um you know we kind of color
code everything to try and map out the
logistics so we're not running all over
the county um you know the basic
rotation is corn soy or peas uh followed
by small grains under so into perennials
and then depending on the field and soil
type uh if we're really hungry to keep
supplying the mill with grain will go
back into corn um but if the soil's not
ready we'll kick it into a longer term
PID perennial pasture that then supports
our grass fed beef part of the operation
so that the two main pressures they feel
like a pressure when you're managing the
farm is you got to grow grain from the
milk and a lot of different grain so
that's kind of good pressure uh and then
the other is you got to make a lot of
feed for the cows uh and that's good for
the soil so I think by having cows and
having the feed mill it it makes it
challenging but it overall really makes
it so you're you're growing a diverse
set of crops in a long-term rotation
that ultimately benefits the soil and
the energy you have there to C around
anything you
want um here's just a real basic look at
the the rotation it's it can get more
complicated than this when we grow some
of the specialty crops but in general
just like uh you know a
stand just like a standard of
jazz song that starts out with like an
eight
bar or yeah an eight bar chord you can
improvise from there so this is our
fouryear cord of you know corn and then
into ease and then into roll and crimp
Ry noil soybeans and then pack into
small grains and if everything looks
good you're P into core um and then I
guess the point is after you undo your
red clover your grasses into small
grains that's where you can lengthen the
crop rotation to really build soil
health and make hey or if you got fence
and water you can you can graze it for a
few
years um so we all know how to grow corn
like like this it takes a lot of work
but it's got pretty consistent High
yielding
results and then you know in that prop
rotation you need soybeans so you grow
them after corn and you can grow them
like this and cultivate them uh with
pretty reliable re results too um but uh
the moment you st out soybeans because
you need peas to satisfy the soyf free
customers that are buying your your
poultry feed um you plant your cool
season Yellow grain peas in year two F
and corn and then you harvest them in
mid July and then you can do some cool
stuff you can plant cover crops
uh like a um rais Crazy Summer Mix from
Rod there um they don't get that still
got plenty of time to put on some
biomass um and you can chop it or graze
it or make bage to finish beef on that
uh and then still plant your fall Ryan
for that midt day too and that sets you
up for soybeans in your
three um so that's kind of a unique
thing you've got your um your big grass
crop corn and then you go into your cool
season legum peas then you do another
warm season legum
soybeans um so it helps kind of break up
that typical rotation and then know
here's a great example of grazing your
warm Seasons um they seem to gain really
well on the a race grazing
mix uh here's just a look at I can't
remember which warm season this is but
you also can just do nothing instead of
hurrying up to plant your Fall Ride just
let it um winter fill and then we've had
Lu no tilling spring wheat
into win killed warm
season um or we no till winter week into
that as
[Music]
well and then if we're trying to
terminate warm season just to hurry up
and plant another cover crop sometimes
doesn't always make sense
but um for no till soybeans that's what
Plan called for so we go out there in
early September and hit it with the
highs speeed disc uh this was a mix from
over Le the 10 away um mix with sorum
cityan CIS on so on um yeah those warm
seasons are so cool that to break up
compaction in in the
[Music]
heavier there we go
and it's it's Rocky you can
hear that field I didn't realize this so
that field is where we grew no tail corn
this year uh that's
interesting um so when we uh yeah we
high speed disc the warm seasons and
then with a no till drill slices right
through it again in our ride and like
Aaron was saying we our rotic RI to the
acre and really try and get it in by mid
September and then if all goes
well um the following late May is when
nesis typically hits us around Hudson we
can lay it
[Music]
down um and then we're out there um this
is a field we did no till soybeans on
it's a really heavy clay field uh it the
moment we try and fill it in the spring
it just turns into a disaster so this
was actually a great way to treat a a
heavier soil field um not to till it at
all so sometimes the joke is well no
till yields less um but then on a field
like this it it yields more than if we
would have killed
it um so yeah what what Matt and Kristen
were good about like okay uh talk about
what motivated you to try planting notto
um and on the farm uh when we're trying
to run around say 1500 Acres of
cultivated crop ground you just start to
run out of time um and so it's it seems
like um a well balanced portfolio to
have you know 70% of the farm or some
ratio of the farm in
cultivated Acres but then to try and
Target some of your soils that maybe you
least ground far away from the shop or
some ground that just it's hard to tell
to keep that in no till uh Because by
the time you finish Road crop
cultivating corn and then soybeans uh
the crew is pretty tired of running late
nights and then when you get up to oh we
still have like 200 Acres of soybeans
and then oh those are no beans everybody
breeds the S Rel you don't have to do
anything um so it it's pretty cool to be
able to plant no till and then uh
kind of walk away and go back and take
pictures and come that Harvest
Time um I see a lot of photos I'm so
glad
that Aon Silva showed photos of harvest
time because you look at all the awesome
seed catalogs and often times you see
photos in like late June early July the
soybeans are really nice and clean the
corn is nice and clean um but then of
course they don't show all the the warm
season weeds to come on in Mid July and
August uh so I thought I'd throw this
clip in this is our this is a no soybean
field um you know hardly any broadlees
we do have a lot of box steel pressure
there um so it it goes right through
theine after a frost
[Music]
filling night but of course we do
scatter some weed seeds
there um I guess that uh overall seems
like we're finding a place in the
rotation to experiment planting noil
with winter wheat spring wheat into
those warm season mixes like I
mentioned um and just relay cover croing
so if we get better at um you know with
a warm season instead of discing it you
could just run right through it uh with
cows and graze it and then no till in
you're R um you know trying things like
that uh and then of course any
opportunity we have to Frost seed
clovers or mustards or if we're going to
after small grains go into a a longer
term pasture we
just there's ways to frosted your your
grass um
so some of the exciting things we did
this year were uh related to noil Horn
uh like Aon Sila said don't try this on
a large scale uh we did it with the Ryan
lab On th Acres which is the largest
Mount we've ever done so this is that
same field I think two years prior it
was in that warm season mix that we were
highpe ising it's kind of it's got some
rock it's kind of cobbly uh and this
year since last year 2024 um it uh it
dried out um but what was cool is that
uh see I don't know if you can tell but
that picture on the right with the
planter uh we're just planting right
through standing bench um we've never
done that before the Ryan lab really
encouraged us to try it out and it
worked really slick um so this was June
10th uh and a room full of farmers June
10th is the last state you can ensure
your corn crop at 100% uh rate so that
worked out pretty cool that we could
still ensure no tail corn at the at the
five 100% of the 5year car average
um here we are June 19th so 9 days later
I me I plant notes of corn you just walk
away and look like nothing's going to
ever grow there um but the corn started
to come up um and this was during that
heat wave uh you know we were in a
drought and the you know our another
look at our cultivated corn on the same
day you know the Headlands are starting
to to wilt there um but that little
Spiker corn doesn't even know it yet it
seemed pretty
protective let's see so five days later
we are rowing up through the through the
rolling crimp very vetch can't remember
if we rolled it by this point but we
basically really didn't need to even
roll and crimp the vetch just by
planting into it standing and the the
Heat and drought conditions of the the
double disc open on the planner seemed
seem to slice and kill the VCH so when
we did roll it probably around there or
maybe just a little bit before there um
you know flatten the corn in the one to
two we stage but the corn came right
back again something I never would have
tried it's the Ryan lab and said yeah
we've done it try it out and it worked
um and then the corn kept and I just
kept doing great even though it was a
really weird hot dry year um you know
August 5th we started the tel out uh on
that 30 acre block we did five different
varieties uh shortest day was 88 the
longest day was
102 um so here we are at Harvest Time um
out of the five
varieties yeah here's the
[Music]
97 but you kind have to see it to
believe it I never thought this would
work out this well
um uh SMI who's R the combine here was
just over the
moon just said like over 200 per second
um I think that variety averaged
126 o was an acre over a 9 acre block of
just that variety U then the 102 day did
um what did it
do
132 no sorry the 95 day did the best at
P anchor um so I was you know joking
last night I think if if we did this on
a large scale I want hydraulic down
pressure on a planter um but it gave us
kind of a crazy amount of confidence to
to keep keep experimenting and scaling
this up it seemed to work really well
even on a dry year um but I think it
depends on your soil type too I mean we
did a control we did till I think 5
Acres of that field we yeah we plowed
down 5 Acres of that field for control
and planted 95 day horn and it it dried
out and definitely was imped by lack of
moisture here's just another few clips
for no planting soybeans and roll
PR here we are when I was working with
Jeff at the farmhub we were Zone
building through standing ride uh before
planting dry beans and this was just an
attempt to try and actually the soil was
really wet and cold so we were trying to
um get through the ride before we rolled
it so we wouldn't Wad and ball up um and
so we're loosening on the the seed zones
and aerating the soil and warming it up
and then a couple days later we came
back in and rolled
it which was kind of scary because then
we thought oh no we can't find our feed
lines anymore but around the same time
we were learning about how to how to
share GPS lines which is really cool
with organic farming because now you can
create these layers and layers um so we
then came back and planted on the same
pre R zone with the
planter um and I don't have any pictures
of the of the beans we but they they
turned out really good and we're still
trying to grow beans as good as we did
back uh these on were P beans think it
was like
lar beginn
[Music]
Lu uh here's just a close look of like a
a the seed trench in the soy you can see
the anyway uh you see that we use micro
risal inoculant in the C box um just to
try and help the bi the SE and help it
partner with microbes in the soil and if
you look on that picture on the right
there's like a little cat mushroom there
too so there's a lot of biology
underneath that that stat
of um what we're learn about noil um
like as already today uh noil soy beans
works really well um know till corn is
still a bit of a wild card but uh I'm
I'm pretty excited about it and uh it's
so hard to scale organic farming I mean
2% of all us Farmland is organic
certified um there's a reason for that
and I think one of the reasons is really
really diff diffult to for a family farm
and one Farm operation to grow and scale
in size just because cultivation is a
real um
bottleneck um so how can we do it I
think through just Innovative noil
techniques when you could a 12 row or or
you know a nice big planter go out um
and plant a lot of corn uh into into
standing veg that that could be a good
day um so we still really don't know
what to do after we plant no till corn
because there is the vetch that comes
back um so we typically just kick it
into a air rotation to manage the the
vet and makes great great
Forge and then we're going to keep
experimenting with different fall cover
crops to set up um for notil corn uh bch
and oats is kind of our standard you
know see 30 pounds of bch 100 pounds
oats
um and then the Max and fixation mix Le
is pretty interesting we've been growing
that as a as a coverop for plow down
corn um but then we started to let it go
too long and it started to Bunch up and
create problems for the plow uh and then
on one piece we saidd don't even plow it
let's just plant right into it and
that's started to work pretty good too
um and then always interested what
happens when you you do less so with a
warm season crop we have established
after PE um you know if we graze it with
our cows and let it Naturally Winter
kill maybe we touch it up once with a
high disc and plant corn um so those are
some kind of
low uh low impact ways we're thinking
about going forward um but like uh erand
that small and scale up um if things are
working well
that's it thank
you so I think we have time for one
question maybe for Jay while we switch
slides so if there's anyone that has a
burning question there will be time
after uh Dean presents as well for
questions but if anybody wants to uh ask
Jay about what he was just talking about
yeah this would be a good time to do it
any problems with
slugs yes um we've never done anything
about it but we go out and count them
especially our our neighbors will call
and say hey yeah we just had to replant
you know a bunch of soy soy that you
check you scattered your Fields they're
they're out there um and that's maybe
why some of the fields are a little less
with noil stor I'm guess that's what
you're talking about yeah um you know
just
spray I think we're going to shift over
here so yeah really inspiring and great
to see some of the the results from the
work at Jay's place there so Dean going
to take over now and tell us about what
he's been up
to
but lot of familiar faces here um I
think it's really good between Matt and
Aaron I mean they're pretty good
Educators that's where we learn we've
been no till on Farm like Matt said for
50 some years so when the work came down
from up above we should try this organic
thing we really hung our heads but we
went out and did like a lot of you guys
we spent a lot of time on YouTube and
podcast and everything and and uh
decided that we'd try this um through
transition especially and see how we
made out this is just a picture of some
roll down Ride This is how we do a lot
of our conventional farming and how we
knew that this stuff could work and
we've even tried things on the
conventional side in case it got out of
hand we could control just to evolve it
into the
organic this was our corn experiment the
first year we went into with a lot of
high folks um we had our leges there was
crimson clover and vet and of course the
Rye um we waited until the ride was in
an to plant horn um the way we do it we
see Road Dale you know there's a lot of
guys talking about roller crimping and I
don't know how you guys did it Matt roll
you know crimp her eye and implanted our
thing has always been play and then
crimp um and it was good to see you got
Aon talk about that the other thing we
often thought was because we could print
later we could actually kind of go a
little bit against the drain you know on
an angle so things would cover the row
up keep the weeds out of the row but
this this was our mix this is what we
were doing um but there again it was a
learning curve because the Rye was ready
to be rolled the crimson clover and the
vet was not so we went both ways on this
field to get the ride down and the
crimson just grew back up and we had to
come back later on and roll that
also um this is kind of what it looks
like I good pictur like to see I think
that's actually some some s and2 inch
beans that we've done too so we've been
there um our first year there again on
the bean side was we were at O greens
and you know we went out to supper and
there was a guy from Wisconsin or
Michigan and he was talking about non
vertil ride he spoke up pretty highly
that so we tried that we tried the Romo
Pro concept pushing the lawn mower up
and down the roads we you know but
because we wanted to stay the noil the
covered soils um you know they say it
takes what 200 years to develop an inch
of soil top soil so it's pretty critical
and you know let's say having been NOA
for for as long as we are that's been
the big thing is the uh CAU out the
erosion so this was this was a picture
after the corn was coming up it uh looks
pretty good you can see the closure
laying there we thought we were off to a
pretty good start couple of broad leaves
there um down here in the
corner you can kind of see some vets
that that wasn't taken out but a little
bit was not a big deal we figured we V
but then as the season went on this is
what we were seeing stand wasn't there
um we contacted different folks and
talked about it and they were thinking
it was a planning depth issue um but I
need to quantify that with our planner
we do have a a plan with hydraulic
downforce so it was not an issue there
um I kind of highly recommend if you're
going to plant through thick covers is
is to have that and if you're not plant
the end Rose first because you won't get
a stand on the endr where the r is laid
over it really is harder to get through
and we had airbags on the last planner
and uh we're not able to plant through
until we've got the hydraulic down
flors um we don't run a road cleaner in
this we don't run a a colder in this
it's just a double dis openers and as as
things have progressed we realized that
we don't need a sep
F but this to this is some things that
we we were seeing uneven emergence V5
and V3 form right there next to each
other so we knew the yield wasn't going
to be really good
um but we did did did get it all and uh
it yielded like 65 bushel so we thought
we're not going to throw it out we
figured we got to try it again second
year it turned dry eyes between the deer
and dry weather we never ran the combine
through the field so we've been pretty
discouraged but it's good to see Jay
offer some encouragement maybe there is
a way to make it work um this was
another experiment that we ran we were
transitioned in this field this was a
year prior to trying to grow Suns Sun
flowers so we decided our planner was
wide enough we wanted to try three
scenarios go through the roller Crim
grow through some work ground and then
plan green um the one thing we found was
that the only place we had any stand was
where it was be ground so that kind of
toss that out I'm not sure if anyone
else's has done that or not with sons
but um it'd be nice to be able to do it
um after seeing the erosion there and
talk about the hard rainfalls that we're
getting nowadays and it is it's kind of
a tough thing to see your soil
walk um the birds made out really well
on the sunflowers there they cleaned
them all in that
year so this is this is kind of where
we've evolved to now we're we're still
trying to
grow beans and Ry and we know that if uh
if we're going to do that we've got to
have a good stand to ride one thing that
we've learned through Penn State about
small grains is to get it tillered out
and so this ground had had the layer
maneuver spread on it prior to the the
riding plan and you can see that picture
was just taken last early last week so
you can see how it is hopefully it'll
it'll do what we want to do with it but
that's one thing to keep in mind is is
you got to make a judgment call on your
stand when when you do this when you're
playing beans because if you don't
you're going to have a mess you're going
to have Ry coming in the row and beside
the row you can't get cated out and
we've done that already we've taken a
field of ride out that didn't didn't uh
look like it was going to do what it was
supposed to
be there's another picture of that
ride so um we've evolved through a lot
of a lot of different things um we
wanted to try playing some beans into a
good stand of winnery so this is this is
what we did um
it's it's come a long way the one thing
that uh we did have do after was
planned this this is roller roller crimp
um the one thing on roller crimpers our
is a 30 foot roller crimper but it has
three sections um to do it again we'd
rather have more sections for uneven
ground so it follows the ground
Contour seem the legings are not not
hard to kill but it's the grass it's the
the R and and they do continue to suck
suck moisture out of the soil it doesn't
kill it immediately
so this is the field of beans a little
bit
later you can see there's a few broad
leaves coming in
there um there it is U we did go back
through that a with a high residue
culator um those beans did 35 Bush
course which was a little off far
average but some of the thoughts where
that field is really stuning kind of
Drive so we're wondering if that's not
what it is but we're willing to try it
again so if there are um so at this
point we're going to transition over to
uh more of a discussion so uh we have
some if you have questions for the
panelists this is the time to ask um we
have some questions that um we are
thinking about as well but want to turn
it over to you first and just see uh
based on what you were hearing a lot of
discussion about reducing tillage in
organic systems again trying to protect
our our soil Health that we've worked so
hard to build up um but I thought yeah
some very interesting stories from from
Jay and from Dean so uh I don't know if
anyone in the audience has any questions
wants to uh kick things off for the
panel discussion at this
point in the back I was wondering either
of you considered or saw did any side by
side see there any value
start we we typically we put fish in the
row
I'm not sure the rate that we put fish
in the road and also chal to the side
just try to get going in the corn there
the pictures I showed to the roll down
covers we knew that you know there was
going to be a lot of nit high up and
that's the one thing that's kind of
tough to get past is you know the ride
um so we know that there is a lot of
that I in the conven side keep talking
about about that but you know we
overcame the ride some folks called
mopath
in by adding like 60 units in we weren't
able to do that on the organic the form
so we kind of backed off trying to do
anything now
with this okay uh we haven't done any
side by side uh trials by the time we
finished the cultivated
to get to the no tail ground we try to
leave the planner just the exact same
way it's set up so we put down uh liquid
micronutrients and organic Gem and and
bio SE Ulin um it's interesting because
it doesn't really go down in with the
sea because it's riding on top of the
mulch it's going out through the Katon
seed permer but I think the liquid's
getting close to the seed and that's
what we're hoping for there's biology
around the seed
the answer is
[Music]
no your sunflower comment brought up a
question that came up when I was at
Purdue at conference we had people
saying that sunflowers do great no till
into rye and we had other people saying
we plant Rye after sunflowers because we
know it'll kill them so there won't be
any volunteers what came out of it was
that there were some varieties of
sunflowers would work with certain
varieties of Ry been great and other
varieties of sunflowers been killed by
the
r and it would be an interesting thing
to assign to Matt or somebody in
your can we figure out which varieties
work with which varieties but I wonder
if that fits any of
your it was just that one time we did
that and that could very well be you
know what it was
um sounds like maybe we ought to try a
little something again if nothing you
know other than just on an experimental
basis because there is a lot of a lot of
erosion in the in the
sunflowers that's it's good to have CLA
asked questions because everybody
thinking we may not find answers and I
think that's the whole or got lots of
questions but the answer may be fleing
but we can can have ideas and the first
you look into things is to why things
are you may find some something to pop
up that you didn't even know that you
can
I'm going to throw another observation
out to you in that discussion we do
there was a researcher who had been
noticing with wheat in the Carolinas
where they they'll double crop and plant
soy beads after wheat and he was
suddenly noticing that certain varieties
of we of some of soybeans would yield 10
to 20 bushel better after certain
varities of Queen he found an
interaction and he started looking at if
you're going to be double cropping after
wheat which variety of wheat would work
which variety of soybeans
afterwards and it was one of those
things that never got followed up but I
think be really useful in noil and it
may take out one variable that's causing
problems yeah that's really cool I
immedately think of animals too just
because uh you have Ang a her and T
doesn't mean they're all the same um eat
every plant
different characteristic and
[Music]
personality I should say that about half
of our research a agenda in the
sustainable cropping systems lab is
coming from from Claus and his
suggestions about things that we should
be doing so really appreciate uh the
Martins and and all their contributions
um no but really interesting ideas here
other comments questions Emily in the
back thereal
going yeah when I was when I was
talking you hear good and I were
catching up before this and was like
yeah Jay you traveled far enough away
from the par that you're considered an
expert now I don't know about that but
yeah back on the farm we're just such
crazy
um because what we do is so different
but I do feel like I was connecting most
with some of our neighbors who no till
uh with using chemicals but they were
really excited to see what we were doing
with the no till core into standing har
bch I that's something that they can do
too um so I feel like we were we were
bonding over
that yeah yeah a question are you you
doing any type of boot grade small
grains or anything and how was the vet
have you had any issues with vet and
those
volunteers why did you have to ask
that yeah uh yeah we we do grow a
Paramount third grade wheat um and we
can't do that where we are experimenting
with throwing no corn or really
[Music]
no down down our way they say grow V it
gets attached to the it's always
there uh you guys
experimented no taing your beans for
something more
than maybe double
15 we have the first year I referred to
that non ver ride 30in beans and also
drill be um the drilled be for the
cleanest out we got to draw that but
overall the biggest thing that we've
learned about organic is you got to have
plan A B C and sometimes the plan B and
the 30in roads have allowed us to have
that and so that's kind of why we're
staying on we're staying on 30 in
Road I know there's some folks near us
um and they're pushing like 250,000
population out no convention just so
they don't have to come up going sh out
um so yeah the one one thing that we
found too I mean in the not we have
mayale on our area and and with the no
the covered crops tend to crowd that out
so that may be
something yeah same my my experience is
the same as we've got it on 30 in in
with a 7 in crin drill um and then we
got into as well uh just uh tilling as
you know doing the same kind of seat bed
prep with tillage and then planting
light like in mid June uh after the you
know first summer flush of weeds come
and then just rotary hoing the soy beans
on S to control that actually worked out
pretty
well y
a question for you J have
[Music]
you running have you ever time we beans
and how many times have you been over
control Leeds
in um okay yes uh we kind of need a lot
of beans come on mik
up
okay um okay maybe just put that thing
down and project uh yeah we time we a
lot too it's basically comes down to
soil type if we've got you know really
heavier soil we go rotary H because it
can it can crack open the soil a little
bit more um and the time heer is great
on lighter soil um depends on the skill
of the operator too anybody can rotary
ho I think but the time reader is really
delicate with the settings um so will
rotary h a lot like sometimes especially
Fe
like times and
it all right well I think we're gonna
wrap it up there but Jay and Dean will
be here all day I think and um please
feel free to follow up
so this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu
but