grow your own food if you can if you
can't support if you can't grow a lot of
your own go to farmer's markets okay um
i brought with me on this trip
homemade fig preserves okay y'all don't
know if anybody ever eats pig preserves
a bunch of yankees y'all don't know
anything and y'all eat blueberries
rhubarb eaters i'm surrounded
figs grow well with no care at all in
the south they're predictable i made
these figs my children helped me pick
figs two weeks ago we made fig preserves
from their great great grandmother's
victory okay my kids know about climbing
in it they know about picking and all
that
sorting mouth getting you know the
getting the bad ones out cutting the
stems off all those details making fish
when the revolution comes my wife who's
a hot shot lawyer she says that lawyers
can be among the first to be lined up
and shot okay but people who can grow
food will be spared
okay
so my kids
know that they've been to vermont and
they know that they can get vermont
maple syrup and every pigley wiggly
y'all know what picky wiggly is
every pink new eagle in mississippi has
vermont maple syrup but you got to know
somebody get homemade thick desserts
okay this is slow food but it's also
slow gardening because we're enjoying
being and we will have something sweet
in the middle by the way i brought a
case of this and a friend of mine over
in pennsylvania swapped me out some
strawberry rhubarb preserve
is this is he playing a joke on me
i mean it's not going to hurt to eat it
so that's what slow guarding is if you
want a real quick run down i've got a
list of a few things that you can do
that you already do these things but you
don't think about them okay you don't
think about sharing with others you
don't think about talking with children
about gardening there's some fantastic
children's gardens all over the new
england all over the country
but all you have to do is bend down and
wiggle your finger in the grass and talk
about whatever you find with a child if
you're lucky it'll be a roly-poly okay
but if you just talk with a child for a
little while and engage them you can
change that child's attitude about not
only the world but maybe about grown-ups
okay so that's what slow gardening is go
to my website
i'll tell you what it is just to say
again it's non-commercial i don't keep
track who goes there click on the thing
called slow gardening okay and see if
it's not things that you already do that
maybe just haven't focused on and that's
my job here today just relax a little
bit i want to throw out one last thing
before we go uh this this bottle tree
anybody have a bottle tree
okay you got a bottle tree
a lot of people don't get it okay it's
where you take an old tree that died in
the stick bottles on the branches okay
um who's been a sissinghurst
okay you know when you go up the tower
about halfway up they got that window
with all the glass in it in the
wintertime
particularly people up north have
colorful glass bottles in your window
you know what i'm talking about don't
you and the reason you do that is
because in the wintertime your pineal
gland that thing that affects your
attitude shrinks up okay you get what
they call seasonal affective disorder
the blues
you put a little chlorophyll glass in
the window and it stimulates you a
little bit it sparks you up okay well
bottle trees are just taking it out of
the yard
by the way some people don't like bottle
trees
my way of thinking if you think it's
okay to hang stuff out of holes in your
ears you just shut up about my balls
but you're fine now
local artists do this and it's supposed
to be swirly throwing organic and swirly
it's an artistic thing and uh these car
what do you have we call them car tags
license plates
head me out here all right say madison
county on the side i'm not from madison
county madison i'm in a little artsy
party community in madison county is the
gated community counties and i do this
with all madison county because it honks
them off
when i say honk them off you know what
i'm talking about
see so i'm being even a little
expressive in a mean way with this kind
of people when i'm driving down the road
when i hear my wind chimes going i smell
rosemary waffling around the cab okay
and i can check my rain days and if i
want to carry watermelons in the back of
it to my friend rod just ran over to new
hampshire that's what i picked up for i
call this my trip crop and all i'm
trying to do is have a little fun okay
any questions
if i blown it out
you never get invited back so let's just
blow it out
whose food was that
deep clipping and all
poorly
you know what poverty is when they come
back little balls
is that good or bad
who says it's good
who says it's bad
right here long eyes
a shrub doesn't care
if it's been pollen then any more than
that food who cares
if it's been pruned into a tuna shake
some people say you shouldn't do that
stuff because it's not natural folks
neither is plucking eyebrows
okay
i'm just saying there's different ways
of looking at stuff and all i'm trying
to do here today is say you know it's
okay
to lighten up in the garden arthur
stewart quoted me
my name by the way i was on a radio
program she said something about how i
look i said look martha i look like a
bubba i sound like a bubble i drive
above a pickup truck i'm no more of a
bubba than you are a stereotypical
blonde
she didn't hang up on me when she's
going to be a saiyan it doesn't matter
what you do or how you do it your
neighbors are going to talk about you
anyway
go forth and have fun
stuff check it out
my name is addie and my colleague pat
and i are working on men's garden and a
couple of other gardens around campus
and we'd like to invite the cornell
community those that are not are part of
the conference but here after the
conference for every wednesday we have
weeding wednesday we meet in the mann
courtyard
at noon we give out free ice cream and
we go around to all the different
gardens we do weenie weeding and we talk
about you know the different blooms