um hi everyone I'm Ruby wiel I use she
her pronouns um I'm the policy and
research manager at climate exchange and
I will just pull up um my slides start
the slideshow um so I will primarily
Focus on the dashboard but also wanted
to give an overview of who climate
exchange is and we have three programs
um so climate exchange is uh an
organization focused on state level
climate mitigation policy um we are do
have a 50 state scope but um don't
really work on local policy or federal
policy um it is primarily at the state
level um we have a mission to achieve a
rapid and Equitable transition towards
zero emissions economy by advancing
State climate policy um and we do this
through three programs um our State
climate policy Network or scpn our State
climate policy dashboard um and we also
have a pro bono policy assistance
program um so first up the scpn um is a
network of over 15,000 Advocates
legislators government officials
Business Leaders researchers and more um
all sorts of people working on climate
policy uh and kind of related issues and
and policies in their states looking to
reduce emissions and and put forward
strong and Equitable policy um we do
have all 50 states represented in the
network um we do also have a lot of uh
people like who are interested in
learning out State policy but that might
not be their main focus uh we do have
people um who primarily focus on local
policy federal policy um but the bulk of
our network is um uh State policy makers
and NGO uh
Advocates um a couple of uh pieces of
programming that we do through the scpn
uh we have monthly webinars um sometimes
more than one month uh these kind of
provided a deeper dive into a specific
topic or policy uh we just had one last
week on uh datadriven climate
Communications um so sometimes they're
more broad but other times they do focus
on specific policies like uh methane
abatement or um we have a transmission
focused series on how State policy can
uh kind of Reform and build out the the
country's transmission system um we also
uh have monthly National calls the last
Wednesday of every month um this is
where people uh on the ground in their
states will provide updates on uh like
what's going on in their state what are
the most relevant bills under
consideration rules regulations um kind
of where F's attention is in the climate
movement in their states um it's a great
way to connect with people across the
country learn what other states are
doing how it might be relevant to your
state um and we also have expert
presentations at the beginning of those
so people can come on and and give an
overview of a tool or report or resource
um that they'd like to share um we also
have a bi-weekly newsletter um we'll
share articles in that uh policy
resources I also draft a lot of state
and federal policy updates um focused on
climate policy um so another way that we
serve to be a resource uh to our
audience um the last thing is you'll see
there's the pro Bona policy assistance
access to peers and expert
connections um this kind of ties into
our assistance program um so we do
provide pro bono policy assistance um we
can do anything from provide
uh like example States and and model
States uh as well as model rules for a
given policy so say you're interested in
um solar sighting uh we can provide uh
best practices for that if there are
model rules um we can share those with
you we have part we can connect you to
folks who do draft those model rules uh
we can also help with identifying gaps
and opportunity ities uh in your State's
climate policy landscape um and then a
big thing that we do through the network
is uh provide connections to um either
experts or other people working uh in
your state or in other states that have
uh maybe like similar uh policy issues
maybe economic drivers um that type of
thing so um the network and this
assistance program is a great way to get
connected to people in your state get
connected to experts um learn more about
uh specific policies and topics um and
we do also like to um complete a lot of
these requests ourself um I've helped
with uh landscape analyses Bill
drafting um research to identify best
practices um all those types of things
so uh you can email one of my colleagues
Kristen who is our scpn manager manager
um or you can also on the dashboard
website you can directly request uh
policy assistance to through that so um
I'll make sure you have the links and
the our contact information if you are
interested um this is just a a quick
example of uh something we've done um
through the assistance program so uh
someone who is a new uh state agency
Environmental Justice staffer kind of
what first position of its kind in a
state um reached out for kind of two
reasons uh the state didn't really have
a Statewide strategy to attract Federal
funding um and again it was a new
position created uh they kind of wanted
to learn what other states are doing um
and how they can learn um from those
best practices so uh we identified
similar States based on political and
economic
contexts uh we provided connections to
technical assistance providers around uh
Federal funding
um uh a lot of people do provide
technical assistance to secure Federal
funding and and help strategize around
that um also identified some best
practices of uh EJ positions and uh
offices within state governments um and
then provided some connection
connections to State and local um
organizations who uh could kind of help
uh guide the strategy around
environmental justice and adjust
transition in the state um we also
identified uh like connections
to uh people in similar States uh we
provided examples of what an EJ office
or EJ position can look like um and uh
identified some kind of similar
positions in other states as well so
this is kind of a different topics uh
obviously based on what people request
but kind of a common way we approach
these um both doing in-house research
and then connecting folks to um relevant
actors um
okay um on to the dashboard so the
climate exchange also runs the State
climate policy dashboard I'll just call
it the dashboard from now on um it's an
online tool that provides uh information
on 62 level 62 State level climate
policies across all 50 states um these
policies span seven sectors which I'll
get into um in a little bit um but it's
designed to kind of provide an overview
of what uh your State's policy landscape
is and help you identify policy
opportunities to increase your State's
climate ambition and reduce emissions
equitably um a couple highlights it's
free and accessible um like I said
information on 62 policies across all 50
states um we do want this and make sure
that it's regularly updated and it's
it's accurate it's ground truthed by uh
folks in theet networ who are working
directly on these policies and in their
states um we relaunched the dashboard to
its own site um in October of this past
year um and so that made it a lot easier
to update it regularly um so we had the
launch in October we just did a big
content update at the end of January um
and then from there we're going to do
kind of a six-month uh Cadence so the
next up date is planned for June or July
I would say um and it's a big uh kind of
consolidator of resources uh we feature
resources from over a 100
organizations um and like I said we
crowdsource a lot of data um from the
scpn and and from um other organizations
as
well um a really brief overview of the
policy framework um you might recognize
a lot of the sector-based
policy areas uh climate governance and
Equity focuses on how states are setting
uh emission reduction targets um how
they're reporting on those creating
climate plans building out State uh
government capacity to address climate
policy environmental justice um how to
in integrate an EJ Into Climate policy
um as well as a handful of just
transition policies and then cross
sector f focuses on economy-wide
policies and policies that span multiple
sectors uh a common one is carbon
pricing that can just be in one sector
or it can be
economy-wide um and then we have
electricity buildings and efficiency
Transportation industry and natur and
working lands um there's a couple ways
to see that full policy framework um you
can go to our methodology page we have
an all policies page um you can also on
a specific State page if you scroll down
to the big data table uh which I'll show
you in a little bit um you can see the
full list of those 62
policies as
well um really quickly on the
methodology um a lot of the information
is manually tracked um as well as
through secondary research we have some
organizations who uh contributed some
data um they do some policy tracking and
uh most notably spot for clean energy
develops policy components um and so
we've Incorporated some of their policy
components and and data um into the
dashboard as well and you can see this
shaded map just is providing a really
high level uh landscape of uh number of
enacted policies so you can see a lot of
the well-known climate leaders are are
in darker colors um and then shading
kind of varies across the
country um so some key features you can
identify State policy opportunities uh
you can explore the status of those
policies by state um or by policy you
can identify the whole 50 state
landscape uh we do have four different
statuses um we have enacted so the
policy exists it's on the books in the
state um in progress is kind of it's a
policy that has been established but
maybe final rules or regulations or a
plan is f pending P final
approval um an example of this is in
Oregon the uh legislature passed
legislation requiring the development of
an environmental justice mapping tool um
by I think October of next year so
legislation requires that tool to be
developed but it's not currently it's
under development now so that's an
example of what's in progress we're not
a policy tracker in the sense you'll see
bills under consideration in the
legislates uh this session but there are
some policies where they're required to
be finalized um so we do feature some of
those uh partially enacted refers to the
policies with components and it means
that some components are fulfilled but
not others and then not enacted means it
doesn't exist in the state um
and that can either just be binary yes
or no for the non-component based
policies um or four components it means
that zero components are
enacted um you can also identify keep
policy opportunities that's a future
we're going to be building out over time
kind of identifying the highest impact
policies um a state can either enact or
increase their ambition for uh you can
sort and filter States and policy by
status by year region and more um and
then we also provide State specific
summaries and establishing policies and
we link directly out to those um so
before the dashboard I found it really
difficult to find all of the actual
pieces of legislation rules and
regulations that uh establish these
policies so we uh made it really easy
for everyone to directly find those and
and uh View view the policy text itself
if interested um we also provide state
level emission projections through 2050
um this is using energy Innovation and
rmi's energy policy
simulator um right now uh business as
usual projections are featured on the
site for most pages but um as we build
out the key policy opportunities you'll
be able to see how
um how a state if they enacted those
opportunities how the emission
projections could change um we also
provide a lot of resources to further
your learning and understanding of the
policies and and how to enact them in
your state so we um identify State
examples um we have Key Resources listed
on all policy pages and then where they
exist we do also link out to uh model
rules so these are kind of
template uh policies that you can fill
in the blanks and adjust the language as
needed and as desired um but really
helps with a lot of that policy drafting
um and as I mentioned you can re request
technical assistance directly from
climate exchange uh through the
dashboard um that's both more of the
policy and research examples I provided
and then connections to experts and
advocates in your
state um I think that's it for the
slides um I'm also aware of the time but
I can
briefly um
just uh walk through the dashboard and I
do also want to
see where folks are um if I want
to
uh uh Kentucky Washington Minnesota
Georgia New Hampshire North Carolina
okay um
I'll do North Carolina because there are
some
interesting uh things to highlight
there uh but this is the homepage I said
you can see our uh oh actually I won't
do North
Carolina uh Rebecca will cover North
Carolina um I'll do another state uh let
me just pull up that list again um I'll
do maybe Minnesota and we do have a
state comparison tool so I'll throw in
some other states as well
um uh if you want to go to the all
policies page you just click on policies
if you want to learn more about who our
partners and contributors are you can go
there the methodology will kind of
explain our policy tracking methods how
we developed these shadings all of that
um and you can see we have definitions
of what those statuses are um if you
just hover over you can see a really
high level summary of just the statuses
um across the 62
policies um I'll go to Minnesota um the
one it says partially enacted is that
like P like the legislature but is
signed by the governor or um yeah that's
a good question I'll go down to
electricity um so you can see we use uh
we do incorporate some spot data um they
are a great resource they develop policy
components that look
that kind of break a specific policy
down into
more uh granular aspects of its design
um I'm not sure if you can see for the
screen sharing but if you hover over the
bars you can see what those components
are and then we do link out directly to
spots website so you can um view the
sources for those you can see uh very
easily what components are fulfilled or
what's not um so partially Ed just means
that some components are enacted and
some are not um so it can it ranges a
lot in terms of what the state uh what
the components look like across States
um but yeah looking at just the specific
policies with components would be
partially enacted so Ruby you're looking
right now at Minnesota's policies right
Soh and only of the renewable energy
section or all related to
climate yeah so I just clicked
electricity um if you wanted to only
look at one policy area you could click
on these so I clicked on electricity and
it brought me down to the table you can
see it's only filtered by the
electricity policy area um if I wanted
to uh undo that you could see it's a
full list of the 62 policy is um kind of
presented in the order that I showed on
the slides um so you can see at least in
clate governance and Equity the state is
uh it has most policies enacted um the
state uh does have a green Bank it
doesn't have carbon pricing um it has a
clean energy standard um you can you if
you wanted to you could filter by your
enacted uh C being the most recent ones
uh
2024 um you can also expand these rows
like I said and and see those
specific uh the policy description in
the state um as well as we do link out
directly to those um pieces of
legislation if it's like a a report or
some type of tool um then we do link out
to those as
well um all I'll go maybe to a policy
page quickly um so we provide uh a brief
summary of the policy here you can
request that policy assistance you can
see the map across all 50 states and the
status um this is one that's not
component based right now so it the only
statuses are enacted or not enacted um
here are some key resources that kind of
focus on emission reduction targets how
they can be designed well kind of a lot
of reports on uh how states are doing to
meet those targets uh we have some model
States uh Colorado for example is one of
the only states that has uh uh targets
every five years starting 2025 through
2050 um so that's a model State um and
then also highlight some of the more
ambitious States as well um here is how
you could see the full 50 state
landscape um if if you only wanted to
see which ones are enacted you could
filter by that um you can expand all of
them see how they compare uh their
targets what their Baseline years are um
all of that and then a nice feature is
you can download this um if it's
something that you've filtered the
download will only download like The the
table shown so if you only wanted
enacted you could uh specifically
download this table if you wanted the
full 50 state list you could do that as
well um and another thing that's nice is
you'll see that the URLs also change as
you filter and sort stuff so if you
wanted to share um the list of the 25
states with targets uh you could just
directly copy this and and share it and
uh the page will open up uh to this
filter
table um I will very very quickly go
over the state comparison tool cuz um
this is one of my favorite features uh
you can select up to four states and as
many policies as you want and just see a
sidebyside comparison um we also
feature um the model States and the
model rules on this as well so I
do I remember Minnesota
um yep
Washington
Kentucky uh and uh
Georgia okay cool um I'll do maybe
buildings and
electricity um maybe some climate
governance and equity in there as well
um I'll do just uh emission reduction
targets um as kind of a baseline policy
uh maybe clean energy
standards um I will show maybe a
component based policy as well and then
I'll do maybe like Pace um to get a
broad sense of them uh so this is a
state comparison tool it also has the
customized URLs um if you wanted to
share those and you'll see just a high
Lev side-by-side comparison uh between
the four states and the policies I've
selected um you can see the model States
um if you wanted to click on that it
would bring you to a state page again um
but uh you can see there is kind of a
variety in what the programs are um
Georgia most recently enacted Pace
enabling legislation um whereas uh
Kentucky Minnesota and Washington their
policies uh kind of have their Pace
programs have been established for a
while can you describe Pace just briefly
for people what is Pace what does it do
um it provides like clean energy Finance
ing that's tied to the property value um
so it's kind of a financing mechanism to
uh uh make like energy efficiency
improvements um you can also see all the
states have net metering partially
enacted um Minnesota is kind of
Minnesota and Washington are kind of the
farthest along whereas in
Georgia they the states utilities are
required to offer a net metering program
and distributed generation Technologies
are eligible but uh they're missing a
lot of the other components in the state
um and lastly I'll just highlight um
where they exist we do also link
directly out to the model rules um so if
you were in Georgia and Kentucky and
said my state doesn't have a clean
energy standard or renewable portfolio
standard but we're interested in that um
this model law for example could uh help
with a lot of that Baseline Drafting and
the model language in
there um so I'll stop there um I'm happy
to answer questions in the chat um or
time permitting um at the end of that
but thank you so
much that was wonderful Ruby thank you
Rebecca you start your screen share and
I'll put the poll so yeah hi guys my
name is Rebecca delamora I am a senior
policy Analyst at the North Carolina
clean energy oh I'll put that like that
hold on I was like there we go okay
that's better um I'm a senior policy
Analyst at the North Carolina clean
energy Technology Center and first I'm
going to go over kind of what the center
does and then I'm going to get into like
Ruby did a kind of tutorial and quick
run through of um our data our database
desire so first um the clean text Center
we are an extension Center of north of
the College of Engineering at North
Carolina State University so we do
public education and Outreach
specifically related to clean energy the
center as a whole has its hands in a lot
of Pies I'm on the policy team we also
do we also have a training Team Clean
Transportation uh clean Power Industrial
efficiency AKA engineering and then
across all of those we just do in
general extension and engagement
work so like I said I'm on the policy
team and we do legislative and
Regulatory analysis related to clean
energy specifically so we run the
database of stay incentives for
Renewables and efficiency AKA desire and
then associated with desire we also have
our desire Insight subscription services
and our 50 states reports so like the
climate dashboard um desires free to use
it's a it's a public good it was
originally funded by um the department
of energy back in like the N 1996 I
think and since then it's grown a lot
but um like it's free for you guys to
use but it's not free for us to update
so that's where desire Insight comes in
so that's our subscription service that
looks at um all of the pending
legislation so any bills that are
introduced any regulatory dockets that
are ongoing any proposed utility
programs that haven't officially been
decided yet or officially enacted goes
into desire insight and then once you
actually you know it's enacted or you
have a decision and it's available for
people to use or look at then it can go
into the full desire database along with
that we also do um customized research
and Analysis upon requests mainly for
government entities or private corpor
corporations that are interested in
clean energy policies across the
US
uh our clean our training team does
Workforce Development so we host on-site
and hybrid trainings related to clean
energy it's mainly focused on the solar
industry at the moment so a lot of
operations and maintenance um
installation the business aspect of
these types of um companies then we also
do with our trainings are also aligned
with um national standards and
certificates so you can take the courses
to learn and then take and then take the
test and get your certificate we also
started a new course specifically now
for solar and storage paired together
and we're actually also developing one
specifically for um electric electric
vehicle trading
stations um next is our clean trans
Transportation team so the quean
transportation team is specifically
dedicated to like electric vehicles and
things like that they do a lot of
technical assistance and Fleet advisory
Services both for um public and private
fleets so a lot of working with local
governments a lot of working with um
small companies to help them Electrify
their company or government fleets um
they do a lot of Education Outreach so
they also usually about once a month
hold the webinar on some sort of clean
Transportation issue they do a lot of
ride and drive events with the public
and then every August they host the
sustainable Fleet technology conference
here here in Ry in the Raley D area
where Fleet fleets Fleet managers can
come from across the country to kind of
learn about what the situation is like
with electri fighting
fleets and then we have our engineering
team which we like to call CPI and so
CPI does a lot of the real technical
assistance and Analysis related to
onsite energy and a lot industri
degeneration so they can do energy
assessments feasibility analyses
Consulting studies they they get into
the really nitty-gritty of actually
helping clients get clean clean
energy and then we have our extension
and engagement work and that some of it
is on the fee for service side so a
client comes to us and they pay us to do
it for them but a lot of a majority of
it is actually through um Grant work
whether it's federal grants or state
level grants so this is this is a list
of all of the current major grants that
we are on there's other grants that
aren't listed here that are still
running and there's lots of grants that
have finished
already um just to pick out a few so the
one at the top is with our engineering
team and that's the technical assistance
partnership or the tap so they provide
free technical assistance to Commercial
and Industrial customers who want onsite
Generation Um our our engineering team
also works with Farmers to help them
apply for USDA funding for Onsite
Generation Um we have a grant going on
helping local governments learn about um
sighting and permitting for utility
scill solar and renewable energy we are
part of the solar for all Coalition for
North Carolina and solar for all is run
by the EPA through I think it was was
either Ira or viil funding can never
remember and that's specifically
dedicated to providing incentives for
lowincome customers and customers who
live in multi family homes they can get
rooftop solar or Community solar um our
transportation team works with the Clean
Cities Coalition helping local
governments across the southeast meet
the Clean City
standard um we also are working on a I'm
working personally on a grant that's
looking for Community resilience using
solar Plus Storage microG grids and so
we're working with around 10 communities
across the state um our transport or not
our our training team is working with uh
Native American communities for work
Workforce Development in the clean
energy sphere and then also developing
new training programs for other people
to use so that's a lot I know um but
it's I feel like it's really important
for you guys to understand that we do a
lot of things in this sphere and so much
of it is specifically extension and
engangement work so when it comes to
desire oh this is our contact
information so when it comes to desire
so like I said before desire is a free
online tool um for people to use and I'm
going to go here there we go you guys
can see
this Okay cool so this is the desire
website um it provides provides
information on policies and programs
related to clean energy across the US so
it's not just the national level but
like like the climate exchange Dash
board it's also at the state level and
then we even have um utility utility
level programs and if big enough some
Municipal level programs so you can
search by state by clicking on the map
and you can see on the map how many
programs might apply to a state so
Mississippi has 23 Kentucky has 33 North
Carolina has 71
California has
158 so you can actually click on a state
and see um all of those States policies
so like I I'll go to North Carolina you
know and then what on the state websites
we have kind of a a large summary of
kind of the major programs in that state
so Energy Efficiency we portfolio
standards um footnotes and you can
scroll down you can
see the list of all of the programs
within the state and programs are sort
of what the name is if you're looking
just at General programs the state
whether it's a financial incentive or a
regulatory policy the type of incentive
or policy when the entry was created and
then when the entry is less updated and
it defaults to whatever the last update
was so our most recent update was all
right February 6 and it was the South
River EMC which is electric cooperated
an area for a heating rebate program one
so if you want to check that out we can
come into the incentive program you can
see kind of all the information that is
provided on this program so who
implements it it's utility it's a
Cooperative it's a financial incentive
in the state of North Carolina and it's
specifically a rebate program we also
then link to the website where you can
where the main website where you can
take advantage of this so This links
directly to the Cooperative website the
administrator Cooperative utility The
Cooperative then we list the eligible
Technologies for the program so here
it's solar water heaters who can take
advantage of it residential commercial
industrial agricultural low-income
residential multif family residential
manufacturers local government state
government tribal government it's all in
it the amount of the incentive the
maximum value of the incentive if it's
if it's different than the standard
incentive value um any equipment or
technical requirements that are needed
to actually be eligible to receive the
incentive and then if relevant ownership
of of renewable energy certificates or
credits then below all of that then
we'll have a quick quick summary so that
you can kind of get an understanding of
what the incentive is for and desire
since desire is aimed towards a general
public these entries should be pretty
easy to read and understand even if you
don't know anything about clean energy
or soil water
heaters and then below that we try and
always have a contact for whoever the
administrator is so here you have the
information for the Electric Cooperative
so you can go directly to them if you
have any
questions and then we'll also have memos
that show you um when we updated it and
what changes we might have made so this
was last updated by our intern Seth and
so it was an annual review and so he
made sure that all the program details
were accurate and up to date based on
what the quer is
offering and the types of things you
might see in these programs are going to
vary based on what type of program entry
it is so like let's go if we just go to
all the programs we have in desire this
is everything it's all the states it is
all the programs and again you can see
it defaults to what was most recently
updated it looks like the intern is
focusing on utility incentives let's see
if we can't find something
different all right regulatory policy
cool so Colorado we recently made
changes to the renewable energy standard
we can go check this out and you can see
here while this the form formatting is
the same the information included this
table at the top is going to be
different so we still have the sector
the category the state incentive type
and the website again but then we also
have because it's a policy when did it
start all of the technologies that are
eligible for the renewable energy
standard um who the standard applies to
investor own utilities M Unis and co-ops
what the standard actually is so all of
the final goals and
targets the technology minimum that they
must reach and any compliance
multipliers or things like
that um the Renewable Energy Credit
lifetime the tracking system they use
they have an alternative compliance
system set
up and then you come down you can see
this is a lot the summary here is a lot
more in- depth than maybe that Co-op
incentive
was and you can see you know it gets
into what technologies were because not
everything is maybe clear if it's just
in the
table the differences between the
investor owned and electric Municipal
util fa ities how it applies to
generation transmission
cooperatives any car vs they may have to
apply to credit multipliers compliance
requirements uh the new clean energy
standard that they recently passed a few
years ago and then here you can see we
also have the authorities so the
Cooperative because it's Cooperative it
doesn't have any legal standards or
requirements that it has to meet or
comply with so we didn't have any
authorities there but with things like
regulatory policies or financial
incentives that are mandated by
regulatory commissions or legislators
will have the authorities in place so
you can go directly to the statutes to
see exactly what it is and here we even
have you know executive orders you can
see when it the date that it became
effective and scrolling down again and
again we have the contact information in
the memos you can see we updated it uh
like five days ago and we added the
section on the clean energy standard
bottom and so that's kind of what this
entries look like as for the actual
types of Entry we have a lot so you can
sort by the technology type that's
available so maybe you're only
interested in you know solar energy
incentives maybe you only want to look
at you know requirements for building
efficiency so you can choose the type of
Technology you want based on all of that
you can choose the date that it was
updated that the program was most
recently updated or if we have it the
expiration date of a
program um categories again BAS
Financial incentive regulatory policy
then the program type of which again we
have hold on we have a lot we even have
Pace financing so we can actually get
into that one if we want as a comparison
going down
still can I request go ahead could we
look for a New York water heater a
friend's water heater just
broke yeah we can totally do that see
what she can
do yeah
so we want State and then we can
actually search here so then I want to
scroll again go New
York and then me apply that I to apply
one it's it's an old website we're
trying to get it updated um but you got
you gotta go through the cycle all right
and then we said
technology so I think a water heater
should be under Energy Efficiency let me
see water heater there we go
actually this might be helpful hold on
do you know your friend ZIP code or like
a New York ZIP code yeah it's
10463 all right so going back
to you can search by ZIP code
one6
463 all right so yeah you can search by
ZIP code for specific because again
remember we have local and utility level
programs so if you're like well I don't
care about you know utility programs for
utility that isn't me you can filter
those out so look now we have 74
programs that match this and it's all
look it's all in New York and now this
ZIP code will be saved once I apply the
filter
for forgot where it was water
heers and now we have 15
programs so you can see here we do have
Federal programs mixed in so just make
sure to be careful because all federal
programs are going to be eligible across
the US so going to show up for every
single Z code in every single state so
let's say I want to just see only ones
that are from the the state or city of
New York all right so we have a reate
program with nerta which is an assisted
home performance with energy star let's
see what that's
about all right so we got an incentive
that can cover 50% of costs for let's
see grants for low income homeowners in
single or multi family buildings for 50%
of cost for Energy Efficiency
Improvement
and so if this applies to your friend
she can go straight to the website to
see exactly what is available for her at
this Nera program but yeah that is one
thing that I think is important is you
can search by ZIP code you can search by
state you can search by the implementing
sector of a program so is it
administered by a feder the federal
government a local government nonprofit
a state or
utility um the eligible sector so we
have it split mainly into residential
and non-residential so we cover just all
sort all residential standard single
family multif family low income things
that are specific senior
citizens non-residential we have
commercial industrial agricultural the
manufactures can we do something with
agriculture yeah so let me clear here me
clear these not that zip code yeah not
the ZIP code so now this is back to the
to the main program and I have it sort
of by state now so Alaska shows up first
so you said agricultural right so
eligible sector non-residential
business agricultural programs so we
have 400 programs where someone in the
agricultural sector is eligible to
participate
in um so okay we have Alaska so they've
got a sustainable alternative power
program Alaska has net metering rules
that allow for agricultural customers um
Alabama agricultural customers are
eligible for Alabama's PACE program so
you have a lot of things that you can
search up
um yeah and then again you can search by
state technology type and then coverage
area I think that's a zip code so that's
all just you know this is that's and
that's just the main part of the website
like with the climate exchange dashboard
there's lots of other things you can
take advantage of Stacy has a question
Stacy what state are you from can you
put in the
state if you filter by count uh County
does it only pull County specific she's
in Arizona okay it only pull County
specific or also the state the county is
in so in other words if you put in
County do you lose your state
incentives um so do something in Arizona
uh I need an Arizona ZIP code yeah put
in his Arizona ZIP code Stacy I can't
you're G to tell to me because I can't
see yes I will 86305
all right
1ar all right so it looks like so it is
going to be Statewide so you'll still
because when you put in the zip code
it's going to give you anything that
that zip code could take advantage of so
that includes anything that is only
local specific it includes Federal
programs and it also includes state
level programs so let me see if the ZIP
code has
anything like yeah like here like if
there's APS the Arizona public Public
Service utility and so it has those in
there because you can take advantage of
those
[Music]
um yeah and then and then not we don't
always have the ZIP code listed in a
program just because sometimes it can be
very difficult for us we're a team of
seven people we don't have zip codes
memorized for every single utility and
municipality in the country um but we do
try to when it's a local utility program
to kind of put those in there but yeah
so when you search by ZIP code it will
always include Statewide and and
Nationwide
programs um if you're like wow that's a
lot of
information we have summary
Maps so for these summary maps you can
choose a program let's go building
energy codes and you can see how many
states have an incentive in desire for
building energy codes Illinois has one
Washington has one Texas has
nine you can even sort by technology
which I'm not going to do because it's
deing energy codes and you can actually
export the map out if you
want oh I've never actually messed
around with this part
before here here under under the summary
tables which you can find under the
overarching programs tab you can see
these are all the incentive types that
we have and if you click one let's Okay
we want a bond program
right now we can see all the bond
programs that we have listed in desire
which is pretty
cool um
but now I want to show you guys all the
resources that we have so this is just
the overarching resource views um we
have a list of all the Publications and
presentations that we've done as a team
so these are all like the Powerpoints
where we presented at conferences over
the past year of which again um what I
use all the time is our detailed summary
maps and so these are kind of annually
updated maps that provide information on
one specific policy so let's go
with energy storage targets because
that's coming in you can download it as
a PowerPoint or a PDF we're going to do
PDF that's
easier and so here we have the map of
states that have energy storage targets
as of September 2024 it's colored in if
it has a Target and we also have the
final Target there available so this is
a pretty new program that we a new
policy type we've been seeing recently
so it's always interesting to see like
what states are
adopting along with the summary map we
also have a list under other resources
of kind of similar organizations uh that
you can take advantage of or look into
related toan energy national federal
state Regional International and then
other energy tools you can use you
should probably B yours on actually I'll
think about it I'll I'll bring it up the
team so I can get the The deim Exchange
daspo on
there um and then if you look I think
under help and
support if you're like I don't know what
you're talking about we have our
frequently asked questions and we need
even have a glossery of all the programs
so like we were bringing up pace before
right so here if you're like I don't
know what pace financing is now you can
find out what it is what happened Google
Google it you can find out what a loan
program is you can find out
here what a renewable energy credit is
or a solar Renewable Energy Credit and
we have our fact and then if you still
need help we have our 20 minute
presentation of how to use desire which
also gets more in depth
and I think that is mostly
everything
so I hope that was useful that was
fantastic um if does anybody have any
requests that they want us to search on
either of these
platforms put them in the chat perhaps
maybe I'll ask the two of you to sort of
speak to each other about how
how how can we as extension
professionals improve the communication
with our communities in order for
helping our communities access these
resources like
specifically like I will share with my
friend how to find her water heater
incentives right but you have had this
experience for quite some time what are
some of the the ways to help people
connect the dots for local action with
local resources and policies
so I mean from a desire standpoint I
actually do know a lot of government
agencies or local governments or
utilities might actually link to the
desire website because they're like if
you want more information or incentives
check out this website here and every
time I see them like oh my God that's
us so I mean one way is like if you know
someone is going to your website
regularly like you know the state
government knows if someone's looking
for a tax incentive and come to their
website they're going to see the website
and so if you know you have half traffic
on your website and you just put the
resources there that it's easy for
people to see then it's a really good
way to like get the information out
there I mean another thing is again we
are similar like engagement focused like
for
example the the sighting and the
sighting and planning grant that were're
on for like local governments um as a
part of the as a part of the grant we
have to have regular um like Community
meetings can't call them not anymore um
Town Halls um with local like residents
and government institutions and so our
team members have been like traveling
all over Northern South Carolina to come
to these communities and be like hey
this is what this stuff
means and so I'm not on that Grant so I
can't tell you like what their marketing
scheme is um but I'm assuming it's a lot
of you know working with you have to
work with the local governments I think
also it's really important to make make
sure to get this information out there
because again a lot of this stuff
happens at the local
level so what about Workforce
Development what are your thoughts on
helping uh helping connect the dots on
on renewable or climate worthy uh
Workforce Development you have some
thoughts on on how you can help activate
that in your
state I mean we have our training team
that does a lot of that already and in
general the center itself works a lot
with the local government so like we
have good relationships with the North
Carolina Utilities Commission and the
Department of Environmental Quality and
the go and the state Energy Office like
the state Energy Office is the is the
group running their solar for all grants
so we are a sub awarde under them so but
you're you're you're just talking in
this particular case like desire is
National right desire platform is
National or database I forget me
um but when you say the workforce are
you does North Carolina invite folks to
come to North Carolina to work about
work on Workforce Development like do
you provide Consulting for
that so I know our training team does do
like fee service work related to
Training
Services um oftentimes just because you
really need that physical experience it
has to be in person a lots of time with
local commun like local governments or
local companies um but I do know it's
possible to like do
things um like remotely through you know
through Zoom or even have people come in
like I remember we had I think they came
in from as a part of one of the grants
we had a group come
from a university in the Navajo Nation
came to Raleigh to take one of our
training courses but that that part's
really going to vary and I do have to be
honest I'm not an expert in our training
team's um practices um but if that's
something you want to talk about in
another webinar I can definitely bring
it up okay Ruby what about you how about
Workforce Development you mentioned it
in your platform but how how can we help
uh local communities build out uh
Workforce Development
opportunities yeah um so that is not
currently an area that's on the
dashboard it is do have like a a whole
long running list of topics and policies
to explore in the future um I will just
say I do
think uh I think there's a lot of energy
around Workforce Development um I've
seen
States uh create like state level
climate uh Workforce Development
programs like climate cor at the state
level um a lot of states are looking
into like
uh the EV transition uh just uh
like uh other other areas where
um States especially with a lot of
federal funding are seeing booms in
these Technologies and these sectors um
so yeah I would just say like States
states providing support uh identifying
needs and gaps in their workforces
providing grants for training or
retraining or educational programs all
of that can help push it Forward um just
a perspective from the state level so
another question for you Ruby of all of
the policies that you've had to look
across I mean because you are sort of
this really unique individual who has
been Tethered to this platform but also
Tethered to all the policies that are
embedded what is one of your favorite
policies that you have seen that just
gives you hope and
happiness that's a great question um I
think uh seeing how states
are trying to incorporate a lot more
environmental
justice positions and policies um into
their like climate policy framework
almost um like the last five six years
or so we've seen a lot of States create
EJ positions EJ offices uh update or
Define uh environmental justice
communities develop tools to identify
them um all of that and I do think the
federal justice 40 initiative also
played a big role in that but um now
it's really up to States and local
communities to continue pushing uh
environmental justice and making sure
that that's a mainstream movement and
concern uh yeah
so well with that that was a perfect
segue I promise I did not ask for that
question
knowingly um I would like to close out
today's event thank you so much for
joining on March 19th at 2m we're having
a solar and environmental justice
webinar so if you want to learn about
different strategies um on that topic be
sure to register and hopefully the link
is it the link is not in there and I
will put the link in there right now the
registration link um I want to thank uh
Ruby and Rebecca thanks so much for your
leadership um and your enthusiasm and
your hard work it's really it's really
wonderful and um timely thanks so much
for sharing your time with
us this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu