this is a production of cornell
university
welcome to this floorcast episode on
understanding compost vermicomposts and
teas the purpose of this floracast is to
introduce the listener to several key
concepts related to using compost
vermicompost teas and extracts as well
as to describe their use in certified
organic production systems in the
greenhouse
composts are simply organic matter that
has been subjected to decomposition in a
controlled process
compost can be useful in substrate
production because they can be a source
of microbes for example for suppressing
root borne diseases
composts have a high cation exchange or
nutrient holding capacity and the
compost itself can be a slow release
nutrient source
in container production mature compost
should always be used immature compost
can be high in ammonia and volatile
organic compounds which can be damaging
to plants
in certified organic greenhouse
production
composts are allowed according to
national organic program nop guidelines
so long as the following criteria are a
met
the compost should use approved
feedstocks which include many plant and
animal materials that are not
contaminated with prohibited substances
such as herbicides
minimum temperature requirements must be
met during the composting process one
thing when using compost and container
production are that all composts are not
created equal
therefore one cannot assume that all
composts can be used in container
production and it is important for a
grower to test different compost sources
as well as batches to ensure that the
material is suitable
i like to think of compost using the
sausage analogy
that is all sausages are not the same uh
sausages will have different feedstocks
and or meat products used in making them
as well as different curing processes
and ultimately that's going to affect
whether you have an oscar mire weiner or
a very nice polska kielbasa
there are some steps that you can check
to make sure that your compost is
suitable for container production and i
do recommend that you test each batch
from a supplier to ensure its
suitability now let's move on to talk
about vermicompost
very simply vermicompost can be thought
of as worm worked waste
worms will digest and fragment the
feedstock into finely divided materials
vermicompost is not just the poop or the
castings from worms but also the other
organic matter that the worms have
divided up
verma compost can be a useful material
because it is because it is finely
divided it is enriched in nutrients
it contains more soluble nitrogen
phosphorus and potassium than a standard
compost
an example of vermicomposting that's
done on an industrial scale is available
at worm power llc
in the process the manure solids from a
dairy operation are collected
these solids are then brought into a
warehouse where they are
thermophilically composted
in static piles
this then serves as the feedstock for
the final step which is
feeding this material to millions of red
wiggler earthworms according to the
national organic program guidelines
vermicompost is allowed in certified
organic production so long as the
following guidelines are met
the verma compost material should again
be made from allowed feedstock materials
and the duration of the vermicomposting
process should be six to twelve months
for outdoor windrows two to four months
for indoor container systems
two to four months for angled wedge
systems and 30 to 60 days for continuous
flow reactors now let's move on to talk
about compost teas
compost teas are liquids that are made
by brewing or steeping compost and water
this process serves to transfer
microbes find particulate organic matter
and soluble chemical components such as
plant available nutrients from the
compost to the liquid the benefits of
compost tea are that it contains some
nutrients
as well compost teas can contain a
beneficial microbial community which
might be used for the control of foliar
and root diseases
these microbes might also be involved in
enhancing nutrient cycling
growers may question whether or not
compost teas work and the answer again
is it all depends returning to the
sausage analogy
compost teas can be
prepared in many different ways and they
can also have many different feedstocks
and additives that are used
whether or not you get a beneficial
microbial community as an end result
will depend on all of the processes that
take place up to that point one of the
things to decide when preparing compost
teas is whether or not to actively
aerate it
a tea is what we call the material when
we do use this active process to add air
or oxygen during brewing this is done to
promote the population of aerobic
microbes
we refer to the material as an extract
when a passive process is followed that
is oxygen is not introduced during the
steeping process this might be referred
to as a non-aerated or passively aerated
extract with extracts there is no need
for specialized equipment and one
advantage of an extract is that it has a
much longer shelf life than a compost
tea in certified organic production teas
and extracts can be used if certain
criteria are met
if the material is prepared without
compost additives it can be used on
edible crops without restriction
if the material is prepared with
additives then it can be applied without
restriction
if the compost tea production system and
materials have been pre-tested to meet
epa guidelines for a bacterial indicator
of fecal contamination
if the above criteria are not met
then the particular tea or extract must
be applied
90 or 120 days prior to harvesting an
edible crop
90 days in the case that the tea or
extract material does not come into
direct contact with the produce
and 120 days prior if the material
doesn't come in contact with the
particular produce
a reminder that organic producers should
always consult their certification
agents before purchasing or using
products
as well always conduct your own in-house
trials with new materials
until next time
this has been a production of cornell
university on the web at cornell.edu