this is a production of Cornell
University
pleasure to be here thanks for the
invitation nice to see some familiar
faces
happy to talk about my work I usually
spend most of my time doing it and not
much time talking about summarizing it
so this was a really good exercise for
me and sort of tying some things
together to give people who have
absolutely no idea what I've been doing
for the last 20 years a snapshot of one
particular area of my work as Tony said
and I'm very proud to say I almost feel
I've been around long enough to say I'm
one of those old-fashioned extension
scientists I really believe very
strongly in my commitment as an
extension specialist and you're going to
see that in my work I've had the
pleasure of course you can't avoid being
involved in basic research at some level
at this place and I've always had the
pleasure of being involved in that but
what I'm going to talk to you today
about is this intersection of systems
based research done at the landscape
level and changing people's behaviors
and using data to drive your education
programs and then further continue to
hone the research and education ideas
that you implement this is the
environment that I work in what we now
know as the urban ecosystem we've got
really nice terms for that type of
landscape now this is the particular
landscape that I will be talking about
today one of the many that we work on as
Tony said I've had the pleasure of
working with the practitioners at
Central Park and a lot of the interest
that I initially get is we have a
problem how can you help us and then
laws get passed that says well you can't
use those things anymore you can't have
those pesticides anymore and so then not
only do you become as I am an extension
scientists where you sort of help them
solve short-term issues they begin to
see the long-term challenges they're
going to face as the people who think
much of this is their front yard and
most of these people have a fair amount
of affluence to draw upon affluence and
influence to draw upon to impact the way
this particular landscape gets managed
so I spend a lot of time on the
intersection of managing plants in urban
environments and as Jenny a gown if and
said in her presentation in our
department meeting this morning the sort
of socio-economic intersection and
understanding how much people are
involved in the decisions and the way
things get managed out in these
landscapes and one of the driving forces
believe it or not in the urban landscape
is mimicry there's a fair amount of
research that's been conducted now to
say well if they see that's the way the
landscape is going to be that's what
everybody wants we know it in for neck
you know sort of common vernacular as
keeping up with the joneses right I
think we've observed this for a long
time and one of the problems is once one
person does it badly
then you've got it multiplied
on and also so I'll show you a pretty
large scale the other thing that's
important to understand about the urban
environment particularly from a
stormwater perspective where I really
spend a lot of my time thinking about
reducing inputs because of these reasons
is eighty percent of the u.s. population
lives on about ten percent of the land
and the urban environments have a
put except put exceptional pressure on
the ecosystems that service them that
most of the time are not in cities
bringing the urban green infrastructure
into the city now begins to connect this
population with an ecosystem that can
service them for their needs but
oftentimes they put a disproportionate
pressure on those ecosystems that are
very much dispersed from where they are
so lots of interest in the urban
landscape
rebuilding it building more and of
course all the roles that the stormwater
management system
impacts this grass is involved in it
we cover a fair amount of the landscape
this is from a 2005 NASA publication
bimal SE and others where they did some
spectral scans of the United States to
look at where grass was and by no
surprise grass is where the people are
you don't see a lot of grass out here
that people our managing as turf there's
a lot of grass out here I assure you
I've seen it but most of what we call
managed turf is managed in these urban
environments and that happens to be in
close proximity where we pave a lot of
places right you use all the sudden now
eliminate a big component of stormwater
management in fact make a lot of
problems worse because where people are
there's also going to be significant
amounts of impervious surface so the
anything that potentially goes on to
that landscape if it is allowed to
escape into those impervious surfaces
then gets channeled and funneled and
concentrated into some of the other
issues that this wonderful picture I saw
on Twitter the other day I couldn't help
myself but steal it the connectedness of
the watersheds and the rivers that
connect our American continental United
States society and you know when you
start looking up in here I actually
wouldn't be surprised if at some point
we start to see laws drawn along the
lines of these watersheds as they do
throughout Europe so these kinds of
connected this connective tissue in the
in the water system is
what I connect myself to in the urban
environment
so now that's ultimately going to impact
it be impacted by the inputs that we
bring into this urban environment and
what do people use in urban environments
well to the tune of about five and a
half billion dollars they spend on lawn
and garden products this is an
enormously large economic driver in the
green industry and if you look just that
pesticides and fertilizers that could
potentially have nutrient and other
health effects you know you're looking
at in excess of fifty percent of all the
money is spent on stuff that gets put on
that landscape that even if we did sort
of crude
percentage losses in the point 0 0 0 1
percentage points you're still looking
at enormous amounts of materials that
can concentrate and get into the water
and of course when you look at pesticide
use specifically New York State's been
keeping records for a number of years
and when you look at the pounds of
pesticides by County which is the way
the Dec has been collecting them for
many years you see that some of the
largest pesticide use gets associated in
the urban areas right Buffalo Rochester
Syracuse up the Hudson Valley into
Albany so lots of pesticide use in urban
areas and you know lots of rural areas
not as much right even though we know
there's a lot of agricultural production
going on there so if you wonder why
someone would be talking about pesticide
use on a golf course or in urban areas
there's enormous there's an enormous
amount of pesticide used in those areas
now is all of it on lawns probably not i
would say a lot of this could be and is
probably related in urban areas to
structural pest control i don't want to
say all of this is getting blanketed on
terrific golf courses but for sure
pesticides are a part of our lives which
is very disconnected from the way I
think many of our citizens view
pesticides well they don't use
pesticides but they don't look under the
counter and see the raid and the tick on
the detik material on their dogs which
is the same grub control we use for
lawns there's a enormous disconnect
where the stuff ends up tends to be a
big problem and so my approach to this
has always been pollution prevention
right if we're not using it if we're not
relying on it the chance that the usgs
is going to find it in a stream and
oddly enough when you see some of their
highest insecticide concentrations they
tend to be located at least in the
Northeast in some of these heavily
urbanized areas now we're not immune to
this from the nutrient perspective this
is the North and South Fork of Long
Island where if they've done some recent
nutrient use and
testing well survey surface and
groundwater well surveys and have found
that you know fertilizers on lawns and
golf courses because of the high
percentage of golf courses and lawns in
these affluent areas there's a fair
amount of materials used and there have
been legislative initiative in these
areas to further restrict the use of
these nutrients so we've been challenged
as scientists to be able to say well how
can you justify this use so my colleague
and retired colleague Marty Petrovic
spent a lot of his career working on
this particular issue but the pesticide
issue is continues to the restriction of
pesticide use continues to gather
momentum in Tony's native land of Canada
one of your native lands of Canada
they've really led the charge in banning
pesticide use in urban environments
primarily on lawns but in Montgomery
County where this recent legislation was
promulgated and about to be passed it
was going to impact off courses as well
as especially municipal golf courses one
of the things that that the people don't
realize is a lot of municipalities
including the state of New York manage
golf as a recreational landscape and so
they provide opportunities for laws to
be passed that don't have to be voted on
by the citizens if the governor signs an
executive order that's the way the parks
get managed that's the way the
municipalities get managed so what's
happening is they're trying to get some
of these executive orders at least on
public land now Montgomery County went a
little bit further and said we want to
ban it on private land as well now you
start running into the private public
land issues that we face in our country
Canada has gone one step further has
been the pmra it's been a very activist
organization since the new prime
minister came into power that
handsome-looking guy you got up there
and so chlorothalonil very commonly used
contact fungicide is going under
significant restrictions at bird I own
thio fan a methyl chlorpyrifos all of
these commonly used turf pesticides are
probably going to be completely removed
from the market in the next five to
seven years in Canada which I think
doesn't bode well for people who want to
sell chemicals in the United States
because I think that that is exactly the
way we are going to be going I've been
saying it for the better part of 25
years of my academic career so maybe by
the time I retire much of what I've been
barking about wine actually come true so
how do you deal with the public that you
when you ask them about environmental
issues how do they respond so this is a
couple of Gallup surveys I wanted to
make you aware of percentage of
Americans wearing a great deal about
certain environmental problems and two
of the ones that I work very closely
with drinking water and
contamination of soil water not
necessarily by toxic waste but pollution
of rivers as well you can see a mount
for the people who worry about
environmental issues which is about half
about half of the American population a
full half of them are very much worried
about the things that our work focuses
on you know how do we keep these inputs
out of those water bodies now the
fascinating thing about the way people
view the environment is when the economy
is not doing well over the last two
decades since we've started to see more
significant financial crises and you can
track the financial crises on this graph
this is a simple question that says if
push comes to shove should we favorite
economic issues over environmental
issues or should we face environmental
issues over economic issues and for many
many years up until the turn of the
century they said wait a minute
protection of the environment should be
given priority over everything right now
you think while we're experiencing this
big environmental movement but I think
what you see is a steady decline in
people interested in environmental
quality certainly at the level that
they're interested in the quality of
their economic life so this creates a
number of challenges when you're
constantly talking to people about
environmental issues whether they're
going to be interested in what you're
selling what's saying whether it whether
there is a driver to motivate them to
change their behavior by using less
products and I think a lot of that goes
back to the sort of
socio-economic stuff that jenny was
talking about in our faculty meeting
this morning and and this SCAF really
depicts that so I'm as an extension
scientist it's sort of nice to learn new
things but as I learn new things I want
to see how I can help change people's
behavior by taking that science and and
putting it to work and that's really the
stage I'm trying to set move them
forward so here's this here's the issue
this is the issue i was on faculty
couple years when this happen Spitzer
signs an executive order banning
pesticide use on state park land so in
1998 he comes in for the five minutes he
was governor and really sort of went
through and in his normal way sort of
slashed and burned everything and took a
real activist agenda and banned
pesticide use on state park land and at
the same time so did Suffolk County
Parks now what I thought was interesting
was what about the 27 New York State
Office of park recreation and historical
preservation courses that's what that
long acronym stands for what about those
courses and what about the three courses
on Long Island and I think they just
wrote he's a state parks we don't need
pesticides out of state park so the
state parks don't use roundup anymore
they don't use any synthetic chemical
pesticides that when there's not a golf
course associated with it so Jennifer
grant who many of you know dr. Jennifer
grant is the director of the New York
State IPM program we've been colleagues
since really already knew or even when I
was a graduate student here in the late
1980s when she was worked beginning her
work with rod farentino and I p.m. and
Jennifer came and said look what's
happening
can we have golf courses without
pesticides I said no you can't have a
golf course without pesticides and she
said how do you know
and that's how dead silent the
conversation went after that no one's
ever tested trying to manage a golf
course without pesticides people say
organic otherwise I can promise you
they're using regular chemical
pesticides and these
executive orders said anything with an
EPA number can't be used that was the
executive order that was signed when we
first started this work so she said how
do you know and so then it was writing
proposals and the normal process we go
through and you know the question was
simply
at first we pitched the idea to do it on
our research plots because as a
practical golfcourse guy I said who's
going to let us kill grass on their golf
course because I'm was fairly sure that
was what was going to happen
ecologically if you are maintaining a
golf course for 70 years with pesticides
and all of a sudden you stop spraying
those pesticides what kind of chance you
think ecologically those plants have
that have been held up all these years
by preventing diseases and preventing
insect problems the problem chances of
them working are very less so I blame
Jennifer for me being here today and of
course my relationship with her has been
one of the great joys of my career I had
been fortunate to start working with the
bethpage Park guys on the center of Long
Island training them because they had it
was announced back in 1997 that they
were going to have the 2002 US Open
which was the biggest golf tournament in
the world and they didn't have a staff
that even knew the first thing about how
they might prepare a golf course for
that they were state park workers and
this golf course which is one of the
great ones in the world was left to into
decline its demise and decline was well
known there just wasn't money to keep it
up the they wanted to the leaders of
golf want it to sort of rien still
public off so this was the first time
the US Open was held on a truly public
off course the kind of golf course you
sleep in your car to be able to play
first thing in the morning and so I had
this long relationship with them and I
literally will tell you i leveraged it I
said to the park superintendent Dave
Catalano at the time I said hey man we
need you have five golf courses here we
need one of them to test this out and he
said absolutely that's what we should be
doing
it almost gets me choked up every time I
say it because if he said no I'm not
sure what I would have done so he gave
us the golf course they basically said
yeah do what you got to do so
2002 bethpage was a great place to do it
because the world was looking at
bethpage right the world had their eyes
on this golf course that hadn't been on
television ever had never hosted a major
tournament and it had to be sort of
pulled off in a five-year period and as
you see it was enormously successful
even got to work with my nephew was on
the ground screw so one of the things to
do as an extension scientist in my world
is when there's work to be done and
there's a chance to get up and do it
it's a way you build relationships with
your peers as say hey least not just a
guy who locks himself up in those rooms
he's out there actually boy knows how to
run a greens mower he knows how to do
this he knows how to do that I do
because before I came back to graduate
school I was a golf course
superintendent but I want to say how
much of a benefit this is in changing
people's behavior I think one of the
great challenges environmental groups
have in general is they're trying to
change systems many times from the
complete outside and I am I don't know
how else to say it I'm a mole I'm this
guy who's been in the turf business for
thirty something years and have
consistently tried to make changes in
this environmental way and I finally
after 25 years I feel like some of that
work is coming to fruition so this is
what work is like during a US open when
it rains a lot that's me
you wouldn't believe they actually try
to play golf in this thing they even
wrote a book about the tournament I'm
mentioned a couple of times in this book
was the first time again the big
tournament was played on a public stage
all right bethpage is a busy place
people love playing golf they'll play
between 50 and 60 thousand 18-hole
rounds a year on the green course that
we work that we play on it's not
uncommon that when you play God at the
golf course here this is one of the
putting greens so here's a group putting
their ball in this group here finished
putting and is waiting for these guys to
tee off who are teeing off while there's
people on the green it's a par three so
they're hitting to the green while
people on the par-3 are standing back
waiting for them to head up that's what
this is like it is a constant play
traffic and all that foot traffic
creates a lot of challenges for living
things of which grass plants are mode at
about a tenth of an inch when they're
experiencing that traffic so what is the
bethpage state park it's five golf
courses 1,500 acres
260 thousand rounds across the five golf
courses only 35,000 on the championship
course it's second only to the parking
lot at Niagara Falls and income for the
state park system nothing makes more
money than the parking lot at Niagara
Falls and Beth blades is typically a
close second to it our work is being
done on the green course we didn't
necessarily think about that at the time
but the green course that was the
original golf course that was on the
land when Robert Moses bought and bought
is loose term for Robert Moses he sort
of said I want it and next thing you
know he had it and so then they built
out the golf course to include five
other properties as well so our work was
on the green course now i want to just
set the stage for the first part of the
study because the meat of it is actually
the second part of the work that we've
been doing in the last seven years so
for the first
ten years 13 years we were conducting an
experiment that was a systems-based
trial and i guess the easiest way to
explain it is when you go on a diet as a
person sometimes nowadays there actually
are prescribed foods but generally you
can eat lots of different things Weight
Watchers has a point system you get
these many points for this food and so
they'll tell you exactly what to eat all
time but they say here's what that stuff
has to be like that's how I would
describe the way we approach the work we
have 18 putting surfaces which is where
we wanted to do this work we put nine of
them under you know what you're normally
doing on the golf course and nine of
them under what we thought would be
practices that reduce overall stress on
the plants and
maximize their ability to withstand
pests pressure if they're under less
stress theoretically they'll be less
exposed less vulnerable to particularly
fungal diseases fungal pathogens insect
predation are the two big pest problems
on these playing surfaces so we had nine
the way they were doing it and nine the
way we thought they should do it in the
future and then within those nine
surfaces we replicated
three pest management approaches one
that they normally used one that we
would call a sort of progressive IPM
approach and one that initially
initially was following the executive
order no
chemicals with an EPA number then I'll
show you in a minute why we have to
adapt that particular treatment to
ultimately become what we published as
bio-based pest management
biologicals reduced risk products that
the EPA indicates as such and so we did
we published a paper in our
international turfgrass research journal
back in 2009 that summarized our first
seven years of work and I don't expect
you to pay attention to the suite of
practices I just want you to see that
these were what the cultural management
systems look like when i say cultural
management it's how you mow how you
fertilize how you water these are
enormously intensive management systems
enormous amounts of intervention on a
daily basis this is gonna put the apple
tree and see you in 30 years kind of
thing this is every day they're at it
doing something to these playing
surfaces on a variety of different ways
to condition them to perform the way
they're supposed to
so what we often call the most
dysfunctional building in the entire
state of New York that's the state house
so the goals of our original project as
we set it out was the first
how do we if you ban pesticides what are
these growers going to do they don't
have there was no one's ever sort of
said how do you do this with one hand
tied behind your back those questions
had never really been asked before so we
said wait a minute we need to figure out
what sorts of things work and
give policymakers an opportunity to see
the work we would invite them out on a
regular basis during the study to say
hey here's the treatment that
you the law you would just are about to
impose this is going to be what happens
when everybody starts managing like this
and so this is the funeral service for
the second putting surface on the green
course it didn't take long for this to
happen the first two years we made it
into two July one year in early August
another year and then basically within a
week that's what happens and they died
from the most commonly found fungal
pathogen that no one ever were about the
disease that actually began came in and
killed these surfaces is one that Nolan
even if you ask people are the top ten
problems they barely make that top ten
list it's so common that they just spray
all the time for it and never think
about and all of a sudden when you don't
have the tools that solve common
problems and you don't have alternatives
to those problem
alternatives to solve those issues it
becomes very difficult to not have
surfaces like this these were putting
surfaces that been managed with
chemicals in various ways shapes or form
all the way back to chlordane in the 30s
these greens had never seen these putty
surfaces had never seen a growing season
without regular pesticide use so when we
stopped doing it two years in a row this
is what happened that's why the final
treatment that that bio-based sorry
the bio-based pest management here at
the bottom had to be implemented because
Dave can Alanna looked at us and said do
you have to keep killing these greens
are you learning something if you're
learning something by continuing to kill
them by all means continue to kill them
but if you're not learning anything
maybe you can stop and we did one more
thing before we softened that's we
invited the policy makers out there the
Suffolk County legislators we probably
had four there and we had two state
senators and their aides there
for the Twilight field day with about
15-20 people and we said this is what
happens when your law gets enacted and
their comment was oh I
I think that there is this and maybe you
see this in agriculture as well there's
this pervasive attitude what do you need
pesticides for how hard is how r could
it be what do you need pesticides for it
and oh it's a golf course why are you
using them on a golf course so the idea
that we would take away a tool and it
would result in something like this I
think speaks to the level of ignorance
that we have in much of our legislators
when it comes to these kinds of
complicated issues so our operating
principles with the project was number
one established cultural practices that
reduce stress create an environment that
has less problems and then when you're
going to intervene with a product right
I can tell you every snake oil salesman
in the country found out we were doing
this and said hey we got the magic
potion for you Frank and we had to
immediately say wait a minute who says
that and they said well you know we
tried it in a greenhouse one weekend on
cucumber and it worked really good so so
that's the kind of stuff that we were
confronted with when we started this
work you know 15 years ago so challenges
of new technology i will say you know
god bless those people at bethpage for
putting up with you know if I had 10
ideas one of them might have been a good
one but they let me try all 10 of them
and we tried brewery waste compost for
snow mold we had to push the snow off
and put the brewery ways down because
there was data that said that would work
and lo and behold we didn't have snow
mold but we had the worst case a fairy
ring you've ever seen this whole idea i
read a recent paper recently that a
paper recently that increasing
pseudomonads has led to more take all
patch problems in week a gal minomycin
species problem goes up when you
increase microbial activity of a
particular microbe so I think we have a
lot to learn about these sorts of things
in this drove many of the golf course
guys crazy this one year we have gone to
pharmaceutical grade
microbial fermenters
put these bugs in the put the microbes
in there blew a slurry put it in a spray
tank and spray it every day for a
hundred and fifty days
so we did that and it was okay I mean it
certainly reduced some of the pest
problems it was a microorganism and that
for a while they were injecting this
stuff into the irrigation system but it
just wasn't practical we did the carbon
footprint that would have been better to
bring a hundred more pounds of pesticide
into the r into the operation then use
this thing we've tried direct injection
sprayers Andrew Landers when he first
came to campus have worked with us on
this it's a pure tank of water with
jockey tanks that it will allow you in
real time to adjust rates and locations
and 2 a 2 full boom set up this was a
state-of-the-art prototype
once we had an intern that used it once
that kid left everybody looked at it
said I'm not sitting on that thing and
agriculture has been doing this for a
really long time and now it's finally
starting to come back to the golf
industry GPS controlled sprayers
variable rate technology I was 15 years
ahead of my time we had this on the golf
course 15 years ago and we couldn't even
get him to take a look at it one student
did it one year and we could never get
it going again
compost teas this was a big deal with
the organic movement on Long Island we
have a lot of very people with a lot of
time on their hands that really believe
organic is the solution to every problem
known to man and if we just use more
compost the world would be better so we
did the research in Ithaca and found and
then we actually did it on Long Island
as well to appease some of these real
critical people say they didn't think we
were doing anything useful because it
wasn't organic
direct injectors on the side of the
irrigation system we did this actually
at the cornell golf course as well
products that you find there's billions
of dollars spent on products that have
no practical value for use in turf no
matter what we say we can't stop them
from using them but they continue to do
it so
just to give you a sense of the golf
course that we're talking about fairly
small putting surfaces about 4,500
square feet and they get a fair amount
of traffic I show you this graph this
was a seven-year track of the rounds of
golf this is what happened after the
first two years of kill and greens so
this is when we started and then the
greens died and they didn't come back
and then the greens died and didn't come
back and so once the state revenue
people said whoa make it less money on
this maybe there is something to this
golf course thing that we should pay
attention to and so we made some
adjustments to our systems that allowed
us that bio-based pest management and we
saw a return rounds of golf and one when
I show this to people who manage golf
courses has small businesses many small
farmers like oh yeah when our greens are
in good shape people don't like playing
here or they want a discount and let me
tell you how rude Long Island Public
offers can be sometimes when they find
they can't play a putting green because
it's dead they want a discount on the
round so
anyway speaking of the golfers we did
interview them regularly this was
Jennifer's part of the project dealing
with the golfers and so we would service
them survey them and ask them if
percentage of golfers had said they
wanted you to keep quality high use
pesticides whenever they might help keep
reasonably good use pesticides
judiciously minimize pesticide use
regardless of quality and don't use
pesticides now what you see in this
graph that's fascinating is particularly
in the early parts of the study we
didn't show we didn't survey them when
the greens were dead necessarily but a
lot of these golfers went through this
experience
you can see a starting an occasional
increase and when we started looking at
this data further there did track
economy the better the economy was and
the more they liked playing golf the
less they cared about pesticide use and
golfers in general don't care much about
pesticide use in general they have sort
of grown accustomed to it like people
who live in agrarian societies and see
farmers apply pesticides all the time
they don't see it as something abnormal
that people do but on golf course is you
know where people don't normally see
people other people applying pesticides
people who are not golfers get all
worked up about it we find that the
golfers tend not to get that worked up
about it
okay so how would you rate the overall
condition of the green course in 2008
and so we had about a sixty percent very
good and twenty-eight percent adequate
so we're going to say tough New York
public golf crowd we've satisfied about
eighty-five percent ninety percent of
the public and we're driving down
pesticide use in this project so we
surveyed the golfers and
we asked them about how they thought it
looked and how they thought it played
so green quality rating by golfers
looking at our I p.m. with alternative
cultural practices all of them thought
those greens were good the can equal to
statistically the same as the way
they've been doing business so we've
developed this alternative collection of
practices that the golfers say is doing
pretty good and
consistent with the way they've been
doing business in the past so if we can
make our adjustments to their management
good for the environment and transparent
to the golfer that's the sweet spot that
I think we were suited for when we
started this work and
playing surfaces as well it can skip
over some of that we monitored labor
hours because one of the knocks on
alternative or organic is it takes more
time it's more labor intensive and we
did not necessarily find that now the AC
is alternative culture I p.m. and the
green bar is the standard practice the
blue bar is the progressive practices
that we've implemented and you could see
early on when we first started
implementing them it took more time
right changing the way they manage you'd
expect things that take more time but as
we've gone along we saw that oh they got
used to this different way of management
and then it no longer took more time
than the conventional approach
now fundamentally the title of my talk
is pesticide use reduction so let me
talk to you about the way we look about
pesticide use obviously practitioners
pick them based on multiple factors
Jennifer likes efficacy economics and
the environment I think it's an easy way
to summarize the way people select
pesticides we have Cornell guidelines
that guides them but I'll approach with
at bethpage and then with our larger
state park group has been first of all
New York State labeled chemicals it's
got to be labeled for use in New York
that's the use of the guidelines
we want it to be effective and I'll show
you how we went about that and we wanted
to introduce some sort of environmental
screening that said okay here's 10
pesticides
they're different chemically they're
different based their potential
environmental impact we want you to
screen the products you use based on
this screening model known to many as
the environmental impact quotient
so before I get to a discussion at the
eiq I want to give you a sense there's
an enormous amount of data available
looking at efficacy of products land
grant institutions have no problem
spraying plots have no problem telling
you what works and doesn't work and they
do such a good job of it I don't have to
do it we don't have to do it and I can
use that information and translate it
here and paul Vance elia proud Cornell
grad at Kentucky publishes a particular
bulletin every year that ranks efficacy
looks at fungicide to mattify tests and
says these do pretty well in a lot of
different studies these do poorly in a
lot of different studies these do good
and some not good in others and so he
ranks the efficacy of the various
products so we've put this into a tool
to help the managers make decisions now
the IQ is one you may be aware of
djokovic a former fruit I p.m.
specialist developed this model many
years ago to see if he could compare
organic apple production to I p.m. apple
production to conventional apple
production that was the original intent
of this model that he began to run
chemicals through to demonstrate one
pest management system versus another
this model is heavily scrutinized by the
scientific communities one person Paul
was the paper said it's no better than
random numbers now i will say there are
some caveats to this when the model was
originally developed there was a lot of
products that were really bad we were
using and i think one of the things
that's affected its efficacy as a model
of screening is a lot of those products
are gone so the wide disparity and
potential environmental impact of a lot
of products is more related to their
overall amounts then necessarily their
their inherent toxicity so this fancy
this model that Joe developed jennifer
and I sat down said hey we should give
these guys a tool at bethpage to screen
these things we adapted this a little
bit for our use and then began to have
them use it so this was table that a
turf manager would get at bethpage for a
dollar spot control a score of tinea
minor that common disease that killed
those greens here's a variety of
products that we know have decent
efficacy the frack code for those of you
that aren't familiar with these action
codes is at a track code and iraq code
this is the frack code fungicide
resistance action committee that
basically codes them based on their mode
of action we want it to stop using a
particular compact fungicide called
chlorothalonil and a lot of the concern
was all we're going to get resistance to
these other chemicals as well you're
going to get resistance of all you do is
spray one particular type of chemical
but if you use a variety of modes of
action you're more likely to hold off
resistance resistance management
continues to be and is emerging issue in
our field as well so this is what they
have and the subsequent eiq numbers that
go along with it we encourage them to
use reduce risk products we encourage
them when ft wizzy was there to use Omri
listed products and we've used a few and
then we looked at the eiq of the various
management systems so a set i don't know
i don't know how i don't expect you to
grab all this but essentially what i
want you to do is compare this one to
this one
coat this is conventional culture
conventional pest management and what
you see here is what we were learning in
these other pest management programs
these bio-based ones
treatment integrity was compromised a
little bit and they started using them
in their conventional treatment so we
were not the best research result but a
really good behavior will change like
wow this product works as good as that
product this one's better for the
environment I'll use that product my
sense is if you give growers options
that they can afford and that work
most likely they're going to use those
approaches if it's not a big shift in
their system so we
see real
this is the one I want you to compare to
not this one alternative culture and I
p.m. versus conventional culture and can
national pest management and so you see
the real low E IQ which is indicating
the environmental impact is
significantly reduced so another way of
looking at the same data which
culminated in a publication that Bob
Portman so we lost unexpectedly this
past March we're sorry to lose Bob we
didn't just lose him from here Bob
passed away suddenly so it was a big
shock to our program but this was his
master's work and a longtime colleague
with mine so once we got that data we
hired Bob and we said hey we learn this
stuff out at the on the green course how
about we take it to the whole state park
system
apply the same thinking and started to
look at our eiq for our pest management
programs and compare them to different
golf courses we were collecting pest
management programs pesticide use
records from around the country
comparing what some golf courses are
doing compared to what our flagship golf
course the tournament golf course was
doing and the average state golf courses
were doing so first of all we were
starting to establish a baseline now the
University of Wisconsin has taken this
and they're creating a statewide
initiative of all their golf courses to
be at or below an average eiq value but
one of the things you notice these are
various parts of the golf course small
area so this is about this represents
about
three acres this is about four acres
fairways generally can be 20 to 30 acres
of turf rough areas 40 to 60 acres so
the more you apply pesticides
to larger areas the larger your eiq goes
up and I've been still comfortable using
the eiq because while it's a measure of
toxicity of the material risk is a
function of toxicity and exposure so
we're looking at the toxicity of the
product and the exposure that a golfer
or the citizens might have by deploying
these compounds on a large area so when
we look so now you're looking at seven
years one two three four five six years
of data we've collected from 15 state
park golf courses that have been
participating in the expanded program
since 2009 2010 and this is the total
environmental impact of their pesticide
use over that period of time so you can
see when we started the program this was
the year before we started we started
the program he said hey use this list
spray less compound uz IQ and boom right
away we saw big reductions now I break
this out into all the golf courses or 15
courses only the five or six on Long
Island no seven on Long Island and then
eight upstate so seven and eight golf
course is so roughly the same number of
golf courses but you see the majority of
pesticide use is occurring on long
island golf courses right on long island
golf courses so they immediately began
to drop their eiq and they got pest
problems like crazy once we started to
take this out to a broader audience they
were going through the same thing we
went through when we started 15 years
ago now what I think we've seen is sort
of a return we watched a big increase
for a couple of years in Jennifer grant
and I worked very closely on training
and trying to figure this out and so in
the last few years we've implemented a
strategy that I want to leave you with
as I wrap up what we've learned in these
last few years about really changing
pest management behavior using this data
so what this data allows us to do and
what Bob really left us this great gift
is this enormous database that allows us
to look at their behavior based on
environmental impact of the products
that they used so we took the field use
eiq which is the toxicity the material
calibrated for the rate multiplied by
the area treated so you see that a
majority of
increases across this is all 15 golf
courses came from large increases to
rough areas weed control it was the
primary product that's driving a lot of
this as well as additional fungicide
treatments that are getting made because
once people see a really good golf
course they want to keep playing on a
really good golf course once you give
them a perfect Apple they want a perfect
Apple all the time so we've sort of were
a victim of our own success that we got
good at it and we watch their behavior
so he said wait a minute we're going to
start to stop this so we started to make
some changes there you also see fairway
use which was high as has gotten bigger
and
yeah and pine green use is stayed fairly
flat this is where it got very
interesting and where we've really
implemented the education first of all
we want you to stop you we told the guys
we wanted to stop using products that
are very high toxicity and
it represented in 2015 about fifty
percent of the products they were still
using we would call bad actors or e I
Q's above a value that we liked you're
starting to see a decline in their use
but boy that use went up quite a bit
even above where we started
this is where the education has been
focused most recently and that is to
pest problems on these golf courses that
50 that about
50% forty-eight percent of all the
pesticide used on these 15 golf courses
went at these two pests and that's what
this aiq data allowed us to see so again
we tried to eat knowing this we tried to
implement some training which included
the use of predictive models skipped be
over this the use of predictive models
that was saying that we've been working
with rt gaetano at the Northeast climate
Center we had these predictive models
available for the last decade so we
started using these models a long time
ago and develop risks that could predict
when this disease would be a particular
problem and we asked the practitioners
to monitor that data so here you have
these dots and low medium and high risk
put out in indices so here is below this
is low-risk medium risk for disease high
risk for disease and this is the trace
of the risk that was experienced at
bethpage in 2014
you can see there was about a 12 to 14
day period when risks were very high
that's when we want to reserve those
high-risk control products for only
those times and use softer products or
products with lower IQ values during
periods of lower risk if they're needed
at all so we began this in 2014 gave
them some suggestions for looking at a
model what would happen and then
actually looked at their chemical
applications during that period of time
and found when you look at their eiq
values that one I don't know what
happened there but when you look at some
of their yo highest ew q values they're
following when some of the pressures
were the highest so we're starting to
see that by bringing a lot of different
ways of thinking about pest management
to bear for these people they're
starting to adjust their management to
be more in line with when the risk
occurs how to use these lower eiq
products and how the result in the end
is going to be less environmental risk
associated with pesticide use
Andy Wilson is our project manager and
deserves all the credit in the world for
putting up with me all these years of
visiting I would spend every other I was
down on Long Island from april to
november every other week for the better
part of seven years and he put up with
me this was at the most recent Barclays
tournament we've shifted some of our
work to enhance pollinator habitat the
project continues to expand we get a
hundred thousand dollars every year from
state parks and we've started to plant
some of these out of way areas now into
places where pollinators have some more
help and of course our most recent
extension accomplishment was publishing
this new york state best management
practices for golf courses this is
primarily for water quality protection
and the eiq and the things that we've
learned from our project are embedded in
this so with that I'm right at my time
sorry for that wish I had time for
questions
one or two quick questions yes
city or two and one was try to turn and
the other is our they're known as
impressive loyalty to the fungal
diseases you're interested in Ian could
you use of like a microbiome transplant
type of book been approached to try to
enhance so the answer to the first
question did you strike a derma the
answer is yes and we continued to use to
try to turn long our product down there
it's worked very well on a number of
root pathogen problems that we've had as
far as suppressing soils no such luck
there Janice we I think everything else
in early on in his career was working on
that particular area I think we found
some things with the pity of that might
be useful but I don't think anybody's
taking that work any further I know
that's something that the microbiome is
James working on and then ad future for
that sort of stuff we haven't found any
suppressant soils that we can
characterize that exists car
one more question anybody had last
question
all right if not let's fight
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell edu