this is a production of Cornell
University okay good morning everybody
and thank you for taking the time to
come to to this talk it's my pleasure to
tell you some of the work we're we have
been doing for the past probably 10 20
years already uh in regards of
understanding what's the function
structure and how uh is the regulation
of a particular set of membrane
transport proteins that mediate uh uh
response response to tolerance of a
particular set of abiotic stress what
I'm showing you here is a world map it's
a heat map of the density of crop areas
uh nowadays in the
world it's pretty
clear come
on okay when you look at at the at the
soils the suitability of soils it's
pretty clear that there's a nice
correlation where there's a high density
of Agriculture taking place with the
quality of the soils around the world
so it's no big surprise we basically do
agriculture where the soils are good
however when you take into account that
by 2050 our population is increasing by
about 25% and just in about 20 years or
so we need to increase uh our production
by 40% it's obvious that we have to
start thinking about moving into this
marginal soils and start increasing the
productivity that is currently taking
place in this sort of mar marginal soil
where the soils are not suitable for
agriculture so these marginal soils are
a result of several abiotic stresses
including drought salinity and also
aluminum toxicity and to tell you why
aluminum toxicity such an important
abiotic stress I'll first overlap a heat
map uh describing the P of the soils
around the world acidic phes are shown
in
red
so in terms of the total area of the
world about 30% of the total uh soils in
the world are acidic and that
constitutes about 70% of the potentially
be arable lands uh around the world
which includes the South the southern
tropical band which takes into account
uh particular regions where food uh food
supply and in food stability is more
tenous at the
moment so so why is aluminum toxicity
occurring this in this kind of acidic
soils aluminum is pretty harmless at
neutral and and basic PHS because it's
bound to to the oxides and the silica
and the soil however when you start
hitting uh low PHS acidic PHS aluminum
solubilizes into the solution and as the
pH becomes more acidic what happens is
the predominant form that you'll find of
aluminum in the solution in the
rizosphere is a3+ and it's this
particular form of aluminum um which is
actually phytotoxic to plants so I have
that so how toxic is it really let me
just show you a couple of examples these
are two maze varieties grown in the
southern part of Brazil in acidic soils
as you can see there's an aluminum
resistant variety and aluminum sensitive
the sensitive variety actually has a
significant U loss of yield likewise
this is uh two contrasting varieties
from wheat the aluminum sensitive
variety which you can see is a really
dramatic inhibition or loss of the root
growth and that's the primary that's the
primary symptom of aluminum toxicity
aluminum as soon as you expose the roots
to aluminum the root growth
ceases what that results in is a a loss
of water uptake loss of uh mineral
uptake and ultimately what what it
translates into is this loss of
yields so this is just a micrograph
showing you the degree
of injury that Roots actually experience
upon exposure to aluminum these are the
same wheat varieties I'm showing you
right here so fortunately there is a a
generic variation in crop plant species
which we can exploit to understand what
are the physiological mechanisms that
underly this this aluminum resistance
process and for most crops what has been
founded was early described back in the
early '90s is that those aluminum
resistant varieties actually upon
exposure to aluminum The Roots Rel
release organic acids into the risos
spere what this organic acids do is they
complex the aluminum they keate it and
they form complexes that a are not toxic
and B are not taken up by the root that
way they're excluding aluminum from
coming into the root system and uh have
its uh phytotoxic events so as I said
this was originally described in wheat
subsequently we describe it in MA
but has nowadays been uh reported as a
very highly conserved mechanism
throughout a whole variety of crop
species so overall aluminum resistance
in plants can be can be achieved by an
exclusion mechanism such as the one I
just described which is the release of
organic acids into the rizosphere
forming non-toxic complexes or true
tolerance or detoxification mechanisms
if aluminum is able to get across the
across the plasma membr of the root
cells it can form complexes uh with
Organic acids which are sequestered into
the vacle of the roots and stored there
in a nontoxic form or in some cases it
it can actually be loaded into Asylum
translocated into the into the shoots
where it sequestered it and this is the
case of uh plants which are aluminum
hyper accumulators such as the case of
um of tea crops so for the purpose of
this talk all I'm focusing
on is what I'm going to talk about is uh
a aluminum exclusion mechanisms and
particularly I'm going to talk about
these two Transporters or the nature of
these Transporters
here so the mayor breakthrough in terms
of uh understanding what was the
molecular identity of the Transporters
mediating this release or of organic
acids came back in 2004 about 10 years
ago by by Sasaki at all in Japan and uh
they basically cloned a novel
transporter which they called aluminum
activated melee transporter or almt in
wheat in
2004 in 2007 Leon's group actually
cloned the second aluminum tus Gene and
what they found out is there is an
additional transporter or an additional
family of Transporters they clone it for
sorum and it's a family of Transporters
from the multi-drug toxic compound
extion family or
mates these two Transporters are very
different in terms of uh their secondary
structure their structure and the way
they function these are predominantly ni
and channel type of Transporters while
these are sort of
antiporters so in terms of uh signal
transduction it's a very complex uh
network of signal transduction Cascades
which basically the aluminum um stress
is sense and there's a whole uh bunch of
transcriptional Regulation going on
which ultimately affects the expression
of these two two transporters the lmts
in the mates however what I'm interested
in talking about today is how are these
Transporters actually post translated
regulated in other words I'm not
interested in in finding out what's
what's the gene uh at the Le at the gene
level what is the transcriptional
regulation of these Transporters but the
protein itself how does it work how does
it mediate the release of organic acid
and can the protein actually respond by
itself to the presence of extracellular
aluminum so I'm going to focus today on
the lmts and I'll leave the the the mate
story for another opportunity so the we
almt was cloned back in 2004 and it said
the it was the the first almt
characterized at that time and thus they
gave it the name of aluminum activated
melee release Channel since then we know
that they're expressing the root tips
and subsequently we and other groups
were involved in the cloning of amalog
uh amalog genes to lmt1 which these
genes are in fact involveed aluminum
resistance they mediate the release of
organic acids and they're associated
with the aluminum resistance response
however nowadays we know that the LMT
family is not just uh Anon channels
involved in aluminum resistance but
they're involved in other physiological
processes there are lmts that are
expressed in guard cells so they're
involved in in the regulation of guard
cells there are other lmts that are that
are expressed in Roots and they are
involved in the in Mineral nutrition and
general
uptake
from a philogenetic point of view from
The genome sequence projects we're able
to establish that the LMT family is
pretty much divided into five different
clades with the set of uh aluminum
resistance related almts belonging to
Clay one now this is the only set of
almts thus far that has been
functionally characterized this is just
based in a genome sequencing
projects from a secondary structure
point of
view most event have a conserved
structure which consists of the first
half of the protein contains about six
transmembrane domains with the other
half of the protein being more uh
hydrophilic and containing
a it's it's about half of the protein
which is a a highly hydrophilic region
which I'll talk later about so giving
the similarity in the structure of all
these almts what we're interested in
finding out is what makes a given LMT
like this a LMT that is related to the
aluminum resistant phenotypes that we
observed we know that there are some
almts that are actually expressed in
Roots but they're not related to the
aluminum resistance so there must be
something about this particular set of
almts that allow them to confer aluminum
resistance phenotype in
plants so for this purpose what we've
been doing is we've been doing
structural and functional anal Anis of
particular of the the weat almt1 what we
do is we use a functional uh we use at
expression in alloc sites what we can do
is we can generate we we can express the
the transporter we can generate using
conventional molecular biology tools we
can generate different chimeras or
single point mutations
trations and so on just Express them in
the oyes we can generate CRNA we inject
the CRNA into the IDE cell which is
about 1 mm in diameter so it's really
convenient in terms of doing micro
injections this cells Express the the
CRNA they translate it they place your
transporter in the cell and you can
perform either functional studies using
conventional electrophysiological
techniques such as two Electro voltage
clamp or you can do structur uh
structural studies using uh taking
advantage advantage of different
fluorochromes what this allow us to do
is
perform the functional and structural
studies set hypothesis in terms of we
are expecting in terms of the relation
of the structure to the function of
these
Transporters and test test our our
hypothesis by generating different
versions or structurally modifying the
LMT and seeing what its impact in the
functionality of that transport protein
is so first giving the let me just take
you back one
slide given the fact that this uh
almt mediates the release of organic
acids upon exposure to aluminum what
we're interested to see first was what's
the interaction of aluminum with the
actual transporter and for that reason
the first step we have to take is to
determine what is the topology of the
LMT across the plasma membrane is this
side facing the cytool side or is it
facing the apoplasmic side of of the
membrane in terms of which is the part
of the protein that first sees the
aluminum experiences the presence of of
the L3
plus so to carry on the the membrane
topology studies of LMT what we have
developed is a technique where we have
taken advantage of the pH sensitivity of
the
gfp in such a way that the intensity of
the fluoresence of the emission of the
gfp is pH dependent such that when you
start hitting acidic
PHS the emission of the gfp or the
intensity squatched down it's
reduced so what we first developed was a
method where we can monitor the
intracellular pH of the oosy using a
small uh pH micro electrode so we impale
those cells with the pH micro electrode
and we establish a set of extracellular
solutions which we profuse on on the
outside of the oide and measure the
changes in PH that occur internally in
the
oide and this is what we observe as we
change the extracellular pH from 7.5
through 7 .5 plus sodium acetate or
extracellular pH of5 we maintain a
relatively constant intracellular pH
however when we put sodium um
extracellular solution of ph5 plus
sodium acetate sodium acetate is a weak
acid which dissociates at ph5 permal
bias is the membrane of the oide gets
inside and yields this intracellular
acidification in the oide so having
established this methodology we look at
what's what's the change in the Rel
ative fluoresence of the gfp through
this this uh set of solutions and what
I'm showing you here is a confocal image
of
uh of the edge of the oide as it's being
bathed through this different set of
solutions so at 7.5 is it running yep
basically the the intensity of the gfp
doesn't change and as soon as we put in
5.0 plus sodium acetate what we obtain
is a quenching of the gfb so we have a
nice system where we can correlate
changes in in the intensity of the gfp
with changes in intracellular pH so that
we we can use that as an indicator of
potentially where where is the gfp found
in this case obviously the soluble gfp
is found in the inell space we did the
same with a particular transporter at
mate by tagging it in the end Terminus
with the gfp and what we obtain is a
similar pattern to that described for
the soluble gfp we know that that that
the the inter terminal domain of the at
mate is located in the inside so we have
a good indication that our technique is
working now we use a negative control
using opt3 a transporter that uh we
heard about early this year a talk given
by Alena and uh we tagged it at the C
terminal we know that the thank you we
know that the ca terminal of of that
transporter is located to the
outside and just as you would expect
when you bath it to the different set of
conditions we have there's no change in
the first two solutions but as soon as
there's ph5 in the extrasellar space we
quench the gfb so we have a nice system
to show to basically use the gfpf an
indicator of is that particular n
Terminus or C Terminus located to the
inell space or the apoplasmic face of
the
transporter using this approach we took
our Gene of Interest the weed lmt1 we
first tag it in the C in the end
Terminus and what what we obtain is
pretty much the similar Behavior to what
we obtain for the soluble gfp indicating
that this particular gfb here is is
facing or it's located in the inter
space of the cell we've taken the same
approach with Transporters tagged at the
C Terminus we know that this C Terminus
is actually located into the inside of
the cell we know that the end of the
transmembrane domain six is also located
to to the inside of the cell and there
was some controversy about the potential
existence of additional transmembrane
domains around this region what we've
done is we've taken the gfp and we've
flanked those different transmembrane
domains and we found that uh the gfp is
located towards the inside indicating
that there's no transmembrane domain
region there even though it might be a a
highly hydrophobic region it might be
involved in the anchoring of the protein
rather than actually constituting a
domain which transverses the the lipid
bilayer
so having established the topology of
the protein the next thing we're
interested in understanding is how does
the protein assemble does the the
channel work as a single subunit so one
single subunit of almt is functionally
active or does it assemble as a
multimeric uh transporter in such a way
that you require the Assembly of several
subunits to form the actual functional
channel for this purpose we have used
BFC pretty much a well established
technique by now we've tagged the
subunits of almt with the two
complimentary halves of the yfp and what
we we get is complation of the yfp at
the plasma membrane indicating that almt
the almt subunits are actually
interacting we've also tagged the the
subunits in in opposite directions with
half of the of the yfp attached to the
end the other half attached to to the C
Terminus and we also obtain
complementation suggesting once again
that the C Terminus in and the end
Terminus are facing in the same in in
the same compartment the cytoplasma of
of the
cell so we know that the LMT subunits
interact the next thing we we were
wondering is what's the stomry of LMT so
are two subunits interacting or is the
transporter consisting of three or four
subunits
interacting for this purpose we're
collaborating with uh the is of lab in
UC Berkeley and uh what they use is they
use uh Turf microscopy
to to address this particular question
so the first step we had to do was prove
that their technique actually is
suitable for starting uh plant membrane
Transporters not just just suitable for
starting animal channel Transporters so
what we did is we tagged uh cat one with
a gfp cat one is a potassium channel
from arabidopsis and there's there's
good knowledge about the structure and
the Assembly of of this type of
potassium channels what we've shown is
that the functional properties of the
intacted cat one resemble those of the
cat taged with the gfp so the addition
of the gfp is not affecting the
functionality of the
transporter when we express that
transporter in all sites and in a low
density under the turf microscope what
you can observe is actually single gfp
molecules that are being photo
bleached single uh single gfp molecule
when you look in in detail to to a
particular set of of those single spots
and I'm just going to show you I want to
focus on on this red region
here what we can do is we can actually
measure the changes in intensity that
take place in that particular spot as
the as the gfp is being quenched by by
the laser so basically what we get is a
high-intensity point and as the gfp is
being bleached you lose the signal and
that's what's being Quantified here over
a period of about 20 seconds now what
you see is that the change in intensity
actually occurs in four very discrete
steps it's not a continuous Behavior but
you have four different steps or
discrete changes what that is telling
you is that you actually have four gfp
molecules that are emitting in that
particular spot four gfp molecules each
one attached to one of the subunits of
cat one in other words but that telling
is in every single spot that you look at
what you're finding is cat one assembled
as a tetr consisting of of the four
subunits and this is what actually forms
the functional transporter of cat one
four subunits assemble in such a way
that this this region in the middle
actually consists of the permeation
pathway or the pore of the transporter
so knowing that we can actually use this
technique for for plant cells what we
did is we implemented it for the almt1
and other almts and what we obtain is
that the Transporters actually assemble
as a
dier so this is the functional state of
the transporter we've done this for not
only the weat LMT we know that it's um
that also happens for the arabidopsis
for the maze LMT so apparently the dim
state is conserved throughout the entire
alent
family so what I've shown you so far is
those structural studies that we've done
uh basically just coming out from a
secondary structure we're able to know
more or less the topology of the LMT
across the membrane which part faces the
cytoplasm which part face the
extrasellar side we know that assembles
as a dimer now what we're interested in
in finding out are uh what are what are
the functional properties of this almt
and how do those functional properties
correlate with the structure
or the secondary structure
prediction so for that purpose once
again what we're doing is we're
expressing our protein of interest in
the oocytes we're able to load the
oocytes with the substrate in this case
melate we micro inject the cells with
melate a couple of hours prior to doing
the electrophysiological recordings and
we used two Electro voltage clamp to
study the activity of that transporter
expressed across the plasma
membrane to to put in simple terms
what we do is the cell is so big it's 1
mm in diameter we're able to impale two
micro electrodes on it with one micro
electrode we are able to impose a
voltage across the plasma membrane of
the cell with the other microelectrode
what we're able to do is we're able to
record the currents that are elicited or
that happen at that particular holding
potential those currents are simply the
movement of of ions across the plasma
membrane current is just the transport
the transport of ions across the plasma
membrane
so let me show you what happens in a
control cells by control cells I mean
cells that have not been injected with
the RNA so they're not expressing the
transporter versus what happens with
cells that have been injected with the
almt
transporter so here I'm showing you a
holding potential ofus 100 molts this is
the magnitude of the current again it's
simply a a it just relates to the amount
of Transport that's taking place control
cells so show a very small current very
basil endogenous transport taking place
across the plasma membrane and lmts in
the absence of aluminum mediate a
slightly larger transport in those cells
however what's really important is that
upon just adding aluminum to the bath so
basically you replace the bath medium
for the same solution but now it
includes uh about 20 micromolar aluminum
chloride what you get is a very
relatively quick it happens within a
couple of minutes a very quick
enhancement of the transport activity
mediated by aluminum by by LMT sorry so
here basically we have a transporter
that is not at the regulatory it's not
at the transcription level but actually
just happens within minute so basically
the transporter somehow is sensing the
presence of aluminum the fact that
aluminum interacts with the transporter
changes it Con changes the
confirmational state and it surrenders
the transporter in a more active
state so this is another way of of uh
looking at the transport activity of
almts so rather than holding holding the
the membrane potential for a long period
of time what we can do is we can just uh
look at the transport activity over a
small period of time of about 600
milliseconds at a given voltage say
minus 100 m 100 - 140 M
volts we measure the magnitude of the
transport at that particular uh voltage
and then we just keep changing the
holding potential to smaller and smaller
less negative holding potentials and we
keep measuring the transport activity at
those particular voltages so once again
these are just traces superimposed or
current magnitude superimposed at
different holding potentials once again
control cells show a very small
transport activity they still have some
transport activity and it's obvious it's
it's the transport activity from the
endogenous Transporters of the cell but
when you express almt you you obtain
a you obtain a magnitude of Transport
much higher which is mediated by this
transporter but most importantly when
you expose them to Al to to aluminum to
extracellular aluminum what you obtain
is once again an enhancement of the
transport activity mediated by the almt1
channel I'm not going to go into the
bioh physics of it but B basically we
can perform our s of analysis based on
the magnitudes of this current and the
different voltages and substrates that
we used which what I what I want to
summarize is that we do know that the
lmt1 one as I showed you is enhanced by
the presence of extracellular luminum
second it mediates negative currents
which are actually the product of melee
moving from the inside of the cell into
the outside of the
cell so here we are we have a transport
water that mediates organic acid release
just like you would expect it in in
Roots and most importantly it responds
to the presence of
aluminum so we're interested in finding
out what is it that
determines that aluminum enhancement
property and this is all I'm going to
talk about for the rest of the talk and
it's what are the motives or what are
the parts of the protein that are
actually responsible for
sensing the aluminum the extraer phase
so what we have been doing is we have no
structural knowledge of the LMT apart
from secondary structureal predictions
so we've
taken uh originally we took a crude
approach which is we started looking at
truncations of the protein so we started
by removing the terminal 19 amino
acids and we express that truncated
version of the protein into all sides
and we compare the transport properties
relative to the unmodified protein so
when you truncate the last 19 amino
acids basically you get a transporter
where the transport properties are not
affected the same is true if we removed
up to residue 435 so basically
expression of the first 435 residues
including this transmembrane domains
plus part of the SE tail results in a
transporter that's functionally
active however when we remove uh five
amino acid acids more from the terminal
region what we obtain is a transport
that is no longer functional we've lost
the activity of the transporter both the
basal activity of the transporter and
obviously as well as the enhan ability
of the the enhan ability feature of the
transporter we know that the transporter
is being targeted to the plasma membrane
so there's something about the folding
that has been lost that surrenders the
transporter uh nonfunctional not
surprisingly when you keep doing more
truncations around the ca terminal
domain we obtain Transporters that are
basically nonfunctional what was
surprising was upon removal of the
entire C terminal domain that long
hydrophilic tail what we obtain is a
transporter that recovers its
functionality however just just the the
end terminous domain being expressed
being functional it cannot be enhanced
or it's not responsive to the presence
of extracellular aluminum so what that
posed um what that what that is telling
us is the interal domain this first half
of the protein underlies the permeation
pathway which is not surprising seeing
that it contains the transmembrane
domains forming the pore where the ions
are going to flow through across the
Bayer but the question is is this C
terminal
domain we know that it's not essential
for protein functioning but is it
actually a domain that determines the
aluminum enhan ability of the
protein
so
when we expressed LMT we're able to
calculate a km for the aluminum enhan
ability of the transporter basically
it's concentration dependent and around
five micromolar we're able to get 50%
maximum activation or enhancement of the
transport activity of the almt what that
is telling us is that that high Affinity
what it suggests is basically aluminum
being al3 plus most likely is binding to
negatively charged residues in the
protein thus stand sorry g g uh we're
measuring the the conductance so
basically we look at the relationship
between voltage and current and the
slope of of of that relationship should
tell you what the conductance or the
transport rate of the transporter would
be so it's the basically the conductance
we obtain at a given U aluminum activity
over the the maximum conductance we're
able to
obtain so what that what that suggests
is that al3+ is most likely binding to
negative residues in the in the
transporter so to evaluate the role of
the C terminal of the LMT what we did is
we started neutralizing every single
amino acid negative residue uh in in the
C terminal of the LMT by changing
aspartic acid either to asparagine or
glutamic acid changing into glutamine so
basically we're neutralizing each one of
those residues we take each one of those
single point mutations we Express them
in all sides and again we compare the
influence or the potential change in the
functionality of the transporter
relative to the non-modified
transporter the data I'll be showing you
just um is just in regards to the
responsive of the transporter whoopa how
did that
happen
wow where are
we talk about
freak where somewhere around there
right
okay Jesus stay away from
it there we go so all the the all I'm
going to be talking about is the changes
in aluminum responsiveness how much does
the uh responsiveness of each one of
these Transporters changes relative to a
while type which we're going we're
calling 100% responsiveness so what you
can see is we we obtain a whole uh
variety of phenotypes in terms of the
percentage of enhancement which goes
from uh transports that are a little bit
more responsive but overall most of the
uh single uh mutations or most of the
neutralizations result in Transporters
with lower responsiveness with a couple
or a few Transporters that have actually
lost the responsiveness to aluminum
another way of presenting that
data is is this way in terms of the
magnitude of the responsiveness but this
is just to highlight that it's not a
discrete response but it's rather a very
continuous
response so there are interesting
residues like 274 275 and 423 where we
have actually lost the responsiveness of
the transporter and it's very tempting
and actually uh
the Japanese group proposed it initially
to say well we have identified the
residues where aluminum is binding to
the LMT as soon as we neutralize them
aluminum can no longer bind to the LMT
thus it's no longer responsive to
aluminum however we know that that's not
the case when when you look at the
distribution of those particular
residues uh throughout the entire 400 or
so sequences so far known for the alumin
for the lmts what we see is that
residues like 274
275 or residues like 423 are actually
highly conserved or entirely conserved
throughout the entire LMT
family so most of this sequence includes
lmts which are not related to the
aluminum uh resistance response so what
we think it's happening is among these
residues we have identified residues or
we have mutated residues which are high
conserved and they are required is
actually for uh they're required for
protein stability and proper functioning
as a overall almt family and they
actually have nothing to do with the
aluminum binding to a transporter or
with the phenotype of aluminum
responsiveness to
prove to prove this uh this hypothesis
what we did is we look for highly
conserved residues throughout the entire
family residues which are not uh
negatively charged s such as the
tryptophan here tryptophan
283 and what we' done is we've done a a
single point substitution in that
residue as well as a residue 218 or 431
but basically what we show is if you're
able to uh substitute those highly
conserved residues what you end up with
is a series of Transporters that are no
longer as functional as the original
almt therefore we do believe that these
residues negative residues we identified
originally are more involved in overall
protein stability folding and
functionality rather than they having
something to do with the aluminum
responsive responsiveness
phenotype so the next question we wanted
to address was can we move then the
entire C terminal
block uh and the entire C terminal block
is the one responsible for the aluminum
responsiveness so we have characterized
several almts this is the one I've been
talking about it's aluminum enhanceable
we know that the Hue in arabidopsis is
also aluminum enhanceable in the Maze uh
almt1 is not aluminum enhanceable so
what we' done done is we've done the
we've swapped the domains basically we
take the end terance of this transporter
and we attach the end terminers of this
transporter or we can take the inter
terance of this transporter and attach
the C termin of this transporter
resulting in this swap domain
in that way we've generated six
different uh swap domains we express the
cells uh we express these contracts in
all sides and we look at the changes in
functionality so just to summarize all
that data in a very colorful way here
I'm showing you once again the lmts
which are responsive and the lmts which
is not
responsive when you take the C terminal
region of the responsive almts and you
attach attach them to the interus of a
non-responsive
what do you obtain is no aluminum
enhancement activity so just the sea
block moved to a pore of a different
transporter is not able to uh enhance
the transport activity of that
almt likewise if you take the C Terminus
from from the non-responsive one and you
place it into the end terminous Poe
region of the two of the wheat and the
arabis what you obtain is actually an
enhancement of the transport activity
which was quite POS uh puzzling as we
thought that the ous domain was not
involved finally when when you swept
them among the two responsive responsive
ones what you get is in some instances
it's able to recover it and the other
construct is not able to recover it what
that is telling us that the nature of
the end terminal domain which what we
had this card originally is actually a
determinant of aluminum enhan
ability
so we decided to look at the end term
domain in terms of the potential
negative residues associated with the
with that protein region and once again
we perform single point mutations and we
look at changes in phenotype once again
we obtain a very continuous uh changes
in phenotype relative to the aluminum
responsiveness we obtain several
residues which basically surrended the
surrender the transporter in a state
where it's no longer enhanced by
aluminum I forgot mentioning that all
the single por mutations that we've done
actually result in Transporters which
are functionally active they mediate the
basal level what varies is their degree
of aluminum responsiveness however once
again when you look at this at the at
the residues at this particular residues
what we find is they are highly
conserved throughout the entire LMT
family so suggesting once again we
cannot attribute a role to these
residues to the aluminum responsiveness
of the protein but rather we think
they're involved in overall functioning
and uh stability of the LMT
family so the question is
uh is it all lost was it a lot of uh
single point mutation analysis that led
us know where um we took a different
approach so far what I showed you is how
we try to correlate the changes in in a
particular residue with the distribution
throughout the entire family based on uh
sequences from genomic uh
efforts now what we tried to look the
question we posed was okay let's let's
take a look at what What's Happening
Here in terms of the functionality but
are we able to find any domain on the
set of almts that have been functionally
characterized we have three lmts that we
know are responsive to aluminum and we
have a set of lmts that are not
responsive to aluminum can we find in
sequence alignments any particular
domain that might be unique to this set
of almes and the answer is yes what we
ended up finding is a motif right at the
beginning of the protein right at the
extreme uh end of the end term we found
a motif that is associated and is found
uniquely in this set of almts which are
uh aluminum
responsive so this is how the motif
looks is basically a highly conserved
region of the first 12 amino acids with
a variable region between two and up to
residues most interesting when when you
now now we're walking back to the
philogenetic analysis and we say okay
let's look through through all the
philogenetic uh through the 400
sequences that have been available at
the moment and see how this uh
identified Mo Motif is present in this
clades what we find is that out of the
403 sequences we find 17 sequences that
contain this Motif and interestingly
that Motif is only contained in
sequences that belong to Clay one which
is the the clay which accounts for this
particular
Transporters so everything seems to
indicate that this motif might be
associated with the uh aluminum
responsiveness of LMT and this is
current work that we're performing in
the lab what we've done is uh we have
removed that in uh that 35 amino acid
Motif and we know that the LMT upon
removing this Motif is no longer
functional so it's no well it's
functional but it's no longer responsive
to
aluminum however if we remove the
terminal eight eight amino acids we know
that is uh the LMT is still responsive
to aluminum so we're still looking into
we're trying to dissect which which of
this entire Motif actually corresponds
to the part or contains the part that
makes the protein responsible and that's
what we're evaluating at the moment a
whole series of of deletions of this
Motif also what we're testing is we're
taking that Motif and we're doing a swap
domain on an LMT which is not aluminum
responsive to see if insertion of this
particular Motif at the end Terminus
will bring back the responsiveness of
the
protein so overall summarizing what I've
shown you is we started with a secondary
prediction of the lmts we've done some
topological work uh and some um Turf
work indicating they assemble as diers
uh we know the topology is such that the
both the end and the C domains are
contained to the inside of the of the
protein what's still puzzling is if
aluminum is interacting with the
protein how come it's interacting with
domains which are contained within the
inside of the protein right if if the
especi of aluminum is such that at
neutral pH is aluminum precipitates as
is a hydroxide how come aluminum might
be getting into the cell and interacting
with motifs located in a in a region
which is basically neutral pH what we
think is we have identified regions
which are involved in the structural
changes that take place underlying the
enhan ability of the transporter however
the regions we have identified are not
necessarily the regions where aluminum
is interacting directly with the protein
and all this has been done with any real
structural knowledge of the L&amp;T uh we
have just done it with uh secondary
structureal predictions but we are in
urge we need to get a crystal structure
that allow us to place a spe uh spatial
structure crystal structure a 3D model
of the lmts to be able to overlap all
the functionality that we know uh to
basically to El elucidate what are the
molecular determinants of the
functionality of the
LMT so the other part that I never told
you about is the other family of
Transporters the the M Transporters
which is a complete different story
they're regulated in a different way and
hopefully one day I'll get the chance to
talk about it so basically summarizing
I've shown use sort of uh a set of
multidisciplinary approaches that have
allow us to initiate function structure
analysis of membrane Transporters which
are involved or mediate a particular
abiotic stress response this knowledge
will allow us to potentially identify
the AL of membrane Transporters that are
most effective in conferring aluminum
resistance in corrup plants and in the
era of uh genome editing it's it's it's
pretty plausible to propose that we
should be able with the knowledge of of
what are the domains that mediate
aluminum enhancement in a particular uh
family of Transporters we should be able
to engineer these membrane Transporters
in order to enhance their ability to
confer aluminum tolerance and thereby
expanding their usage in available
marginal soils so finally I just want to
acknowledge a lot of people that have
been invol involved at different parts
of this
project first of all the Oldtimer in the
kosing lab thanks for all the help
technical help and intellectual
discussions particularly I want to
acknowledge people from from my group
Allison aalu and armont who have carried
part of part of the work as well as
visiting Scholars International visiting
Scholars rotating students from plan
biology that have collaborated and added
little bits and pieces to the puzzle as
well as uh undergrads who have rotated
during the summer through the plan
genome research project that bti hosts
over the summer also
collaborators Ingo uh Ed they're
involved in the phenetic analysis as I
mentioned Ed is involved in the turf
work um Jeffrey Chang is our rightand
man uh in regards to fun to the
structure and crystallization of
Transporters and uh Dave snar and Kula
involved in other work that I hav't
present so thank you very much I finally
want to acknowledge the funding from
what used to be NRI nowadays is the is
the Nea Grant and uh thank you for your
time
um have you estimated the single channel
conductance for
melee no we
haven't with with the expression of Al I
haven't done any single
Channel because I looked at your Turf so
you have some Channel density yeah that
you can estimate and from your IV curves
I guess a melee are going in per
second so I wonder if you could maybe
estimate you do the correlation yes we
haven't uh I haven't done any single chw
from uh from experiment to those for
those that are not familiar basically
single channel is uh you can actually
isolate a little patch of the membrane
to measure the activity of the single
molecule of that
transport and measure the transport rate
what we did do was uh back in the early
2000s we did a lot of patch planing
looking at uh the transport activity
protopass for Maze and from that we
detected a we characterized a Ani
current which basically accounts for the
release of intracell uh an into the
extracell part of the protoplast and we
did single Channel work with that and I
believe it was a conductance of around
20 to 30 p seens in those conditions and
what we know is that that channel
isolated in patches also was dependent
on the presence of Mr Alum basically the
the patch is quiet if you remove
aluminum but as soon as you bring
aluminum seemly CH appears which is
consistent with the activity of but no I
haven't done any any single Channel Do
you have do you have any estimates of
the channel density from the turf
no
so I'm curious I know getting a crystal
startu obviously be a wonderful approach
to this but in VI of that if you look to
see whether that inter terminal domain
that you've identifi is potentially to
be some involvement in aluminum um are
there similar structures and other
transport proteins involved in C IR
binding that could give you some Clues
not for that particular so there's
something unique about that domain yes
it's pretty frustrating to work with you
know this guys when you work like for M
you just simply put your sequence out
here and you get three four different
Cales so all you have to do is take your
sequence thread it through those C
structures right those predictions you
get nice you throw in Te get nothing
choing half you throw just the internal
domains nothing it's a family unique
unique to the plan Kingdom all the more
reason to sorry all the more reason to
get that
in the LTS uh no I mean yes there are a
couple of substitutions at least for the
weak one originally they had proposed
two differents and uh the I think it's
like two or four me
last um originally they had proposed
from working all sides that uh
there was a functional difference among
them but uh but we have done the work
basically transport same expression so
no we don't which would be nice to have
you know a changing
phyp well there are no more questions
thank
again
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu