good afternoon everybody this is Laura
mcdermit from Cornell Cooperative
Extension I'm talking I just want to
welcome you to the Northeast s
professional development project um soil
management and Berry crops as a model
for management education this is the
11th in a series of 12 in-depth Berry
crop nutrition and soil management
trainings and um we are really happy to
have you here as you log on if you would
please just um uh know in the chat box
where you are from and what you work
with that would really help our speaker
who is from the University of Florida um
get a better idea of who is in the
audience um um I expect that we'll have
a few more people log on but in the
meantime I'm going to just show you um
around in case you have not been here
before I want to make sure that you're
uh custom and familiar with the um Adobe
classroom the web links box at the lower
leftand corner is where you can download
or you can be linked directly to the
websites that are listed the webinar
archives and Northeast s are listed
there then in the lower right hand
corner are the files um that we would be
very uh happy to have those of you who
have not filled out the educator
Northeast s educator pretest and the
Northeast s demographics questioner both
of these are very important for the
grant information so we encourage you to
um do that and send that back to Kathy
heyen Reich um but let's just allow just
a few more moments for people to log on
and then I'm going to go into the second
part of the training but just let me
give them another minute or so to make
sure that everybody's logged
on I do want to draw your attention to
the fact that um we're looking for a
little bit of input and at the very
bottom of the notes po if you scroll
down Cathy has stated that there's um if
there's any topics or issues related to
Berry crop soil and nutrient management
that have not yet been addressed um next
week on
March uh what is that March 6th uh
excuse me March 9th um the that is the
last webinar for this series that'll be
at 2 o'clock pm and Dr Harold vaness
will be leading that but part of that
will be to address any remaining
questions that might
exist um so I think at this point let's
um let's move into the second portion of
the
webinar and I'd like to introduce to you
our invited
speaker um Dr Santos Dr balinsky Santos
is an assistant professor of horiculture
with the University of Florida and EAS
he conducts research on strawberry
tomato bell pepper and increasingly High
Bush blueberry he works out of the um oh
sugar I should have read from the other
side I think it's the research station
the golf research station
um at Ias and he works specifically with
fertilizer irrigation protected
agriculture um with those remaining
crops and increasingly
blueberries
um and that's the Gulf Coast research
and Extension Center experiment Center
so thank you very much uh Dr Dr Santos
sorry I kind of got that introduction a
little bit bobbled but um um I'm going
to let you take it from here and people
will be continually logging on I think
that Dr Santos had asked um we spoke
about this earlier if you could hold
your questions till the end or if you
want to type them in go ahead but we'll
we'll take all the questions at the very
end of the presentation so thanks very
much and we'll get
started well thank you Laura uh I really
appreciate the opportunity to be here uh
today and talk to a very diverse group
of colleagues uh both in research and
extension really appreciate that and
also appreciate the fact that I am 80
degrees here in Florida where is kind of
cold up there uh so if you guys don't
fall asleep I'm going to try the best
that uh to try to keep your attention
towards this next uh few
minutes uh as Laura mention part of my
responsibilities at the University of
Florida
to direct the vegetables and small fruit
Horticultural program that focuses on
fertilization Water Management protected
egg and cultural practices for most of
our Target crops that include tomatoes
peppers strawberries blueberries and
most
cbits uh today uh we are going to be
talking mostly about
strawberries and how uh the fertigation
techniques and some of the Hydroponics
have been experimented here here in
Florida and abroad also because uh part
of the activities that we conduct uh
both research and extension uh not are
not only in Florida but also in
California Spain Argentina Chile and
other parts of the world where we have
all the research been conducted right
now
so with uh with that said we are going
to be focusing today on three basic
aspects and the fertigation by itself uh
we're going to be talking about a little
bit of the concepts of this um we're
going to be try to be really really
Broad in this knowing that previous
speakers probably touch a lot of the
aspects of the nutrition and
fertilization uh later we're going to go
to the rate determination which is
sometimes one of the most important
aspects and what relates to this when it
comes to fertigation and fertilization
of strawberries in general and also the
third touch aspect is going to be
touching on the some of the diagnostic
tools uh we are using right now I've
been asked
to look into not only the way that we
produce strawberries which is along with
California very different to the rest of
the country uh we deal with strawberries
as an annual crop uh we don't have a
second crop or the third crop like in
some cases we have in in in the north uh
but also some of the uh emergent
technologies that some Growers are using
not only here but in other parts of the
world when it comes to fertigation and
trying to determine the best way uh the
the best way the crops can
perform So within each one of the
subjects you're going to be seeing that
we have certain aspects that we're going
to be touching uh hopefully we're going
to be kind of thorough about it and give
practical examples of what each one of
these aspects mean and what we've been
doing in Florida with regard to each one
of them uh so
when we look at
fertigation uh we we cannot separate the
nutrition aspect from the irrigation PR
practices and we always tell everybody
that if there is one thing that
we when we talk about Fertilization in
general is that there are not uh certain
recipes that need to be followed uh
every situation is going to be different
and uh one thing that you're going to
see today is that we are not going to uh
give
specific recommendations blanket
recommendations for everybody to do
fertigation as opposed to touching the
principles that take you to those
recommendations and for you to adjust to
your own
programs so when we we call fertigation
in the process by which we apply
fertilizers uh through the irrigation
system and uh by doing that uh we can
use two types of specific specific
fertilizers the one that are ready to
use in a liquid Matrix uh which is the
most common method that is used by the
strawberry Growers here in Florida and
in in in in parts of California and also
we have the hydros soluble salts these
are solid uh salts uh just diluted in
water that you similar to the ones that
you buy sometimes in the in the hardware
stores that you go buy a salt and just
dissolve it and apply it both of them
have pros and cons obviously
when you carrying a big liquid Matrix of
fertilizer they charge you a lot more
for the for the cost of taking that
fertilizer to you uh because they're
carrying a lot of water with them
however these are fashionm made formulas
that you they are tailored to your
specific needs and you just apply the
formula don't have to worry about
usually about the formula precipitating
to the bottom of the tank unless that is
really cold uh and you know exactly
where you are applying the problem with
the salts when they are hydrosoluble in
contrast with that is that usually
people the the more that you handle this
the more R the uh opportunity for error
for human error that you're going to
find because one day somebody's making
the mixes in a week somebody is going to
be doing it uh and there might be
differences on the type on the
fertilizer you really applying in the
field however we at regardless of the
formula that you use no fertilization
program is going to be ever efficient if
a poort irrigation program is in place
and this is something that we've been
formulating to our Growers this second
aspect is extremely important uh
strawberry growers in Florida are very
efficient handling the water during the
season and that uh translates into good
use of uh the fertilizer that is applied
during that period
now uh we know and when we talk to our
Growers that usually this process is not
a a simple process that that they can do
uh on their own without the education
that we carry to them and one of the
principles that we uh tell them all the
time is that nutrients only move as far
as the water moves those nutrients so
they have to be clear about that and
that's that's why a lot of uh strawberry
Growers are very very successful in that
regard however many of you might be
wondering you know how they handle
Fertilization in a situation like they
do in Florida well soil this is the type
of soil that we have it's very Sandy
extremely Sandy is the closest that
you're going to find to a beach without
sodium in it uh and that makes it
extremely challenging in fact somebody
asked me the other day uh how we were
able to do this and I just tell them
that we take a lot of the hydroponic
principles to produce strawberries here
because it's the closest to the
hydroponic system that you're going to
find in real life when you got this deep
Sands infiltrate really quickly and
that's challenging to us because when
you have a soil like this when Growers
apply water and have a crop like
strawberries that we grow and a annual
health system like this when usually we
establish the strawberries with
sprinklers irrigation
protect the berries also with the
sprinklers and have one or two drip
tapes like the ones that you see here at
the bottom of this slideing each one of
the beds um it creates an opportunity to
apply fertilizers in a very efficient
way but at the same time it's a CH it's
challenging because you can have have a
high risk of leeching fertilizer and if
you don't believe me that I'm just going
to leave you with this picture when this
is a cross crosssection of a bed uh
Sandy bed like we have here in Florida
and the picture on top uh
represents uh watering that bed with one
drip tape for one hour that's how
quickly the water moves down without
moving further out on the
sides uh and that's when we have to
challenge ourselves to keep those
nutrients within the root Zone on and
making sure that nobody uh Waters
excessively so they can be efficient
when they apply
fertilizers uh the pictures the P the
second picture at the bottom of the
slide represents beds with two drip
tapes and in both cases this is one hour
of irrigation and the top uh uh in that
case we were able to achieve 31%
coverage of the bed of the area of the
bed whereas with two tapes you get
barely 67% that means 2/3 of the bed
have been are being water when when you
have one/ third of the bed that hasn't
been uh touched by water so you have to
be sure that you not only put the right
rate to fertilizer but also the
placement of that fertilizer along with
the irrigation program has to be
efficient for us to make sure that we
make uh we make make the best use
possible of the uh resources that are
put out there in the field for producing
strawberries now uh going back a little
bit to the principles that we uh follow
here in Florida particularly we usually
tell our Growers that they shouldn't be
irrigating for more than an hour uh and
the reason is that those pictures that
you just saw after an hour of irrigation
you're probably dumping uh most of your
fertilizer into the
aquifers uh because it just leaked
down also another important
thing that we tell our Growers is that
they should have monitoring
equipment to make sure that they monitor
how much water they have in the beds and
knowing when to apply and when to not to
apply uh later on we're going to see
some uh pictures of the type of
equipment that they're being that is
being used right now to make sure that
the water is used
appropriately also we extensively
educate our Growers on on on knowing uh
the kind of soil that they have they
have to calibrate their soil they have
to know what the Field capacity is
because believe it or not all the Sands
are not equal there are some Sandy areas
here that are very fast very fine sand
that you get the Field capacity when the
soil is barely in 12% whereas there are
other areas when you have a heavier type
of sand that where Field capacity is
around 18% so they need to know exactly
what kind of soil they have and even
within the same Farm knowing the pockets
of soils that they might have and I'm
going to provide more details later on
on the broad diagnostic of farms and how
Growers can section that farm uh
depending on what kind of soil they have
uh the whole objective of all this
obviously is to keep the water in the
rooting Zone and to do that we want to
make sure that our Growers at least have
one of these two if not both pieces of
equipment that allow them to uh monitor
water in the
soil for that uh we have two basic basic
pieces of equipment uh tensiometers
which are the traditional uh piece of
equipment that measures water tension in
the soil they have very decent accuracy
even though we are disputing this more
and more because sometimes in the middle
range uh of tensions you might not have
an accuracy that that will tell you
exactly how much water you should put
out
there the disadvantage is that you have
to use one unit per location that you're
going to be collecting data and making
sure that that uh unit is there and it's
clean that's it's not collecting algae
and anything like that extremely easy to
use and very
inexpensive however there are other
pieces of equipment like what you see on
the right here the which is called a
Time domain refle refle
reflectometer uh which is relatively
expensive one of these units can go
anywhere from 500 to thousands of
dollars uh it has this handheld unit
that gives you an instant reading of a
so volumetric water and has these prongs
that going into the soil that can be
calibrated at different depths and you
it can tell you instantly the the volume
of water that you have in the soil
therefore if you know that your soil fi
capacity is at
15% uh at 6 in deep you immediately get
a reading that tell you that that's what
you have over there uh the another
advantage of this unit is you can buy
one unit or two units for the whole Farm
you can have a farm manager just going
around and just collecting the the
volume of water in the soil uh the
beginning of the Cycles or before the
beginning of the irrigation Cycles it's
very easy to use however the downsizes
is that could be a little bit
unaffordable for some people there are
other units that are extremely more
complicated that are based on the same
uh principle or similar principles uh
but I think that that escapes the scope
of what we're trying to do today we're
not trying to do a seminar on how to
monitor water but rather to use prti
itical tools to monitor water and a in a
in a situation when Growers might be
struggling to make a profit
so uh usually when we go into into also
in farms we are try to make Growers
aware of the necessity of knowing what
kind of cultivar they have one thing
that we found is that uh ctiv might
respond totally different to the same
fertilization and irrigation programs uh
uh and obviously varieties that have
been bred in Florida will respond
different than varieties that have been
bred in California just basically
because they've been bred in to totally
different environments so the selection
pressure will be different and the
situation of the California soils would
be different to ours and that would be
true for a lot of varieties that are
bred in other regions too so we' been
trying to develop tools that allow us to
tailor different formul for different
varieties and we're going to talk about
that a little bit
later now um when it comes to the second
part of the fertigation uh soil versus
soiless culture I realize that the vast
majority of strawberries in the US are
grow on the soil however there is a a
increased uh movement of people going
into protect the culture and going into
soiless culture within those structures
and that requires all also for us to
provide knowledge to that increasing
group uh both for the traditional H uh
Market of strawberries and also the
organic market of
strawberries but for that we just have
to make sure that we know the physical
and chemical properties of our soils if
you're doing soils uh Field capacity as
I mentioned wieling Point texture
structure as as important as uh all the
chemical properties such as or organic
matter content pH nutrient content
salinity and Carion exchange capacity we
have to make sure that our Growers
understand that that's extremely
important uh to adjust those
fertilization programs when it comes to
soiless culture uh so you got three
different categories of soils that
you're going to find you got the solid
substrates uh that which we're going to
talk a little bit in the next slide we
got the pure Hydroponics that are the
plants just and the liquid Matrix of uh
solution uh nutritional solution and
also you got a something new that is
called relatively new that is called
aeroponics when the plant the plant
roots are in the air and you get the
constant mist of water with nutrients
that are spray into it obviously of all
this the solid substrates is the most
common and the most used uh not only
here in the US but in other parts of the
world now when talking about soiless
media uh the basic principle is that we
are just replacing the natural
soil with a lot of these materials uh
however many of them are naturally
deficient on a lot of nutrients you got
you you can you can pick whatever
soiless media is out there and you
always going to find deficiencies uh of
certain nutrients and that's when they
know how comes into place play you need
to know what kind of media you have uh
but we know that a so good soiless media
should provide good root support uh good
nutrient water retention allow gas gas
exchange and also be a pest-free
environment because is a way for us to
get away from the fumigation of the soil
and and and other problems that we may
have now when it comes to Mineral origin
media uh you got perlight mulite sand
and rock wool which are very common out
there and in the organic uh side you got
all from very vegetable or animal origin
you got coconut core Pete Pine Bar
compost different types of compost all
kind of compost out there and also rice
holes that I usually either used as they
are or
burnt uh you look at a lot of these
materials and as I mentioned as I put it
in a slide before not necessarily the
cheapest is the best uh it all depends
on what kind of needs you have what kind
of irrigation fertilization program and
Equipment you might have in the farm if
you have a an equipment that you can
only fertilize once per day you might
want to make sure that your soiless
media adjust to that type of regime uh
otherwise you're going to may be running
in trouble here in Florida we have some
specific examples of
soiless and containers that are being
used for strawberry production this is a
grower uh field here in Florida when we
get strawberries growing in troughs and
those troughs are filled with pine bark
uh all of this with drip tape and
fertigation uh also bags almost very
close to the soil over this uh concrete
blocks uh when when we fill the bags
with pine
bark also Soo you got other Growers that
have bags that are filled with coconut
core uh usually these bags are premix
and bring the coconut core and usually
it's imported from
Asia and
uh finally you have also Growers that
might been have been struggling in the
past and have tables like this and they
may be reusing those tables for
something else like people that had
nurseries before and we've been
converting some of these people to uh
producing strawberries on top of the
tables with
substrate also other people have been
looking into vertical production with
these vertical systems they they they
might save a lot of space however
usually when you run into these lower
levels the the light quality and
intensity is a problem and strawberries
might not flow too well down there
however for the first two three four
five levels depending on where you are
and the type of plastic cover that you
have on top you might be very successful
producing the
crop now moving on when we look at the
injection
equipment uh for fertilizers you usually
are talking about uh two or three
classical pieces of equipment that are
uh convenient and some of them are very
cheap and has pros and cons uh with
regard to one and to to the
other the first uh piece of equipment
that I want to show you is uh what they
call the ventory so uh suction uh
injector this is very simple uh uh
system however the problem is that when
you have a system like this you as the
pressure of the line of the water line
changes you might be changing
the pressure and the injection of this
uh each one of these uh ventes into the
line which is going to end giving you a
very variable fertilizer rate that
you're going to be applying so this is
very simple method very inexpensive for
a lot of Growers but they require to
monitor the injection of each fertilizer
more efficiently that they would do with
a system like this this is uh what
usually the very constant
uh injection they could be both
hydraulic like the one on the left or
they could be electric like the one on
the right and there's a company that is
called dosatron that's why we're taking
the name from uh no endorsement intended
here uh but these systems in inject a
very constant rate uh at at a very broad
range of pressure water pressure so if
you go from 20 psi to 10 psi you you're
going to continue injecting the same H
concentration of fertilizer into the
stream which is going to allow you to
have the same rate it's just that the
irrigation and the fertigation process
is going to last longer if the pressure
drops so for those of you who might uh
uh have plenty of money to go into it uh
especially Growers uh there are some
computerized consoles that do all this
for you and you you don't have to mess
around a lot with this system because
they adjust the fertilization throughout
the season by themselves you just have a
program that goes into but this these
are a lot more expensive that all those
methods and one thing that we want to
make sure is uh and take home message is
that more expensive not necessarily
means
better uh it depends also how you uh set
up your system and how committed you are
to be precise in terms of the fertility
ation that you're going to be applying
uh in many cases when you got
hydrosoluble fer fertilizers you got the
multi-tank injection point when you got
one tank for every type of fertilizer
that you're going to be applying out
there uh for example in this tank in the
left in this case you got the acids like
phosphoric acid is being injected
through that tank and this one you got
micronutrients uh that are being
injected in other cases you got
phosphates and sulfates and in the other
one you have nitrates the idea for this
is that you don't mix a lot of these
fertilizers
because they can precipitate to the
bottom so the if you have a hydrosoluble
fertilizer you need to separate them and
make sure that you inject inject the
right proportion of all of them this is
a very common system that is used in
green houses all over the world when
salts are added to water instead of
ready to use uh liquid solutions like we
use in the open field in Florida in many
parts of
California so moving on to rate
determination which is the second part
of our our conversation today uh you're
going to see a lot of now practical
examples of how we calculate rates for
strawberry production in Florida I just
want to put this slide here so you
refreshing to you what the macro
micronutrients are and a lot of this
formula sometimes might not have all the
micronutrients uh and they need to be
supplemented depend depending on the
soil needs that you have so but even
more important even as important as uh
rate determination also we need to make
sure that we know the sources the place
the placement of the fertilizer and the
timing when all this is going to be done
and to make
sure that we sometimes in some cases for
some micronutrients like for example
zinc or iron or sulfur uh we use blanket
recommendations because sometimes we
don't have specific calibrated uh test
that would tell you exactly how much we
need in a syst in that place or you
might have a piece of land that is brand
new that nobody has done any any
strawberries in that part of the the
state and you may need to do use blanket
recommendations while you calibrate the
system in anyways when you are
determining the the specific rate of
application you have to make sure that
you take into account the crop
requirement the leeching the losses
through volatilization and chemical and
biological immobilization in the soil
and that's going to give you a rough
application rate that you're going to be
applying all these tools we taken into
account when
determining uh the best rate for
producing uh for applying and
fertilizing and producing strawberries
in our state now at the same time that
we say that we mentioned earlier that
the different
cultivar uh with different growing rates
and plan arit tecture is going to play
major role on how much fertilizer you
put out there uh so we focus a lot of
our attention here in Florida to looking
at pre-planned and early n andp
fertilization as well as uh um at the
adjustments during the season of
nitrogen and potassium throughout the
the production
cycle uh
to give you a clear picture of what we
do in that regard
we concentrate a lot on nitrogen and
pottassium because these two are the
most used nutrients or the most applied
nutrients in our situation nitrogen is
usually apply 100% through the drip
tapes uh Sometimes some people might
apply a little bit and pre-plant uh 6
years ago this was around 60% of the
acreage right now uh we are only below
20% of the acreage of people that apply
pre-plant nitrogen uh and supplement
that that with drip later on the usually
the rates were between 20 and 50 pounds
per acre of nitrogen that were applied
before the drip tapes were in uh in the
case of potassium 100% is delivered
through the drip tapes uh a lot of this
has been changing in the recent years
because of the environmental concerns
that we have in terms of nitrate moving
into the groundwaters and uh also
implementing best management practices
for the crop however there is no single
best management practice better than
Rising prices of fertilizer and
sometimes I say that in a way that sound
sarcastic but that has created uh a more
conscience uh throughout Growers of how
to use fertilizer more efficiently
because the prices have been going up uh
in the year 2000 one Tong of fertilizer
was below $200 an acre the $200 a Tong
and right now fertilizers are above 500
and that's has created that conscience
of we need to be more efficient applying
fertilizer uh for strawberry
fertilization a common very common
fertilization program here in Florida is
using one to one and a half pounds of
nitrogen per acre per day which is going
to add up to around 150 to
175 pounds per acre per season remember
our season starts in October and we are
done at the beginning of March it's a
very short season because our
Market is the Winter Market and after
that other states take over the
production in the state and we become
really hot to produce strawberries so in
that short season we apply uh usually
between 150 175 pounds per acre
potassium is a little higher because
people have the perception that apply
more potassium at the end is going to
increase fruit quality uh which we're
going to try to illust rate you uh on
that regard in the next slides and also
we are more conscious now right now
about looking at phosphorus and the
early stages of production now when it
comes to using start the fertilizer for
applying nitrogen we've conducted
research in the past that that where we
compare uh the no application of
pre-plan fertilizer versus the
application of 50 pounds per acre of
pre-plan nitrogen using a monium nitrate
as the source and what we found uh in
that research consistently over time is
that uh there was no significant
difference across the board in any of
the months when we H compared the
production uh of strawberries by not
using stter fertilizer or using stter
fertilizer at the beginning and this was
done over a period of three years and
this this this is important because it
means not only that the Growers might be
saving around 17 to 20 bucks an acre on
the application plus the labor and
everything else but also it's 50 pounds
per acre and you multiply that by 10,000
acres that's a tremendous amount of
fertilizer that was just sitting there
and doing absolutely nothing uh for the
crop
so after that you know a lot of Growers
were moving out of the business of
applying pre-planned nitrogen uh to the
CR
and what they did is that they started
applying drip H connecting the drip tape
as early as possible to the crop and
started injecting uh nitrogen fertilizer
as soon as the plant was on the ground
and they did that for the first 10 days
well we also conducted research looking
at this but this time we made it a
little bit more complicated and we took
two different varieties two varieties
are standards for us Florida H
Strawberry Festival which is a most
grown variety uh here in Florida and
that is is the red line and Florida
Radiance that is the blue line and what
we found is that these two varieties
that had two totally different
architectures react totally different to
that initial fertilizer rate that you're
putting out there uh in this case we
compare zero
0.5 one and one and a half pounds per
acre per day in those two varieties for
the first 10 days after transplant we
injected that amount and we collected
the early yields of the varieties and
what we found is obviously with zero
there was no difference but there were
two totally different patterns as you
increase to two
0.5 pounds per acre you can see here
that Strawberry Festival continues
increasing its early yield As you move
to one pound and stabilizes after that
whereas with Florida Radiance the
maximum yield was obtained with 0.5 PBS
those are appli more than that there
were no significant differences uh from
that obtaining at 0.5 pounds per
acre that is giving us more confirmation
that we need to design uh more tailor
made formulas for specific cultivar and
taking into account that many Growers
apply as much as one and one and a half
pounds per acre across the board for all
the varieties uh now we have to come up
with ways to differentiate across the
cultivar and part of the research that
we've conducted uh had a lot to do with
that and and that's why you see right
there we look at two other two varieties
and then we started applying nitrogen
throughout the season which is different
what you just saw what you just saw
previously was nitrogen at the beginning
starting in the season
and uh we started looking at nitrogen
throughout the season now uh in two
different varieties and I have to make a
a a a note here that this is regardless
of the source we didn't find any
significant differences if we were using
uh calcium nitrate and other nitrogen
sources we were getting similar
responses as you're going to see in a
second uh what we found again is that
there are different responses across
cultivar regardless of the source of the
fertilizer that you're using and some
varieties like this blue line winner
Dawn which is a very small plant uh all
it requires is 3/4 of a pound of
nitrogen per AC per day whereas a big
variety like strawberry festival needs
to get at least to 1.25 pounds per per
day to maximize early
yields
uh when when we look at that we say okay
what about if we start comparing this to
a newer variety like Florida radians and
we did a similar study when we were
looking at that and we found that again
we had two very Sim two very different
patterns in the two varieties Radiance
and Festival when uh Radiance was
maximizing at
0.75 3/4 of a pound and Festival was
getting the maximum at
125 so that's giving us extra
confirmation where it's even more
important that extra half pound per per
day if you were applying an Radiance
without needing it it might mean 60
pounds per AC per season that's a
tremendous investment that you don't
need uh when you uh producing Florida
Radiance
so what
about nitrogen and potassium ratios
during the season we've been told and
led to believe that by switching
potassium towards the end in
strawberries is a good thing to incre
increase fruit quality well uh we've
been doing studies when we are looking
looking at the traditional grower
practice that is uh applying a formula
like 604 or 704 during the season until
mid December and switching later to a
heavy potassium formula like 406 or 408
towards the end supposedly to improve
quality well research has been conducted
in that regard and what we found out
consistently is that plan di diameter
when you go in different ratios one 1 to
one 1 to 1 to 125 and 1 to 1 and a half
nitrogen to
potassium there were no significant
differences across the
board however when we move to
Total uh uh fruit weight of the plants
there was the same pattern that was
occurring with uh plan diameter when
there were no differences uh among all
the ratios that were used the same occur
when we look into the the soluble solid
content or the bricks of the fruit there
were no differences of the ratios uh
remember that when I'm talking the
ratios here uh Growers tend to switch to
one to one and a half pounds during the
SE during the end of the season to
increase quality well that wasn't needed
of in any of the three varieties that we
tested uh consistently in the last two
years here so there goes that myth that
potassium heavy at the at the end
increases the quality and the total
fruit number and weight what we did find
and this was
expected were differences across the
cultivar and that was
expected uh
so uh when it comes to changing nitrogen
and potassium during the season we can
conclude that uh that we can use a same
fertilizer rate to throughout the season
provided that you providing the correct
rate from the beginning and the plant
has develop a very good rooting system
to go down there and get the fertilizer
that you already been applying in the
beds and you keeping all those nutrients
without the root zone
now uh also we are looking into making
sure that we adjust the practices for a
specific Growers and that Growers design
programs that make sense for the needs
now how do we design these programs uh
in the sense and how we monitor all this
throughout the season
obviously the diagnos diagnostic tools
are going to be a tremendous help for us
and yeah I know a lot of
the uh uh visuals assessment has been
done during the season and nothing beats
your own eyes but the problem is that
usually when you see a deficiency is
kind of late it's usually it has taken a
toll on the crop and you see a situation
like like in this picture on the right
you got a severe deficiency here and and
you want to make sure that you get to
the plant before the leaves turn this
yellow uh obviously s deficiencies
cannot be seeing a plain sight and uh we
need to monitor uh nutrients throughout
the season we usually tell our Growers
that there are several tools out there
that they need to make sure that they
have and no specific tool is uh it's
going to help you
to do a one fits all type of diagnostic
sometimes you need you need your own
eyes out there looking at the field also
you need need also uh to do probably
some kind of colorometric test at the
same time you might do the foler test of
uh to the plants uh in the past the
peral sap has been used uh there are
several there are severe contradictions
out there on whether this is the right
time to use a perial sap test and
whether this is a really valuable tool
to measure deficiencies in plant because
uh some people argue that when you have
high concentrations in the pedial perals
act as reservoirs for uh nutrients and
not necessarily means what is going
through the vascular tissue to the
leaves so that that's one thing that
keep an eye on that not only to use
perial sap as only test other people
also look at colorimetric measurements
to determine the greenness of the leaves
especially if looking for nitrogen
magnesium iron deficiencies uh and they
use this pad meter which uh measures the
greenness of the leaves and uh those are
just two of the most common tools that
are used out there however when you look
at
the uh composition of nutritional
composition of the leaves uh usually
nothing beats a a good Leaf analysis the
downside of this is that obviously by
the time you collect the samples and
send it to the lab and you get results
back several days might go by and that's
why the mo the the proactive approach of
making sure that your
Solutions are accurate that you have the
right pH that you have the right
Electric electrical conductivity of the
solution which by the way we haven't
touched a lot but usually you got
certain targets like for the pH of the
solution you don't want to to go above
7. six or or even to eight nor lower
than
6.2 uh to make sure that you have the
right solution out there it's also going
to depend on what kind of media you have
if you're growing in the soil or if
you're growing in a media that captures
or retains a lot of those nutrients that
might give you more leeway in terms of
what kind of solution you might want to
apply out there at the same time uh the
electrical conductivity of the solution
you don't want it to be too high and I
know that's particularly a Pro a problem
in places when you have very high EC of
the water for example here in Florida in
in our station our water is 7 point 0.7
DEC cement per meter uh uh the
electrical conductivity of our solution
so when we apply fertilizer we usually
don't want to go above two because
strawberries are extremely sensitive to
any solution that is applied to them
consistently above two the per meter so
you want to make sure that you keep a
balance and that's going to have a
direct influence on what frequency of
fertilization you're going to use if for
if to obtain the given fertilizer rate
that you want it's going to take that
solution above two then you probably
better off lowering the concentration of
your solution and applying the applying
it more frequently so all those are
aspects that we work with Growers to
make sure that they have the
right program in place so they don't go
overboard and start seeing salinity uh
problems and uh pH uh uh pH disorders
and the soil uh that I going to I going
to start showing in the plants some of
these problems and also blocking the
absorption of certain nutrients
nevertheless we have a sufficiency range
for strawberries that uh our university
has put together in our uh production
handbook and we get certain uh
guidelines not no written Stone but
certain guidelines and how much nitrogen
phosphorus potassium calcium magnesium
sulfur iron manganese zinc Borum copper
and M mum the plant needs uh in a
driveway basis when when it comes to
adequate range of fertilization all this
is available either through our website
uh here in my program or uh the
extension website of the university is
free of charge
uh could be accessed from anywhere if
anybody has a question about later on I
would like that uh table to get to you
you can either get a copy of the
presentation or to access the website
and I will be happy to direct you to the
right right spot below that table we
have another table as I mentioned
earlier we use all these measurements
all these diagnostic tools to complement
each other you got a table that also
show show you the perceived sufficiency
ranges for our conditions for nitrate
nitrogen and the perals and also for
potassium uh in the in the leaves so all
that is available at the same time and
both tables are together like that so uh
we just want to make sure that we
designed the right uh programs for our
Growers now towards the end and we are
in the last few slides here uh we want
to concentrate all also in what it's out
there
um now uh I know a lot of people use
area photographs as a tool to diagnose
uh symptoms and this is extensively used
in agronomic crops uh when people uh
corn uh soybean and other crops out
there and it's a tool that has been used
more increasingly more in vegetables now
especially when this extend growing
extended uh ER areas uh people are using
S more actively nitrification Inhibitors
uh just to slow down uh the process of
conversion from from nh4 to uh
nitrate uh and also uh more and more
people are using crop crop refractance
measurements that are is just a
sophisticated method to determine uh the
colors of the plant and what is
reflecting from the plants and I know
some fellow scientists have been working
Act in this uh and I I wouldn't be
surprised in the next few years this
method takes uh is used a lot more
extensively in the US one of the methods
that has been used here in Florida
especially for people who have large
very large uh strawberry areas talking
uh above 100
acres is using the aerial infrared
photographs as you can see in this
picture it gives gives you a good idea
of what the high uh Vigor areas in your
field are and what the low areas are and
usually that's tied up to the the
specific properties of the soil or
specific practices uh of that soil for
example in this specific case you're
going to you're going to see H the areas
in green that represent the low Vigor
areas of that field and reading a little
bit of The Narrative of this picture
those were areas that were both either
poor fumigated or uh have very uh
limiting drainage situations in it and
this is a a tool that has been used more
actively now
to know what you have in the field and
make sure that you make adjustments
either on that season or for next season
uh to do amendments uh pinpointed to
specific blocks of land of your field as
you can see here you got in the left
side of this picture you got nine
different fields all of them with very
different uh Vigor with the same
variety uh and that allows that grower
to to say okay this is a very low spot
this is a very high spot or this is a
spot that has higher organic matter than
the other and that allows you to make
adjustments now towards the end now uh
we are looking more increasing
into uh looking at the effect of
nutrients and growth and quality not
only the traditional nitrogen and
potassium but also I mentioned that
we've been focusing even more on
phosphorus now uh the reason is because
even our soils have a lot of phosphorus
uh available uh sometimes we see
phosphorus uh addition increasing the
quality of the of the plant and then
that's probably because when they own
transplant is putting in the beds you
don't have enough phosphorus around the
root zone for the new uh roots to absorb
at a given time so you might have
phosphorus in the environment but might
not have it where you want it so we we
are working on that too the other thing
that we're doing uh is working actively
on management of soiless culture uh to
make sure that Growers have what they
need uh and every specific soilless uh
meat I has specific
characteristics and we want to make sure
that we pinpoint to them what are the
practices that they need for a specific
conditions that they might have in the
farm if you got any further questions
Beyond this seminar um I'm putting my
email there so anybody can feel free to
expand over this and discuss this a
little bit further or if any other
subject was left out uh I would be more
than happy to answer your question just
allowed me couple days for it because I
keep traveling all over the world so
sometimes I might not even be in the
country when I might be answering some
of the questions but I will be happy to
do it because this kind of a exchange uh
with uh people from other states on
colleagues researchers and extensionists
is what really what enriches the process
of uh gaining knowledge and generating
Technologies for our Growers and all the
growers in the US with that I'm going to
leave it for questions and I appreciate
your attention today and your patience
with all this uh
presentation Dr Santos thank you so much
um this is Laura speaking and we do have
a couple of questions that people have
typed in I imagine there's a few other
questions out there so those of you in
the audience go ahead and if you have
them please type them in I have a few
but first um Jeff Miller asks whether or
not you've compared the use of calcium
nitrate with Ura or ammonium sources of
nitrogen for trickle
Solutions well that's a great question
uh and as I mentioned before uh We've
compared those sources and uh talking
about calcium nitrate and and ammonium
sources and we have found no significant
differences in the way that it's used
for strawberries now if we were talking
about other crops it might make a whole
lot of a difference especially
blueberries that we know that respond a
lot better
to uh NO3 sources than rather than
ammoniacal sources uh but in the case of
our strawberries and the way that
Growers handle it uh and the rates that
we use we haven't found any significant
differences across the
board all right thank you and the
beginning portion of you started talking
about ratios of n to K where K was less
than a 1:1 ratio you were talking I
think more about K being a higher ratio
but can you uh mention if you check
those ratios where K was actually
less yes we have we have checked those
ratios before and we decided to leave
that out of the research because in
preliminary studies we found out that
those ratios that correspond to less
than one pound per acre per day
pottassium really start taking a toll on
the plants so usually from the condition
that the Growers have here in California
Growers tend to over apply fertilizer
not to under apply and but by looking at
those ratios and preliminary stuff uh
research that we conducted told us that
yes we didn't need to go lower than that
but rather to compare one one and a qu
and one and a half pounds of potassium
during the season which is the most
common practice for those Growers
here okay and then we have one more
question and I think you mentioned that
the goal for the pH of your solution
would be a 6.2 of a low and then the
maximum would be somewhere between 7.6
and
8.0 that's correct and th those are the
extremes and you try to have a a
nutritional solution that doesn't go
below 6.5 and doesn't go higher 7.3 or
something like that if you have to deal
for a short time with a solution that is
7678 is not the end of the world but
that tends to accumulate over time so
for a given point in time when you're
applying that you might might be fine
especially if the plants are big and
vigorous they can take it really well
however you try to stay close to
neutrality as much as
possible okay wonderful um we have
another question