this is a production of Cornell
University thank you Susan for the
introduction and it's always nice to
talk to your colleagues about your work
so to today I'm going to tell some of
our recent research on crop nutritional
quality improvement so my lab has been
focused on mainly four areas one is the
C noid research and the ano signning
selenia and the michelon bio
fortification and today I'm just going
to tell you some of our recent research
results on CR noid research so this is a
slid I always like to use to introduce
Crow noise so Crow noise are not Le to
any of us because CR no gave their red
orange and and the yellow color find
Elling vegetables fruits and flowers so
why are we interesting with C noid
research this is because C noid are know
to be important in human nutrition and
health like reduce the risk of cancer
heart disease and eye age related eye
diseases and it's some of the croto we
called Pro vitamin A choid like a beta
Carin contain one or two beta rings and
they are not to provide the precursor
for vitamin A senses since our humans
can't synthesize the vitamin A so all of
the vitamin A in our diet can be
ultimately traced back to Coto origin
and many staple crops are known to
contain very low level of crop noise as
a result they contribute to the global
prevy of vitamin A deficiency and as you
can see vitamin A deficiency affect a
large number of preschool children and
the pregnant women in those poor
areas so typically uh CR noid are C40
turboid compounds the croo bi synthetic
pathway has been very well established
over half century ago and the main crop
noid because the double bond and the
ring structure give distinctive colors
like we know tomato is red color because
tomato accumulate a lots of lco beIN and
carrots is orange color because
accumulate lots of Alpha carotin and
beta cartin many yellow flow like a
death de is yellow color because
accumulate looting and other zensor
fails so during the past two decades we
also start to understand uh the the
process to produ to produce April crop
noise include some plant homas Ava and
St electon and also beta ions they
volatile compounds to give flow fruits
the the flavor and aroma so all the
genes in the Coro biosynthetic pathway
have been major Gene all the gene the
major Cal biosynthetic pathway have been
clone and the whale studed from many
crops and plant species however T now we
still have a very limited knowledge
about the transcription factors and the
Rory genes control the expression of
those paway genes so crop noise
essentially are synthesized in plastic
in Plants
tissues
so crinoid can synthesize in nearly all
kind of plastic like amop plast uh
chromoplast and chloroplast Etc but they
accumulate in high levels in chloroplast
in Green Leaf tissues and also in Chrome
plast found in many flour fruits and
vegetables since the ultimate goal of
our research is to understand how plants
can synthesize high level of crot noise
so this is our Focus to try to
understand how crot noise are
synthesized and regulate In
chloroplast so for many of you know for
long time my lab has been work with the
orange Jean that was originally Clon
from Orange
cauliflower and uh you the map based
cloning strategy we cloned this Gene and
found it's does it does not encode a
enzyme involved with croto bios
synthetical pathway but instead it's
encode a protein with one on low
function and contain DJ sit in reach
domain but it's not Cho on protein by
itself because it's lack of the J
domains so recently in collaborate with
Israeli scientist we found that the O
Gene is also also controls beta cartin
senses in mow
fruits so our collaborate uh
collaborator from Israel and they made a
cross between the orange mow fruit dely
with orange green mellow fruits tamy Jew
and in the F2 population in this
particular population they found the
orange fruit flash
segregate with 3 to one ratio
essentially it's this tray segregates as
a monog genetic dominant trays so they
did Association analyze and they found
that the O Gene completely cosegregates
with flash color in this F2 mapping
population as you can see with green
green flash fruits contain this band and
orange contain this B so in C in in
addition they also servered a white
genetic collection they have and they
found the or existed in two hpo ties one
is associated with green flashh for from
all those ger plant collection and one
is associated with either yellow or
either orange or green or
white so in
collaborate in collaboration with them
we clone the oin from green fruit green
flesh and uh orange flash fruits and we
transform them into plants as you can
see they Gene from Orange if the Gen the
O Gene from Orange Flash fruits can
introduce can induce Coto accumulation
like the orange cauliflower Gene however
they Gene from the Green Flash fruit
can't introduce additional Coro uh
accumulation just like a white Ty
control so we looked at the the SE the
seing a sequence between this two
variety there there are six nips and
five of them cause silence mutation and
but one of them cause msense mutation so
essentially the the later genetic
variation show that the in green flesh
fruits contain the G and in the orange
contains the A and with the the they
change it's CA one single amino acid
change to change the ariny in the o into
hting the orange o so to see if
this sleep or this single nuclear tide
difference uh is indeed responsible for
the fruit flash color and the g the sequ
U the nuclear TI was CH was mutagenized
so what we did is that we changed the g
into a in the green Gene and we we
change the a into g into in the orange
Gene and as you can see the green Gene
now can induce Coto accumulation and the
Red Jeans can't introduce croto
accumulation so this will confirm the
effect the indeed this slip is
responsible for the or function and we
called this slip golden
slip and we called it L sleep because
with this single sleep change one amino
acid and it can cause beta carotin
accumulation and also change the fruit
color and this golden slip is
responsible for all the Mellow color
difference at least from those germ
plasma I a collaborator
collect from all around the world so the
next question we asked uh was does this
golden slap also work in other plant
org so what we did is that we changed
the conserved we did Cy direct muten Li
to change the conserved ariny in this
case in arodis or Arin changed Arginine
to Hine phenoline lysine and Aline and
we also Chang the nearby Arin into Hine
and transform those construct into
plants to look at the color change and
as you can see here when we ought the
conserved ariny into history in the arop
OR Gene and the it's CA the crop no it's
cause the color change in arabis C and
when we looked at the color change and
found that the color is indeed
associated with Cortino increased Coro
accumulation and more importantly if we
look at the profile and we found that
the beta cting ratio in the white uh
colors only 15% but this become over 50%
during two weeks of dark in
incubations and in addition we found the
hesting substitution in a crop or in
this case San or gen it's also caus the
same effect lead to high level of croto
accumulation moreover we found that the
hting is not the only amino acids change
show to be effective we showed that the
Aline replacement in the org is also
equally effective to promote croto over
production as you can see the the the
the colors cure become dark orange and
show high level of coronoid
accumulation so this experiment shows
shows that the both o or Aline can serve
as effective genetic tools for croto
accumul for croto manipulation so what
does this finding means for CR
Improvement and sometimes go when we
first close on the cauliflower or Gene
and we we test its effect to improve
crop nutritional quality and in
collaborate with Joyce W and we put the
cauliflower or g into potato
tubers and the or transing does not only
induce CR no increase in the fresh prate
tuber but during the storage they it's
stimulate continuous accumulation of
beta caring as you can see here
following five months of storage the
crot no increase over 10 times in some
lines and furthermore in collaborate
with Mike mour we also look at the cral
accumulation during storage of the
squash and as you can see the color
become darker during storage and it's
also associated with with increased CR
noise so what this means the actually
the significant of this findings that we
know staple crops with as I just
mentioned staple crops with low level of
beta cartin contribute to the global
prevalency of vitamin A deficiency and
we also know know that the beta carting
in stable crops is not very stable
during storage because in most of the
case those beta cartin are synthesized
and store in Amo
plast so through this two o uh o
transing experiment in potato tuber and
also the Squatch experiment we know that
the oing or in the squash case the both
most case they provide some unique
mechanism to improve beta carting senses
and also stable storage during the sto
during stay uh and beta carting
stability during the storage so if we
can find the mechanism maybe we have a
way to improve our stable crop with
enhance the beta carting level not only
for continuous senses but also staing
storage during past post Harvest
storage so I showed you that in Orange
cauliflower we know the mutation is
duing to a insertion of large transposal
elements however in the M case the
mutation is this duing to a later
variation with the single nuclear TI the
difference so because this is single
nucle tide we Pro that that the single
nucleotide change to change a specific
amino acid and it change the
functionality of the o to promote corol
accumulation so all of many of us know
that Geno editing become the technology
you to use to change our G to
enhance to change to improve economic
trace and so we are waiting for the
maturity or advanc of the technology so
we can
specifically replace one or two nuclear
tide to change one amino acid to say its
effect you
improve beta carting accumulation in
staple crops and actually in collaborate
with Peter bear as the inventor of
golden rice they are not trying to put
our o h
they are trying to manipulate the rice
Orin to change the hting to change the
Argin into hting and see if it can help
indeed can help improve the total CID
level in Golden rice and most
importantly say if it can help stabilize
the beta carting doing post Harvest
storage and also we know that or I'm
sorry so we also we know that there
there's taing method and also looking
for later genetic variation so so
through those approach we are hoping in
future we can improve the staple crop
beta carting level not only through
transg approach of no we know it's not
uh in good state to do that but we we
believe we can get use some way to
improve to to create the function a of
the org in stable crops through non
through transitional breeding
approach so maybe some of you already
notic that in our experiment we
expressed both Y type O Gene and the
mutant o Gene and although both of them
show the similar level of gene
expression and also similar level of
protein expression but they show the
dramatic difference in induced CR noid
accumulation as you can see the both the
color and the total crop no accumulation
so one question we were asking was how
does the or or Aline or the or mutant
differentially regulate C noid
accumulation so to answer this question
the we try to ask what is the function
of the Y type O Gene so to answer this
question we did uh we were looking for o
interacting proteins to find the O
interacting proteins we use the co imuno
precipitation in conjunction with mass
spectral analyze so essentially we have
our robotop plants Express the or Y type
Gene TCT with gfp and the gfp only we
extract uh protein from this plants and
mix with beads and you then you loot out
the COO precepted protein and in
collaboration with T touser at our
usdf unit and they his lab analyze those
Gil band and identified uh around
19 proteins that can be this is 19
conserved protein actually from each
each gel and we identified more than 100
proteins so we essentially from multi
biological replicate samples we identify
Protein that's as potential candidates
for all our interaction proteins very
excitingly we found the psy or Fon
senses as one of them so what is Psy the
psy of Fon senses is the rate limiting
enzyme in Cal by senses paway and uh
it's also the first enzyme in the
specific pathway there are lots
of experiment shows that manipulation of
the PS why expression can have a
profound effect on total crop no
accumulation and here I show you some
example like a golden rice here's a
golden rice one and golden rice two you
can see the crop no level is quite
different actually the only difference
between Golden rice 2 and golden rice
one is change the psy and golden rice 2
use a high active Psy from Maze and
golden rice one use Psy from Death de
flowers and also here's the golden
colola it's just Express the psy you can
see the Colona seeds color change from
green to orange color and there are Lous
experiment show you express any Psy from
from any plants normally you can get
orange
colors uh showed like here so to come
confirm that the psy is indeed they all
are interacting proteins we use we used
three different approach to confirm that
and the first through e two Hy for acid
and as you can see not only cifl or but
Aris or there's a
lot or like protein they all interact
with Psy in yeast two Hy I
and we also did put down assd to confirm
such interaction as you can see here
when you mix the psy tack protein with o
tack protein you can see the O put down
with gfp and you can detect with CMAC
show the direct interaction but not in
the selective controls and the third
approach we used the BFC and the further
confirm such inter action in Vil in
plastic this is the site of CR noise
senses so what does this interaction
means and how does this uh interaction I
found affect the psy expression so we
generate the O over Express n we also
got the lockout and also generate the
double lockout as as you can see with
those AR robotop Sy night they show the
dramatic difference in O protein and
gene expression and then we looked at
Psy gene expression as you can see here
you alteration of the O expression does
not affect gene expression then we
looked at the protein level and as this
slides show you with the over EXP press
of the org cause increased accumulation
of Psy and in the single lockout the the
psy protein level is very similar we
think that they complement with each
other but in the dou lockout the psy
protein level was significantly reduced
and this is showed in leave case and
similar in Roots you see the similar
pattern of ofly
change so how does o affect Psy
abundance now we know with overe Express
Psy reduce PS overexpress o reduce
Express o and it's cost Psy change so
how how does or affect the psy abundance
so what we did is we introduced Psy gfp
tag protein into Y type or arob is and
also into all our background our
robotopsy plant and then we extract the
protein and uh inhibit with CHX the
protein senses inhibitor and looking for
the the psy gfp protein level and as you
can see in the O background the turn
over rate of the psy was significantly
dramatically reduced compared with
without the protection of
or so in addition in our collaborator RF
Welsh from Germany and he also looked to
say if they increase the
psy uh protein level is in active or not
quite often when you upregulate a
protein it can be just a protein level
up regulate but not lary means active
enzyme level so from his result clearly
showed that with overexpress o increased
the psy protein level cause increased
enzyme activity as you know that PSY the
key enzyme in the quoid Bios sensis and
then they correlate accumulation of
choid was observed in leaf tissues when
we have overexpressed o and when it's Dr
significantly reduced when the or level
was
reduced so in summary of this part
essentially we showed that both o and O
like directly interact with Psy to to
enhance Psy protein level and activity
through regulate Psy protein stability
and because Psy is the key en um in the
Copo bensis pathway it caus increased
cropo accumulation and actually this is
one of the first case demonstrate a
protein can act act as a post
transcriptional regulator of Psy to
regulate crop no
accumulation so let's come back to the
same question we tried to answer so how
does or mutant differentially regulate
cloid accumulation in both of this case
does the differential regulations
through differentially regulate uh
Psy or there are some other
mechanism so to answer this question and
uh we compared the o h and O interaction
with Psy EAS two high as you can see
both
or and
or white type protein interact with PSY
and both of them also caus increased Psy
protein level in car's culture and we
also looked again in collaborate with r
wor from Germany he looked at the
psy enzyme activity from o his line with
O and we found there's no difference
so which indicat that the
differentially induced Coto accumulation
it's not duing to the O H has a high
capacity to increase the psy activity or
increase the biosynthetic
activities so previously in our study we
showed that with the O mutation in CIF
flow with the single gene mutation it's
caus the change from lumous Pro plastic
into one or two large Chrome plast in
the CT M Curt influence mer stem cell
and also in the shoots epidemic shoots
cells similarly our collaborators from
Israel and they also observed in mellow
case if you look under light microscope
and there's one or two large much Chrome
plast per cell like if you look at
tomato there each cell contain a huge
number of chrome PL so both of them
shows that the mutation or the later
variation can
induce large chrx formations so what
happen with
arabidopsis Ki that show the difference
big difference with Coro accumulation
and we look at this is long TR G and out
dois C and you can see there's a plastic
contain some dark circle that's plast
globin and with the overexpress or the
plastic become larger but they can they
retain the same shape but the pl Globe
will become darker and um with the high
electrod dense this is the same as Psy
only express We Believe crot noise are
accumulate there but when you look at
the ORS mutation or or mutation and you
can see the plastic shape changed from
those and become the membrane structures
actually those member structur member
member Chrome plx show exactly the same
as what we observed in Orange curved
cauliflower so those experiment uh
confirm shows that the key for this
specific high level of Coro accumulation
is duing to the unique ability of the o
h in induced Chrome plast biogenesis
actually this experiment is fairly
significant in a lot of way we know
arobic are excellent model system to
understand genes the signaling in many
many process however ad dois
doesn't contain doesn't contain a tissue
with chrome plast so essential we show
here now we generate our robotop 9 that
has a program to be able to form Chrome
plast therefore provide us a system to
better stud genes and signaling in
Chrome plast
biogenesis so here's from our research
uh we should show that the O mutant has
du functions in induced croto over
production why as post transcriptional
Regulators to regulate Psy enzyme
activity and a larger one
is actually the most important is have
unique ability to induce Chrome plast
biogenesis and because Chrome plast
provide WR a storage sync that can sta
storage a crot noise at the same time
it's also stimulate continue bio senses
that's why the lines can those plants or
those lines can can have high level of
Cino accumulation currently we still
focus on or because till now or still is
the only genes that know to convert
conver Chrome plas biogenesis so but how
this o gen control Chrome plus Genesis
is still unknown so this is the topic
and we are focus on
now so in addition to those research we
also take the advantage of VAR is omic
tools to discover genes and proteins re
require for high level of Coro
accumulation so one full experiment we
did is protein omic analyze of chrome
plast proteins in fruits and vegetables
as you can see here we
extract uh Chrome plaster from some of
CR no in Rich fruits and vegetables and
we are hoping to looking for the common
mechanism involved in those crop
enriched crops for Chrome plaster
biogenesis so we
we we separate the Chrome plast protein
from all from all from those those
vegetables and the fruits and one thing
interesting we found that if you look at
the All Chrome plast the ATP senses and
ATP ATP trans locators are most abundant
proteins in those in all those six
chrome chrome plast so the high
abundance of ATP senses and the nuclear
tide translocators suggest a important
role of them in control or energy
production and transport in control
Chrome PL
biogenesis and the one project uh is
going on in the lab is we trying to
figure out if the ATP and ADP
translocators is indeed involved with
chrome plas
biogenesis in addition we also did quite
a lot of RNA SI ex experiment in
collaborate with many colleagues on
campus and one of experiment is the bulk
segregate R A6 transcript and analyze
so in again in collaborate with Israel
scientists we use the same lines to that
they all our are gen mow fruits so what
they did is they grow the the homoy F3
family uh plants and they extract the
RNA from 25 orange or green fruits at a
is develop fruit developmental stage and
actually here are the RNA samples showed
there so we bed those RNA and did the
transcripton analyze and here's showed
the crot metabolical passway gene
expression pattern and you know we know
you have as we know that
mow the orange mow accumulate high level
of beta cartin we found nearly all the
Upstream genes are up regulated doing
fruit development similar as a fruit
mature and the down stream gen are uh
down regulate during fruit development
but very
interestingly in Orange fruits and the
croo accumulate but for the green fruit
there's no huge CR accumulation but the
gene expression pattern is similar which
indicate additional mechanism in this
case we believe the storage sync a
mechanism difference between the green
and orange fruit to distinguish the two
kind of fruit
varieties and in addition in collaborate
with Jung Jin F uh at BP he helped us to
analyze of those transcripton data and
in addition he also did the Sleep
analyze of the orange and green
box and with this box essentially we
only got very low only 64 slips that
with over 90% of R to distinguish orange
and green buls and within those snip
only two genes one is the O Gene and
there is another one it's totally
completely distinguished 100%
distinguish between the box so if we
don't know the org is responsible for
the orange color through the bulk
segregate r s Allin we will uh we would
identify the oring which also show the
effectivess of the bulk strategy for G
discover and the a co-cr gate currently
a visitor scientist who made law in the
lab is study that Gene to see if it also
contribute to the cateo accumulation so
we we looked at the differential Express
Gene at different fruit
development stage and we found that
there's only one gen Shield differential
expressed in all fruit development stage
but we are mainly focused on the 20 da
to and we select a few candid genes B
candid genes for functional analyze as I
told you the AR robotop is color system
we used to start the O function and it's
showed very responsive and effective to
response the genes that's involved with
scoto accumulation and we all know that
the AR robotop is with flowering deeping
method you can simultaneously transform
a lot of genes so this system also
really give us a relative High
throughput to test those genes and the
proteins identified from other omic
techn
omics and in addition as I told you that
in M case it's no o control the orange
was non orange fruit flash color but
within the o g plus collection there are
several magnet there is the SE there
there is the several magnitude variation
of beta carting levels so again in
collaborat with is really scientist we
are going to genotype those germ PL
collection by GBS and then look the
association between the mow fruit beta
cartin content and the later genetic
variation not only to identify some
markers to be used for M mow breeding
but we are hoping to identify add
additional Al that control high level of
Coro
accumulation so in summary our data
shows that the O mutants can serve as
effective gen I two for CR no
enhancement in food crops both through
transitional breeding and hope through
both through genetic and the
transitional breeding approach and also
all mediate beta carting over production
through regulate both Psy with enhanced
bios sensis ability and also Chrome plas
with storage
abilities and uh as I just as I
mentioned we believe that if we can put
the
croto into Chrome plas instead of Amo
plus we can help to it can significantly
help to stabilize the beta car in stable
crops and a lot of things our data
showed that post transcriptional
regulate of Psy represent a lava
mechanism under crop no accumulation so
finally I like to say co- co- workers
here's the people currently in their lab
and especially I want to
thank posted in the lab for the work I
described and also some foral lab member
for their work I Des described here
especially Shang jino and also a
undergrad student Katie aing and she did
fouryear research in the lab she's a
co-author of three of our
Publications and she was graduate last
year with the high honor and her honor
sisss research I mentioned briefly and
then now she's a MD PhD student you a
very Prestige PhD MD
program finally I also like to thank
some of my wonderful collaborators the
Israel scientist and their students and
ra for menal work ra W from Germany from
for all our Psy work and
some Changi and Shing then from China
for the plastic work and also some
long-term collaborators on campus for
their contribution for their work I just
mentioned here and the funding from our
research SE from our USDA space Farm Bar
Grand and USDA Lea Grand and thank you
for your attention I'll be happy to
answer any
questions this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu