this is a production of Cornell
University so I'm going to do my best to
use the the Mouse as a pointer here so
that everyone can see in both
locations uh it's my great pleasure to
uh give an overview of our
research uh I'm going to touch
on a number of projects uh that we got
going but there are a number of projects
that I don't have time uh to get
to and I'm going to break up my talk
into four sections here so here's an an
overview of what I'm going to talk about
starting with the most applied and
ending with the most uh basic aspects of
our
research we start by talking about uh
the overall agronomic system of growing
shrub Willow as a bio energy crop give
an overview of our breeding program and
some of the unique aspects of breeding
uh
Willow I'll talk about our emerging
resources for uh mapping in Willow both
qtl mapping and Association mapping and
then get to a project that's funded by
the department of energy uh their feed
Stock genomics Program uh where we're
trying to look at the genomic basis for
heterosis in triploid hybrids of
Willow so this is the typical land that
we target uh to grow Willow on uh Willow
as a pioneer species will do well on
marginal Agland and uh it is a crop that
we uh aim to avoid the conflict uh
between food and fuel uh by targeting
underutilized or abandoned Agland uh so
this is a site at Vernon Verona Cheryl
High School near Rome New York uh that
is typical of a lot of the abandoned or
underutilized Agland in uh the Northeast
and Upper
Midwest with Willow we can convert that
uh marginally profitable land back to uh
more conventional agriculture although
very low input and very low labor
requiring agriculture uh so we planted
Willow at the high school here in uh
2010 I'm sorry in uh spring of 2009 and
this is what it looked like uh by
October of
2010 uh at that high school they have a
very active uh FFA program uh where they
make maple syrup and they're actually
harvesting the willow to burn in their
evaporators uh while they make maple
syrup
so here's an overview of the willow
agronomic
system uh we are aiming to uh develop
conservation tillage as a method of site
preparation you see here that uh the
first thing we have to do is kill the
existing
vegetation and uh as a part of that for
both weed management and nutrient
management uh Eric Fabio in my lab is
doing a lot of work on uh first planting
cover crops as a part of that site
preparation but we've also been working
with agenetic a company in Rochester uh
to use GPS guidance uh for Zone tillage
which is uh what you see here uh
followed up by uh GPS guided planting
using one of these mechanical Planters
this one was built in
Denmark so we're planting uh dormant
cuting stem cuttings here these are
whips that are about 7 or 8 ft long that
the planter will cut into 8 in pieces
and push into the ground as it moves
along we plant in a double row system
with 30 in between the rows with either
a five or a 6ft Alley between those
double rows uh with 2 feet between the
plants giving us uh a planting density
of about 6,000 plants per
acre those plants will uh those cuting
will root fairly readily and uh push
buds to make new choots that will grow
about 5 or 6 feet tall by the end of
that establishment year and uh we take
advantage of the natural biology of
Willow by cutting them back or
compassing them which then stimulates
vigorous regrowth in the start of that
second
year so while we uh discard the biomass
that's produced in that establishment
year uh once those plants are
established they will vigorously
resprout after each cut
back by the end of that first year after
Copus or the second year of of
production on that site uh we typically
have growth of 12 to 15 feet tall and
our normal production cycle would go on
a three-year Harvest
Rotation by which time the plants are 20
to 25 ft
tall we harvest in the winter time
typically we're planting on poorly
drained sites that are wet uh so in the
winter it uh is an advantage uh to have
the ground Frozen it's a time when uh
forage Harvesters like this New Holland
forage Harvester are not typically being
used uh so that uh harvesting operation
can switch off their corn harvesting
head and put on a willow cutter head and
continue to use that Machinery through
the winter it's a time when we need
chips for heating and obviously it's the
time when the plants are dormant so it's
a good time to cut them back and you see
that all the leaves have fallen uh so
and and returned back to the soil uh
recycling those nutrients in the leaves
back to the to the
soil uh that those wood chips then would
be collected blown into a truck taken to
the conversion facility uh here you see
a whole truck dumper at a power plant uh
just north of Rome New York uh where
they're piling up chips uh to load into
their
boiler again that following spring the
plants would vigorously resprout
starting a new growth cycle a new year a
new three-year Harvest cycle we modeled
the economics based on seven of these
three-year Harvest Cycles but there's
good evidence from Sweden that uh yield
is
maintained uh for at least 10 Harvest
Cycles so there's really no no end in
sight in the productivity of a willow
Plantation once it's
established that biomass can be used in
a number of different conversion
processes uh here in New York state we
have three woodf fired power plants uh
and Willow is uh more than adequate fuel
for those power
plants uh there is an Emerging Market uh
for feed stocks for liquid
Transportation fuels and in fact the uh
US government has set some very
aggressive targets uh to produce 20
billion gallon 20 billion billion
gallons of uh Advanced renewable
biofuels uh by 2022 we're nowhere close
to getting to that point uh because the
technology for that conversion is
lagging behind and is quite expensive at
this point compared to uh
petroleum another viable Market that we
have in the Northeast is to use wood for
renewable Heating and this is a
smallscale boiler that uh We've
installed here in Geneva to heat two of
our buildings entirely fueled by Willow
Willow can also readily be pelletized
and used in uh in uh pellet stoves or
pellet
boilers we've done a fair amount of work
to look at the wood composition of
Willow that composition will be critical
for many of these liquid biofuels
conversion
methods uh it's not so critical but but
even still uh ther thermochemical
conversion combustion uh or
thermochemical conversion to liquid
Transportation fuels will also have its
own optimal biomass composition and we
see quite a bit of variation in biomass
composition uh among our different
varieties in our breeding program so
unfortunately that's about all that I
have time to talk about in terms of uh
biomass composition but it is a critical
trait uh for these different conversion
systems uh just to emphasize that uh
Willow is a viable commercial crop and
that the government is invested in
developing Willow as a crop uh in 2011
the USDA initiated uh a
program uh to plant uh to provide
planting Subs for Willow in Northern New
York
specifically uh this overall program is
called the biomass crop assistance
program and our area in New York among
these uh uh nine counties I believe it
is uh is specifically to pay 75% of the
establishment cost to plant Willow uh
provide an annual land payment and to
link the Harvest of that Willow with
conversion in local uh Power Plant
facilities these three Woodfired power
plants that I talked about uh one at
Fort Drum called Black River this one
just north of Rome uh the lion sale
power plant and one up near MSA the
shatay power
plant uh and those power plants are then
paying uh a contract price uh set by the
uh bcap
program so we have about 1, 1200 Acres
about 500 hect STS or so of shrub Willow
uh in commercial production in New York
State uh there's about uh 20,000 acres
in production in
Sweden uh in Denmark in England uh
growing production in Poland uh and
Ukraine uh Hungary so uh it is a viable
commercial crop uh being developed for
renewable
energy so that sort of summarizes our uh
production system or
agronomics uh again just want to point
out that there are significant barriers
to adoption of Willow uh including the
high cost of establishment the cost of
cutting production is a limiting factor
uh compared to seed production such uh
such as for switch
grass uh it is a system that needs
specialized planting and harvesting
equipment which most of which is built
in Europe New Holland has invested in
developing their own uh Willow cutter
head that uh is matched with their
self-propelled forage Harvesters uh but
still there is a lack of commercially
available planting and harvesting
equipment the key uh point that uh leads
into the next section of my talk is that
the economics of of biomass production
of Willow is dramatically improved
improved when we get increased yields
per acre as you can
imagine so breeding for improved
yield uh for more stable production
across marginal sites is a critical
factor for the long-term adoption of
Willow as a renewable energy
source so I'm going to move into talking
about uh our Willow breeding program
first of all establishing our goals
first goal well the first three goals
are all yield
uh as I just mentioned fitting that into
the economics of the system the more you
yield per acre uh the more uh we will
encourage
adoption it is a perennial crop that
will stay in the ground for as long as
30 years so longterm uh durable Pest and
disease resistance is critical as I
mentioned Uh Wood composition is a
critical aspect for uh matching feed
stocks to conversion
technology and we also always need be
conscious of the cost of cutting
production and uh stool form and plant
form Crown form uh branching for
example uh is a critical aspect for
efficient cutting production as well as
harvesting
efficiency we're now moving into looking
at uh aspects of stress tolerance as
well for particularly marginal sites and
I'll show you that uh one type of site
we're very interested in is reclaim
minland in Pennsylvania and West
Virginia so keeping all of these goals
in mind and underlying premise that we
work with is that we want to maintain a
genetically diverse Suite of pedigrees
among our commercially deployed
cultivars uh since we are planting
clonal material we always want to
maintain a high level of genetic
diversity in the field uh to hedge
against any uh individual cul of our
failure due to Pest and disease
susceptibility so our overall approach
and strategy in breeding Willow is to
rely on species hybridization and the
hybrid Vigor or
heterosis uh that we observe in species
hybrids so here I've got uh pictures of
three people who have been critical over
the years uh in actually doing the
controlled
pollinations uh and the cross that we've
done starting in 1998 and 99 uh Rich cop
who was one of my PhD students at Sunni
ESF really developed our techniques for
uh extracting pollen doing controlled
pollinations in the greenhouse did our
initial uh
hybridizations and many of our current
commercial cultivars are uh genotypes
that rich bread uh many of which we've
now patented
uh Kim Cameron took over for Rich and
did a number of very successful crosses
in 2002 through
2005 uh which I'm going to talk about as
well uh working as a postto in my lab
first at ESF and then helping me move
here to
Cornell and more recently uh Sam Noka
who was a Hobart student helped out in
the greenhouse over the last two years
helping to uh manage and maintain
thousands of seedlings in the greenhouse
he was a a real asset to
us so one of the features of salx and
I'm going to distinguish salx from
populus uh the two main species in the
salic AC one of the features of seix is
the tremendous species diversity uh that
we see in that genus there are over 300
species of salx while in populace there
are only I think 34 different speci
species and they range from dwarf
sprawling uh Alpine shrubs uh to you
know the weeping willow or black willow
trees that we're familiar with we work
exclusively with uh species in the
subgenus vitrix which are primarily
shrub form Willow they grow with
multiple small diameter stems never
really uh achieving a single stem uh
like the tree form Willows do
and in particular we're working
primarily within the section Helix and
making crosses with the section Dion uh
but you see there is great potential for
species hybridization here another
feature that's unique about cix
especially compared to populus is the
abundance of polyol across the genus and
in this particular scheme of species
that we work with in our breeding
program you'll see that cix may be
from Japan is Teto a natural Teto and
seasic Clos very common in the European
reading programs is hexaploid while all
all the other species here are
diploids uh I'm going to talk about some
of our genomics and we focused in on
seix peria as a reference genome uh for
our initial uh genome sequencing efforts
it is a central species in our breeding
program it is a consistent diploid but
you can see that it is a good species to
hybridize with uh many of the other
species in section Helix and also uh
across sections here with members of
themen I'm also going to talk about in
our work on triploids uh crosses between
seix peria and salx Miana as well as
crosses between seix Vialis which is the
main uh species in the European Willow
breeding programs and salx Mayana as you
can imagine these crosses between
tetraploids and diploids will generate
triploid progyny and that will be a an
ongoing theme here through the rest of
my
talk so uh since 1998 this is
uh uh a list of all of the different
species combinations that we've been
able to produce over the years uh I've
underlined the species that are
triploids so you see a significant
number of those progyny are triploid but
we have the capability to combine uh
multiple species here and and our
long-term strategy is for overall
Improvement of diploid
species independently of tetraploids to
make that final uh F1 hybridization
between the dip diploid and the tetrol
generating triploid
progyny uh since I moved to Cornell in
2009 we've produced about 10,000 uh
seedling progeny representing our next
round of potential uh cultivars for
selection so up till now we've largely
been relying on phenotypic selection and
the other uh Willow breeding
programs uh the main ones being in
England and in Sweden Sweden as well
have been relying on phenotypic
selection and this is our overall scheme
that we've been using first to do those
control pollinations in the
greenhouse uh producing seed that we
immediately sew uh and get started in
the
greenhouse uh in Midsummer we transplant
those out to the field so here we're
talking about thousands of
progyny uh outplanted to the field here
as you see we're doing uh in our Nursery
beds here in
Geneva and then typically we would
evaluate seedlings within uh family rows
in those Nursery beds and make a
selection on the order of 10 to
15% uh within the best families and then
propagate those to replicated selection
trials and these have only been on
single
sites uh and here we're talking about on
the order of 60 to 80 genotypes that are
Advanced into these selection
trials finally from analysis of those
selection trials we select on the order
of 12 to 15 genotypes to advance into
Regional yield trials where it's
critical to evaluate genotype by
environment
interactions uh to look at uh their
response to varying Pest and disease
pressure on different sites their
response to different soil types and
climate conditions uh so overall that
phenotypic selection process uh takes us
to Regional yield trials within four to
seven years and our overall cycle of uh
identifying new cultivars runs on a
cycle of about 10 to 12
years so we uh went through that process
again using uh genotypes that rich cop
bred in
uh uh 1998
1999 uh got those into yield trials that
were planted from 2005 up through uh
2008 across New York State and through
collaboration uh across many parts of
North America all the way from uh
Montreal Quebec out to uh Wasa Minnesota
just south of
Minneapolis uh even in the Upper
Peninsula of Michigan so those are our
Target regions the
Northeast uh and Upper Midwest and
Southern parts of
Canada and you can see when we look at
the yield of the top five genotypes in
each of these trials and compare them
with the foundation breeding material
that we had in Syracuse originally and
yield trials that were managed by my
colleagues Tim vul and Larry
abrahamson those new cultivars from uh
first round of
breeding uh produced about a 30 to 35%
increase in yield
overall so uh that's our success in one
round of breeding through capturing
heterosis of species
hybrids among those cultivars that we
tested in those yield trials we have now
patented eight of them and uh those are
licensed uh by the Research Foundation
of Sunni to a very active and
collaborative uh Nursery producer many
of you uh know uh through his primary
business which is producing uh wine
grape cuting uh Dennis rack at doua
Willow so he now is the main source of
planting stock for commercial growers in
North America uh with production
capacity of about 30 million cuting per
year that's enough uh for 5 to 6,000
Acres of Willow each
year I just want to highlight again that
uh many of these cultivars are hybrids
between the diploid cix viminalis and
tetrol cix Mayana or between the diploid
cix peria and tetrol salx
Mayana
okay uh we have now continued to advance
our breeding program program and our
next round of genetic selection trials
was planted here in Geneva in 2008 again
with 75 genotypes we harvested that the
first time in
2011 and from those genotypes bred in
2002 and 2005 um and some in 2001 again
we have captured about a 15% increase in
yield compared to our current commercial
alvars so these are now uh have now been
Advanced to Regional yield trials to do
that same type of genotype by
environment interaction testing uh but
now we're getting into the yields of 17
dry metric tons per hectare per year
that are really going to have an impact
on the economics of the
system so I am uh very fortunate to be a
member of uh USDA funded project uh to
develop Willow and switchgrass as
bioenergy crops in the Northeast us it's
led by Penn State uh and our
contribution to this project which we
call new bio was to establish a new
round of uh Regional yield trials
through collaboration with Sunni ESF uh
daa Willow and fonia Folks at Penn State
Marvin Hall and John Carlson including a
site on Rec claim M land uh
collaboration with Steve defasio at West
Virginia University and with Ray Miller
up in esim ALA
Michigan so we expect that uh once we
have the results of this new round of
yield trial we will advance at least uh
a couple new cultivars uh to commercial
production now we recognize that our
potential to capture uh those yield
improvements
is getting smaller and smaller meaning
that we need to be more precise uh in
our selection methods and we have
recently moved to
planting uh to not relying so heavily on
unreplicated performance in these family
row trials in Nursery beds but rather
propagating all of the genotypes
that we produce in a family and testing
them now in replicated
trials as you can imagine these are
getting very large uh when you pick
almost 300 genotypes or here we have
genotypes uh replicated in four reps I
would love to do this on multiple sites
uh but even on one site uh this is a lot
of plots to go out and measure and
evaluate uh but that is what we have
done here in
2013 uh Fred Galer is my PhD student is
managing this trial and Craig Carlson uh
my third PhD student is managing this
trial both here in
Geneva okay so to summarize uh our
current strategy for breeding seix
hybrids uh is to capture heterosis
through species hybridization uh
especially to produce triploids
uh that our initial selections uh
produce some impressive yield gains but
uh in order to maintain those we will
need to get more precise and produce
larger families with better overall
Precision of
selection uh which we think we can gain
and also gain uh advantages of early
selection by developing genomic tools
and developing marker assisted
selection so really what we're talking
about is whether we can pick a needle
from a hay stack right whether we can
pick those particular genotypes out of
thousands that we can produce through
breeding uh that have all of the
traits uh and additive uh genes combined
in that one single Superior
genotype uh so I wish I could just look
at the pots on the greenhouse bench and
pick out that one needle out of the
hyack of
seedlings uh but again we can't do that
by eye we need to develop genomic tools
uh that can do that for
us so we are very fortunate uh to
collaborate with Folks At
Doe uh especially Jerry tuskin at oakd
National Lab uh and his uh relying on
his connections with the joint genome
Institute of doe uh who have invested
resources to sequence salx Pera as a
reference uh for
salx so we selected one of our female
clones again a central clone in our
breeding
program uh did entirely alumina
sequencing uh that was done at
jgi uh the assembly was done by high bow
Tang at the Craig Venter Institute in
Chris towns lab and we now have uh
released that First Assembly
uh in phytozome version 10 this is the
doe uh genomics
website so uh we're up to here if you're
uh a genome jockey we're up to uh
scaffolds with an l50 of 190 KB uh but
we still have about
9,300 scaffolds in our assembly so
basically what that means is using this
short read alumina technology
uh we have assembled The genome but
still it's in a large number of small
pieces uh are our ultimate aim is to
assemble all of those sequences into
chromosome scale
assemblies uh but that is going to take
some additional sequencing work which we
are
undertaking uh as we
speak what we have been able to do is to
take advantage of this great Tech
technology developed in Ed Buckler's lab
uh Ed is in the USDA uh down in itha uh
called genotyping by
sequencing this high resolution uh high
density marker system uh can be uh
developed without any prior genomic
sequence
knowledge uh it's very cheap per sample
so we can get uh thousands of markers
for only 35 per
sample and we were very lucky uh to get
in early on as uh Ed and Rob Elshire and
Sharon Mitchell down in nitha were
developing this technique uh to uh
develop GBS markers for uh seix peria
which has now helped us in developing a
genetic map and improving our overall
genome
assembly so what we did was to apply GBS
to an F2 family Fairly large 495 progyny
of seix
peria developed using our reference
genome 9 9406 as the original
grandmother uh so that we can develop we
uh produced uh in collaboration with
Steve defasio and Eli Rogers Melnick at
West Virginia University a
highresolution genetic map uh this
pedigree we could then take those GBS
markers and align them uh to our
scaffolds in the
assembly and using the powers of the
genetic mapping could then assemble our
scaffolds into chromosome scale
pseudomolecule uh level
molecules so we have
about uh 75 or 80% of the assembly now
uh aligned into these 19 pseudomolecules
equivalent to the 19 chromosomes of salx
what I'm showing here in this figure is
the alignment of the seix map to the
popular
genome and uh here is the alignment of
the salx uh sequence assembly scaffolds
aligned to the genetic
map so some things that we've learned
and we continue to uh analyze uh the
genome assembly is that there are some
major chromosome rearrangements between
salx and populace uh big one here is uh
between chromosome 1 and 16 there is a a
fusion uh between popler and
seix uh a major chunk of popler
chromosome 1 is fused with salx
chromosome 16 we also see some uh
important translocations and I'm I'm
going to uh uh tip my hand here and say
that we have been mapping the sex
determination Locus and actually that
sex determination Locus sits in a region
that is translo translocated from
popular chromosome 19 to salx chromosome
15 so we're we're learning some
important differences between popler and
Willow
uh having the genome assembly here
there's a lot more analysis that uh we
will be doing in the in the near
future at jgi they also sequen some of
the express genes uh so that we could
develop uh a highquality annotation of
all of the genes in the in the genome
doing uh RNA seek from uh eight
different tissue libraries made from
five different tissues here
uh basically what we see is that there
are slightly fewer genes expressed in
salx than there are in popler uh but
still we have a pretty good library or
or annotation of the uh 38,000 or so
genes expressed in
Willow okay the next step is to use that
genetic map those GBS
markers uh and the genome sequence to
develop uh mapping populations so that
we can relate phenotype to genotype so
that we can start to uh work towards
marker assistant
selection and we are using the
complimentary approaches of both qtl
mapping using biparental populations
with Association mapping using a diverse
collection of cix
Heria so we are now going back to that
same F2
family uh which has a pretty large
number of
progyny uh and Craig Carlson here has
planted that out in a replicated trial
here in Geneva so that we can start to
characterize traits of importance for
biomass production for Willow
biology and map them into this uh
highresolution uh biparental mapping
population we've done that on some of
the some of the simple traits already
since Willow is dous we have been able
to map uh the Locust controlling sex in
Willow as I mentioned before it maps to
a single spot on chromosome 15 and in
fact uh we see that salx peria and
perhaps all salx are using a ZW sex
determination system that means that the
female is the heter heterotic sex the
male is ZZ while at least populous troc
carpa uses an XY sex determination
system so again there are some
interesting contrasts there between poer
and
cix and in the overall evolution of
daishi uh and whether uh that XY and ZW
system can flipflop back and forth or at
what point in the Divergence between
popler and cix uh did it
flip-flop that's just one example of the
types of traits that we can map uh using
uh this powerful
system now Fred Galer has been working
to develop Association mapping or genome
a genomewide Association study or
gwas uh using the collection of salx
peria that we have assembled uh from
across the Northeast uh so we have uh
it's a relatively small Association
mapping population only 112
genotypes uh but we have planted that on
replicated trials here in Geneva out at
the uh clarel station in Portland and in
collaboration with Steve defasio down in
Morgantown West
Virginia we have fully genotyped that
collection with
GBS and uh for the last two years Fred
has been working on uh phenotyping those
populations with some of the key traits
again that we're interested in for
biomass production including as you can
imagine stem height stem diameters uh
stem numbers we're very interested in
Wood density we use highresolution
thermogravimetric uh analysis to
determine the composition of cellulose
hemicellulose ligant and Ash in the wood
and we've also been able to measure Leaf
area uh use a spad meter to measure Leaf
nitrogen and a parameter to measure
stodal conductance we've also developed
some techniques to look at overall Crown
form and and growth uh form also looking
at Pest and disease resistance which
aren't on these which which isn't on
this
list again some of the initial hits uh
that Fred has been able to map and he's
actively working on uh mapping all of
those traits right now uh again a simple
one is to look at sex
determination and the mapping in the
association
population matches that that we see in
the biparental qtl population pointing
to a single uh major Locus on chromosome
15 so that highlights how we can use
these two different mapping populations
to complement one another and to confirm
the hits that we're getting uh in both
types of
mapping some other hits that uh Fred has
come up with here we see a significant
hit for
uh variation in stem height so as we
look at these Manhattan plots each of
these different colors represents the 19
different chromosomes in salx and each
dot represents a uh a snip or a marker
on that chromosome uh as it gets higher
in this plot represents a higher level
of significance uh for the correlation
between variation in that trait and that
particular spot on the Gen or
snip so looking at uh hits for stem
height here uh he has some Snips that
are significant and map uh to this very
specific region of the genome which we
can map using uh I think this was done
with about 25,000 GBS markers uh mapping
those Snips between a glyco hydrolase
and a
cellulose uh which we now need to follow
up on and see uh how how they are
involved in regulating stem
height another hit for hemicellulose
Content Quantified by TGA here we see uh
significant Snips here in a sugar
nucleotide epimerase uh potentially
involved again in Sugar nucleotide
conversions during cell wall
biosynthesis but this gives us some
targets some canidate genes that we can
follow up on look at their patterns of
expression look at uh the variation in
alals in our association population uh
and to see how uh those different alals
uh are influencing uh the traits
involved okay so to summarize we have a
pretty good genome
assembly uh in place right now uh
produced through a good collaboration
with the joint genome Institute of doe
we continue to advance uh those genomic
resources we have developed both qtl and
Association mapping populations that can
complement each other uh the big issue
the big uh the most expensive part now
is phenotyping those
populations uh with thousands of plots
out in the field but we have great
potential for
identifying uh good candidates for
marker assisted
selection now the final part of my talk
is that I think that seix also
represents a unique system for the study
of
heterosis uh and that having these
genomic resources gives us uh the
potential to uh probe some of the
genomic basis for heterosis in this
highly
heterozygous uh species which has
undergone no domestication up up to this
point and also uh displays heterosis in
uh across Ploy
levels or in
triploids okay so I'm going to take you
back to this 2008 selection trial uh
which has 75 genotypes and if we look at
the yield the mean yield of those 75
genotypes in that trial and look at the
pyy uh the vast majority of the upper
50th percentile of genotypes in that
trial were triploid
and the overall yield of the triploids
was significantly and dramatically
greater than the yield of the diploids
in that
trial uh the yield of the tetrols is not
significantly different uh but when we
look at some of the other traits like
stem number or uh aspects of biomass
composition we do see significant
differences between the triploids and
the
tetrols the bottom line here again is
that uh we are seeing uh
dramatically better performance in
triploids compared to
diploids so we want to ask uh what is
the genomic basis for that heterosis
that we're capturing so just to uh sort
of Define uh what we mean by heterosis
the classic example is in maiz where if
you cross uh one inbred line with
another inbred line you see that the
progyny display either midparent
heterosis meaning that their mean
performance is better than the average
performance of the two parents or you
may see better parent heterosis meaning
that the progyny are better than even
the best uh the better of the two
parents right uh and there are some
classic uh models to
explain uh how that heterosis is
occurring
whether it's occurring through a
dominance
model uh or through an overdominance
model uh the dominance model meaning
that uh there are complementary additive
alals which come together in the hybrid
to make that hybrid even better than its
parents or uh in the in the other model
uh the overdominance model where the
presence of a uh
heterozygote even at a single Gene can
confer Superior performance to that
hybrid over its two parents the main
difference being that in the ma example
those are inbreds highly homozygous
inbred lines that have been breed for
decades here we're seeing heterosis when
we cross two wild
accessions uh that are highly
heterozygous
and when we cross a diploid with a
tetrol to get a triploid
right so the approach that we're taking
is to look at the patterns of gene
expression in the triploid progyny and
to what extent is the inheritance of
gene expression in the hybrid progyny
non-additive meaning different from the
midparent
average can we identify a Le specific
expression inherited from one or the
other parent
and the obvious question would be is
there a dosage effect uh in those
triploid progyny that are getting two
copies from the tetrol parent and one
copy from the diploid
parent
finally uh are those differentially
expressed genes responsible for
heterosis so can we correlate the
patterns of gene expression that we see
with uh phenotype in the field or in the
greenhouse
so as we look at quantifying patterns of
gene expression uh this is a scheme that
we use uh first of all sort of the
default is when uh gene expression
equals in I'm sorry in parent
one uh is equivalent to that in parent
two here parent one will always be the
maternal parent so when there's no
differential expression and the progyny
gene expression is at that same level we
classify that as
additive that's not so interesting to us
the more interesting case is when there
is differential gene expression between
the two parents here the mother has
higher expression than the father here
the mother has lower expression than the
father if the progyny expression hits
the midpoint between the parental levels
of expression again we would call that
additive if the progen any expression is
equivalent to the high parent or the low
parent then that's an example of
dominance or if it is below the low
parent or above the high parent again
that is a non-additive pattern of
expression an example of underdominance
or
overdominance so in the cases where we
see differential expression between our
two parents we will classify the
expression in the progyny according to
the these five
categories
okay in order to to
test uh to look at uh differential
patterns of expression we've developed
these eight
families uh first of all an F1 family of
cix peria that same F2 family of salx
peria that I've talked about and then
reciprocal crosses between peria and
viminalis here peria as the mother or
Vialis as the
mother and then triploid families
representing crosses between peria
Mayana or between viminalis in
Mayana and we have planted uh uh
typically a 100 progeny from each of
these families in the field and uh the
experiment that I'm going to describe to
you was done by selecting 10 random
progyny from uh six of these eight
families uh growing those in the
greenhouse and then we extracted RNA to
use for RNA
seek
okay uh we extracted tissue from uh
extracted RNA from two different tissues
either from Cho tips or from stem
internodes and uh map those reads back
to our uh genome assembly did statistics
to look for differential patterns of
expression and we will will continue on
unfortunately I don't have time to talk
about this today but uh use some
additional techniques to look at a
specific
expression okay just to quickly go
through uh some of the main conclusions
the first one being that triploids
Express more genes than
diploids so when we look at the total
counts of genes that are expressed in
the triploid
progyny uh we see that there are
thousands of
genes uh Express thousands of additional
genes expressed in the triploids than in
the
diploids so that may be one clue right
there interestingly the overall levels
of expression tend to be lower in the
progyny than they are in the
parents now when we cluster the patterns
of gene
expression uh between progyny and and
the midparent values here the first
level of clustering that we
see is distinguishing
progyny from those midparent
values so the greatest level of
difference in
expression is between progyny and
parents the next level of CR clustering
is at the level of
tissue and Fin finally sort of the
bottom level of clustering is at the
level of
species so it's interesting that uh the
greatest difference in the gene
expression patterns that we're seeing
are differences between progyny and
parents even greater than differences
between
species to put that another way uh we
see greater differential gene expression
between the mid parent and the progyny
then we see between the two
parents uh which are different species
right so here when we compare uh one
parent to another male to female you see
that most of the dots are fairly close
to the one to one line but when we
compare progyny to M parent now we have
a much broader sorry much broader
scattering of uh spots representing
greater differential gene expression
between progyny and
parent okay the next thing was to
quantify among those genes which are uh
differentially expressed between the two
parents okay so statistically which
genes for which parent one is not equal
to parent two and as you can see here
the triploids and the interspecific
diploids have far more genes showing uh
differential expression between the two
parents than our seix peria
families so of about 35,000 genes here
as many as 7,000 genes are
differentially expressed between the two
parents okay so now for those
differentially expressed genes and and
they're more in the Cho tip than there
are in the
internode for those differentially
expressed genes we fit them into those
five categories
are they maternally dominant paternally
dominant overdominant or underdominant
or are they in that sort of default
additive case where they hit the
midparent mean and the interesting thing
here is that those genes that show
additive expression are very very
few in fact the vast majority are
showing highly maternal dominant
patterns of
expression so again that may be a clue
to uh the heterosis that we're seeing in
species hybrids in salx we see more in
choot tip than we do in
internode finally uh what we want to go
on to look at is uh can we actually look
at the AL coming from the mother and the
expression of the mother's alil compared
to the father's alil we needed to ident
identify Snips or sequence differences
between uh those two parents so we have
now resequenced all of our parents in
this experiment and you see we see quite
a few differences Snips that we can rely
on uh to give us as many as
18,000 uh Snips uh so we can start to
sort out uh a Le specific patterns of
expression between mother and
father okay so so to summarize this
final uh experiment that I described
there is greater differential gene
expression in
triploids uh than in our our salx peria
diploids that the gene expression levels
in the progyny show a strong pattern of
maternal parent dominance which is very
interesting The Next Step that we need
to move on to is to start to phenotype
individuals in the field and in the
greenhouse
uh and correlate the patterns of gene
expression and perhaps expression of
individual genes that are differentially
expressed with the heterotic phenotypes
that we can quantify in the greenhouse
or in the
field so uh that's all I have time to
talk about today I want
to uh express my sincere thanks for all
the folks who have worked in my lab over
the years my three current uh PhD
students Fred Eric and Craig and Kurt uh
my technician uh Michelle cilia who was
my graduate student and and then postto
here in Geneva uh who did a lot of work
to develop our methods of analysis of
wood composition and my collaborators
Jerry tusin at Oak Ridge Steve defasio
at West Virginia Chris town at Craig
ventor Institute I mentioned my
collaborators at Michigan State Penn
State uh and Sunni ESF as well as all of
the crews that we've had here working
with us in the summer primarily here in
Geneva so I will stop there thank you
for your attention and I'd be happy to
answer any questions including those
from itha if you unmute your microphone
so
[Applause]
thanks jaro quick question do you think
the uh uh
cor the differential expression that you
see in the
mother genome is is related to uh the
connection with the plased uh plased
genomes uh that are inherited and
therefore foro syesis and everything
else all the other Machinery you think
that is reasonable that they communicate
better uh because they they' evolve
together yeah so just to uh repeat Jar's
question the question is whether the
strong maternal dominance of expression
that we're seeing may be due to the
influence of the chloroplast genome
which is inherited from the mother I
think that's an excellent hypothesis
that we can test and and Craig I know is
very interested in testing that
hypothesis and has looked at the
expression of chloroplast genes also in
our RNA SE data the other question is
whether there is some epigenetic
imprinting involved in uh
this maternal dominant expression and
the maternal dominance let me
reemphasize does not matter which
species right so whether salx viminalis
is the mother or cix Pera is the mother
it is maternal dominant it is not
species
specific
Larry you know in some species like
potato when you make a cross between the
Teto and the diploid you get a pretty
high frequen of tets due to um unreduced
or diploid gamins so I'm wondering um I
hope your your triploids what you've
done to confirm that they're triploids
and I'm wondering whether diploid gamuts
occur among cellic
species uh yeah so Bruce's question is
how how detailed have we gotten to
confirm that their triploids uh at this
point we've only done flow citometry
we''ve done repeated flow citometry uh
because that technique can be a little
inconsistent from run to
run uh we have not ruled out that there
could be different levels of
anlo uh I think we could go back and uh
look specifically through our GBS data
to look
for uh GBS markers that might indicate
anupy of a particular chromosome
uh
so uh yes we do see unreduced gametes
and salic because sometimes we are able
to get progyny from our
triploids so that's probably the best
evidence that I can give you
that there is some shaky control of
chromosome number in G
production uh uh no you sure that
there's some native poly uh Teto and
hexaploid I just wondering are those Alo
or or this Auto polypoid and uh if it's
Auto again that will be question related
to what Bruce just mentioned earlier the
gam and reduction you know uh how uh
that may complicate the the breeding
system yeah I I don't know how detailed
anyone has characterized so the question
is whether they the polyploids are Alo
or
Auto I'm not aware whether anyone has
done any detailed descriptions of those
but I would assume that they are Auto
polys Thomas and then maybe we should go
to IA okay so I'll ask the production so
you said that having several genotypes
in a field is is superior to a single
one um but it strikes me if you say your
had three genotypes in a field and one
of them got wiped out now you're in a
field with only 2third of a crop which
can't possibly be economical isn't it
better to just wipe out the whole thing
and start over if you
get a one of your genot types with a
fatal
flaw okay
so so if you have picked the one best
yielding cultivar and have planted all
of your Fields with that one and it gets
wiped out then you have no Yi right if
you have planted three and you planted
them in blocks or maybe this field in
one this field in another then yet your
one field is wiped out you can replant
it or that one block is wiped out you
can replant it uh the standard in
Ireland now and and in England I think
is to plant in random mixtures and over
time the superior genotypes went out the
rust susceptible genotypes diminish and
you end up with a lower number of plants
per acre but what we found is that that
does not severely in overall how much
percent plant loss can you handle have
comp uh I think you can go down probably
30% in Stand density and still realize
comparable
any questions from
itha uh yes you
indicated that there are going to be
seven Harvest commercially so the first
question is is any fertilizer put on
that at all because you're removing a
lot of nutrients from the
soil and as a coroller of that it would
seem to me that over the long term the
plant's ability to take up nutrients
would be a considerable factor in the
total yield but you never mentioned that
at least I don't think so so I'd like to
know whether there's any plans to look
at your uh preny for the ability to take
up
nutrients yeah thank you Peter that's an
excellent question and it's one of the
aspects of our research that I had to
drop out from this seminar but is the
main topic of Eric Fabio's
research uh so he has done uh fertilizer
trials using some of our current
commercial cultivars in the
greenhouse uh has been looking at the
impact of
nutrients uh nutrient management by
cover crops on uh early establishment of
willows in the field and again has been
analyzing yields from across now 24
different trials to correlate uh soil
nutrient levels with uh yield and growth
parameters there are conflicting data in
the literature some papers which say uh
there's very little influence of
fertilizer I believe that uh there is an
influence of fertilizer especially in
the early Harvest
Cycles but that it seems fairly likely
that after a certain amount of time uh a
a cycling of nutrients will be
established in Willow plantations so
that long-term fertilizer application
may not be
necessary any other okay I think that's
all the questions we have here okay uh
thank you one more Willows Mich RIS uh
so uh Jay is asking if Willows are
Michael risal and yes they are and uh
they're rather promiscuous they can form
associations with uh multiple different
tax of mizing that's a very interesting
question and again ties in with the need
for
fertilizer uh but it's one that needs a
lot more attention
okay one more what type of uh marker you
are using for F2 population like whether
you are using all kind of marker like
inter
cross cross and home have yeah so we
have used both pseudo test
cross uh male parent back cross markers
and female parent back cross markers as
well as intercross
markers uh I think in initial analysis
we had about 8,300 markers and I think
about 3,300 of them were intercross
markers and something like
202,000 or 2200 were were pseudo test
crossers
yeah okay thanks very
much this has been a production of
Cornell University
on the web at cornell.edu