this is a production of Cornell
University well good afternoon everyone
and we're going to get started this
afternoon even though I know that there
will be people coming on in there's so
many incredible wonderful and competing
U events that are happening over this
wonderful reunion weekend uh that I know
people will be will be coming in
throughout our presentation this
afternoon so that's great I'm Katherine
bour I am the Ronald P Lynch dean of the
College of Agriculture and Life Sciences
here at Cornell University and welcome
home to those of you who have traveled
to be with us this reunion weekend we're
very grateful that you're here and we
hope that you have a weekend that you
will remember long into the
future and I especially thank you for
joining us here today for the our panel
presentation that is entitled genomics
and the future of Agriculture and I'd
like to start this afternoon by giving
you a little bit of background on the
Liberty hide Bailey lecture series and
and that is the Liberty hiy Bailey
lecture series that we are celebrating
this afternoon this is an annual feature
of our reunion events here in the
college and this featur
this event features distinguished
faculty who are working in key priority
areas for the college in previous years
topics have included for example why
Social Media Matters and we also have
taken a look at the debate on the role
of GMOs in feeding our growing Global
populations it is my hope today that
this Liberty hiy Bailey lecture will
both deepen your understanding of
genomics and help you see the future of
Agriculture and further we hope that
this lecture today will help demonstrate
the impact that the College of
Agriculture and Life Sciences has had
and will continue to have as we look
toward addressing complex Global issues
it's particularly fitting that the name
of this lecture is Liberty Hyde Bailey
and Liberty Hyde Bailey was the very
first dean of the College of agriculture
at Cornell University and I think you're
all aware that the iconic Bailey Hall
right across the street here is named
after our first Dean now Bailey had many
roles throughout his lifetime he was a
botanist a horticulturalist he was a
plant breeder certainly a teacher a very
successful administrator he was a
lobbyist a very very prolific writer he
was an editor he was a poet he was a
rural sociologist he was a philosopher
he was a traveler and certainly he was
an
environmentalist it is not in any way an
understatement to say that he
single-handedly helped to create the
science of horiculture his tireless
lobbying of the New York State
Legislature led to the establishment in
1904 of the New York State College of
Agriculture right here at Cornell
Bailey was an early Visionary in terms
of seeing agriculture as an academic
discipline and to him the fundamental
purpose of Education was to serve the
people and he believed that the
resolution of agricultural problems were
every bit as important as resolving
other cultural ethical and legal issues
and hence his bringing agriculture to
the four as an academic discipline he
led a remarkable life and a remarkable
career and his influence not only here
at Cornell University continues to
resonate to this day now just like
Liberty Hyde Bailey today's panelists
are pioneers in their fields not only
are they conducting groundbreaking
research they're also helping to fulfill
the College of Agriculture and life
science's mission of providing knowledge
with public purpose to the people of the
state of New York to the nation and
around the world today's speakers Susan
makuch Greg Martin and Jim giovanoni are
not only Pioneers in their field they
are all former alumni of Liberty Hyde
Bailey Professor Amer Steve tanksley's
lab Steve tanksley is a giant in the
field of plant breeding engine genetics
and we are so honored that Steve is here
today and Steve if you stand up that
would really be appreciated so Steve
timson Steve's work in molecular
genetics revolutionized modern plant
breeding by creating the first
chromosomal maps of plants and by
pioneering genetic techniques that are
absolutely essential to development of
new crops his research paved the way for
improvements in size nutritional value
and disease resistance of major food
crops his work also helped to lay the
foundation for the Breakthrough
technology that is known as marker
assisted selection which is critically
important tool for plant breeding Steve
did his undergraduate work in Agronomy
at Colorado State University and he
earned his PhD from the University of
California Davis where he worked on
rudiment M AR genetic maps for plants he
came to Cornell in
1985 as an associate professor in what
was then the department of plant
breeding and biometry over the ensuing
decade he and his team developed tools
that allowed for complete mapping of the
Tomato genome and in
1997 he spearheaded the Cornell genomics
initiative which coordinated way more
than 50 faculty members from more than
20 departments across the entire
University to help helped develop
synergies that were based on the
University strengths in the Life
Sciences Steve was elected to the
National Academy of Sciences in
1995 and the Royal Society of London in
2009 and he was appointed the Einstein
professor of the Chinese Academy of
Sciences in 2006 Steve retired from
Cornell in 2010 to work at nature Source
genetics which is which is an Ithaca
bioinformatics company that he founded
in 2006 in addition to all of the other
achievements that I've already mentioned
Steve won the Alexander Von humble
Foundation Award the Martin Gibbs medal
of the American Society of plant
physiology Israel's wolf Foundation
prize in agriculture the rank prize and
the Kumho award in plant molecular
biology and technology and this year he
was awarded the Japan prize which honors
scientists and this is in quotes whose
original and outstanding achievements
are not only scientifically impressive
but have also served to promote peace
and prosperity For All Mankind Steve was
one of two honores that were honored
this year Steve not only had the vision
to transform the whole field of plant
breeding his legacy also includes
mentoring the next generation of
groundbreaking plant scientists here at
Cornell and build the university into a
world leader in genomics and and here's
something that you may not know right
now by us and news and World Report
Cornell University is ranked number one
in the world in plant sciences and to a
very large extent that is the legacy of
Steve tanksley and his team so that's an
incredible accomplishment for Cornell
University and thank you for that so now
building on Steve tanksley's Legacy here
at Cornell I'd now like to introduce
today's panelists and they'll come up
one by one to give their presentations
and then when they're finished with the
presentations uh we'll all be seated
here uh at the front uh but for now I'll
talk a little bit about each panelist
and then I'll invite Susan up to to give
the first presentation so I'll start
with Susan and Professor Susan makuch is
one of the world's foremost experts on
rice and rice breeding she received her
ba from Smith college her Ms from the
University of Massachusetts and her PhD
from Cornell in 1990 during which time
she worked in Steve's lab she spent 5
years with the international rice
Research Institute in the Philippines
before joining our faculty here at
Cornell in
1995 Susan's Research into the genomic
variations of different varieties of
rice has led to the development of new
rice strains that are more Pest and
drought resistant and that provide
higher yields for farmers and very
importantly Susan's work has created a
more stable Global Supply of this
essential food source our next speaker
will be Greg Martin and Greg is a
professor of Plant Pathology and plant
microbiology and he is an expert on
tomato disease resistance since 2005 he
has been the Boyce schultzy Downey
professor at the Boyce Thompson
Institute for plant science here at
Cornell Greg received his BS his Ms and
PhD from Michigan State University and
he was a National Science Foundation
postdoctoral fellow at Cornell from 1989
to
1992 and it was as postto that Greg
worked in Steve tanksley's
laboratory Ste uh Greg's research
focuses on the mechanisms that bacteria
use to infect plants and in turn the
mechanisms that plants have evolved to
interfere with the bacterial
pathogen our third speaker this
afternoon is Jim giovanoni and he is an
Adjunct professor of plant biology in
the school of Integrative plant science
he's a research scientist for the US
Department of Agriculture agricultural
research service and he's a professor at
the Boyce Thompson Institute Jim earned
his PhD in molecular and physiological
plant biology at the University of
California Berkeley in 1990 and that was
followed by two years as post-doctoral
researcher
in Steve's lab so you see how this all
connects Jim was recently elected to the
National Academy of Sciences and let's
give Jim a round of applause for that
incredible
apption Jim's research focus is on the
molecular and genetic analysis of fruit
ripening and the cons and the
consequences of those um effects on
ripening on nutritional quality so now
I'm going to turn the podium over to
Susan makuch and Susan if you would join
me up here
please so it's a pleasure to be here and
uh this is of course honoring Steve it's
a rare opportunity that we get actually
to tell somebody who has influenced our
lives so deeply how much we appreciate
what they pass on and I think we all
know the importance of a professor so it
also resonates back to each of us as
professors uh hoping to influence
another generation of students
so this is the Steve tanksley I knew in
1986 when I joined his lab we were in
418 Bradfield Hall the department of
plant breeding and
biometry Steve arrived at Cornell with
big visions of what molecular genetics
could do for plant breeding for
agriculture and for Global Food security
and in 1986 the world faced many of the
same Grand global challenges that we
face today although I think the
understanding of what global climate
change would represent had not yet
become embedded in our minds in any case
Steve was bringing new tools and a new
vision to the Department of plant
breeding and biometry and molecular
markers would revolutionize the field of
plant
breeding and of molecular genetics
particularly interesting to me was that
it had immediate application in the
opportunity to translate the discoveries
that were being made in some of the
basic Sciences into important products
in agriculture medicine and
environmental science and to me this was
music to my
ears I had a background in history and
literature I was coming from a liberal
arts background I had lived and worked
extensively in the developing world and
during my first few weeks in the
tanksley lab I quickly realized that I
was going to have to learn an entire
enely new language it was one of the
most exciting periods of my
life I joined the team working to create
the first molecular map of rice and with
funding from the Rockefeller
foundation's program on International
rice
biotechnology I joined two colleagues
jenang Wang and XI Hong Yu who were
recent um recently emerged from the
cultural revolution in China this was
among the first wave of scientists to
come out of China and we were very uh
excited to have them in the lab working
on this the development of the rice map
it consisted of
135 rfl rflp markers and it was
published in theoretical and applied
genetics in
1988 when I finished my PhD in Steve's
lab in
1990 I took a position as a rice breeder
at the international rice Research
Institute in the Philippines and and I
worked there for 5 years during that
time we established the first molecular
marker lab which was called The genome
mapping lab and it was the foundation
for the application of genomics in
breeding at the time which was all
devoted to the concept of marker
assisted selection the lab remains
productive to this day and during the
time I was there one of the more
exciting aspects of being in the
Philippines other than the fact that I
had the rice patties right outside my
window was the fact that we had the Jean
bank right on campus and part of the
opportunity was to start to mine that
Gene bank for natural variation that we
could use in breeding and many of the
genes that are actually present in
ancient land races and wild species that
are housed in the irie Gene Bank have
now been deployed through the use of
this technology marker assisted
selection not GM technology but actually
through back Crossing have been deployed
to confer heightened levels of disease
and insect resistance drought tolerance
submergence tolerance and many other
traits and those varieties are now
planted on hundreds of thousands of
hectares across Asia Africa and Latin
America other students in the tanksley
lab built on the work that we had done
in rice using the rice genome as an
anchor to start to map other related
genomes that were larger and more
complex the first comparative map was
the rice maze map and as you can see in
this uh diagram here we have a rice
chromosome in the middle and we have two
corresponding uh comparative segments
that were conserved in Ma and the
interesting thing about this is that
rice is a very small genome and it was a
fairly conservative and fairly uh stable
genome so it provided a very robust
framework for this comparative mapping
to assemble these much more complex
genomes and it demonstrated that these
related cereals they went on to develop
maps of rice wheat and Maze and
eventually many other comparative Maps
but these three related cereals which
are the foundation of the world's food
supply were mosaics of their last common
ancestor and they all shared large
segments of chromosomes that were still
recognizable after 3 million years of
evolution despite being rearranged and
reorganized in modern crop genomes for
those of you who are familiar with this
it's not surprising today but at the
time it was really a very profound uh
strategic concept that started to in
inundate the field of molecular biology
and molecular genetics and these
comparative Maps had enormous
implications for application in both
Agriculture and
medicine because of its small size the
rice genome was the the also the first
crop to be fully sequenced and it
provided a scaffold that allowed us to
more easily assemble the more complex uh
Maze and wheat
genomes now maze is six times larger
than rice it's about the size of the
human genome and it was a slow and
difficult process to assemble the genome
sequence of maze but even more difficult
was was wheat hexaploid wheat is 30
times the size of the maze genome and it
was only just recently completed in
2014 in any case the comparative Maps
laid the foundation for this major
accomplishment in the field of the plant
sciences and I might say also paved the
way for my return from Erie to join the
Cornell faculty in
1995 because it if it had not been that
Rice was the foundation for the more
important crops in the West nobody would
have thought of investing a faculty
position in a person who would devote
their life to
rice in any case with so much attention
focused on genotyping and sequencing of
genomes people sometimes seem to forget
the reason for doing it and the
creativity and effort that would be
needed to translate that sequence into
products that would ultimately impact
the human Li human Liv lives around the
world now I returned to uh joined the
faculty in 1995 and by
1995 things were starting to get
underway at Cornell many people were
involved in aspects of genomics but
everyone did it in their own lab B
buying their own Machines working
independently and ofing often having to
learn very difficult lessons each one on
their own and there was no forum for
sharing information and Technology
across the campus the way there is
today and Steve at that time had started
to think about what the implications of
the discoveries in the basic Sciences
meant for institutions and institutional
organizations and I'm going to quote to
you some actually I took this off of an
overhead slide and I thought of coming
in and putting up the overhead projector
so that you could actually see I still
have this this these slides in my in my
uh vast repertoire of old pap papers and
this is some of the these were some of
the insights that Steve uh shared with
many of us at that time the DNA sequence
will soon be known for most major life
forms not just for the major species but
for most major life forms and biology
will move from being an information
limited science to a science that is
limited only by our ability to organize
and analyze information and today we
live in the era of big data and digital
information and we all know what a
burden it is to have an overload of
information biological research will
shift from a reductionist to a synthesis
approach in fact it has dramatically
shifted from dissecting complex genomes
to predicting and synthesizing future
outcomes more basic discoveries will
emerge from biology in the next 30 Years
than from any other single discipline
well I joined Steve's lab in
1986 and here we are 30 years later I
would say we've had a pretty good
ride and Steve's one of the most lasting
contributions that Steve made to the
Cornell research Community was his
unswerving support and Leadership of the
Cornell genomics initiative under this
initiative we would initiate a new
campus-wide hiring strategy that allowed
candidates for faculty positions to
interview with prominent scientist s in
genomic related fields all across campus
we would form a set of core facilities
that provides the entire Cornell
community and survives to this day with
access to the latest in genomic
Technologies at a cost that was finally
manageable for Cornell researchers due
to the economy of scale that came from
uniting the campus and departmental and
college boundaries would be lowered as
faculty staff and student students
started to get to know each other
through their shared research interests
and the kind of uh consolidation and
interactions that I think Katherine
mentioned cut across many many different
colleges many different departments and
has affected the lives of many people
who were either at Cornell who or who
were recruited to Cornell under the
genomics
initiative when somebody says to you
well you know what you did for your PhD
that took you four years and was 135
markers on a map is going to be done in
10 minutes a few years later you kind of
look back at your thesis and you think
wow those were a lot of late nights in
the lab manually running gels and
waiting for things and turning them
around and all I can say is that it was
hard to imagine what somebody at that
time could have foreseen when we talked
about being in data Rich environment but
indeed I just want to end by saying that
currently the largest project in my
portfolio is called the Gobi project the
genomics and open- Source breeding
informatics initiative this is a project
funded by The Bill and Melinda Gates
Foundation there are four piis principal
investigators from plant breeding and
genetics alone one from bti and one from
computer science
department it is the objectives of this
Pro of this project are to program the
software that that is needed to
facilitate the use of big data in
breeding and the goal is to assist
breeders in the public sector working to
accelerate the rate of genetic gain for
staple food crops in the developing
world so you can see how this thread has
actually permeated my entire career here
and I just want to close by saying that
the Gobi project encompasses three
different International crop Improvement
centers simmit in Mexico rasat in irie
and rasat in India and irie in the
Philippines there are three institutions
right here in Ithaca all of whom have
pis on the table the USDA the Cornell uh
Cornell and that's cows n bti and we are
addressing simultaneously five of the
world's most important crop species rice
ma wheat sorghum and chickpea and this
is in fact I think a consolidation of
the vision that Steve expressed so many
years ago just to show you that Cornell
Still Remains I think a leader in the
field and I am very impressed Katherine
by your news today uh that the plant
Sciences is ranking so highly I must say
I'm not surprised but I think it's
important for us all to recognize the
Excellence that is housed here at
Cornell and with that I'll close by
saying I think I've done my part to
contribute to the Next Generation as
well so thank you very much
[Applause]
well thank you very much Susan and next
we will hear from Greg Martin so
Greg well I'd like to begin just uh
simply by thanking Steve for his
mentorship and for really his friendship
over many long period of time now so I
was actually also a beneficiary of the
Cornell genomics initiative because it
provided me an opportunity to return to
Cornell I first uh joined Steve's lab as
Katherine mentioned in
1989 which is hard to imagine that that
was actually 27 years ago and then uh
and then of course was then able to come
back in in 1998 I guess is what it was
so it's interesting for me reflecting
back in that period of time back in the
late 1980s and the early 1990s was it
turned out to Encompass a really
interesting intersection between two
important developments in in my field in
Plant Pathology and that is it was the
uh first development of new experimental
systems genetic systems that allowed the
genetic characterization of how plants
respond to pathogens and then of course
the second important development were
the methods of using DNA markers that
was spearheaded in Steve's lab and those
two different developments again
intersected and allowed then the
identifications of genes from plants
that confer disease resistance and that
uh ended up being the basis of my career
so what I want to do today is to give
you an overview a very kind of uh broad
overview of what we've learned in the
past 25 years about plant disease
resistance and then I'll touch a little
bit about how on about how we can use
this knowledge to to make better plants
to make plants more disease
resistant so if anyone is a home
Gardener you'll know that plant
succumb to all sorts of different
diseases they attack uh let's see stems
fruits leaves and not shown on this
slide but also Roots um they of course
have a huge impact they can have a huge
impact on yield but also on quality and
if you're a large farmer that affects
the marketability of the crop if you
like this kind of thing and I do they're
also really interesting to study
diseases because you can learn a lot
about about how the pathogens actually
cause symptoms how they were able to
suppress defense responses in the plant
so aside from the the fact that it's
just a lot of interesting biology and
it's kept my lab occupied for about 25
years of course plants also uh sorry
diseases also have a major impact on on
Plants so it's kind of hard for me to
see this up here but 10% of food
production it's estimated is lost due to
diseases um they it's to control
diseases and cost a lot of money and of
course involved the application of a lot
of
pesticides there have been a
introduction of important diseases into
the United States that have had a big
impact on all of us the the American
chestnut tree was lost to an exotic
pathogen that came in and of course
we're now currently dealing with Citrus
Greening which is shown here and then
the problem and it's just like the
problem with the super bugs that are in
the news recently is that plant
pathogens also evolve very quickly and
they develop resistance to uh different
pesticides that are currently being
used so the good news is that plants
actually have a very effective immune
system and in some ways it's analogous
to the human immune system and it's
important that some plants actually have
a natural of disease resistance in the
form of certain genes that allow them to
resist infection so this is a just a
simple picture that makes the point that
in this case both of these plants were
inoculated with the same bacterial
pathogen but you can see that one plant
appears to be uh completely resistant to
the disease it really doesn't show any
symptoms whereas the other one has
really succumbed to this disease so this
is an important point is that plants
naturally have these genes that confer
resistance so where do they come from
many of them have actually come from
Wild relatives of tomato and these were
collected back in the late 19 50s and
early 1960s by Dr Charles Rick who was
at the UC at University of California
Davis and was Steve's PhD adviser so
seeds of these uh different wild
relatives were collected and are
available now for us to analyze and
that's the sort of work that we've been
doing over the last 10 or 15 years is
screening these to identify new uh
disease resistance jeans that could then
be uh introduced into tomato varieties
so how do we do this it's a little bit
complicated and I'm not going to go into
all the details but the main point is is
that we're able to take advantage of
both sort of classical genetics and
classical Plant Pathology as well as a
lot of the more contemporary genomics
Technologies in order to very precisely
map a gene on a particular chromosome
get down to a very fine level and be
able to pick out the individual Gene
among the 35,000 or so genes that are in
tomato the individual Gene that's
important that is that's actually
conferring this disease resistance so as
Susan alluded to already this sort of
technology has really expedited things
25 years ago when I cloned a resistance
Gene when I was a postto in Steve's lab
it took four years and many many people
working on it uh we recently cloned a
gene and it took four months so that's
the sort of progress in the field we're
able to identify these genes much faster
and of course that will benefit the
plant breeding in the
future so what do these resistance genes
do uh I just sort of describe this in a
very simple way we now know that
resistance genes produce proteins and
these proteins allow the plant to detect
the pathogen so pathogens produce
certain proteins in their process of of
infecting the plant is in the process of
causing disease and these proteins that
resistance genes make we refer to as
receptors they can act either inside
inside the cell or outside the cell once
they detect a pathogen protein it
activates uh the immune response in the
plant and lead to disease
resistance so this is really kind of the
basic thing that we've learned in the
past 25 years but you can imagine with
so many people studying it in lots of
different Labs we actually know a little
bit more than what I'm showing and
that's Illustrated in this slide and
sort of again actually a rather
simplistic view of of what we actually
do know about the immune system we know
a lot of different components that act
both in recognizing the pathogen and in
the plant response how it actually uh
resists infection Downstream and so each
one of these different sort of items on
this slide represents a different
potential Target that plant breeders can
use to then uh introduce into new tomato
varieties and that's exactly what
they're doing using the sort of genomics
technology that was pioneered in Steve's
lab back in the in the late 1980s uh
plant breeders in this case tomato
breeders are using genomics Technologies
in particular DNA markers to be able to
very rapidly breed uh more disease
resistant
tomatoes so with that I'm just going to
end with this sort of a simple summary
slide to tell you that uh plants uh
sorry that diseases of course do have a
huge impact both in agricultural
settings but also uh to the impact the
economic impact on the farmer there's
been a lot of progress in understanding
exactly how the plant uh immune system
works and that's due to many different
labs and we've been fortunate to have
really an excellent level of federal
funding at least in the past 20 years or
so not as as much currently and that's
allowed a lot of progress in this field
and then as I mentioned the genomics
Technologies allow both the detailed
study of the immune system but they also
facilitate the breeding of of more
disease resistant plants
so I'll end with that thank you very
[Applause]
much well thank you very much Greg that
was great and now we'll hear from Jim
janon so
Jim okay well thank you very much first
I'd like to again thank Steve um you
really changed my life uh and in a a
very positive way so some people have
changed other ways but you had a great
impact um and I'd also like to thank you
and Susan and Greg because I never get
to talk to so many people so it's a it's
nice to have a big crowd
also um so I'm going to uh I guess tell
you a little story about some of our um
work some of the implications of our
work in Fruit development and fruit
biology but before that to really just
emphasize that it all started uh with
coming here to Cornell for a postto and
coming to Steve's lab um at the time as
Susan and Greg mentioned the technology
marker technology was being developed
and applied to both the utility and
genetic selection for breeding purposes
but also
towards understanding and identifying
genes so it's being used both for
practical and for basic biological
purposes and at the times the first
targets that Steve was approaching and
that Greg implemented was the cloning of
of the first disease resistance Gene uh
from a plant and but before that Jee had
been cloned I had met Steve and said
look I'm interested in fruit and these
funny ripening mutants and Steve said
yeah maybe there's something about those
disease genes that's not going to work
out so why don't you come and work on on
the fruit jeans just in case um because
the fact is disease resistance is much
more important you never get a fruit if
the plant is sick um so that's why I
ended up here um and uh and it was a
very good thing
okay so thinking about fruit um you know
we all know that in meeting our needs
for food security having enough to eat
in our state in our country in the world
we often think about yield but there's
another part of that equation and and
Greg alluded to it and that's how much
we can keep how much we can actually get
to the table so shelf life storability
these are all important seeds are
designed through Evolution to last right
they'll overwinter they'll make it to
the next year but the plant organs are
not necessarily so designed and so fruit
and vegetable tissues tissues of the
plant that we consume often have much
more of a problem in terms of
storability in terms of Decay and the
fruit in particular I is a is an
interesting organ because it's one
that's designed through Evolution to be
eaten so you think about um the fact
that uh most of what a plant is doing as
Greg just mentioned is defending itself
and suddenly in this stage of
development an organ is going just the
opposite saying come here and get me
consume me and to do so so as to release
the seeds because the fleshy fruit has
really evolved as a means of releasing
seeds uh for the Next
Generation but that process that makes
the fruit attractive the ripening
process also eventually leads to Decay
and that's the other part of our
equation in trying to meet our food
security needs how much can we produce
but also can we get it uh to the to the
consumer so this process that I've
mentioned or referred to as ripening is
really the sum of all those activities
the physi physiological changes the
biochemical changes that sum together to
make the fruit attractive to some
organism that will consume it and
Liberate the seeds and again if it
doesn't come along Plan B is become
susceptible to things that will rot the
fruit and let those seeds out so that's
always the challenge how do we get high
quality and something desirable to eat
without getting into that later phase of
what's referred to as overripening and
eventually Decay so fruits do a lot of
things uh and they don't all do the same
thing they accumulate different pigments
they become different colors some get
soft some don't get soft but they have
many of the similar properties so they
generally accumulate sugar they
generally produce volatile compounds
often compounds and these are what give
fruits their characteristic Aromas
they're attractants they smell nice to
you they're often derived from necessary
nutrients so they're also signals that
there is quality there Beyond uh just
something that's fun to eat it's
actually going to be good for you um
they again typically accumulate pigments
but different Pathways and different
fruits are activated and nutritional
content often changes in the fruit as
well and finally as noted in the corner
eventually they rot this is all part of
the same developmental process the same
genetically controlled program so all of
this is going on as the fruit reaches
that stage of
maturity and again the challenge is how
do we get it to the consumer without
losing too much of the crop to uh to
Decay and we put a lot of money into
this a lot of energy a lot of time we
hold things in uh modified atmosphere
storage this is an Apple Shed in the
Pacific Northwest where fruit are held
uh in modified CO2 and oxygen levels and
at low temperature and that allows us to
keep them for 9 months U Beyond Harvest
and get them to Market virtually all
year round uh but in certain parts of
the world uh often the the resources are
not available or the means for uh
sustaining uh quality product is not
necessarily there it's too expensive
it's simply not available the energy is
not there so we lose a lot and we lose
the most of parts of the world where we
need uh that food the most so it's a
challenge to address this problem and it
begins with us for really understanding
the basic biology of the ripening of the
fruit and uh we do this in tomato and
again because really in Steve's lab so
much was developed in terms of molecular
uh resources things like the genetic
Maps eventually the DNA sequence that
Steve really uh ch championed the the
sequencing effort in tomato and uh a
number of other attributes of those of
you who grow tomatoes in your backyards
no it's pretty easy so I can grow
tomatoes and without killing them uh off
uh the genetics is good because it's an
important crop breeders have collected a
lot of the type of genetic diversity of
wild species that Greg mentioned and
also just a lot of mutants because they
see interesting things they put them
into the the seed Storage Bank so
there's a lot of genetic material that
we can use to ask questions about plant
biology and particularly the
fruit so I mentioned the sequencing
effort I'm just going to highlight this
for a second because again this was
really Steve's Vision um and he got
together the group that started the
sequencing effort and it was you know
tomato is not a crop that is that
important anywhere for anybody to be
able to do it by themselves so you organ
ored an international Consortium that
that tackled this uh problem and this is
all the tomatoes represent the countries
where there was actually funding um
starting with a white paper that Steve
organized that everybody submitted to
their respective governments got money
to uh bring about this project and many
other countries who didn't have funded
grants also participated as well the US
was really the lead group uh and Steve
is biggest here not because he has the
biggest head but because he had the
biggest impact uh and but what I point
out with this slide these are all the
groups in the US and many of the people
here are people that either worked with
or were students here's Zack Litman one
of Steve's former students Andy
Patterson another former student Rod
Wing a former postto so many of the
people who are working on this project
as faculty had come out of Steve's lab
earlier
on and the sequence was is important not
just because tomato is important but
because it's closely related to a lot of
other important uh fruit and vegetable
crops potato eggplant pepper you combine
those tomato and you really have the
most important fruit and vegetable crops
in the world and even coffee is not so
distantly related and Susan showed you a
while ago the comparative Maps between
the cereals that were done with rice and
Maze but Steve had also done this
between tomato and coffee demonstrating
that these genomes are not that
different and that you can use one
genome to make inferences about the
other um one of the real um great
impacts of of uh of Steve's vision and
his
leadership so I'll spend a few more
minutes now kind of coming back um to
some of some of the things I did and put
it in the context of of how I ended up
here uh at Cornell also I did my PhD at
UC Berkeley in the late 1980s and I was
working on a gene in tomato called polyg
galacon and and uh that's referred to up
here with the PG polygalacturonase
becomes very highly expressed in the
ripening fruit it's uh the predominant
protein in the cell walls of the fruit
as they mature and what it does is it
breaks down the pectin in between the
cells so think of a brick wall and if
all the mortar started liquefying that's
what polygalacturonase does it breaks
that down it was thought that that
caused the fruit to soften and so a
company you may have heard of called
Calene said let's make a genetically
engineered tomato that won't soften
it'll last longer we can leave it on the
vine longer it'll taste better because
we don't have to harvest it too early
just so that we can ship it across the
country uh and I assume probably many of
you have heard of the flavor saver
tomato and Calene and that was the first
GM crop so so I was doing my PhD and it
was actually to test the function of
that Gene and my PhD was that's not
going to work so what we did was Express
that we did the opposite experiment we
overexpressed it in a hard green fruit
and said does it get soft the answer was
no the hard green fruit we used were a
mutation called the ren mutation or
ripening inhibitor that actually arose
spontaneously here on the Cornell campus
in Henry munger's Greenhouse so Henry
Munger former Alum and also a faculty
for nearly 40 years passed away recently
uh was in the plant breathing Department
here and this mutation arose
spontaneously in his Greenhouse the
fruit do not ripen at all that let me
test that hypothesis but it also made me
much more interested in well what's
wrong with this fruit that it won't
ripen and that's what led me to Steve's
lab because he was pioneering the
technology that allowed one to go from a
phenotype to the that underlies that
defect um so that's why I was here in
the early '90s I was actually in the
same aisle as Greg Martin we were
bouncing into each other not as much as
we would now I was much smaller then um
but still did once in a while so the the
ren mutation what I just showed you and
and you can see again here is a
homozygous mutant fruit never ripens so
that's a pretty serious defect it
actually has practical utility a lot of
it it's used very widely and Commercial
Tomatoes as a heterozygote where you now
get a long shelf life slow ripening
tomato that nobody likes right everybody
Tomatoes never taste as good as they do
when I grow them in the backyard this is
one main reason why but they do have
long shelf life you can ship them across
the country easily and it's really
partly because we haven't focused too
much on the quality we primarily focus
on making sure we can produce the crop
and get it to Market but a lot of the
Breeders now uh uh are focusing back on
the quality of the fruit but again our
interest was this must be something
really important if you can alter this
single Gene and and have such a big
impact on the ripening of the fruit and
so in our lab and work I started in
Steve's lab and then completed a little
bit later we identified the underlying
Gene it's a transcription Factor so it's
a a master regulator of other genes and
uh it basically we know now controls
almost every Gene that we know is
involved in ripening or has a change of
expression in ripening this Gene sits on
its promoter and influences its
expression so it's a key regulator there
are many other interesting tomato fruit
mutants in implementing these same kinds
of positional cloning technologies that
Greg mentioned earlier we've identified
many of those genes as well in fact
virtually every important or kind of
major effect mutation in tomato has now
been cloned either by our group or in
collaboration with
others and Julia rebov who did a lot of
this work is a former uh Cornella lump
she received her PhD here um and we one
of the interesting things we've done is
once we had this Gene we asked well is
this just tomato or is it other species
we know now working with a number of
collaborators generating Knockouts in
this Gene through GMOs and banana and
melon and strawberry that this Gene's
very well conserved and if you alter its
expression you alter the ripening of the
fruit so it's a very basic regulator of
ripening and it's a very well conserved
through Evolution regulator of ripening
so if you're interested in controlling
shelf life variation in a gene like this
is probably one you should be looking
at as I mentioned there are a lot of
other interesting mutants I'll just
point out one U here that we've
identified the gene for another Cornell
Alum Kong Wen did his PhD on this uh
this is a gene called uniform ripening
so this is a a wild type non-mutant
tomato it has this kind of green
shoulder on the top most Tomatoes you'll
find in the supermarket carry the
uniform ripening mutation so they're
uniform in color when they ripen they'll
be uniform red the older varieties and
you know if you're interested in
heirloom tomatoes one marker of an
heirloom is if they have the green
shoulder um it's thought that that's not
a nice appearance so it's been bred out
using the uniform mutation what we know
now is this is another transcription
factor that greenness up here is of
course due to chlorophyll if you remove
that you have less chlorophyll you end
up with less sugar you have less
chloroplasts so you also get less
carotenoids you actually have probably a
less nutritious fruit but it looks nice
um so but it's an unintended consequence
and we understand this now and uh we can
probably do things about that because of
that knowledge to bring back some of
that
quality as Greg mentioned we're also
using genetic diversity now to look at
um to basically to identify additional
genes for which we don't have mutations
uh but for which there is uh diversity
in the wild germ plasm and this is just
um an example of a
population that was developed largely
using the marker technology that Steve
had had developed um and he's also
developed some of these populations in
his work as well here we're just looking
we're interested in in the nutritional
quality and one of the main attributes
of that in tomato is the carotenoids
lopine beta carotene that gives them
their typical orange reddish colors and
I think you can see just looking over
this slide there's a lot of variation if
we extract those and measure them and
just plot the different compounds across
the different lines you can see a lot of
variation in different nutritional
compounds so we're using that now to map
new Loi and identify new genes that
regulate this particular pathway and the
outcomes and again this was another
Cornell Alum um Ryan mcquinn who
received his PhD here just last year who
did a lot of this
work so I thought I'd end if I have a
minute to end with just one last slide
about about you know who are our our
greatest faculty and of course we can
replace this word here with Steve tley
these two words so he fits all of them
and uh we didn't coordinate but you
heard a lot of these words uh from Susan
from the dean from Greg earlier uh so
I'm glad to see we're all thinking of
the same things when we're thinking of
Steve an educator an innovator not just
in science but also in the in the
university community and how science is
done uh Vision to see things I think
Susan showed that very well with her
slide um you know when we were sitting
here uh running gels it was hard I think
certainly for me to imagine where we
would be now and I think Steve saw that
coming and help bring us there so that
leadership as well and the most
important thing I think is still a human
being in the end very compassionate
person um and also sometimes he helps
keep you out of
jail um so I'll tell you a little story
it's not not as bad as it sounds but
when I was a postto here I was out in
the field in Varna you know where Varna
is down
366 Steve had his tomato Fields there
and it was a Saturday morning and I was
out with another postto Rod wi and we
were harvesting tomatoes from our uh
crosses so these wild species crosses
they make little tiny
tomatoes and along Along came a Cornell
University Police Officer wondering what
we were doing out there on a Saturday
morning picking tomatoes he thought we
were stealing them he didn't seem to buy
the fact that across directly 12T away
from us was Martha much's field for
breeding tomatoes that had these big
beautiful tomatoes and we had all these
little tiny orange tomatoes so he gave
us a
test it's not the kind of test you see
here but he would turned out was a
recent Cornell Grant he gave us a plan
physiology test in the
field we couldn't believe it and the
funniest thing was both rod and I were
do you know that do you know started
asking us about photosynthesis about
hormones he had taken a hormone uh from
uh from Peter
Davies uh very uh very uh excited young
police officer and after that we told
Steve of course we tried calling Steve
there was no cell phones in those days
so he was calling into the police
station to call steveen lab who was in
the greenhouse so we couldn't get
rescued by Steve but after that we
always carried a letter from Steve out
in the field saying we actually worked
from him and we were not um tomato
thieves so so um yeah that was quite an
experience so I I will end there uh and
just uh thank again all of you for
coming today and uh and thanks Steve for
so much
[Applause]
and now if I could ask Susan and Greg to
please join us all up on the stage we're
going I have a a series of questions
that I'll be asking our panelists and
then I'll open up the conversation to
everyone who's here today but I cannot
tell you how happy I am to finally learn
the answer to the riddle why those
Supermarket tomatoes never taste as good
as the ones you grow yourself so Rin
I've got that now that's terrific so
anyway let's start our
conversation uh here among our group and
the first question that I'd like to ask
our panel here is what do you see on the
horizon what are the the the the number
one Challenger question I'd like to hear
from each of you that you see on the
horizon that will be important for plant
scientists to research and address in
the coming decade
[Music]
just like that just like
that so one of the things that I think
is really exciting is how to develop and
deploy diversity meaning genetic
variation in time and space in a way
that will help us mitigate the effects
of the variability of the climate so if
you can't predict something you can't
you can't really work with a uniform
agricultural system you have to now
reintroduce diversity how are we going
to do it what's it going to look like
and how are we going to manage it so
that it's actually both productive and
um appropriate for the challenges at
hand I guess we
here well I think uh I I try to sort of
illustrate this in my talk in my field I
think the biggest challenge is how we're
now going to start to take advantage
really of what we've learned over the
past 20 or 25 years about the immune
system we've we know a lot about it we
know about the individual genes but
we're just at the sort of uh inflection
point of now starting to uh use those
into improve disease resistance in the
field and that's going to be really
important I mentioned also super bugs in
the news that does happen with plant
pathogens and we need to be able to
understand how to actually use multiple
resistance genes in the same variety to
be able to uh thwart the attack of these
kind of super bugs that are always
evolving out
there I guess uh I mean one way I would
answer that is what keeps me up at night
which is what what do we do with all the
data I we generate I mean and this is I
speak for myself we generate so much
data that we uh maybe pick a few
cherries from or or anal Anze in a very
specific way and extract some nugget
from but there is so much more potential
there uh and I think you know actually
being able to take advantage of all the
data that we generate um more
efficiently than than I know at least I
do now I think is one of the the big
challenges uh probably for many groups
certainly for our group The the good
news is that I think we're all thinking
about that and we're starting to address
it you see that in the types of people
you know we hire there's much more you
now the typical student I think in the
lab is spending half their time at the
bench and half their time doing
computational work so that they are
certainly changing how they do things
but I still look back and see we
generate so much that we really just
scrape the surface off of so I think
that's an opportunity it's not a
negative thing but it's something
certainly we need to figure out how to
take better advantage of a terrific
theme in all three of the is about
complexity and complexity of biological
systems and taking advantage of what we
can learn from that so terrific now you
all are renowned scientists and and you
come from from years in fact of of
focusing on scientific questions as
scientists what would you like the
nonscience community to know about plant
biology and genomics what what would you
say if you could distill it into the
most critical thing for nonscience
scientists to wrap their head around
what would that
be I could start off with that I think
for me it was sort of a revelation I was
at a dinner party two or three years ago
and and somebody asked me what I worked
on and I started talking about the plant
immune system and many people just kind
of stared at me blankly because they
hadn't really thought about the fact
that plants have an immune system and so
I guess that's the one thing I'd like to
be able to communicate to to people into
the public is that plants do have an
immune system it has a lot of really
fascinating aspects to it a lot of
parallels actually to the human immune
system and what we uh learn in plants is
of course important for making disease
resistant plants but it's also can have
an impact in how we understand the human
immune
system
ahead I was still
thinking um I I guess you know maybe one
of the most important things um is to
just uh keep in mind how much potential
there is out there I think I think it's
so easy to go to the supermarket and you
see a ear of corn or a a a fluet of
broccoli and you think that's it you
know that that is broccoli that is corn
that's a tomato and there's so much
diversity that we still don't exploit in
crop breeding there's so many
opportunities to bring in new traits to
bring in more disease resistance to
bring in different fruit quality uh that
there's a lot more out there and that it
I think Al also a lot of people when you
think about something different I know
what if I always get asked you are those
orange Tomatoes GMOs or how about the
yellow ones um and you know all of that
is non- GMO there's no GMO tomato out in
the marketplace so this is all natural
genetic diversity that's being brought
into uh modern breeding programs and
there's still just a tiny tip of the
iceberg of what's potential that's being
exploited I think one of the things that
has always impacted me a lot is to look
back at the underlying commonality that
all living things
share and that's the reason
why comparative Maps
work it's the why it's the reason why
you can take a gene out of one organism
and put it in another is because
fundamentally living
things honestly they at their B at their
base genetic level they're very similar
and they function in very similar ways
and so I wish that the public could
understand that that we're not so
different in many ways we look and
appear different and we emphasize our
diversity but fundamentally underlying
that diversity is this incredibly common
origin that we share and that's a very
profound thing that genomics has helped
us to
understand thank you those are great now
switching just a little bit how are the
objectives of plant science research
influenced and changing in the context
of climate change in the context of
globalization population growth and how
we are going to feed our global
population so how how do you see plant
science changing to address these
emerging Global
needs it's obviously a really big
question a lot of really huge problems I
guess the one that I think a lot about
because it really does impact the what
I'm working on and that is that climate
change is going to have a huge impact
actually on diseases because as as the
climate changes different pathogens are
able to adapt so we're going to see
entirely new diseases start to develop
that we just haven't had a problem with
in the last you know 20 or 30 years and
uh yeah disease are going to appear in
different uh further north than they
used to and further south in different
crops so that's going to be a huge uh
problem going forward and it's and it's
and it's due to climate change
I think we can already see an emphasis
on local production and I think that the
return to thinking about being locally a
little bit more self-sufficient and less
dependent on some Grand scale is very
important in the face of both population
pressure climate change and also our
appreciation of the varying interests
and um let's say preferences that
different consumer communities have and
so it's both out of interest for the
diversity and it's also out of I think a
need to find a system that has both a
local as well as a a more Global content
that I think that emphasis is a growing
one and one that's quite healthy for us
to have an much more direct connection
to our food supply our water supply and
the sources of things that we need to
survive I I think my colleagues have uh
have covered these big topics very well
I'll focus a little bit on the fruit um
and I think you see certainly the
effects of
globalization right you get Summer
fruits all year round now because they
come from someone else's summer um and
but you know and they're different often
different varieties they're growing in
in different uh growing regions maybe
different climates so they're not
necessarily the same varieties you would
be seeing in the summer here say if
you're looking at peaches or something
like that uh so that it's from that
perspective there's certainly a lot more
uh opportunity there's a lot more things
that maybe we didn't have uh not so long
ago but at the same time there are you
know the challenges of growing just U
you know a narrow selection of genetic
diversity I think we probably often
appreciate that there isn't the quality
you get when you have something locally
grown because you're dealing with all
the realities of of uh shipping and
transport and storage it's often it's
just hard to get that same uh quality
that you can get from something that's
fully matured on a plant that is close
by and then picked the day before and
brought to you uh so I think in the end
I think what all this represents is just
a lot more opportunity for plant
scientists like us because as we
understand better the biology of these
systems we'll be able to understand
which of these issues we can actually do
something about which are going to be
more difficult which which maybe there
is no really good solution right now um
so I I think you know these um big
issues are impacting all of us and we
think about them all the time in our
research um and they do certainly change
how we how we focus our research and
certainly where the money comes from to
do our
research okay now this is your cue this
this is the last question coming for me
before we open up the conversation to
the audience and and it's intentionally
meant to be provocative and that is how
do you see GMOs fitting into the current
research arena in the plant sciences and
tell us if you see Alternatives perhaps
to to the strategy for uh creating uh
plant varieties that we will need to
address some of the issues that we've
been discussing here
well my my research has taken tremendous
advantage of GMO technology over the
past 25 years we couldn't have done many
of the experiments that we have done
without GMO technology um obviously
commercialization uh using GMO
technology has met a tremendous amount
of resistance from the public and and
the uh the good news there is that there
is a new technology available now it's
being referred to as genome editing you
might be hearing about it on the on the
news and in the newspaper so it really
is a new technology that so far is not
being considered GMO it really isn't a a
genetic or GMO it doesn't fit that def
definition of GMOs and allows a very
precise uh change to be made in a plant
genome and so the good news is is that
it looks like this is not going to have
as much uh regulation and hopefully not
as much concern on the part of the
public in its use and it'll be more
it'll be be used more
[Music]
widespread
ready I I I was yeah just kind of
jumping to the microphone because I I
think in a lot of ways the the path that
uh some of the work we do and Greg does
is similar we identify genes that we
think are responsible for a process and
we often test that function in a GMO
plant we alter its expression we
overexpress it and we asked does it
change the trait that we think it might
be changing so it as a research tool
it's certainly extremely important but
again as as Greg mentioned there's been
a lot of resistance um you know
something like tomato after flavor saver
it's been uh 25 years there hasn't been
another GMO tomato um so there are new
technologies and I think also with uh
more appreciation and more exploitation
of available genetic diversity there's
more opportunities for solutions that
don't necessarily necessitate a GMO
approach so and I think practically
that's probably where a lot of the the
seed companies are focusing if I can
solve this problem by using available
genetic diversity why get into the the
the storm of uh GMO
controversy I think one of the
underlying reasons why GM technology is
is
so considered so essential in some of
the uh in some of the big a applications
is because it's easy to patent because
you can see it because you can prove it
because you can prove it's yours okay so
you can defend it so that's very
important what's interesting about the
new technology is that as Greg started
to say you can do something very
precisely and it leaves no Trace no
footprint no fingerprint it would look
just
like nature does it it's a mutation
exactly like what nature does so I think
what's interesting is will the public
now that the human can do what Nature
has done
before will the human find that
acceptable or if the intervention of the
human not the thing itself but the
intervention of the human is the thing
the public objects to will that then be
the grounds for further rejection but
what if you can't prove it so we're
entering a whole new terrain I think
of really
complicated uh Concepts about ownership
and the defense of patents if this new
technology leaves no footprint and I
will say that I think it's both um an
opportunity and it's very terrifying at
the same time time and I think that we
should all be quite thoughtful about
what it is that we're willing to do and
yet at the same time I think if if
you're the one who's faced with the zika
virus or you're the one who's faced with
a malarial epidemic that can no longer
be treated by any antibiotic or any uh
there's no medicine to treat
something would you just sit down and
let that m microbial population overtake
your life so I just feel like we're at
the moment of real
ethical turning points and it's going to
take it's not about whether it's good or
bad it's just going to take a lot of
real thought on the part of many many
people to understand when and how and
under what conditions we use the
technology that the human being is
endowed by nature to be able to conceive
of and develop because that's who we are
too anyway I find it to be worthy of
great thought and I'm not ready to say
it's uh A Brave New World or not I just
I think we're at
the we're entering into some very
unknown
territory that was very profound and at
this moment I'd like to open to the
floor uh further questions that you
might have and uh I think our panelists
might be willing to stay um after for a
little little bit if you would prefer to
do one-on-one conversations for a little
bit anyway but we have our first
question
here yes I've been confused about uh the
Uproar over GMOs because I've always
thought it was a great idea but it
appears that the uh objection relates
more to the kind of
chemicals uh that have been the Monsanto
uh curse I guess to and the people are
afraid that the uh all of this uh
auxiliary um stuff is that's going on is
is polluting the vegetables that we're
eating and the crops and I thought well
this is a wonderful time to ask this
question because I've been uh very
curious I've always thought the GMO
approach was great so uh maybe uh
somebody can explain to me why there's
such uh fear and uh desperation about it
yeah I think you sort of put your your
finger on it there is that the the first
really sort of commercially successful
use of the technology was for herbicide
resistance and that did uh sort of it
was Associated then with more herbicide
use which was really effective in the
field the farmers you know accepted the
the
technology um uh the sort of downside of
that was that there was then a lot more
regulations that occurred around the
technology and this partly relates to
the public public concern about it so
there became more and more regulations
and it actually prevented more
widespread use of the technology it was
sort of counterintuitive but it became
so expensive to regulate crops that
there were very few companies that could
actually do it so you know Monsanto of
course was one of those companies that
were able to uh deploy the technology
and it sort of uh you know it sort of
stained the the use of the technology I
think in the in the minds of the public
it just so happened that that was the
the first first use of the technology if
it had been used for you know uh proving
disease resistance or a number of other
things improving nutrition of crops uh
and there were subsequent uses of it for
those purposes it just uh it might have
been completely
different actually let me just add to
that I think the other big use
of um GM early on was insect resistance
in the form of
BT and the impact globally has been to
reduce the use of pesticides by
somewhere between 20 and 25 and 50%
depending on the crop in the
region so the use of GM technology has
actually improved Environmental Quality
and the lives of many many many many
many millions of farmers around the
world many small farmers in fact just in
case you don't know the average size of
the farm using BT uh BT cotton today is
less than a hectare of land so there's a
huge mythology out there that it's only
the big farmers that benefit it's not
the truth but it is in fact the
mythology and now I think it's so
confusing in people's minds between the
use of glyphosate and then this
alternative that it's not one and the
same thing and so if you had to somehow
create one monolithic
understanding it's very confusing
because it's not one thing or the other
it depends where and how and who it's
like any other form of intervention
right too much is not good but we're at
that point where I think it's been very
very very
confusing I think part of the problem is
that this extends Beyond plants you get
this Frankenstein element of well we're
introducing different species and mixing
with humans and uh we're modifying DNA
and so forth and um part of us goes well
beyond um uh the plant uh development to
concerns about what the limits of
science are in in areas that directly
relate to
human uh the human uh development and so
forth and uh some of that fear of the
Frankenstein element is is coming into
um uh the area of plants and vegetables
I mean actually the
technology is applied to all forms of
life but so far we don't apply GM to
human but we do apply it to try to
improve human quality of human life in
different Arenas including probably most
of the medications you take
today you know we don't chew on the bark
of the willow tree to get our
aspirin uh we don't you know are if any
of you are diabetic and you have to take
insulin it's GM insulin so we forget how
many of the things that we think are
fine are GM technology as well but I
agree with you that is the confusion and
I think it has implications
for we have a an understanding that life
was natural before GM which is another
one of
those bizarre concept cepts that
we've I I have actually two
questions it seems to me that the known
genetic diversity among all the major
crops and the fact that each of them is
susceptible to uh different pathogens
that have po
specificity is it possible this is
thinking 10 years from now or 20 to use
that information from one uh main
cultivar like wheat to use genes that
confer resistance to put them into corn
to confer resistance to uh pathogens
that now can't recognize that because
the pathogens of corn don't under know
have never interacted with wheat jeans
or whatever the the products of wheat
jeans I me in a very diverse way it
seems to me uh this understanding of uh
all the diversity and and then making
use of that in a global way could really
uh arrest some of the problems that we
have with the ability of microbes to to
become adaptable to to now infect the
resistant cultive our four five six
years down as the way we have with rust
variants and and wheat for
example yeah in fact it's not even 10
years from now that actually has already
been done so there are examples where a
gene has been identified in a a mustard
plant and was transferred to tomato
tomato in this case didn't have any
genetic resistance to a certain disease
uh of course you can't cross a mustard
plant and a tomato plant so they were
able to use GMO technology to move the
gene from mustard to tomato and it gave
really effective resistance there's
others examples too where it's not been
commercialized right oh no this has not
been commercialized yet but it's being
tested this happened paper was published
a couple of years ago and there's many
other examples in the literature of
moving Gene from rice to ma to corn and
so forth so the technology is available
there again probably the main holdup has
again been the acceptance or lack of
acceptance of GMO technology terrific my
my second question is really directed to
you uh the plants have uh quite good
innate immune mechanisms but not
Acquired and is there any way to
introduce into plants an ability to
learn from the experience and even
transfer that immunity to the seeds so
that the Next Generation I mean that you
know that there's some resistance that
gets conveyed through the germ plasma
yeah that's a great question it I mean
we do view plants having an innate
immune system just the way that humans
do it doesn't rely on antibodies but
humans also have this sort of system
that basically like plants every cell
needs to be able to respond to a
pathogen so in a sense I mean that is
acquired they they evolve over a longer
period of time but they plants don't
have antibodies in the sense of they
meet a entirely new pathogen and acquire
that and it's passed
on good good afternoon um I'm I'm here
from San Francisco I work with some of
the big egg Growers and processors
um and mostly in product development
post uh Harvest and uh one of the
frustrations I have is everybody um in
in the the production business and the
marketing business fears getting a label
of oh this is a GMO product and so I'm
going to go back to to Professor Jon's
first bullet point on on what are the
the mission and that is to educate and
particularly when it comes to I think
some of the hysteria about genetic
engineering is a lack of understanding
and so I'm going to throw it to you to
say what are you doing to educate people
the EU last week cleared GMO crops that
there's no Health effect negative health
effects from this and on the record and
yet they still oppose it they're no uh
they're not allowed to import any GMO
products into to the EU so what would be
what standards would you propose
to uh demonstrate safety both from a
plant side from a biological side and I
the bigger issue is other health issues
uh but is there a standard that would
meet your criteria and how are you going
to get get that that standard out
there thank you for the
[Laughter]
question so I no I mean I think uh you
hit on a lot of important observations
right so it it's it certainly is a big
problem in terms of perception of GMOs
and I I'll just start first with one
antidote so I I was at a dinner once in
France with the head of an inra lab so
this a lab that's kind of the equivalent
of a USDA lab and this was a lab that
was doing a lot of GM modification this
was a lab that was promoting the
positive benefits of
GMOs um very aware of the fact uh and
promoted the fact that there are EU
studies there's National Academy of
Science studies there's many studies
addressing kind of the inherent risk you
know is there you could probably design
something sure you could you could
express uh something that'll cause an
allergy and that would be dangerous but
is there anything inherent about GMO
technology that is dangerous and and
many have come to the inclusion
conclusion that that's not the case so
here we are at the dinner
and the wife of the director who is so
positively Pro GMO says I will never
touch anything GMO because I think it's
dangerous so he can't convince his wife
U so some some people I think are not
going to respond to the logical
arguments no matter what whether it's
because you know some of the this is
food right it's something we put in
their mouth that's probably the thing
you're going to be most concerned about
um before everything everything else I
think in the end the best arguments as
has been mentioned before is going to be
um products and you're in that area
where the consumer appreciates the fact
that it's GM because it's more
nutritious because it has better quality
um I think just right now it just I mean
I yeah I understand I talk um to to a
lot of the seed companies and yeah they
just don't want to touch it they they
don't want to be the one to take the
arrows let somebody else do that um
because there is a lot of negative
perception and I'm not sure that it's as
simple as education there's a lot of
people you can explain and they have
other agendas other reasons why they're
not interested in maybe necessarily
following the the logical arguments and
again you know in there not to be too
negative I think again because it is so
basic our food is so basic to us we are
probably the most risk averse with that
more than many other things so that's
people a lot of people have a lot of
concern is stand is way to
come yeah biolog I I think I I can't
really address that question but I think
Susan alluded to it'll be really
interesting to see how people respond to
the editing technology where it's very
you know that we use mutation breeding
all the time natural variation all the
time these are going to be changes that
will be EXA exactly the same as what you
would get through natural variation are
people going to respond to those as okay
yeah that's fine are they still going to
say you intervened so therefore it
doesn't meet my standard of what I
accept and it it's true again you know I
was you'd never see anything you see
practically growing in the supermarket
in the wild right it's all the product
of
manipulation but in the end the reality
still is a lot of
people don't want it my answer is label
it label it GM now we should have done
it at the very beginning we pasteurized
milk people hated it at the beginning we
labeled it it's fine but you don't label
it it looks like you're trying to hide
something you people don't believe you
because they you don't tell them the
truth tell them the truth it's GM
they'll get over it they'll try it I
don't think it's I wish we would just
label it I I I would stop everything
else and just put the label
on that's my answer we have time for one
more question so you were speaking
earlier uh about some of the issues with
the zika virus and malaria that's
resistant to a lot of antibiotics and
Other Drugs um as sort of a way that uh
um something that unifies people behind
uh some of the genetic modification um
but I was kind of curious about uh
something such as golden rice where we
see like widespread beneficial impact of
of this uh possible um variety of rice
and uh you still see a lot of groups
such as Green Piece uh like vly uh
against these sorts of things so uh in
the problem of like kind of implementing
these uh this technology um are we
looking at like a vocal minority that
that we need to like out Lobby or
something like that is this an issue I
think maybe about um universities not
being able to uh go to governments or or
consumers with information as readily as
uh organizations that you know aren't
governed in the same way that we are so
I'm kind of curious like how do you see
us changing the minds of not just
consumers who I think are probably a
little bit uh easier to reach but but
the people who are really like affecting
change policy wise on these
issues I want to I want to just say
um it sounds like you think golden rice
is a
product no no no no you know it's never
it's there is no golden rice you know
that right it doesn't exist as a product
on the market it nobody is eating golden
rice anywhere in the world right yeah
okay so why hasn't it gone out you mean
yeah many reasons probably I mean I know
some reasons but I think
you're my my
my my thought is that there's been a lot
of attempt on the part of many people on
all sides of this argument on all sides
of the fence to reach policy makers and
to discuss at in a logical scientific
way and I actually agree with Jim I
think the fundamental reason that the
scientific arguments The Logical the
rational don't necessarily convince is
because the objections are
not uh logical rational or
scientifically based so you cannot
counteract them with those kinds of
arguments I have I I have an
understanding that actually
many I don't know if this is true but I
think many
um having talked to many people I think
many people have a deep-seated
understanding that uh comes from judeo
Christian
beliefs that the world was made in God's
image and
any changes
are against the law of
God and that's why I think evolution is
not taught in some some
schools it's the same fundamental Clash
of some very very very basic belief
systems it's not reachable by science or
by Logic so I I actually believe that
that's underlying a lot of the
resistance and it's not something that a
policy maker can change it's not
something a university class can change
it's something that
people um maybe the reason people change
is because they're confronted by a
greater
evil and it forces them to reconsider
their belief systems sometimes but as
long as you can hold on to your belief
system I know there's a fundamental deep
deep seated belief system that probably
each of us has we will defend it to the
death and I think that's the at that's
actually where you know when cernus or
any of the the great discoveries in
science that that the Earth revolves
around the sun things don't revolve
around us anything that takes us out of
the center is somehow very threatening
so I actually believe it's at that level
and that's
why um it it doesn't follow a linear
course it never disappoints me when I
hear conversations among cornellians
this was a fabulous session this
afternoon I thank each and every one of
you for joining us for this thoughtful
conversation and please join me in
appreciating our panelists this
afternoon this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu