this is a production of Cornell
University and today I I'll be giving a
a brief overview of the work that my lab
is doing on sustainable cropping systems
and plant breeding um and then I'll
focus in on a subset of the work that
we're doing on cover crops so as B
mentioned I'm housed in plant breeding
and genetics um but I also um work kind
of at the intersection of of agronomy
and agricology integrating some
management and um social science
questions along with the genetics and
breeding work um So within this kind of
broad topic area we work on several
different crops and cropping systems uh
including uh in including forages um
cover crops and some emerging real crops
so working on on dry beans and hemp AIT
um and some of the major thematic areas
that we work on
include the establishment phase of of
many of these crops um weed management
winter
hardiness organic systems multicrop
systems there's you know many many
others but those are some of the sort of
core themes that we're thinking about in
my lab um and working on these across
several of the different crops that we
work on so lots of interconnections
across the crops they not going to be
able to talk about all of these themes
and crops today U focusing in more on
cover crops so um yeah we we touch on a
lot of the big thematic areas within of
the cover crops that we work on so
across all of the cover crops we're
thinking about early Vigor and in that
establishment phase um with serial Ry in
particular we're focused on allopathy as
a weed management
tool um across all of the crops so we're
mostly focused on on winter annuals so
fall
planted um and so we care a lot about
winter survival and and in some cases
we're thinking also about um breeding
for tolerance to later planting dates um
and uh we do most of our breeding and
trials in organic
systems um as cover crops are an
especially important tool for organic
farmers uh and then we also are working
on um a lot on cover crop mixtures so we
plant a lot of our trials um in
multispecies mixtures because that's um
how a lot of farmers are using cover
crops so that's kind of the the big
picture of what we're thinking about in
cover crops um and before I get into
more of the nitty-gritty about how we
operate I just want to acknowledge the
efforts of the staff and graduate
students and the many undergraduates
that that come through our lab um I feel
really lucky to have um a super
hardworking and adaptable and
collaborative team that um yeah have
they've been really Nimble as we're
working on this huge range of of crops
and
systems um so uh the core of our our C
crop breeding work is is done through
the the cover crop breeding Network so
this is um a network uh of collaborators
across universities uh USDA AR research
stations uh and USDA nrcs plant material
centers um the network started in 2015
and was really motivated by um a of
breeding activity and named cultivars
available for cover crops um and we know
that cover crop adoption has been
steadily increasing over recent years um
but that most cover crops that are
planted on the landscape are variety not
stated so they haven't been um sort of
explicitly bred for specific breeding
objectives or or adaptation to specific
regions um and our premise with the
network is basically that that having
improved cultivars will um
uh improve the performance of cover
crops and support continued uh increases
in adoption of cover crops on the
landscape um so as I said the the work
started in
2015 um and Matt Ryan in in soil and
crop science has been part of the
network since the beginning um I joined
the network uh starting in 2019 I was
the the cover crop Network cord
coordinator um uh based out of a USDA
Research Center in Beltsville Maryland
um and then when I came to Cornell in
2021 I became the director of the
network um and sve Hansen is the current
Network coordinator she's a research
support specialist housed in my
lab uh
and um the network has been funded by
several different uh Grant programs over
the years the most um Central and most
important uh program for our network has
been the organic research and extension
initiative I'm so or I supported the
first grant that that started the
network in 2015 and has funded two
additional cycles of of Grants to um to
support the network since then um and
then we also currently have uh a bigger
uh sustainable egg systems cap Grant out
of USDA um and that's a a project that
includes our breeding work but is also
has a larger mission of increasing the
production of cover crop seed in the US
to support that um expanded adoption and
expanded Acres of cover crops that we're
seeing um
and so so since the Inception of the
network in 2015 so we we started out
working on three winter annual legum
species winter pea hary vet and crimson
clover um and then over time add
additional species so we now also work
on serial Ry and um on brasas uh
primarily winter canola and
um over that time period in addition to
expanding the number of species we've
also expanded the number of sites in the
network so as of this past year we have
let's see nine uh breeding locations
across the country and we also have two
farmer breeders that participate in the
network so they have breeding nurseries
on their farms in their based in the
Upper Midwest um we also have 14
Advanced line testing locations so
testing early generation breeding
material uh compared to commercial
checks and then as part of the new sasap
project we also have 12 locations that
are planting a variety trials that a
larger scale that are more um focused on
Commercial cultivars and and providing
recommendations to
Farmers um and this network represents
the first um n National effort to to
breed cover crops and um it's I think
particularly important to mention um in
the current uh political climate um how
important USDA collaborators especially
have been in in the Inception and
continued success of the network so we
work very closely with ARs breeders who
who were involved in founding the
network and uh we also work super
closely with the the nrcs plant material
centers and if people are not familiar
with the
pmc's um
they're uh about two dozen locations
across the country in different Eco
regions and their mandate is to evaluate
plant materials that are useful for
conservation programs so that includes
cover crops but also um you know native
species things that are useful for for
uh restoration work things like that um
and they have been really critical in um
they they especially have contributed to
the advanced line testing program and
they several occasions are doing seed
yield trials and are providing seed
increase services for us so we have
enough seed to plant larger trials um
later in the breeding program so so
that's been a really critical role for
them um and okay so so next I I want to
talk about our breeding pipeline I know
that a lot of people here are not plant
breeders and and so I thought it would
be useful to talk about what that looks
like for us um okay great um so so I'll
go through this quickly but we so we
have um we start by sourcing germ plasm
from a variety of places and plant them
and breeding nurseries we have
preliminary uh trials that are single
row plots uh planted at a few locations
and over time we expand to more
locations and larger plots we also have
seed yield trials that we plant at
several different locations across the
country and then we're now at the stage
uh for a couple of our crops Harry vet
and winter pee that were um moving
towards variety release and working with
seed companies to make that happen um
and I also wanted to mention we have on
on firm trials as of this year 70
locations across the country we're doing
this uh using seed links which is a an
app uh to coordinate a participatory
variety trials and breeding and we're
planning to do more of that in the
future um mentioning briefly that we're
also doing some uh evaluation for
freezing tolerance in growth Chambers uh
don't have time to talk more in detail
about that but it's work that's being
led by uh my graduate student rakaa
um so evaluating tolerance to freezing
um in these and these are new chambers
that um were installed this fall in
Bradfield and that's been supported by
several grants including an equipment
Grant and S and uh the Northern New York
act development program and I'll I'll
wrap up by plugging a field day that
we're doing in late April um and this
will be uh hosted in conjunction with
the annual meeting for our Network and
so there'll be cover crop readers from
across the country here and you'll have
an opportunity to engage so I would
encourage you to come if you're
available and I'll leave it there thank
you question
for question the the gr chamber do they
allow to to
freeze the do they allow freezing yes
nice yeah yeah so so we wrote this
equipment Grant to install so we have
three chambers now that can go to
Sub-Zero temperatures and they are I
didn't have time to to talk more about
it but they they're um a shared use
resource so so my grand student is is
using the chambers monopolizing them a
little bit right now for her her
dissertation project but uh in the
future um I think starting summer
they'll be more available for other
folks to use
yeah okay so uh my name is Lind seski I
am out of the horiculture section in
Geneva New York at Cornell agretech and
I am uh the weed science extension
specialist
for uh fruit and vegetable production
here in New York state now when we talk
about weeds weeds are problematic for
lots of reasons we think about the
competitive interactions that interfere
with crop growth and yield production uh
but they're they're problematic for
other reasons including the fact that
they can serve as host for pests and
pathogens they can physically
contaminate our yields uh this is
nightshade berries they can be uh a
contaminant of peas and of Snappy which
Can U impact the ability to accept loads
at the um at the processors and then
they can actually interfere with
harvestability these are beets we can
actually have weeds that are in the row
with beets that can actually interfere
with the lifting and The Cutting process
which reduces Harvest efficiency now
we're frequently using herbicides for
weed control but we need to think about
why we need to adapt first and foremost
uh pesticide development is costly and
slow it can take hundreds of millions of
dollars in a decade uh or more to bring
a new molecule from Discovery to
commercialization talking with a senta
colleague and they said oh I might have
something for you to test next year
we're looking at
2035 for uh a product release there's uh
effects of export Market access using
certain herbicides might not allow us
access to say the European market
there's changing consumer perceptions
about pesticide use and then there's
worker protection and crop injury
concerns if anyone has been following
the uh epa's new strategy for dealing
with uh their obligations Under The
Endangered Species Act that's also going
to complicate our pesticide use and then
there's herbicide resistance and while
we think herbicide resistance is being
an issue in our agronomic crop
production systems we do have herbicide
resistant issues in vegetables as well
so speaking of herbicide resistance some
of the work that my lab does and I I do
do herbicide trials and evaluations for
companies for The Growers for the ir4
project but we also look at the impacts
of uh overuse of herbicides this is work
uh from my graduate student Aaliyah
Butler Jones this is her master's work
where we confirmed glyphosate resistance
in a new weed problem here in New York
state Palmer amaran uh it's a big
problem throughout the United States and
just started moving into the more
Northern latitudes so we published that
paper and we're working with Terry
basone Kyle Brun Haro and Jim poock uh
to now uh prepare the manuscript where
we're characterizing atrazine resistance
in these same populations and we'll be
working with vipin on resistance to the
ALS
chemistries besides Palmer Amar that was
primarily in our agronomic crop
production systems we do have again
herbicide resistance in our especially
crop systems this is a paper uh from my
graduate student Bethany Schultis
looking at horse weed origer on
canadensis in New York Vineyards and
Orchards a lot of The Growers in uh New
York um Orchards and Vineyards are not
comfortable using glyphosate because
they're concerned about crop injury so
some of them have switched to using
paraquat well the use of paraquat has
led to the uh the development of
paraquat resistance in our populations
this one here in the vineyard that's
actually at Cornell agretech I've been
spraying that with paraquat and they're
like it's not dying and I'm like I've
got a I got an explanation for that so
we do have paraquat resistance we also
have uh low levels of diquat resistance
that are evolving uh we're currently
working with Terry basone and Kyle Brun
Haro to uh characterize misot trione
resistance in um our horse weed
populations as well so why do we need to
look look ahead obviously you know I
we're not going to spray our way out of
our issue so we need to be thinking
about what's down the road what kind of
technology is available to us and
there's a lot of focus on novel weed
management uh tools such as robotic
weeders and the three that we're looking
at is electrical weeding with Oregon
State you see Davis uh Optical spraying
with ruers and then laser weeding uh
with r
University so electrical weeding uh it
everyone expects arcs and Sparks this is
actually my electrical weeder where
we're using the mechanical energy from
the tractor engine to power a generator
that charges the applicators and those
applicators is right up in the front you
can see the metal uh electrons basically
that flow of electricity generates heat
it disrupts cellular mechanisms leading
to tissue death and that includes some
crowns and Roots so this is electrical
weeding 24 hours after treatment and
then this is one week after treatment uh
my graduate student Aaliyah Butler Jones
has been looking at it uh in our Organic
Apple production and this is uh funded
by an organic um research and extension
initiative basically she wanted to
compare electrical weeding to uh a
commonly used practice such as
cultivation as well as organic
herbicides and the work she's been doing
basically shows is that we're getting
better weed control of our perennial
weed species using electrical weeding
compared to cultivation she's also done
some work stacking electrical weeding
with cultivation if we go in and do the
electrical weeding first and then come
back with cultivation we find we get
even better weed control and it's much
easier to run those cultivation events
she's still conducting research but
right now the data suggests we don't
have any kind of lasting impacts on the
soil biological communities such as U
micro diversity micro activity or soil
microarthropods we are doing targeted
spraying so Vision guided spraying work
uh this is some work that we started
doing in perennial crops specifically in
blueberries and grapes and we're using a
system called the weedit system from
agretech America basically it just uh
looks for uh chlorophyll fluoresence
when it has that near infrared signal it
just turns on the nozzles that are
associated with the location of where
that unwanted vegetation is in the field
and what we've shown is that it's
actually very effective in our our
grapes and our blueberries for
controlling weeds and we're really
interested in the technology because it
allows us to reduce the amount of
herbicide we're applying annually we
have that ability to reduce crop injury
potential that are associated with
postemergence applications because we
have less contact potential with the
crop we might be able to eval valuate
new herbicides that could control our
herbicide resistant weeds or those
perennial weeds because of this enhanced
safety and importantly I mentioned The
Endangered Species Act uh it uh using a
vision guided sprayer will be a
mitigation strategy for preventing
off-target herbicide movement that can
threaten endangered um that can impact
threaten and endangered species or their
critical habitat because we're applying
less herbicide to less Acres uh using
the technology we're also working with
Terry bits if we can see the weeds can
we see the crop and we've actually been
doing work with Terry bait saying you
know what we can actually use this weed
it sprayer to uh preferentially treat
suckers so they don't need to have
someone going around either putting you
know the herbicides on continuously
applying and and applying the herbicides
where we don't need it or having someone
with a wand having to go Vine to vine to
vine to vine to vine to spray them so
we're working on that publication for
Hort technology on our weed sucker
control our next step is actually
putting our weed it system our spray
system on a fully automated Little Robot
uh training it to where all the The
Vineyard rows are and sending it off to
do the whole process
automatically I'm we're getting into the
vision guided spraying in our vegetable
systems I have been bothering this
company for years verdant robotics
please bring a unit to New York please
bring a unit to New York please bringing
a unit to New York we really want to
test your unit because our Growers are
interested in it but I can't give them
guidance if I can't work with it and see
it so this is a really unique Vision
guided uh spray system it's uh obviously
it's it's it's a an AI uh based models
where it sees the crops and it sees the
weeds it discriminates between them but
rather than say like uh some of the
systems like the John Deere systems that
just has a bank of nozzles that turn on
and off
uh verdant robotics actually has an a
turret that can move and turn and focus
uh to direct a concentrated stream right
at the weeds and this is actually The
Verdant robotics unit operating uh in
organic carrots out in Bolt house farms
in California that's not lasers that's
actually just lights showing you how the
turrets are moving and targeting the
weeds and the little insert here you can
see exactly in these tiny little dark
patches how uh precise uh the herbicide
application is and we actually have one
grower in New York who is looking to
invest in this in
2025 but we're going to be speaking
about and and again verdant robotics has
agreed to bring a Research Unit this
summer for us to do some trials with but
if we want to talk about the biggest of
the big uh of uh AI technology and
targeted weed control that would be
carbon robotics they are the only
commercial laser weeding company in the
United States they were founded in 2018
they manufactured the units in Detroit
they launched in early 22 with their uh
the first version of their laser weeder
really looking at the large vegetable
growers in Arizona California the
western United States basically they use
high-intensity bed toop lighting to to
illuminate and and remove all the
Shadows so they get a clear view of all
the crops and the weeds and then uh they
with their AI deep learning models they
discriminate between them and then they
have uh 150 watt CO2 lasers they're
their newer editions are now 240 watt
dodes with a millimeter accuracy that
just shoot the weeds and I have a video
here that you can see basically that's
scanning the bed top and then all the
little pin points of light that is uh
the lasers actually targeting the
individual weeds in between the lettuce
plants and in the lower part you can see
basically the Precision of going after
uh meristematic and other
tissue we were very lucky to work with
their uh their research and demo unit
that was the one that was in operation
in the previous slide so we uh conducted
trials in New York in New Jersey uh we
looked at Laser weeding uh I purposely
looked at beets spinach and peas and we
compared lasure weeding to um a commonly
used pre-emergence herbicide uh esor
also known as dual Magnum we looked at
the laser weeding alone or with the uh
in in partnership with the Dual Magnum
and what I want you to focus on is look
at the difference in the crop sizes not
so much the P we didn't have differences
but we in this trial one of the things
we were really able to see is how much
under our growing conditions the Dual
Magnum held our crops back our small
seated crops back we actually had really
warm temperatures and really intense
down pores that led to crusting and
because the Dual Magnum was actually
holding back the beets and the spinach
from uh the the
emergence uh they weren't able to break
out of the crust as easily they also
took up the herbicide and it resulted in
season long stunting in these crops now
this isn't necessarily out of the
ordinary isn't a function of me we had
several Growers who had to replant
Fields last year for this exact same
reason we found that the laser weeding
was as effective as our herbicide
applications for early season weed
control and like I said we got that
boost in the crop Vigor uh in the
absence of the pre-emergence herbicide
Terry got similar results in New Jersey
and we're currently preparing this for
Pest Management science we've also
leverage this for a moonshot grant uh
Brian n Christy hting and we're working
with Tor Farms to see if we can kill
many birds with one stone using laser
weeder the Tories have two commercial
laser weeders um which come in at a $1.6
million each uh but basically we know
that laser weeding can affect weed
control uh we also know it can improve
crop Viger so if we can improve onion
Vigor by taking some of the more
injurious onion herbicides out of the
program uh can we also potentially
reduce thrips damage and then uh the
incidence of and severity of stem filum
Leaf blight the last thing I'll talk
about is uh you know technology is great
but we have to ask a lot of question
questions about it technology doesn't
absolve us from being uh good weed
managers being good Farm managers being
good stewards these tools and
Technologies are going to impart
selection pressures on our weed
community so we we need to be aware of
who wins because someone always wins and
it's not us uh we have to think about
costs the units themselves but also
parts and services and then adoptability
we are not a small California the other
thing I'll say is we have to really talk
about infrastructure and Regulatory
Readiness uh our technology is advancing
a lot faster uh than say the EPA can
keep up with writing herbicide labels so
I just want to thank my lab and I want
to thank all the funding sources that
are supporting our
research this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu