this is a production of Cornell
University all right thank you George um
so yeah I guess I'll jump right into
George gave a nice introduction um I'll
jump right into talking about my
dissertation work I'm studying cardiac
glycosides in erysimum chy anthes so
first I want to start pretty broadly um
talking about how
plants um avoid being eaten and there
are uh a number of different strategies
plants take one of the main ones that
people might think about are physical
defenses so things like spines and
prickles um maybe they have really tough
leaves that make it difficult uh for an
insect to eat them but plants are also
really well known for their production
of chemical defenses um and this is an
area that's been pretty well studied
because plants produce just a massive
diversity of different compounds that
often have really interesting um
biological activity so I'm showing two
examples here um of some compounds that
plants produce that humans are a big fan
of so on the top we have coffee here um
and this is of course caffeine and then
on the bottom uh this is tobacco and
nicotine um but in uh the plant that I
study Arison which is a member of the
mustard family brassey um they produce a
group of compounds called glucosinolates
which are some sometimes known as the
mustard oil bomb um and these are what
glucos look like when they're intact in
the plant they have variable side chain
here um of derived from amino acid
metabolism um in sulfate group and these
compounds actually are pretty harmless
um as they exist in the plant but then
the plants also have an enzyme called
morinas which cleaves the sugar and
produces this unstable intermediate um
which then degrades into these reactive
um
products that you see here on the right
that are ENT um anti-feedant and
anti-pathogenic compounds um and these
compounds are what give um flavor to a
lot of the plants in this family that we
eat including things like mustard and
kale um that give that
bitterness uh but these compounds have
been around for a really long time it's
thought that they evolved about 90
million years ago um in this lineage and
that's a lot of time for insects to
adapt to these defenses um there are a
number of insects that actually seek out
uh glucosinolate producing plants and
they have a number of strategies for
dealing with um these toxic compounds so
one of them is the Cabbage butterfly
here which is you commonly see flying
around in the
summer um and they use a redirection
strategy so they have a special um
enzyme that redirects the unstable
intermediate to kind of a less toxic bio
product um other insects like the
Diamond Back moth here use um enzymes to
modify the glucosinolates before the
sugar is cleaved so they have a
sulfatase that removes the sulfate group
um and uh preventing the formation of
the the toxic compounds to start with um
and another strategy is
sequestration which is exemplified by
the Cabbage aphid here um and they're
sometimes known as The Walking mustard
oil bomb because they take the
glucosinolates from the plant and they
store them in their bodies to use them
for their own defense
and so in response to this uh herbivore
pressure uh from these potentially from
these specialist glucosinolate adapted
insects um some members of the brassic
casy have evolved new groups of toxic
compounds that can be seen as kind of a
second line of defense against these
glucosinolate adapted insects so a few
examples of these are garlic mustard
which should be popping up soon around
here all over the place um which makes
these hydroxy nitr glucosides
which kind of gives them the garlicky
flavor candy tuft is another example
they make these steroid derived
compounds called
cucurbitacin um and finally my study
plan the uh Wallflower or orisome which
makes cardiac glycosides also known as
cardenolides which I will just splp back
and forth between calling them cardiac
Glides and cardenolides because it's
hard to to stick to one um but they are
steroid derived compound compounds um so
as you can tell because they have this
four um these four fused Rings uh from
the steroid core and then they also have
this lactone ring up here at the top and
then they're often modified with um
sugars or hydroxy groups or asil groups
um that might kind of fine-tune and
change the
activity and um so as George mentioned
earlier they have very specific activity
in animal cells they're Inhibitors of
sodium potassium
atpases which um are critical for
maintaining uh membrane polarity in
processes like heart function um and for
that reason they're used in certain
context to to to treat some heart
conditions but in addition to their um
medical importance they're also of
pretty substantial evolutionary and
ecological interest um they've evolved
repeatedly in a bunch of different plant
lineages some of the ones that people
might have heard of are milked up here
at the top um with monarchs which are
adapted to cardiac lydes um as well as
Fox Glove down here which is a plant
you'll find commonly find in gardens and
this is the source of the um the
pharmaceutical um where it's purified
from
today um but I am studying orisome which
is up here in the bras Casey um and
uh I my main goals were to understand
the biosynthesis of cardiac glycosides
in this lineage so the biosynthesis is
not known in any of these
lineages and so what I'm hoping is as we
understand the biosynthetic pathway it
can give us some insight both into um
how these defensive compounds evolved in
this lineage but also potentially in
other lineages it seems like it's a
relatively biochemically and
evolutionarily accessible defense since
it has um convergently evolved so many
times and also what role uh these
defensive compounds play in a plant that
is already pretty well defended given
that it produces glucose
inates and so arism chirines uh has a
number of resources some of which I
developed but actually a lot of them
were developed before I started I want
to point out to BS zeust who's done a
ton of work um developing arism parentes
as a model um including helping with the
the original genome
sequence um and uh also a lot of the the
resources that I've been able to use
including gene expression from the you
know 48 different species that George
mentioned um and a transcripton based
philogyny that I used in some of my
research and then also M Amai who was a
um former postto in the jander lab and
she collected a lot of the gene
expression data across erysimum chantho
tissues that I used um and really
enabled a lot of This
research um but Aris in particular is a
is a good model um for use in lab it's
small and deployed it's relatively
closely related to the model plant or
rabid opsis um which so some of the the
resources available in a rapid opsis are
pretty easily transferred to orisome and
we can grow it easily in the the growth
Chambers and Green Houses in the lab um
oh yeah and I was able to develop floral
dip stable transformation which really
facilitated characterization of some of
the candidate genes
um that I will discuss later before I
dive into that I do want to go through a
hypothetical pathway so that we know
what kinds of enzymes we're looking for
um and so as I mentioned earlier they
derived from plant steriles I'm showing
here campesterol which is an abundant
sterile in plant membranes um and the
very first step um has for a long time
thought to be the CLE
of this carbon side chain um to produce
the first intermediate in cardiac lco
biosynthesis
prone uh and this enzyme has been known
for a long time in animals it's
catalyzed um by a cytochrome
p450 uh but when I started this research
it was not known in Plants
um and the next couple steps involve the
formation of this pregnan scaffold that
cardiac glycosides are built on um and
this involves a series of oxidation
reduction and isomerization steps um
these types of reactions are mostly
catalyzed by a group of enzymes called
short chain dehydrogenase reductases
they're pretty well characterized in
animals less so in Plants um although
there is a substantial amount that is
known so there were some obvious
candidates going in um the oxidation of
this hydroxy group to a ketone likely
catalyzed by a three beta hydroxy
steroid
dehydrogenase um the isomerization of
this double bond from here to here
likely catalyzed by a three ketosteroid
isomerase in animals these two reactions
would be catalyzed by the same enzyme
it's not clear that that's happening in
Plants um more on that
later uh next the stereo specific
reduction of this double bond um with an
enzyme called a progesterone 5 beta
reductase um such that this hydrogen is
pointing out of the fa page which is a
little hard to see here
um and then the reduction of this Ketone
back to a hydroxy group potentially by
the same enzyme that catalyzed this um
earlier reaction
here next we have a series of two Hydrox
Elations um at two specific positions
one at this 14 position here and then
another Hydrox silation at this 21
position um and no enzymes when I
started were hypothesized to catalyze
either of these reactions um this 14
beta Hydrox silation in particular is
not a very common position for for
steril to be Hydrox and so that one is
of some
interest um finally we need to form the
lactone ring um it's been hypothesized
that this occurs through transfer of a
malinal group
um and then cyclisation which might be
spontaneous or might involve the
activity of some kind of cyclace and
then we have a bunch of enzymes that are
modifying the end products through
glycosilation Hydrox isolation that sort
of
thing all right so next I'm going to
talk about some of the strategies we
used to identify candidates um for
cardiac lco
biosynthesis and I want to point out
again here to people who did a lot of
this work um um Marty who's here today
and also mia Who collected a lot of the
data and and um did a lot of the work
that my work was built off of um so one
of the approaches was a philogenetic
approach looking for enzymes or genes
that were duplicated in arism cyanides
it might have been new genetic material
that the plant was able to use um for
this new pathway also looked at
correlation between transcript abundance
and metabolites across a bunch of
different tissues and
treatments um did some Gene coexpression
so looking for uh gen that are all
expressed together in the same tissues
under the same conditions with the idea
that uh if they're all involved in the
same metabolic pathway it's likely all
happening um in the same tissues or
under the same conditions and finally um
mutant screens using chemical
mutagenesis um I again want to point out
that I did not actually do any of the
mutant screens M Maria did one round of
screens and then Marty did another round
of screens um that resulted in some
really good
candidates and once we had these
candidates uh we characterized them
using a number of different approaches
one was knocking them out using crisper
cast 9 and observing any potential
cardenolide related phenotype um another
one was transient expression in
osiana um to hopefully reassemble the
pathway um either partially or in full
um and also in vitro assays with
purified recombinant enzymes
um and so the gene coexpression
networking was one approach that um was
very fruitful in identifying
candidates uh so we first tried doing
this across tissues of arism
chantho and um kind of surprisingly we
actually didn't find anything with that
there were no modules of coexpress genes
that seemed like they might be involved
in the formation of a steroid like
molecule um and so I turned to another
source of variation um that was
available to me which was the the 48
different species of arsum that tis had
worked with that I mentioned earlier
that we had collected RNA seek data for
for the purpose of building the
philogyny but we also had it that and I
was able to use that to build a
coexpression network of genes across the
entire genus or at least the the species
that were included here um and that did
yield some pretty good results there was
this module of co-expressed genes um
nine of which were involved in the core
steroid biosynthesis pathway um shown in
blue and then there were a number of
other genes that were good candidates
for involvement in cardiac glycoside
biosynthesis um some of which were
annotated as being potentially steroid
related but they haven't been
characterized yet um that included a
glycal transferase two cytochrome p450s
um and then two hydroxy steroid
dehydrogenases um and then there were
another there were a number of other
metabolic enzymes that potentially had
roles in some of the other steps that I
talked about so one of those cyoc p450s
was CP 87a
126 um and when I expressed it in niosi
um I observed the formation of this
compound here called prone which
is um the product of the sterile side
chain cleavage that I discussed earlier
um so it seems like this enzyme is Catal
izing this reaction a few other groups
actually simultaneously found the enzyme
from other species um and they did some
more in-depth characterization showing
that those enzymes are capable of using
a number of different sterile substrates
including campesterol and cholesterol um
to produce
pralo and so I knocked this out um
actually Marty made this knockout um it
was one of the first ones we made in
arism and um in the two independent
knockout lines this is total cardenolide
related Peak area saw pretty much
complete knockout of cardiac glycoside
accumulation and because we were
perturbing um this one important defense
we wanted to look at the glucosinolates
as well um so we checked those and the
glucosinolates were completely unchanged
so it didn't seem like there was
substantial uh cross talker feedback
going on
there um and so this is exciting because
we learned more about the biosynthesis
but this also gives us a really useful
tool for understanding what role uh
these compounds are playing in an
ecological
context and so the first thing I did U
was with the help of anoro and Amy um I
did a sodium potassium hbas inhibition
assay so as I mentioned earlier um
cardiac glycosides um specifically
Target sodium pottassium atpases and
inhibit them in animal cells so they've
developed a um an invitro assay that
allows us to test plant extracts for how
much they inhibit sodium pottassium
hes and so what I'm showing here on the
left are the um inhibition curves from
that with wild type um arism in Black
here um and so farther left is more
inhibitory activity and then as a
cardenolide free control um we used
arabidopsis so in theory we shouldn't
see any any inhibition with that
although at high concentrations of plant
extract the um we do see some inhibition
but not exactly sure what's going on
with that but what was clear was that
the two knockout lines in one case it
was maybe there was maybe some residual
inhibitory activity but for the most
part it was on par with cardenolide free
um
arabidopsis which is exciting um and so
from there I moved on to testing the
response of some insect herbivores um
to The Knockout lines compared with uh
wild Ty
and so for these experiments in the lab
I used four different insects two of
them were broad generalists meaning that
they happily feed on a bunch of
different plant species um
and they're likely not specifically
adapted to glucosinolates like I
mentioned earlier and so these two uh
insects were the Cabbage Looper and the
green peach aphid and then I also use
two of The Specialist herbivores that I
talked about earlier that specifically
seek out um plants in the brass of Casey
to feed on and this is the Cabbage
butterfly and the Cabbage
Eid and so for each of these insects I
did two assays uh one of them was a
choice assay where I put them either in
a Petri dish with a wild type leaf and a
mutant leaf and I let them make a choice
about which they preferred to feed on
over the course of you know one or two
days um and then recorded their choice
at the
end uh the exception to this was for the
Cabbage butterfly where I
um didn't overos Choice assay I put a
gravid female in a cage with one wild
type one mutant plant and allowed her to
lay eggs on uh the plants and then
counted where she laid the eggs at the
end and then the other kind of assay I
did was a growth assay where I bagged um
insects on to to plants so they were
either restricted only to Wild type or
only to the cardenolide free mutant
plants and observed their growth over a
period of a week or
two uh and what I found was that the
generalist insects um in some cases
showed a slight preference for the
mutant lines but in general they were
able to perform at least okay on both
lines so for for the green peach
aphid um there was maybe a slight Trend
that they preferred the mutant lines um
but overall wasn't significant and then
for a colony growth where I just put
five apids on the plants and counted how
many there were after two weeks um there
was absolutely no difference between the
two
lines um things were a little more clear
for the Cabbage Looper um so there was a
very clear preference for the
cardenolide free mutant plants if they
were given a choice um but if they were
restricted to plant um there was maybe a
slight growth Advantage if they didn't
have the cardiac lides um but they were
generally able to perform okay um even
in the presence of cardiac glycosides
oh
those text does not look very good
there
um but uh with the two Specialists they
appeared to be far more impacted by
cardiac
glycosides and so for
the Cabbage aphid um there was again a
clear preference for the two Mutant
lines and um for Colony growth there was
a very drastic difference
the aphids I put on wild type plants
were not able to reproduce at all most
of them died in a few cases there was
one or two aphids still alive at the end
of the week um but they were able to
happily establish colonies on the the
cardenal free mutant lines um saw
something similar for the Cabbage
butterfly um where they almost never
laid eggs on the cardolite producing
wild type plants um and they completely
refused to feed even if that was their
only option um on the cardal producing
plants but they happily began feeding on
the um knockout lines I will not I used
uh refused to feed or began feeding
because most of them did still die on
the mutants uh but a few of them reached
pupation and made it to adulthood um so
they were able to complete their life
cycle on on the mutant plants which was
exciting um and so I wanted to take this
one step further and I planted them out
in the field this past summer I'm not
going to go too much into the design but
I had wild type plants and um The
Knockout plants in the field I visited a
couple times and just recorded what I
observed on each
plant um and so at the end of the
experiment these are the most common
visitors with the number of observations
at the bottom by far the most common
insect that I saw was this striped flea
Beetle um which is a crucifer specialist
and it did not seem to care at least in
terms of how often it occurred on any
individual plant it didn't seem to care
about cardiac glycosides at
all um and then the turnup aphid which
is another crucifer specialist uh I saw
a lot of them but that's really because
there were a few colonies that were
really quite well established so I can't
really draw any conclusions from that um
I also saw a good number of
snails as well as a lot of spiders um
that were
not eating the plants but they were
building their webs and living uh in the
plants
I also want to give an honorable mention
to the wood Shu that managed to just
completely chop down 22 of the
plants uh and they also did not care
about cardiac lydes probably because
they weren't actually even eating it
they were just I don't I honestly don't
know what they're doing
um so but for two of them I did get two
EX in results the Cabbage butterfly like
we saw in lab really doesn't like laying
eggs on cardenal producing plants
because it knows well I don't know if it
knows but it the the larvae won't feed
on it so it's a good idea not to lay
eggs on
them um and then the snails also which I
was not expecting were more commonly
observed on The Knockout plants I didn't
do anything like measuring Leaf area
eaten by snails or anything but the fact
that they were um almost twice as likely
to be found on the cardal knockouts
suest that they're doing most of their
feeding um on The Knockout
points all right so that was all I had
on the insect side and so now back to
the chemistry and searching for enzymes
that are involved in this pathway um so
I talked before about this scaffold
formation step that involves a series of
different enzymes that catalyze Redux
reactions on the steroid core
um and this
isomerization and there were two good
candidates in the co-expression
cluster uh to catalyze these kinds of
reactions the two hydroxy steroid
dehydrogenase uh
genes
and then um there were also some EMS
mutants that showed promise here one
that Marty found one that Mia found um
and
so with those three enzymes uh which are
marked here about whether they were
found from an EMS mutant that's the
chemical uh mutagenesis or the
co-expression cluster in one case the
three beta hydroxy dehydrogenase was
found using both um
approaches um but I used inv vitro assay
with purified recombinant enzymes to
confirm that they at least possess the
activity shown here in um in
vitro and so especially with this three
beta hydroxy steroid dehydrogenase it's
kind of unsurprising that able to
catalyze this reaction the the oxidation
of this hydroxy group to a ketone um and
in vitro I did see some apparent
isomerization along with the
oxidation um but at this point I'm it's
not clear to me whether that's happening
spontaneously um or whether that's
actually activity that is catalyzed by
the enzyme so if I feed this ISO
progesterone here to the three beta
hydroxy steroid dehydrogenase I see
really very little isomerization but
with this other enzyme three which I am
calling a three ketosteroid isomerase um
we see very good isomerization of the
iso progesterone to the progesterone so
it seems like these two enzymes are
working together to produce progesterone
which is in contrast to animals where
there's usually a single enzyme that
catalyzes both of these steps um I think
in bacteria It's also two separate
enzymes kind of interesting there um
there was one report actually of a three
beta hydroxy steroid dehydrogenase from
plants that is able catalyze both of
these reactions but I'm still not quite
convinced it seems like with um some
potential spontaneous isomerization
there that uh careful attention needs to
be paid to that to to really
definitively talk about that enzymatic
activity and then this progesterone five
beta reductase catalyzes the five beta
reduction of progesterone um
unsurprisingly and then the three beta
hydroxy steroid dehydrogenase which is
the same enzyme over here at least in
vitro is able to catalyze the reverse
reaction the reduction of this Ketone
back to the hydroxy group um whether or
not that's happening in planta I'm not
sure at this point um there was actually
another enzyme in the co-expression
cluster that caught my eye and this was
a steroid 5 Alpha reductase which
catalyzes the same reaction as the five
beta reductase but with inverted
stereochemistry so you can see the
product of this the hydrogen here is
pointing out of the page and here it's
pointing into the page um and this
enzyme is called deated 2 um or de 2 uh
it's fairly well characterized from
arabidopsis because it is involved in
brass steroid biosynthesis um and so
mutants to this enzyme are deficient in
brass steroids and they are dphs um and
it seems like this enzyme in addition to
catalyzing the analogous reaction in
brass and steroid biosynthesis is
capable of using progesterone as a
substrate um to potentially produce
these five Alpha intermediates which
might lead to the production of
um cardiac glycosides with altered
stereochemistry at this position and
that might not seem like a big deal but
um if we draw the compounds in kind of a
different way to give you more of an
idea about the 3D structure of the
molecules um it does actually make a
substantial difference in terms of the
overall shape of the the cardiac lcoes
so in the 5 Alpha configuration here the
fused rings are relatively flat with
each other um whereas with the five beta
cardenolides um there's this kind of
Kink that's introduced um at the final
ring so with the knockout mutants we can
start to see um that these uh the
presence or absence of some of these
enzymes might be controlling
the overall configuration of the cardiac
glycosides that the plants produce so in
Wild type plants when all the enzymes
that I discussed are present um we see
production of these five beta
cardenolides
here which is represented here um with
each cardal colorcoded with um as in
terms of the overall Peak area on the
mass
spec so wild type we pretty much only
see five beta card analyed oh and I have
the little configuration down there to
show you that it is
different um but the pathway mutants we
see the accumulation of atypical
cardenolides that we don't usually see
in Wild type plants so if we knock out
the three beta hydroxysteroid
dehydrogen dehydrogenase um we get
these cardiac glycosides that are still
reduced at the same position as this
prone intermediate so it seems like the
pathway enzymes are using intermediate
that accumulates in this mutant line to
produce cardiac glycosides with altered
um reduction at the steroid
core we see something pretty similar if
we knock out the ketosteroid
isomerase um where we see accumulation
of these Delta 5 cardenolides
um if we knock out the progesterone 5
beta reductase we see a complete loss of
the five beta cardenolides um and the
accumulation of five Alpha cardal with
inverted stereochemistry at that
position and then if we knock out the
five Alpha reduct a. two we get these
tiny little mutant plants um they're
yeah you can barely even see them here
these plants are the same age um
and the Cardinal profile is relatively
unchanged um which is perhaps
unsurprising because we don't usually
see five Alpha cardenolides um in arism
Kor
but if we knock out both d 2 and
progesterone 5 vuas we completely lose
or almost completely lose cardiac
glycosides that are fully reduced in
their steroid core um and instead end up
with the a mix of Delta four and Delta 5
cardenolides with the double bond at
different positions
there um and
so uh with these mutants it became
obvious that it was relatively easy to
change uh the end products of the
pathway just through the activity of a
single enzyme in the middle of the
pathway um and we looked at some of the
variation in the sequence and expression
of these enzymes across the genus um and
saw some amount of correlation
especially with this progesterone five
beta reductase um in terms of when it's
expressed we get five beta cardenolides
when it's not expressed we do see the
accumulation of some five Alpha
cardenolides in certain species um I
don't have time to go in depth about
that now we did just upload a pre-print
by archive if you are interested in
learning more about
that all
right for the last part of my talk um I
want
to discuss the two
hydroxylases that are acting on cardenal
intermediates uh so if we go back to the
coexpression cluster one last
time uh there are some two oxylate
dioxygenases that were coexpressed with
other cardiac glycoside biosynthesis
enzymes um two oxylate dioxygenases are
pretty abundant um type of gene in
plants and they uh mostly catalyze the
addition of hydroxy group or otherwise
oxidized um small molecules and are
often involved in specialized metabolic
pathways uh one of them is this aop1
like
uh
enzyme so aop1 aop means alkenol hydroxy
alal producing it's known from
arabidopsis and it the so aop2 aop1 the
function actually isn't known but aop2
and aop3 which are closely related um
are involved in glucosinolate
biosynthesis so it's kind of interesting
that there would be this close relative
of these glucosinolate genes um
coexpressed with the um cardiac
glycoside biosynthesis genes and then
not in this iteration of the
co-expression cluster but in a slightly
modified one with different parameters I
also saw another two oxylate
dioxygenase um which is a duplicate of
dioxygenase for oxin oxidation one and
this is an enzyme that is involved in
oxin homeostasis it oxidatively
deactivates oxin um and there are two
copies in arabidopsis but one of them
has been duplicated an additional time
in orison and that one is coexpressed
with cardiac glycoside biosynthesis
genes uh so I knocked both of them out
and they both are deficient in cardiac
glycoside biosynthesis which is exciting
um suggesting that maybe they're
catalyzing these two successive Hydrox
Elations um the aop1 like was pretty
much undetectable levels of cardiac
glycosides Dow one like uh I could
detect cardiac gdes but there was about
a hundredfold reduction in total
abundance of the comp
so it's exciting to have these mutants
but what I really want to know is what
these enzymes are actually doing so for
one thing what order they're acting in
and for another the position of Hydrox
silation catalyzed by each of these
enzymes um and so the mutants do give a
little bit of a clue to that in the aop1
like Knockouts some of these earlier
intermediates in um cardol biosynthesis
accumulate to higher levels than we see
in Wild type suggesting that maybe this
one is acting directly on those
intermediates and might be the first
hydroxy and then in the Dow one like
Knockouts um we see really high levels
of
accumulation of an
apparently I guess dihydroxy
intermediate suggesting that it might be
the um second enzyme to act in the
pathway and these intermediates are also
glycosilated which is why we see several
different Peaks corresponding um to this
Mass
um another clue that the
um that these mutants can give me is
through feeding up substrates to the
mutants to see if we can restore cardiac
glycoside
biosynthesis um and so most of these
intermediates are not commercially
available or I wasn't able to find them
but one somewhat similar compound this
21 Hydro hydroxy progesterone was
available um so the only difference
between progesterone here and the 21
hydroxy progesterone is this hydroxy
group here um which is required in
cardiac gide biosynthesis so shown here
at the bottom um is the wild type um
chromatogram of um a mass that is
commonly associated with a bunch of
different cardiac
glycosides and so I'm kind of using
these Peaks just to show you know we are
seeing the cardal Peaks or we're not and
so in Wild type we see a bunch of
different Peaks um and in the aop1 like
knockouts um whether I feed it
progesterone or 21 Hydro hydroxy
progesterone this was uh infiltration
with a syringe into the leaves um after
24 hours we still don't see any cardiac
glycosides but in the da one like
mutants if I feed progesterone I don't
see much of anything but with 21 Hy
hydroxy progesterone we do see those
cardiac glycoside Peaks reappear um so
this is pretty decent evidence that the
da one like enzyme is required for 21
Hydrox um I also took these enzymes and
well I expressed them in osiana and
co-infiltrated some substrates to see if
they were active um on the cardolite
intermediates and the aop1 like enzyme I
found readily hydroxylates pretty oh
pretty much any cardenolide intermediate
I'll throw at it it doesn't really seem
to care what's going on down at this
part of the molecule um
and I am showing the hydroxy group at
the 14 position although I don't have
super great evidence that that's what's
happening um in addition to the other
enzyme maybe catalyzing the 21 Hydrox
ilation so by process of elimination
this one would be the 14 hydroxy uh this
compound right here has been reported in
some plants just to accumulate to high
levels so in this paniculate swallow
wart which is used in Chinese medicine
um this compound accumulates and when I
feed aop1 like with prone here I see a
peak with this mass that is also present
in paniculate swallow wart um so that's
maybe some more evidence that it's the
14 hydroxylase um although it would
require additional uh
confirmation uh to be really sure about
it and then uh if I coexpress both aop1
and DOW one like um and at some of these
intermediates I do see that da one like
seems to consume whatever is made by
aop1 like uh and
produces new intermediates that don't
have quite the mass that I would expect
for one thing they seem to be
glycosilated this is likely happening uh
by um endogenous enzymes in the
kosana uh which is one of the problems
with trying to rebuild the system in N
kosana is that we have some potentially
promiscuous activity of nios benthamiana
enzymes um but that's not really what
I'm worried about what I'm more worried
about is that the mass of these
compounds actually correlates with the
addition of this um potentially an alahh
right there so we're missing two
hydrogens compared to what I would have
expected if it was a
hydroxy um and so maybe these
intermediates are involved maybe this is
something else weird that's going on in
kosana um I don't know I also don't even
know that these structures are correct
um but it's definitely active um which
is
exciting uh all right so I do now want
to talk more about I think both of these
enzymes are kind of interesting
evolutionary
stories in terms of looking at Gene
duplication and how plants evolve new uh
metabolic pathways and so as I mentioned
earlier Dow one um there is duplicated
an ARIS relative to other related plants
so here we have the rice um Dow as the
out group and then these are all a bunch
of other brassas so that's chamina utria
Brasa um in general in brassic Casey
there are two main clades Dow one and
DOW two and then in arism there's
seemingly anisum specific duplication
here with uh presumably this 1G
2032 um maintaining the ancestral
function of Dow one in Oxy oxin
homeostasis um and this 1G 20322 which
is the D1 like enzyme that potentially
is taken on a new role um and so if we
look at micro syntony between the the
um lowai containing these enzymes in a
rabid opsis here on the top in arism so
in a rabid opsis Dow one and dow2 are a
t duplication and then in orisome um
there's just an additional tandem
duplicate of uh
Dow one that has seemingly taken on a
new role in cardenolide
biosynthesis I'm not showing it here but
um we're working with a collaborator
Cynthia Holland at Williams College who
just right before my seminar sent me
some exciting uh modeling results uh
that are helping us understand which um
changes to to amino acid residues in the
active site um might have contributed to
this pretty substantial shift in
substrate preference from this small
oxin molecule here to the larger pregn
intermediates in cardiac gly
biosynthesis so aop1 um is a little bit
more complicated in that in
arabidopsis we have aop2 and aop3 which
are involved in glucosinolate
biosynthesis and then aop1 here which
does not have a known function relative
to the one copy of aop1 in arabidopsis
there are five inimum um that are
scattered across
a few different Lite on chromosomes
three and two
um and it is this one over here 3G 34150
that seems to have taken on a new role
in cardiac glycoside biosynthesis I also
think some of these other enzymes um I
didn't mention but some of them are also
coexpressed in the in the coexpression
cluster I showed earlier so it seems
like some of them might also be involved
um potentially in modification of
cardiac ldes and I think they're good
candidates for further study
study um and so that also leaves open
the question of what about the rest of
the pathway um and the answer is I don't
know I cloned a ton of genes and um
didn't see really any activity in N
kosana for a lot of them although part
of this might be the fact that we're
seeing um modification of the
intermediates in nikosi by endogenous
enzymes that might be interfering with
the activity of some of the later
enzymes
um there is a asil transfer a malal
transfer that seems like a really good
candidate in the co-expression cluster
but I haven't seen any activity um when
I've tried to clone it so I don't know
what's going on there there are also
some good candidates for glycosilation
and Hydrox silation that I won't discuss
further um so that's all the science I
have but I do want to think uh
acknowledge all my friends
H who uh really made School great and my
girlfriend who also made grad school
great uh
and uh also my family Oop There They Are
Who many of whom came to see me
today um and then also of course all the
people who were involved in my uh
PhD who uh you know taught me different
techniques advised me in various ways
collaborated on various products
projects um these five people up here uh
are well Mia I talked about a lot
earlier as as well as Marty um but Toby
Anamaria and Julia are undergrads who
worked on arism with me as well and did
some really great and exciting work um
and contributed in really important
ways um also of course want to
acknowledge my funding sources and my
committee uh who are always ready with
good advice um and guidance I'd be happy
to take any questions
yeah so it like a lot of your insects
weren't feeding on the with parales on
them they were choosing not to do you
have any ideas about the mechanisms that
might underly
that like how are they KN yeah um so the
the Cabbage butterfly in particular are
interesting because they just as far as
I can tell when I watched them they
would land on it and then just fly away
and they wouldn't it I mean I don't know
maybe they're scraping their osit on it
or something um but it seems like yeah
there there has to be some kind of a
recognition mechanism even without
feeding for them so on their tari they
they probably have some sort of receptor
and then they are bitter I believe I
have not tried them um but in terms of I
I think they they'll feed on it and then
it it just tastes bad
maybe
yeah
yeah the involvement of dt2
card I'm wondering if you know or
hypothesize anything about any potential
cross talk between brass and cardiac
cardiac like do you think like if you
appli you think you've seen induction
of production
or yeah I think that's an interesting
question in particular I mean they're
using the same precursors as well so you
can imagine especially in the The
Knockout lines where were I knocked out
cardiac gide biosynthesis which was like
a huge sync for for sterols so maybe the
accumulation of those might have led to
differences in brass and steroid
biosynthesis I didn't see anything with
that and I do know at Cynthia who I
mentioned earlier did some
experiments um with growing arism on
plates with brassin steroids and I don't
think she saw anything um one
interesting thing what oh there were
more of them with the brass steroids so
oh okay cool there you go did you do
some of those experiments too okay
anyway uh yeah apparently I don't know
but uh I was going to say something else
oh yeah another interesting thing so in
risum chirines there's only the one copy
of Deb 2 which it seemed maybe a little
surprising that it could be active in
cardiac gide biosynthesis but then it's
also involved in in brasin steroid
biosynthesis um there are other species
of arism that do produce the five Alpha
cardenolides and I don't know in some of
those species whether they might have a
dedicated copy of De 2 that could be you
know regulated or have different
activity um compared to the de two
that's involved in brass and Stor bios
synthesis but yeah a good good
question yeah I guess I was wondering so
um in the plants that make the five
Alpha card lights or the like Delta four
Delta 5 CES do you do you think that
those have like different effects on
sodium potassium etpa or like I guess
when we were looking at Mia's mutant it
like it was more toxic to the insects
despite having lower abundance of
cardinales like do you think that like
like what do you think this is doing to
the insects if they have I guess these
are mutants but what yeah yeah I think
that it is there's definitely potential
there for differences I mean it's
definitely known that I think the five
beta C analy are generally thought to be
more
toxic uh although I've Maybe seen some
conflicting things with that and I don't
want to speculate too much without
knowing uh for sure one thing about so
what Marty alluded to was with the
progesterone 5 beta reductase mutant
that Mia made it was a one the
chemically mutagenized line she
tested uh insect growth and she
generally
saw better growth on the
mutants no they grew worse on the
mutants anyway there was a conflict
between what she saw in the mutant line
or when she was doing insect feeding and
when she was doing the the sodium
potassium inhibition assay um and so
there's also potential there for
different for different herbivores like
some herbivores the five Alpha Cales
might be more effective against some the
F beta might be more effective against
um and then another thing with that
mutant was the Hydrox silation was
completely gone um and so the that can
affect the polarity of the cardenales
which could also affect things like
uptake and AC ity which might explain
why we're seeing a difference between
the feeding and the invitro
assay yeah um you said for the
progesterone there's two enzymes working
and that was also seen in
bacteria yeah for yeah yes could that be
like horizontal transfer you look at the
sequences or do you think it's just
converging I don't think it's horizontal
transfer no um I did look at the
sequences um I mean there are there are
homologous enzymes in animals of the
what as far as I can tell only has the
ketosteroid isomerase activity um and I
couldn't
find I couldn't find a lot of
information about what those enzymes are
doing in animals so I think there's a
lot to be done I think what I did did
um still leaves a lot of questions open
um but I don't think it was horizontal
gen transfer
now so I think we're out of the time
let's thank for one more time
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu