this is a production of Cornell
University hey yeah so I work with um
John Luke Yanik and Virginia Moore on
two different intercropping projects um
and intercropping is just when you grow
two species together in the same time or
space and there's um some cool benefits
of intercropping um that have been
described in literature including
increased biodiversity and environmental
service capacity of a system um reduce
Pest and disease you spread the risk um
of like natural disasters and still
getting some kind of yield um there's
the potential for Niche differentiation
and um the compatibility facilitation
effects but um for these to work there's
a need for a lot of agronomic in
Innovations including um planting and
harvesting processing those types of
things and it also presents a novel
environment to breed for breed for since
um the species must perform well with
another species in the system and um not
just by itself um so we may need to look
at both genotypes when we're breeding
for these
systems um so intercropping two species
together that can be a cover crop with
cash crop or it can be like what I'm
working on with two different cach crops
together and they can be configured in
different ways like in mixtures think
about like broadcasting just um
different species of seeds they can be
in alleys with um one crop between rows
of trees in rows or in strips and the
way I'm doing it with the intermediate
we grass Alfalfa is alternating rows and
with the oats and peas with um John
Luke's lab it's mixed within Rose so the
oats and peas are together in the Rose
as you can see in the picture and um
some of the preliminary results I'm
going to show today are for the oats and
PE project um but I did want to bring up
the intermediate we grass alphalpha
intercrop um because it's pretty cool as
well and it's also a dual use system so
you can um the farmer has the option at
least a little more option on the
markets that they go to where you can
Harvest for grain and
forage um yeah so this o1p project
included 48 different oat accessions and
12 different p accessions and that's
over 500 different combinations if we're
evaluating um them in inner crop so
they're spread across six different
locations
um where each possible combination is
represented at least in one of these
locations and um we had two different
types of peas the forage
which is this coming up on the screen no
okay so the the forage is on the far um
an example the forage is on the far side
and then a field or grain type P is the
one in the middle um you did this
there's like a difference in morphology
um where the field type has a lot more
Leaf area it tends to be taller and the
grain type is um more Compact and has
more of its tendrils so this the idea is
that these difference in morphology um
could maybe have an influence um in the
competitive interactions in an inner
crop and um yeah so this year from New
York here's kind of some box plots of
what the biomass looked like when we
sampled at four different time points
throughout the season and um we found
that the oat biomass in a plot was a lot
higher than what we got for the biomass
of the peas but that there's no
difference between um the O biomass on
whether it's with a field P or Forge P
or even in the monoculture plots that we
did um where I guess I should explain
that a little bit it's like there's this
intercrop with a specific oat accession
and a specific PE accession and then
right next to it we had that same oat
planted in a monoculture um so what we
found is no preliminary at least um that
that interaction for biomass was not
significant um and then for grain yield
I used mixed linear models and did find
that certain genotypes were significant
covariant for both the oat the p and the
total yield of the plot um I do need to
do more analysis on this but it
indicates that there are differences in
intercrop um
compatibility um to evaluate how
genotypes perform with any genotype of
the other species we look at the general
mixing ability and for this I use beian
generalized linear regression um which
is a multivariant with a multivariant
model um so I can look at the both the
outcome of the oat yield and the PE
yield with um multiple sources of
variation from um location block within
year and location and the hood accession
the p accession and then year by itself
um so what we're seeing here is in the
top one it's the oat genotype on the
x-axis that genotype effect on that oats
yield and then the P that it's with any
of the P that it's with um is on the Y
AIS um so in Orange we see that there
are some oat genotypes that have a
positive effect um on positive effect on
the both the oat and the PE yield in
that plot and the same we see that there
are some that for p genotypes doing the
same thing
um I was also curious on the competitive
interaction between the specific oats
gen oat excession and P excession so um
here what I did was looked at um that
oat in crop and the monoculture right
beside it for Oat yield and found that
some combinations the oat yield was
higher in inner crop than it was in the
monoculture rided and then some
combinations that oat um had a lower
yield than it was in the in crop um
again showing that there are differences
um in these
compatibilities um so the these plots
are the um specific combinations from
Illinois and New York so that's why not
every combination is shown as a color
here um not every location had these
monocultures to compare um but yeah the
the reds are like the the more red it is
the lower the oat yield in intercrop was
and compared to its monoculture and then
greens are where the in crop oat yield
was higher than its
monoculture um comparing this to like
these General um General mixing ability
idea saw that there are PS like Maxum
where no matter what it's with it has um
a negative effect on that oat yield um
and there's some also that are are at
least more positive um so excited to
work more on this and um
acknowledgements I am very thankful to
be in two great Labs with John Luke and
Jenny um our field crew for this o and
PE project is Peter Hyde Mir is doing um
very similar work with winter oats and
peas and we have a great undergrad um
Adrien who's been with us for a couple
Summers now um I also got great feedback
on this um from joint lab meetings with
the Soros lab so thank you for that um
and get a lot of field help from their
field crew of David and Jason um the
Odin P project has a lot of
collaborators with um Patrick hu at the
USDA Vermont Martin wolf at University
of Alabama Juan David Alvarez at
Illinois um CZ Chone at University of
Wisconsin C mili in Minnesota and melan
Cafe at South Dakota um and then the
more lab our field crew is um jly Hansen
Jamie and Ryan Crawford and Jesse Chavez
um and that Al Alfa intermediate project
is funded by the AL Alpa and Forge
research program and um part of that
project was done um previously by
someone who
graduated um with their masters in 2024
Megan Williams and we have collaborators
listed for there as well
thanks any are there any environmental
uh predictors of these
compatibilities um are there any
environmental factors for the
compatibility I haven't looked into that
yet I do need to calculate genotype I
environmental factors and um we can get
like climate data but we haven't yet so
those are future things
thanks um I was wondering for like the
one variety where you saw it just kind
of decreased the O yield across the
board are you interested in looking
further to try and figure out why like
that's variety is decreasing the yield
or this kind of outside the scope of
your
research um yeah so I showed that the
one P Max on P had an overall like
negative effect on whatever oat it was
with um and so am I interested in why
that might be um not right now
um maybe I'm still I'm still figuring
out where I'm going with my thesis work
so um yeah more interested
in more General like interactions but
yeah totally um it is it looks like a
forage type but I didn't see any like
difference between like forage and field
so not quite sure what that morphology
or what that
is yeah like what other phenotypes um
are we looking at we um took height
measurements and um emergence counts and
maturity um notes as well and then Peter
hide also flies a drone um quite
frequently so um we have multispectral
data that I'm not working with but we'll
have that to compare as well so good
afternoon
everyone so can you hear me good
afternoon everyone my name is BR ConEd
and I'm with the backa lab this
afternoon I'll be talking about
exploring tradeoffs between cold and D
tolerance in trypto
loides and so we picked these two
stresses because drought has been known
to be one of the single most limiting
factor affecting maze production in the
US and then also by building Frost
resilience crops we'll be able to
improve um yields by 10% and also reduce
our Reliance on nitrogen by
20% and then based on Research there are
some similar shed Pathways between these
two stresses but then there's still a
knowledge gap between the tradeoffs and
then the synergies that exist between
these two stresses and that is where
this research comes in
and so it got me thinking about how
certain maze relatives are able to adapt
to these two stresses whilst maze
doesn't have that flexibility and so I
was thinking could it be that they
possess certain specific genetic and
physiological adaptations or it could be
due to
modifications that helps them to um
better Express their genes or their
metabolic pathways or their genomic
structure
and then we settled I settled on
tripsacum because it is it's been known
to be the closest peral relative of maze
with frost tolerance and then
evolutionists believe that about 500,000
years ago Maze and tracom diverged from
each other leading to some lots of
functions in in maze that are still
present in tripsacum and so tripsacum
tends to serve was like a reservoir for
some good trades that could be used to
transform
Maze and so the data sets that I intend
to use to capture to test my hypothesis
include some samples of tripsacum that
were sampled by Denise cage and Nick
leak in Al lab um they were samples
across the US
and then crossed with each other to
generate f1s and then left to open
pollinates to generate
f2s and by observation we realize that
there are some of them that have that
are Frost tolerant and others that are
drought tolerant and so we have the
right population to do this work and
then also another data set that will be
involved in this study is a tripsacum
population panel from a panan project
that was conducted in collaboration with
our
lab so to test my first hypothesis I
have eight high-fi long G assemblies
that I'll be assembling to create a PhD
after which I would use that PhD to
impute on hundreds of tripom samples
from the panan project and by doing that
I intend to perform an environmental G
study to identify some drought and cod
plusi and then also use a DNA language
model to identify some causal
variance so my eight genotypes that I
selected I tried as much as possible to
capture enough
diversity within um the population that
we the populations that we have and so I
used this MDS plot and then selected My
AG genotypes and so I have my Hi-Fi long
GRE now that I am currently
assembling and for my next um hypothesis
test on the comparative expression
analysis of hold and drought myself
together with um Lara bindes who is a
postdoc in our lab I've been screening
tripsacum and the cold and the cold and
so what we we've been doing is to have
some batches that are cold acclimated
firstest that is we move them after
planting them we move them to the cold
chamber at 10° Celsius during the day
and then 6° Celsius during the night
after which they are moved to the
freezer at minus 6 deges and during this
time points we sample um tissue for RNA
sequencing and then the non-cold
acclimation batch we just moved planted
them in the greenhouse and then move
them straight to the freezer and also do
tissue collection at these time
points another cool thing that I also
did together with my Pi this summer was
to harvest um tripsacum and so if you've
ever worked with tripsacum you would
know that it's very tedious to do they
tend to shatter and lose their seeds on
on the field so if you want to um get
enough Harvest from your seed you would
have to try 1 me that end up being
extremely tedious so we tried out this
protocol whereby we cut the head some um
tripsacum seed heads together with the
connes and then repl them in Mason jaar
filled with
water and so initially we were very
skeptical about this because we didn't
know if it was going to affect the
viability of the seeds
and so far so good we realized that
after performing our germination test
when you DEH hold the seat you have
about
54% um seats germinating however the on
the whole SE T to have like lower
germination germination rates which is
pretty cool especially for
triple and so for my next step I the
seeds that we obtained from this um
summer summer seed Harvest will be used
to set up my ad tolerance experiments
which will be conducted in the bti
phenotyping
facility yep and so that brings me to
the end of my presentation I would
however like to thank the bua lab
for assisting me during this research I
have bagged a whole lot of people and I
would like to thank them specifically
for that because I'm I'm not even done
with that and then also I also like to
thank my committee members for providing
insights into this research and then
also my funding sources the slum
foundation for supporting my doctoral
journey and then the usds for supporting
this
project thank
you
yes
I'm your set of relation can you explain
why that specific U reading team the
process
Chosen and
maybe um okay so with
Crossing I said that there were some
that were drought tolerant and then
there are some that were freezing
tolerance and so by Crossing you end up
um Crossing some some of these traits
together and so moving on to um the F2
Generation you would have these Straits
segregating within the population and so
yeah that is why we have the F2 and then
the f1's population you're
welome um so I saw you collected a lot
of your samples from like lower
latitudes in the US you find that they
grow a bit differently or a bit less um
when they're put up here in New York
state
um I wouldn't say they grow up
differently but then they have so I know
that the lower parts are like much more
warmer and so there are some that
collections from that side have proved
that they are F tolerance being here
under controlled
environment yeah so hi everyone yeah I'm
a third year in uh VTech plavsky lab but
um I did a rotation project with Holly
um and this is how it started so I'll
I'm actually going to be speaking about
my work with Holly but at the end I will
just warn you there's going to be an
abrupt
change I just have a couple slides about
text
work so how this study arose I feel like
it really started in my undergrad like
when we would be in the field uh for
long days and we would just talk about
anything and a lot of times we talk
about career versus family and the
challenges with that uh and then also uh
just
observing a more diverse uh graduate
student population and faculty
population it really made me wonder like
where all of the women
go
so uh then since I don't have any uh
experience with social science work or
uh just understanding
Parenthood I decided to read literature
and so the topics in bold are what
really like stood or kept standing out
um Parenthood kept standing out and then
also in literature they said that the
solution was
policy so what's missing from the
literature is that there's nothing on
this topic even in plant science in
general but for sure not plant braing
and then the studies either have women
or
men um and then also most of these
studies only have like five or eight
respondents and I was able to get 31
respondents way more than I uh
wanted and then also uh so I I
originally actually wanted to interview
the people that had left the field but
that data is either not there or it's
confidential so it made me uh realize
that I have to collect my own data so
this kind of turned into a qualitative
project and I landed on the question of
understanding how care responsibilities
and gender have shaped ATT 10ed track
faculty's academic career in FP
breedy so to go over a few
definitions I wanted to broaden only
talking about Parenthood and I asked uh
the respondents also about like Elder
Care caring for another person in their
family and also
themselves another definition I want to
go over is gender Norms so gender Norms
are the social expectation and rules
that dictate how people should behave
and express themselves based on their
gender this is usually developed during
adolescence and
um can be influenced over time and also
by
culture so to go over the process a
little bit because I'm going to assume
that most people have not done this
before uh the first step is to develop
the project and kind of figure out who I
want to interview what questions I want
to ask uh so I uh write up forms like an
interview guide uh an email that I would
send out to people and I submit all
these forms to the uh IRB for
approval uh this is also a TDS process
but once it's
approved then I can actually reach out
to the
participants and then I conduct a one
hour semi structured interview uh so
that means that I can start out with one
question and then I can ask follow-up
questions that the IRB is not aware of
so the questions or the big topics that
I asked about were like what are your
care responsibilities
uh what's like how do they affect your
work environment and were there any
policies
involved and then after I uh have the
interviews I verify that the recordings
match the transcripts and then after
that I code the transcripts with Max qda
uh which is a software to uh
systematically analyze I think it's
probably the most similar to um someone
like phenotyping for disease resistance
they come up with a standard first and
then kind of go based off of that and so
that's kind of what this is doing
here and eventually um after a few ODS
of coding I develop a code book and that
is used for
analysis and then the criteria to
participate in the study was that you
had to be a 10year track faculty uh you
had to be at an R1 University that I
selected but I'm keeping that
confidential and then you have have to
be defined as a comper by your
institution uh to reduce my
bias and then just some facts about the
participants in the study uh there were
31 participants 11 women 20 men and I
found that to be pretty uh
representative of the actual population
out there and then I interviewed
assistant associate and F
professors um and then I will say that
there were eight participants that did
not have any care responsibilities
I had to cut the slide even though it
was very interesting and then also this
is a huge part of the study uh is that
people who were like International or
foreign born they said that um it was
much more difficult um but due to time I
had to cut this slide and uh child care
and Elder Care were the most like common
care
responsibilities so to dive into like uh
some of the examples from the interview
my first which is that uh like
upbringing uh kind of shapes cultural
norms so one example is this uh
Professor who um is in Asian culture
it's very common to expect that the
Mother-in-law will come for a few months
after birth uh so he didn't even think
to take any time off or um do that so he
expected his mother-in-law and
wife and then uh this other uh Professor
both of his parents worked when he grew
up and so he expected that um his wife
would never stay home and he him and her
would also share the care
responsibilities so I'm just going to
talk about a few difficulties and then
I'm going to talk about how they coped
with those
difficulties so these were the main
difficulties that I saw within the
interviews I will only talk about
fieldwork and dual career your couples
today and give examples um fieldwork I
think is very specific to plant breeding
um because you just are so dependent on
so many other factors there's so many
collaborators and also weather um is
another big one that makes it kind of uh
difficult so to give some examples on
how uh PL breing field work and
balancing care responsibilities is
challenging when I brought this up in
the inter interviews I got lots of
comments like this is a nightmare this
is the busiest time of the year hard
just part of my job um but in this
example she said that it was very
intense and her and her husband were
both PL readers uh so they had to be out
in the field and she said that she
didn't really start uh actual field
breeding until her kids were like three
or six because it was just so
challenging but as they grew up she was
able to spend more time in the field
and then moving on to discuss a little
bit about dual career couples uh this
one PI says that when he uh says oh I
need to take care of the kids his
response is fairly positive but her
response I mean yeah she can get
criticize sometimes even though they
both actually uh try to share their
responsibilities and then I also just
want to note that I had a wide range of
uh participants that had a partner as a
stay-at-home mom all the way to like
they were also a plant reader and even
the in the relationships where they
really did strive to be equal I still
noticed that the mothers were still
handling more of the logistics and
management of the children like making
sure that they are going to the dentist
every year or um like knowing the names
of their doctors or things like
that and then moving into how these Pi
is cop I it the biggest one was mainly
family that lived close
by um and so for example this uh Pi she
really relied heavily on her parents to
take care of her child for the first
three years and she's uh is an assistant
professor and so she said I really could
not have started uh without my parents
like they helped so
much and then the other thing that uh
was the main form of support was uh just
money being able to hire uh
Nanny and so I guess as a grad student I
was surprised at how many people had
nannies especially for like three to six
years so these nannies really became
like a second mom to the children and
then daycare was another huge topic um
but in this example she said that
there's zero flexibility with drop drop
off and pickup times so uh she would
have to leave leave and if she wasn't
done with work she would have to work in
the evening which would be pretty
exhausting and then so to finish up with
this um the main points were that care
responsibilities are shaped by our
upbringing and cultural and gender norms
and then fieldwork and traveling were
the biggest
challenges um I guess I kind of forgot
to mention traveling a bit but traveling
uh both men and women I noticed that
they had to reduce uh their amount of
travel and this was even uh worse in
dual career
companies and then uh community and
financial resources were the main uh
things that helped faculty kind of
overcome these difficulties and manage
it and uh so so much so because of
literature I did ask about policy and I
had that in the interview um and not one
faculty had anything good to say about
policy so I really don't think that this
is the way to
go um I
think reasonably it it would help more
so if we adjusted our mindset and
attitude about care responsibilities in
Academia I think another thing that
would be big is um like changing our
attitude to especially towards uh using
the policies there's a lot of um
negative uh attitude towards that and
then one thing that I wish I would have
asked more so in the interviews is uh
more so about like your work environment
I think that plays a bigger role than uh
if there's policies or not and and then
also just building
community and having no support network
seem to be the most helpful for these
faculty
and now we're going to make the prep
change
so uh yeah so I am again in voytech plow
lab and so I work on double stred breaks
in recombination with
maze so uh recombination is obviously
very helpful for plant breeders it will
allow us uh like uh breeders to stack
traes or kind of break trades apart to
create new combinations of
alals and then um so Rec combination
starts with double stred breaks and it
ends in Crossovers and so as we can see
uh the Double stranded breake uh
distribution is quite uh uniform but
then crossovers mainly happen at
chromosome
ends oh I guess you can't see it but
there's roughly 200 to 500 double
stranded braks there's so many but then
only 10 to 20
crossovers myosis and so it made me
wonder if we can predict these double
stranded brakes compared to these double
stranded
Brakes in the middle of the chromosome
and so my one of my questions is can
crossover competent dsps be
distinguished from crossover incompetent
dsps and so I am looking at genomic
location
uh CG and chg DNA methylation and DNA
replication
origin uh my hypothesis is that double
stranded breaks that do result in
crossovers um have very similar
environments and so um I think that dsps
in genic regions and low methylated
areas and in early replication regions
in S phase are more likely
to um result in
crossovers so I just wanted to say a
little bit about this but I won't go
into any results or anything so I just
want to say uh thank you to Holly for
letting me do this project and also for
the participants for giving me their
time to be interviewed and uh for them
to trust me with their stories and
experiences because I think that is
really hard to do and then for voidtech
um for my trended break
project
thanks yep I was just wondering how do
you feel about your like two different
types of research that you're doing like
if there something that you like more or
less about kind of moreal research
versus what you're doing now and what
motivated that
switch um uh I guess so what motivated
the switch is I worked in industry for a
little bit in retor my undergrad in grad
school and I just felt like I like had
such a horrible experience that it kind
of pissed me off when I said I'm going
to do this project with hly and then um
I guess I forget what the first part was
but just the differences yeah but is
there something that like more about
one
um I will say with the dsb project it is
really hard to analyze chipseek
data not with uh like transcription
factors but something that occurs all
across the genome that is difficult and
then also something difficult with uh
the qualitative data is that each story
is so unique that it's just so hard to
kind of make sense of it which is why I
find Max qda really helpful so that I
can kind of Mark up the transcripts uhuh
yeah um I also just want to comment on
like kind of how poetic switch was
talking about like going from like your
work to your like life and how that
Ballance sometimes isn't balance as it
kind of was ination so I really enjoy
the fact you included both they're both
really important to you so in The Care
Project is there any sort of um Contin
thought that you have a conversation
that we can start having for now to be
able to know open the the dialogue up
for like women who want to go faulty
positions and worry about having
children and timing and like do you have
any
thoughts yeah I have thought about uh
potentially having like a discussion
here or at a conference especially with
like the generation now and the older
generation to
hear uh some of the challenges that
they've gone
through um yeah because that is actually
something that kind of prompted this
like having conversations with older
women and just kind of seeing how sad
they
were um and then also just uh having
conversations with my peers I feel like
a lot of people kind of worry about
being able to do both take time off were
they similar or were there a lot of
variation depending on what Unity
par I I guess they were similar as in
that they had PR to leave but the amount
of time was very different like some
were like two weeks some were at 10
weeks I think um at one University it
was like two
months uh I oh I just want to point out
this afternoon The Graduate science
start having discussion about topics big
red from I think it's from 430
so there are these fin of discussions
going on on and yeah that's talking yeah
thanks as a sociologist reading program
thank you for doing this considering
your your um you mention um that when
when explaining thex that would group of
you do not have person how how do you
define that um so that they don't have
family or they have old care for or they
do have children what do you mean by
that and my second question is um when
you mention that for du couples there is
more toll takes more toll on the the
woman than the man what what exact
impact does this
need yeah those are a good questions
um so I guess
I'll oh yeah I'll answer the first
question first how did I Define someone
with no care responsibilities it was
someone that either didn't have any
children um didn't have any sort of uh
dependence and then also people that had
not yet uh had to take care of their
parents I know eventually they might
have to but they didn't really have any
sort of care need uh they also said that
they it wasn't really a burden like they
didn't have any health issues um
anything
self-related and then uh can you remind
me what your
second um you were talking
about asking the field work and the
traveling to tool on women than the men
so what exact
imp yeah one example that I had to cut
out was that she uh this female faculty
she said that her husband also was a
faculty or I mean he also was a pimp
reader but in industry and so he had to
drive I think he worked like 20 minutes
away and so she said since she was
closer she still had to like if uh there
was any sort of emergency she would have
to go pick up her
children
um or she would have to take the day off
she was always kind of the one
sacrificing if there was any sort of
need that the kids
had if that makes sense sense
okay this is more comment a question but
what
the side effects of and everything going
on is that they virtual a lot of
offer can't
that's something that I don't think
organized that I don't think realize
that that's
actually that's
com I don't know
yeah that did come up in the interviews
where some people were like wow I am on
Zoom but I still have to take care of my
child this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu