this is a production of Cornell
University please let me know if you
have any difficulty in understanding me
because you know I have a really strong
Brazilian accent and not to help I went
to Australia know to know to get a
better English you know I I probably I
should have gone to New Zealand you know
to get a better English but you know I
have this a strong Brazilian Australian
accent so
first of all i' would like to thank Dr
alopi for the invitation for me is a
great honor to be here today giving this
presentation as dropi told you i' I came
here in 2015 as a visiting Professor
with a G Watkins Dr G Watkins and I
actually loved Cornell not just for the
scientific interaction that I had but
also it was
summer no and was beautiful I loveed the
campus and but and then I was just
wondering how is is this campus during
the winter and here I am 9 years now
later here at the campus and it's still
beautiful I love it okay um ex do shopi
also
mentioned I was a professor in Brazil I
had never ever worked with potatoes
before I was a I was a post Harvest
physiology work with mangos bananas a
pineapples and I think the University of
Idaho was crazy enough to hire me
disposition and then the title of my
presentation is pretty much what I'm
experiencing so I'm still understanding
potato PSE Harvest and I'm bringing that
to you so today I'm I will give you the
glimpse of understanding potato post
Harvest okay and let's start with a a
question so why potatoes are so
special first of all because they are
yummy and very versatile you know many
people like
potato and by the way
the potatoes
USA said that the for the last two
years the Americans uh rated potato at
the most preferred vegetables that they
can have as a food choice and the second
one is
broccoli you know I think it's a really
you know easy race you know if you
compete with broccoli I think everything
is going to be good you know but anyway
potato is now the leading the most
perfect a food in the United States in
vegetables and potatoes are so really
nutritious if you think about potato uh
people just think about a carbohydrate
as a source of energy but potatoes also
is really is a good source of protein
and as a good source of potassium when
and if you go to the gym people eat a
lot of bananas because bananas is rich
in potassium but potatoes are some some
of VAR are richer in pot in potassium
than bananas and the same as Vitamin C
we have a lot of vitamin C and
potatoes a and also there's a
fight
a between the industry and the health
people uh in terms of ping potato are
not as a vegetable or or is a healthy
food and one of the achievements of the
potato a Idaho Potato commission was to
be able to put potatoes as a as a good
food for the diabetic Society now we
have this label and then so potatoes are
good is a good food not not just yummy
but a good
food
right potato is also economically
important so China is the the the the
largest producer in of potatoes in the
world but China produces a lot because
they have to feed 1. 5 billion people
and India is the same so the US is the
fifth largest producer of potatoes in
the world and Idaho is the leading State
Idaho produces 35% of potatoes in in the
United States then we have a Washington
state with
27% then we have a Wiscosin and Oregon
so the Tri State so Idaho washingon in
Oregon produces
67% of the potatoes in the United States
so it's a lot of potatoes that we
produced in the in that the tri-state
area but how about New
York okay here we
go the new the upstate New York produced
roughly 200,000 tons of potatoes in 2022
that's an industry ofer approximately
$50
million okay it's important industry for
the state
good and Cornell plays a vital role for
the potato industry in the in New York
in New York not just releasing new
varieties I just visit the lab with
neaty Dr W was marvelous to see all the
research that's been Carri out and Dr
joh also doing a research with potatoes
uh I I know I know him by name I think I
met him in some of paa I'm I'm pretty
good in in in in in faces but I'm pretty
bad names but you know I think I met him
but you know although potatoes are
really important not just nutritionally
speaking but economically speaking take
a look at the
losses so FAO report that say say that
in the world we're still losing
45% of all roots and a
tubers if you're taking CH the race just
in North America oceia like Australia
New Zealand it represents 1 billion bags
of potatoes it's a
lot it's a lot so it's good for us as a
potato plus harest no we still have a
lot of room to improve and a lot of work
to be
done uh the losses are mostly due to
disease that's a picture of my colleague
Dr Nora Olsen she took that she works a
lot with pathology I don't work with
pathology and then that would be another
seminar just to talk about a a the
pathological problems of potatoes doing
storage is huge I'm going to talk more
the physiological aspects of a potatoes
in storage
good so that's a quick overview about
potatoes so now we're going to move to a
PO Harvest and in Brazil when I when I
taught all these different crops like
bananas mangoes I always start for the
origin
why because you need to understand from
where that crop came from and then you
can understand all the horiculture
practice that you can
apply I cannot grow mangoes in
Tropicals I actually I do we grow potato
apples in in in Brazil in the High
Altitude but it's really difficult
because because it's not the climate we
can use a lot of chemicals Etc but it's
hard so a a bananas are apples
are from tropical a from temporate zones
and potatoes are also from the temporate
zones from the andies in the South
America so they they develop in the high
altitudes for the
temperate zones in South America there
are a lot of the different varieties
types colors shapes so it's a it's a
huge diversity but the Spanish they took
just a small portion of this variety of
diversity and introduced in Europe and
from Europe to the UK and from the UK to
the United States in other parts of of
the world but the most important thing
of understanding the origin is to
understand the
climate I don't know if you can see well
this graph a that's a climatological a a
information from Cusco in Peru then you
have the mon here in the XX and the
precipitation is the black line and the
temperatures the highest temp
temperatures the the orange bars and the
lowest temperatures the gray
bars and you have to take into
consideration that the seasons in the
South hemisphere is the opposite from
here so right now it's winter here and
it's Carnival in
Brazil what am I doing here so it's
summer and Carnival and actually my
brother is sending me pictures of you
know he is no dancing in the carnival he
loves Carnival
anyway so we have spring when the crop
starts to develop
why the such develop industry and when
we plant potatoes also in the us because
we have a increasing precipitation and
the minimum temperature starts to
rise then potatoes are be able to grow
and then we have the
summer the crop will grow develop the
canopy and we have a the start of the
the reduction in precipitation and also
the reduction in the day lamp and they
have the
terization and the plant will sess
during the
Autumn less water the temperatures will
go down the Plant will sess and
eventually in the winter the tubers will
be in the
ground dormant they cannot grow why
because it's cold and there is no
water that is exactly where we Harvest
potatoes they are
dormant so potatoes we have to think
that we are just just animals that
eat a fruit and vegetables to the
disperse know the
seeds potatoes were not meant to be
eaten potatoes were meant to reproduce
the
plant okay good and then I like this a a
classical a chart about
development and the H cultural maturity
so that was published by Wata is Cooper
in 1984 it's classical
information if you look at the tubers
and and root and Roots you can see that
they have to be harvested at the
physiological maturity state I'm going
to explain that okay so many crops for
example if you go to browser CR you're
going to harvest then at the maturity
stage a they are all immature in the
growth but potatoes not they're
physiological mature
and this is how the potato potatoes
develop we plant the seed potatoes then
we meet the stem this stem will grow
forming the canopy of the plant and some
stems will develop in the
ground the
stolin and this stolin they will
accumulate a lot of starch forming the
tubers so
basically potatoes when we eat potatoes
we are eating a stem or a branch of a
tree that accumulates the start so this
is a
branch of a tree we have the bud epical
bud we have the leaves and scars with
the buds we have many eyes with the buds
we have the Len cells we have multiple
Len cells in the
potatoes the only difference is that
front developed in the ground okay then
is a picture just to show all the parts
of potato so we have the very same parts
of a
br and then
maturity I told you
that potatoes will develop and then when
start to reach the alt the PLS will sess
and the tubers will be ready to be
harvested
do you think it's easy to determine the
maturity of
potatoes it's really hard because you
can't
see when seen an apple turning from
green to gray to Red is pretty easy a
mango from green to Yellow is pretty
easy you can look at them and say okay
that's it's turning it's getting mature
I can Harvest that how about
potatoes oh Gustavo
this not all varieties some VAR they
keep they are really vigorous they still
have really green canopy so some people
are developing like drones and try to
have satellite images and imagery and
try to get neur maturity determination
is really complicated because it depends
on not just variety but you have a lot
of nitrogen what's going to happen with
the
kopy you will be braing but the tubers
are already
mature okay then you have a lot of
maturity
indexes some of them are related to the
quality for the industry spe especially
specific gravity that's related to the
content of dry metal in the
tuber and the desirable tuber size for
example if you're are growing a
specialty potatoes you as a grower you
want a small
tuber you don't want a big tuber for
specialty potatoes but on the other hand
for the industry you have potatoes this
big
so and Y is really important and the
sence of the canopy some varieties and
in some conditions and the thickening of
the skin that is called Skin set so just
to illustrate how that develops in the
in the in the field so we have the days
after planting specific gravity and
reducing sugars so take a look at how
the gravity increases over time when it
reaches the desire the desired number
that's
1.08 we can get the one indication of
the maturity the same with sugars the
industry doesn't like a potatoes with a
high content of sugars because when we
put in the the fryer having my AR
reaction we turn do okay so all these
numbers together together a we can
establish the physiological maturity as
expected we have differences in
varieties the differences in the maximum
yield the maximum specific gravity the
minimum suos or the minimum sugar
contents if you get all these numbers
and you add and divide it by four that's
the physiological maturity this magical
number but in general this is the best
indicator of a Acuity is the
accumulation of degre
days um above 4 Celsius
or 39 fahit so that's the accumulation
that during the season that's the better
prediction predictor of a physiological
maturity and why physiological mat
maturity is
important because as any other
crop potatoes are really susceptible to
the the varieties of of the differences
in the environment in temperature
especially temperatures and in higher
temperatures the tuor will be
physiologically mature or older I have
one student in Brazil and she's doing
her PhD and one of
her one of her experiments a she went to
the grower four hours away she spent the
whole day a har you know digging getting
potatoes when she arrived at the lab the
tubers were already sprouted
why no we are in Brazil we don't have
you know cold weather so when potatoes
are exposed to higher temperatures
during the growth period they're going
to get
older and why is that important because
older potatoes or physiologically older
potatoes do have shortened shelf
lives and I love this this
trial a it a it was a a study published
by zic and co-authors in
2014 just to illustrate how temperature
can influence physiologically
physiologic phys the physiology of the
tuber in the in the field the guy so the
aler put a lot of a
a
resistance in the
hill to increase the temperature at
different periods of the tuber
development especially after during
bulking bulking or at the end of tuber
bulking and increase the temperatures
over here to 29 c in relation to the the
the environment that was 16° C so what's
happening take a look at what's
happening 29c at maturation for Ranger
Russell take a look at this
Sprout compared to the the
ambient just to illustrate that what my
student faced in Brazil if you have
higher temperature in the boat that's
what you're going to have older potatoes
and short shelf
life good the another indicator that's a
skin set so skin set is really important
and it usually develops well after three
weeks a after three weeks of Vine CU so
the Growers they have the the the crop
and then they spray the crop with a a
herbicide or other product to kill the
vine so the vine kill then after three
month 3 weeks they can harvest the PE
will be well
developed but how about in
Canada three weeks in Canada is too
much in Canada they don't have the
luxury of waiting three weeks sometimes
they they harvest potatoes that's a
green potatoes they still have the vine
green because the season so so is too
short
they cannot wait 3 weeks 3 weeks they
will be frozen in the ground and then
it's a big problem especially because
immature tubes of a poor skin set will
lead to more disease more dehydration
and more
defect good so this part I covered the
physiology that's now I'm going to go to
the funny part let say Harvest and food
in the
storage so Harvest potatoes are not easy
you know my students she needed to dug
all the potatoes for her trial and there
always is a balance I just showed you so
this balance of maturity that we need to
go an adequate gravity a low respiration
rate when they are mature a adequate
skin set low weight loss and the
opposite when they are
immature and how to harvest potatoes I'm
not going to cover every single one one
but it's just to show you that you have
multiple
steps that can lead to Mechanical injury
why because potatoes in in many parts of
the world the commercial production are
harvested using mechanical Harvesters
and to illustrate that I brought this
video I hope it works
yeah from a big farm in Idaho this water
farm from Japanese descendant family
take a look at the size of the farms in
Idaho we have a digger or more than
eight
rows taking potatoes out of the ground
take a look at these and the
possibilities of mechanical injuries in
there sorry for the sound but you know I
could not take this out and we have the
Harvester that no collects the the the
tub from the ground put in the
truck so the
pets
again take a look have to go all around
and follow into the
truck and then this truck will take the
potatoes today to the seller we just say
call seller because in the past you used
to store potatoes actually in the seller
of the
house take a look the the size of the
the
farm here we go so we have the the the
potato load in the truck they cover the
the potatoes with a a a a sheet that's
really good to avoid the heat load from
the
sunshine and it goes to
the the
we have some people here sorting the
potatoes and also taking the dust out
and they go into the the
storage just to show the many steps that
we
have and they can feel one of these big
cellers in one
day take a look at the the amount of
potato have the ventilation system here
so this is
amazing it's amazing how they can
manage all the farm the logistic is
involved and then it's not surprised
that we have a lot of mechanical damage
so knows and co-authors publish that the
70% happens during the Harvest it's a
lot 14% at a truck the pile of 14% And
here very low 2% but all this a
mechanical damage will result in death
really poor
quality and the PO quality is not just
related to the bruising itself but also
the skinny that's all all opening a
openings that can lead to more weight
loss and the entry of a path pathogen
and have a shadow bruise and mechanical
Dam like internal black
spot and all this blackening is due to a
enzy called polyphenol oxidase we also
have know when you have a
scratch it doesn't turn
black it's the same enzyme it's doing
the same job oxidizing the monophenols
in dienols but they still colorless they
don't have color and the D phos in or
quos that are a little bit yellowish
color but they are really reactive
compounds why they are reactive
compounds because the plant produces
that to protect the plant against the
pathogens so this compound will react
with the amino acids and proteins from
the
pathogens okay but uh in that case we
react with the amino acid and protein
leading to dark polymers that the
industry doesn't like and the industry
doesn't like to the point to develop a
silenced
po a potato that is a a
a potato that was released by Simplot
one of the largest companies in in the
United States so that's a take a look at
the difference between a one potato
without the p with P5 and without P5
equality so there's no Brown they also
developed that the silen Asar synthes A1
Gene there's
noide a synthesis so it is a toxic
compound the only thing that I don't
like in that is a as a as a post Harvest
physiologist we never can
forget all the the vi the Via Cress that
the potato passed from the field to go
to the storage the multiple steps of
mechanical damage so it's not because
it's not
showing the brown that they are not
suffering mechanical damages because
this mechanical damage can also affect
all the quality aspects of potatoes
okay now CH storage
so there are multiple steps in the
storage I'm not going to cover all of
them I'm going to jump into directly to
the co the curing because I showed you
one picture of the the potato with a a
lot of skinny problem that's due to
abrasion when they are moving from the
the the ground to the to the cell and
the Cur is really important esec
especially to produce a new layer of a
periderm and protect the potatoes from
disease and dissocation
okay and I'm going to follow all this
recommendations from a no from
Washington State University about curing
so what is curing Cur is not exclusive
from for potatoes so onions and garlic
we have the curing
a process in the post Harvest you need
to dry out this problem and develop a
new skin to protect against pathogens
okay so what is wound healing
so we have the the sound peel of potato
we have a subis layer subepidermal cells
and cortical cells when it's damaged
potatoes do do have a a really nice
capacity of producing new
a perm a a layer of cells due to this
dep position of
subin if you cut potatoes and let in
your table in four days you have a new
SK on
top so many other crops do have that
like sweet potatoes for example they
also have curing and it's a three-step
process we have initial one that takes
plac in 0 to 36 hours have the
solarization that takes a little bit
longer and also the wood the W be their
information in terms of a the initial
response uh is really interesting so we
have the the damaged
cells and the damaged cells will produce
what we called damage Associated
molecular
patterns especially a oxygen reactive
species and the release of
calcium so the the reactive oxygen
species and calcium are will be
responsible for sealing off the plasma
desmas not leaving the the pathogens to
getting the adjacent
cell so protecting that sound cell and
also the calcium will
move through the other the cells
and initiating the Cascade of
phosphorilation that will lead to the
transcription of defensive a a defense
genes to protect the sound
cells but you know it's not that
complicated I love this paper uh what is
really important is to understand the
role of the reactive oxygen species es
especially a the oxidase this
NPH oxidase that has a pick in 24
hours what what this enzyme does this
enzyme produces super
oxide super oxide have a super oxide
dismutase that will convert this super
oxide into hydrogen peroxidase and
hydrogen
peroxidase uh is a substrate of
peroxidase that will oxidize the
phenolic compounds into a a subar it's
not that complicated come on and leading
to the
suberization and suberization is a
process of forming that new layer of
subin in the damage cells
okay and if you look at this
time you can see that is
extremely dependent
on
temperature what's the rule of Tomy post
Harvest cool as soon as you
can not with
potatoes because if you cool potatoes
really quickly we're going to affect the
wound healing and it's going to take
longer take a look
so we need to keep a the a little bit
warm for this process to take place and
another enzyme that's really important
in that in that part is
the or as in United
States
Li uh so this enzyme is responsible for
converting the amino acid penine into
trinamic acid okay and then the
accumulation of a trinamic
acid with a not activity producing
superoxide a hydrogen peroxide and the
wall associate peroxidase forming this
the the subar that will be that will
lead to the accumulation of subar in the
new per there
okay and finally is the the the
differentiation of the new cells that
also is dependent on temperature so it's
always a tradeoff
between
the temperature and the physiological
process that you
want if it's the highest the temperature
the faster is going to be the C the
curing but at higher temperature what
you going to have a higher probability
of disease development and weight
loss if you we if we C that down we're
going to slow the curing process control
the the the K development
and reduce the weight loss but with a
cust in the process okay just to show
they you know how the W new wound bird
will form using a different a DI you can
see that a
microsof okay let's go to cing in the
Pacific Northwest we use a the vapora ti
Cooling in the majority of the store
we don't very
few potato storage do have mechanical a
refrigeration
system some do have especially when they
harvest potatoes in August they still
really warm have a huge heat load do you
imagine one of those a storage full of
potatoes at
68 degrees fhe it's a huge heat load
inside that building so thetive to
doesn't have the capacity of remove all
that heat no they have a supplementary a
mechanical unit or you can actually a
lease a a mechanical refrigeration
system and put in your system to try to
cool potatoes down okay the most
important part of the evaporative
cooling is
this relative
humidity potatoes
always it must be stored at 97% relative
otherwise you're going to lose a lot of
weight and weight is
money water is money PO is 80% water if
you lose water you lose money okay and
ventilation is the is the is the way
that is used in the industry they talk a
lot a lot about ventilation oh
ventilation is really important but
ventilation in my my perspective is just
a way to p down the
props we cannot use hydrocooling if I
could use hydrocooling I would talk
about the water I'm not talking about
water I'm talking about air air movement
is ventilation and the main the two main
systems we have a like a the pipes that
are put on in the bottom of the cell and
you have also the concrete with
perorations
that I go
down yep so have this this a structures
here we have the planet the air is blown
from my side to the end and get they get
in this a
holes and they leave from from here to
the top of the
CR and the thing
is we have 18 ft of potatoes for this
air to move so we have the capacity of
the the the the VAP cooling is huge to
be able to have the enough air to move
through the scrub and remove the the the
moist and also the temperature
okay um so whenever the cool the the
curing period is
over we need to cool that crop really
quickly to the holding temperature so
it's usually done by you know reducing
using the temperature 4
25.5 de F per week so it takes longer if
you imagine that the you're going to
move from 50 to 55 to 42 it takes almost
one month to reach that temperature it's
a h is a long period that potatoes will
be exposed to higher temperature and the
possibility of losing a lot of weight
then the ventilation takes place here
that's really important because if you
have a higher ventilation right we can
cool that crop really quickly but and
the most important part again is to keep
that high
moisture High relative humidity because
take a look at the it's not the the
speed of the air that will lead to the
weight loss it's actually the relative
humidity in that air that will drive the
weight loss so at 99% take a look potato
actually get
weight
in 97 that's the recommended you you're
not you're not going to lose weight even
though we have a huge air flow here and
90 take a look so that's the relative
that drives the weight loss and not just
the ventilation
itself okay let's go to holding holding
is the temperature that we keep potatoes
for 8 to 12
months and potatoes are not different
from the other crops so the the higher
the temperature the shorter is going to
be the Shelf line or on the or we can
say the lower the temperature the longer
is going to be the Shelf FL for potatoes
okay that's exponential relationship as
many other
props but
potatoes always Happ it's a complicated
problem there's a problem that's called
sweetening so what is called
sweetening who likes
barbecue I'm from Brazil I love B and I
and I love
beer so what I do I get my my my my
cooler I put the ice water and
salt why I put the
salt to reduce the freezing
point so it's going to be below zero and
it keeps my beer
cooler potatoes do the
same we have the
cell if I put the cell in the lower
temperature as an adaptation potatoes
will hydroly the
star
producing glucose and
fructose increasing their osmolarity of
the cell protecting the cell from
freezing or
cooling is an adaptation do you remember
the first one of the first slides that I
showed you origin the tub is on the
ground in the ground during the
winter that's an adapation to survive
the winter to be able to to germinate
during the Spring but is pretty bad for
the industry why because this reducing
sugars when we fry potatoes again in
when they at higher temperature have my
my reaction so the reducing sugars will
react with amino acids producing melano
that are d pigments and also can produce
aamine that's a toxic compound so that's
why the temperatures for the holding
period
varies according to the end use for
example for table potato or or fresh
potatoes that we eat now we buy in the
supermarket to make Smash Potatoes I'm
going to cook uh we don't have this
problem we can put potatoes at below 45
actually some grows put at 39 40 fhe and
for frying we should keep these potatoes
at higher temperature because we need to
avoid that cooling the cooling Sweet
Cooling sweet
Mo and uh for chips is even worse so
depending on end and use you have
different temperatures so what why
because consumers don't
like
dark French
fries I don't I don't care I know I can
eat B french fries but McDonald's for
example
wants just USDA number zeros that's
really
pay potato so the whiter the
better okay just to simplify here a some
a trios at
Theo Tina brand she now she works for
for SE plot but she did the say she
worked for the invest of for many years
and then we have here two different for
artists rber bank that is standard in
for the industry and Clear Water rusted
now is a a also approved by McDonald's
just to show how they react uh during
the storage so we use three mostly three
temperatures 32 45
48 and take a look that's the limit of
sugars .1% glucose
take a look at Burbank at
42 during the holding
period all above the threshold just at
48 was pretty much know at the limit but
take a look at Clear
Water so that's why the industry is
moving so they called cold resistant
varieties so they don't have this
increase in sugars during the storage
and in terms of reflectance that's the
color of a the fried so we have used the
USDA a chart let's consider USDA Zer 1 2
3 and four take a look at a clear waters
they all the chips all the fries were
above a
one and I'll take a look at the the
russer bir bags so just to show that a
the quality can change according to the
varieties and also the temperature that
we use to store potatoes so that's
really good when you have like in a
reading program post Harvest program
working together because that's a we
need to determine the end use of that
variety that can be really good in terms
of eeld but you know cannot store well
at
42 should be stored at 48 to keep the
sugars below the threshold in the color
as a good
power there are some
remedies but they're not 100% a a how
can I say efficient one is conditioning
what is breare conditioning is to take
potatoes from that cold environment and
increase the temperature it's like this
one so we have a potatoes stored at 4
Celsius that's a 39 fah and then
transfer to 16
Celsius take a look that this one G
gstar russet is cold resistant so it
doesn't matter the temperature take a
look at the color zeros zeros it's a
really good variety to store at know at
low temperature take a look at the
fender it was USDA number three and then
when you increase the temperature it it
went down to
two but no I like to explain why what is
behind this that's the
respiration the respiration wasn't here
when we put that 16 take a look what
happened with the respiration this speak
respiration is a process that that
consumes sugar and by consuming sugars
we you can improve a the quality but not
a little bit well so the best way to to
do with this is a to get like cold
resistant
variees good and also have biot
technology as I showed that
PO the industry also is moving to have a
a RNA interference a potatoes especially
a blocking the action of
Inver with that we don't have this
problem so because with the invert the
sucrose cannot be converted in glucose
and and
fructose and don't have a reducing
sugars and then the industry is doing
that so I was talking with a Dr Ali
maybe 20 years you're not going to have
any problem po Harvest because all the
Transformations they're going to solve
all the problems that we we face
and one of the other problems that we
fac is sprouting as I as I showed you
you have the dorant
period and the dorant period now is
related to the dormy that the potatoes a
present so the dorcy is related to the
accumulation of a hormone such as aysc
acid that prevent the growth of the
buds whenever this abic acid is
metabolized is oxidized then we have
the the and many other metabolic a
process we can have the the
Sprout again just to show that's a
adaptation for that period and it's
really dependent on
variety and
temperature take a look at this standard
Russ birbank at
42 as a period of aous period of how
many minutes sorry okay
175 days at 48
130 how can we store potatoes at what
240 to almost a year so we need to apply
a a chemicals to control that we can
apply in preh Harvest as as Mal hydr or
in the post harvest in the United States
we we use a lot of chor profane that not
is not allowed in the in in Europe
anymore they use a lot of Eilene in
there so but know chopine is really
effective take a look at this the same
varieties 45 48 with cipc without cipc
take a look how effective is this
product
okay now again have biotechnology taking
place so controlling they start start
breakdown we don't have sucros and then
we have potatoes without
is proud and finally marketing so it's
the same as apples we have just one
season in the year in Brazil have we
have a luxury to have three seasons of
potatoes here in United States just one
and have to put these potatoes in the
storage and supply all the market it's
not an easy task to take potatoes out of
the
storage uh we need to avoid new Bru that
the the industry called the old bruise
from the Harvest period and have the new
bruise that's formed in this uh this
step of the post Harvest management
especially if potatoes are really cold
when they are really cold if they heat
something they will shatter help to
increase the temperature a little bit to
be able to take potatoes out and one of
the main problems that causes a lot of a
rejections is the flattening of potatoes
especially if they when they take this
potatoes out of of the storage in four
to 5 days we have this internal Browning
that the industry called a cutting
black for Fresh Market that's what we
are seeing Idaho a lot of robotization
and artificial intelligence used so this
company the same company W they have
seven
robots just three people working so it
reminds me the the the book of yal
Harari
Homo sapiens and talk about artificial
intelligence
substituting
us so take home message I don't have
time just to show you I hope you had
understand a little bit about potato
post Harvest so we have all these things
taking place when we put potatoes in
storage and I'd like to thank my my my
my team univers of Idaho so my
technician Sam P my students from PhD
from Brazil Vanessa ped and Mike Zoro at
University of pido and and the potato
consor in USDA for funding my research
I'm I'm I have to do my altise I'm
hiring people especially MERS and PhD
student and saying that I open up for
questions thank you so much so the
question was if a Browning has some a
safety problems
yeah
the if there isn't
no do you like coffee do you like tea do
you like
chocolate all of all these
products they are dark because of
Po so for us to have like a dark
chocolate we have ch they have the the
Coco and a nuts the kernel and we put
them to ferment and after that we we
roast that roting process is a exactly
the PO a all this conversion of a
compound a tea for example so many
products that we eat the Browning
actually is a a is really good for us so
that part you know so doesn't that have
any a a safety concern the only think
that's a nutritional concern because
when po a reacts with the amino acids
reduces the avilability of proteins and
amino acids for us but it's not in the
point that we reduce the protein
content thank you great thank you so
much this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu