This is a production of Cornell
University.
So, it is my pleasure to introduce
Hannah Zonavville, who is a secondyear
PhD student here in soil and crop
sciences. Hannah got her bachelor's
degree from the University of Michigan
uh where she worked on topics uh
including moose herbivy and northern
forests. Hannah then went on to uh live
and work in Chicago for two years um
where she worked for an environmental um
education nonprofit and also was a uh
community science fellow with the
American geoysical
union here in SIPS. Hannah has served as
the graduate student council chair, the
soil and crop sciences graduate student
assembly vice president and as a
representative on the DDI council. She
also regularly leads outreach activities
and finds way to create broad and
inclusive science focused communities.
Today Hannah will be telling us about
her dissertation research which is
supported by an NSF graduate student
fellowship. Please join me in welcoming
Hannah.
Thanks for that kind introduction, Dan.
And hello everyone. If I haven't met you
yet, my name is Hannah and I'm a PhD
student with Dan. And today I'm super
excited to share with you all the work
that I've been doing since coming to
Cornell, which is leveraging remote
sensing to quantify pollen production
across space and time for Junifer's
Ashi.
Before I jump into the nitty-gritty of
my project, I wanted to first give you a
little bit of background about me. As
Dan mentioned, I hail from the great
state of Michigan where I attended the
University of Michigan and fell in love
with plant ecology through a series of
undergraduate experiences there. After
graduating, I wanted to do some more
community focused work. And so I did an
Americanore service year in Chicago with
an environmental education nonprofit
that partners with Chicago public
schools to bring a comprehensive freeof
charge outdoor STEM education to
students from low-income households. And
it was during this experience that I saw
firsthand how the systemic racism in US
leads to really awful inequities in
terms of educational opportunities,
access to nature, and ultimately public
health outcomes. And so when I was
thinking about returning to graduate
school, I wanted to find a way to unite
these two passions and ultimately do
work that could help alleviate some of
the public health burdens that I was
witnessing. And that is what brought me
to the cat's lab here at Cornell. And we
focus on plant related public health
problems. And the one that I focus on
specifically is that of airborne
pollen. So who among us has pollen
allergies? Raise your hand. Oh yeah.
Okay. Well, don't worry. Misery loves
company and you are not alone. It is
actually estimated that over 80 million
people in the United States have
seasonal allergies. And the worst that
most of you will suffer are, you know, a
runny nose, maybe trouble sleeping for a
few weeks out of the year. But for
people with chronic respiratory issues,
these asthma allergies and subsequent
pollen exposures can be dangerous and
result in emergency department visits
due to asthma exacerbations. And we also
know that asthma is not equally
distributed across the United States.
There's plenty of research that shows
that asthma is um in a higher
concentrations within communities that
are lower income. And so I have
additional bad news and that is that
pollen exposure is increasing with
climate change. We're seeing that the
increased temperatures are leading to a
longer growing season. What you're
seeing here is the consecutive days
above freezing which allows plants to
start releasing pollen early in earlier
in the year and then continue later into
the year. It's also resulting in range
expansion for different allergenic
species. This is something we're seeing
in common ragweed in Europe. And a
recent meta analysis done in the cat's
lab showed that plants are al able to
allocate more carbon to reproductive
structures under increased um carbon
conditions. And so there's a variety of
mechanisms that climate change is
increasing pollen exposure and therefore
possibly impacting downstream public
health effects. Um lucky for us, as with
most things, uh science has the
potential to offer a solution. And this
solution can look like better airborne
pollen
forecasts. Um, airborne fall pollen for
forecasts can help people know when they
might be exposed to pollen such that
they can take their allergy medications
with enough time prior to exposure so
that it reaches its full efficacy by
time that they are exposed to pollen. It
can also let people know when to turn on
their air filters or help them avoid
pollen hot spots.
However, current predictions of airborne
pollen are insufficient to help people
avoid this exposure. What you're seeing
here is some work done by Dan that shows
the predicted airborne pollen
um concentration from commercial
forecasters compared to the empirically
measured pollen concentration from
pollen monitoring stations. And so
pollen.com is doing all right, but the
rest of them leave a little bit of room
for improvement. And if you are
associated with any of these companies,
I'm not smack talking. I'm just inviting
you to fund me. Um, so with that, you
might be asking, well, why is it that
current airborne pollen is is modeled so
poorly? And one of the key reasons for
this is because we just don't really
know how much pollen is being produced
across space and time. The current
method for measuring airborne pollen is
through a sparsely populated network of
airborne pollen monitoring stations.
There are only about 50 in the
contiguous US. And so it does a really
bad job of capturing the spatiotemporal
variation in pollen production. Um, and
it is really difficult to calculate the
amount of pollen being produced based on
ecology of plants because it's super
hard to study how plant reproduction
varies over large spatial extents. Um,
as you can see, the historical way of
doing this is is manual measurements
that take a very long time and actually
can limit studies that involve counting
these reproductive structures on plants
to sample sizes of only 10 to hundreds
of individuals. And further, it only
covers a small portion of the tree and a
small portion of the range of these
plants.
Um, lucky for us, we live in the time of
remote sensing, which is an amazing tool
in our toolbox that we can use to study
ecological processes across the entire
ecosystem. And there's been plenty of
literature in the past couple years that
uses aerial images to track the timing
of plant reproduction. And so it has
been posited that we could perhaps use
aerial images such as with drones or
with satellite images to quantify the
number of reproductive structures on
plants such that we could calculate
pollen production that we could use to
inform these better airborne pollen
models. So as you can probably guess my
research focuses on one central theme
which is building better airborne pollen
models. I have just proved to you all
that this could definitely help public
health outcomes and improve the way that
people interact with plants. Um, but in
order to do this, we need to have a
better understanding of pollen
production across space and time. And to
help do this, I have designed three
chapters to pursue here at Cornell. The
first one is to actually measure the
amount of pollen production over space
space and time using remote sensing. The
next is to build off of the data
collected in chapter 1 to then start to
disentangle the biot abiotic drivers of
plant reproduction. This is possible
because the chapter 1 data set will let
us quantify the number of reproductive
structures on plants that we can pair
with grided environmental data and start
to model what might be the dominant
drivers of plant reproduction. And in my
third chapter, I hope to take a
ecological forecasting approach and
actually try to predict how climate
change might affect future pollen
production of these plants. Uh this is a
similar approach that has been done in
phenology but has not yet been done for
pollen production. Um I'm going to spend
most of my time today talking about
chapter 1 since that is what I have
worked the most on so far. Um but I will
also give you a little teaser into
chapter 2 towards the end. Um with that
let's get into it. So, I'd now like to
introduce you to my study species, the
beautiful ash juniper or juniperous
ashi. Uh, juniperous ashi is an
evergreen dishious plant that is the
dominant tree species along in central
Texas where it thrives on the
calccarious soil of the Edwards Plateau.
And uh it is known by locals as an
infamous infamous producer of pollen
that causes something known as cedar
fever. And cedar fever is an awful
affliction that results in severe runny
noses, achy joints, trouble sleeping,
and it can actually even cause some
people to run a fever. And the culprit
of cedar fever is the super abundant
number of reproductive structures on
these plants, which are pollen cones.
Um, male individuals can actually
contain up to 1.3 million pollen cones
on a single tree. And each of these
cones can have almost half a million
grains of pollen. And so this pollen is
so abundant and so allergenic that past
work in the system has revealed that it
can contribute up to 18% of asthma
related emergency department visits
during peak pollen season. So yeah, you
can see the pollen coming off of these
trees in waves and it is um from
personal experience very unpleasant. So,
um, the thing that makes ash juniper a
horrible neighbor to all of the Texans
actually makes it a wonderful study
species for me because the pollen cones
have very distinct visual properties. As
you can probably tell, this individual,
which is a male with pollen cones, looks
quite different from this individual,
which is a female having no pollen
cones. So, let's take a little bit of a
closer look at these cones.
They have this kind of beautiful orange
color that makes them stand out against
the the green foliage that you can see
here. And so it is this aspect of the
ash juniper that makes it observable
from aerial imagery.
In this case, I have been trying to
derive methods that use aerial images
from drones as well as manual methods to
quantify the number of cones on these
trees using their spectral
properties. And I'd now like to show you
a little bit more about what those
methods look
like. So to test my methodology, I have
established 14 study sites across the
range of the ash juniper trees in
central Texas. You can see that the
study sites cover a range of
environmental conditions including
temperature, precipitation and what is
displayed here is soil moisture data
from SMAP. And uh at each site I choose
between five to 10 focal trees on which
I take a comprehensive suite of
measurements. And I take additional
phenology measurements from surrounding
trees to try to understand how the
timing of reproduction varies among
these trees and how that might impact
the spectral reading from the images. I
have done this for two field seasons now
which I go to Texas in January. So it's
a nice little escape from Ithaca winter
but um Unfortunately, that seems to last
until mid April. Anyway, so um I was
also very lucky this past field season
to be joined by a wonderful UT grad, Dr.
Analisa Shield Estrada, who was not only
a really hard worker, but an absolute
joy to be around. So, I'm really
grateful for her help on this project.
And so to show you a little bit more
about the methods in practice, um I
first select my focal trees at each
study site and take a couple of manual
measurements. This year this included
the diameter at breast height and the
height. I then put a quadrat with a
known area in on a branch of the tree so
that it's facing upward and visible by
the drone. And after I fly the drone, I
harvest all of the foliage that falls
within that known area of the quadrat.
Then I use a super sophisticated method
for homogenizing it where I run it
through a mulure and that enables me to
have a repres representative sample
where I can subsample the foliage 10
times, take its weight and count. And
this will give me the number of grams of
foli number of cones per grams of
foliage that I can then multiply to the
number of cones per grams of foliage for
the entire tree by using alometric
equations based on diameter press height
and height to give me the total gram of
foliage for the tree. And so these are
all my manual methods. But we're not
done yet because we now get to do some
fun remote sensing things. So from the
drone images, I find the quadrats, crop
that down so that it only contains pixel
values that fall within that known area.
I then extract all of the pixel values
from that image and correlate these
pixel values, their red, green, and blue
values to the known quantity of cones
that I just estimated using my manual
methods. This results in an index that
can be used to predict the number of
cones per grams based solely on the red,
green, and blue values. So having this
index allows us to extend our
measurements of these reproductive
structures beyond just the focal trees.
And I'd now like to show you the
index. So this is what I am
provisionally calling the oreness index.
If you have any other um
recommendations, let me know. Um, but it
is a combination of the red and green
values. Red minus green over red plus
green. And as you can see here, I on the
y-axis we have cone density. And so this
is the manually estimated cones that I
used with my subsampling. And higher
cone density results in a higher index
value because there are more cones in
the picture, more red values, more
positive value. compared to this quadra
over here that has very few cones and a
very low cone density has a lot more
green values associated and therefore
returns a lower index value.
So awesome. We have our index. What does
it look like when you actually apply it
to images? What you're seeing here is a
quadrat picture that I have processed to
only retain the pixel values that are
either foliage or cone. I use a random
forest pixel classifier. You can see the
results down here, but it performs very
well. And so when you apply the index to
this, you can see that the positive
values do indeed match up with where the
cones are. Uh for visualization
purposes, I just created a binary. So
the positive values associated with
cones are orange and the green values
associated with foliage are negative and
green. Um and so yeah, you can see that
it it works pretty well and does a good
job of picking up the distinct
properties of these cones.
But remember that the overall goal is to
use this index to count cones from trees
that we don't actually have the manual
measurements on. So let's try to do
that. Here you are seeing a uh subset of
an orthomosaic image from the drone
which is basically just a stitched
together landscape level picture that I
put together all of the pictures from a
drone at a study site. And you can see
the the varying densities of of cones on
these trees. So there's some with a lot
higher density compared to some here
with lower
density. And what I've done is manually
segmented these tree tops so that we can
only retain pixel values that fall
within the canopy. And once again I can
extract the pixel values here and apply
run it through the pixel classifier.
Apply the index and here we are. So
again, the lower values are associated
with more foliage and the higher values
are associated with a higher cone
density. From here, we have all of the
ingredients that we need to actually go
ahead and quantify the number of
reproductive structures and therefore
the pollen production of these trees
because we can again calculate the total
grams of foliage for these trees using
alometric equations where the gram of
foliage is a function of the diameter,
breast height, and height. And then we
can take the average pixel value or the
average index value from these trees,
multiply it by the grams of foliage from
the alometric equations, and this can
give us the number of cones per tree.
Using this, we can calculate the pollen
produced, and this can all go back into
creating better airborne pollen
forecasts based on a more comprehensive
measure of the amount of pollen being
produced.
So, well, I am definitely very excited
about these methods and my um my work so
far. There's plenty of limitations and
it's not um perfect. Some limitations
that have been difficult to work through
are that the trees have kind of a wide
variety of coloring in their foliage.
So, as you can see here, this is a tree
that has a lot more yellow foliage
rather than green. And so it's returning
a really high index value despite there
not being very many cones in it.
Further, the index is sensitive to
lighting conditions. So when we have
pictures that are either very
overexposed or very shadowy, they um the
index is is not able to do a very good
job of calculating the number or
predicting the number of cones based
just on the spectral properties. Um,
additionally, it has been difficult to
calibrate the index using coarser
resolution images from the drone and so
I'm still working out some kinks there.
Um, but when I'm thinking about next
steps, there's a lot that I am looking
forward to working on. So, first, um, I
plan to create alometric equations that
are specifically using remote sensing
variables. Um, this is what these trees
look like. So it is really not that fun
to take the diameter at breast height of
these trees and also probably not that
useful um because it is not a variable
that's observable from aerial
images. Um so I plan to use lidar in the
coming field season to create better
alometric equations that rely on
variables such as height and canopy
diameter instead of diameter breast
height. that will save me a lot of time
and a lot of being stabbed in the eye.
So, I'm looking forward to that. And
next, um these trees, as I think with
all other trees, are 3D objects. So,
they um contain a lot of information on
the sides of the trees that are missed
from aerial images. So to account for
the number of cones that are hidden from
aerial images, I've taken some orbital
flights around my focal trees and I plan
to create a conversion factor for the
number of cones that are missed when
just looking at the trees from the top
down. Um, next, and this is kind of like
my my big push right now is to figure
out ways to adjust for different
lighting conditions. Again, you're
seeing here a quadrat picture that is
just a in a lot of shadows and the index
doesn't really know what's going on with
the number of cones that it is seeing
here. So, if you have um any kind of
workflow that you've used in your
research, I'd be very happy to hear
about it. Um and hopefully I can find a
workaround for this. And lastly, one
next step that is feeling especially
exciting to me is scaling up to uh
satellite images using the the index to
be able to measure cone production and
pollen production across much larger
spatial and temporal extents. Um, and
this would allow us to get a more
comprehensive data set across central
Texas at the regional level rather than
just being limited to the study sites
that I'm able to visit. Um, so I want to
now bring us back to where we started.
So I have shown you so far how we can
better measure pollen production across
large spatial and temporal extents. Um,
and so now that we can measure it, how
can we use this information and pair it
with existing environmental data to
start to understand what the abiotic
drivers of reproduction might be um that
yeah drive variation reproduction across
space and
time. So this is um this is very uh new
data that is more of a proof of concept
than anything. But what you're seeing
here is the mean index value from my
sites compared with the mean soil
moisture data from SMAP. And it is this
kind of workflow that I hope to use in
my second chapter to compare the
reproductive output with grided
environmental data sets. Obviously,
reproduction is an incredibly complex
process that will require um much more
sophisticated statistical tools such as
um hierarchical modeling to start to
uncover what is driving the variability
in reproduction in these trees. But um
yeah, I'm I'm excited to explore this in
my uh coming years at Cornell. Um so key
takeaways um if you remember nothing
else from this presentation my name is
Hannah and also um I have just shown you
that we can measure pollen production
over these large spatial extents using
aerial images which will allow us to
create better airborne pollen forecasts.
That is part of my chapter 1. Um and
then we can also use the data set
collected here to start to explore the
abiotic drivers of the variability in
reproduction for these trees. And this
will be part of my chapter two and you
will just have to stay tuned for chapter
three. Um with that I'd like to thank
everyone who made this work possible.
Everything we're doing is in the
presence of others and I'm I'm so
grateful for everyone. Um not only the
people listed on this slide but um just
to be in community with you all has been
a real joy at Cornell. So thank you and
I'll I I'll take questions now or later.
Okay.
I'm just curious how did you arrive at
your sort of oreness index and did you
try other sort of indicy? Oh yeah, great
question. Yeah, I tried a lot of indices
actually. It was a lot of like looking
through the literature and seeing what
other people have used. Um, and we
arrived at the oreness index just kind
of by way of it being what seemed the
most feasible. like because the cones
are so orange, it's um we thought that
maybe because there would be more red
values um associated with those cones
compared to the green values that would
be like the best combination of bands to
actually pick up on those differences,
but um yeah, definitely was still could
possibly change, but that's what's
worked the best so far.
I was wondering is there hope to uh I
mean maybe the answer will come when you
have more information on chapter 2 but
is there hope to kind of do a survey
um one year and then run with that
information for several years or you
think that it's going to be something
that has to be done like yearly? That's
a good that's a good question. So like
how often for data collection? I plan to
do three years. Um, but the idea is that
if we could scale up to satellite
images, this would enable me to not
actually go down and collect the the
data, but have a longer time series
both, you know, back into before I
started at Cornell and then when I don't
have to go down anymore and kind of like
using that um, information as well. But
yeah, awesome. Okay, thank you all so
much.
So um thanks again Hannah for a
wonderful talk and I'd like to introduce
Dr. Dave Miller next. Um Dave is a
posttock working with me here in soil
and crop sciences. Um and he did his
undergrad at Boston University and then
he got a master's and PhD from uh UC
Santa Barbara. Um he then went on to do
a posttock at UC Berkeley. Uh and some
of the the topics of the work uh for his
uh dissertation and for his first
posttock uh were about uh trees and
cities and using remote sensing to
understand the effects of drought on
them. uh his work from these
uh was published in journals including
nature communications and remote sensing
of environment
um and we've been very fortunate to lure
Dave away from sunny California um and
he has been instrumental in uh this uh
transdisciplinary uh collaboration the
cool trees team which is working to
understand how we can use trees to keep
cities cool during heat waves and
ultimately reduce heat related
morbidity. Um, and we've been very
fortunate to have uh Dave here and to
benefit from his expertise in remote
sensing and in making beautiful maps.
So, um, please join me in welcoming
Dave.
Um, thank you Dan for that kind
introduction and um, welcome everyone to
our second of two talks today. Um, it's
a tough hack to follow and I'll do my
best. Um so today I'm going to be
talking a lot about New York City and
classifying urban tree species using a
lot of high resolution satellite time
series for heat related public health
impacts. Um a lot of our co-authors here
are at Cornell in civil engineering and
also in Wild Cornell um in New York. Um
and we'll kind of get into it. So tree
species vary in cooling capacity, but
how can we use this to actually reduce
heat? anyone who's walked under
different types of trees in your
neighborhood, a big maple tree is going
to provide a lot more shade, a lot more
cooling than perhaps a smaller cherry
tree would. And so tree species actually
cool differently in the environment, but
these differences aren't really included
in models of for heat and human exposure
health related. Um, so shading, for
example, tree size, of course, um, and
leaf area, so how many leaves do you
have on this particular tree? Um, as
well as evaporative cooling. So, this
has to do with transpiration rates. How
much water can these trees actually pump
into the air to cool things down over
time, small density, things like that.
So, there's differences across species.
Um, but these aren't really included in
tree selection decisions. Um, the most
you'll probably get from these sort of
things is like, um, how big is this tree
going to get? Is it going to get in the
way of power lines or something like
that? And also, um, is this tree
actually going to survive in this
location? But in terms of a lot of these
species level differences, we don't
really have that information. And we
don't really have good information about
what trees are where in the city of New
York. Um we have some information quite
a bit but we don't have information
about where they all are which is really
needed to reduce heat and health impacts
more precisely. Um so maps of tree tax
are really needed to reduce heat more
precisely in cities. And because of this
um we can actually estimate cooling at a
scale that's more relevant to urban
residents. Um, if you're thinking about
a large um, neighborhood area, a lot of
this uh, health analysis is done at like
census blocks or census block groups, it
may be shady and cool in one part of the
neighborhood but not the other part of
the neighborhood. And that's an issue
because if you're walking down the
street um, in your particular part of
town, um, if you don't have many trees
in your street, what does it matter that
that park has tons of trees just down
the road? Um, and so there are many
methods from remote sensing to do tree
identification, but getting down to
genus and species level stuff is just
pretty hard in general. Um, big issue is
that midsummer, uh, you may have
experienced this yourself, green trees
kind of all look the same. Um,
especially from multisspectral images
like a lot of the satellite data we
actually use. Um, but at certain times
of year, trees can look very different.
So, I'd like to show you one of the few
windows in Bradfield Hall. Um, this is
looking north. Um Dan took a bunch of
these pictures and um what you can see
here is that these are a few different
times of year. So summer on the top left
trees all look pretty green but spring,
early fall, late fall they look kind of
different. So if you're looking at this
particular tree over here, well it's
turning yellow while other trees are
sessing a little bit. Um but this one
over here um it's not quite the same
color as the other one. So perhaps
they're different species. Maybe we can
lean on this type of information to get
at um different types of seasonality. So
can we use deciduous phenology to
classify trees? And by phenology I mean
the seasonal timing of um different
events in nature. So in the case of
deciduous trees, when do they put out
leaves? When do they lose leaves? How
does this timing differ year to year in
between species? So urban trees have
been classified for multiple seasonal
images recently. So you take a big stack
of satellite data, you throw that all
into a big classifier. Um you can do
pretty well with that. Um but what there
haven't been before is that
classifications based on the time series
that actually deres uh the phenological
dates. So like what is a precise date
you could give to a model to say oh what
is the leaf out in the start of spring.
Um so what we can do is we're aiming to
identify taxonomic differences at fine
time scales. Uh which all sounds well
and good but actually getting the data
to do this is not the most
straightforward thing in the world. So
there are kind of some data requirements
to this. Um, one of the big trade-offs a
lot of the time with satellite imagery
is different types of resolutions.
Usually you can get pretty good uh
temporal resolution, so lots of
observations, but the pixels have to be
pretty big. Um, but if you're dealing
with something that you want to get lots
of precise measurements, you need high
spatial resolution as well. Um, so
fortunately, Planet is a commercial
satellite company and they have a
constellation of satellites called
Planet Scope that both has high spatial,
roughly 3 meters, and high temporal
resolution imagery. So you can get
observations almost every single day.
And the way they get around this is by
launching hundreds of these small sats
that take observations pretty often. Um,
so we can do that and lean on that to
look at individual trees and their
seasonal timing, but we also need good
label training data to actually predict
on. um you can't do uh a classification
without having some good training data.
And thankfully the city of New York has
um tree stem and ID database from a
street tree database where people
literally went out and hugged a million
trees in New York City and labeled them
um with different genus levels, cultivar
quality, status of the canopy, which is
awesome, but that's still less than 20%
of the total number of trees in New
York. So there's still a lot of places
that need to be filled in. Um, and also
you need a good tree crown polygon data
set because you actually need an object
that you're putting a label on.
Otherwise, you're just doing pixels and
it could be pretty noisy. So,
thankfully, um, there's already been,
um, classification of tree crown
polygons, um, from citywide LAR flights.
Um, we tried to make polygons ourselves
from LAR. Um, it's pretty challenging
and so we'll we're thankful that this
data set already exists. Um so the
research goals from this um examining
the differences the first step in this
and examining the differences in urban
tree phenology by taxa in New York City.
And so the main research questions for
this is how can satellite based
phenology be used to actually separate
urban deciduous tree taxa in New York
City. Uh one of the key things to keep
in mind and how why we're getting away
with this technique in place like New
York is that it's mostly deciduous trees
like over 90%. If you were doing this in
a place with a lot more evergreen trees,
like let's say Seattle or Miami, you'd
have a lot harder time doing this and
this may not be the best technique for
you. Um, some other questions, temporal.
So, what is the year-to-year variability
of spring leaf out? Like, in terms of
the start of season among different
types of trees, and also spatial. So,
how does spring leaf out vary spatially
across the city? Maybe you're a tree in
Manhattan, you're a real go-getter, you
leaf out early. Trees in Brooklyn, maybe
not. I don't know. It's So, we'll have
to just take a look at it.
Um, we're also going to look at the end
of season, but it's going to be a lot
more challenging. Um, so here's an
example of tree data in Flatbush,
Brooklyn. This is a little bit south of
Prospect Park. Um, what's cool about
this neighborhood is that you have a lot
of single family homes with uh trees
individually um across this sort of um
central neighborhood, but larger
apartment blocks over on the side. So,
big differences in the amount of tree
cover you have. Each one of these
colored points is a street tree that the
parks and recck department actually
labeled and so different colors are by
different uh tree species. So there's a
lot of these points which is awesome but
there's still a lot of places that are
missing. So this is what this tree
polygon data set looks like on top of
that. Um and this is from the Nature
Conservancy and the University of Mont
Spatial Analysis Lab. Um so this data
set is really cool because we can
actually put labels to all these trees
for the places that are missing. Um, so
how do we actually get there? Um, we
have this map of tree stems from the New
York City parks and wreck. And what we
want is a final map of all the trees
labeled in New York City, right? No big
deal. It's fine. Um, how do we actually
get there? Uh, we use this planoscope
satellite time series, light our tree
crown polygons and structure and also
air temperature data to look at what
time of year should trees leaf out based
on accumulated how warm is this
different place um in the city. So for
each tree crown polygon, extract this
time series of reflectance from planet
scope um reflectance time series, clean
this up, extract key phenology data and
then also um light our structural
variables. So like how tall is the tree,
how big is the crown, what how dense is
the canopy and air temperature related
data. And so we have this suite of
different information all for this
individual tree.
Um, so we can use the labels of tree
stems from the New York City parks and
wreck as our reference training and
validation data set. So this is the
trees we know what they are and where
they are. And we can use that and
develop a classifier. Yes, I'm using
random forest to classify trees and
apply that classifier to all the unknown
tree polygons across New York. And tada,
we have New York City training data set.
Um, all completed for a final map trees
in New York. But I'm going to talk
mostly about this part up here. Um, in
terms of actually how we get the
phenology information out of this. So
here's from the National Agricultural
Imagery Program, NAPE. Um, if you've
looked at any agricultural data, you may
be familiar with it. They do it in New
York City as well. Um, so this is a true
color air photo from summer 2019, which
is great, but they only do this every
couple of years and right in the middle
of summer, so you can't get much
seasonality out of this. Um so this is
plant scope um which is slightly uh
coarser resolution but much more
observations. I'm showing it in a false
color composite near infrared red green
with near infrared and the red um
display. So plants reflect way more
light in the near infrared. And so
anything that you see on this map is
bright red. That's normally green plants
that you would see with your naked eye.
So here's phenology time series of a
particular oak tree, a very charismatic
one that's well behaved in the South
Bronx. Um, so that's what it is in the
NAPE imagery on the top left um, from
the street. And so this particular tree,
I'm showing the plant scope imagery down
here. Um, and this is a time series of
NDVI through time. And you can see as it
gets bright red in the spring, that's
when it's greening up. And so this is
what we're tracking for every single one
of these tree crown polygons across New
York. And the actual value we're
tracking is the NDVI, which is a very
common satellite remote sensing index
where you're comparing the near infrared
to the red. As this number gets higher,
the plants are greener. Um, and we can
track this
year-over-year. So, for example, for all
the trees that we know, what they're
labeled, um, this is for all the maples
in New York City for 2018 from Planet
Scope. Um, so this you can see a lot of
these are sort of the first week of May
roughly, but you can do this
year-over-year. And so you have
approximate timing of leaf out
variability across every single year
that we have available. Um, you'll
notice there's some year-to-year
variability. For example, 2019 and 2022
tend to be a little bit later. Um, but
what what we can see is that when we can
separate this out further, you can get
down to species level as well. So, for
example, example, silver maple in the
middle here tends to be a little bit
later than red maple or Norway maple.
So, there are some different species
level differences we can get at as well.
Um, so we can do this for other genera.
So, for example, here is platinus. So,
they're plain trees or sycamores. One
thing you'll notice about this one is a
it tends to be a lot later than the
maples, which is uh reassuring because
they probably should be, but also this
year 2019 is super duper late. So we're
looking at like late May for this tree,
which is suspiciously late in some ways.
Um so how do we actually translate
phenology into a classification? Um one
thing to keep in mind is that this is
one particular year in 2019. Um and this
is just separated by different genre.
Um, and this is different months in the
spring box plots showing the
distribution of timing for the trees
that we know. So, for example, based on
this, we could do a pretty good job
separating glitzia, the honeyloust from
Acer, our maples. Um, but getting back
to platinus, it's way way later than
everything else. So, for example, we
should be able to readily separate this
genus based on it consistently spring
leaf out in 2019. What we think is going
on is that there is a anthrachnos fungus
causing delayed spring leaf out. This is
a fungus that causes the plants to
attempt to leaf out in the spring. Then
it looks like they have frost damage or
leaf wilt and the leaves kind of shrivel
up and don't look that happy. Trees look
bare until much later in the growing
season. Then they get their act together
by the end of May and you know summer
goes on. Um but what we can do is that
for an example test case on a
classification we can lean on this and a
few other um structural variables from
the LAR and do like a prototype
classification for the Bronx for
platinus versus other generia genera
just a split and so we get like a 93%
overall accuracy in this. The big points
that you see on here are the actual
labeled street tree stems. Um and so
everything else we label it as either
platinus or something else. And so the
blue you can see a lot of platinus are
labeled in a lot of buildings where we
uh around buildings where we don't have
the street tree labels. So we're
painting everything in um that we needed
new labels for. And we can do this in a
lot of bigger neighborhoods. So for
example, this is a relatively large
apartment blocks. Um and you can see
that a lot of the trees that weren't
included in that street tree database we
can actually provide labels for based on
this. Um so we can do an initial t test
case on this but what about spatial
variation in phenology? So we need some
more information um based on temperature
as well. So this is a temperature data
set um that takes coarser resolution
data downscales it based on um different
uh structural parameters on the surface
like green vegetation impervious surface
things like that. Uh we didn't make this
product, but what's really cool about it
is that it's really high spatial
resolution. So we can get pretty good
information on what is the temperature
accumulation for different trees. So
what's important about that is that if
you have different amount of
temperatures in different locations in
the city, you would expect, oh, if I'm
in this location and it's this warm,
well, what will my leaf out timing be
for this genus versus this genus? If we
have information about, okay, it leafed
out here and it's this warm. Well, we
have a much more better information
about which is which. So, for two
different genre, we might see different
response patterns in air temperature.
Um, and this is where we're kind of
going next steps for this. One other
thing that I've been dealing with the
last week or so is looking at a webcam.
Um, this is what's called a phenino cam.
So, phenology camera. Um, this is at the
top of um in northern Manhattan. Um, and
this is just staring at this park all
the time. So, this is St. Nicholas Park.
Um here it is in um this is beginning of
April
2022. What they look at is like they
take a polygon like this and then work
through it through time. You can see the
trees green up. And so just back of the
envelope um comparing this sort of
polygon shape that they have versus the
trees in this polygon. Uh 2022 we're
roughly the same time. May 3rd, April
29th, which isn't too bad. um 2023 we're
a couple weeks off but um in digging
into the data there may be some issues
with the phenocam and there may be some
issues with the plant scope imagery so
take that one with a grain of salt for
now um but what I'm working on now um is
examining individual trees so taking
little boxes of trees and tracking those
through time individually
um so just some implications for this um
phenology shows promise as a way of
identifying urban tree taxa uh so we
have this platinus classifications of
proof of concept. And there's
separability that currently exists for
other genre, but we're going to build on
this and include temperature phology
relationships and lots of other things
in order to do a better classification.
And so the goal will be well, we're not
going to get every single species across
the entire city. There's just too many
of them. But we can get a lot of the
most populous species. Uh we won't get
populist, that's not in here, but we'll
get a lot of other things. So methods
have potential to be scaled spatially
and temporally. Um, so we could do this
across multiple years if we needed to.
And the eventual goal will be to create
a scalable pipeline that can be applied
to other cities. So if you live in
Cleveland or Chicago or I don't know,
Ithaca, if you had the data, we could do
something like this, which would be
pretty cool. Um, you'll notice I didn't
talk about health at all for the last, I
don't know, 16 minutes. So what's the
big picture for this? Um, we're going to
link tree identity to public health
decisions. And
so my corner, Dan's corner of the
project is in this tree tax of
classification, mapping trees in New
York using the remote sensing and the
phenology product. Um, but what we're
actually planning to do is hand off this
information to colleagues in civil
engineering um in Professor Chi Lee's
group to do genus level classification.
Uh, take that genus level classification
and turn it into an urban heat model. So
they have a model that can run at pretty
high spatial resolution, roughly 100
meters or however much they want to
define it. Um, and include that
information on tree structure and
cooling to be able to have better
information on what is the condition in
different neighborhoods at a scale
that's relevant to people. Um, so when
we have that sort of temperature and
heat information that can be used
related to epidemiology and social
justice. So assessing marginal effects
species on like emergency department
visits like if you have certain amount
of certain types of trees in a
neighborhood, comparing those
neighborhoods, how many department
visits do you have during heat waves or
other times a year and also those uh
different types of health effects of
these trees into urban greening
decisions and public health policies. Um
so that includes colleagues at wild
Cornell um including Arnav Gosh and Wesi
um colleagues in natural resources and
also in other um parts of um around New
England as well. Um and so additional
acknowledgements um colleagues at the
Nature Conservancy and the Natural Areas
Conservancy, two separate organizations
with similar sounding names um and some
other information were um from
colleagues at American University and
CUC Santa Barbara to help with the PL
and scope data. So, I'm going to leave
this up for the end and feel free to ask
any questions and thanks for your time.
So, many cities are considering what's
going to happen with climate change and
how that's going to have to change the
kinds of trees they plant in a given
location. Are you contemplating
those issues in your in your work? Yeah.
So the question is about
um with climate change is that
information in terms of what the tree
species pallet should be um included in
our work and how we're we're looking at
that. Um we're not addressing that
specifically, but that is definitely a
question longer term. Um and it could be
something where you look at different
parts of the city and say, "Oh, this
part of the city is warmer. You could
use the survivability in this part of
the city to compare and project in other
parts." Um there's stuff being done in
terms of like moving different genotypes
and planting those that are from further
south. Um so we're not dealing with that
end specifically, but that's definitely
a consideration for sure.
Uh I really like the uh the animation,
the time series animation with the DVI
going up and down. I was expecting that
thing to kind of plateau and stay kind
of high fairly level, but it's kind of
it peaks and then starts going down. Is
this uh typical of all trees doing this
or is this something that could be used
uh for uh maybe differentiating trees?
Yeah. So that's pretty typical for for
trees. It peaks and then it's Yeah. And
you get you get a peak and like around
Juneish and then it slowly kind of
declines through the summer. Um it's
still a dense canopy through the summer.
It's just they're not as bright vibrant
as you would have first thing in the
growing season. Um so yeah, that plateau
isn't necessarily totally flat.
Yeah, really cool.
Yeah, that was great. Thank you. It's so
nice to hear more about what you've been
working on. Um, kind of related to this
last question. I'm curious if um like
there are other um like land surface
phenology metrics besides just start
season and end of season that kind of
describe that curve um in more detail.
Have you guys looked at how some of
those other metrics might vary across
the species in terms of helping to parse
those out? Uh, so the question is about
um other land surface phenology metrics
besides just start of season and end of
season. Uh, and we've looked into it.
Um, but we haven't actually gotten too
far with that yet. So there's other
stuff we can fit in that curve besides
what I'm showing as start of season, end
of season. It's just like the 50% point
on these S-shaped like these sigmoid
curves. But you can do different times a
year and a lot of these other phenology
models will do stuff where they have
like here's the max, here's this mid
mids slope decline, lots of other things
like that. Um, I think for now we're
just going to stick with these and then
build out from it. One thing we actually
want to try to do is actually lean on
the color component of it more and see
if we can pick out individuals that have
really distinct color situations uh
different parts of the year. for
example, like GKO trees, like that GKO
tree out there turned like this electric
yellow in the fall and if we can capture
that, that would be really helpful. Um,
so yeah, I want to think about that more
for sure.
Does your system allow you to um capture
like invasive trees? I mean, I'm
thinking, you know, New York City, Tree
of Heaven, Bradford pears, which, you
know, a lot of folks certainly wouldn't
want to see or at least an increasing
number. So, I'm just wondering, have you
come across that as being an issue?
Yeah, I mean, if so, the question is
about can we capture invasive trees? And
the answer is if if they're in the data
set already and there's enough of them,
we can probably label them. Um, we don't
have 100% like what the classification
level is going to be, but heaven, um,
Atlantis, there's enough of them that we
should be able to get those. Um, but if
they don't currently exist, so there's
very few, it's they won't show up in the
classifier. Yeah, unfortunately.
Nice talk. Dave, I have a question
coming back to your very original
motivation like the cooling different
cooling factor from different species.
Um I was wondering how your class map
can be combined with ET like M is doing
to do the optimize like special
distribution of different tree species
uh to
basically to best mitigate the the heat
um way in in the future. I think that
that's probably most important. And also
the second question is have you
considered the uh air quality impact
because a lot different trees in many
like iso prints right that's a huge air
quality issue. So I think the
optimization like with the different
cooling effect and also air quality
should be included in your like the
downstream work.
Thanks. Yeah. So the first question is
about um looking at um different species
types and the vapor transpiration and
how their cooling will be included in
the model. um we're talking about that
and we're not 100% sure how that's going
to slot in exactly. The first factor is
leaf area index of course um which is
just the amount of leaves you have over
the surface. Um but what we would like
to do is look at like the tri database
and look at different species um cooling
capacities and be able to work with the
restly um to include what we can in the
model. Um so that's still a work in
progress. Um the second question is
about um air quality measurements and uh
I I know Dan's very interested in air
quality. Uh so yeah, we've been talking
about some of the stuff related to
pollen and um but other things related
to like VOCC's. Um we'll talk about that
more because there's a lot of cool
implications that can come out of a
classification once once we have it. But
yeah, thanks. All right. This has been a
production of Cornell University on the
web at cornell.edu. edu.