this is a production of Cornell
University so good afternoon everyone
thank you for
coming um so I thought it would be
interesting to give an update on on the
adap end technology and uh uh
specifically how uh integration with
other software platforms is really
critical if you want to bring this kind
of technology to um to the farming Comm
Community before I do I want to
introduce this gentleman here is
Professor Rafael Otto he's been here for
a few weeks now but I hadn't had a
chance to introduce him he's a professor
uh at the of soral science at the um
university of sa Paulo in Brazil and so
he's uh interested in this particular
Topic in improving nitogen
recommendations so um with that so Kevin
will do the uh the second part remotely
he is in Minnesota right now uh but we
thought it would be a great way to kind
of talk about uh the uh the opp
opportunities around this kind of
integration okay uh so quick uh overview
so
adapten um has a bit of a history coming
out of uh Cornell out of my program very
much a team effort and um we um rolled
it out in 2008 which is already 16 years
ago and uh then in 2013 we decided that
uh it wasn't um good to remain in the
public space and uh so we uh decided to
license it to a startup company um and
then uh we continued working on it and
it became a cloud-based uh uh solution
and we did a lot of uh uh on fire
validation of the of the technology then
in 2017 was a was a great year for us at
uh the startup company was acquired by
Yara International which is uh big
Global uh crop Nutrition Company it's a
Norwegian company they're in like 160
countries or so uh we want a big
International price around the same time
I think they were only a month apart so
was was a very nice time um working also
on API integration so integration with
other software
systems and then uh earlier this year
Yara sold the adap and Technology to
ever a which is a really a u sort of
digital uh agriculture
uh platform and so they they have field
management software but also uh
livestock related uh I believe insurance
and financing uh so they're a very big
player in the in the digital uh
agriculture
space um just quickly I'm not going to
go into details but you know uh this has
very much been a a multiple team efforts
uh here at at Cornell
University um as well as when it went
commercial commercial uh some very
talented entrepreneurs software
Engineers uh marketing people and all of
that and we also worked with many
farmers consultants in uh you know in
New York in Iowa in in North Carolina
many many other places to uh validate
and and test and refine the system okay
so why why ad OP 10 so nitrogen is uh by
far the most problematic of the crop
nutrients I would say
uh that's not an overstatement I don't
think uh from the uh sort of farmer
perspective it's
costly uh the use efficiency tends to be
relatively low uh because there's a lot
of losses and there's a lot of
uncertainty around it especially as it
relates to weather and uh by uh that
Association also you know High
sensitivity to climate change especially
extreme
events from an environmental perspective
five major concerns uh big energy input
into cropping systems uh nitrous oxide
of course the big greenhouse gas uh
concern groundwater nitrate
levels uh as well as the hypoxia and
anoxia concerns in estuaries the dead
zones and then particulate formation
from ammonia of lization so a lot of
concerns there I'm going to go into a
little bit more depth um so when we
think about the input puts into the
system into a field you might say we
have kind of two major inputs one is
through the biological pathway mostly
legumes or maybe some free living
bacteria of course the synthetic
industrial uh process Hab BOS notably
takes a lot of
energy um Berkland a by the way is an
older um uh technology that was
developed by Yara at the time norsk
Hydro uh that now is gaining some
interest because of the green interest
in green ammonia uh using renewable
energy um and then of course a lot of
you know uh there's a lot of cycling of
this organic nitrogen uh through the so
organic matter or inputs or residues or
things like that so you have all these
different sources of nitrogen that you
have to deal with and then you have a
fairly complicated nitrogen cycle and I
won't go into details but you have all
these inputs that I U mentioned and most
of the
Transformations that happen in the soil
are microbially mediated so that means
that they're impacted by the the
environment you know the temperature
water but also crop management practices
and all of those kind of things most
nitrogen in Aerobic environments ends up
in the nitrate form and thereby is then
subject to losses so either leeching
losses or denitrification losses both
being obviously very problematic and
then these uh Transformations and and
the associated crop and availability can
change dramatically in very short uh
periods of time especially if you get a
lot of rainfall so that's a challenge a
little bit about the hypoxia Zone
because that's very relevant in uh when
you are dealing with n especially in
corn production systems you're probably
most uh most of you are familiar with
that especially in the Mississippi River
Basin uh the large uh so-called dead
zone that develops typically in mid to
late summer and uh this past year this
is an updated graph it uh The Dead Zone
was again about the size of the state of
New Jersey very large area where um
basically most of the uh uh the fish are
being killed because of a lack of oxygen
um and U and this is the uh I should
say this is the level of the hypoxia
task force goal Which is less than 1,900
M square miles
and uh they have not been able to reach
that for quite a while so a lot of money
being poured into it but relatively few
results um the hypoxia Task Force is is
pushing the states to uh reduce their uh
nitrogen
losses uh and reduce them by 45% that's
what these two states they're big corn
states of course what their goals are um
long-term 45% with no timeline which is
very convenient uh
but for 2025 they said minus 15% uh
which as far as I know has not been
reached I don't think that they've tried
that hard quite
frankly the greenhouse gas emissions so
nitrous oxide is about
18% of the global greenhouse gas
emissions uh so a little less than let's
say
one5 um the I think what's notable is
how little attention it gets and uh most
of the attention goes to carbon dioxide
and of course methane for us a it's uh a
little over 50% of the greenhouse gas
emissions are associated with nitrous
oxide uh and that's more than the
methane by the way doesn't this look
like a like an a precedential polling
result of the past few days especially
with the red and the blue and all of
that you know but it's not um but it
seems kind of tough but anyway so uh so
pretty significant right uh and very
little attention being paid to it U for
New York sorry you can't see that it has
a little thing here with that's a that's
a zoom thing uh it's about onethird Is
nitrous oxide we have a lot more
livestock especially dairy industry uh
in New York so methane is is is a bigger
deal um I think the nitrous oxide uh
estimates are a little low for New York
um but New York is all in on the on on
the methane it's a Millions of dollars
are going to that very little as far as
I know uh on the nitrous oxide
issue okay so in order to understand uh
why it's difficult to affect change with
Farmers on on niten we need to
understand the risk so farmers are
inherently Risk Managers you got to have
nerves of Steel to be a farmer these
days so um if we have here an economic
Optimum end rate that's that's the the
perfectly right 9 rate for a particular
crop in a particular field and you know
think corn because that's our Focus here
so risk is probability times cost and we
have this asymmetric risk for the farmer
that is if they under fertilize because
there's uncertainty around this eonr if
they under fertilize it's a lot more
costly to them than if they over
fertilize because they lose yield and
especially when the grain prices are
high which they were a few years ago uh
they uh they don't want to lose yield
they can't afford that if you over
fertilize you wasted money on fertilizer
okay but that's much less costly that
that's a much lower risk right so the
farmer has an incentive to always make
sure that there's enough nitrogen that
means that they tend to apply excess
nitrogen and that's just realistic
that's just risk management on their
part but from a societal perspective
it's kind of the opposite in that we
like to see Farmers apply less might as
INF fertilizer and not over fertilized
because then you see a lot of losses
some of our work some of the work that
was done at M Michigan State where we've
been able to demonstrate once you exceed
the planned update you obviously have a
lot more losses right so this is kind of
uh uh opposing interests right so what's
the solution to that well from our
perspective the solution is to get this
uncertainty down to very minimal so that
we can estimate what is the proper
uh nitrogen rate for your crop in any
particular field in any particular year
in any particular location
okay so the industry um let me get rid
of that okay
here the industry response to that has
been the four RS of nutrient management
so right Source right rate right time
right place that's what they're what
they're promoting right uh great concept
but the problem is what's right how do
you define what's right
okay uh and especially when it comes to
rate the problem is that the rate is is
is the right rate is defined by the
other three Rs Source time place as well
as weather and many other factors okay
so it's a complicated issue just to
illustrate that it this is data from uh
Iowa State
University uh that shows um the economic
Optimum n rate from many n response
trials over for number of years and many
locations that shows uh quite quite a
distribution right so one could ask the
question well what's what's the proper
what's the correct nitrogen rate right
it's very very difficult to decide that
it can be from 50 to 250 this core after
soybean right so you can throw up your
hands you say well is there maybe
something underlying that causes this
variability now the ISU recommendation
is this one here around
150 so that would mean that uh in about
a third of the cases you would under
fertilize in about two-third of the
cases you would over fertilize okay so
obviously having a very generalized
recommendations which they do I mean
it's remarkable the state of Iowa number
one corn State the recommendations is
the same for every field and every year
in the state every soil type everything
okay um we can do better than that so um
so some of the work that we did starting
maybe about 25 years ago where we uh
started to look at this uh temporal or
or weather induced variability so Jason
kahabka uh who some of you may know as
the associate dean of the grad school
here uh he was a master student with me
so like in one case we needed 110
kilograms per hectare in another year we
needed 220 right I mean huge differences
this is here at the musra farm in New
York Shan sbgi who was a PhD student
started to work with the Lea model and
said hey wait a minute we can kind of if
we incorporate weather information we
can sort of simulate these effects and
that was basically the idea behind adapt
end to say we can make better
recommendations by incorporating these
factors so more recently some uh work
came out of uh Illinois where they did
The Meta analysis of many site years in
the US and Eastern Canada where they
looked at you know what's the source
main source of variability in this
economic Optimum in rate and it was
basically weather so especially
precipitation okay two3 of the
variability was weather related so you
don't incorporate weather into your
recommendations you miss a lot of the uh
information that's critical soil factors
was second about 10 to
23% and then they said well you need to
also account for risk which of course we
had already been working on at that time
but it was nice to see that
confirmed you know some of the earlier
work that we did and uh justification
for use like a that use like a tool of
that
then um but most of the uh
recommendations that are being used
around the United States and actually
anywhere else in the world almost um are
either static or there are what we might
call Dynamic and and and adaptive so
static is basically the one that I just
Illustrated with Iowa State the official
New York recommendations are also static
they're relatively simplistic they don't
account for WEA uh as a source of
variability the other category is the
dynamic or adaptive approach it can be
soil testing like a ps&amp;t uh it can be
canopy sensors or it can be models which
is really what the area that we sort of
started to work in and they each have
their pros and
cons the main question however is does
it give you a good recommendation you
can have fancy equipment but if it
doesn't give you a good rate then what's
the point right so you have to prove
that the other kind of complicating
factor is that a lot of these
recommendations are based on very simple
cropping systems like corn after corn or
corn after soye okay but now we're
interested in more diverse type of
cropping systems in a sort of
multiobjective environment we're care
about Cal Health about carbon
illustration about water quality about
energy about greenhouse gas emissions
and so we're bringing in these more
sustainable type cropping systems or
regenerative uh rotations cover cropping
uh using more organic inputs we have
higher yielding uh crop genetics all of
those kind of things we have better
fertilizers right so if you just base
all your recommendations on these very
simple systems you're missing some of
the technological uh
Innovations so that really was the the
whole point of adap 10 so this here
shows the adap in as an Standalone user
interface the way uh it was originally
offered so Kevin is going to be showing
how this technology is better integrated
with other field management systems
because that's what farmers are using
Farmers don't want to use a standalone
piece of software they wanted to be part
of another piece of software that
already has a lot of the data in there
okay
so what are some of these inputs for
adaptin and I'm not going to go into
details some of it is sourced
automatically like climate data uh soils
data as well we have our own uh soil
databases and then there's user in
inputs on basically soil and crop
management practices right uh fertilized
applications manure Etc but you'll see
that some of these kind of regenerative
practices are also included in that
cover cropping rotations organic
amendments and and all of those kind of
things very important um and then the
model basically discretizes the soil
into layers and then it discretizes in
time on a daily basis so uh based on uh
daily climate data are the simulations
that then generate a
recommendation so just quickly about
some of the results and this is uh a
graph that was actually developed by Jim
shephers from the ARs after we shared
the data with him um and this this is
based on uh field validations where we
had uh strips in a field where we had an
adapt end rate and we had a grower rate
whatever the grower used to apply and um
and you see on the left side of the
graph those were the uh situations where
adapt end recommended less nitrogen than
what the grower was using and you can
see that there was virtually no yield
loss on the average no yield loss so the
savings were with the fertilizer that
was 83% of the cases in the remaining
70% of the cases we uh adapt and
recommended more than the grower but it
was justified by a yield
increase okay so this is kind of the
situation that that you want in most
cases you reduce your end rate but you
acknowledge that especially in wet years
you may actually need a little bit more
nitrogen but overall you can actually
have considerable benefits in terms of
profits both in terms of saving a
fertilizer or avoid avoiding yield
losses
in terms of the environmental losses um
we you can simply by using a more
precise recommendations you can
significantly use your environmental
losses so on the left is uh is leeching
losses any of the dots above the one to
one line meant that there was a
reduction in leeching losses from adap
10 relative to uh Growers and the same
on the right side with the gaseous
losses so 36 to 39% reductions simply by
not over fertilizing basically in in a
vast majority of of the cases without
any yield
losses so we also did uh work with some
third parties uh notably University of
Nebraska has a great uh on Farm uh trial
Network really fantastic um and so they
were interested in testing adap then and
uh so you can see on the left there um
that uh for one of the field they had
several of the fields I'm just showing
for for one field at adapt end
recommended a much lower rate than the
canopy sensor or the what the grower was
using but you can see that the yields
are basically the same so that's a good
situation right same yield with less
nitrogen um they also did some multi-
rate uh trials where you can determine
the economic Optimum end rate and they
compared adap 10 with uh grower uh
another commercial product that's now
off the market from Cava uh and then
uh University of Nebraska
recommendations and you can see that
adap ended very well in terms of
following that onetoone line which is
really uh what you want to do so um so
it's been nice to have third parties do
some
evaluations okay before I hand it over
to Kevin uh wanted to maybe talk about
some of the learnings from doing this so
having a product and and integrating it
with commercial software so first first
commercialization is critical adapt end
would be dead died on the vine if we
didn't license it and partner with the
commercial Company software integration
as Kevin will show is critical for
scaling you want Farmers to use it you
got to you got to you got to integrate
it with other software systems and these
cloud-based uh software end Solutions
have very distinct advantages especially
when it comes to scaling it's Rel you
don't need to buy equipment or anything
like that you can scale it up relatively
quickly so specifically for adap
in um Yara when it was still within Yara
did an the marketing department did a
survey of adap 10 users and the number
one thing that they really valued was
the scientific validity it does matter
to them there's a lot of stuff out there
very muddy waters but they like the
scientific validity the customer turn
rate is uh relatively low so most people
that start to use it app then want to
keep using it they don't say doesn't
work and they throw it to the site so
that's good um third party providers
offer additional scaling so both Yara
and now ever do work with what are
basically competitors and say they make
they will make adap in available uh to
them so that's you have that additional
scaling and then uh and this my my
experience is that the the the public
sector really struggles with this kind
of Technology they like the old
recommendation systems that are very
simple and then you have much more
Innovative improved technology and uh
both within the landr university system
as well as like state agencies they
don't really know how to deal with that
and uh and so that's uh that's a topic
for another discussion at some point in
time anyway uh so with that I now I'm
going to hand it over to Kevin who is in
Minnesota and he's going to do a
demonstration of the adapt end tool
within the field allytics uh field
management software system so within
their their platform okay uh Kevin uh
you can take
over go ahead and start sharing
excellent thank you Harold um appreciate
the time appreciate the invite to
present field allytics and the
integration of adapt and into field a
lytics um to this group uh little bit
the history
that I have um that I think is is
important in my role today is I spent 25
years in production agriculture in the
retail setting um started off out of
college have a BS in geography with GIS
started off with a crop consultant um
teaching basically University extension
people throughout the United States on
how GPS is going to work in tractors how
it's going to work in combines and and
how the data is going to be used so I've
been in this game um quite a long time
and the thing that I always um been
working towards is efficiencies how do
we make the tool more efficient so we
can get it to more people and that that
is one of the drivers on why I um left
retail and went to Yara with adap Den um
back in April of
2023 um my goal was is to help them
understand retail better
understand the grower at the farm gate
better so we could build a tool that
could help with a lot of the issues that
Harold talked about and the the thing
that really hits home is is Harold
mentioned the
eonr and we in universities and and you
and people who are researching we
understand that nitrogen is is finicky
right but when you try to convince a
grower that they need to cut 40 to 50 to
60 pounds an nitrogen out of their
program It's A Hard Sell um they'd
rather pay the money for the extra
nitrogen to not have the yield loss so
we're working in conjunction trying to
to help ease some of that pain and and
this tool has really opened up a lot of
eyes but we need to get to a lot more so
if there's 96 million acres of corn in
the United States today we're running in
about 500,000 Acres of that so we're not
even you know the tip of the iceberg
here on the number of fields and Farms
that we can touch and help manage
nitrogen better and um and for the
industry for the environment for
everything it's it's the right thing to
do and that's why I'm excited to take
this job with ever
egg as a product manager is now I'm
helping the developers and our modelers
make things more efficient um and put
into this software so I'm just going to
give you a little rundown of the
software usually our software demos take
two sometimes three hours depending on
questions so forgive me I'm going to
condense this into 20 minutes and um you
know do the best I can in that 20
minutes so basically the software this
is a we call it an fmis a farm
management information system it's not a
true GIS because I can't write scripts
in it I can't do a lot of third party
stuff but but we have grower farms and
Fields and this would be what a typical
retailer would look like where they
would have different locations and then
they would have within that location
they would have Growers and then a
grower would have farms and I'm going to
just share this my little demo Farm here
that I Call KOA adop in So within that I
have I have a handful of different Farms
that I manage and I'm looking at and if
I were a a retail agronomist or a grower
that had access to this and I wanted to
look at my Farms I I could come to this
dashboard and I could pull up this
dashboard and quickly look through what
are my nitrogen needs for today so this
RX is giving me a A Min average and Max
nitrogen need for each of these fields
so I can see this Field's calling for
137 pounds of nitrogen today this Fields
98 pounds this Fields 130 pounds and I
can I can click around and I can open up
the map and it'll Zoom to the map and I
can see what what encompasses that
recommendation I can look through uh I
can click on a cell and it'll tell me
what is needed I can look over here and
see that um on the right side I can see
a a few of the metrics for that field
such as planning date rainfall since
planting and again this is current day
so we're looking at all the information
set up I can see I don't have any
applications set on this field and I got
a little bit left to do but this is this
is the area that um the retail
agronomist or the crop consultant will
spend they'll come in here on a daily
basis and look or you know when it's
that when it's on schedule to say I need
to see what's going on in these fields
they'll come here just to see where
that's
at the real the real power of this tool
is um having an integration with field
allytics is the ability to batch process
or do batch things in batch so I'm going
to just come back out here to my grower
level and I'm going to come in here to
configure fields on adapt end so the
first thing I can do every field that I
have a check mark in I already enrolled
into the program so if I if I have a
grower come and say I need I want to
enroll these three Fields I can come in
here I can say click that I can hit
enroll what it does then is it starts to
process and sends that through the API
to the adapt end model it starts
building out the soil types the
autogenerated um layers that Harold was
talking about um our goal in the future
is to make more layers automated and as
I click through some of these layers I
you you'll get an idea of how we might
want to do that
but that's the start of that and I'm not
going to hit enrolled because I don't
want to enroll any extra Acres that
aren't enrolled because it um it will
trigger an
invoice so once I have the fields um
enrolled then I can start to I can start
to um configure them so I can just pick
a couple Fields here and I can go into
configure selected so now what I'm doing
is I have these two fields that I have
not configured yet I I have them in a
rle but I haven't configured I can come
in and I can do them individually or I
can do them in a batch so I can say okay
my expected yield on these fields is 225
bushels I'm going to have 105 day corn
and I plan to plant somewhere around
April
15th so I can look at an individually I
can come back in after the fact and say
okay I actually didn't get into this
field until April 20th so now I can just
change that I can also load different
yield management zones so on and so
forth but it's it's really easy to
create a system where you
can um multiple do multiple fields and
this is I could go 10 Fields I could go
20 Fields I could do his whole farm at
this
level so that that's really a powerful
thing that we we had some of that in the
past but not to this level so this
allows us to batch process and enroll
multiple fields at
once for for the purpose of showing you
some uh transparency and and get more
granular with the data I'm going to I'm
going to zoom into just one field and
I'm going to spend most of my time that
I have on on this one
field so the power of having an
integration and using the API to Shell
out to adapt to to grab that information
that nitrogen rck is it allows all of
the data to be in one space so a lot of
the issues that I had as a user of adapt
end when I was back in retail and a lot
of the customer feedback that we get is
that there there are times when you
don't want to leave a software I don't
want to come in here and take my yield
data and Export it I don't want to
export my soil test cuz it's all export
import and you're touching things a lot
of times that you won't have to so if
you have this system where everything is
sitting then you can start to configure
the field um
individually so I can come in here and I
can look and say okay what's my expected
yield so on this particular field I'm
using a a yield potential layer that I
created off of a normalized yield yield
map so I can I can assign different
yield goals to it here or I can take
what the what the data is in my tree
then I start to look at population so
this field they didn't have a variable
rate planter so he just put one flat
population in it I can look at the prior
crop I can change the tillage method
organic matter so I'm using my most
recent soil test Point um I can put in
an emerging State when that crop came up
this field was planted May 18th I or Mar
yeah May 18th and it took a while we we
were very wet this spring in southern
Minnesota um I can add a cover crop if
there was a cover crop to it so on and
so forth so so this screen gives us a
lot of Versatility once all that is
entered it sends the data on its way and
then a wreck comes back and in season
this wreck will update
daily but we shut this off around August
15th August 30th um just because people
are not applying nitrogen after that day
so if I look at this particular field
I can see what the setup is so May 13th
was the planting date I had full
emergence on May 28th I've had 23.4 Ines
of rain since since uh planting
estimated growth stage this stops at BT
so one thing that we're looking for in
the future is how do we how do we expand
this out into the r stages um and does
that make sense or do we just stop it at
VT and and that's it um what is the
maturity class prior crop tillage then
we look at organic matter so this field
has an organic matter range from 1.4 to
13.5 welcome to
Minnesota um that this is a very this is
not abnormal in the region that I work
in so we work a lot with different um
organic matters and that's important
because it's a
mineralization factor that a lot of
people don't take into account when
they're when they're figuring their
nitrogen programs
then our yield targets so this is what I
want to hit on why why one of the major
reasons why the integration with everg
and field allytics is is is big for
adapt end so here I have a yield Target
right everybody has a yield goal going
into the season but it's not always
attained due to environmental factors
that you can't control as Herald
touchdown so if I start this year and I
got a 266 bushel yield goal which is
field has attained that it's been in the
two 60s um it's not it's not
unreasonable to have that goal to start
but then I start to think about all
right I didn't start PL I didn't plant
this field until May
13th um it had kind of a slow emergence
it was cool and wet this spring so how
can I justify changing that rate well
there's a couple different ways that we
can do it and and it depends on what
your Agronomy philosophy is my my
Agronomy philosophy is is I'm going to
look at historical data to see what did
this achieve with similar years so
there's different ways that you can look
to see what was similar what was not one
of the tools that adapt in has um that
we can run in the old user interface is
a multi-year comparison so what this
shows us is what were my nitrogen needs
for this
field the
past the past years that it was corn
because I just wanted to to simplify it
a little bit I can go back to 20 2010
and do every year but I skipped a few
years and I wanted to look and see okay
what's similar so this 2018 seems pretty
similar to what 2014 is for loss
recommendation and rainfall so then I
start to look at my data and say okay
what happened in 2018 in this field and
I can load up the 2018 yield data and I
can look at this and say hm well I had
170 bushel yield
average and I had quite a few areas here
that this this spot here was 89 bushel
this spot was 63 bushels over here on
this little sand on this little wet hole
was 93 bushels I did I did obtain some
okay yields
215 200 so my first thought is is I am
going to reassign my yield um estimates
because the 266 bushel is not accurate
or realistic
so how do I do that well I could take
this past Year's yield data but I don't
really want to do that because it's not
exactly what's going to happen this year
so I'm I'm going to go back to inseason
imagery so what I'm going to do is I'm
going to come in here and I'm going to
look through my inseason imagery so
imagine with me it's it's July 15th and
the Corn's about v18 V16 and I'm going
to Y drop it so what I would do is I
would come in and find the most recent
image closest to that day obviously if
it's July 15th none of these would be
populated yet so I'll look at this July
12th
image and when that image comes up it's
going to show me the ndvi so now I can
see what is my crop Vigor in those spots
and I can tell I've got almost crop
failure or really poor
um
Leaf reflectant in those areas so I can
assume that these are poor yielding
areas I could also go out and Scout that
I can send this to the field of litics
mobile app I can look at this image as I
go out there and I can verify on foot as
well if that's the issue so I'm going to
use this layer so what I'm going to do
is I'm going to create a new yield
potential for it and and I would come
into this tool and say create yield
potential and I'm going to call it
uh July
12th yield adjustment
and I have to tell what commodity I'm on
SO corn
field and bushell's breaker so it's
taking these numbers from a database
that that ever EG has generated off of
Nas data based on historic yields so
it's saying in this field the range is
going to be from 178 to 276 on a normal
year on an average year so I create that
and then I can come in and look at that
created
takes just a minute as it rasterizes
that
data so now I have this yield estimation
layer and I I can edit that as well so
because it's going off of averages and I
don't feel that I'm above average or at
average so I can do that two different
ways I'm going to take this back to what
I feel is appropriate for That season so
now I'm going to go average yeld 210 and
my range is going to be from 134 to 232
so I can submit that
and now I've got a yield potential layer
that I can load into adap n that will
change the rre accordingly based on the
those yield
estimates so I come back into the adapt
end
configuration and under expected yield
I'm going to unlock that
layer and I'm going to change my
expected yield to average to
210 and I'm going to use that July 12th
yield adjustment
number and it's going to give me values
that look like this and I'm going to say
this hole because I went out and scouted
is not going to be 143 belel I'm going
to take that down to 120 bushel and
these areas over here I also looked at
those because I didn't feel that those
were and I'm going to take those to 150
so you can be it gives you gives the
agronomist the opportunity to
um change things on the fly as they see
fit they might say where the field that
where it's good is really good and and
then you could change that to
245 um you know whatever you felt that
number was so then you save that
configuration and now what is doing is
hitting the API sending that data
to um the adapt
n
model and it takes just a minute because
it's it's a you know
it's this is it tells me that my
configuration was complete and that
adapt end accepted the the configuration
changes so then it usually takes about 2
minutes for it to come back so in those
two minutes you know I I'll go to
another field I'll look at something
else on this maybe look at some
statistics
or try and figure out what my next step
is with with
that like I said it it the calculations
there's quite a few calculations that
are being done on it um it's no slower
than if we were in the user interface um
working within the model
itself so I'll just give it a minute um
the other things that that are really
great about being integrated is the
transparency so I can look at um my soil
test I can look at my phes and I can
make that I can make a decision if I
want to add pH to the the model or not
some of our users will add it
automatically others might say uh pretty
neutral I'm not I'm not going to mess
around with it it's just another
variable so you know you could look at
this and say okay in this sand area here
I've got some pretty high phes i' I
might want to add my pH to the
configuration if I haven't already um so
there's different different advantages
of being in all the data in one as
applied data so anything that's applied
to the field if the if the controller is
hooked up to field alytic then the data
will come back into the software so we
have access to everything um in one
spot and
again so you can see part of it is back
because the yield has changed to 217
because I changed those high that high
level to 245 but the wreck still is
still is on its
way but we can use what we have and I
can come back to that so the user then
would would then the next step would be
to pull up the PDF off of the field and
what this tells tells us is what's going
on in this field what is happening that
would make that recommendation 91 pounds
and so you can see the range of total
end loss so we can look throughout the
season on what our losses are from the
men and the Max and the
average then I can break that down into
a gas loss or a leeching loss so I
didn't have a lot of gas loss this year
most of my loss came from the leeching
state
um which is normal to the of moisture we
had so here I'm looking at the Field
capacity um of moisture and you can see
how the up and down throughout the
season um and we were wet most of the
Year up until probably early July um
then it dried out and we finally got
back into the fields uh there probably
wasn't a wheel turn spraying or um side
dressing in southern Minnesota from June
10th to July 4th um just that much rain
um so here's you know the different
graphs that we we look at so the grower
and the and the agronomist can can see
what's happening to this field why are
we getting that if we have fall um
application of ammonia then we look at
okay what's mineralizing where are we
getting some winter losses are we
getting you know was it warm here so we
can see this is not normal for Minnesota
in this February March time frame to
have averages of
50 consistently usually it's it's down
here we only have this one cold spell
January February this year so uh for for
winter lovers it was kind of a dismal
winter but for people that like the
warmth it was nice um we can break it
out lost by different soil structure so
sand leeching so this this field the two
red spots in the field sand so we are
losing a lot of nitrogen on that sand so
what do we do we talk to this girl the
next year and say maybe we pull the
anhydrous bar up as we go across those
spots maybe it's not worth it to put
that nitrogen down in those areas and we
we treat it differently or we go to a
all spring Ura application variable rate
and and just start with a lower rate at
that point so those are all the metrics
that that we look at when we're we're
trying to Define what what the wreck
will look like
so now that other wreck is
back so I can look to see now
how the wreck is adjusted by changing
that nitrogen um that yield that yield
goal so we were we're going to go from a
95 pound rate to a 40 pound rate so now
we're looking at a new
recommendation based on
um this lower yield goal which is more
realistic to what the season is so this
is where the user would go
out
um and and take this to the field to
apply and you can see the how much time
do I have left
Harold uh we're just about out of time
yes okay so I I I just want to do one
more thing here so the main thing about
this is a tool that's in this tool set
that's really um powerful is I'm going
to pick this field so I'm I'm going to
get ready to take this to the to the
field to spread and what I can do is I
can come in here and and select this
adapt end only
wreck and I have a product built in here
um called just straight nitrogen so I
just call it adapted nitrogen need and
what I do is I run
this and I do a flat rate comparison so
if you remember this field was calling
for 40 pounds of n so I'm going to
submit
this and this is where you would send
the the prodct to the machine it sends
direct if your machine or asset is
connected we can send it right to the
machine out in the field we don't have
to do jump drives and stuff like that
that we had to do in the old user
interface but what this is showing
is the red areas are being underapplied
and the green areas are being over
applied or vice
versa so in this 50 pound application
rate that we're going to put on this
field
some areas are getting 135 pounds and
some areas should get a lot less than
that and so what it does is it shows the
farmer that if I went out with that 50
pound rate or the yeah if I went out
with that 50 pound
rate some areas I would be under
applying by 110 PBS and other areas I
would over apply by 40
PBS
so by by doing a flat rate application
you're not putting the right product in
the right place and that's the main
point of the 4 hours
is if if I were to recommend if this
person absolutely did not want to do
varable rate and they wanted to um
maximize yield on this
field the recommendation to that grower
would be you need to be somewhere in
that 120 to 150 pound range across the
field because you want to maximize y the
yield at the highest
level so it's it's really unfortunate
that people are looking at what they can
do and not utilizing the tools that are
out there with the GPS and the variable
rate application and and and and it's
getting more and more I mean things are
coming online faster than ever and and
looking forward to where you know the
next 10 years are going to go with with
all this technology and Automation and
and AI um EV valuations of fields and
and data so maybe you don't have to go
out and boot check it or you can use
data imagery more quickly and have more
more images available so um again yeah
appreciate the time I I get excited when
I when I think about all the
opportunities that users have now today
with the DAP in and and just appreciate
Cornell and Harold you know coming up
with the tool and and hopefully we can
continue the relationship to to to
continue to make it better and one other
thing the the university validity is is
a big deal Farmers want that that check
they want that that um I know what I'm
doing is right um and I'm not going to
lose
you great thank you very much
Kevin I hope that gave you a little bit
of a taste of um the benefits that we
have from integration with other
software and the innovations that are
happening on that end and and how we
basically can partner with him Janice
you have a question uh at the 10th
celebration
of school I hope you were there's
presentation I wasn't no okay where he
heralded un
intended in on one of the slides as a
pleasant outcome of the school but
yeah so
congratul Wasing his
presentation really delighted to see so
there was a little bit of her Buckle in
the back when um uh end supplying
capacity of the soil was discussed and I
just want to understand this aspect of
it a little bit better I mean um
andiz your your climate and all the rest
so are you starting from um
a position of having a soil Heth measur
on soil protein for example and then
work that into the bottle how is the end
the capacity of the soil itself being
put into these calculations in account
yeah no that's that's a good question um
so we we we we basically have um kind of
two pools that we're working with so one
is the is the soil organic matter pool
and the mineralization of soil organic
matter and we're basing that currently
on uh basically on uh organic matter and
texture so um uh we're not using any of
the soil health indicators uh that's
something that I'd like to do um but
it's not that widely measured you know
so so organic matter is you know
standard soil testing the other pool uh
is the more layby pool that is
associated with uh sort of these more
recent additions so like a cover crop uh
Kevin didn't have time to really talk
about that but we we you know worked and
Matt Ryan actually contribute Matt was
here right yeah um uh helped uh and um
Steve mky as well had some good data on
You Know cover crop nitrogen uh
contributions or uh previous some of my
earlier work at the willsboro farm on
you know Alfalfa contribution so those
are kind of seen as more L B Pools and
then we had s organic matter pool so
it's uh you know you have to you have to
make shortcuts right you have to so you
have to focus on you know what what
really matters and uh so yeah so that's
basically manure of course is a big
issue and you know being here in New
York we put a lot of effort into the
manure component and U and it's
interesting because the here in New York
especially uh the Consultants so ACS
which is the big uh crop consulting
company their headquarters right here by
the airport on for Road they're
developing new software uh that uh
focuses a little bit more on the dairy
industry and uh so they're going to be
one of the users of adap and through
their own ecosystem through their own
platform basically so but the but the
yeah the the manure manure issue is any
of these organic inputs as you know are
much tougher to deal with then sort of
like a straight you know Ura or you know
uh uh
uh liquid solution or anything like that
so I think we can take a little bit of
Pride on on that component at least that
I think we've done a fairly good job
yeah any other questions
yeah no not that I'm aware of we we did
work with um environmental defense fund
a few years years ago on uh the issue of
a benchmark the end balance uh uh
Benchmark uh and to see how that sort of
related to actual recommendations and
whe you know you'd be able to meet a
certain criteria certain uh inbalance
benchmarks that's about about the extent
of it you know it's been you know one of
the reasons why we uh decided to go and
license it is uh is because it was very
difficult to work with other
universities uh they they um so when you
do an innovation you're uh to some
extent disrupting I mean I don't like
the term disrupting because it's kind of
overused
but within the us we have a land gr
University system and every state has
their own langr University and has their
own nutrient recommendations and we only
have that with nutrient recommendations
we don't have it with tillet or cover
crop recommendations or but nutrients
every state has their own
recommendations system and so our system
was much more Universal and um and so it
was difficult working with the
specialist in each of the land grant
University uh and so we said okay let's
in let's in Just Go the commercial route
and I'm really really glad we did
because you can see the the the result
that if you work with the commercial SE
sector you can really innovate and keep
innovating you
know I the
I we need to talk to the company you
know the the uh the company has an
exclusive license so so they can sub
license uh but Cornell cannot sub
license to someone else but yeah we've
always worked with with other uh
organizations like the University of
Nebraska um Auburn University NC State
University so uh they're uh the company
is very open to you know collaborations
we always are careful that uh because
sometimes you have collaborators who
don't use the the tool properly and then
they say oh it doesn't work it's say no
you didn't use it properly uh so uh
there's but yeah in general they're very
open to that yeah yeah
baru
thisat kinon something I was watching so
complex or
compated very
busy of
things I would say that the that the
vast majority uh of the users are these
consult these people these agronomists
and they could work either with um you
say a co-op uh they could be a private
consultant uh sometimes they work with a
larger company maybe Kevin you can chime
in a little bit on that but I would say
it's now fairly rare that it's an
individual farmer although it may be a
larger farm that employs their own
agronomist you know it's basically you
know it it it probably looked a lot more
complicated than than is you know there
there's not that steep of a learning
curve but you know you always have to
strike a balance between uh you know
people want certain level of
sophistication because they want good
recommendations but if you have a data
driven tool it does require you know
some skills to be able to uh you know to
use it effectively so Kevin do you have
any did you hear that question yeah I I
heard a little bit of it it was breaking
up but I think the the the the gist of
it was I would say 98% of the Acres that
are run through adapt and today are done
through a retail agronomist or a crop
consultant type of business and the
reason is is that farmers want that they
want they request that second opinion um
just like doing their taxes a lot of a
lot of farmers aren't going to prepare
their own their own tax returns um just
because there's so much detail and
nitrogen is the same way a farmer wants
another set of eyes and they want proof
and data to know that they're doing the
right thing Farmers want to be
environmentally sensitive they they
really do but they also have to do it at
a cost and so how do how do we marry
both of those together but I would say
the majority of our users are crop
consultant or retail
anonomous this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu