this is a production of Cornell
University I'm here to tell you today
about our Ash seed collection Workshop
um so we started this effort um actually
three years ago we were funded um about
a three-year Grant from the northeastern
area St and private Forestry Association
and essentially we were tasked with
doing five workshops in New York state
each of the three years to educate
people on um you know the fact that
we're losing our Ash species across the
states and now across much of the East
um and in addition to these workshops we
um were tested with making 150
collections over the course of the three
years of the three most common uh as
species that we have have here in the
state so here on the right hand side of
the slide you have the Latin uh fenus is
the genus for ash so we have Americana
which is the white ash pennsylvanica
which is the Green Ash and which
is the black
ash so just a little bit about um the
Nationwide collection program because
this program you know it extends beyond
our efforts here
um in New York state um as I said it's a
US Forest Service effort so there's
collections happening you know all
over um you know from Ohio down to the
southeast um in
Massachusetts um it's a really big um
almost Nationwide effort that we're a
part of which is pretty exciting and the
general gist of it is that we want to
collect these seeds to preserve the
genetic diversity of um of Ash um and
I'll explain a little bit more about
that um in a second but um in essence
we're losing these species to an
invasive insect amerald ashb which I'm
sure the majority of you have heard
about by now um so these seeds will be
stored um long term up to 50 years um in
a US Forest Service seed bank down in
Georgia um and you know so that way
researchers and breeders will be able to
look at the genetics of these treat
and see if they can't you know breed a
more resistant species or you know look
a little more about why some trees are
more resistant than others um and not
only that you know the potential for
these seeds to be used um in future
restoration efforts once we have um the
problem of Aral ashor under control um
fingers crossed that we do one
day um so to tell you a little bit more
about Emerald ashore um as I said I
assume if you're a citizen of New York
State you have an infestation somewhere
near you um here in the catvills we
unfortunately home to the largest one of
the largest now and fastest growing
infestations in the state um so Emerald
ashor is a little teeny tiny beautiful
insect which is to Asia um it arrived
here in the states a long time ago um
probably in Detroit first and it came in
and packing material um for car parts so
it you know came into those those car
factories that Detroit was famous for um
and started infesting trees in Michigan
and Pathologists were really scratching
their heads over it because trees start
to show symptoms of infestation
before um the bug is actually visible so
you know they'll start dropping leaves
their canopy will thin they'll just you
know look off and they have this thing
called epicormic sprouting which is when
leaves actually come out of you know the
trunk itself or the base of the tree and
it's just a sign of of stress that
they're um the tissues that they use for
transporting nutrients and water are
being
compromised um so it was discovered in
Michigan in 2002 and it came to New York
in
2009 and now it's in over 24 States and
at least two Canadian provinces um
probably more than that it's incredibly
fast moving and hard to track because it
um it will be transported in infested
material like logs and Ash is a very
popular um useful
Timber um the green black and white
species of Ash that mentioned before
they're very Su um and unfortunately
expecting nearly 100% mortality in
forests um in Ash forests across the
state and you can see that it happens
really fast if you live near one of
these epicenters um as I said where I
live in the cat skills that arriv first
in
Woodstock um around 2009 probably a
little earlier it came and um already we
have over 95% mortality um in in those
areas I mean the ash are dead and have
fallen and you know it's the is over so
we're looking at functional extrap of
this species um this is a huge blow to
not only the ecology that these trees
are a part of but you know also
economically as I said it's a very
important Timber species so to take a
little look at you know why this matters
so much as I said you can see on the
left that map um is it's a distribution
of Ash by County so it's kind of like
the density of Ash in each County so you
can see up by Ontario there is a ton of
Ash I mean that's like 30% Ash in those
forests there so this is a huge huge
blow to lose those trees um but it's a
very common tree species throughout the
state um they somewhere around 7% of our
forests are ash and there on the right
is um a map from last year that looks at
sort of um the core areas of uh where
these EAB infestations have gotten
started and how they're spreading so the
black is like you know the are dead and
dying and the red is how it's sort of
spreading out from there um and to see
more updated maps of these they update
them you know maybe once or twice a year
you can look that up on the Department
of Environmental Conservation
website so this is just a closer look at
some of the biggest and fastest moving
um infestations in our state a lot of um
Urban and Suburban infestations Ash is a
very popular Street tree because it's um
you know super Hardy and toer into
pollution and compaction and things like
that so you know a lot of these streets
have um ash trees that are going to be
falling on houses and cars and you know
it's it's a it's a pretty serious
problem across you know many uh sort of
spheres um and one of the ways that
state has been trying to deal with this
problem is by setting up quarantines um
this particular strategy was enacted
last year I think it was maybe last
May or somewhere around there um so
there's
little you drawn stations and they're
trying to limit or regulate um the
infested materials that are moving in
and out of those areas because as I said
it's really
um very hard
to is to pop up because Timber or
firewood is around all the time if you
don't burn pieces to firewood or you
know you're transporting Timber during
flight season one of these little larvae
can metamorphose and just fly out of
that infested wood um as you're driving
along um so that's we have these rules
about don't move firewood more than 50
miles uh crow flies in New York state
because this is how these Forest pest
gets get
transported so you know some of the
other ways to deal with it other than
quarantine
um are removing the trees and replacing
them with something that is an ash um be
great and some native a lot of these um
these Ash are native but um they come
from sort of Midwestern stock um so we
you know we like to think about you
genetically local um seed stock it you
know makes things kind of more
accustomed to vories of our clim and
stuff like that um you can use in ITI
sdes um in do work ases um so long as
they're not you know super infested um
however it's
expensive a beautiful specimen tree or a
great seed producer or something hanging
over your house you know by all means
that's a great option to treat it um but
again you're treat it
for
expensive trols native like woodpecker
non-native um there are a few species of
wasps that are least right now that are
pretty effective
parasitoids um you know however they do
Target some of our native ash
borers um and by the way our na Ash Bor
not a not a
problem is um our ash trees are adapted
and evolved to deal with our native
Ash and then there's seed colion as a
great management option I'll tell you a
little more about that um why we like
seed collection so
much you know outside actual habitat um
so if we can't stop EAB we can take
their seeds and Bank them and ensure
that those trees have a chance of
survival later on in the
future um it's fast and it's inexpensive
which is huge like I said you know
cutting down trees and treating with
insecticides very expensive seed
collection very you know comparably
cheap um you can do it for a long time
and anyone can do it which is why we are
having this webinar because we would
love for you guys to
help um so as I said this grant has been
going on for three years last year we
had a huge season so Ash is am masting
species like Oaks for example which
means that they tend to have sort of a
mass massive seed production year um so
this is kind of to overwhelm seed
predators and stuff like that you just
put all of your seeds into one year and
that way you make sure that at least
some of them survive seed
Predators um so we collected like crazy
last fall we had a ton of volunteers who
were involved in scouting for us um it
was about 75 80 people who were scouting
for us and then we had 60 folks were
actually making
collections all across New York State
um and we New York State uh has divided
into eight these eight um uh Eco regions
so that's how we make sure that we're
kind of um getting a lot of diversity of
different trees growing in different
habitats AC the state so these were you
know evenly dispersed less across the
state um and we made
2 last year which was was way above
150 uh um collections for the actual
grant that obligated to do um we had
tons and tons of white ash um you know
that's a very easy species to find U we
had a good amount of green it's a little
harder to find and then we had not too
much black um and I'll talk more about
later um Mr gr areas where people don't
you know go very often
so didn't get too many collections of
those
oh hold on a second here we go um so we
were thinking you know wow we they see
this go much we got 223 collections what
can we do this year since it's probably
not going to be another Mass year these
trees have really exhausted themselves
by this huge bumper crop year in
2015 so what we did is we thought about
um you know species that are associated
with Ash so what are the species that
are going to for as well once these
trees um that dominate The Canopy die um
and how can we preserve their genetics
their diversity so we came up with a
list um of species that um were well as
I said were associated with these Ash
forests and we did this primarily by
looking at the New York natural heritage
programs um data on ash forests and then
we took out any rare species um any
species that has Orthodox seed which
means that um you can't preserve it for
more than a more than a year it has
really high moisture or oil
content and we came up with 22 species
um and I was hoping that today could go
through some of these because they're
you know they're all relatively common
um but we only have an hour for this
webinar so what I'm going to say is if
you have an interest in Plants um and
you think you would like to do some
collections of these associated species
then get in touch with me um and we can
go through some of the ones you know you
could pick five or or 10 um to kind of
get really really good at identifying
and then um could collect those seeds
and contribute to our seed bank um all
of these plants are um they produce SE
seed in the fall so I've just started
collecting some of them now um it's a
little bit challenged challenging
because you have to collect from um a
large population so over 50 plants um
but it's really fun it's a great way to
improve your plant ID and like I said
it's it's part of this really um big
growing network of of seed collectors
working to conserve native CL so it's
important
work um and we were going to focus on
these associated species this year but
then all of a sudden we started getting
reports that blow and behold some ash we
actually still producing
seeds so since that's sort of the focus
of our grant we um we're continue uh
hammering on fraxinus and trying to get
more collections of Ash seed
particularly the green and the black
ash um so we need your help um so what I
am going to do then is go through if I
can advance this
slide is go through um the ident ation
of these three different common species
of Ash that we have in New York state
and what our seed collection protocol is
and in the hopes that some of you might
be able to help us
out um so this is a white ash um
PRX and I would say this is you know one
of the easier this is the easiest Ash to
identify not only because it's very
common and abundant um but because it
just sort of well maybe I've been
looking at too much Ash but I think it
just sort of jumps out at you uh you
often see it along roadsides and in Old
Fields it's more of an Upland species um
you know it inhabits drier soils than
the other two species that we'll we'll
talk about um but characteristic of the
ash is it has what what we what we know
as opposite leaves so the leaves
actually come off of the main stem um
opposite one another and there aren't
you know too too many other tree species
that are going to do that um you know
the maples do that um box elder does
that that's actually a maple but you
want to make sure the first thing that
you're looking for is those opposite
opposite leaves and opposite
branches and that's a picture of a white
ash there um and White Ash has these
sort of broader leaflets so the those
two things that you're looking at there
th that's an entire Leaf um the little
leaves coming off are known as leaflets
uh which I have pointer
um so White Ash has these sort of more
rounded chunkier wider leaflets uh
whereas Green Green Ash has more lcal
light thinner um leaflets so that's
really good identifying feature also
White Ash has pale undersides so you
could think white ash white undersides
or white ash wide leaflets and then
Green Ash is green green all over Green
Ash also t kind of glossy Sheen to it I
find um a little glossier than the other
two and then here is a black ash leaf
which like I said it's black ash is more
difficult to find because it likes you
know sort of wet lenss or it grows a lot
in the Hudson around here in the sort of
the tidal swamp area so it's not like a
white ash or Green Ash where you're
driving along and you're like oh hey
there's there's an ash kind of rare that
you would be able to see a black Dash
that way um so again in these pictures
here the whole thing that you're looking
at is a leaf and those little leaves
coming off those are leaflets so with
black ash leaflets are sessile which
means that they just sort of sit right
on that Central stem they don't have a
little teeny stem coming off that
connects them to that Central stem that
Central stem is called a racus I'm
trying not to to do too much um
botanical terminology so those leaflets
are just sitting right there on the
stem and um I think another another good
way to determine black ashes it also has
this kind of almost flaky bark in
comparison to the other two which have
quite regular grooved uh some people say
diamond shaped
bark
um and then there are other ways which I
don't I don't find as helpful um to
determine the species you can see the
black ash twig on the left has a sort of
fatter terminal blood Bud some people
call that an ice cone terminal Bud as
opposed to the Green Ash has smaller
terminal
Bud um then you can also look at uh what
we call Leaf scars so if you pull off a
leaf from a stem that little sort of you
know looks kind of like the shape of a
smiling mouth uh where you pulled the
leaf off that's the leaf scar um so you
know a lot of characteristics on these
Ash can be very variable and they can
actually often look like they're sort of
somewhere in between two species and
I'll talk a little bit about that later
but um with white ash often the the leaf
scar looks like this Crescent Moon um so
I know someone who reminds herself of
that by saying white ash white moon so
remembering the shape of that leaf
scar uh the seeds are another great way
to distinguish between V seeds um and
you would be looking at seeds a lot um
when you get really good you can
determine them you know as you're
driving by at 60 mes per hour the um the
Green Ash are in these like really tight
sort of chunky panicles so the whole
aggregation there is called a
panicle um and Green Ash is that picture
on the left see how it's just really you
know big chunky clump of seeds and the
seeds are are narrower as well um and
more I guess tapered than the White Ash
and then the white ash the picture on
the right are much looser much sper
panicles and then looking at the seed up
close um you can see the differences
between the the Green Ash and the white
ash the green being much narrower and
sort of more elongate and the white ash
with that broader Bas and then the black
ash is totally different it's sort of
most oval
shaped um and the black ash well I'll
get into this later actually getting
ahead of myself here um so let's re just
to quickly review the identification of
those species you remember you want to
straight away look for the opposite
branching um and Ash had these what we
know as compound leaves so I said you
know the that whole structure was a leaf
and the little things coming off of it
are leaflets so that's a compound leaf
so opposite branching compound leaves
and then you know make sure you're
looking at multiple characteristics so
you can look at the leaf scar or the
buzs look at the seeds and I think that
the habitat um you know the location
where you're going to find the species
is really helpful too so as I said white
ash is usually more of an Upland species
um it can be found in an area that gets
you know sort of uh with have a higher
water table and then you'll see white
ash will uh start to you know it's
called Ash yellows we start to get a
little stressed because it likes uh some
drier soils Green Ash is in the middle
you know the soil can be moist it can be
dry um and then black ash um really
likes wet wet areas likes wet feet so
it's kind of a spectrum that you have
there okay so moving on to our
collection strategy and
protocol
sorry I'm having trouble with this
clicker there we go um
okay so this is just kind of a an
overview of what we're going to talk
about so we've identified the species um
you're going to want to locate monitor
some good seed trees you know these
could anywhere in your local park or um
your
backyard um your front yard along the
street you just want to make sure that
it's not a planted tree um good way to
determine that is you know you first of
all you identify that it's one of the
Native species it's not an Asian Ash um
and it's not planted in a row you know
sometimes you'll see an ash tree planted
out in the middle um of sort of a a
really neatly Mo um maintained lawn in a
park or something like that it might
be questionable whether that's planted
or not sometimes you can talk to park
staff to confirm that um but you know we
don't want to be Collective
the seeds and preserving the genetics of
these trees that have you know
questionable Origins you we don't know
where they come from we want to be
collecting seeds that we know are native
New Yorkers um you know because we care
about our New York
natives um then I'm going to teach you
how to check for seed maturity because
it's important to collect seed at the
right time um make sure they're not too
insect damaged tell you how to show um
fill out the data sheet how to to pick
seeds and how to handle them when you're
done I mentioned before our sort of
General strategy for this this
three-year program um was to make 150
Collections and those collections um are
divided supposed to be divided evenly
between those three common species so 50
collections of green 50 of white and 50
of black and we exceed those collections
we got 223 however we got you know
something like 150 white uh um 60 green
and then the remainder were black and as
I said that's sort of based upon ease of
of of finding uh since the white is so
easy to
observe um and we're trying to get these
um trees sort of spread more or less
evenly across these ecro regions that I
mentioned before so you can see the map
on the right is a sort of um finer grade
map of some of the Ecco regions across
New York State these e regions are BAS B
on things like you know climate and soil
type and you know how much it rains um
things like this um and again that's
just to make sure we're capturing the
most genetic diversity possible in these
collections so our protocol generally um
you know we're looking for naturally
occurring trees as I said and you want
to make sure your trees are 100 to 300
feet apart so 100 foot minimum between
your trees you if you find Three Trees
sort of in a cluster and they all look
great just make sure they're not super
close because you know it's possible you
could be um collecting from two trees
that are you know connected underground
or something like that we want to make
sure that they're genetically uh as
different and as
possible um you're going to make one
collection per tree so not multiple
collections on One Tree if there's tons
tons of seed just all in one collection
if they seem to be maturing at different
times just all at one
collection then you're going to take a
regular grocery bag you know just one of
those paper bags and it needs to be
filled with at least two to three inches
of seed so it seems like a lot of seed
but generally if Ash is producing seed
you'll have no problem filling it that
high and the paper bags are kind of neat
actually because the first crease line
is is pretty much where we want you to
you know it's sort of a minimum fill
line if you
will and then you're going to need to
fill out the sheet um you're going to
get a twig sample and you're gonna have
to take a couple of
photos it sort of sounds like a lot but
I promise you it's
not but first you have to know when the
seeds are ready to collect so we're
going to go through a few through a few
images of that um so an ash seed the
whole structure is called a Samara or
samura and they're going to start
maturing very soon so some um as early
as mid-september we found last year and
they can really hang on the tree for a
long time so you know into November we
were collecting in and early December
last year and you want to do is you want
to look for a brown seat coat so the
seed is actually inside the samur and
the samur helps with dispersal with wind
um so these seeds can fly away from
their n tree and a good spot to root and
germinate um and the seeds that drop
early we often get a lot of questions
about this are often damaged so don't
worry about picking them up from the
ground because those are natural
abortions um we want to be picking off
of the tree starting around
mid-september the only exception to that
is that black ash seeds don't actually
mature on the tree often they'll drop
off um so you can collect those from the
ground that's that's perfectly fine just
make sure you do these little checks
which I'm going to show you now now to
make sure it's um viable feed so you can
actually peel off exterior of the ca um
as is shown in these pictures and if you
can look closely on the picture in the
right it's actually
revealing um the seed inside that whole
fruit the samur structure and you can
see it has a brown seed coat so that is
key that's what you're looking for that
pale Brown seed coat if you peel it open
and you see that it's green or white or
it's shriveled or it's not filling the
whole cavity then the seed is either bad
or um not yet mature too
early so you want a pale brown seat coat
and you want to make sure it's nice and
plump and
full so here are some good pictures
demonstrating that you can see on the
left that embryo is immature pale green
um and then on the right you can see um
a great looking feed coming out of that
um samura nice and full and it's also
firm so if it seems a little floppy
again you're probably too early it's a
nice firm with a brown pale brown seat
coat um if you don't have the
fingernails to tear open the samurai you
can also use a razor blade but they're
pretty easy to get open and uh these are
just some more cut tests that show you
what it looks like um inside that samura
so on the left there you can see that
this really maybe half of its actual
mature size so not ready and then there
um on the right um same
thing um here are some very goodlooking
seeds nice and full with those brown
seed
coats and then you also want to look for
insect damage because um this is a major
major thing to look for um weevils are a
huge problem um they love Ash seeds um
and you don't want to collect a tree
that's highly infested with weevils
because um you know that seed is not is
not viable it's damaged um so sometimes
you can see that Weevil image on a on a
cut test but you can also just see it on
the
exterior the last
side penetrated
the the fruit to lay an egg and then if
you open it up inside this is pretty
common you can you can see this it's
it's kind of you'll see there's a little
larvae inside who's munching away on
that seed so if you find an ash tree
that has good fruit you know go around
pick some seeds off of each side of the
tree and do an inspection if it seems
like most of the seeds are infested then
just forget it you got a got a bad tree
don't bother collecting from that um you
want to you want a tree where the
majority of the fruits are you know nice
and full and not
infested Okay so we've identified the
tree found a good crop the seeds are
full and mature not damaged the next
thing is to look at the data sheet so
this ash seed collection data sheet I
can either email it to you or you can
find it online at
www.ars.org
um looks little but I assure you it's
very simple basic stuff like date of
collection what your name is what
species you're collecting from where you
are what the Topography is the most
important thing um is to fill out that
little black box in the top right hand
corner which asks for your collector's
ID number and your seed Lot number this
is how we're going to link you and your
seed to the actual and this data to the
actual collection of seeds that you make
um so your collector's ID number is be
your last name so my last name is marand
and then the number um collection that
you've made so if you've made one
collection it would be marand
001 when I make my 100th collection
it'll be marand one Z so that's your ID
number and then the seed Lot number seed
lot ID is Mars B so that's you know just
a way of showing that you are linked to
our project and this information also
has to go on the paper bag that contains
the seed just as I said to make sure the
information on that data sheet is always
linked to that feed and if you're part
of a group you know if you're um you you
as Master Gardeners get together and you
want to do something for your town you
can come up with a unique uh collector's
ID number that's fine and and then it'll
be stored in the bank under your group
name and um you know it ever comes to
the point where you'd like to use some
of your seed for you know restoration or
whatever you can query based upon that
name and there's a picture of the paper
bag that has um claraa my coworker's
last name Holmes it's her first
collection so it's
001 and then it's Mars B that's part of
the project that's that she's working
with that's the
lot so in terms of picking the seeds
very easy very straightforward just make
sure they're mature pick them off of the
panicle you know you don't need to put
any other material in the bag because
that could alter the moisture content of
the bag so just strip the seeds right
off um oh you can also toss them into a
tarp sometimes it I've had this
experience where it's been really windy
when you're collecting and you need need
something a little sturdier than a paper
bag because it just flies away you can
put a tarp under the tree um or have you
know a heavier bucket or something
whatever works for you so this is the
minimum fill line that I was talking
about you can see that crease is right
right at three inches so that's at what
we need at least if you want to fill the
whole bag go for
it then you're also going to need a twig
sample and this is for identific
identification purposes we had a few um
specimens last year that it was just
kind of like oh I I know is this green
or is this white ash um so taking that
twig sample of it's about six to n
inches long just pull all the leaves off
and Chuck it in the bag with the seeds
um that can help with identification
purposes and it's an important part of
the
collection and then once the twig um and
the seeds have been collected you want
to label your bags um just ignore these
pictures I don't know um we want to make
sure you have your last name and the
number of the collection and then Mars B
um and pulled them down and staple them
make sure the seed doesn't explode
everywhere and then you're going to send
them off to midterm SE bank which is in
Staten Island and we give you that
information when your collection is
ready um and we go over all your data
before we actually send them to the seed
bank um the forest service seed bank in
Georgia and you're also going to need
two photos um one is an up close photo
of the trunk of the tree um again for
identification purposes showing your
seed lot identification number on the
bag and then the other one is going to
be the whole tree and this is to kind of
see the landscape that the tree is a
part of and those those it's easier to
just email those photos to me um like to
do copies but you know you don't have to
go through that whole pull if you don't
want to and once you've picked them um
you know just basic conents don't leave
them in your car if it's a super hot day
you don't want the seeds to
roast um they want to be you know dry
dryish but remain cool um you know sort
of around 30% humidity if that helps
anyone um you could put them in sort of
a cool cupboard or maybe in your
basement if it's dry um after the seeds
get shipped to the bank they're um kept
in that nice sort of cool um sort of
dryish uh climate um and they're chilled
also to make sure if you missed any
weevils um that the weevils will come
out and build you know stay in that
collection of
seeds um I think I just went over that
yeah um oh and then yeah they're frozen
up very very very cold temperature this
is how they're kept for up to 50 years
is because we essentially
stop any metabolism that's happening and
that seed comes to a halt which is
pretty pretty interesting and all of the
information um about your collections
are recorded in this you know National
Information Network that's called grin
um so you can actually you know look up
your seed and see it there and all that
information in the um in that
database um so ways that you can help is
um again um helping us find these these
trees this fall it's as I said it's a
pretty spotty um seed production year
but we know that they're out there we've
gotten reports particularly from the
southern um and around the Great Lakes
um so we're we're you know we're trying
to collect um more Green Ash and more
black ash in particular but you know
we'll take whatever so long as it's a
naturally occurring
tree um if you're interested in
collecting other species um the
associated species please do reach out
to me
um um I would be happy to as I said go
through and sort of make a smaller list
of species that you could focus on um if
you felt like that was something you
wanted to do and my email is ash.
Marb gmail.com so
ash.
MSB atgmailcom
um and then there's another project that
also involved in um with multiple
partners um we're still kind of coming
up with um an informational sort of
Outreach toolkit for it um but we're
working with the New York Botanical
Garden and the US Arboretum among others
um to try and work on this question of
Ash biogenetics um you know there's not
a whole lot that's known about the
distinction between species um in the
fraxinus genus and the ash genus and so
this project is hoping to sort of take a
finer uh grade closer look at where
those distinctions may be and this is
going to be you know really important
for determining which species are more
susceptible to Emerald ashor and how we
can assure that we're you know
conserving uh that's really important um
genus of trees and for that project we
need citizen scientists to help us make
collections of seed and herbarium
specimens um so that we can have um
samples for the herbarium but also um
the DNA that we need to look at those
phog gentics so there's a number of
different projects that we have on our
plate um we need a lot of help um but I
think it's you know a really fun way to
be involved in native plant conservation
and a really important
cause you need more than one as to
participate or is one okay yeah one is
all you need can you collect from a tree
that's already infected by the emerald
as for yes absolutely yeah I mean uh
sometimes if you have a really badly
infested tree um it'll put out what's
called a stress crop so it's just kind
of like oh I'm dying I better make a Las
Stitch effort to get my my genes out
there um and it try really hard but
those seeds will be kind of shriveled
and empty so if you see that your tree
is infested and it has seeds just make
sure you do that viability check uh if
they look great we'll take them are
there areas in the state that you are
most interested in having seeds
from uh yeah that's a good question I
mean yes we we didn't get that much seed
from the adiron Dex last year but from
what I hear from scouts um there's not
really much going on there um so that's
one area that we we miss missed a little
bit last year um but this year we're
trying to focus on Lakes Region and
we're hoping that because it does have
such a heavy heavy um density of Ash in
the canopy that we'll be able to find
something so you know all sort of along
like Buffalo and Rochester along those
that lak Shore um would be great but
anywhere honestly
anywhere all right well if um we don't
have any other questions coming in
either we thank you again for join us
and thanks Molly for for sharing that
information with us and a good luck in
the months
ahead yeah thank you very much laui and
thanks everyone for tuning
in this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu