this is a production of Cornell
University uh so I'll be talking about
transcript analysis in between under
CEST stress today which is a big part of
my PhD and um I want to start off this
talk by introducing the problem with Sol
stress uh talking briefly about a
particular mechanism that plants uh use
to cope with uh with salinity
introducing you a great new model to
study Sal stress which is petunia
briefly talk about genomic in different
species uh and then briefly mention
about uh advantages of using RN
technology uh then I want to walk you
through the experimental design and I
want to spend most of the time talking
about the result which I broke down into
um RC without reference genome and
expanding results with a reference
genome so uh solid stress it is a big
problem worldwide there's no surprise
about that you can see in this map all
these red color uh that are pretty WID
spread throughout the world uh represent
5 gram of sodium chloride per per liter
which is equivalent to 90 Mill of sodium
chloride it's a pretty pretty big amount
of salt uh pretty wi Express wi spread
in the world um we also see that 20% of
the irrigation water is affected by
solid stress so uh why is this a problem
well salinity and drw stress are the
primary causes of crop loss worldwide
and sodium chloride actually it is what
disrupt the normal plant growth and
development this is a simple experiment
in which uh sodium chloride plant
treated with sodum chloride I can um
show this uh really phenotype
compared to the
control now um the longly there's a
really long list of detrimental
consequences of sodium chloride I'm just
mentioning a couple here uh there's a
big disrup in Mineral nutrition
specifically with potassium and there's
also a more in a cytosolic level uh
strong inhibition in in enzymes so when
I talk about sodium chloride at a
cellular level I basically mean uh when
in the cytool you find more than 100
Mill sodium chloride as opposed to uh
less than 10 Mill in the cytool but
luckily for us plant have developed
different mechanism to cope with cell
stress and um and there's again a really
long list of uh coping mechanism I'm
just showing you here five which is
restriction of Sal uptake Extrusion and
compatibilization uh controlling the
long distance of sodium um um for
stabilizing membranes and increase
osmotic potential just as a long list
now um so I brought this up because it's
an interesting uh cycle that uses uh one
or more of this coping mechanism so
sodium chloride in high concentrations
can be perceived by unknown receptors
which trigger the elevation of a
cytosolic calcium a secondary messenger
that activates this protein receptor S3
which activates this kinas s to which is
pretty much uh the kinas that does a lot
of the work work in this mechanism by
phosphor this plasma uh this transpor
here in the plasma membrane which
actually extrude calcium pump sodium out
of the cytosol uh this kindness so to as
well um um can control the expression of
NAX which is a tonoplast uh transported
the pump sodium into the vacle which
will correspond to compar
mization um one of the ways in which
sodium gets in the cytool in the first
place is by utilizing low affinity
potassium transported that you guys can
see uh down here and uh there's a big
unknown and there's a lot of research
going on as um to figure out how this
complex SO2 SO3 um can downregulate and
stop the stop this uh low Affinity
potassium transporter uh and again
there's a lot of unknowns we don't know
how this uh complex interacts with the
high Affinity potassium transporter um
so this of course pathway has been
figured out in
arabidopsis most of the study that we we
not today in solid stress as comfor
opsis which is a great model for a lot
of things but not really for solid
stress so we are actually suggesting
that uh we should shift a little bit the
pattern uh with the AR abdes to petunia
and why do we say this because petunia
under Sol stress uh it really deals
pretty well with Sal stress um 1% of of
sodium ions by dry weight it is um it
can accumulates 1% of its weight in
sodium um now we did this uh experiment
in 2011 where we screen the ability of
of 14 species to withstand sodium
chloride and we group them in four in
four Big groups the most tolerant
species are somewhat tolerant sensitive
and extremely sensitive and you can see
that petunia actually ranked in the most
tolerant um in the most tolerant um
upper level now um when you grow
petunias um under 60 40 20 Mill sodium
chloride the really the growth um and
the phenotype is not really affected um
you see some detrimental consequences at
80 MIM not really affected in flowering
but just returing the growth so we think
that petunia uh can offer a really good
U can be a really good model to further
study uh sodium the effect of sodium
chloride so petunia it is uh is one of
the member of the solania family which
is a pretty many of these Solon species
are great for genetics and biochemical
uh studies this is a these are the par
of petunia hyria axillaris and inflata
and I'm going to talk about this later
on later today and then we have the
distance related
tomato now when we think about petunia
as a model species uh the first thing
that we actually think about is that it
is a really good model for transposons
almost as good model as maze for
transpose of elements uh there's a lot
of cogenetic analysis it is a great
model for uh pigmentation of floral sand
and for vs but um but we're pushing now
petunia as a model as well for solid
stress now what has been done in terms
of solid stress in this family well uh
unfortunately there hasn't been a lot of
research conducted uh with the solania
family the most thorough study that uh
was published in 2007 was a microway in
tomato where uh they screamed two
accession of tomato this one up here uh
they stress the plant with 150 M sodium
chloride and they uh all uh sample Roots
they mic
using the micro rates they uh they were
able to identify roughly 100 ests that
were uh differentially expressed at 30
minutes of sodium chloride exposure uh
700 ests at 2 hours and 1,000 ests uh at
6 hours uh they were able to group all
these ests into different group using
genology uh such as energy metabolism
Etc now this was a great approach
because it really changed uh the way
that we approach the study of soral
chloride look single Gene single Pathway
to a more Global holistic uh point of
view so um so we're doing something
similar in fact uh the only difference
is that we're not we're not using uh
we're not using these chips anymore
we're actually using an RNC approach and
the reason that we decided to do it this
way is because um micro Ray were great
Technologies in the early 2000s uh
however they are relatively low throw
put they really depend on sequencing of
cdna and est's libraries um they can be
expensive and not quanti quantitative
they uh they do have a false positive
through cross hybridization and they
have a really small dynamic range that
is to say transcript that are uh low low
transcript transcript that are
transcribed really low and really high
um they're not going to be uh picked by
the micro so instead we decided to use a
more novel technique RNA which is a
really high throughput uh approach where
you can sequence millions of nucleotides
of DNA in a single run uh it is cheaper
compared to a microway it has a really
good dynamic range you you don't it has
more Sensi sensitivity than the microway
and it has a bar coverage so this is the
flow the flow as to how we we actually
do the library preparation but I'm not
going to go over that um and this is a
protocol developed by James janoni the
bti which I'll talk about in a few
minutes okay so what are the goals of
this uh project we um wanted to
characterize a transcriptional profile
of P hybrid and Sol stress 150 M and
control we wanted to develop a
transcriptional profile through a Time
course of gene expression and we aim as
well to understand how biological
processes changeed withell stress um for
the specific goals which I'm going to
get later today um we wanted to compare
using our NC platform um how hene
expression changes with and without
reference
genome um so how did we set up the
experiment we uh had 18 plants growing
hydroponic Al in a growth chamber which
were randomly divided into two groups uh
these are nine plants corresponding to
control which I color coded with dark
green and nine plants uh corresponding
to the the treated plants with 150
millimolar now uh when you do R and when
you do basically any type of science it
is really good to do biorbs um and
that's what we did we uh pull one leaf
from three plants will become one bior
replicate U so we have rep one rep two
rep three and we will do this uh this
time Point 06 and 24 hours after solid
stress uh and we would do it at both uh
at both control and treatment to control
for circadian genes or genes that are uh
mechanically induced that we're not
really interested in looking so we did
this for roots uh for roots for leaves
and this as it is it is a pretty big
experiment a lot of RNA to extract from
different tissues so we decided to focus
uh on leaves to begin with and we left
uh roots for later on so uh we did all
the leaves at the beginning and uh at
these three time points 60 and 24 and as
I said at the beginning we use this
protocol developed by bti by janonis
group where we struct total RNA with the
trial method we capture messenger RNA
with Magnetic bits which we reverse
transcribe to cdna and then at this
stage of the cdna stage we index the
library with a six uh with a barcode six
nucleotide barcode with hplc primers
which would give us an indexed Li
so uh so this is the way that the
protocol works this is an already
optimized protocol now as we were doing
this we realized that ordering o hlc
primers it was quite expensive so we
said well what happens if we indexes
libraries with non hplc primers so um so
in this case for example we have these
two indexed libraries one of them uh
with this set of primer one of this with
this set of primer all of them coming
from the same pool of r&amp; name right so
they would be virually the same except
for the code the six nucleotide code and
we did this little side experiment with
all the leaves to optimize this protocol
um by assessing if hlc versus no hlc
would have an effect in uh Library
preparation why do we bother to do that
well because if if they actually the
same we can treat these libraries as
technical replicate increasing the depth
of our experiment and of course if we
prove that this doesn't really affect
the data uh it's a big Advantage for
future RN experiment um so we uh we did
this for all the libraries all the Le
libraries from the three time points uh
generating 30 libraries corresponding to
both uh Technical and uh biological
replicates we pair in sequence in a
single Lane to uh rule out any Lan
primary effect in a high 2000 and we
generated 196 million
reads so um so how do we how do we go
about to uh how do we go about to do r
with all this 196 million r that we just
generated with the illumin high so the
first question that we asked was uh
regarding to the hlc or hlc primers was
okay are those sample the same uh if
they were not then we would just discard
n h PLC samples and we will proceed the
without them now in our case and I'll
show you that actually doesn't really
matter we uh they were the same so we
proceed to Dem Multiplex uh and we
process we got rid of the illumin
adapters we increased the Q value of the
RS Etc and then we work with this uh
clean basically clean rits now the
second question that we had to ask is
well do we have a reference genome that
we can align all the short reads against
so uh if you have a reference genome
that great you just can proceed to map
and then look for Gen expression if you
don't have you need to assemble generate
a consensus and then you go back to
mapping uh once you map you generate a
bom file and then you can uh count
basically reads which is the basics of
RNA cic and gene expression and I'm
going to get to this part later on um so
going back to this first question uh are
these samples the same or
not so it turns out that it doesn't
really matter whether you use hlc or non
hlc primers uh so this is a hit map of
differentially expressed genes in which
we're looking at how the sample claster
together so we're basically comparing
the biological replicates R1 R2 R3
versus the technical replicates NH and
hlc and you see that all the distance
between the distance between the
technical replicates HP and N NH it is
uh smaller than biological reps so I'm
just going to assume I'm just going to
assume into uh this heat map to show you
that unfortunately this is uh so this
says R2 so all the technical replicates
HP NH H NH h HP are more closely related
uh than the biological replicates so
this and you see this across all the
samples so this was a great indic a that
really uh it doesn't really matter
whether you use hplc no hplc now the
final uh and most strong evidence uh to
argue that you can use non H PLC primer
it came from the statistical analysis
where we run a multiple analysis of
variance between these two uh data set
um and in our in our statistical model
we include primary type hlc on hlc time
points 0 6 and 24 and interaction of
those and we looked at the cut off of
the most Express transcript at 10
100,000 10,000 and 100,000
rpkm um and here I'm just showing you U
the output for uh the expression profile
of the top 10 most expressed transcript
and you can see that both treatment and
time points are significant as well as
the interaction of treatment and time
point but primary themselves they
actually they're not significant so with
this data we were able to conclude um
that um we can and we should treat our
libraries our non hlc and hlc as
technical replicates and it has the
great impact uh that can uh by
decreasing the cost of Library
preparation for future ironistic
experiment um so great that was a but
that wasn't my research that was a
little site project that we had going on
the real research it was to do RN with
petunia under cess and the question then
becomes how do we um how do we attract
biological information from these
reads and uh the first problem that I
had is that there's already 60 PL
genomes sequence and available uh these
are just some of them arabidopsis L Pana
of course models we have maze over here
there's a couple of solanas uh tomato
and potato but there's no petunia so in
the era of next generational sequencing
you have to have a reference to align
your RIS so how do you how do you go
about if you don't have a reference um
so it turns out that there is a way
there is a way to do this
which is by generating a transcripton by
the noo assembling all the millions of
uh rits that you generated with the
Luminous sequencing into one final
transcriptor this is of course a very
simplified uh example but um and then we
would we would basically treat this um
we will basically treat this
transcripton as if it was a genome right
it is not a genome but we will use it in
in the same way uh to map so how do we
do this step there's different type of
assemblers nowaday that can allow you to
do this uh the first three assembler
Myra GS assembler and I assembler they
uh they basically rely on overlapping
DNA sequences and looking for consensus
and they are actually more suitable when
you have long reads um for my experiment
I had short rates of DNA um I so then we
would look at these four assemblers down
here trans Adis soap belet and Trinity
which they don't really rely in this
overlapping consensus sequences they
rely on really complete Le mathematical
algorithm based on the Brin graph um to
to generate a
transcriptor so um the way we did this
is that we chose the three of the uh
most the newest assembler Trinity soap
and trans abis and we generated three
independent transcripts and we would
evaluate which of these transcripton
would give us uh would be the best and
and use that transcriptor for Downstream
analysis so um so here we're looking at
the comparison of the messenger RNA
length distribution of uh the different
transcript the different assemblers we
use compared with tomato so we didn't
plot transcript longer than 5,000 base
paars because otherwise this uh box body
would have been huge um and so here we
have the Tomato transcripton which uh we
know the medium size is roughly 1,000
base pairs for all for all the the
transcript and uh when using trim with
Thea KR 25 we obtain a really close
distrib ution to Tomato which was closer
uh than uh any of these other three now
uh soap with KR 47 it was good it was
the second best uh getting close to
Tomato but it wasn't as good as Trinity
and uh soap with the default it wasn't
really it wasn't really good and trans
AIS uh was the worst uh it didn't really
recover most of the transcript so um so
it was great um and this allow us to uh
to see that Trinity it was the V the noo
assembler now we also looked at B
informatic parameters to make sure that
Trinity was indeed the best assembler um
and when we look at con Min size of all
the assemblers Trinity was by far the
best it was almost twice the countes
were almost twice as big as any others
of the assemblers we had a pretty big
l50 and uh we have a really low n50
which is basically an indication as to
how fraction have to uh how cut off the
transcription can be so the lower the
M50 the better um the only uh really uh
bizarre thing that we observed it was we
that we found we identified over 100,000
uniin uh with this denovo assembly and
that was really passina because we know
well at this stage we don't know how
many jeans petunia has but we know that
um tomato has roughly 35,000 so Pia
there's no way that pia has more more
than uh more twice as that unless there
crazy duplication Gene events which is
really unlikely um so this was
interesting and I'm going to get to that
in a in a couple of minutes but um
anyway we went ahead and we annotated
this transcripton that we developed
using blast to go um and blast to go
actually uses uh the ncbi database to do
all the blast and the notation it wasn't
really good and I spent a lot of time
trying to figure out why the notation
wasn't wasn't really good and then I
realized that well the Tomato genome is
actually not on ncbi so I was doing the
blast against all the other species
except tomato uh so then we reannotated
the the same transcripton against the
this is the sgn database is a database
exclusively for solanas that is run at
bti um so I reannotated using a blast X
against the sgn database and The
annotation was actually way better um so
we were able to annotate roughly 33,000
uni and uh this 32,000 map directly to
the coding region of tomato with an
average average size of roughly 1 KB we
identify a ribosomal approach a few uh
bacterial genes and the large majority
of the genes were unannotated uh we
think that they correspond to variable
five Prime and three prime UT regions uh
that are unique to petunia that are not
really conserved with tomato and um as
you might recall from the beginning u p
is a great model for transposons uh and
we think that we're actually uh
capturing a lot of that here now um we
need to keep in mind as well that um we
have this big number of unin and that's
because uh multiple un genes can
correspond to one gene so this is a
simple example in which we have a gene
with four exons and assuming that this
Gene um doesn't have any any isopor this
is the only isopor um we would see that
uh the same correlation of the exons in
the transcript and uh when we map we see
enough coverage uh of RS to that align
to xon one and two but we do not see uh
enough coverage from xon 2 to xon 3 uh
in the same from xon 3 xon 4 so
basically the software uh which is
pretty smart but it's not smart enough
um it is thinking that these are
actually three independent uh genes so
this also explain why we get a big
numbers now this big number uh it is um
it's been uh reported other people that
have done other denovo assembl in other
species in Chinese cabbage for example
find a similar number of unun which was
surprising um so anyway we decided to
use use genology uh to assign function
to all these denovo assembly uh
transcript that we were able to annotate
and uh 50% when you look at the UN genes
distribution 50% of those um are related
with both metabolic and cellular
processes uh in 10 20% of the the
overall distribution correspond to
response to stimulus and biological
regulation now we uploaded this
transcripton this transcripton can be a
great tool for bi formatic purposes so
we decided to share this uh we uploaded
as a FTP file in the in the soul genomic
database and um after a few weeks that
we published this work we actually got a
lot of emails from people asking if we
could make this bastable so whatever
favorite gen that were working with they
could uh blast it again the transcripton
so we uh contact people at the sgn and
requested if they could do a blast B uh
so that was pretty cool um so this is uh
you can go now to the sgn to uh
transcript project uh this is our work
and you can uh type whatever uh partial
sequence that you have for your favorite
gen and see if you can uh retrieve more
of the gene itself or The annotation for
it um so this was pretty cool and but
again that wasn't the whole purpose of
the project the project it was to do R
to study Sal stress but we needed to go
through this denovo assembly to find or
to have all the players to do RN so now
we have we have a reference and we can
map
um we can map using this software B High
uh to um to look for gene expression
when you do this you generate a bomb
file um and then using RM You Can Count
normalize and uh look for RS per
kilobase of Exon of rib Maps which is uh
which is a measure basically of gene
expression uh and then using this
package in this bioconductor DC you can
look for differential expressed genes um
so in between these two things the rpkm
and the Dex you spend a lot of time
doing the data mining now why do we need
to data mine um so this is uh what you
get from using RM bioconductor it is a
pretty complex Matrix of numbers and
it's really hard to to make sense of it
you can see this is for example
corresponds to Leaf uh when there were
treated with salt under 24 hours you see
all the RPM values uh uh RCM is bound
with Trinity so you can identify genes
and different I I forms of the gene but
still this is not really intuitive uh
you can make you can make absolutely no
sense of this and this is what your data
mine now what type of uh data mine uh
method do you use well that really
depends on uh on the type of research
you're doing um for for our case making
sense of these 100,000 uni gen um we
decided to do look for anomaly detection
uh perform a geneontology analysis
cluster analysis and compar in compare
basically our data with uh with other
transcript analysis I'm just going to
talk briefly about these three today and
so when we look at anomaly detection you
have to remember that uh all these
sequences were coming from leaves right
we left the roots at the minus 80 at
this point um and this is uh when you do
leave leaves uh you basically would
expect that rubisco it uh it is the most
abundant enzyme in the world uh you
would expect that the expression of
rubisco is uh the highest in both Sal
treated and controlled leaves um and
this is and this is what we saw we
observed that the top 10 most expressed
genes in terms of RPM were all related
with the
photosynthesis uh in in fact rubisco it
was the highest now this data of course
uh is not really interesting it just
sort of to validate the RNA data you
don't do anything with this uh but it
let us know that we're on the right
track with the
analysis uh so with the genology
analysis we just aim to better
understand how biological process
processes are affected with solid stress
and um so as as I said before we U we
use genology to uh to assign function to
this transcript but the real question
that we were looking for it was how do
these biological processes change it
with sodium chloride so we perform a
statistical analys analysis Fisher test
of genology term differences where we
would look for the dexs uh of let's of
two time points control six cell six and
we will we will compare those against
our universe which is the transcripton
now there are different ways to uh talk
about and represent uh geneontology I
think that the work cloud is one of the
most uh simple ones to understand uh so
just keep in mind that all of these are
over represented go terms that have a
significant FDR that I'm not showing but
when we look at these two time points
control six and sell six we see that we
have abscisic acid and ethylin are one
of the most over represented go terms um
we also find kineses and G protein cople
receptors as the most over represented
good terms so all of this actually it
makes sense um we know that kyes we know
that ABA and ethylene are the stress
hormones so we should of course uh see
an over over representation of those we
know that kis and gpcrs are crucial for
signaling transduction Pathways and
we're actually seeing those um finding
salicylic acid it was really interesting
because this is been reported uh with
more plant pathogen interaction so this
is an interesting cross talk between the
biotic and abiotic type of a stress now
um the most interesting and uh part of
the go ter analysis it wasn't this it
was that we found 72 unique go terms
Associated exclusively with 24 hours
after Sol stress so all these 72 uh
unique go terms were not found uh
control six and uh when we think about
it actually makes sense because at this
at this stage uh cells have been exposed
to uh 24 hours of sodium chloride so
you're actually seeing a lot of cellular
damage and the cells and cells are
trying to cope up with it how do they do
that um one way is that they produce uh
lipid biosynthesis uh they you can you
can also see that there's a lot of
glycerol uh transport and you can also
observe from uh this uh go analysis that
uh cellular biological process such as
DNA replication DNA binding are highly
affected um so I just want to uh bring
this uh slide from the very beginning to
show that even in this really short list
of uh consequences we were able with
this uh with this analysis to
identifying uh how um membrane
stabilization and osmotic potential are
represented here now um so this this
analysis is what's really useful for us
to better understand the biology of the
cell stress um and this of course is a
really Bri brief summary so the last
thing I want to talk about um with this
uh first part is the cluster
analysis and U so this is a heat map
where um using with the rsen package
again where we look at the differential
expressed transcript isoforms across the
different time points and in green you
see uppr regulated genes and red down
regulated genes and um one of the
interesting things about the hit Maps is
that uh or clustering for that matter is
that it allows you to identify uh
patterns of biological interest so Ren
actually gives a uh it gave us 12
cluster here and you can see how they
are related with this sideway dendrogram
and um and in the heat map you see that
this is a s six s 24 and the three
control which of course it makes sense
that the Sal cluster more closely than
the controls um and when we look at
these clusters uh there were four
clusters that were highly interesting
for me um uh two subclusters 7 and 12
were at the very bottom where you can
see that under salt there's a lot of
green colors and under control red color
then we have um the largest cluster to
and u a small cluster up here where you
actually see red colors under the result
and green colors under the control um so
the interest so this can be confusing
but the interesting thing about
clustering is that we can now go and
zoom into this clusters and look at the
profile of these genes that are behind
this so when we look at this uh for uh
subcluster of interest um by looking at
soucer 12 and seven the one that we at
the very bottom of the heat map we see
that um so each one of these Gray Line
correspond to a single transcript and
the the blue one correspond to a
consensus of the cluster we see that
under the control the expression of all
these genes is pretty low but when when
salt hits the expression in subter 7 and
12 it goes dramatically up uh in fact we
identify that these three AB regul
transcript were
chaperons uh over uh that were induced
over 90 folds uh and then this uh this
was the largest subcluster which wasn't
really interesting um it does show an
increase in their in their expression
upon solid stress but it's not nearly as
dramatic as these two cluster and uh
finally this was a interesting that we
only find in this whole LEF experiment
49 uh transcript that were highly
expressed under the control but upon s
treatment their expression would uh
would down dramatically now um for our
purpose purposes of uh narrowing down to
kind the genes we looked at this this uh
cluster which was the most interesting
for us and um we had 88 transcript that
had a really interesting pattern that we
that we were interested in following um
and there were interesting transcription
Factor like this one uh but
unfortunately some of this Gene had
already been described in literature U
so when we decided to select a few
candidate genes we of course we we
narrow it down to those ones that were
not previously described
and um so that led us this uh
discrimination of this uh of this Gene
led us to narrow it down to basically
eight candidate genes eight Noel
candidate genes that were not that have
never been uh have never been uh
described in literature for solid stress
um and we group these candidate genes
into two groups basically those that
were induced at both time points Sal 6
and Sal 24 they were induced by several
folds actually and uh the rest of the
candidate genes they were induced only
at 24 hours after cestr so when we look
at the profiles of these candidate genes
I just want to draw your attention right
right away to this one so um so the
expression of this Gene is amazing it
just it is virally zero under the
control but at 6 hours of Sol stress it
is induced by 17 folds and at 24 hours
of Sal stress it is induced by almost 60
fold so this makes this Gene really a
really interesting candidate and uh the
fact that it makes it also really
interesting is not that has a high
expression and induction but also is
unknown so uh we know that this Gene
Maps directly to chromosome 3 in tomato
but we weren't able we were not able to
retrieve any information about it we
know that it's not a chap room because
we wouldn't able to retrieve that uh so
following up this Gene would be really
really interesting um so these other
genes are also highly Express and
induced but not nearly as dramatic as
this unknown one and lastly to uh the
the last four candidate genes that uh
that we selected they were only highly
induced and highly expressed at 24 hours
so these genes uh are there are self
sensitive genes that are uh that are
late in the induction process um
so lastly uh I want to say that U doing
AR Sig is great it allow us to identify
uh cluster genes understand a little bit
of the biology of he stress but uh in
order to make this kind of gen official
quote unquote you need to do the
characterization of them um so so what
we did is that we ordered a few of these
mutants one of the eight candidate genes
that I just show you and um and by we
genotype um trying to find uh the
homozygotes that has the tdna insertion
in both alals um and we were able this
is only one one mutant we were able to
identify uh roughly like five lines of
homoy line for this uh for this genotype
now
um uh following up with this uh part of
the research it really takes time it is
a long process and I was running out of
time so I'm going to S suggest that uh
the next uh PhD student in Nils lab uh
maybe have a really interesting task to
follow up this Gene especially the
unknown one that's uh the unknown one
you can definitely leave you to a plan
cell type of publication um and I also I
also would like to say that the next uh
PD a student uh follow up with these
reverse uh genetic approaches screening
the mutants doing vixs as I said between
is a great model for vixs uh
complementation imp planta
overexpression with 35s and uh inducible
promoter and also like a more broad type
of research would be interesting just we
looked at only one uh one cultivar Mel
deploy but it would be interesting to
see if uh other petunia hybrid do
perform in the same way than this um
just to finish up this section um I like
to say that pretty much everything what
I just mentioned it was a publish in
pls1 the paper came out a couple of
weeks ago and it was a big collaboration
uh between of course Neil uh myself uh
people in plant biology orano who is
actually now a faculty member at
Virginia Tech uh Mike scanon and James
janoni and um also I'd like to
acknowledge um two of my colleagues uh
Margaret Frank who is now postling the
down for Center and Brian emed who
contributed with uh really thoughtful
comments uh especially Brian with a lot
of statistical Consulting help so
between all of them we were able to
publish this and we were really excited
about it um and so the last thing that I
want to talk about is uh how can we
expand basically these results uh now
with the reference genome and including
uh root
samples uh so the specific goal for this
was to compare um these using this
platform aluminum with and without
reference genome and I show you this
experimental design and I I said at the
beginning that we focus firstly on
leaves so now we're including everything
we already have the sequence for leaves
so we just needed to include roots and
the only different thing that we use now
is that uh that we use the tuo package
so uh in this package basically uh you
map all the RS using top hat that runs B
TI two in the background to align all
the RS to the chromosomes uh and then
you use CF links to uh to look for all
the Align rats make them into transcript
and then with cfd you can look at G
expression so the question is why did I
bother to do all the denovo assembly in
the first place if you have reference
genome uh so as Neil said at the
beginning um we didn't really have a
reference zenome when we first started
but it wasn't until late September that
we started to collaborate with the
petuna genome Consortium which allow us
to use one of the reference genome uh so
very briefly um the pum Consortium it is
a really big effort between scientists
in both the US and Europe um basically
the probably the most important people
are uh in bti Lucas and or we have
people in Switzerland Chris ker uh
people in Italy and Tom Jareds in the
Netherland and as well as Franchesca uh
so this was great uh because it really
allow us to use the genome as a
reference and that expand a whole l lot
uh the way that we can do RNA sequencing
basically um so what are we specifically
doing with the pum project I can't
really say much because it hasn't been
published yet but uh one of the thing
that I'm looking at is um I'm looking at
molecular markers single nucleotide
polymorphism Snips uh to assess how many
transcript are inherited from each
parent to hia um for uh for the tuxedo
analysis what we used it was this genome
the eponia axillaris genome because the
both the functional and structural
annotation of the genome it was actually
in better shape than in flat um so you
can actually see that here we have
roughly 36,000 gen which is much less
than the 100,000 that I find in the the
no assembly uh but this using this uh
genome as a as a bioinformatic resource
it was of great help so um so we when we
run the analysis uh using tuxedo and the
reference genome uh we found actually
34,000 genes which is much much more
accurate than uh the 100,000 uni genes
that we find with the den noo uh we
found uh 37,000 isoforms with toxedo and
135,000 form with denovo so basically
there's no question that running toxedo
uh it is a much more accurate uh uh
approach to do RNA sequencing we
identify 11 roughly 11,000 differential
Express genes between roots and leaves
uh over a million promoters and over a
million splicing sites when we look at
the tuxedo
output now one of the things that is
really interesting with tuxedo is that
you take everything into R and into R
you really can do whatever you can do
anything you want um and I like to uh do
the analogy uh with the cell cycle
because doing AR it is really like the
cell the cell cycle where you have a lot
of uh checkpoints um and if the
checkpoint has not been satisfied the
cell cycle stops so with the RN is
really the same so this is the the first
checkpoint for us where we see how do
the sample cluster together um so in
this case in this dendrogram we see that
we have two big branches one
corresponding to roots and one
corresponding to leaves so so this makes
sense because Roots should be more
closely related to each other than
leaves so if you don't see this sort of
pattern there is something that went
wrong and you have to stop and go back
and in fact uh I had to do this twice
because one of the script that I wrote
it wasn't good um so and when you look
now between this Branch you see that the
control cluster more closely together
than the Sal treatment so so this is
this is a really good sign that you're
on the right track uh when you look at
the at all the biological replicates and
the technical replicates here you see
that they also clustered together you
see all the leaf uh sou 24 cluster here
um so this is again is a good indication
that U that you're doing things well um
when we look at differential Express
genes now with tuxedo we actually can uh
can uh can further look into leaves and
roots and with with this toxo package we
were able to identify 6,700
differentially expressed genes some of
them that were exclusively expressed in
this early time Point some of them were
exclusively expressed in this later time
point and of course some of these decks
are expressed between both time points
um and so with the denova assembly we
were able to identify 7,000 uh
differential Express genes which wasn't
that far off from what we actually found
here so that was pretty cool um and
again we did the same thing with the
roots they specific genes uh induced at
this time point and all at all time
point now uh as I said this is uh still
uh ongoing research I don't have all the
data that I like to show but one of the
thing that I'm currently working on is I
see well how many genes are differential
expressed that are between leaf and
Roots so that's going to be interesting
to know um uh lastly uh so I still need
to do uh geneontology analysis for uh
for tuxedo uh do the clustering using
these uh two softwares and um and talk
about candidate genes now um I don't
have all the candidate genes but uh we
do have this one that it has a really
amazing profile uh that you can actually
see that the expression it remains
pretty flat actually zero in leavs uh
even in Roots but only at root Sal six
it is expressed over 100 our fpkm
induced 24 fs and at root 24 U it is
induced by almost 80 FS so uh the
expression of this kind of jeans is
amazing um it is uh this is the
orthologue in tomato I need to still
look the function of it um and then uh
lastly I just want to wrap up with some
conclusions so uh we actually develop a
really Noel transcripton of of p hia and
soless where we identify over thousand
different uh abated genes and through
cluster analysis we were able to narrow
it down to a candidate genes um however
using tuo package it uh it's really a
much more accurate uh B informatic tool
that giv you a better representation of
gene expression and differentially
expressed genes um I'm still working on
um on finishing up with this this Tu
package you uh I need to do the ontology
and the clustering and then one of the
thing that I really want to do is
compare uh how do the C the genes from
the denovo compare to the uh toit
analysis um so lastly I'd like to uh
acknowledge uh Mike scanon from plant
biology uh marine hansome and Debbie
from MBG also all the collaboration with
James janoni we really appreciate that
uh orelo was the bi informatician that
helped us a lot with this um he also
taught me a lot of bionformatics so I'm
really grateful to him Lucas Mueller we
run all the all the software for free
basically in a huge server at the bti so
that was great also the Cornell
sequencing facility they did a really
good job and lastly I want to uh very
specially thank uh Dr n
matsum uh so as he said I came in 2008
and nellia was young and this is in 2008
uh so this is isic uh so I just want to
thank Neil for uh all his patient all
his mentoring has been a great advisor
some went really great to work wigs and
I'm basically uh mostly grateful because
he really led me wander off pretty far
away from his owner of expertise uh so
he was willing to collaborate and learn
with me which is something that sometime
faculty members don't do and I think his
his really kind approach to do that uh
enable us to build a a stronger network
connection in in Cornell um so Dyan
wasn't in wasn't even in the map at this
point uh the only weird thing about new
I have to say say is that he likes to uh
think in really strange places and uh
this is one of
them um so um I when I first came I
thought maybe it was an American thing
uh but um I realized that no it was
Neil but um anyway uh he always even
even in this places he wanted to talk
about our research uh and I always was
procrastinating and lastly uh I also
want to thank my girlfriend Amanda for
all her support and uh and of course her
dog
and and this is the last slide I also
want to thank the horiculture department
very much for this great six years uh
also Soho for supporting six years as
well and um all the biology different
biotas that I've done over the the last
four years that I've been here uh
actually Professor Duron is here who
runs this bio um and and thank you thank
you for everything and if there's any
question I'm happy to answer
that is that you said 2% of your un M to
bacteria do you think it's because uh
the funas were infected with certain
diseases or La contamination good
question where do those bacterial gen
come from yeah uh question there's
always some little percent of
contamination with d I don't I don't
know exactly where I'm coming from we
did grow the the lot ofter there um and
maybe when we did the RNA instruction we
capture a few bacteria as opposed
to it
was did you find any human gen like
suggesting uh
yeah
hey um at the very beginning of your
talk you could have a slide showing the
general response mechanisms for um for
soft stress um our sos1 and sodium prot
anti those two genes are among the up
regulated sodium prot anti okay yeah is
a sodium
prot both are up regulated yeah
they did you find them in your oh find
sorry U actually no and um and that's a
good question and and the answer for
that is that is is a model that you
really with spend our stress so we think
that under 24 hours you start seeing
damage but you don't see uh you don't
see the articulation of this mechanism
so if you want to see for example the
exclusion mechanism here you would have
to expose plants to uh to 48 96 hours
and then you will see these typ
responses how long is it going to take
to provide information to plant
readers come up with more
resistant that's a good question too um
so I think it will take a long time uh
because uh as I said the functional
characterization of the G is equally as
important as as the R so we just
identify a no kind of je that may or may
not be suitable for to use as Mar for
breing or to use for genetic
engineering thank you
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu