This is a production of Cornell
University.
And we've got a lot uh we want to do
this morning with our great guest here,
the director of the Northeast Climate
Center and professor here in Earth and
Atmospheric Sciences, Dr. RT Gaitano.
Thank you all for taking the time to
join me and us. Uh Carl, I think it's
not too early, is it? It's Mast's week,
right, brother? the the beginning of
spring for every male species uh in in
the in in that plays golf. I would say
this is a global uh phenomenon, right?
Because you hear people in Australia
talk about the Augusta effect uh that
they get things. So this is sort of like
become a cultural uh piece of cement
that we deal with uh in this thing much
like uh spring lawn care. So let me get
to the vide tape here hopefully. There
we go. Okay. Well, you know, listen, the
slow coming out of the spring allows us
to see poa annua in its glory, right?
These perennial types on the old poa
putting greens. Uh this is what a
walking around on a golf course in the
spring is is all about to really enjoy
this and and see the diversity that you
get. And then by uh summertime, you
can't tell the difference. It it looks
like a uniform uh stand of grass. Carl,
I thought I'd draw, you know, like to
show a picture every once in a while of
things going good. Make, you know,
things. We used, we used to do this
during the pandemic, so we always tried
to have a picture, make somebody smile.
So, here's somebody out at Sahali, uh,
with his daughters. And I took this
picture, Carl, cuz I got a guy wearing
those DG shoes, right? Stupid shoes. We
keep saying, who wears these shoes? I
found a guy in the Pacific Northwest
that wears these shoes. Anyway, uh I
also al also always love a good uh pet
picture and and this is Tyler Warner. Uh
I don't know Tyler at all, but he lost
Brutus recently and I just love how he
says it. This is as emotional as money
guys get. Dang dogs are so awesome,
right? I mean, it's just something about
a dog in this business that makes
everybody smile. We had our fir we had
our really well attended shortcut
conference call this week as we've been
doing for the last 29 years. And on the
docket was mole and vol damage, right?
You a lot of more snow cover than usual
left a lot of places uh with some
surface scarring. And so in good term,
we say get out and roll the darn thing.
That's what you need to do. Get get that
lawn uh smoothed out. Um even if you
have grub damage, just roll it. I mean,
if the soil's in good shape and and the
grass was growing good, just roll it
down, get it smooth, and then throw some
seed on it. It really isn't any more
than that. So, before we get to Carl,
you two uh setting Art up for our
conversation today, I'll just do a
little bit for the week and tie it into
some of the things that we heard as
observations across the region. So, as
Art said to us earlier and the maps from
the forecast uh website that anybody can
access, you know, cooler to the north,
warmer to the south. Um I don't know
that we're necessarily falling behind.
Looks like we're pretty close to normal
in most cases. Uh soils, you know, have
have made an interesting turn. This was
soils last week where we had very few
soils in the 50s. And here it is this
week, uh really seeing a few more many
much more widespread 50s, uh higher 40s
and 50s. So things warmed up pretty
quick. And this is why I asked you about
the soil stuff, Art, because things
really moved at the 2-in level pretty
quick. Yeah, this I mean this is a time
of year where we really see the soils,
especially at 2 in, move around a lot,
right? They're tied to the air
temperature in some some degree. We've
talked about us being on roller coasters
in in terms of of the air temperatures.
Yeah, there's some lag. There's some,
you know, there's some buffer in the
soil, but particularly at this time of
year, uh you know, when we're going from
the 30s to the 70s in terms of air
temperature, uh you see the soil start
to respond to that. So, so since we're
here, we're chatting about this. Uh,
obviously the wild card in this thing is
moisture. How much does the moisture
then affect that swing at this time of
year? Yeah, the the moisture makes a big
difference. It's a lot easier to heat up
soil when it's dry. You're not heating
up all that water in the soil and things
like that. So, uh, the the moisture
plays a huge role actually at this time
of year. So, and so when you look at
growth, right, Carl? Uh, and I'm sort of
setting up some other things that we've
talked about, but when you take into
account temperature and moisture as
you're doing with our grow growth
potential here, and you look at the New
York metropolitan area, you still see
we're really not growing. It's greening
up. No question about it. The landscape
is greening and and for starting to
bloom. We're hearing reports of this.
And of course, big disparities between
the east end of Long Island and where
Walt Nelson is up in the Aderondex,
right? It's like living in two different
countries. So, it is important to
understand, you know, you when you when
you do when you go to the forecast
website, make sure it's localized uh for
your location or if you're looking for
some other location. Now, as we've
talked about before, we had a really dry
fall, historically warm and dry fall and
that left a lot of grass looking pretty
bad already. And so, the even, you know,
it because we're not growing, we might
be green. You can see in this image,
we've got a few things that are green,
but more things that are brown that have
not recovered. And so, one of the things
we talked about, I think this is worthy
of some mention, is we've got a lot of
first-time homeowners, right? Even
though it isn't necessarily the best
time to get a home, a lot of people are
buying homes again. Economy seems to be
plugging along. Uh firsttime homeowners
are very anxious to sort of get after it
uh and and do some diagnosing of
problems. the first thing they run to is
a soil test, right? And so I I you know,
I will say this image, these images and
this image is completely AI generated
and and except for the ribbon. So what
I'm trying to say is, you know, you can
go and test your soil and a lot of
people will do it for chemical purposes.
We recommend that you just take a put it
in your finger, make yourself a ribbon,
right? See, if you get a really long
ribbon, means you got a lot of clay.
It's gonna be a little trickier to grow
grass in that. it'll hold more water,
but it can be difficult if you walk on
it a lot, right? And then at the other
end, if you can't even put it together,
it doesn't have structure. It might be
more sandy. It may need more water to
grow some grass. And understanding those
physical properties and how the moisture
you add is much more important than the
nutrients you add uh in most cases um
really helps you solve this and sort of
break us out of the soil chemical
testing because then we go and we run
and we do this, right? We run and we go
buy products, walk down the aisle, leave
with a bunch of products. And the
problem is, as Art told us earlier, it's
going to rain this week, right? This
weekend, you know, we're looking at, you
know, almost, and what I thought you
said almost an inch and a half of rain,
Art, and we've got the maps and you can
see the data. You can go to the forecast
website and see that stuff. But we also
have a runoff model. And the runoff
model indicates over the next few days
that we got a moderate chance for
runoff. And now I I you could look in
there and see the map and zone in on
where you're at to see if this is an
issue. But at a time when we tend to put
a lot of stuff on, right? It not as big
of a deal. Nobody's fertilizing in the
summertime very often. You know,
nobody's putting weed and feed into the
summertime very often. Nobody's putting
insecticide down in the on lawns
especially. So this is a particular time
of year we're understanding runoff risk.
And this is again the great climate work
that happens over in the climate center.
And so we also have this pollinator risk
assessment. So you're running out there
putting products out. We've also got a
model that's looking at flowering and
I'm sure we're starting to see some of
these dandelion flowers and early spring
ephemerals come into the landscape. So
this is the change. So this was um this
was this is today and this is what it's
going to be like in another seven days.
So the the forecast website gives us
this opportunity to see where we are now
and also see the risk if when you're
going to plan what you're going to do
for the weekend. So now Carl, here we go
in on the website. One of the things
we've sort of I would almost say Art, we
didn't pioneer the sort of study of it,
but we certainly pioneered the idea of
using it to make decisions in a visual
way. looking at maps. We were the first
one after this and bringing in a lot of
data. And bringing in a lot of data. A
lot of data. Lot of data. So, so, so
here we have our two seed head control
recommendations uh that we base on.
These are base 32 growing degree days.
They are. These are our dandelion uh
recommendations. And these are base 50
that starts at March 15. And I'm going
to leave it there, Carl, because we have
predictive models that use growing
degree days. And your question for art
today is about growing degree days. So
is this Can I pass it to you here? Yeah.
So, and one thing you guys have talked
on the show before is when should we
start growing degree days? And and Art,
what you've said in the past is you sort
of turned it back to us. Well, when do
you think it matters to a crabrass seed
that's going to germinate or a bluegrass
weevil that's going to start marching
over there? if there's a if we get 20
base 32 degree days in February 10th,
does that mean anything? And so I
decided I'm going to look at a little
bit of data, right? Art's talking about
a lot of data on the website. Just a
little bit of data. This is 14 years in
Ithaca, New York, uh 2005 to 2023. So I
just looked at how we accumulate those
growing degree days, base 32 in the
spring. Uh so for those watching right
now, you can see uh this is if we start
March 1st, just like a forecast website.
Uh, and if we throw out there's two
outlier years that are really early or
really late, but in general we can
expect to hit the 200 growing degree day
mark. That's about when we start
thinking about proxy about when we start
thinking about crab grass pres or
something like that. Uh, we have about a
month bracket in there where we may hit
that 200 growing degree day mark between
March 24th and April 18th in Itha, New
York. So then I decided, okay, uh, you
know, we we thought, okay, the the
spring is warming with climate change.
Should we start maybe February 15th? And
that's actually what the Michigan State
uh degree grade tracker does is they
start February 15th. Does that change
how we we make our actions? Uh so this
now you could see it's a little bit more
scattered, but actually if we bracket
getting rid of those outlier years, it's
the same exact dates, March 24th to
April 18th, about a month in there where
we hit that 200 growing degree mark
where we start thinking about doing
stuff. Uh so that's number one is Art, I
think you're right, is is uh hey, it it
might actually not matter. That's that's
point point number one. And point number
two is you can see in some of these
early years when we accumulate stuff in
February these sort of flat lines these
stalling years and that is exactly what
you're saying art is we accumulate some
degree days and then we're cold for 5
days 10 days and to us that probably
doesn't matter biologically or you know
to weeds or to insects. Um so I think
this is rationale from you Art is like
ah I think we're still good with our
March first. I mean, I think that's
where I mean, I think location matters,
right? I mean, you looked at Michigan,
but I wonder what this would look like
someplace down in Virginia or something
like that. Clearly there I I I think
your your graphs show um actually quite
nicely up here in the Northeast. March
March 1st is fine except for maybe an
outlier year here or there. Um yeah, in
terms of that those plateaus, I guess
that's where I'm the meteorologist and
you're the biologist. you know, does
does a seed or does an insect kind of
put those degree days in the bank and
they're able to pull on that? You know,
are they there there or not? Um, so I I
think we often times I I I think we I I
think sometimes, and this may be an
overgeneralization, but I think
sometimes when we stall and then you
know how it's a light switch sometimes
where it's boom, it was cold and then
boom, it's 85 degrees and you're getting
a warm rain. you get this what feels
like a rebound effect like like you just
said it's storing it up art and it's
waiting and it responds but I don't know
if it's responding because it stored it
up or because we're flipping a switch
and the next day it's just 80 degrees
and it's just physiologically ready like
we said it's green so it certainly has
the solar panels to collect the sunlight
and turn it into energy it's just not
that the conditions aren't right and I'm
wondering does it store it or I you know
this is a question for you but but
here's the this is the other thing right
uh is how big the window is right yeah
so it's not only when we start hitting
that 200 degree day mark if you want to
go back yeah there you go it's how many
days we're spending in sort of the the
time we have to do something 200 to 500
is what our proxy window is right we're
getting late if we're we're doing we're
making that app beyond 500 about the
same for crabrass and this is the chart
I think most people care about
especially landscapers who of hundreds
maybe thousands of properties where it
takes two three weeks maybe to make an
application of pre-emergent herbicide to
all of those properties. So uh if I have
longer time spent in that window if it's
generally cooler in in that growing
degree day threshold I can get to all my
properties and get pretty good timing.
If it's a shorter window and I I'm
really warm and I blow through those
degree days I don't have enough time to
get to everything. What is a general
range in Itha New York? How long do I
spend in that in that sort of ideal
application window? On average, it's
about 20 21 days, 19 days, 3-ish weeks.
So, that's maybe just enough if you're a
landscaper getting to all your
properties, right? On the short end, you
know, the really warm year, you blow
through that in 13 days. 2008, 2018,
2023 were really warm years in Ithaca
and we had very little time to make
those apps. Some years, 2020, 2016, you
had 30, 33 days spent in that window. So
this is a big, you know, that's three
times as long really as as the shortest
year. Yeah. So this is this is
interesting, Carl, because and Art, you
said location matters. All right. So
we're up in Ithaca, centrally isolated
up here in Ithaca. If we were in Jersey,
where our brother Rich Buckley is, um or
or even, you know, where our, you know,
our turf programs in Virginia Tech are.
Um, do you think this window's narrower
narrow narrower? N Yeah, I can't say
that word. Uh, not as widearrow. Narrow
as you get uh further south.
Um, I I knew you were going there and I
was thinking about it. Um, I I Well, you
set it up. Yeah. Um, I my my intuition
is the window will not get much narrower
as you go south. what the window will do
is move earlier in the year, but the but
the width of that window is is really
going to change quite a bit. Um, you
know, I I guess I hesitate a little bit.
I could see the the warm up coming a
little bit quicker. Or, you know, if you
even think of what we've been having
lately with these warm spells where, you
know, we we get up up here in upstate,
we might get up into the the 60s, upper
60s and think it's great, but when you
you know, when I when I call down to my
family in New Jersey or Philly, they're
up in the, you know, 70s almost 80s. So,
you are accumulating a lot more degree
days there. So, uh, that that might
might affect things in some years, but I
think overall I' I'd expect to see the
same same window size.
It's interesting, Carl, because this is
a knowable thing. I mean, you could sit
there and ask the machine a simple
question like on average, what's, you
know, what's the ideal time, right? I
mean, you have this window and your
window is from when it starts to when
it's not any good anymore, but there's
this period of time where it's ideal,
which is maybe its own range. Is this
ideal or this is just it'll work if you
put it down at this time. This is the
ideal range. Yep. So, and if you bracket
on the ends, a marginal, we could also
look at that too. And Right. And and
then when you start thinking about, as
Randy tells us all the time, early down,
early gone, right? If you're you looking
at a pre that doesn't last as long
because you put it out early, you know
what we don't know is how much
degradation or movement of it happens in
the spring as soils warm and things
break down. But but we know they don't
last more than 10 12 weeks. Some of
these pre-emergence, maybe barricade
could be 14 or longer. But if you're
going with team like a homeowner might
be doing, that one's only going to give
you six or seven, maybe eight weeks of
crab grass control. And crabrass prop
pressures well into July now. So you're
you're burned out by then. So this
window becomes more important for
something that wears out like that. Uh
and less important for a proxy because
you just need to hit it, right? And most
of these guys, this is a followup
spring. you know, you're locking in seed
head suppression in the fall and that's
a whole another area study. So, Carl,
listen, we've sort of I I think
concluded here now, you know, we talked
earlier that the grass isn't growing,
but yet every, you know, they see it's
green, they want to be on it. Even
Bellich, we found out this week, is
ripping out synthetic turf to put
natural grass, and that's the guy that
ripped out natural grass in the middle
of the season, got himself in some
trouble, and then they started playing
on synthetic turf in New England. So,
apparently Dr. Bellich there has changed
his tune. But Carl, these multi-purpose
surfaces have a role as we've talked
about in the spring. But, uh, when you
get in the summertime, it starts to
cause a problem. And Art, you also have
experience of this, both in your
meteorological world and in your world
as a soccer ref. So, we're going to want
to draw on that, Carl. Let's hear from
it. Let's hear from you. Yes. I I wanted
to start with the summer. This is when
everybody thinks about uh synthetic
turf. It gets really hot, and that's a
bad thing. Uh, in the spring, if it get
warms up, it's actually a good thing, I
think, for us when when we need it in
the shoulders of the season. But, uh,
this image is just showing 89.2 to
Celsius is what synthetic turf can some
synthetic systems can get to. I mean,
that's 170 or something. We're getting
to a really crazy that's up there,
right? It boil water boils at 100. So,
you ain't too far off from there. Um and
and Art, I was reviewing some of the
stuff. Um high solar absorptivity and if
you go back to that slide, yep, the two
primary factors of why, you know, why is
it so hot? High solar absorivity and
water evaporation. So maybe Art from a
physics perspective, you could just
explain those just why is it so hot? I
think Go easy, Art. I'll go easy. We got
a few Penn State people listening. So
you got Okay, I I can I can I can I can
dumb it down then. Um yeah, I mean
actually the physics isn't all that
complicated. We do this in my intro to
physics class actually. Right. There's
there's three ingredients and Carl Carl
kind of hits it, right? There's the
incoming solar radiation. That's the
energy coming into the system and once
that energy comes in I would say three
things can happen. It can reflect, it
can be absorbed or it can evaporate
water. So basically right if think um I
would say the the reflectivity of
natural grass and synthetic turf is
probably about the same. I don't think
you get a a big difference there. But
but what you do do is I mean the
absorptivity goes up the darker the
surface is right. in in I I know what
Carl's next slide is, right? Um those
darker surfaces uh absorb a lot of solar
energy and once they absorb it, they
have to do something with it and uh one
of the things is increase their
temperature. Uh the other thing they can
do is evaporate water. So if you're
taking a system that no longer
evapotranspirates,
um you have more of that energy going
into upping the temperature as opposed
to evaporating water. Yeah. And this is
one of the things we've learned, Frank,
is is these systems are great. They
flush the water. They don't hold any
water. Yep. Which is uh great for
playing on the field all the time, but
but not great from a storm storm water
perspective. So So here we're gonna, you
know, they always say it's not rocket
science, right, Frank? This is actual
rocket science. This is from NASA. Uh so
these are absorptivity coefficients of
various black coatings they can put on
rockets and white coatings. And the high
numbers on the left 8.9 is how much of
that solar radiation it holds versus
white coatings
3.1 2. So there's just the you know the
physics around a black a dark surface is
going to hold more of that absorptivity
and in the background we have a black
synthetic field that was put in at
Morrisville and Ari were just talking
before you have refed on this field. So,
as a ref, you know, sort of get setting
aside your expertise as a climate
scientist, what were your thoughts when
uh when you were refing a game on this
field? I I always want it to be a cloudy
day when I go to Marsville basically
because it sucks when it's when it's
when it's sunny. And I mean I even going
late in the season. I know this past
season I refed up there. It was oh you
know end of October basically at least
midocctober and bright sunny day and and
you know the the air temperature was
wonderful off the field but on the field
it was just hot and dry. Um just not not
a good thing. All right Carl. And and so
this is and and as a high school ref Art
I looked in the New York State you know
public high school athletic association.
They refer every uh sort of person
responsible for are we going to play a
game or not when it comes to heat stress
to wet bulb globe temperature and
there's a weather bug app that you can
go on to. We we've talked a little bit
in the past about wet bulb globe
temperature. Just a a brief primer on
sort of what is that looking at from an
athletes perspective heat stress. It's
more than just the air temperature,
right? Yeah. I mean it's there's been a
whole progression in these things. IO
first it was the air temperature then it
was what the the the temperature
humidity index that brought in the
amount of moisture and then really what
this wet bulb globe temperature is is
really brings in everything the
temperature the humidity the wind speed
and uh I think most importantly the
solar radiation right again you think of
a a nice sunny uh day up here in spring
and you know might feels pretty good
when it's uh 60° out it doesn't feel the
same on a cloudy day so that the body
absorbs absorbing that solar energy just
like the synthetic turf um actually
helps quite a bit in that in that
temperature and that's that's what
they're doing. So So is this the feels
like
it's it's the feels like temperature on
steroids, Frank. It it it kind of it's
the extension of that. Okay. So So all
right. So this is the New York State
Public High School Athletic Association.
I'm assuming the NCAA's got another one.
How does this work in practical terms?
All right. Have you confronted this in
any way where because let me just step
back. I've chatted with some people who
manage natural grass fields in the south
and synthetic fields in the south and
they got this rule down there and
they've never cancelled the game on
synthetic turf. So I just wanted for the
record while this is there I wonder how
it actually gets implemented and if it's
not implemented you know because
everybody wants to get the game in. It's
the same thing with rain on a field.
they want to get the game in. Um, you
know, how does this h actually happen in
practice? So, I've had high school games
either canceled or delayed because of
the New York State rule. And basically
there again, it's kind of it's the
athletic director at the field looking
at his phone to the Weatherbug app and
and telling, you know, Weatherbug in in
this city is saying this and, you know,
we're either delaying the start of the
game if it's close or or or we're
canceling the game. Totally. Totally
that call. Um, I've never had a college
game cancelled uh because of the heat,
although I've definitely been out there
on some very very hot days. You know,
standing at midfield before the game at
the national anthem and and basically
just sweating like crazy. Um, so I I am
not familiar with what the NCAA rule is
there. I know in a lot of cases the game
will go and we'll have more frequent
water breaks and things like that. You
see that in professional soccer as well.
Um, but to my knowledge there's not a a
cut off like in high school. Is this is
this a good metric art? I guess that's
the question. Like if we were going to
pursue this and you were an athletic
field manager, you know, at a university
or at a really, you know, nice high
school where there's high expectations
and you've got one of these carpets. Um,
and this is more likely something, as
Carl said, they'll encounter when they
get back in August for play. Rarely are
we worried about this thing uh up north
because actually it's desirable now,
right? It's a place where you can get
out there. So So I'm I'm wondering about
is this a good uh measure of what you
think is uh simple enough for them to
use a and also actually protecting,
right? You need some kind of measure. I
agree with that. Uh where I think this
might go astray a little bit is is it
goes back to natural versus artificial
turf, right? So all these measurements,
measurements you're getting from
Weatherbug and things like that, they're
clearly not over artificial turf. You
know, most of those measurements are
coming from at least something that's in
a a more favorable environment to to
produce a cooler temperature. So um you
are, you know, that that skews things
quite a bit. So I mean really there
should be, you know, if you wanted to do
this uh the right way, there should be
some special onsite type measurements of
of doing this. So this could be also
something that if you got enough data
from different fields, you could model
just like you do everything else, right,
Art? Yeah. And I mean again, it's just
not the temperature. You know, Carl
started off with 80°C at the turf
surface and looked like he was showing
that from an infrared thermometer. So
right there at the surface. So yeah,
maybe uh maybe you could fry an egg.
Your shoes I mean that's going back yet
your feet are very hot on these surfaces
when you referee. you know, up at body
level there's a difference and that
difference is going to matter whether
it's a real windy day or a calm day and
things like that. So, there is some
variation even in there within the
height of a typical athlete. Yeah. And
then even with with the different
synthetic surfaces, right, Frank, we're
learning more about alternative infills
and there's ones that purport to be a
lot cooler. They hold water and you will
irrigate those fields and it holds water
and you get that evaporative cooling. It
probably won't last very long if I had
to guess. Maybe maybe half an hour or
something like that. You see this on
campus, right? They're they they spray
their they're irrigating the at least
they do it at the field hockey field. I
assume that's for ball play but also for
for some cooling. Yeah, there's no
question about it that this remain I
mean listen this is a part of every
everybody that's managing uh natural
grass surfaces at a high level is man
managing synthetic surfaces. It's just
the nature of the people that we service
in this work. And I think what I like
about this and I think always have said
about this with sports fields, sports
has liability that just about every
other part of turf doesn't have, right?
And you know, kids can get hurt. And I
think to your point, Art, these laws are
a little bit these recommendations a
little bit more stringent on youth
fields. And and I think when you're
younger, you not only are you closer to
the ground, but I'd say when you're a
peanut, you're spending a lot of time on
the ground. On the ground. On the
ground. So that so that that does bring
the measurement into play. All right,
Carl, we're getting close. Uh any
questions from the field or any more
final questions from you? Uh we no
questions yet, but uh I did want to
point out on this chart you see region
one, two, and three. And the cuto offs
for sort of low threat, moderate threat,
high threat are different for those.
Those are the regions of the country you
live in. Basically, how acclimated your
kids are to heat matters in how you will
change the play of the game. So if
you're from the south and you're used to
warmer temperatures, that would be
region three here that the cutoff is a
little bit higher because you're used to
that a little bit. Um if you're up in
the aderondex, uh actually within New
York State, we would be cut into two
different regions. So actually public
high school events played in the north
country would be subject to region one
versus region two for more downstate. I
think that's something that probably
gets overlooked, but is is sort of
interesting. Like, wow, in New York
State, we have two different sort of
Well, it would explain a little bit why,
you know, maybe games in the South
aren't canceled. To your point, Carl,
they may be uh as a population, uh more
more heat acclimated. Um so, so listen,
Art, thanks for taking the time to join
us. It's it's really great to have
always fun to be with you guys. Yeah,
this is great. Hey, Carl, who do we got
next week? We're gonna have Evan Machete
on next week. So, we're going to be
talking sports turf again and Evan is
going to be one of the experts on we're
gonna ask him about traction. We don't
have a good idea of best ways to manage
traction. Evan's probably one of the
experts in the entire world on using
some pretty advanced machinery to uh to
measure that. So, it'll be it'll be a
fun next week uh with Thanks a lot, Art.
Take care, everybody. Take care,
everyone. Bye bye. This has been a
production of Cornell University on the
web at cornell.edu.