this is a production of Cornell
University all right thank you VCH and
thank you Adrien for the invitation it's
a pleasure to be here and indeed so I'm
going to talk about plan development so
not myis I left the field a little bit
in the years maybe I will come back to
it I don't know uh okay so my question
today is how do plant read their own
shape uh this might be a bit of a
cryptic question but it's a way to
address the role of mechanical signals
in
developments but I guess it's going to
be clearer with the the presentation so
one thing that okay I need to use this
uh one thing is for sure is that there's
a lot of data in the literature showing
that cells are able to sense their
mechanical environment and one thing for
instance is that if you so this is all
in animals if you grow a single cell on
a micro pattern like this you can
actually predict the orientation of the
spindle and the next Division and this
is due to the fact that because it the
addition pattern is biased by the
pattern then you bias also the spindle
but this is the force within the cell
that is guiding the the spindle
orientation another thing has been shown
also for cell division is that if you
compress or stretch a cell you're going
to accelerate or decelerate uh the the
Mito mitotic
progression okay so that's one example
but there's another one that is maybe
even uh Stronger I would say is that if
you grow stem cells so mimal stem cells
on substrate so this it has exactly the
same chemical composition the only
difference is the stiffness of the
substrate so if you grow those stem
cells on soft matrices you get a
neuroblast if you grow the same stem
cell on a stiff Matrix you get an noo
blast so it means that the mechanical
environment or in this case The Matrix
is defining the
sufate in this case and what's also
interesting is that so you have this
relation with stiffness but the entire
cell is actually uh changing so if you
if you grow those stem cells they're
going to have a more dense extracellular
Matrix they're going to have more
cytoskeleton and uh the even the nuclei
is going to become the nucleus is going
to become stiffer on a stiffer medium so
you completely reprogram the cell based
on the mechanical environment of this
cell okay so this is at the Single Cell
level and there's a lot of data at the
Single Cell level there's fewer data at
the multicellular level of course
because it's much more difficult to
address and it's also well it's more
complex to interpret also but the
general idea would be that you have a
gene Network here uh in one cell this is
impacting the mechanical properties of
the cell this is changing the shape of
the cell this is changing the the shape
of the overall organ
tissue and this in turn because there is
growth in there there is to pressure
there is mechanical stress here this in
turn could feedback on the gene Network
and you realize that at this point this
is a mechanism that is allowing the
tissue or the cells to know where they
are um all the tissue what size it has
so it's it's a sensing mechanism for
shape in a way so if you read mechanical
signals you can know your shape and then
you can adjust you can buffer your size
so you can do a lot of things so that's
the let's say the conceptual framework
for this reading shape thing and here
I'm focusing on the mechanical signals
but of course there are over signals too
we can do the same feedback loop with
biochemical signals only I'm just saying
that here I'm looking at the
contribution of mechanical signals in
this feedback loop okay so uh the fact
that there is mechanical stress in this
tissue can be a bit mysterious so I just
want to clarify this point with some
very B basic images so if you have a
bunch of rods piled together now you put
a thread between those rods what happens
here is that this structure is stable
it's metast stable if you want so it's
not going to collapse it's it's there it
looks inert but actually what is in this
structure is a balance between tension
and compression so all the threads here
are under tension they're pulled and the
rods are under compression so want to
simplify
and it's it's this balance between
tension and compression that makes this
structure
stable so okay this is very theoretical
but it applies to shapes and biology so
if I take probably the simpler shape you
can imagine a balloon or a sphere a
balloon is a stable shape but it's
stable because there is a gas inside
that is under compression and there is
an envelope that is under tension and
it's the balance between tension and
compression that allows the balloon to
be stable uh in shape you can also
generate flat shapes with a balance
between tension and compression so this
is the the kite example so you have two
rods under compression and the membrane
that is under tension is pulled and with
this uh balance you can have flat shapes
and of course you can generate any
shapes and that's what the modern
architecture is all about so I don't
know about the brutalist architecture
but any architecture you can use this
feature all right so all this is for
buildings so you could ask a question
whether it's applicable to a living
organism and of course it is so here if
you again an animal example but if you
if you go through a section of a human
fmer you see this pattern of trul in the
in the F it's very intricate very
organized but you can also see that
there is a pattern it's not random and
if you cut several F you always see this
kind of overall pattern so now if you
calculate the pattern of stress of
mechanical stress in in this tissue
you'll see here that there is uh tension
and here there's compression it's
basically the the weight that you put on
your fmer and what you see also is that
this pattern of stress is matching the
overall the the pillars in the in the
fer the trul orientation in the in the F
so that means that the bone is building
to resist to Mechanical stress so you
build the pillar to resist in this case
to mainly to to compression so it's a
little bit like in the building you
build a vertical wall to resist
gravity okay so this is for solid solid
medium let's say so what we are working
on is soft usually it's soft matter so
is this true also for soft matter answer
is yes so here I take the example of the
the saval paper in 2011 where what is
looked at is a mouse intestine intestine
and so you have this uh well spring
shape I would say like this cir voluted
shape and so we want to know
what is there any forces in this
structure so what he did was an anog
analog model so here you put you take
two pieces of rubber you stretch one and
then you GL you glue the two pieces
together and then you relax and what you
get is this so you get a structure the
shape of this structure is relatively
similar it's not the same scale of
course but it's the shape itself the
geometry is relatively similar to this
one so this is an indication that maybe
in this structure there is also a
balance between tension and compression
and that is what is generating this
actually that's something you can even
feel when you do a dissection of a mouse
and you get to the intese it looks very
springy right so that fits with this
idea but the the best actually
demonstration is to do the reverse
experiment where you take your intestine
you you cut the tube and you cut the
meant tree so the two pieces and what
you see that the tube is expanding and
the mes is Contracting so again it
reveals that there was a balance between
tension and compression in
this
organ all right so I'm going to stop
here for the animals now I'm going to
plants so in Plants it's the same idea
and actually in all living organism it's
the same there's always the balance
between tension and compression I mean I
should never say always but usually
there is a balance between tension and
compression so here I'm just taking an
example so the the radishes it's a
classic example that I like to use so if
you do a radish salad the first thing
you do is that you cut the radish and
they pop open so they pop open because
the epidermis is under tension and the
tissue inside is under compression
there's also a classic example is the
the rebarb so if you have rebarb and you
peel the epidermis or the cortex of the
rebarb and you do you do that in water
to avoid dehydration uh you see that the
cortex is going to contract which means
that it was under compression under
tension before right it was a tension we
peel it so it
contracts all right so here I just want
to quote Carl's work here because there
this very important paper summarizing
this idea and going into more detail to
show that really it's the epidermis
usually in most tissues in most plant
tissues or iil tissues usually that are
under tension and this has a primary
role in um growth and morphogenesis for
plants okay so now into what we're doing
more specifically so here is just a
scheme that I I stole from ja dum uh so
this is a plant cell or really
simplified scheme of a plant cell so you
have TGO pressure inside the cell wall
is resisting to this TGO pressure and
you have aligned cellulose microfibrils
that are driving the direction of growth
of this cell which is orthogonal to the
cellulose microfi I guess to this
audience I don't know I don't need to go
into full details you're I guess all
aware of this this fact all right so
what is controlling the deposition of
the cellulose microf fds what's
generally accepted is that it's the macr
tributes that are guiding the deposition
of cellulose in the cell wall so here
you have a piece of the plasma membrane
the cellulose sentes is here it's
extruding cellulose inside the cell wall
and just beneath the plasma membrane you
have the cortical macules here and the
cellulos SAS is basically moving along
the microt tubules so it's not always
true and there are exceptions but in
most tissues actually the the more we
get data and live Imaging data the more
we see this type of behavior so that's
really interesting for us because now we
can easily Image micr Dynamics with gfp
markers and we can can have an indirect
image of the deposition of cellulose
inside the cell wall and as you may
understand cellulose is much more
difficult to image because it's inside
the cell wall we can't really put any
fluoresent marker for for the cellulose
so we have an indirect image of
cellulose deposition and so we have an
indirect image of the mechanical
properties of the cell in a way because
we know that cellulos is as stiff as
still so we we can have an idea of in
which direction the the cell is going to
be stiffer than over direction right we
have the mechanical an isotropy of the
cell with the orientation of the microt
tributes okay so I'm going to start with
um an example that we on which we worked
the past few years which is the the
payment cell so here what you see is is
a young arabidopsis plant you have two
Coons and if you look at the coons you
see those cells that are inter digitated
that have a jigo puzzle shape here you
see a stomata so this is a typical shape
for epidermis it's not for all epidermis
but in arabidopsis at least it's it's
very clear and this is actually a very
well-known um cell type I would say
there's a lot of experiments done on
pavement cells because it's it's a
interesting model uh and something that
we know is that we know actually it's
been characterized already for the
cytoskeleton and in particular for the
macules so when the the cotillon is in
the expansion phase so when it grows at
fast speed the macules within one
pavement cell as a stereotypical pattern
in which you see those rings of macules
between the necks of the payment cells
and in the lobes there is less mic
tubules so it's sort of bodal
distribution if you want to you have a
lot of macut that are aligned in the ne
and less in the loopes
so of course when you see that and if
you um feel like the cellul is going to
be oriented same way here what we should
see is this right so you have a balloon
you have more microtubules so more
cellulose you have a ring of cellulose
here and this could explain why you have
a jigo puzzle shape so there's only
indirect evidence that this is the case
there's been some staining for cellulose
for the ma tuu but no mechanical
measurements for the stiffness of
payment cell so what we did was to um
adapt Atomic Force microscopy to measure
the mechanical properties of those cells
at very high resolution so in in two
words Atomic Force microscopy is
actually it's a it's a sort of a old
technique now but uh it's it's been used
a lot in Material Sciences so you use
here a Cy lever the micrometric C Lev or
like maybe a little bit bigger than
micrometric with a nanometric tip so so
here the the little the c l we use at
the end the radius is at 2 nanometer so
it's really small and we apply this Cy
lever on the surface and with a laser we
can measure the curving or the
deflection of the the Cy lever so if the
Cy lever is applied on a stiff surface
it's going to bend immediately if it's
applied on a soft surface is going to
indent the substrate and then it's going
to bend so you can measure the delay in
bending if you want with the laser
that's going to be proportional to the
stiffness of your material and if you
know the stiffness of your C lever then
you can deduce the material properties
of your of your tissue so of course here
we use a very small uh tip like 2
nanometer to only indent the like a
little bit of the cell wall and just to
have the local mechanical properties of
the
cell okay so this is the type of image
we get so this is uh we can get the
Topography of course with these images
so you have here like the the boundary
between two pavement cells so you see
again the jigo puzzle shape you have the
Cure so at this scale it's very very
bumpy as you as you can
tell and it's actually I mean it's it's
smooth it's bumpy but smooth in a way
but now if we get the force measurements
so the mechanical properties this is the
type of map we get of map we get so when
it's white it's stiff and when it's
black it's soft uh so when it's so I
should do make a little disclaimer first
so the really white zone or the really
black zone are probably artifacts or
zones that we cannot really interpret
because it's too slopy so we don't know
what we're doing so basically the the Cy
lever is inting on something that is at
an angle so it might slide uh I mean we
we don't really know what we're
measuring so we prefer to ignore those
areas whereas if you focus on the
relatively flat part of the cell you see
those lines here so you see some white
lines here some white lines here uh too
that are matching the macru pattern that
we saw earlier so in this case that
would mean that there is some wall
reinforcement along those lines between
the necks in those cells so that's if
you want one evidence that indeed those
cells are reinforced along those lines
matching the predicted cellulose
deposition we have a positive control
which is the stomata so as you may know
in stomata the the microtubules and the
cellulose is transverse and we see also
transverse stiffening in in those tissue
okay so this uh model I mean which it's
has been around this is conceptually
it's not new it's just more evidence
that it's true let's see but of course
now the question is what is orienting
the microt tribul so how come the micr
trules are orienting like this and
relatively stable during this fast
growing phase so one possibility uh is
that uh it's actually mechanical stress
that would Orient those Maes I me there
are other possib ISM I'm not saying it's
only mechanical stress but there are
here we want to test whether it's
mechanical stress that can Orient those
mutes so to do that to test this
hypothesis uh so pav krinski in enrik
Johnson lab did a Model in which he
could calculate the tension in the top
wall of those cells so basically you
have uh you take a cell you put you put
your pressure in it so you have cell
wall that is under tension so if the
cell wall was half sphere it was just
the shape of as sphere the tension would
be the same in all Direction so it would
be isotropic mechanical stress but
because here we start with a puzzle
shaped cell like this if you follow the
red lines which are the maximal tension
lines you see that they converge in the
neck regions and so this is the
prediction of the tension in in this top
hole and you see that it's converging in
those necks and of course there's a good
match between the predictive
maximal tension line pattern and the
orientation of the
maules okay so that's the idea that
maybe uh the macules are able to sense
someh this tension lines and align to
resist to this mechanical stress or to
allow the cellulose to resist to this
mechanical stress okay so first you have
to show that there is tension in this
tissue so this is one uh movie to show
that so here you have um cadon actually
might be a leaf in this case I'm
wondering now
I have question so you take this tissue
and what you do is you cut it and it's a
little bit like in the r Barb experiment
or in the radish experiment if you cut
it you should reveal the pattern of
stress uh in this tissue so if you do
that so here we've removed the large
part of the of the cotillon when we when
we cut it and what you see is that it's
it keeps open opening after it's been
cut so it means that it is under tension
indeed so maybe I should play it again
check but this is not really a surprise
right I mean we've all we've seen before
I mean Now is really accumulating
evidence that the epidermis is on
tension imp plant tissues so now we can
U do a model in which we uh put the
epidermis on the tension and we look at
the pattern of stress in this uh in this
tissue and we're going to do an oblation
and predict the orientation of the
mechanical stress pattern after ablation
so this is again what pav did so you
upate those cells here so you can forget
about the color code but what you see is
a circum frenal orientation of the
stress here which makes sense right I
mean it's you you if you take a piece of
paper you cut it it's going to tear so
for it not to tear you need to reinforce
it um around right so this is the the
predicted pattern of stress so now if
you do it on a real cotillon that's what
you see indeed so here you a blade a
large piece of the cotillon and and you
see this uh orientation of the macules
here so actually since then we've tried
to do this oblation at different stages
of the and there's a good match
between I me there's a good relation
between the the growth rate so if you do
that when the the codon is really not
really growing anymore you have less of
a response so you really need to do this
at the fast growing right which makes
sense right that's where the the stress
would be the the
highest okay so this is evidence that
indeed the macru can reorient to align
along maximal tension
so of course there's over experiment but
I'm not going to show but if you do
compressions or if you do a phac
pharmacological treatment to soften the
cell wall for instance so to increase
the stress level you also see the same
type of reorientation of the of the
microtubules okay so the general idea
then is that a cell with its microt
tribute is going to reinforce its cell
wall this is going to okay that's what
you see here so this is a different
color code but the pink is stiff
um okay so you reinforce the cell wall
uh this is controlling the cell shape or
stabilizing the cell shape if you want
and the shape itself is prescribing a
pattern of mechanical stress that in
turn is controlling the the micr
tributes right so in in this case if you
start with a puzzle shape you're more
likely to maintain a puzzle shape it's
not going to go towards a balloon shape
because of this uh feedback loop anyway
and so and this is a way I mean to go to
go back to the reading shape idea here
this cell is able to read its own shape
through this mechanical feedback and to
amplify or to stabilize uh its shape
through this mechanical feedback
loop okay so now if we move at a larger
scale so this is now it dates back like
a few years uh so we've done some work
in the in the shopical marem so this is
an arabidopsis again if you remove the
flowers when you get to this Dome of
cells so that's the sh typical marem and
uh the FL are on the side so here we use
this system I mean we can do a lot of
things with the marem but here we we use
this system as a morphogenetic model in
a way so this is a tissue with a
specific shape in a way there Dome there
tissue folding here and so we want to
see whether what we showed for the
payment cell is also true for the
marem so when you look at MCR tributes
in this marem so this is viewed from the
top so the center of the mar stem would
be here this is a young organ this is an
older organ and you see these alignments
of macules here between the organ and
the mar stem so again here an alignment
of macu between the organ and the mar
stem you also see this alignment of micr
below and this is stereotypical so we
always see this pattern in the mem this
is really like a constant thing each
time you look at the the M with a ma
marker this is what you this is what you
would see so here again we can make the
analogy with the payment cell so you
have here the mar stem especially in the
boundaries where you have an organ the
mar stem and you have this alignment
supracellular alignment of Mac in the
boundary looks a little bit like in
payment cell where you also have this
alignment of Mac tub between next but
here it's at the Single Cell level and
here it's a supracellular but if you for
if you forgot about the sub cell
division or the the cells it would be
basically the same so you have tension
lines and the Mages aligning here okay
so is this true so if you again assume
that the epidermis is under tension you
can calculate uh the pattern of stress
in this tissue and what you find is that
at the top because it's half sphere the
stress is isotropic there is no
Direction no preferential Direction uh
for the the stem it's a cylinder so the
circumferential stress is going to be
twice higher than the actual stress and
so this is well known in in engineering
and the mechanics this is for instance
why the when you boil sausages they're
going to open lengthwise because the
stress in the second frenal orientation
is larger than the actual stress so this
is what you would see here so if the
epidermis is under tension the the T the
tension is going to be higher in the
circumferential orientation than in the
actual
orientation and in the boundary domain
here so it's a bit of the mix between
this so This starts to be on the side of
the mar stem so it starts to become a
bit more like this but in addition you
have an organ here but is growing fast
so because it grows fast it's going to
compress the cells here so now you have
have compression in this orientation and
tension in that orientation so in terms
of tension it's really really ionotropic
very directional so here you have a
strong tension in that orientation and
of course when you see this it's a
little bit like in the fmer what I
showed you earlier like the Dy Thomson
or the wall flow on on fmer you see that
you have a good match between the
predicted pattern of stress and the
orientation of the of the Mac tributes
so again so we did a number of
experiment to change the pattern of
mechanical stress and see if the micr
tuu would reorient along the new stress
pattern so I'm just going to show one
just the simplest one because it's
easier uh so here it's an ablation so we
have again a model with the the tension
in the on the top hole we do an oblation
so we predict a circumferential
orientation so it's like in the this
is exactly the same idea and so when we
do the experiment so this is which has
been done by Marcus eer so here you have
the mabu the cell shape and this is the
mer image you use a UV laser so you burn
two cell one or two cells so this is
what happens right afterwards and then
you let the ma tuu reorient and they
reorient circumferentially around the
oblation so of course this is not enough
to fully prove that it's response to
Mechanical stress is wounding there lots
of chemicals that are induced by
wounding but if you do compression you
you see the same and again I mean you
can do over experiment that show that
indeed each time time you change the
stress pattern each time you change the
M orientation also in the
marem so basically what we're saying is
that it's a it's a general rule in a way
so but when you have microt tributes
you're going to change the shape via the
effect on cellulose deposition but the
shape itself is going to prescribe a
pattern of mechanical stress that in
turn is going to orient the ma tributes
so this is in this case it's uh this
feedback loop is a way to uh read tissue
shape so here uh the the the tissue is
able to read the tissue folding at the
marem boundary and amplify the folding
so in this case this feedback loop would
help the organ
from to move out of the marem domain so
it would like be more quickly separated
physically separated from the mem with
this feedback
loop okay so the problem with the of
course the feedback loop is that uh it's
sort of self um maintained and so you
could imagine that we've lost the
biology in this because white it's doing
its own thing so you just uh kick first
and then that's it it goes forever and
you don't have to do anything there's no
regulation which I mean can be an
advantage in biology because you have
less control let's say but I guess in
biology we usually like to see some
regulation for these things and
especially because we know that shape
can be modulated by the environment or
uh the stage of development so what
could be the regulation for this
feedback loop so we've uh started to
touch upon this by looking at Regulators
of micu Dynamics and in particular what
we found is that the katanin so the
katanin is is a molecular scissors that
cuts the macules and increase the macu
Dynamics and what we found is that in a
mutant for the Kine gene or the Kine
protein we have a slower Mac Dynamics
but we also have a slower response to
Mechanical forces so we could imagine
that by playing with katanin activity we
could have a feedback loop that is going
to be more more or less efficient and
then you can imagine that you can modify
or modulate the shape by modulating the
katanin but again playing with this
overall context of the mechanical
feedback loop okay and we found also
some interesting consequences on growth
heterogenity but I'm not going to go
into this detail here another question
we have for this is the mechano
transtion pathway so how come I mean how
can how can a cell sense tension
so there's a lot of data known I mean
there a lot of data in the animal
systems there are mechano transtion
pathway that are identified in animals
there is formally no or maybe there's
some indication in Plants about mean
transtion Pathways but there's no formal
demonstration of a full mean transtion
pathway in plants so this is an open
area so yeah I'm just going to uh
pinpoint one maybe piece of data to show
whether what we found is actually making
sense with what we know about the
macules in relation to stress so if you
um what we know is that the macules are
extremely Dynamic so they polymerize
depolymerize they are cut all the time
and they can also zipper so they can
bundle with one another so this is the
standard situation so mices self
organize constantly and so that that's
the way they can change orientation
quite quickly so now if you put that in
an isotropic
environment well you you might have more
or less a bundling but this is not going
to give you a direction you need
something to bias the the direction so
how can we relate that to tension
there's been some data showing that if
you put the macro tuu under tension
you're going to promote the
polymerization of the macu so the micr
is going to polymerize faster if you put
the micr triu under compression it's
going to depolymerize actually it's
going to deize very very quickly it's
going to go through catastrophe so it's
going to just very quickly you can even
see on mov is in front of your screen
you can see the Mac really going away so
it can be very quick so if you add this
in the mix of the self organization then
it's logic that the maute would align
along the maximal tension right because
you're going to favor the Mac tuu that
are under tension and Destroy if you
want the Mau that are under compression
and and since this is self organized in
a way you're going to have more and more
M bundling in the direction of maximal
tension and so this is based on um data
in animal cells also in vitro so it
seems it would be something pretty
General risk response at least it makes
sense that plant cells would have used
this for their
response okay so just to conclude I'm
just going to go back to the animal
world just to expand a little bit on
this so this is um this idea that gene
expression can be impacted by mechanical
forces is not new and this is one of the
few examples where people have looked at
this in a multicellular context and this
is in in drilo so here what you do what
Emanuel far did was to indent like to
push on an UMO and you can see that this
Gene in green twist is ectopically
expressed after this compression so okay
this is very artificial I mean often is
dropil ambrio pushed by micro indentor I
guess not too often in nature but
actually what's what's interesting is
that this Gene is expressed in the
domain
but during gastrulation is experiencing
compression so that means that maybe
during Evolution there was there is
tissue movement especially during
gastation actually where you have
patterns again of compression and
tension and this can affect gene
expression so this is in dropil but
actually more recently last year
actually he showed the same thing in
zebra fish and what's spectacular here
is that so here you have the gulation in
a drad so the cells are compressed and
you induce twist in zebra fish so this
is epiboly so that would be the the
equivalent you also have tissue movement
and you induce no tail which is would be
the equivalent of twist here through the
same mechano transtion pathway so in
this case it's a beta cine pathway so it
it really shows that it might be a very
well conserved mechanism in all living
organism or at least we can say in in
two fet that are very very distant
between the dril and and the fish and
also what's interesting in this study
and here is really going beyond the
state of the art is uh I mean these
genes so twist and noil they are really
critical for mesoderm differentiation
and mesoderm differentiation that's
really big in animal development because
this is like well a lot of things are
derived from the the mesoderm people
have been looking for the the molecular
que that would trigger meod
differentiation and no one has found the
gene that would really be important for
meod differentiation and so what Emanuel
is proposing is that it's because we
haven't found the gene because it's a
force and maybe it's also of course
there are gen involved but the trigger
the triggering event could be this
movement so of course this is like the
next boundary I guess all right so with
that I'll stop here so I have a number
of people to thanks so in the teamon I'm
working with Aris budwood who is a
theoretical
physicist uh I so the work I've showed
was mainly done by Beno Pascal Mi for
the FM and magali wal for the the
katanin experiments we do a lot I mean
we do a little bit on on cell division
with Mario V some modeling and Maria
there some people involved in imaging
here Nat and mati involved in the in the
seple analysis project with Adrian and
Richard so so I haven't talked at all
about the seel I thought we had talked a
lot this week in a workshop so but there
some interesting data coming up soon I
would say from this
Consortium uh the work on payment cell
was done in collaboration with the team
of enrik Johnson and elot movitz and
this overall project actually was
initiated by if cair again theoretical
physicist and yantras right thank you
very
[Applause]
much this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu