this is a production of Cornell
University uh what I'd like to do uh
with my time here today is to uh talk
about a survey that uh I and others have
been very involved with over the last
year and to give you the survey results
and both uh are some very to very
specific questions and most of the uh
information will be presented in charts
on the very specific questions and then
we had some o open-ended questions that
also created uh and
generated some very good information
about what Growers are thinking and then
uh before I finish up uh Andy mentioned
immigration reform I want to put some of
the things that we found in this survey
in the context of immigration reform
because that is so much on the mind of
Growers today and uh has so much
relevance to the future of labor
intensive agriculture like like apple
growing
um let me start by uh recognizing the
co-authors of this study uh first of all
uh is Paul Baker Paul is the executive
director of the New York State
Horticultural
Society uh Paul said that Paul actually
came to me and and asked if we could do
this survey and he said that he would um
help get the survey out and get the
responses back which he did Allison
dearie uh retired over the last year as
a regional fruit specialist but her
background uh in Fruit production and
economics uh was very very invaluable to
this project uh Nicole ho uh was a grad
student from the Dyson school who helped
do data analysis um I took the
leadership on uh writing the report
which will be out shortly and Brad
Rickard helped with uh with the uh data
analysis and the manuscript uh review
and input uh on the report
so let me tell you about what we did and
and let me first say that um Paul Baker
in the hord society spends a lot of his
time uh working with the labor
department and other government agencies
getting them to
understand uh horiculture and in this
case uh the Apple industry and uh one of
the things that one of his his
motivations was that if he has specific
information about what goes on in the
orchard he can help uh inform the
process of regulating through uh labor
department and other
agencies um the other motivation the
motivation for us in extension is to
have a data set and be able to say
something more about the industry and
about Workforce issues in the Apple
industry then what our government data
sets uh give us today yes we get labor
information from the Census and we get
some from the New York New York EG
statistics and there is something called
the the agricultural workers survey uh
out of uh out of Washington but none of
those give us the detail that we can get
when we do a survey such as this um so
we uh Paul through the Hort Society took
the initiative to uh mail out
480 surveys to Apple Growers who
contribute to the New York State Apple
order for
promotion uh we asked it was a
three-page survey we asked the Growers
to report their information based on the
2013 growing season we got uh 955 usable
responses back about 20% uh response
rate we were fairly pleased with that
and uh one of the things that I want to
point out right up front especially with
so many grad students in the audience is
that this is not a random
sample uh this is 95 Growers who self-
selected to return our survey form and
as a result uh we have to be careful
about expanding to the entire industry
because um I'll give you one example
here at the bottom of the slide um it
just so so happens that uh the many of
the people who decided to send this back
happen to be Growers who use the h2a
program about half of them so uh this is
not a random sample but nonetheless we
have uh more detailed information about
what's going on in on New York apple
farms uh than is available elsewhere
so the number of bearing acres per Farm
uh this slide uh gives you a sense that
um we did get responses from every size
group uh 19% were greater than 250 Acres
19% were also less than 20 acres and
then uh
distributed uh in between that as well
but no one group uh was is far larger
than the other in terms of size based on
Acres uh in the
survey um we asked for their threeyear
average annual Apple production and
specifically asked for the three-year
average because there was a a very poor
year with frost uh damage and cold
damage to the crop that uh really
reduced some people's yield a couple of
years ago so that's why we asked for the
three-year average and you can see how
that distributes uh as
well and then we asked for the total
number of workers and uh not
surprisingly the workers we've you can
see very visually there that the workers
are concentrated in the top two size
groups uh
100 to 250 acres and over 250
acres and then we did uh we asked each
grower what region that they produced in
and so um there are far more charts uh
that will be in the report than uh I'm
able to provide here today but we were
able to um to cross tab between regions
and get some interesting information and
uh so uh there are basically four uh
Apple growing regions in the State
Central and Western New York Northern
New York Eastern New York and Long
Island uh Long Island is not a very big
player in all this although Long Island
is a very
Horticultural uh spot for New York State
uh there aren't all that many apples
grown on Long Island but this gives you
a sense of how many
uh how much response we got uh from all
over the state we only got five
responses from Northern New York but you
can see that up in that's the uh Lake
Champlain region there are there are
very few Farms up there but they account
for a lot of the Apple
production apple farms hiring uh h2a
workers and uh so I I alluded to this
earlier
48% said we hire on our Farm h2a Workers
um the other 52% said that they didn't
now one of the reasons why this is
important is uh there is that in that
52% very likely there are some Growers
who have some undocumented workers who
are working on their Farm anecdotally
what what I find from talking to grower
is even if you are in the h2a program
and hire some h2a workers you might also
have some non h2a workers that are
undocumented workers and so uh it's many
people have have looked at and discussed
the fact that even though we don't have
specific numbers undocumented workers
are not only a part of
uh labor intensive Agri all kinds of
labor intensive agriculture but they're
a part
uh likely of the New York Apple industry
as
well for those of you who may not be
familiar with the h2a program uh let me
just make a couple of comments about
that uh the h2a program is a Government
Federal Government run program operated
through the labor department that brings
in seasonal agricultural workers for
commercial farms in this country they
can come here for up to 10 months and
then go home this time of year Growers
are filling out their work orders and
planning ahead to get their workers for
the coming growing
season the home country of h2a workers
um primarily in this state U most of the
workers are coming from Mexico Andor
possibly other uh Central American
countries some are coming from there but
most of them are coming from Jamaica
and
um the I I will just go into more detail
in a few minutes but the h2a program is
very controversial uh it's
expensive and uh there's a lot of
paperwork and red tape involved in in
using the program uh so sometimes it's
criticized on the other hand uh if we
look at Lake the Lake Champlain area and
other areas to the state where Jamaican
workers come uh to work on apple farms
and we talk to The Growers we will find
that many times the Growers will say
that these Jamaican workers have come
here uh
for sometimes for decades for 20 30
years the same workers coming back to
work for 8 to 10 weeks uh they're very
productive they're very reliable from
the Grower's perspective and from the
worker perspective they can come for 8
weeks or 10 weeks and make a fair amount
of income compared to their income
potential at home and then have a much
better standard of living in their home
country the length of seasonal
employment uh this just tells you that
uh for those uh Growers that hire uh
seasonal workers 28% just hire Harvest
workers the other
72% uh hire workers throughout the
season for production various production
practices such as pruning and thinning
and other
operations using a crew leader um 26%
said that they did use a hired crew
leader and Allison de tells me that this
number has slowly decreased over the
years and continues to decrease
worker experience
requirements um now I want to go back to
Paul Baker and the hord society because
uh a few years ago with the h2a program
one of the things that happened and uh
policies change and rules change based
on political
administrations and for some reason in
the labor
department um the labor department
started to change their Phil philosophy
of what experience was needed uh for uh
Apple Pickers and and Orchard
workers
and uh
consequently a farmer a few Farmers
would farmers would put in their work
order and find out that and ask for a
lot of experience requirements and the
labor department said well you Pro you
don't need all these work requirements
and so we're going to they ended up
sending in some cases less experienced
workers and this created some concern in
the grower community and so the Growers
went to Paul Baker at the hord society
and said um we need to document the
kinds of experience that workers need
because these are not unskilled jobs and
so this next set of slides gives you
some idea of uh the kinds of experience
that Growers feel that they need when
they're hiring uh workers so um 35% said
no we can deal with the workforce the
way it is we don't need uh previous
experience but 65% said yes we
definitely need previous experience uh
for what we're trying to accomplish in
our
Orchard uh months of experience required
by types of work uh on the left hand
side you get a sense of the kinds of uh
um experience that is needed pruning
equipment operation tractor driving
picking uh for both fresh and for uh
process and then we have this whole list
of specific work experience requirements
some of which Growers not All Growers
ask for this but some Growers do ask for
all of these pruning chainsaw operation
Etc all these different kinds of
experience they want the workers to have
had for productivity reasons before uh
they show up on the
job then there's a picking requirement
people want uh workers that can uh pick
quickly and without bruising and so
there's not only so there's two
components to that requirement one is to
uh be very productive and um pick
quickly and also not bruise the fruit
and uh so the average hours uh that we
found uh workers were working for
picking uh was
8.6 and they were doing all of these uh
they they might be asked to pick drop
apples uh they might be asked to uh do
fresh stem clipping spot picking uh
cleaning the whole tree and then picking
for process apples and the requirements
on how fast they do that depend upon how
how difficult or easy the job is to do
now um many of you may be familiar with
this but but I learned a few things as
an AG Economist doing this project and
one of the things I learned was about uh
fresh stem click clipping and if you
don't know what that is uh very often
you have a thin skinned Apple like honey
crisp and if you leave the stem on the
apple and that Apple gets in a bin with
other honey crisp apples the stem is
going to pierce the skin of the other
apples and so uh so the
worker uh the Picker is given a little
set of Clippers that look like uh small
scissors and that is used to do the
picking so now we've made this job of
picking apples uh even more complex
because they have to clip the stem when
they pick the Apple instead of just uh
pulling it off the
tree how Apple Pickers get
paid um by say we we gave uh four
choices for this uh by the hour only 26
% said that's how they paid only by the
piece 14% said that and then 27% said we
have a combination of Peace rates and
hourly rates depending upon what we're
doing and how easy or difficult it is to
do the job and that also um goes to the
last one
depends uh means it depends upon how
difficult it is to do the job uh if a
job gets difficult enough and you can't
make your piece rate by doing that job
it makes more sense for a grower to use
an hourly rate and so we have all
combinations of how Pickers get
paid wage rates so this will give you an
idea of wage rates for fresh apples and
this goes back to my comment about the
random sample uh if we had average wage
rates for the entire industry
they would be a bit lower than what you
see here but when you have 48% of The
Growers in the
survey um uh as h2a Growers the h2a rate
is uh I'm not sure what it was uh for
2013 but it's around $11 it was around
$111 per hour so these rates are very
likely higher than what would be the
average for the entire
industry uh I think wage rates are
really important that we keep an eye on
them and take a look at them examine
them uh I'm going to talk about
immigration reform in a minute uh one of
the big challenges that we have in
agriculture is paying enough to compete
with other Employers in the geographic
area that the business is in and so um
keeping an eye on and making sure our
wage rates are competitive is is an
important issue now and I think it's
going to become even more important in
the
future uh and this just gives you an
idea of what the peace rates are peace
rates uh generally are um by 20 Push bin
and this gives you an indication of
those as well and uh as the rate as the
uh job gets more difficult uh we start
with cleaning the entire tree is the
easiest job and so that rate's a little
lower and that goes all the way up to a
much higher rate for fresh Sten uh
clipping when that is required in the
orchard
now one of the things one of the
opportunities we have and this this is a
good example of the kinds of information
that we cannot get from other government
data sets and that is the um we can ask
in a survey like this what are your
worker shortage issues do you have
worker shortage issues and I don't have
I don't have my slide I don't have the
slide here for the whole group but what
that slide says is that
36% of The Growers said uh in the in the
whole of all those who responded 36% %
said that that they were short of
workers in 2013 and this gives you a bit
of an idea of uh of a Breakout by region
of who said they were short of workers
and who said that they had uh sufficient
workers and Central New York and
Northern New York indicated that they
were most short of
workers then we asked them along these
same lines uh what was the average
number of additional workers that you
would have hired if they were available
for your farm in
2013 and you can see that uh in in some
of the smaller Farms that started out
with two workers and the Very largest
farm said they would have hired uh
almost 11 workers full-time equivalent
wise uh to work on the farm if those
workers were available
then we went one step further and said
well what do you as you look at your
Workforce needs in the future what are
you
anticipating and uh how many employees
do you think that you'll need three
years from now uh fewer less or stays
the same and 74% said um that they are
were anticipating with the needs of
their business that they were going to
need more employees than what they hire
today and this has real implications for
immigration reform and how we where
these workers are going to come from uh
in the future and how we Source uh labor
in the
future and then finally so the last
thing that the grower got uh in the Sur
when he was filling out he or she was
filling out the survey was a couple of
open-ended questions and here's an
opportunity for us to ask some things
about um they can answer the question
any way they want now it gets a little
bit you have to then do this grouping
lumping process at the end but uh we end
up writing out all the answers on
summary sheets and it's very interesting
to look at what uh Growers say in an
open-ended question when they can answer
it any way they like
um so we asked them first what were the
top three issues that you think grower
organizations that work on your behalf
should work on in the next 5 years labor
availability and immigration and h2a and
efficiency and all those things were Far
and Away above the the following two um
so labor labor availability was number
one uh not surprising in government
regulation is number two we hear that
all the time especially as the farm
grows in size um and then marketing
consumer education Global markets
bilocal all those marketing issues uh
were number three so this is what they
said they wanted organizations that they
belong to uh to do on their behalf in
the years
ahead um and this just is to reinforce
uh the point that uh we hear this not
only in the Apple uh industry today but
many many labor intensive IND industries
that um labor workforce issues are our
number one management issue and if we
could solve that life would improve in
terms of managing the farm
business now to me this W is the
question U that was most interesting of
me almost of interest to me when we put
this together one of the things that was
on my mind a lot is okay we all know
that immigration reform has stalled but
the farm manager is dynamic operates a
dynamic uh business and does not stop
just because immigration uh reform is
stalled they have to keep running this
business because they have such a large
capital investment in many cases so we
asked the survey participants given the
labor pressures that you've experienced
uh in the last several years including
labor being short how has or will your
business
change and uh so these are in order of
the response again we we grouped uh
their open-ended responses and in order
of priority this is what they said
Orchard design planting systems and
equipment to be more labor efficient was
the biggest thing uh that they were
doing uh the other thing that goes the
second item that goes along with this is
downsizing producing less and decreasing
L acreage um and and what that really
means is uh with these high density
planting systems that we have converted
to in this state over the last 10 years
uh with a Vengeance we are producing
more apples on less acreage or more
apples far more apples on the same
acreage in some cases um the other the
third thing that they said is we are
relying more on h2a than we have in the
past which means two things sometimes
the grower was not in the h2a program
was but was going to uh go to the h2a
program to hire workers and others were
hiring more workers through the h2a
program and then fourth uh and this is
not surprising either it's gone on for
decades if if a business becomes too
labor intensive or too complex there are
certain people who say we just cannot
come up with the capital or we don't
want to proceed with this business it is
uh the business is not viable for the
Next Generation a and we're going to opt
out
so some further comments on the
open-ended questions Growers are
reporting a shift to high density
planning systems um uh higher yields per
acre platforms and other equipment
dramatically improve labor efficiency I
took this photo at the uh fruits at the
fruit extension fruit tour uh up in
Orleans County this summer and uh this
gives you a look at two things one is
the planning system is uh the tall
spindle planning system a high density
system that has been uh developed and
refined and promoted at Geneva and the
other thing is uh there you have in the
middle of that row a platform and that
platform uh the workers stand on the
plantform and can prune and can uh pick
and do other operations that make the
operations far more labor efficient than
they ever were before and so the uh the
the one thing that is really interesting
to me about all of this is that the high
density planting system and labor
efficiency were were not developed
independently it was all developed
together to be integrated so um so all
of these the row spacings and the
timeing and all of these things uh were
all put together in a way that uh labor
could be the very most
productive so grower response to labor
challenges uh make each full-time
equivalent uh worker as productive as
possible in these new systems C do that
uh eliminate excess labor and less
productive acreage I was uh I was in the
orchard I was up in Western New York
during Apple Harvest and one of the
things that's increasingly clear land
prices in Western New York and around
the state are going up dramatically and
so if you can be more productive on the
same acreage or less acreage then you
don't have the extra capital investment
of of new acreage and new high-priced
acreage uh reduce Risk by using the h2a
program and I haven't said anything
about this yet but in New York um
immigration enforcement pressure has
been
dramatic and uh the the most likely
reason appears to be our border with
Canada and a high critical mass of
enforcement officers in in Border Patrol
out of Buffalo and in the North country
and so um one there are several reasons
why a grower would use the h2a program
one is to make sure that they have the
workers they need if there is a little
bit of Labor shortage out there the
other is to make sure that they don't
have workers that are undocumented and
could get deported in the middle or
detained in the middle of the harvest
season or the middle of the growing
season so reducing risk is becoming a
more important part of the h2a program
uh and a motivation uh especially in
this state where we have so much
enforcement pressure I go to other
states I talk to folks from other states
and uh New York and Vermont uh uh seem
to have a disproportionate share of
enforcement pressure and The Growers
feel that as they try to operate their
businesses um and then the other thing
that uh in their open-ended questions
that the grower said is we we're going
to continue to aggressively advocate for
immigration
reform um I already made this point
Growers report an increasing Reliance on
h2a because other workers are not inv
available they can manage risk and uh
it's a response to enforce re
enforcement
pressure
now the h2a Paradox and I've sort of
been leading up to this Growers who use
the h2a program are often very critical
of the program it's expensive there's a
lot of paperwork occasionally you don't
get your workers on time uh and Growers
don't like that they want they're in the
program so that their labor needs will
be predictable and their the labor force
will be
predictable and so there can be a few
problems along the
way that said some Growers have reported
in their open-ended question on this
survey that without the h2a program they
don't know what they do without the h2a
program they would probably be out of
business and
so um so
h2a is especially in this state is
becoming um more
important so now that I've sort of now
that I've gone through some of the
things we found and there are a lot more
uh there's a lot more information that
will be in our publication that'll be
posted on the Dyson website in the
extension section um so now that we've
gotten to this point I want to put this
in the context uh a little bit of uh
immigration reform and what does what
does some of these things mean to
immigration
reform
when we talk about what agriculture
wants out of immigration reform policy
what agriculture wants is very clear uh
and the entity that speaks for
agriculture in Washington is called the
agricultural Workforce Coalition and it
is a
uh it is a coalition of dozens of
agricultural groups like American Farm
Bureau Western uh Western
Growers uh Western United dairymen and
so on all of the
major uh Farm organizations that deal
with labor intensive agriculture are
part of this Coalition and the Coalition
speaks with one voice and it says uh the
following and right right before the
last Congress about almost 3 years ago
after the presidential election they got
together and redid this and reinforced
their position which is that
agricultural operations must have access
to a stable and skilled Workforce and we
need to do this by doing two things one
is providing an adjustment in
immigration status for the undocumented
workers that are already working in ag
culture so that can they can stay and
work in
agriculture and the other thing that is
needed is to address Workforce needs
with a modern guest worker visa program
and what that means is uh if we continue
with the h2a program it needs to be
fixed and if we don't we need a new
program that improves the good things
that that improves upon on the good
things uh that we already have uh in the
h2a program and one of the realities of
policy in this country is that
government policy is often based on
inertia and the likelihood that we are
going to throw out the completely throw
out the h2a program and start over is
pretty slim in my estimation which means
uh immigration reform needs to look at
what we're what's going right with the
H2 proa program uh think about what
needs to be improved and then come up
with a new guest worker program that
will combine those two
things so that's what agriculture says
it wants so let's we just started the
114th Congress uh a few weeks ago let's
look at what happened in the 113th
Congress the last Congress that ended on
July 31st
the senate in that Congress passed
s74 uh which was a comprehensive
Immigration Reform Bill it had its own
separate agricultural title largely
because that's what the agricultural
Workforce Coalition
wanted and uh in my opinion we probably
agriculture could probably have not done
much better there was uh an opport Unity
for legalized status for uh the
undocumented workers and there was a new
and improved guest worker program that
would make some real changes to the h2a
program so what happened it went it then
became the House of Representatives term
turn to do something with this piece of
legislation uh last year at this time we
knew that the window there was a window
before the midterm election
uh right up until about the August
recess they there were some bills
introduced none of them uh that were one
was introduced by the Democrats and it
looked just like s74 and that was going
nowhere the other bills introduced by
the Republicans failed to do anything
about the 11 million illegal immigrants
in this country and at the end of the
day the August recess came nothing was
done no bills were passed out of the
house and uh and at that point President
Obama began threatening and saying well
if you're not going to do if you the
house if if the Congress isn't going to
do anything then I'm going to do
something on my own uh which he did uh
it prob it only it probably only would
affect what he did with his executive
action a small number of workers to make
them
uh allow them deferred status and
deferred uh detention and deportation so
I don't see it as having a big uh impact
on agriculture and all the organizations
that represent agriculture within 24
hours of the executive action being
announced uh came out and said uh this
is no substitute the executive action is
no sub substitute for comprehensive
immigration reform which we still want
and are going to work hard to to
get so that brings us to the new
Congress the 114th
Congress um I uh had the opportunity to
be uh with a group of farmers who were
um visiting house members on Capitol
Hill two weeks ago and it
is increasingly apparent that to me that
the House of
Representatives uh cannot agree on how
what to do with the 11 million ilal
immigrants what immigration reform
should look like and the likely it seems
unlikely that anything is going to
happen in the 114th Congress because we
have the presidential elections that
will be in full swing by this summer and
when we have an election cycle it's very
hard to get these kinds of of tus tough
pieces of legislation passed so it is it
seems unlikely to me that we're going to
have much progress or any progress in
this Congress which means we're probably
going to have to wait until we get a new
president and another new Congress and
hope at that time that we can get some
movement
so what if you are an apple grower if
you're a farm manager how do you think
think about all of this stuff that comes
out of the survey and uh emanates from
the immigration reform process um I I
think Growers there's no doubt that
Growers uh will continue to improve
labor efficiency these new systems have
worked great and they continue to take
out the older varieties and the tall
trees and put in uh these new dwarf
trees and these new high density systems
that is going to
continue um they have said in their
open-ended question answers that they're
going to stay involved in the
immigration reform legislative process
and I think that if uh I think we have
an environment now that if the
organizations like Farm Bureau and
others send out a letter that says it is
time to call your Congressman this this
issue is so important that if there a
piece of legislation to support or to
oppose those offices will be flooded
because Palmers are now paying a lot of
attention to this and then finally uh
develop a human resource strategic plan
to include improved wages and benefits
improved housing and supervisory
training one of the things that comes
out of this discussion of immigration
reform is how do we keep the
undocumented workers once they have a
piece of paper that says that they have
a legalized
status uh and uh I think that one of the
answers to that is going to be these
three points the wages benefits housing
and supervisory training now with
housing Apple Growers have a leg up over
for example Dairy Farmers and we're a
big we're a big Dairy state
well Apple Growers because of seasonal
label labor already have housing
inspections Dairy Farmers don't and uh
if so Dairy Farmers are going to have we
still have to be vigilant in the fruit
industry but da uh farmers are going to
have to uh have a a whole new way of
thinking about their housing and some of
the regulations that may come about
because they're less regulated uh than
the Growers are at this point
at this point I will stop there and I
think we've got we stop at at 1:10 so
we've got time for some questions and
comments and rebuttal and so
[Applause]
on my name
is this year back in the50s what we have
to do with that
time those people who do not have Farm
experience before cor we have to work on
farms okay um
um what we did was a lot of things that
are being done today you show the slides
we had pick the apples uh thin them and
a lot of different things at that point
I know farming has changed and Cornell
has changed are we still doing anything
here at Cornell to uh to have some of
our students work in the Summers and and
and do the U uh do the growing process
in in let's say up state
champagne Val Etc not to my knowledge
but I might not be the best person to
answer that question there are there are
a lot of internships available to
students and so those opportunities
exist in the form of internships okay
yeah both off campus here I know like
the fruit group right here Cornell has
five every summer that they come and
take them on and they work on various
aspects of growing
fruit plantations has interns yeah so I
think there are there's also a formal
course you can take on farm equipment
and and use uh you sign up for like a
regular course and every week you know a
couple of days a week you out and you
learn how to drive tractors and hook up
equipment and stuff like that right you
mentioned um positions with people would
the stem clipping for the you mentioned
the honey crisp apples right what is the
in New York state what is the economic
import I mean I know honey CIS is a
relatively new and also very high value
variety um what is the the like What
proportion of farms are growing like the
these high value varieties that would
actually require that versus something
like a red delicious or a granny smith I
I we did not we did not have enough
information from the survey to answer
that question and I don't know the
answer to that question those the newer
varieties keep expanding and the old
varieties
keep uh keep being
replaced so so farmers as a whole in
general tend to be conservative
politically and folks that are sort of
pushing for you know slowing down you
know no path to citizenship and no
amnesty and all that are also
politically conservative so there seems
to be there must be some tension between
those two groups is the n what's the
nature of that conversation between the
politically conservative politicians and
a politically conservative farmer is it
different than the what we hear here as
sort of the general public and what
what's the farmer say to the politician
who seems to be working against their
interest in this particular
Cas well that that's that is a
fascinating question I can tell you what
happened two weeks ago when when we were
on Capital
Hill we um so I went with a group of
Growers and we went to five or six house
member's office and usually end up talk
talking to the staff now some of those
congressmen are new and so then you have
to start at the beginning and say why
all this stuff is important but some of
them like Tom Reed and others have been
around for a long time Chris Collins and
they've heard this from the same Growers
for several years running and so then
you don't have to educate them and so
then uh it's likely that one of the
Growers will say well so what do you
tell us really what you think is going
on and one of the things we heard was uh
and this is one this is a quote from one
of the staff members was there are two
dozen Knuckleheads in Congress in the
house that do not
want anything want to do anything with
the 11 million undocumented uh
immigrants and so you have that small
group that is very vocal and very dug in
and trying to find the middle for the
Republicans has been very very difficult
does that help to answer the question I
mean the the if you're Tom Reed or Chris
Collins and you come from an Upstate
agricultural
District um you get it and you know that
the farmers are not going to get off
your back so they're going to these
conservatives and trying to get
something going and the conservatives
are having are are just staying dug in
to Marvin's question the argument isn't
ideological it's between those in
agriculture who want them to do
something and the Republicans who can't
do anything so they end up explaining
why it can't be done and we and we have
to remember politic
that those house members who are taking
that um that hands off we don't want to
do anything on immigration approach or
anything for the illegal immigrants they
come from districts whose electorate
want the same thing so while Chris
Collins's electorate wants this moving
for agriculture you've got another
person a Conservative Republican in a
Conservative Republican District who
doesn't who wants the same thing that
that house member is
saying uh Geneva do you have any
questions I was wondering on that point
three you have down there on that last
slide whether uh they're looking to
current employers like McDonald's that
trains a lot of people in supervisory
training as a source of Labor or crew
chiefs or anything along those
lines uh will you I'm not sure I
completely understand the question are
would we get would we stand to hire some
workers away from McDonald's is that
what you're saying right so that it's
not immigrant
labor um they're working at sort of
similar wages um and they have some
training uh I think that
uh that we're there is a difference
between outdoor work and working in the
elements and so on uh and working at uh
McDonald's uh number one number two it
gets back to this whole question of will
Americans do these
jobs uh and I have a feeling that there
are probably some
McDonald's uh managers who wonder the
same thing if Americans would do those
jobs so at these low labor levels um I
think we're going to continue to
struggle with how
to uh get the workers and get them
trained and compensate them uh to get
the work done I I actually don't see
much movement between a job like
McDonald's and an apple orchard but I do
see both employers having the same
challenges just one thing I we always
take it for granted that h2a is an
oppressive program and you've
explained the fact that that it's
difficult for employers why is it that
way why isn't it built to to provide
that stable Workforce that everybody
wants
can um I think a large part of the
reason is that when laws like this are
uh enacted the labor Advocates have had
something to say about them and so there
are assurances put into the program I
think part the paperwork is part of that
I think the wages are part of that that
the labor Advocates have said uh the
workers need more than what you're
willing to give and so they compromise
on something that uh does have higher
wages and more uh
restrictions along the
way okay I think we're
[Applause]
done this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu