this is a production of Cornell
University okay I think the numbers have
stabilized many of you already know me
I'm Luci VI I'm organizing our lab's
annual hemp webinar I am a third year
PhD candidate in the Larry Smart Lab at
beral University and I'm working with on
hemp father Milo in hemp we are focused
on hemp grain this year and today's
speaker is Ian grah gra I'm
sorry who is joining us from the UK
thank you Yan for accepting our
invitation we're all excited to hear
your talk following uh
postdoctoral postdoctoral fellowships at
the University of Oxford and kage
Department plant biology in Stanford
California Ian took a faculty position
on set up his own love in the UK at the
University of Glasgow in
1994 when I was born in 1999 he moved uh
to become the Western chair of
biochemical genetics in the center for
novel agricultural products at the
University of York where he remains with
his research focused on biosynthesis of
plant natural products and how these can
be developed for various industrial
applications representing the University
of York Ian has granted the
UK was granted the UK plant breeders
right for a higher Lake hemp seed
Variety in February of
2021 Ian was elected a fellow of the
Royal Society in 2016 and this a science
Trustee of the Royal Botanical
Gardens K Yan is also the academic lead
for Bio Yorkshire a partnership
involving the University of York pheros
science and asan Brian college that aims
to develop uh to deliver green economic
growth and is the director for the UK
government funded high value
biorenewables
Network the title of his talk is
molecular breeding of new seed all
varieties of industrial H the webinars
are recorded and uploaded to our school
of Integrative PL science sip YouTube
channel feel free to check the four
previous ones that we have have already
uploaded to our Channel and with that
the virtual stage is all your in good
yes thank you I should first of all
apologize for providing you with such a
long bio it's taken about five minutes
of our valuable time so it's a great
pleasure to have had this invitation
from Lucia and the people at Cornell I
think it's a great idea to have it such
a global seminar I would I honestly
didn't appreciate it was so so Global
but welcome every and thank you for
turning up to listen to me for the next
40 or 50 minutes uh this is a story
which is really close to my heart it's
uh I've been working on hemp in the
background of my other main projects and
medicinal plants uh for for the last 15
years almost and I think as in other
places getting funding to work on hemp
has never been all that easy it's maybe
getting a little bit easier now uh with
a relax in uh regulations around
planting and growing and and all of that
especially in North America but uh yeah
it's a great opportunity to to tell you
about some of the work that we've done
and uh and also maybe give you some
insight into into seed biology uh which
is another one of my interests and has
been since I started my lab the year
that uh Lucia was born as she pointed
out so that kind of makes me feel a bit
old but there you go so uh molecular
breeding of new seed oil varieties of
industrial hemp I think Industrial Hemp
when you talk about it most people think
about fiber but my focus and my
interests over the last uh 40 odd years
have been very much on seeds and uh and
oil and then progressing into other
exotic medicinal crops uh the the
concept which I'm going to introduce and
many of you will be familiar with in
terms of altering traits in industrial
hemp varieties is reverse genetics and
that's really going from Gene to
phenotype rather than forward genetics
which is going from phenotype to Gene as
it were and of course the potential of
reverse genetics in orphan crops orphan
crops being those that are not all that
well studied or being developed by uh
molecular breeding Tools in particular
uh the whole you know revolution in DNA
sequencing and and knowledge of the
genome and genome assemblies now as well
uh are greatly facil greatly facilitate
this concept of reverse genetics because
we can get to so-called candidate genes
much much easier than we we ever could
before and I'll give you some insight
into how we went about doing this even
before the sort of that revolution had
really taken off so uh so first of all
just let's talk a little bit about
Industrial Hemp uh it's of course a
multi-purpose crop we we use that
terminology Industrial Hemp for low
canabo hemp that's grown mainly for for
fiber and uh and seed and and then from
seed oil applications as you'll see
uh and and as you'll see in my talk uh
that whole concept of doing
transcriptome analysis has allowed us to
identify genes and modify genes involved
in the seed oil composition and uh just
to in North America in fact in Canada
the industrial hemp is grow is still
grown largely for seed rather than fiber
and there's huge potential to develop
this crop as a as a multi-purpose crop
for fiber as well as seed and maybe I'll
just say initially
uh that you know hemp has been growing a
very very long time and in fact in in
the UK uh during the reign of Henry VII
when uh in the
1600s uh every farm and farmer in the
country was legally obliged to grow a
road which I think is about a third of
an acre of hemp because it was so much
in need for sailing ships for the for
the sales and for the Rope of those
sailing ships so you can see
it's been a very important part of
uh of of the of the UK as well and but
it's Fallen right back and my ambition
is to really increase the the acreage of
it again from the something like you
know 800 hectors that that are grown
mainly for fiber in the UK today so uh
yeah
uh so just a little bit then about the
crop I don't want to dwell in this
because those of you have tuned in your
interest in hemp you'll know all of this
but it's an annual herbaceous uh plant I
wanted to make the point that you get
both monious and dious varieties dious
varieties are are are those that where
the the male and female flowers are are
on are on separate plants in fact uh and
uh and that introduces challenges itself
to to to breeding programs so it
basically behav like you know uh
separate male and female uh individuals
for for uh for
crossing and
uh and I've mentioned the different the
different drug types it originated in
Europe north northern India and Persia
but it's now cultivated uh you know
around the world in warm to temperate
regions and and and there are good
claims around it being used for low
input farming and uh and in fact in the
UK one of my ambitions is to really get
it adopted is as a brick crop to grow on
on good orable land where cereals are
growing where every 3 or four years you
need to have a break and and at the
minute that's large that break crop is
often oil seed rape or Canola as as you
refer to it in in in North America and
uh but there's all sorts of issues with
that as being really uh terms of in fact
in Europe now the main sprays that are
used in canola are being banned and so
they're looking for alternative brick
crops and and Industrial Hemp as one
such that could be really be adopted and
Farmers like growing it uh and so the
applications are in fiber and and canabo
and in seed oil the the industrial hemp
varieties that that they need to be
below
2% THC in the UK for us to get a license
to grow them I think in the U other
places it's 3% and now if you just take
a look at this seed it's uh got about 30
30 to 35% oil 25% protein the amino acid
composition is really really good for
human health and if you go into Health
Food Shops you can often buy uh you know
hemp hemp seed powder because of the the
uh protein composition and the oil as
will come on to as also very interesting
good for dietary fiber vitamins and
minerals so so nutritionally it's it's
very interesting and is usually in those
high-end uh nutritious Foods
uh so just this uh when we start this
project and in fact still in North
America this variety phola is one of the
favorites that's grown in Canada in
particular uh there are there are other
options as well of course but it's it's
uh uh fola itself is interesting it it's
a relatively dwarf variety uh which
means that you can combine harvest it
for for seed uh early flowering at 25 to
30 days early maturing at 115 days and
it's it's a really nice diploid variety
that we really like to grow and and work
with here in York as well because it's
fast cycling so so we can you know get
uh a couple of uh Generations in in in a
year for example in under glass and uh
can be grown at high latitudes hence uh
it's popular popularity in in Canada
good rotation crop and a see I put in
here a seed yield of one to two hectares
there's claims out there that you can
get above two hectares and it's very as
like any crop it's not magic and what
you you get out what you put in and it
so depends on the soil and the the
the uh the conditions for
growth uh I just I'll say something
about the actual fatty acid composition
because it's the fatty acid composition
in the seed oil uh that that makes it
interesting in particular for hemp and
uh so so what you've got what we've got
here is the different types of fatty
acids along the top and then I've
compared hemp uh with or this this table
Compares hemp with other oil crops as it
were and you can see immediately that
hemp has got high levels of linolic acid
which is 18 carbons two double bonds
that's what this numbering represents
and alpha linolenic acid which is 18
carbon three double bonds we'll come on
to this in my biochemistry tutorial in a
minute and uh and then the interesting
one that I'll be focusing on is OIC acid
which is 18 carb one double bond and and
so you'll see that the number of double
bonds increases as we go across this
table and uh and this puffer is
polyunsaturated fatty acids so you can
see that there is a polyunsaturated is
anything more than one double bond so
you can see that the level of puffers in
in in hemp is high at
84% and uh if you compare that with
olive oil then you can see immediately
that olive oil has got an elevated
levels of OIC acid 18 carbons one double
bond and uh and then all of these other
uh ones uh nutritionally and and
healthwise both alphal linolenic acid
which is uh which has got three double
bonds and gaml linolenic acid we'll come
in come onto these in a minute uh you
can see that many of these oil crops
don't have any GLA uh hampus is
relatively uh special let's say rather
than than unique and having a 4% GLA and
uh and this ala
GLA uh which is omega-3 and Omega 6 oils
again many of you will be aware and may
may indeed take them as as supplements
uh are important for uh are important
for your health and so we were
interested in this when we when we were
when we thought about changing the
composition because obviously if you
compare uh the levels of gla galin linic
acid to borage which is very well known
to have elevated levels of of gla it
would be nice to have more GLA in in
hemp oil obviously and then but one of
the issues with polyunsaturated fatty
acids is that they get uh they they are
oxidized they become oxidized as soon as
you take them out of the seed and in
that protective capsule and in fact just
just like fish oil which is which has
got elevated levels of polyunsaturated
fatty acids in fact 20 carbon and 22
carbon fatty acids in fish oil but that
smell of fish oil that you get when the
fish isn't fresh is because the fish oil
is becoming oxidized and exactly the
same happens in fact with with temp oil
when you when you take it and leave it
open to the air it becomes rancid uh and
so so because of that it's not really
all that attractive for for cooking or
for processing for processed foods and
so obviously then one of the targets
could be how could you make uh make this
fatty acid composition more like olive
oil and increase the amount of OIC acid
and in so doing you would predict
increase the stability and uh so that
that was sort of the context that that
we came into this project to see if we
could do something about that and that
then I just want to then summarize very
quickly the what happens in a developing
seed when fatty acids are being made
that accumulate in the seed to give that
that uh vegetable oil that we get from
all plant seeds in fact and also in fact
from olive oil which of course isn't
derived from seeds and so so we've got
here this is the plastid which most of
you will be aware of that's present and
this is this is involved largely in
photosynthesis but it's also involved in
that first stage of fatty acid
biosynthesis in seeds and and in fact
fatty acids are synthesized in in
developing seeds and in seeds all around
the plant up until they reach that 18
carbon one double bond oleic acid that
we T that I mentioned
uh and this is a fatty acid to saturat
that's soluble and and it's quite unique
and just having this job of converting
160 to 161 pal palic acid and staric
acid to 181 and then and then the fatty
acids come out into the cytool and there
is this whole Suite of of fatty acid
desaturases in that keep introducing
more desaturation and double bonds into
that fatty acid backbone and uh and we
know a lot about these from from work
done in other plants so it's a a
so-called Delta 12 desaturase which
introduces this fatty acid double bond
uh to get linolic acid and then there's
a Delta 15 desaturase that takes it on
to alphal linic alphal linolenic acid
and then there's a different desaturase
which converts linolic acid to gaml
linolenic acid and and and the
difference between gamma and Alpha as
you'll see on the next slide is that
they they occur at different positions
on the fatty acid backbone so this is
now this is now a depiction of a fatty
acid this is a leg acid with just one
double bond at the double bond at the
nine carbon position this is what comes
out of the plastid and then gets acted
on by these membrane bone
desaturases that uh then introduce
another double bond a Delta at the at
the 12 carbon position and you get 182
and then and then you have as I said
this Delta 60 saturase which then gives
you uh gamma uh alpha linic acid and
then Delta 15 desaturates which gives
you alpha linic acid so so you'll see
where we're going with this is that you
need to understand and identify those
desaturases before you can modify them
to uh uh in whatever way you want to and
here what we've got is now a developing
seed and these are just the this is the
embryo of the developing seed uh and uh
you can see over SE over a couple of
months this embryo matures from torpedo
stage to upturn Stage to to this is
filled but not desiccated stage fnd and
what we did was we we looked at the
trans scripto of the of these developing
seeds and we identified using
bioinformatics a whole bunch of
candidate desaturates genes and uh and
because there is homology between genes
uh we we then used functionally car
characterized desaturators from other
species and we identified so this this
is
a this is the fatty acid disater 2A and
2B and basically these are the
deur uh the the the nomenclature here is
confusing uh in the literature as well
for people not not
lipidologists uh but this naming came
from mutants and arabidopsis in fact fad
2 which was uh which is the Delta 12 de
satures and so this is The Fad 2A and
fad 2B and and and this is just a heat
map showing level of expression in the
developing
and so you can see immediately that this
fad 2A uh if we're interested in
identifying this Delta 12d satures is is
is a really strong candidate because
it's got this really high level
expression and similarly you can
identify you know for these other
desaturases uh candidate genes uh but of
course they're only candidates until you
really prove the gene function and uh so
this is exactly what we did uh and we
were then able to
uh to then further explore the function
of these genes and and we we then rather
than just rely on on gene expression
data and Counting the number of
transcripts that we come across in gene
expression data this slide comes from uh
quantitative
rtpcr and you can see oh sorry uh you
can see that for this Delta 12
desaturase that we we looked at the
expression of two of them and and this
one uh is very impressive in terms of a
potential candidate for developing seeds
because it shows this massive expression
at this at this filled not desiccated
stage when the oil is fatty acids are
being made and the oil is accumulating
in the seed and then this is the mature
seed this is Young Leaf and mature Leaf
so so of course when you when you're
interested in finding mutations that
will alter SE development or in any kind
of way you you want to find genes that
are only expressed in the seeds because
you don't want to have an effect
elsewhere in the plant and in fact you
could see then this second Gene uh is
very very lowly expressed so this this
this Gene immediately became our our
Target and then the other thing we did
is we took the
the the cdna the in the protein en
coding region of the Gene and
overexpress that in in sacris CIS which
is uh brewers yeast and and uh so this
this is a really good model for
understanding fatty acid uh functional
gene expression because the the wild
type uh Brewer Yeast only makes
161 and 181 so it makes the fatty acids
which you find in the plastid of a plant
but not any of those more sophisticated
fatty acids and then when you express
that candidate Gene you can see
immediately that the level of 161 Stone
from from this level to this level uh
but you get 162 appearing when you
express this uh Gene in yeast and then
also the 181 goes down and you get
appearance of 182 so that's really good
evidence that we have indeed got a uh a
hemp Gene including the enzyme which is
responsible for
desaturating uh OIC acid and uh and then
we did the same thing with that series
of candidate genes for the Delta 15 de
satures and uh and we found a gene which
was predominantly this time some
expression in young leaves and mature
leaves but predominantly expressed and
increasing expression during C
development and then again what we did
this time because this potential
substrate uh isn't made in yeast we fed
this substrate uh lenic acid and uh and
we could see that uh when we then add
that with this uh Vector expressing the
gene that we actually then get
accumulate we get
accumulation of of the it 183 uh
N3 and so
uh and so that's then good evidence and
and this these different variations of
empty Vector we also added GL and uh and
found that we were able to then also
desaturate gamma linolenic acid to the
stod donic acid so 184 and3 so so that
that then I hope uh takes uh
demonstrates to you that we've indeed
got this Gene that is that is producing
182 and we've also got this Gene which
is producing 183 from linolic acid and
184 from gaml linolic acid and so that
that then is is great evidence that we
if now if we could knock out those genes
wouldn't it be really cool because then
we could basically introduce a block
here and introduce a block here and then
we could play around with cross signals
as well so uh and that's exactly what we
did uh and we we used this method uh
this is before we had Gene editing going
and and also uh this is now really a
combination of you know traditional ways
to do plant breeding in the 1940s 1950s
1960s where you just used you just used
a mutagen and introduced lots and lots
of mutations into the genome and then
looked for often using forward genetics
of course just screen to get a trait of
in a change in a trait of interest but
in this case what we're doing is reverse
genetics where we we use this so-called
tilling approach I won't get into the
the nitty-gritty details of it but
essentially what it'll what this is now
using molecular biology where
we where we can find
heteroduplex uh we can find heteroduplex
formation when we when we mix a
combination of
seeds uh from different individuals then
if there's a mutation in a gene in one
individual then when we do when we when
we melt that DNA that's mixed from a
number of individuals we can then find a
mutation because first of all you will
get pairing of a m a mut a muted Gene
sequ a mutated Gene sequence and a wild
type Gene sequence to form a hetr duplex
and then uh we use this enzyme cell one
which basically Cuts DNA wherever you
get a
heteroduplex and in fact this enzyme
comes from celery which is why it's
called cell one and then basically that
allows us then to just
using using gels using polyacryamide
gels in fact is how we did this and uh
and we found mutations and genes and uh
and the power of this approach as well
is especially when you're working with a
dious uh uh species s uh such as hemp in
this case phola it allows you to
identify
mutations in the heterozygous state so
even though recessive mutations you can
identify them in the heterozygous state
which is almost a prerequisite for us
because it was really really difficult
still is really really difficult to self
M1 M1
plants uh
and so so basically that's what we did
we did uh ethyl methan sulfinate
mutagenesis which caused G GC to at uh
Transitions and uh we generated a
mutagenized population and basically the
way that we crossed that then any
mutations we had were going to be
heterozygous in the M2 seeds and then we
did screening essentially the way I'm
not going to dwell on it but uh but it
that was once we got the the M the
mutagen dose right this proved really
really productive for us and uh in fact
it allowed us to identify heter this
So-Cal heteroduplex mapping uh we got
about 60 mutations in two Gene targets
because the molecular biology then
allows you to to amplify uh specific
Gene targets and do the heteroduplex mar
mapping on those Gene targets and we
followed up 15 of those
mutations uh by
phenotyping and five five of those
showed Mark Chang as a fatty acid
profile which is again quite remarkable
and and thus we took those forward into
M mutation breeding program in summary
we had three
mutations in that Delta
12 uh Gene that we that I showed you
that the function of and uh I summarized
here what these do you get these really
interesting at sorry these really
interesting transitions we had stop
codons and when you're looking for
knockout mutations you you really like
stop codons obviously but we also got
other interesting this is a a ProLine to
Lucine transition and Proline which is a
really powerful amino acid in terms of
of impacting on on protein function
because it's responsible for that those
Proline kinks are really powerful
mutations as well and uh so we got a
really nice range of of mutations across
these two genes and uh and of course
this was described 10 years ago in in
this Bika at Al paper which which uh we
published so then we did
experimental this is then the work
program that we followed where we had
Gene Target Discovery and validation
just keeping an eye on the clock here
and uh
and then we did lots of uh screening as
I've just shown you selected promising
mutations and then we do did breeding
and back Crossing and uh I'm not going
to dwell on this because you're all
experts in in breeding in Cornell and
around the world but basically we took
this through and ultimately because of
course this is a dious species we we
ultimately end up in Crossing because we
could track the gene in the heterozygous
State because we had nice mole markers
for these mutations as well we then
ultimately took them through to
backcross 4 and then crossed homozygous
siblings to get homozygous backos 4mh
seed and uh and we we we then uh and one
of the nice things we were able to do as
well in terms of phenotyping is we could
just NE cut off a one of the cotle Edens
one of the true the first leaves from
the seed and do f acid profiling at the
same time as doing molecular markers and
so so then just to quickly show you then
I wouldn't be telling you all this that
we didn't have really nice phenotypes
when you knock out this Delta 15 de
saturas you expect to see an increase in
L linolic acid you would expect it to be
a a recessive mutation and that's
exactly what you see the black bars here
are the homozygous mutation you get this
elevation in in lenic acid you get this
decrease in 183 and3 in the homozyg
state compared to Wild type and and the
heterozy in fact is intermediary in a
lot of the cases and that was really
nice and uh and yeah I don't I don't
think I need to say anything more about
that impressive phenotype and what's
even more impressive is the is when you
knock out this Delta 12 de satures uh
with a with a uh with either of these
two different mutations which we talked
about which you see here depicted as
well and this stop codone is ex is is
really nice and Powerful you get nearly
a a you know a transition from about 10%
to almost 80% OIC acid with this single
uh point this single mutation in in that
uh in that
Gene and and this is what we've focused
on and in fact we've done field trials
and taken this through and as as you had
mentioned Lucia this is what we
registered in the UK as a UK variety and
not surprisingly then in that high line
there's really high levels of the fatty
acid in the triol glycerol the seed oil
as well which is is reassuring compared
to the wild type where there's nothing
and uh and then really interestingly
things like hexanols which are you know
some some of those molecules that that
that are uh give you the SM the runid
smell uh that when you when you look at
the phola wild type uh seed oil this is
in head space analysis of the seed oil
compared to the high variety you can see
that this is more or less flatlining
whereas these hexinol are really
increasing in in Wild type phola seed so
just just as further evidence of uh of
what's happened in terms of volatiles
being emitted When you crush the seed
interestingly there's elevated levels of
uh of of uh Tofer rols in in the scap
the high L variety and we don't really
know why that is but you know these
antioxidants are present in seed
obviously to protect the the the well
not obviously but assume because they're
protecting the fatty acids from
oxidation and if you don't have
polyunsaturated fatty acids in the cnap1
HOH maybe that maybe these tphols aren't
being used up and there's just more of
them but it it's just another
interesting uh statistically robust
trait and perhaps most interesting is
that is that we we do this uh sort of
Industry standard Ransom mat analysis
and if we just focus on the standard
hemp and the scap one HOH and this is
the this is the projected stability in
months of the oil at three different
temperatures 20 4 and 0 you can see
this significant re significant increase
in the in the stability uh so at 20 it
goes up to 10 months compared to 2
months and at at 4 it's
going it's going from 4 months to 29
months so you can see and this is
basically getting similar then to to
Olive Oil and and similarly we're we're
now doing a whole range of Industry
related uh St uh you know food standards
for for this hemp oil and it
behaves uh very very similar to olive
oil and so makes it very very
interesting for a much wider
Market we got patent protection of this
in the US for that particular Al and uh
we have plant breeders rights in New
York we also uh been working with uh
Partners in Canada and uh that's gone
into the list of approved cultivars and
I just put this in which is taken from
the Canadian government website uh where
they grow they they they record where
where across all the different states in
Canada uh that the different varieties
there's other varieties as well but this
is fola which is one of the most popular
varieties in in Canada and it's grown
across all these states and this
reflects that in Manitoba uh they they
were triing uh cenap 1 HOH in 2023 and
and they continue to be interested in
this so so it it performs pretty well it
performs very similarly to fola in fact
in the
field so I just wanted to mention uh if
I if I can this is my last trit that I
that I really like uh and so this is
this is one of those Delta 15 uh this
sorry this is one of the the other Delta
12 the saturas mutations which we found
for some unknown reason we don't really
understand why but as well as
producing
uh what it does is it elevates the
levels of Gamlin AIC acid and uh you can
see here it's not you know it's not
amazing but it takes it up to about 7%
from
4% and and it may have something to do
with the way that this desaturase works
we've we we haven't managed to separate
this phenotype from the from this point
mutation in the desaturase the Delta 12
desaturase and then what we did was we
combined that mutation with the Delta 15
desaturated mutation and we've managed
to take this the levels of of Gamlin leg
acid up to about 11% which as you know
when I mentioned is is getting much more
interesting in terms of uh a a new GLA
variety and we're in the process of of
trying to get variety registration for
this vary because I think this can be
very very significant significant
commercially as well it's not borage as
I said which is 24% but when you compare
the yields that you get for for the hemp
crop compared to bage which is a really
challenging crop to grow then per he per
Hector it can be really getting there in
terms of production of gla per Hector
compared to to borage if you understand
what I'm saying so so this is the range
of varieties that I've talked about I I
I I hope I've convinced you that you can
really do reverse genetics and get some
really nice interesting new traits out
of uh out of industrial hemp and there's
plenty more could be done of course you
could now use Gene editing but of course
a lot of people still don't want to be
doing Gene editing even with the
technical challenges but but also the
Regulatory and public acceptance
challenges so this is still a nice way
to go I'm still a huge advocate for Gene
editing and GMOs and I would use it
every time if I if I had a choice but
just pointing out that this route is
still very very broad public acceptance
all over the world that we've been
using so that's it uh these are the
people K has really LED this for me
Monica was the postto at the time who
was really on this project along with
these other wonderful people we've had
funding from the from Au uh and from The
Garfield Western Foundation charity and
uh and from other bits and pieces that
I've got over the years and so I think
with that I'm very happy to stop and
take questions I think I've just been
running about 40 minutes so there I'll
stop
sharing
perfect thank you Yan we have some
questions in your in our Q&amp;A okay chat
um I'm sure we are going to have couple
more coming up yeah okay so the first
question I see is do you think we can
increase the amount of oil apart from
modifying the proportions of the fatty
acids uh very good question yes uh you
know there's different ways you can
increase the the amount of oil
typically uh you know if if you if you
just consider you know the amount of oil
is yield per Hector you can you can
increase the amount of seed you can
increase the size of the
seed uh you know I think in with oil
crops that that ratio of oil to to to
protein in the seed is is is much more
fixed and and harder to do anything with
so so the increasing the amount of oil
is I I think in terms of and what we
what we're doing in fact is now looking
at you know looking at more conventional
breeding programs to to
increase uh to increase oil yield and
there are other varieties for example
that have got larger seed size than the
phola variety and and uh so there's
various ways you can go about doing that
I hope that answers that question
uh and I've got these are all Anonymous
attendees
uh can change in fatty acid composition
have negative effects on seed
germination uh
no is the is the clear answer I I've
done quite a bit on this in the past as
well uh because my when I started my lab
the first thing I worked on was seed
germination and and fatty acid
composition and during the '90s in fact
uh there was a really interesting
program that was funded by a company
called or worked on by a company called
cgen in in California and then by
Monsanto where they actually made C12
lric acid in arabidopsis and in canola
and that's a really really different
fatty acid and there were some
challenges with that in terms of using
it because basically what happens when
you germinate seeds is of course the
fatty acids are converted into sugars
and used to fuel growth uh but with all
of these fatty acids the the enzymes
involved in fatty acid beta oxidation
can cope with all of these different
fatty acids quite easily and so that
conversion to to sugar is is not
inhibited by and we don't see any impact
on of any of these on on seed
germination either uh so and danela uh
that that variety you registered where
is it been grown and how much of it is
been grown so basically I showed you
very quickly there we're really just get
it's just getting traction now and uh I
showed you that that screenshot from
that Government website in in Canada so
it grows well in Canada it grows well in
up up there in those higher latitudes
maybe uh even even further north than
Upstate New York uh so uh that that's uh
that's my bad sense of humor there
coming out uh but yeah so so it's it's
at that stage where we're really
interested I think it it's the tra I
think it's got huge potential because
this this trait of holic acid you know
it's been it's it's now been introduced
into soybean sunflow
corn uh and canola and and Industry love
it you know the food industry love the
trait because you know you can fry with
it and and and use it in food processing
I think hemp oil has got other
advantages you know it's got a really
nice nutty flavor and and it's got a
really it's really good for low impa
impact farming and you know as I say my
ambition is to is to really use this
trck to get much better adoption of
industrial hemp in in by Farmers as well
so uh yeah so I hope that answers your
question
Daniela uh is and then another anonymous
attendee is oil from this variety being
sold in the UK not yet but I hope it
will be
soon are there seed oil traits or
compositions that could be used as
proxies for domestication syndrome
across different hemp or cannabis
varieties see sorry I what what I'm I'm
now because I'm not really a plant
breeder I'm just I'm just uh pretending
I'm one well what what an earth is
domestication
syndrome can you tell me Lucia you're a
plant
reader a exam question I think it's
referring to all those uh different
trades um for example that they lose or
they shatter less or that
they okay so so all the other trats that
you need to to to facilitate
domestication
uh I don't think so because you know uh
pod chattering or or sea dropping and
and dorcy are all regulated by different
genes this these genes are really really
really specific to fatty acid
composition
uh oh gosh what would be the best fatty
acid profile for sustainable aviation
fuel that's probably yeah I won't I
won't start making any jokes about who
might be asking that question uh but uh
so okay the best fatty acid composition
for sust aviation fuel is more like C8
and C10 fatty acids so much shorter
chain fatty acids uh than than these and
and I wouldn't I really wouldn't go near
an aeroplane with uh polyunsaturated
fatty acids uh because you know the
whole aviation fuel that oxygen is her
you know and and desaturation is their
enemy so uh yeah so
uh yeah so C and and
people I think you know that I mentioned
lric acid C12 and C10 that was played
around with but and anyway they you
would you would want really really high
yielding crop to to give you to give you
aviation fuel and be competitive uh
whereas with with Industrial Hemp you're
looking at more at a higher value end of
the market than uh an aviation fuel uh
Did You observe any change in the
protein concentration uh
no uh and the and the either compos
concentration or composition uh and as I
mentioned because the fatty acid
composition of hemp protein is very
interesting as well
uh but is it commercially available not
yet we're in the process of
commercializing yeah Danielle isn't
giving up here so uh
uh you speak screening genetically
diverse germplasm for unusual oil
profiles good so so this uh Zachary is
asking about ger uh looking at germplasm
for unusual oil
profiles uh very good question uh
Zachary we we haven't done much of that
because we haven't really had access to
a
huge uh germ plasm and there to be
honest there isn't really a huge you
know diverse germ plasm of industrial
hemp varieties and you know we've looked
at a few but we haven't seen anything
come out uh that gives you a different
fatty acid composition in the scene we
haven't spotted anything in fact that
that's different if doesn't mean it's
not there uh and then the last question
from Joy Beckerman any general claims
that are made re ham seed oil the most
prevalent being that there is a perfect
ratio of omega3 to
6 how accurate is such a statement and
if one should apply a qualification to
it e generally speaking most varieties
provide a perfect ratio of Omega-3 to
six what is the most appropriate oh good
question Joy I'm no Nutri I'm not a
nutritionist and I would never I would
never uh assume that I was qualified to
step what's the ideal Omega 3 to six
composition because I think it depends
on who you're speaking to to a
significant extent all I will say is
that you know that ratio that you see in
hemp in in in traditional hemp if I if I
would call it and all of the varieties
that are out there it's pretty much
fixed with that low amount of gla and
much higher amount of
AA because you could see that GLA and
and and and stonic acid are are very low
4 5% and uh and ala is much higher so so
I I you know I
I there there are applications where
people like that ratio of Omega 6 to
omega3 but of course there is
also an industry need for for ala on its
own or GLA on its own and that's why if
I if I could go back that's why I'm
quite in that's why I'm quite excited
about the prospect of of developing a
variety which is not making
ala uh but is making significant amounts
of gla because when you take those two
oils and try and separate them in the
factory it's quite difficult to separate
ala and gla whereas if you produce a
variety which is just making GLA and and
and linolic acid then then for the
processing of that oil it's much easier
to get pure GLA out
so uh and so industry often have
requirements for that Downstream
processing that that you that that are
interesting targets as well so it's not
just the end user targets so I'm not
triv trivializing the question at all I
think there's you know it's it's a very
good question and it depends on who
you're talking to and what what
nutrition uh what nutritionist you're
talking to
okay hit increasing liene from Andrea
Herman ah yeah like I I haven't really
focused on that all I know is that what
I've read is that you know the ratio was
pretty good uh it's it's it's another
job to increase life SC
uh increasing compounds like that you
really need to upregulate biosynthesis
of them and that becomes a whole other
challenge where you really do need to do
start thinking about doing uh well you
could forward screen and see if you
could do it but upregulating genes uh by
by by Gene editing or GMO would be the
way to go if you want to increase
lysine awesome I think we got to the end
of the list the questions thank you so
much Ian for your fantastic talk and
thank you for answering all our
questions um for everyone yeah uh We've
recorded the talk we're going to upload
it to our sips YouTube channel in the
coming days thank you so much for
connecting
today and see you in two
weeks thank you byebye bye Ian have a
nice rest of your
week this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu