this is a production of Cornell
University yeah I will talk about um
tree selection and hopefully I will end
this presentation within the time
otherwise we we see
what we'll do uh I will start to try to
explain what I mean with improving or
Urban resilience when it comes to tree
selection because
today the urban habitat or the last
decades or so the urban green
infrastructure have been identified as a
very important element in order to
create the resilience to both current
happenings but also future happenings
like climate change but also new
functions we given more and more people
in urban areas and more pressure to
urban areas and the green infrastructure
have been identified as one of the most
important elements in order to meet
these changes and new demands for urban
environments uh and when you look at the
green infrastructure goes from
everything from the cut lawn to
Shrubbery to pocket Woodlands Street
trees green roof green Walls even the
pots on a balcony all these together is
recognized as a green infrastructure but
when you look at the plants which
individual plants and Plantation that
they have the the biggest impact trees
is outstanding when it comes to
delivering different kind of services
and function and we talk about this
ecosystem services that trees can be
delivering from Urban environments in
order to create resilience and so on and
this is just a compilation by Johanna in
her thesis and I just stole it it's
easier to steal stuff that's how we do I
just stole it but it shows really good
what trees and urban uh the green
infrastructure can deliver and the most
things you hear about is this regulating
ecosystem service like storm water
management
microclimate mitigation pollution relief
and so on but there are also others
function like cultural provision
supporting uh ecosystem Services as well
where trees can and have the capacity to
deliver a great share all this together
because when we come to Urban
environments today the spaces where is
allowed for a tree planting or
Plantation it get fewer and fewer so the
few places where you allowed to plant
trees this Plantation is not only to be
a good-look space to create a local
identity for the place is equally
important to serve many kind of function
so that's why tree selection is really
really crucial when it comes to create a
resilient in urban
environment however and also this that
the capacity for the trees to deliver a
function increased by space and
condition so well- growing
trees large trees of course deliver or
have the higher capacity to deliver this
function so therefore the thing we plant
here have to reach to this in order to
create this resilience and so on so what
we are doing the plant selection is
really really important and that
includes for of course site preparation
by good imp plant environment but also
the plant selection that's why we focus
on this speaks in a
way and this is actually how it looks
many times this is actually a plant uh
this is um a parking
space uh in the southern Sweden this is
it looks worse than it is actually this
is a um a space where water can go
through and it's a structural soil here
so the main idea here was that this
Plantation should mitigate the urban
heat island effect by shading the space
but also shading the cars so the dogs
and people in the cars don't die
directly it take some time but Al the
space is part of the local uh storm
water managements in order to mitigate
that as well so it is good but what the
problem is here is completely wrong
plant material they're selecting they're
selecting a suore maple a maple tree
that needs moist condition more or less
all throughout the season and even if
this is a good space the situation will
not give that so the plant selection
completely wrong here so you completely
fail and it cost a lot of money with
doing that and this is not
situation in southern Sweden you can see
it both there in Nia New York City all
over the world where plant selection is
completely wrong for site and we have to
because it cost a lot of money to
replace this and also producing trees
are going to die and so on it's just
stupid so we have to increase our
knowledge about uh plant selection so
that's one side of the cone when coin
when it comes to plant selection the
other ones is this there is a lack of
diversity within Urban areas this is a
study we did a couple years ago in
Scandinavia when we evaluated the Urban
Tree population in Denmark Finland
Norway and Sweden and this is the street
environment in Helsinki you know this
Capital Finland Oslo capital of Norway
and you can see it's just few species
that stand for the dominance and if a
disease hits one of these Oslo risk to
uh lose most uh
44.3% of the street in just over a year
maybe and then you lose the resilience
for that and it takes many many years in
order to build that up again and this is
not a
Scandinavian problem only this is an
international problem problem this is
from a study we are working on when we
try to evaluate the tree diversity in
urban areas around the world in the
Northern Hemisphere and this is Street
environment as well you see Pittsburgh
four species stand for more than half of
the population Beijing China three
species Camden which is the borrow in
central London UK four species Spain
three species stand for so this is
a a situation we have around the world
where there is a lack of
diversity and you can't say lack of
diversity in resil in the same sentence
it's not possible it's not it's not
going so what we standing in front of
the two M main challenges we standing in
front of is first increased knowledge
about untraditional or rare tree species
in order to introduce a wider diversity
of urban
trees but secondly start to understand
or start to develop knowledge about
their capacity this new UN traditional
plant materials in order to grow on
really challenging growing condition but
also their capacity to deliver different
kind of ecosystem services so these are
the two challenges we stand in front of
today and the work we are doing they
have done for many years but what we're
doing here in Corell and we probably
going to continue forever and ever
anyway so this is one I this is just an
introduction I like to talk about
so developing sight related knowledge
this is what Nina said learning from
nature because in nature trees and
plants generally have developed
different kind of traits and strategies
or even Personalities in order to
compete for resources in order to
compete for or tolerate different kind
of climates and grow condition so by
developing knowledge about which kind of
traits species have it's easy to find
their use potential also in urban
environment so this is not rocket
science pretty common sense because in
nature there is plants like this plants
that can take more or less everything
they have a lot of different kind of
superpower plants that can take a punch
or two and still be standing I have a
quote here here I really like this is
Mike Tyson everybody has a plan until
they get punched in the
face and this is really good because
this is what it's all about some have a
plan how to take this punch and still be
good-looking still be standing still be
performing well but they are plants they
don't have any sorry in the case of Mike
tyon or until they get bitten in the ear
exactly and then there are plants which
are stupid or maybe not that clever
that have developed less different and
can't take many punches even if this
person probably deserve many punches in
the face
anyway when it comes to plant selection
it's
important to start to
know how well they can take or which
kind of superpowers or personality
plants have which kind of strategies or
traits to have but also how welld
developed these different traits
are and in urban environment there is a
lot of stress factors that affect the
trees and one of the main stress factors
that trees is facing today will probably
face even more in the future climate is
lack of water so water stress is the
main Contra trees in urban
environments because the urban
environment is a more warmer climate
with a more effective e evapo
transpiration but also you have a very
effective water Runner all these hard
surfaces but also the space for many
trees especially below ground is limited
because of space of pipes and other
things in this
multifunctional place as Urban
environments represent today so what
we're focusing is drought stress for
trees and see what kind of superpowers
they have in order to deal with what uh
and this is um a compilation by our
colleagues Andrew irons from my school
college that did this for a couple years
back where he tried to put
together how trees dealing with water
stress and you can see that you can
divide them in two groups avoiding water
stress and then second is just take the
water stress and tolerate it and I will
start with avoidance the tree how how
trees can avoid um water stress and then
you can have two subcategories like
maximizing water this is a hard word for
me acquisation is that good acquisition
yeah can you say it acquisition there
you go I can't say
it and that's of course that's the main
thing is to invest in a root system that
can support a tree with water that's the
main avoiding strategy that most of the
plants do some are better some are
weaker but then we have this one reduce
water use or would reduce water
loss by for example stoo tomato closure
reduce leaf and stem growths um they're
investing in pession of leaf thicker
Cula but also this one which is less
attractive so to say just throwing the
leaves this is a a picture from a close
to our summerhouse in southern Sweden in
a place where you have a thin soil layer
we have rocks and just half a meter soil
after a couple of weeks really warm and
dry weather the root system can't
support the tree with water anymore and
some trees don't have any second plan of
Plan B they just just rely on tree roots
when the tree roots fail they have no
idea how to deal with the situation so
they go into panic and you can see
what's happening just throwing the
leaves in order to reduce the water loss
a very effective way you can see are
many species this is the
burges Betula pendula in Sweden but you
can also see it like this this is from
the plantation here at Cornell even if
you have a structure soil here which is
better than normal it's better than it
look like these trees this is from
August uh four years
ago when they're panicking they they
just have no idea what to do the root
say the root calls the tree Crown we
have we don't have any water down here
so they go into panic and don't want to
lose anything and throw the leaves you
can compare to the trees here plant at
the same time and they have more or less
an unlimited rooting space and they
still and doing well so this is an
example of avoidance strategy avoiding
when it comes to rules but there's other
example of avoidance strategies for
example this I think I showed you this
last year when I have to speak this is a
silver lime silver Linden all these
American names of tree I'm very sorry
about that Tia tomosa this is a picture
from mavia Republic of mavia but they
they also invest in a root system of
course in order to avoid but they also
invested other tools for for example
pesan leaves and they invest in a
special pesan or hair type which is this
Star Hair which is like small micro
umbrellas which cover the can you say
underside of leaf or is that okay thank
you UND side sorry about it underside of
the leaf which reduce the loss of water
so that that's another avoidance
strategies the silver Lindon use and the
silver have another level of avoidance
strategy this is an interesting Forest
just on the border between Romania and
Republic of um of um mavia you have to
bring your passport when you go into
this Forest because you never know which
country you're going to end in i I've
done that mistake a couple of times but
here you can say the silver Lindon in
the Oak Forest and this is a very warm
warm and dry day and you can see also in
the plantation here that a warm day the
silver Linden is more silver compared to
a moist and cool day because on a warm
day they turn the leaf upside to the sky
and by doing there that theyed they they
reflect away some of the sunlight which
makes the leaf doesn't heat up in the
same amount as normal and if the leaf
doesn't warm up that much they don't
have to use a lot of water to cool down
the leaf there's a very clever way to in
a warm day reduce water loss by
reflecting away the sunlight and doesn't
get that up heated so to say so that's
that's
a
um that's some example of avoiding
strategy trees have in order so by
that's what part of the research we're
doing try to identify all these types of
strategies avoidance strategy trees have
and also try to understand how good they
are root system of course is good but
when the root system or in the soil
dries up what kind of other plans do you
have in order to step up and take the
drought so to say
but the thing is same picture again same
situation very dry but there are trees
that have the same lack of water in the
soil the root system failed to support
the tree but the tree doing well
anyway so this is an interesting
strategy we are looking at we have been
looking a little bit extra to this
tolerance that's taking the punch so to
say and still be standing well and
looking good to take the drought in in
order to avoid it so to
say because when it comes to tolerance
of water uh uh water or limited water
availability there are several different
kind of strategy that trees have
developed osmotic adjustment for example
elastic adjustment but also low low
turgo loss point which have been a
special interest for us because that if
you have a very low turgo loss point you
have the potential to just shut up just
to stand there take the punches and wait
out the drought and then when the rain
weather comes it
just goes on business as usual so that's
the interesting to see how much you can
shut up and how long you can do it so
that's why three three years ago we
started a project together which is a
collaboration between the Swedish
Agriculture University Cornell with Nina
but also with mycope college in UK with
Dr Andrew irons
and we call the project shut the hell up
or die which actually what it's all
about try
to see how much a tree can or why they
can standing there and just shut the
hell up but also see how long you can
take it how long how many punches you
can take because that's important to see
in situation where you need to have
trees that can standing and taking the
punch of the punch and still looking
good and deliver different so low turgo
loss points we thought that was
interesting to look at and tuross point
can be used as a universal measure of
physiological drought tolerance that is
quantifi and
measurable and this is very attractive
for me rank species in terms of their
physiological drought tolerance because
today when you rev your literature he
stand it's tolerant for Drought yeah but
how much drought that's the problem we
can't say this is better than other ones
and that's very attractive that if it's
possible to rank Spees actually give a
number to actually say this is drought T
this much and this is actually this much
then it's easier to pinpoint which
species that can be used on that site
because in that site you have to take
the drought this much and so on but the
problem before is that taking uh to
measuring the turgo loss point is a very
complicated time
um sorry consuming time consuming thank
thank
you can you read
mines it's good time consuming work
which means that maybe for a year you
work with four or five species and you
can take the tuross point for them and
that's it but when it comes to diversity
we have to look at a large share of
species to in order to see the potential
of which one can be introduced or uh to
for nurseries or Landscape Architects
tree planners and so on but the last
three years or four years ago a group in
in China together with people in
California come up with that there is a
close relationship between osmotic
adjustment and turgo loss point and that
makes it possible in a much easier way
to to develop or to take out the turgo L
point we can use um another methology
but also it's possible uh with new
techniques to use it more easy that
makes it possible to take tur to to
create turgo loss point in a much easier
way and faster way so last year we spent
more or less a whole year to just
adjusting this uh methology testing back
and forward because the the work that
had been done before have been developed
for subtropical tropical and
Mediterranean plant species and we are
not there we are working in temperate
zone so that's why we're testing back
and forward so the result last year have
been actually published or accepted for
publication so it's going to be
published anytime here and we was
looking at Maples 27 different species
and genotype of Maples um we tested last
year when it comes to turgo loss points
and this is what's I thought it was
interesting to actually do some kind of
ranking but also you can see because the
more negative pressure you can take the
longer you can shut up longer you can
take the drought after the root system
all this avoid
strategies fail then you can take a
longer drought before because turgo loss
point if if I should explain it is that
when the root system fail to um deliver
water you go into a wilting uh position
so the cell structuring leaves just
shrinking and they can shrink to a
special level and then it just implodes
and then the cell structure just gone
the in M the trees have done for that
Lea everything is gone they can't
produce any photo or any photosynthesis
anymore but this level before the cell
structure just implode and destroyed
different between different species so
some species can take just three or four
days of drought and then the cell
structure just goes out but some they
have a very strong cell walls and so on
so they can take a long cells uh very
what say very low negative pressure
without get damaged
so this is what it is so these species
down here with a long can take their
cell structure can take a long drought
and a very high negative pressure and by
doing that they can take the drought and
still have an active photosynthesis and
and still can capture resources and
invest in Roots and shots and and things
for next year and that's a very positive
thing but this spe it up in the top
there can take it very short and then
the leaf structure destroy
is that you understand
or pretty clear okay the interesting
here that there is a difference between
the season you can see in the spring
some of the species that are very very
strong in the summer are weak in in the
spring that's interesting when it comes
to climate change when we get have
drought in different parts of the Season
that we even thought
before but I would go through and show
it so what it means more practically is
that the trees or the species or the
genotypes that belongs to the group up
there which have a very low negative
uh pressure on the cell structure these
are the species that rely very much on
the root system avoiding strategies so
they should never ever be planted
outside very generous parking Vines
where they're unlimited resources for
the roots but also have a good water
holding capacity in a
soil but when you look at the trees
where they grow naturally it makes sense
because Asus patum which was the weakest
one in this test this is the place where
you can find it along streams as an
understory species in moist woodlands
and that's the case also for as
pensylvanicum I have no idea what this
species calls in English I just stick to
the the scientific names this is from
the tree man state park outside
Etha but also Asun cartum or mono
whatever you want to call it this is
from the tingling mountain in China
what I did my PhD work a lot of field
work but here you can see it as an
understory tree inside a protected moist
Forest
environment so it makes sense the trees
that have a low turg loss point they
grow naturally in sides but it's a good
guidance also for tree plan is landscape
archit that these trees don't have the
equipment to grow in Street environments
where you have period with really severe
droughts they should always be a garden
or Park tree that that's
it but then I had the other group here
these are the guys that can take drought
for a longer time they can be planted in
more challenging growing condition
condition like this in a courtyard where
deep
rooting
uh strategy is not that clever because
you can't force the root system through
the office here through the parking lots
and so on it's not possible so trees
here have to have a b b c and a d plan
to take this and these guys
have the potential to be growing here be
growing well looking good delivering all
these ecosystem Services they wanted in
there even if the condition is really
really challenging and the same thing
when you look at where they grow in
natur in nature you can find them
growing really challenging growing
situation this is AC gred in Tatum from
Utah in s national park and if you have
to grow here you have to have strategies
more than just the root system on that
you have to have you have to step up and
take
that and this is from the step forest of
Eastern Europe as tataricum together
with quercus pans because if you should
grow here on the steps of Eastern Europe
you have to have a tolerance to take
weeks of drought really severe drought
and every time I have anina in an
audience I have to show this picture
because everybody who takes Nina's
classes she they know that AO Tor we
named as on a
stick because Nina doesn't like this
tree so that's why I just showing her
how goodlooking tree it is this is from
Lun Sweden on a courtyard with a parking
deck
Below have you seen enough
Nina yeah I give her few
seconds but also in the same study you
can show that it shows that also within
the same species there is a significant
difference between different genotypes
and this is interesting when it comes to
selection that within
species you can find both sensitive but
also really really tolerant genotype or
genetic or ecotype within the species
this is about red maple three different
kind of genotype but
also it's really attractive when my new
job when I have to travel around the
world to collect species that this
mythology makes it possible to screen in
an early stage the potential of the
species so if we are hunting for Drought
tolerance tree species or species for a
or genotyp for a future climate we can
use this technology or the methology we
develop in order to screen in early we
don't have to wait three generation of
gardeners before we know it's tolerant
or is weak we can do a really early
screening so this is the work we did
last year so this year we went all in to
screen as many species that we could in
order to
see especially among the untraditional
so this is the work from this
year and I will go through them
all no I won't but this is what's
happening when you get carried away in
your research you feel like an alcoholic
one more glass this is like one more
species just one more day and this is
the result here so this is about 140
species of genotype we're testing this
year in order to see but then you can
see the significance difference between
species and genotype when it comes to Dr
tolerance and the main work is in not
only to to create this data set but also
testing untraditional or rare tree
species because we have to we can't just
go to conference and say that everybody
are idiots the nursery industry or the
landscape architect industry we have to
give them some kind of guidance or
confidence in order to shift from a
traditional plant material to testing
new plants and new species and so on and
by this research is possible to actually
show them that for example a
comais I think it's Chinese rubber tree
that's the English name I look it up
sorry Hardy rubber Hardy no
okay I was wrong there anyway rubber
tree and you can see you can show them
that the most common tree for example in
in Sweden is Tila Kata and you can show
that this is fully hard in Sweden but
much much more tolerant for dry
conditions so should be better in urban
streets environments compared to til
Kata which when it comes to more to dry
condition they have all these things
going on and honey and so on but the
same thing is important to
identify the trees that belongs up there
because in Sweden any a way the
landscape architect really really like
Magnolia Cobalts this a new trendy trees
they they want it
everywhere and they also start to force
them into Street
environments but the result they look
like crap because they just have wilting
Leaf in July no flowering die off in the
tree Crown Z so it's really important
also that show that manula cobos is and
will be an exclusive Park tree or garden
tree should never be forced and through
this research it's possible to have that
kind of communication that they don't
have that they don't have they can't
take many punches they just they take
one and then
down so it's equally important to
identify the tough ones but also the
weak ones in the communication when it
comes to um diversification of urban
environments so
on and and through this data set I just
narrow it down a little bit to go
through some plants or some groups that
this is the Oaks we done 22 different
genotypes of Oaks we testing so you can
see it's a huge uh differences between
them also within the season bear in mind
that this Axel is changing a little bit
in number so it's but also this work
this is from Birches this is made not
here in E Cornell this is made in NES
Garden which is the botanic garden in
Liverpool UK by Andrew
irons because um the man director there
is um just wrote an a monograph on
Birches so he wanted us to come there
next year we have been invited to queue
Garden in London to do a screening of
their trees there because they want to
know the future potential of the tree
stock they have at uh at the botanic
garden and so on so the word start to
spread there so so I hope all next year
we can present some really interesting
data when it comes to Red trees from
Botanic Gardens but also we try some
shrub species me and Nina you can also
see this is a ground covering shrubs we
just started with and play a little bit
with but then you can see also that
there is a big difference between
species and and and cultiv but also when
it comes to use potential where the
potential
is so this is what was my goal when we
started this because I will I will try
to explain this pretty boring I know but
I try to try to explain it n and
valadares uh presented a paper 2006 by
ranking drought tolerance for 800 wooded
species shrubs and trees by reviewing
where and how they grow in the
wild but this is once again just
assumptions like oh between three and
four so it should be a little bit
drought tolerance but what we can show
we put our data based on their ranking
and you can see there is a relationship
really close relationship in our data
with them but what we can do we can
actually show not only like between
three or four should be there we can
actually show a number this is how it is
but also interesting that some of our
most drought tolerant species for
example seringa reticulata what's the
name of that Japanese
ler There You
Go Japanese treer uh which Dr tolerant
but when you base things on rev or
review literature you can read about the
species where it grows in southeast
Siberia when it grows in cool and moist
sites but when you go to to the
mountains in China he grows together
with alantis a colia one of the most
drought tolerant species on very very
Rocky and dry sites but they that book
they didn't read so that's why they put
them in as a not that drought
tolerant so that that's the when you're
reviewing ecological literature together
to with the research we
doing so as I said we are in a start we
start to develop this database hopefully
next year we can add 100 to the list and
so on and work it on and we have a lot
of side projects which is interesting
where you can see that if uh if you
stress a tree they can step it up and
actually increase the turgo loss points
and so so also important to see the
window how much they can take not only
when they're growing in plant Park
environment but also when you stress
them and see how much they can step up
some species doesn't have that uh
capacity some species have a very wide
capacity so bear in mind this is just a
starting it but I I think it's really
interesting and the most of all is
really interesting or very useful in
order to communicate with tree users the
plant user plant
designers how much time do I have
left okay then I would like to show
another perspective that we work with as
well because when it comes to plant
selection many things that trees right
tree for right sight but I would like to
add another aspect of that right tree
for right sight and functions because
when it comes to Urban Tree or Urban
Forest today everybody's talking about
tree increase the Urban Tree canopy and
so on if we increase with uh 10% we will
gain this and if we
a add another 10% we will gain that
that's not possible I don't I I can't
buy that I'm sorry because it's
different between trees and trees
because when it comes to a landscape
architect and I'm one of the most hated
teachers in my University because I'm
the guy that shows up in the
presentation and just ask them why why
this green blob there what is it and
what should it do
there I don't know it's a street we
plant trees along the street and then I
fail them they have to come back they
have to every dot they have to have an
idea why and which tree should be there
because when it comes to buying a car
we don't go in and say I just want to
buy a car we don't do that because when
we buy a
car we have a lot of ideas what we want
for the car what kind of car how should
I look in the car and so on what kind of
stereo what kind of all this bling bling
but if you don't do that if you just go
in there and say I want a car you can
end up with this one but that is good
that's a lottery but at the same time
you can end up with this
one both is a are but the capacity
between them is
different but this is what we're doing
when it comes to tree selection for
ecosystem services or trees are good for
pollution reducing pollution or
mitigating Urban heat island so that's
why we plant tree without thinking of
where to place them and which beaches to
use and that's very very frustrating
because it's much more because this tree
is not a tree sometimes goes well this
is two good example this is from
Stockholm this is from Manchester in UK
when the tree selection have been really
good probably it's just luck but
sometimes they're using species that
doing a good job there taking the wind
or shading the situation where it's
needed but sometimes it's sometimes you
can actually can plant tree and make
more problems rather than actually
benefits for the
tree and I would like to show this is
research I'm just part of so Johanna
braise your hand is the main
uh person behind this research I'm the
plant geek I'm in the end just adding
some trees and so on but I I would like
to just show this this is a um a program
a climate uh modeling program where it's
possible to to see the effect of urban
green infrastructure and how we can uh
adjust the microclimate in an in a
building area it's like Minecraft from
grown-ups you're building up uh um what
hit the
quer neighbor a neighborhood um in a 3D
um way this is the houses and then you
add numbers of the houses if a concrete
house is a wooded house how tall they
are uh what kind of roof it is uh if you
have climbing plants and on the and also
which kind of glasses and so on but also
it's not only taking the the the buildup
uh environment but also the outdoor
environment
what kind of surface is it is it
concrete graveled grass uh is a shrub
Plantation is a tree how tall the trees
on which kind of level and so on and
then you build this up it's called MV
met and then you can download it for
free on internet and then you add local
climate data and then you press the
button and take a weekend or 10 days or
so and then you come back and this have
been uh harvesting for a long time but
the problem in the beginning was that
that the plant data is not available so
the work we have done for three or four
or five years
yeah yeah
yes so we have been collecting this Leaf
area index data for I think it's about
75 or 80 trees pieces U and then we add
these values in and this is what can
have and then you can ask different kind
of question it's also for pollution but
also for wind speed from microclimate
and so on so then you can get a good
pictures it's not only you here in the
USA that have stupid politics like
Donald Trump and so on also in Sweden we
have pretty slow minded people that are
politic politic but this is a a model
where it's possible to to show or to to
communicate the effect of green
infrastructure within building areas I I
will show you when it comes to wind
speed this is the housing area with no
trees whatsoever this is the ocean here
there's a lot of wind comes in so you
can see there's a really window
especially in this passage when you when
you force the wind in and here here you
have more or less storm every day and
it's really good when you do this study
to ask uh dog people because people with
dogs need to go out every day even if
it's snow storm or raining so they know
you can ask them where's the worst spot
and then can actually give the exact
same what this modeling program do but
this is um the effect if you add due to
the master plan with a fancy landscape
architect company in Stockholm did I
don't think they even wear here to look
at the the site so they they did more a
traditional way of placing the green
infrastructure trees here group of
Plantation here and so on so you can see
that they reduce the wind something but
what we deal after that is to
placed just to change some of the
species to other species but also place
them in other in other s so to say in
order to gain most
effect and this is one
proposal and this is the one so by using
this program and also adding you can
show that species
selection not only placing the species
but also which kind of species we're
using
matters I think it's
cool and this is on the summer but when
it comes to Winter you have the bronch
Shir index because we have long Winters
in Sweden we need to care about how the
trees are acting in the
winters because in this in the winter we
don't want any any tree not close to
buildings because the Sun that hits the
buildings in in winter time warms up as
much as we can reduce 30% of the heating
cost that's a lot of money we can use by
just using the sun energy just hitting
their their facad in the winter time so
by placing Trees Too Close in a winter
time with too dense canopy can cool down
and actually increase the heating costs
in a winter time then we have a negative
ecosystem Services actually that's bad
so by placing trees just increasing tree
canopy without actually thinking about
where and how to place them we can
actually cause
problem so this is what we want we want
trees that have a dense canopy
summertimes with a lot of leaf High Leaf
area index that cool down facades and
building or even if a we have a square
where we have Tor
handle markets so so on on the Square in
the summer time we want to have shade
but in the winter we want to have a lot
of sun so what we look at is trees that
are dense in the summer but sparse in
the in the winter and let a lot of
sunlight through the tree
canopy so we did a research of
evaluating different tree species when
it comes to Branch ARA index
and this is Gino Boba which is more like
a joke when it comes to shading
wintertime because it doesn't have
anything more or less but then we have
this this is a carpinus betus fata which
is a horn beam upright which is very
very
dense so this can shade a lot but at the
same time the Ginko can't reduce any
winds in a winter time because winds is
another Shilling Factor so you don't
want to maybe have Trees close to the
buildings but a little bit farther away
to reduce winds so Geno doesn't do
anything while the hornbeam do a great
job for that and then we have something
in between this is Atlantis so we did an
evaluation about um 55 or 60 species or
genotypes of trees about 30 35 years old
planted the same time planting the same
site and so on so was evaluating so you
can see that when it comes to Branch
area index that's the density of tree
crowns in the winter you have gko this
is from Stockholm a new Ginko
Plantation but one of the most dense is
the upright corinos or the horn
beam so what we did we are playing
around with this Envy met again and then
we place this is a courtyard this is a
buildings the wind comes main the main
wind comes from the West here and then
we placed a tree free row it look like
it's a hedge but it's not because in the
program when if the canopy touches each
other then it's it's looks like a hedge
but it's not it's just a traditional Tre
row but what we did is using the data or
the the the values we collected from
this uh the data the field the brch a
index data and add it into the program
to see how much they can reduce the
wind which is a very important ecosystem
service when it comes to Sweden anyway
because we don't we don't have that warm
Summers but we have cold Winters so
reducing the wind and a cold temperature
winter time is more important in order
to to reduce energy cost but also a
really good outdoor environment so we go
through this is Gino
Boba this is Noel Maple Emerald Queen
Hony long hyong Locust or it's turkey
Oak coros
Kona fat hornbeam and last uh upright
type of uh of of Western Pine but then
you can
see so we have to care which trees we're
placing where because there is different
capacity within between species and even
between genotype within the same species
so we can't just say that if we increase
the tree canopy with 10 or 50% we will
gain that
and this and so on we have to be more
precise we have to force ourself in the
planning of the green infrastructure to
talk about detail to talk about plant
selection but also the spacing where to
put them and so on and this is really
clear uh uh research that really show
and this is this paper is out it's um uh
published early this year so if you want
some copy of this paper please let me
know I will send it to you
so to summarize this uh presentation is
that I would like to launch the
statement that the cool people the most
important people the new superheroes in
the future will be the plant Geeks
because the plant Geeks are the people
that knows all
these stupid facts about plants but
these stupid facts all these details are
important in order to to uh build
or construct
res resilient Urban
environments so that's it thank you very
much for
listening looking at the graph that you
showed with the drug
tolerance uh for spring and then for
summer yeah you're concentrating on the
summer data and more or less ignoring
the the spring data no I it maybe in my
talk here but in in the we we we care
about the the spring de is equal because
it's interesting
that the weak ones so to say they have
more or less the same values in the
spring as in the summer they don't
change that much they go out weak and
stay weak but interesting that the most
drought tolerance uh species in in the
summer some of them are really really
weak in the spring for example the
Golden Rain Tree
colia in it's one of the weakest in the
spring but in the summer it's maybe
number one number two in our data so far
it's really really strong and that's
also important when we transplant the
trees are establish the trees they are
very weak in the beginning so we have to
focus even if it's drout to when it's
established it could be really fragile
in in establishment phase especially in
the spring phase that we have to be
really careful to walking the PS so but
is what's happening then uh with this
adjustment from the spring to the summer
that you're having osmotic adjustment by
the by the tree because you've got a
series of small stresses during that
period which adapts it to the drer
condition exactly so that's also the
next step we actually we have some
spinoff studies going going on beside
this doing trying to compile this big
data set that we have trees that grows
for example in the plantation we have
unlimited the same species or even same
downtown with more restricting pl we
have been actually um done some root
penetrating rers we know exactly how
much space they have but then you can
see that the trees in the plantation of
course because if I have unlimited why
invest that much because everything's
good here the downtown they invest very
very much much much higher but
interesting in this St is that the Coria
uh the gold R Tree have the same high
levels even in a plantation as downtown
so they just invest in very high or very
low tural loss Point even if they are
standing in unlimited rooting space they
just programm to be really strong from
the beginning they don't have any other
thoughts but for example cusia which is
other spe in the same study have this
huge adjustments between planting
Plantation with unlimited space compared
to for example the library downtown is
very limited
they have maybe half or double its turbo
loss point you can take it more because
they have adjustable the side so what we
see there there is among some species
some species just have a burden St from
the very beginning what we can see that
there's a lot of things we have to
continue look at but what's interesting
is to to developing knowledge about the
window how much you can take or the the
adjustment That's The Next Step In This
research to try to understand which
beaches had a very narrow window for
example City It Go or as goes out
weak stay weak and doesn't have any
adjustment but then you have some other
species like perusia we have a way Wide
Window of adjustment so that's the next
phas to try to create these window to
see how wide they are and how narrow
they are so but we are working on
er uh along those same lines if you look
at a moisture release curve for a soil a
Sandy lone soil the volumetric water
content at a water potential of -4 megap
pascals for example is vanishingly small
not a whole lot of water even left there
might be interesting to look at the
duration of drought
in reference to something like potential
evapo transpiration to see so to speak
to use a different metaphor how long the
plant was going to have to hold its
breath if you're investing a lot of
energy in making neutral osmotica for
osmotic adjustment and you're going to
get another 6 hours worth of ability to
extract water that might be a less
prudent kind of adjustment investment
yeah definitely I I I totally agree the
think we through this methology we we is
a we come up with new spin-off and try
to relate it here try to relate it there
and so on so it's yeah I totally agree
we could we should look at that as well
so it's we are in the very beginning of
this this work so by creating this data
set and next year we're going to compare
to we're going to work a three place at
Q got the wordon god also here in
Cornell so we while we create in this
data database it's more it's greater
chance to stop and play with it starty
to to to see see the same thing but from
different angles and S play I'm totally
agree with you okay I think we're out of
time I I would like to end by say thank
you for having me here for almost two
years and I would like to thanks Nina of
course to taking so good care of me here
both in Corel but also outside the world
here by helping me to get a credit card
American credit card no
idea social security number
impossible to beat up some people but Al
also the people in at the department I
really enjoy to be here and we have some
as you probably understand we have a lot
of things going on and I will come back
here but I want to thank you for this
time I really enjoy it and I was really
inspiring to be here so thank you very
much thank you
[Applause]
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu