our speaker today is Bob schindelbeck
he's an extension associate in the
department of crop and soil science at
Cornell University with responsibilities
in research teaching and extension Bob
coordinates the Cornell soil Health
laboratory operations and has been part
of the Cornell soil Health team's
development of soil management
strategies to address laboratory
measured soil constraints he's produced
a number of uh peer-reviewed and
extension articles and has delivered
over 200 presentations related to
tillage soil compaction and soil quality
at Farmer Twilight meetings and
professional conferences Bob's going to
talk to us today about soil health
management with that Bob I'm going to
turn the program over to you thank you
Jeff I hope everyone can hear me okay um
right so two weeks ago I kind of
introduced the uh Cornell soil Health
test uh in a presentation called
applying the Cornell soil Health test to
Berry production and I'm going to build
on that today uh the title of today's
presentation is understanding the soil
biological and physical properties with
a special emphasis on the
management so
move forward
here so when we talk about um any sort
of soil management we find it very
useful to break the soil into if you
will these great groups the physical
biological and chemical properties uh
the reason for that is that soil ecology
itself is exceedingly complex and uh
full of uh so much so much interaction
that our only chance is to use the
reduction reductionist approach of
Science and kind of understand the the
little bits um and at the same time
realize we're going to have to put those
little bits back together into the the
whole ecological package uh so that's
kind of the strategy uh that we use uh
for understanding the soil itself as
scientists then we we take that sort of
knowledge and strategy and then manage
the soil to uh the manage these
different properties of the soil then to
get the sort of interactions moving in
the direction we want so the uh the
power of management or wise management
is understanding what's what's beneath
it so uh we kind of model that strategy
with this uh with the approach I'm going
to go through
here so um just kind of visit in a
nutshell here our our philosophy really
is that this that a healthy soil uh is
balanced between the um the blue disc
the yellow disc and the green disc you
see on the right uh we see that as a
three-legged stool of these different
soil properties that we want to
understand what's going on in each of
these Realms such that our stool is
balanced and um not weak at one place or
another and so what we talked about last
week was measuring different indicators
in these different uh soil Arenas uh to
find out if we have any limitations then
we take that same understanding of
perhaps impaired processes if they do
exist and we when we manage the soil we
can address those ideally several at a
time and I've produced a caveat down
here at the bottom of this slide which
kind of gets at really the underpinnings
of all this um a person would say why
would you want to increase your soil
Health well certainly it's at the very
um end of things has to be uh money
increased profitability we want to be uh
more successful with our with our
management and so again part one would
be to identify these soil limitations
and then when we can understand it and
see just what's going on it gives us a
chance to uh create opportunities what I
call for synergistic management we know
there's a lot of work to do out there
and we want to make sure that all our
all our steps uh all our all our
practices are addressing if if necessary
several issues at once that need uh
addressing so we saw uh this sort of
strategy last week the the main goals um
Now using this uh Cornell soil Health
test which you see on the right of the
slide uh as we want to understand uh
these different processes going on in
the soil and just just how just how our
soils uh kind of doing uh seeing what
these where these levels are at find out
where where we need really need to focus
our attention but then part two is where
we'll spend our time today or a lot of
our time uh thinking how can we then uh
velop management strategies uh that are
holistic that consider all these things
simultaneously to restore our soil
function and you'll notice we have the
uh the cornal soil test report field
management sheet at the bottom left and
you see some folks uh in a classroom
setting where we actually go through and
we we practice this uh where we take a a
soil Health Report like you see in the
upper right um and kind of break it down
into four steps and kind of tease out as
much information as we can on this part
one so that we can develop uh again a
sound manage sound and satisfying uh
management strategy uh if you note the
um so Health Report you see in the upper
right um what we have here is a a a
grower who had Ry vetch three years ago
on a field and then two years of
strawberries it's a Sandy LOM soil and
you can see that there's some a couple
of uh where you see these red scores um
we've outlined some soil Health uh
constraints some soil processes that
that aren't aren't quite up to snu that
we could address to their management and
we'll come back to this uh at the end of
the end of the talk uh and actually
tease this apart and use this um this
four-step strategy to kind of dissect
this and uh I'll just give a an example
uh dissection of the information and a a
movement forward through uh through the
four steps to a um proposed management
strategy okay so let me begin uh we're
going to talk about a lot about organic
matter today so this is a very useful
slide to kind of put things um into our
our perspective of how we're of how we
think about organic matter so I guess
this probably all makes sense to us by
now uh if you're interested in in soil
processes but as we feed the soil this
organic matter we affect a lot of
different processes and I'm outlined
here in in blue soil physical processes
that are directly affected by uh organic
matter U modific additions and
Transformations as well as in green some
soy biological processes that are
directly affected by organic matter and
of course these are in fact processes
that we test in the soil Health uh
analysis uh each one of these has a um
has an analysis that gets gets right at
uh These Nuts and Bolts of uh soil
function but at the same time now we
need to think also as managers so when
we say add organic matter and all these
processes that are affected well
certainly different organic matter could
affect some of these processes more than
other organic matter be the character of
the organic matter the age of it do we
stir it in uh do we apply it to the
surface do we grow it in as a uh green
manure Etc so that's uh that's where we
where we'll go today um again it's a uh
it it asks for really
uh holding these processes in your mind
uh that are going on in the soil
simultaneous with uh the idea of
managing them with um very outside the
soil
um actions by a
grower okay so uh to step back a little
bit um the there's some actors in This
soil food web uh uh starting with
organic matter on the far left we've got
uh living roots and CHS which they are
organic they're not dead organic matter
but they're living organic matter and
below that we see dead substrate so
we've got the the source of all our uh
soil um biological processes really is
is the plant um and so we we um want to
keep in mind that these are quite
variable we have different plants that
we can use in our management uh
different substrates that we can apply
so when we we look at this table we see
that uh from the blue circle the living
uh living material we're going to affect
certain living bacteria and fungi and
nematodes in the soil and same at the
bottom the dead substrate can affect
this uh this next box this Nev next
hierarchy of um
organisms but right the fact that we can
affect and promote certain of these uh
organisms or um actually restrict them
based on our choice of organic matter
forces us then as managers to to be
aware of of all the um all the influence
we can have by modifying what we see at
the far left the living and dead
substrates so to kind of put that in
text here U all organic matter is not
created equal I'll use this title on
another slide later in the talk to kind
of bring this uh together uh once again
but um when we when we're dealing with
fresh material uh this this could be
additions like grass clippings or leaves
as well as uh growing uh cover crops the
crop itself uh GRE if you will green
manure um these these uh compounds are
very young and fresh and wet uh when
organisms attack this and when these
products break down we get a lot of
these um glues if you will that uh help
bind the soil together we talked about
this with soil aggregate uh creation
very important W even earthworms as they
pull this material into the soil the the
goo and glue on the earthworm itself
helps hold soil particles together this
is really an early function of organic
matter as it goes through its uh through
its uh cycles of
breakdown this fresh material really
favors what I call bacterial
populations um they really take off on
this this carbon energy um and we've
seen of course uh nitrogen
immobilization um and where nitrogen is
made unavailable to plants because the
competition by these bacteria is so
great for the nitrogen that the plants
can can be uh plants can suffer so this
is just a um one of the properties of of
fresh material um on the other hand
composts and here I mean uh kind of an
extreme sense compost uh uh everything
from um p build up leaves uh bio salads
isas biochar um Municipal stockpiles
these sort of
long-term um you know produced composts
that could be trucked and brought in um
what we see here are typically more
stable composts than more stable
material than the fresh material and
what's happened is the um the comp this
composting has taken place in a pile
when we add the fresh material in
contrast the composting is so to speak
is taking place out in the field in situ
right in the right in all these little
micr places in the field when we produce
a compost of course a lot of those these
early um uh processes nitrogen
immobilization for example is taking
place in the pile which of course we can
manage uh to produce a a a net uh final
product compost but the idea is we're
we're producing something where these
these early processes have already taken
place
um so these then these uh uh the
products that we put on the the added
compost then is more stable which is
what we get ultimately from the the
breakdown of the fresh material that
ultimately becomes more stable but here
we're we're kind of short circuiting
that by making by doing it in a
pile but also uh the last sentence here
under composts uh we can also
concentrate uh nitrogen and phosphate um
in the compost and come up with actually
a quite Rich material so we have to be
aware of that as
well okay so U we see that these
biological processes then uh that we see
in the soil are going to be affected by
the uh the type of organic matter so how
much fuel uh this living fresh material
uh is in is in the um the source organic
matter and how much is already in a
stable or passive condition which um
isn't
necessarily uh food for organisms and uh
it's it's more of a inert loosening
compound and of course in our soil we
have existing soil organisms that we can
that will be affected by this material
that we add uh that we give to them in
our management and of course we can
affect that and the way we affect that
is uh with management is what we'll be
talking about but this they these these
two um these two actors here um interact
through moisture temperature how we mix
them together or for example tillage um
the fertility level particularly
nitrogen um can affect how fast these
things turn over Etc so let's get right
to that so here it is in a nutshell
different plants and plant debris
composition is going to affect our soil
biology and this is where we need to do
a lot of thinking and learning um about
new new varieties um new uh for example
in the cover crap Arena what I wanted to
say is that um I'm sure you're all aware
now of these crucifers these mustards uh
that can have um compounds associated
with them that we can use to our
advantage to control organisms in the
soil we've seen that um any number of
times now in potatoes even in
strawberries um that we can kind of
manage our and and choose a cover crop
then that has a has a byproduct of its
breakdown that can affect affect the
soil biology so that that's a um kind of
an example of how we can um
modify the biotic Community to suppress
a
disease but at the same time when we U
build the soil with a cover crop we're
also keeping in mind that we're making a
by making a healthier plant we can
sometimes simply outgrow um a
lowlevel a low level of uh disease
organisms in the
soil and the way this is done is that
the plant itself um can produce
defensive compounds uh that stress pests
or the plants can enhance beneficial
organisms so it's not just what we do
the plant itself is um is acting to um
protect itself and I'd like to go
through that a little here so the
uh I think we all know that the plant
root root modifies the rise of spere
environment so the way I like to think
about it is um not unlike a a tree uh
growing out in a uh in a field that as
it pulls nutrients out of the ground it
grows leaves and then drops those leaves
ultimately onto that same soil so it's
in a it the plant in fact does very
overtly modify its environment uh its
soil environment by pulling nutrients
out turning them into leaves dropping
the leaves as those leaves break down
compounds are released that help the
plant
in the photo at the bottom left in fact
some estimates are suggest that even um
even up to 50% of plant uh photosynthate
uh is used in um underground to not only
grow roots and uh the the dry matter of
the roots but that the root is actually
giving these cells if you will uh this
energy to the environment in the risos
spere just like it's giving leaves um in
the fall to the soil above ground so the
root tip loses some of these cells these
uh epithelial cells as it moves through
the soil and then as these cells die
they they break open and release release
their contents into the risos spere
these cells can become food directly or
they can simply dissolve uh nutrients in
the rizosphere zone um and make them
available to the succeeding cells living
cells in the root tip these cells can
release compounds that um are
antagonistic to disease organisms in the
vicinity um this is a very direct effect
but the these um these cells and and the
plant is really working again in its own
in its own best
interest and the reason for this is is
that the um this root tip is kind of the
pilot uh going through the going through
the soil um it doesn't take up much
water or nutrients where that happens is
further up the root so where I show the
root section and the root hair on the
top part of the slide I'm actually
suggesting that we kind of put this all
together into one picture and imagine
that behind the root tip then as the
root tip's passing into the soil the
section behind that uh is where the
these root hairs developed these root
hairs are single uh single cells uh that
are very um effective at uptaking water
nutrients and remember this uh the
environment they're growing into has
been affected already by these um
slopping off cells of the root
tip of course these root hairs are what
get infected by Rise uh by risia
bacteria in nitrogen uh fixation in uh
in a lot of the legumes also these root
hairs um entwined with fungal melium uh
which is very important for for um
increased capture and again increased
surface area for capture of nutrients
and water ultimately these root hairs
will burst and release their release
compounds uh into the soil again
dissolving uh dissolving uh the soil to
release nutrients um releasing compounds
that again affect um antagonists in the
soil and provide an environment
favorable to the next root hair that
moves into that that
zone
okay so um I wanted to talk a little bit
about um just very broad sense here a
lot of interest in these uh different
fields these days of a bacterially
dominated system and fungally fungal
dominated system um and this is very
broad sense U but it's I think it's a
useful strategy to kind of keep these
keep some of these IDE ideas in mind so
we said before that the bacteria are
very fast acting um their population
changes very quickly
um the they're at the the root of um the
way we manage most um annual field crops
we're counting on these bacteria um what
we what they're doing then is using the
last year's and previous years's organic
material and mineralizing that into
often um plant available
materials and tillage promotes that um
because it stir the soil and provides um
fresh fresh opportunities for bacteria
to meet fresh organic matter so the
bacteria don't move very far but when we
till we of course add air and oxygen uh
but we also provide new opportunities
for the uh for the bacteria and the
result of this is we get as these
processes continue we get somewhat
stable uh humic carbon
compounds that are somewhat recal citrin
and can build up into our long-term
total organic matter accumulation in the
soil but we see more of that in a more
fungally dominated system simply because
when we're stirring we always provide
yet another chance to take this uh this
longterm material and have something get
at it so in a fungally dominated system
now we've kind of moved past this these
early stages of of breakdown and the
fungus I see them as somewhat slower I
don't mean that directly but um they're
more um if you will more deliberate in
the the these systems in their approach
to using the the nutrients that are
there uh they take a little bit longer
to associate they're uh uh they're not
just um the the these organisms don't
necessarily just float around in the
soil they they're while they're in the
soil they're looking for a a
relationship uh to a PL to a plant or to
the material where the bacteria are just
really more
opportunists uh we talked about how
these then as these funguses develop
these relationships uh that they um
produce a wide network of Mycelia that
can
um uh increase not only uptake of water
nutrients for the plant but also protect
the plant against uh outside uh attack
uh by by disease
organisms and since these these
associations uh are more complex they
develop a little more slowly and uh they
require not so much of this uh
favoritism towards the bacterial end the
rapid the rapid turnover but in
undisturbed or permaculture environments
or what we might see in a more of a
berry situation uh there's time for
these uh these infections and uh
long-term associations to to develop and
because of that then we have a chance
for a more complex carbon sequestration
uh in in the more complex compounds what
we would call humification then and we
can produce uh compounds that really um
sequester carbon over the long term um
and uh help our soil with these um with
the with the processes that are more
associated with uh this what we called
last week the very dead stable organic
compounds right so kind of a um fun
little slide I made here I show some
people uh collecting leaves into a leaf
pile in the this last fall and across
the top uh they simply pile them up and
don't stir them and at the end of at the
end of a year the next fall we see that
the the pile is about 2third as high as
it was the year
before uh not many of the leaves have
broken down they've uh the weight of
snow and rain is has kind of compressed
some of the air out of it but we haven't
had a whole lot of a lot of breakdown
and so my CO2 Evolution out the top of
these
um these boxes uh is smaller at the
bottom we show a leaf pile the same leaf
pile being collected but we're doing a
lot of stirring so we're going to turn
our compost pile uh provide
opportunities to move uh bacteria into
zones of fresh material to attack uh and
breakdown and Etc and we see because of
that then we're getting going to have a
lot more carbon dioxide release so we're
going to increase our respiration
through this through this opportunity of
the bacteria and as we release carbon
dioxide we move through the soil food
web to if you will uh more complex uh
carbon compounds the simple ones being
used up by the bacteria
um and of course I think we all know the
the model of the carbon cycle but I put
this up because I I really see the it as
being a balancing act between the the
top Arrow the top orange arrow and the
bottom orange arrow Arrow so on the one
hand we're composing we're taking carbon
dioxide from the atmosphere and
composing um carbon into um into sugars
cellulose and starch um and on the other
hand we're
decomposing through the respiration of
soil microbes decomposing this organic
matter back to carbon
dioxide and it's this spinning uh this
the rapid spinning of this as I was
saying is the is what's favored by the
um the bacteria and when these when
these cellulose and starch compounds are
can be more complex or or just different
we're going to affect the the soil
microbes then that would that would be
able or want to or rapidly decompose
them so I just I kind of like this this
sort of a concept to think about um
composing and decomposing and what we're
kind what we're the uh the kind of
strategy that we're going to have to
approach and of course when we add
manures or compost on the upper right we
kind of short circuit the plant it had
been done elsewhere uh but then we can
uh directly affect the this carbon
cellulose starch uh whatever you want to
call this this complex uh material that
are that microbes are going to act
on okay the here we go again with the
soil food web on the right I'm showing
some uh fungi colonizing this plant
rizosphere in a more undisturbed
environment um just wanteded to uh use
this slide to kind of introduce this
idea again of we've got uh living and
dying soil organisms so there's a
there's really a web of life um going on
it uh quite rapidly in our soil that
we're going to want to affect with our
management but first i'm going to take
just a few minutes to kind of say how
we're going to look at the processes
themselves in the soil so that we can
apply management to those
processes so these right as these uh
organisms cycle they're basically
breaking down organic debris and
modifying
it and then one by one I want to step
through these other ideas um in this
Cornell soil Health test we we're going
to look at how these organisms create
and release glues and and try to try to
measure that and quantify it on the
right I show a um a clump of sad dug up
and you can see the the nice soil
structure the nice crumb structure uh
these uh soil particles are glued
together not only by uh The Roots
themselves of the plants and the what
we're talking about these exudates from
The Roots but also the organisms the
rapid turnover of organisms uh in that
zone helping to glue these these
particles
together uh another thing to consider
when we when we grow a if we call this a
cover crop or grow a crop we're actually
inserting organic matter into the ground
when this plant dies uh right where
right where you see the roots now as
opposed to tillage where we would um
kind of or tillage of let's say a
compost applied to the surface where we
um accomplish something very different
we would mix we would mix the soil from
the surface in um very heavy-handedly as
opposed to Growing it in uh in place so
that's going to obviously affect our our
net result and this is something we have
to keep in mind as we go forward with
decisions on how we want to affect our
soil and at the bottom right here I show
um just a kind of a contrast in uh what
soil looks like uh when we test it under
the uh the soil Health test on the left
that that soil tested uh right in the
medium to medium low range instability
and the same soil under different
management uh of no tillage um we see
that the soil is holding these Crumbs
are holding up better uh to the action
of the
raindrops right so so these soil
organisms in the soil uh can mineralize
nutrients by breaking down
mineralization refers to taking organic
material and and removing the literally
the nutrients and minerals in it uh back
into plant available forms plants tend
to take up inorganic substances and
combine them into organic forms so here
we want to go the other way and
mineralize so that's kind of the uh the
opposite of what a plant does we want to
break that plant down into into um
ideally nutrients for our plants and
we're going to look at that we look at
this with the um potentially mineralized
o nitrogen test in the soil Health test
uh we look at the rate of uh of
breakdown of organic materials to
release
ammonium we mentioned before that these
soil organisms can uh protect or infect
crop plants based on what organisms are
there and how we manage for or against
them we can use that to our advantage um
to protect our our Target
plant and again this is the we saw this
last week this is the soil bioessay um
test that we use in the soil Health test
um this is actually a um Greenhouse test
where we plant um you see replicate
samples here in the on the upper left U
of U of A samp of a soil sample where we
put it one of these um green beans into
each tube and grown it out in the
greenhouse this is a this variety of
green bean is called high style and it's
well known to researchers particularly
uh in Plant Pathology uh because it's
sensitive to a wide variety of of
diseases a lot of Growers or Growers
typically don't buy this variety anymore
because it is so sensitive but we can
use that to our advantage uh to kind of
see what's in the soil and how our
management has affected these uh some of
these um list Aral players like pythium
and fusarium in
particular and then another test in the
Cornell soil health health test we
talked about last week was this active
carbon and here's where we're looking at
the uh the food value if you will or the
energy literally the energy value of the
carbon in our soil um this is the um
what I would call the kindling of the so
organic matter this is the easily
accessible um easily oxidizable easily
available uh the sugars the uh the
cupcakes of the soil organic matter um
this is uh bacteria would um act very
quickly on this sort of material but a
we can measure this and say a high level
of this would then suggest a high level
of uh activity in our soil so we can use
this information toward as we approach
our
management and we talked last week it's
um mention it again we talked last week
on about how this purple potassium
permanganate also can break down not not
unlike the organisms can break down and
burn this uh soil organic matter and so
the more purple that's used up in the
course of this test it's a 10-minute
shaking uh the more purple color that's
used up the more available organic
matter was in the sample so it's it's
kind of a again it's a we're testing
that flare up we're looking for that
that kindling potential of the of the
soil organic
matter right and here's the uh slide
that we talked about a little bit last
week about the uh uh these long-term
humic materials and how important they
are and literally these are the those
presistent
compounds that we really talk about when
we say about building soil organic
matter uh the other material it's just a
matter of time this this fresh material
won't be fresh for long it's always on
its way to being uh converted into
something else as as organisms uh
transform it but these compounds are
kind of the end of the line uh these are
the ones that as I say when we're
building uh are sequestering carbon over
time these are the ones we're concerned
with uh or that we're talking about and
that I had said uh we see um more likely
to develop in these permaculture
environments not just because of the um
the action of this a little more fungal
domination but also because of the lack
of stirring and why these are so
important directly is that these these
humic substance really loose in the soil
uh they're very uh light and spongy they
hold a lot of water um they soften clay
soils um and they also hold um chemical
nutrients based on their charge they
negative
charge
oops sorry I went the wrong way on that
one
slide Mel function sorry about that here
we go so back to our uh the slide we saw
before where we add organic matter again
these red boxes are all the different uh
tests in the analyses in the cornal soil
Health test looking at these different
uh soil
processes but again I have to stress
when we think of we want to we want to
understand all this but now we want to
talk about okay different organic
matters organic matter sources and uh
qualities are going to affect these
differentially so it takes we have to
use the same sort of thinking and and um
logic if you will on how these how these
processes are affected um through the
through their interaction of the
different um Realms of um of their
actual qualities now how could we use
that to our advantage and to what we
want out of the um
the the soil that we're working
with going to mention this is the
Cornell soil Health test uh Suite of
measured indicators on the left and on
the right are the soil processes that
we're
measuring here it is the soil Health
Report again the the indicators the
value uh where the blue arrow is so
these are the um the lab or field return
values we rate remember we rate the
um these
values with our database the lower 30%
of scores uh in the database are scored
red uh and that's useful for uh
developing what we call constraints on
the far right so if uh uh if a value
comes back in the lower 30% for the soil
texture for its soil texture then we
would say yes this uh these these
functions are are U below certainly
below an Optimum or room for improvement
and so the is where we kind of start to
put together these uh these different
processes in the soil that we can then
approach with our management to kind of
get at uh several of these at once as I
said before create these these
synergistic opportunities for um for
knocking out multiple uh multiple issues
at
once and I have to mention the uh
the website here a lot of this material
that we talk about is on our website um
in the training manual very useful
document um available as uh a free
download from the website also there's
all sorts of information on sampling um
delivery of samples to our lab just
strategies in general um and in the
manual not only does it talk about part
one the soil test itself but what we're
going to move into now this the soil
management guidelines so kind of a
starting place for using the information
to go
forward right so last week really we
talked about uh the soil processes and
the soil Health test indicators at the
bottom we spent a lot of time on that I
introduced this this idea that we can
use this um use this information in the
test report then towards uh our soil
management but again to use this
holistic strategy we have to understand
in the processes find out which
processes are impaired then tweak our
management to address
them coming back to our um soil Health
Report from before so this is a um a RI
this was a a strawberry field that had
excuse me Ry vet on it for two years um
3 years ago and then strawberries were
planted and grown for 2 years it's a
Sandy LOM
soil so the first thing we're going to
want to do uh to use this holistic
strategy is to um test the soil and get
the information on what functions in the
soil are good bad and indiff and from
this then we can learn a lot for example
we look at the aggregate stability the
first physical indicator we see that it
comes back at a 95% rating it's in the
green so we've got a really nice soil
structure according to the test yet as
we move down down the list we see that
there's surface hardness and subsurface
hardness so we've got some compaction in
the
soil which we'll want to take into
account as we move forward and down in
the biological realm we see we've got a
dis a decent amount of total organic
matter 2.8% for a Sandy lone that's not
bad but our active carbon our our fresh
organic material and our um the the rate
of um mineralization nitrogen so this
this breakdown of of organic material
into available nutrients and and fresh
material uh that that rate is also
slow looks like our soil chemistry is
pretty good our
pH kind of kind of at the bottom end of
of where we'd want
it but pnk look good micronutrients look
good too we've got an overall score soil
Health score of 59 call that 60 uh in
the medium range kind of useful for just
kind of thinking in the long term uh
several years later we we we'll try
we'll try some uh different Management
on this field and several years later
we'll sample again and see how we've uh
affected
things so we've talked about the first
step step two what might we do our
management options uh this is kind of a
brainstorming um strategy here where we
kind of say well it's certainly we'd
want to identify this hard layer find
out just what's causing it um where it
is exactly what are we going to do about
it what might we do about it I list here
that we might we might plow it up we
might uh maybe use a deep Ripper we
might go with a cover
crop um then to address the soil biology
while we're thinking about plowing and
ripping and and perhaps growing a cover
crap we want to maybe feed the soil with
some heavy debris if we could get some
if that's possible that debris could
feed the soil um particularly if it's um
got rich uh biological material that
would start to spin our soil food web
and perhaps address our active
carbon um if we use a nitrogen-rich
material again this is a as a compost as
we feed the soil directly um if we had
something that had uh nitrogen first
Fair supply of nitrogen in the organic
form that would help build our
population of mineralizable uh nitrogen
uh Critters uh and increase that uh that
rate
we may in our cover crop we would want
probably a rich root residual like we
saw in the sad photo a few slides ago
where we can maybe without even plowing
we could move this Rich organic material
maybe maybe even rich with or with
nitrogen right into the soil profile
without plowing or bringing anything in
and that would be for example growing a
a clover or a vetch or an elf
Alpha you may want to mix uh the disease
rating here looks pretty good however
there uh I mentioned these options with
these new crucifers um a lot of
different uh options out there for um
crops to use as cover crops and uh and
nurse crops to to build the soil but but
again we want to we want to have that in
mind uh just because this test tells us
we're in good shape with uh with root
health doesn't mean we might not want to
um get something mixed into our our
rotation here that provides
uh some suppressive capacity towards
something we know that's out there or
have heard about in in the vicinity so
then we're going to move to step three
and step
four uh but before we do uh we want to
think about uh what we're trying to do
with soil management um it's it's an
Ever more complex world there's so much
information out there that we have to
continue learning uh modifying what we
know asking questions
uh seeing what people are doing all over
the world really uh certainly in our
region um to learn of these latest
Technologies strategies um so that we
can be better not just better Growers
but as consultants and Educators better
uh suppliers of information uh and
sharing this information so that we as
as a group uh can just all be more
successful and of course as
we try to capture new markets or um work
with new varieties new cover crops that
requires us to um really I use the word
transition to be capable of applying
this new knowledge then incrementally
into our own minds first then into our
management where we kind of realize that
we the things we haven't been doing uh
might behoove us to to learn and to
learn how to do uh never easy with uh
agriculture as you know there's a lot of
risk associated with it and so we're we
tend to want to be risk averse and these
changes are risk um because because
there's a learning curve so that's where
the uh the Consulting egg professionals
and the grower uh we'll see more and
more of these um uh Liaisons being
necessary yet uh at the same time that
we're going to see probably less and
less money for um State and County
support for this so we we really need to
uh be thinking how can I get this
information out uh as Educators but also
as Growers how can I get this
information in um from all these from
all these different
sources okay and again this information
all this information is we really have
to deal in a case by case field by field
grower by grower basis so even when we
learn principles and strategies
somewhere at a conference at at a
particular Growers field we need to take
from that then the principles and say ah
can I use that principles back in my
Locale and this it's actually very
exciting if you're an educator because
you you kind of get to go out into the
world and and learn and then apply that
learning um really without the risk that
the grower has um but the grower is
doing the same thing uh going out
learning coming up with new questions uh
for of things to try and more questions
for the educator so this all this
information going back and forth it
really requires considerable attention
and thought and really if you will
creativity um to be useful because
things are changing and that change just
requires this kind of a uh a a
deliberate process of of of adapting to
it right so in our soil Health manual um
we've got table five here on page 57 if
everyone anyone has the manual um they
kind of lists shortterm and long-term
management strategies to deal with um
for
example limitations identified by the in
the soil Health Report but uh I have to
mention these are just starting points
but they do kind of get at this this
idea that we have a we have a
generalized model that we start from so
there's no I don't want to say there's
no answers here but there's no
recommendations here it's it's
information that we again apply into our
model and go forward with more specifics
that are germine to us but use this just
as a more of a reference uh starting
place so uh I'd like to use this the
first uh circled um uh physical concern
there this low aggregate stability the
um like to talk in the short term how a
manager might address that if that was
the case uh we we note here that it's we
talk about fresh organic materials
shallow rooted cover crops we saw the
the picture of that grass sad um um some
slides ago showing that how we could
build soil structure with that um of
course a rotation crop as well could can
provide that when we add fresh manure
and or green clippings um to the surface
of the soil of course we're uh these
these materials will be rapidly attacked
there's a lot of fresh carbon there a
lot of sugar so to speak for the soil
bacteria uh so rapid order they're going
to turn turn over spin that soil food
web help glue our soil back together in
the longer term again we're going to
want to be thinking about well how did I
get into this uh position in the first
place uh it may be that we want to look
at uh a lot of interest these days in
reducing tillage not not necessarily
going to what we call no till uh but
there's a new term out there called Low
till where we just simply try to reduce
the tillage intensity and frequency uh
look for opportunities to really think
can we focus the tillage right in a Zone
rather than across the whole soil
surface for example
we might want to think about a surface
mulch certainly in a um in a berry
situation we're often dealing with
surface mulches that can protect the
soil and provide a constant Source um of
material that we can kind of maybe dis
in or or uh stir in a little bit once in
a while uh to keep our um our soil
bacteria cycling and protecting that
soil uh
structure
okay so in a again in a broad sense when
we um talk about the soil Health Report
strategy uh gone over this several times
and I do apologize but I I think it's
important to to keep mentioning this
we're going to identify uh areas in the
soil uh that need uh attention because
they have we're determining that the
processes are are are
constrained so now we want to combine
this information with the Growers needs
skills and available resources to come
up with a strategy to deal with them and
I mentioned here the the four really our
four broad sense options in management
there anything we might do to the soil
really pretty much falls into one or a
combination of these groups so we can
change the U the crop that we grow uh
and what that leaves behind how that
that organic matter uh affects the soil
uh also the the the uh production
strategy how we manage the soil to grow
that crop affects the soil uh by again
of changing um varieties or um to longer
season shorter seasons for example we
can open windows for cover crops to be
inserted into these
windows so hybrid Choice becoming very
important in cop rotation a lot of uh
lot of documentation of what these
different hybrids can do uh to provide
uh as we mentioned before um certain
chemicals in the plant that um that we
might want um as a if you will as a
byproduct uh to affect our soil soil
environment and of course cover crops
themselves what a uh what an easiest
thing to say you know we need to grow a
cover crop but that that only that only
puts the book on the table it still
needs to be opened and red um and this
is where it's uh it's a Brave New World
a lot of information out there um we
just need to really be on top of what
all these options are we'll go through
that in a moment organic and chemical
amendments we when we manage the soil
certainly I mentioned a couple times we
can bring material from other places in
and apply it to our soil surface either
as organic or chemical um and work that
in or or leave it there and of course we
typically work it in uh with tillage and
soil stirring and so we always have
options to uh manage the soil that way
so we'll go through those one by
one um the crop
rotation suppressing disease smothering
weeds all these uh again kind of broad
sense caveats of um really an agronomic
approach um the when we rotate crops we
can again put different material there
or not there at different times uh to
affect our soil biology different cover
crops same idea but there's different
windows for for different cover crops
and again they're going to have
different qualities the different cover
crops not only when they're because
because of when they're grown but what
they bring what they bring to our um the
organic table the
pallet organic and chemical amendments
my gosh uh manure and compost so easy to
list them but the diversity of manure
and compost and green manures how we
might uh use these um in these it's it's
very easy to list these but there's a
lot of information behind each of these
that we'll discuss in a moment but we
have to be aware that it's going to take
uh creative thought and movement into um
uh the the Page Beyond this page uh to
make our best decisions and of course I
mentioned crop residues themselves U
biochar um then more conventional
fertilizers pesticides herbicides that
we can also add to the soil to manage it
and of course tillage this I mentioned
the low till and no till tillage can
break up or prevent
competion and there's lots of new
equipment out there um that allows us uh
I call it Innovations in disturbance
different ways we can stir the soil um
different shapes of shank everything
from different shapes of Shanks couters
Etc um that can be very useful for
us
okay um I show here on the right um crop
rotation on Organic Farms that's a uh
fairly recent publication available
through the the s website s.org uh for a
very low price also available free as an
online download uh this looks like it's
for organic farms and it is uh but
that's not to say that there's not
principles in here that are useful for
any grower uh you know as you know
organic grower must be very cognizant of
crop rotations uh to protect their or to
right affect their soil uh biological
populations because they don't have the
literally the luxury of coming in with a
with a very specific chemical that that
has very specific chemicals that have
been developed for us by chemical
companies to to kill or or uh manage
very specific pests so uh the uh the
organic perspec perspective here is very
useful um towards as we strategize
towards uh understanding of how we can
affect our our soil biology right so the
again the different crops uh suppress or
break disease Cycles uh there's uh by
growing crops that take more or less
time uh we open up
Windows where can grow a cover crop for
example to some other weeds uh ideal
crop rotations uh best U utilized our
Our Land equipment and labor resources
allow us to grow crops that um people
are are clamoring for and paying money
for and of course rotation was sad I had
to mention this um in a cop when we talk
about crop rotation um it's important to
consider um taking a field not out of
production but putting a or part of a
field into sad uh for all the wonderful
things it can do um to rebuild the soil
very dramatically
drastically wanted to talk a little bit
about cover crops again wonderful book
out there U managing cover crops
profitably uh available for free uh to
download at the website below or very
low cost um and this gets at um The Cult
the culture and aspect and um um
qualities of a whole Suite of cover
crops uh for the whole certainly for the
whole Northeast uh in this this book
actually goes uh further south and a bit
into the into the western state in the
Midwestern states talking about all the
different um effects in culture of of
cover crops but again
different cover crops will have
different
qualities more or less of of them of
some of these listed uh features here so
if we had a if we had an issue of that
we wanted to for example add
nitrogen with a cover crop obviously
there's we want to choose in the legume
family but um the idea here is we want
to we want to be really be wise and
clever um and choose well um but there's
a lot to learn we can't it this isn't
just an offthe cuff decision um I'm
going to plant a cover crop and now I'm
done until I plant it no that as I say
that that book needs to be opened and uh
takes a lot of discussion a lot of
research uh a lot of questions to be
asked and answered uh by the grower and
the any sort of
consultant so that we can maybe even
with a with with our cover crop not only
address some of the things we see here
um but do more than that simultaneously
and again some cover crops do several of
these um singularly circled um factors
at
once all right there's even a uh online
cover crop decision tool I've got the
website down at the bottom this was
developed by Thomas borkman um a cornal
researcher up at Geneva uh where you can
uh actually type in a a management goal
so what is he says the reason you need a
cover crop so from that last slide if we
wanted to enhance one of those
particular features if are if we're
really looking to
um uh affect um one particular aspect of
our soil uh very powerfully we could
type that in here and then the the crop
the decision tool would also ask us well
when is your window how and how long is
it open um and and then it would um give
you different uh options uh of cover
crops that fit uh fit that need but
again uh I'm going to go over all four
of these bullets here note that each
option tested in strategy is always an
iteration towards a final decision I had
to read that it's this idea that uh we
need to kind of go through it in our
mind and say does this work or how well
does it work because we can always
modify that a little bit towards what we
need and that that we have to keep that
in mind uh lot lots of um Success
Through sharing success stories uh when
we see a grower with a particular
situation in an area that kind of uh
comes up with a cover crop uh crop
combination uh that has luck with that
um we hear about it at a field day for
example or we see something we can think
ah now how can I modify that or use that
for myself as a starting point very
we've seen a lot of great um we heard a
lot of great success stories built out
of success stories um Growers often
start small and we recommend this uh
using strip trials or you know half of a
field managed one way or another way to
kind of learn on their Farm what works
or or what they uh find just doesn't
won't work for them also as we enter
into new worlds of cover crops and
different rotations uh we can also
introduce new pests and problems uh that
we didn't have before because we weren't
using these strategies so again we have
to be uh Vigilant and uh ready to learn
whatever is necessary um to move forward
right now I want to talk a little bit
more about this managing of organic
matter um again I put uh a book by
Harold vaness and uh Fred magdoff in the
upper left corner this building soil for
better crops um available free online
very low cost if you want to own the
book
itself and uh what this book talks about
at Great in great length is how to
balance this idea of we want to
decompose organic matter to release
nutrients we want want the organic
matter to break down to as I've
mentioned before glue our Aggregates
together we want to feed the important
soil biology but at the same time we
also want organic matter to
accumulate for all the important reasons
that we want organic matter in our soil
to to store water to retain nutrients uh
to loosen the soil um carbon storage so
the really the only way to uh to be
successful at this is to literally keep
adding organic matter because we uh as
we decompose it we we have less and we
can only accumulate it by growing or
adding more so we we need to kind of tip
this scale the other way so we're kind
of accumulating on a on a net basis or
should say a gross bases even though at
times we need to decompose some of that
organic
matter so again it it we're going to
have to um feed the soil with uh
different materials and regularly and
the more diverse organic matter we can
add the more the broader a base of U
organic activity we have in the
field and again I mentioned compost
cover crops these crop revenues adding
leaves biochair when we when we add
these different materials or grow these
different materials remember that we're
going to uh
accumulate a different kind then of um
soil food web res response to this
different food source and that's really
what ultimately what we're managing
for here's that slide all organic matter
is not created equal I've talked about
this any number of times now but if we
look at this pyramid when we add a a
green matter or green manure as a cover
crop we're adding these sugars these
these lighter less complex compounds
that the U bacteria are very hungry for
when we had composts or when we're
dealing with composts we've moved
further down the pyramid already in the
compost pile into these more uh complex
longer lasting um
materials and again the different types
of organic matter are going to affect
the bullets you see etherite some of
them will affect soil aggregation
particularly um the green matter but
different green matter will have
different effect um on the soil itself
we've all heard of for example buckwheat
having a particularly profound effect on
soil aggregation under very short time
uh so we again we need to keep that in
mind it's they're easy again easy to
list as bullet points but we need to
think about what exactly will do that uh
to be to affect our
management right and also uh this is
also um something we see in uh Herold
Vanessa's in book more is not always
better so we have to be careful
particularly when we apply uh compost
and manure on the surface of the soil um
it's very easy to a to to over apply um
and cause leeching and denitrification
concerns
um in vegetables in particular we don't
want uh too much fgure um from uh too
high supply of nitrogen or or other
compounds or other nutrients in the soil
U also uh over application of compost
might keep the soil too wet um all
important considerations to uh always
work within if I can move down to the
last bullet point uh to kind of start uh
start from an an what I'm I'm calling an
industry standard we don't want to go
overboard with these application
strategies um we want to kind of start
from a um a safe place and then modify
from there as our crops and our field
and our our material
requires and keeping in mind also that
uh particular I give this wine example
here um how some crops and or grapes
grown for wine actually we don't want
this great fgure and we want to be
actually be very careful of what we're
adding um just kind of a if you will an
overe extreme example of um really
thinking ahead towards what we're doing
and make sure that that is indeed what
we
want oh right back to our stirring of
the soil again to speed up these
bacteriological
processes um
the our organic matter is going to
mineralize faster when we stir
it and the way we do that stirring so
often was with tillage um this is a
slide showing tillage addiction so I'm
going to go from the upper left
clockwise around where we till a soil um
we see being completely inverted this is
aad um it's being PL plowed a little wet
uh kind of show the kind of a worst case
scenario here of uh of soil um tillage
nonetheless we're always uh involved at
kind of some aspect of this so after we
flip the soil over with this till mour
tillage now we've got uh cloudy soil
that needs to be made into a seed bed or
a planting bed then typically we come
across the field and Teck it down uh
firm it up but then we're set up for
potential crusting the soil is
unprotected it's bare uh this is a kind
of a worst case scenario but uh I show
this to make people realize that or or
not forget I should say um the tillage
is a very powerful uh very powerful tool
that we shouldn't shouldn't take lightly
that when we when we apply tillage were
really really affecting a lot of um a
lot of soil processes not just the
physical things you see here but the
organisms um are going to be literally
tipped upside down um and they're going
to respond to that in a way that may be
useful to us or um or maybe not so we
want to keep that in
mind we see a lot of focus tillage uh
through this uh this sort of Ripper
strategy uh instead of a the last slide
that was a full uh full width mward plow
just flipping over the entire soil
surface uh these rippers I think
everyone's seen these uh have a rather
narrow shank typically an inch wide um
this is shown setup for row crop
production however the idea is that we
uh Focus the tillage uh really right in
the vicinity of this rip shank uh we
don't flip the entire surface over and
we end up really just um kind of plowing
in a in a in a narrow
Zone here's kind of what it looks like
then in the upper left uh we've got an
uh kind of an undisturbed surface for
most of the soil surface but then our
our rip shank can go at a variety of
different depths whatever is necessary
to break uh restricted layers up and
we're left with a if you will a no till
environment between the rips and a
tilled environment where the rips are
very handy in uh approaching a certainly
a bedded situation where we're we're
almost forced to do this um but you know
keep in mind that by focusing the uh
focusing the disturbance we can kind of
get the best of both worlds and allow us
and this is a of course a field crop
example but we've got then a hybrid
system where we've plowed where we're
going to plant the seed and have a small
plant but then as the plant grows and
explores new areas it'll actually be
growing between the rows into a
virtually unplowed or no till
environment so we've got a plow a plow
Zone and an unplowed Zone and so we can
take advantage of of the season if it's
wet or dry or periods of wet and dry the
plant has areas uh where the root is
that where the soil will be drier or
moiser um because of this hybrid uh
scenario so I really like this sort of
um slide to show you how we when we
change our management a little bit we
look at the bottom center uh picture we
see on the right the conventional if
it's hot and dry our entire soil surface
is going to dry out for example where
with a restricted wi tillage where we
focus our tillage we get a lot of hot
dry weather we're going to have a little
bit more uh water storage underneath all
the debris between those ripped
areas right and I list here some of the
these tips for transitioning that's a
one of my favorite words uh to reduce
tillage Crop Production um the idea is
is that we're uh trying to transition to
less tillage so we're we're we're
thinking about do I need to do what I've
always is done is there a new method out
there or I've heard of this new method
how do I transition uh my field into
using it um and here are some of the uh
some of the ideas so first of all we
soil compaction is a question of soil
being dense uh to allev alleviate that
we want to loosen the soil again this is
uh with with the iron in the field as
opposed to a um using plants to do it
but we can focus AR tillage to to
specific
zones in particular for example A Wheel
track Zone maybe the only area compacted
in our field is where a particular piece
of equipment went well it would it might
behoove us to focus directly on that
rather than attempting to loosen or till
till the entire
field um and that's um where we can also
um when we when we put this in concert
with uh the green text uh I guess number
four we can feed the soil food web with
our organic material and combine that
with our tillage and say wait this is
this is how we can
accomplish more than one of or a second
and third objective simultaneously um in
my management
strategy of course then there's longer
and shorter term uh strategies for that
uh with the the cover crops rotations Ed
adding Organics reducing tillage we
listed those in the in the
toolbox um when we can build the soil
and reduce our tillage and and build it
with um rebuild our soil structure the
soil can become more resilient to
weather
extremes and I have to mention at the
bottom that when the soil is in this um
uh if you will healthier condition and
better balance um everything seems to
work better uh this this idea of
applying reduced tillage uh to to huge
effect positive effect is enhanced when
the soil is in good
condition here I just wanted to show how
there's a synergistic effect to our
management so we see soil Health on the
y- AIS and years across the X if we
apply U if we modify our management with
uh finding windows for different cover
crops or reducing AR tillage uh
individually if we apply these
managements we can increase our our soil
Health but if we can uh creatively put
them together and combine them uh with
an overall holistic plan um we tend to
see faster and greater overall response
what we call an additive effect of
putting these positive management
approaches
together kind of a a opsis slide here um
showing the um soil Health Report on the
left the one we're going to talk about
in just a minute as we go through the
final management uh stages of
interpreting this uh but we do want to
remember that the uh the soil health
tool soil Health Report is a tool um in
a whole program of developing solutions
to farm field uh Market
issues um what we're talking about here
is that we have this framework for
guiding our soil
management using these Pro using a
process-based approach but in the
context of the the Grower's needs and
desires and uh
limitations and I've mentioned this
several times but this idea of There's
Always Forever on now uh there will be
more and more information available um
to people in the field um in terms of uh
strategies other and Technologies other
people are using and that's going to
require that we we stay a breast of this
so that we can do our best job to um not
not fall behind uh the rapid pace of U
of soil management uh these
days also I had to put this in as a um
this idea to illustrate this idea of
creativity um we really like
um um this uh got a kind of a going from
a a closed I like going from this idea
of there a closed uh
a closed mind that says there's we can't
that this won't work here uh so uh we're
dealing with some uh extension Folks up
in Vermont um that said well we can't we
can't put cover crops after our corn
silage up here our growing season is too
short and some Specialists up there said
well wait a minute let's let's work with
some of the Growers and see if we went
to a for example a shorter season
variety opening up a window of time at
the end of the season for a cover crop
um they they tried it they went with a
10day shorter corn variety for uh field
for uh field corn and allowed them to um
actually be successful with establishing
a rye cover crop with these just just a
few extra days gave them quite a quite a
heads up on the on using the tried and
true older season varieties so it just
goes I just wanted to show with this
that um sometimes there's um with a
little bit of risk or creativity risk
and creativity kind of put together and
try something as a little trial um we
can come up with something that's useful
to perhaps a lot of
people okay so I'm running over here so
I'm going to go quickly uh through these
last two steps step three and four of
our uh uh soil Health Report here we
said this was a um two-year strawberry
field coming out of ryet two years ago
uh this grower is willing to experiment
with different cover crops he's
considering transitioning to organic
because the the market value
he does have a dairy farm nearby just a
little bit of background on um who
exactly this person or who specifically
this person is so step three we say we
want to uh apply this uh the soil
process information that we have in
front of us with the uh situational
opportunities where is this guy what's
he up to what does he have at his
disposal so we've listed it here step
three uh this grower does have access to
a grain drill uh this this local Dairy
nearby uh has a deep ripping machine uh
for de possible decompaction this Darman
will bring his big tractor and this
Ripper uh to the field and and a person
and we'll rip this up for and will
agrees to rip this up for $100 per acre
so this this is an8 acre field so for
$800 um or to do half the field this
Growers this Dairy Farmers is willing to
come over and um experiment with that um
the grower again is interested in cover
crop so he tends a workshop
go to step four oops
huh there one
moment be in step four so putting all
this together sitting with the grower um
the grower has come up with a management
strategy for this year in the spring uh
he's going to plow plow the field up and
see the Ry vetch mustard mix and he's
trying to uh get a sad forming cover
crop there with the Rye um the vet to
supply um nitrogen as well as a deep Tap
Root the mustard for some uh disease
suppressive compounds uh he also wants
to try a strip trial of uh Rebeca or
Andor switchgrass he learn this in his
uh cover crop class um these uh these
crops um have good um cover crop
qualities and the organic debris from
them uh is useful in uh maintenance of
of soil Organics for
strawberries this grower is proposing to
then um flail moow and deep rip during
2012 leaving all whatever in any of
these uh
uh organic growth systems here including
a strip trial he's just going to mow
that and leave it on the field so
everything's U going to be grown and
left uh left in place he may even
consider a different cover crop if one
of these doesn't uh pan out and then
he'll decide based on the soil looks at
as the season goes on in 2013 if he'll
continue this cover cropping or perhaps
go to a cash crop like sweet
corn so that's the end of the
presentation uh just listed here uh some
of those ideas we've been over uh couple
of times during this this talk how the
soil Health test identifying these soil
constrain soil processes kind of the
beginning uh we're going to keep those
in mind as we think what might what
might this this grower do or what might
I do uh that get at to get at these uh
constraints what can I try to see what
will really work
uh adapt many sources of
information ultimately building the soil
to increase this
resiliency the extreme weather we're
going to continue to
see okay and with that I'll say thank
you and uh open the uh the floor to
questions and I just would encourage
anybody that's been participating to use
your chat box in the lower right hand
corner and type in any questions that
you may have so that Bob can
respond uh Glenn had a comment his
comment was resiliency to extremes uh
interesting given increase in intense
rains I don't know whether you have any
comments to that
Bob right well I I kind of mentioned
this at one point um any time right when
a soil is degraded it's uh it's already
down and then when we get extreme
weather it's then then it gets kicked so
to speak um but when it when we can
build a soil and certainly protect the
surface um but that surface can also be
protected if you will internally by
getting organic matter um to break down
in between these particles and help glue
them together again building our soil
structure um in particular really uh
really uh gives the that's the
foundation if you will the house they
talk about soil structure being the
house um of the for the soil microbes to
live within uh we can you know kind of
build that or as we build that uh we're
just um making a a more stable
environment for whatever is thrown at us
be it um heavy rains or drought um from
what we've seen at least in this area uh
this winter it's been um very different
than what we're used to but uh I think
we can get we should get used to um
non-typical weather um so that said
we're going to have to modify our
management so that non-typical weather
isn't as hurtful or damaging as it as it
could be so that's going to take again
that's of creativity that kind of uh
hedging The Bets with u with management
to get at processes that are going to
leave us in a better better better um
better position to weather pardon the
pun um the weather that
comes I I do want to mention in your
discussion you were talking about
compost and I think people equate
compost with a lot of uh very positive
um attributes and I will say that you
know one of the things listed there was
Municipal compost I would just encourage
people to be a little careful with
Municipal composts they they you should
really ask for an analysis and a heavy
met metal analysis of those kinds of
products and even the heavy metal
analyses can be a little
misinforming um we had uh a composting
Facility in Syracuse area and Syracuse
has some industry in it it's not just a
residential Community where you'd expect
like things like copper in compost made
from those materials but it had some
light industry in Syracuse and they used
uh lime at I think it was close to
onethird of the dry matter weight of the
material uh as let's say an Adent uh to
help processes along to reduce the
pathogen level down and in the process
it does tie up um heavy metals and when
they did the testing to test what the
heavy metal levels were uh they were not
really available at really super high
PHS which this turned out to be and a
homeowner could be uh fooled and
purchased or a grower could be fooled
and purchased material thinking that it
really didn't have any heavy metals in
it