this is a production of Cornell
University thanks
[Applause]
Tony it's really good to be back at
Cornell and back in a my home department
or section now crop soil and crop
Sciences so thanks everyone for being
here and today like Tony said I'm
sharing results from my dissertation
which I I completed last summer looking
at invasive plants and white tailed deer
so to begin with I just want to thank my
committee um Dave Morton and Erica
Smithwick were my co-advisors at Penn
State and I had a lot of help with this
project from fi lots of field assistants
to several contributors of data uh a lot
of scientists in the region shared their
large Plant Community data sets with me
so I'm really grateful for those
contributions and also for oh this might
be advancing
automatically
uh and also for the other support I
received at Penn State both funding and
and
otherwise so invasive plants are
associated with a lot of changes both at
the Eco at the ecosystem level and
within the plant Community such as
altered plant animal and microbial
communities biodiversity is often
associated with plant invasions and
ecosystem processes can can also be
influenced oh I'm apologizing for this
advancing let me just switch this pres
presenter
view if I can
okay let's go back here for a
second so although all of these changes
are occurring alongside plant invasions
we don't necessarily know that plants
are the drivers and so the question is
whether other processes such as changing
disturbance regimes or altered Community
assembly factors such as landscape
configuration and deer browsing might
actually be the ultimate drivers causing
ecosystem changes associated with often
associated with invasive
plants so deer are quite abundant and
for example at Valley Forge the current
deer density is 84 deer per square
kilometer and this is several orders of
magnitude higher than pre- European
settlement deer densities which were
often less than 10 deer per square
kilometer often around five and
uh in nearby areas in itha actually the
there are about 100 deer per square mile
in certain places so deer populations as
many of you know are are quite high and
they can have big effects on Plants
especially in Forest understories where
where deer take shelter and you can see
in this Ohio Forest a very strong uh
browse line as a result of heavy deer
pressure so this can reduce the number
of shrubs and herbs in Forest
understories causing impacts on other
animals that rely on those species for
habitat and also this can create a
window of opportunity for invasive
plants and indeed there are a lot of
examples of plant invasions in forest
underst stories such as this is Japanese
barberry in Connecticut garlic mustard
which many of you are probably familiar
with there are yearly poles of garlic
mustard in
fingerlakes and Japanese stilt grass
this is in south southeastern New York
and this this grass and the others are
potentially facilitated by selective
deer
browsing so why are there so many deer
across the
landscape and to show this I I just want
to give you an idea of how the landscape
has changed since pre-european
settlement currently there's a lot of
agricultural cover whereas they're used
to be large contiguous tracks of forest
so in the yellow here you see
agricultural land the red and the pink
indicate developed land cover whereas
the blue and the green are much less
apparent in these in this map yet that
used to be the the pre prevailing um
land cover across the landscape so deer
are responding to this change in
landscape configuration because the
foraging quality is much better along
Forest edges and in open habitats
including crop Fields deer can be quite
problematic in both soy and and in corn
even and especially in cover crops a
deer can cause quite a quite an
impact um in addition invasive plants
are also responding to changes in
landscape configuration so especially
over the last century both deer and
invasive plants have basically gotten a
huge Advantage by the effects that
humans have had on changing landscape
composition and
configuration so broadly my research
falls
into the overall overarching um field in
Ecology of community
assembly and
what I'm showing here is the three major
selection factors that go into
determining the local plant community so
first plant species must disperse and
move to a certain location and then they
must tolerate the environment there so
they must have a physiological tolerance
for that site and then within the
ecological species pool these species
compete and also must cope with natural
enemies such as deer in the case of
plant communities and only then will the
local plant community be realized so I'm
focusing my research in in this area
where I'm looking at the effect of deer
on on
Plants so spatially deer are responding
to the landscape by choosing which which
Landscapes and communities offer the
best foraging opportunities
and also weighing those against other
requirements they have for finding mates
and and
shelter so my research today I'll be
sharing uh occurred at three different
fosi so the first part of my work is at
the plant Community scale and the plant
Community level where I looked at
unfenced and fenced plots from across
the region and I'll be showing you those
results first then I zoomed in to look
at the deer to look at whether deer
preferences are helping to explain AB
plant abundance patterns that are
occurring in plant communities across
the region and then lastly I step back
to consider the context of landscape and
the effect of deer on introduced
plants so first across the region what
are the effects of deer on introduced
and native plants at the community
level so first I want to show you an
example of a fenced and unfenced plot
this is a fenced plot on the
right and you could see a very clear
dividing line and this slide better than
the other and I have to say this deer
has been super imposed I just for for
illustrative
purposes um but in the plot on the left
you notice a lot of Japanese DT grass
and
this plant has grown almost all the way
up to the F the fence Edge and then it
completely almost completely stops in
this case there's hardly any Japanese
still grass occurring inside the fence
where deer have been excluded so this is
a really striking difference in the
plant Community composition and
structure and it appears that deer
browsing their selective browsing might
have facilitated The
Invasion so how might deer facilitate
plant Invasion again they're very
selective
browsers they browse only species they
find palatable and avoid other species
which then gain a competitive advantage
in the plant community so the effects of
deer include changing competitive
hierarchies in the plant communities and
this can have the result of limiting
Forest to understory diversity and
creating Windows of opportunity for
exotic plants to invade again there are
ecosystem processes that are influenced
and the decreasing stability in some of
those processes can again invite plant
Invasion so some Studies have already
looked at the effects of deer on
invasive plants showing that in many
cases dear increased plant Invasion such
as by increasing the cover of garlic
mustard and Japanese still grass however
at other
sites there have been no effects or
conflicting effects within studies such
as at one site multi Rose was increased
and at another site which happened to be
older it it was not the same um pattern
so the really interesting study is that
in some cases in this particular case
deer decreased Oriental Bittersweet
Oriental Bittersweet is another invasive
plant and it appeared that deer presence
actually decreased the
abundance so my work aims to bring
Clarity to some of these equivocal
results in the literature and also to
more broadly understand the role of deer
in plant Invasion across the region
whereas these sites these studies only
used one or two sites my intention was
to use sites from across the
region so this is a map of those of
those 24 sites
and I collected data at these two sites
in Northwestern Pennsylvania but again
like I said most of the data sets were
contributed by other
scientists in this first part of my work
I hypothesized that deer would alter
plant Community composition and doing so
they would facilitate plant Invasion and
of introduced plants and reduce the
abundance of native plants diversity and
abundance of native plants so the data
comprised 200 uh 229 paired plots so
that's a total of 458 plots across the
24 sites and although the experiments
varied quite widely in the purposes for
the experiment in the first place and
the
duration um all of the sites in had in
common that they had fenced and unfenced
plots not sure what's going on here
sorry about
that so the commonality was they all had
fenced and unfenced plots and they all
measured Woody and herbaceous
vegetation so the again the data sources
varied um
the duration of the experiments varied
but I'm controlling for that as you'll
see with a random effect approach
so using data from lots of different
sources can be very unwieldy and this
was a really big challenge particularly
in that different abundance plant
abundance metrics were used across the
the 24 data sets at 14 sites stem
density was used to estimate plant
abundance whereas in many other cover
was used or cover
classes or cover
classes so this is an example or of all
of
the Let Me mute
this okay we have some background noise
um so the these are the cover classes
used across the data sets and as you
could see they they've really really
varied from experiment to experiment so
I tried to combine all of the abundance
metrics into oh
boy yeah I might might be a Mac
issue it happens to
me gather windows do I want to do that
room yeah
okay so moving on to the data
analysis so to look at plant Community
composition I used an indicator species
analysis and this determines the species
that are associated with certain
treatments so in my case I'm looking at
the species that are associated with the
deer treatment plus deer in the control
plots and without deer in the fenced
plots
and to look at species and Community
levels I used mixed model analysis of
VAR
variants and looked at both plant
species and Community levels though
today I'll only have time to talk about
that plant Community level in addition
to um Community
composition so just briefly I used fixed
the fixed effect as deer but the random
effects were plot pair and sight so I'm
controlling for the within sight
variability
as well as between sight variability and
the between sight variability I think is
where a lot of um a lot of the noise
might come in if I wasn't controlling
for those as random
effects so first in summary about 700
plant taxa were recorded ac across the
24 sites 383 of those were Native and
111 were introduced plants and there's a
big gap there you'll notice a lot a lot
of the species unfortunately over 200
could not be identified down to species
level so that's that's a little bit
unfortunate but I think that tells us to
a certain degree where the state of our
taxonomy expertise lies in in going out
and collecting this
data um
unfortunately um that occurred but I'm
Focus so I'm focusing on the species
that we could identifi to to the level
of either being introduced or
native and about 18 species were present
in plots where deer occur two additional
species
were were apparent were occurring where
deer were excluded on average and those
were Native species you'll notice that
there were about three introduced plants
whether deer were present or not and
interestingly a lot of taxa were only
occurring where deer were present or
absent so 14% of the 700 taxa occurred
only where deer were were present not
occurring where deer were excluded and
then
similarly 18% of the species occurred
only where deer were absent so I'm
beginning to show you the differences
between deer and no deer plots and you
can already see that deer have a very
big impact on plant community
composition so first here I'm showing
you the indicator species analysis
results and I'm beginning with the six
species that are the six introduced
species that are indicators of deer
presence and you'll notice that three of
these six are considered highly invasive
and they're also
occurring across a lot of the 229 deer
plots and across a lot lot of the sites
so these are some of the most widely
spread invasive plants in in the region
in at least in Forest under
stories and the native spe there were
several native species associated with
deer so these are the species that
you're more likely to see across the
landscape and are more likely to persist
despite High deer
pressure and in contrast they're
occurring across many fewer of the plots
and sites so they're not as widely
distributed across across the region as
are the invasive
plants and these are some of the more
frequent species Oxalis clear weed
coralberry and stinging nettle so these
species are ones that I might consider
planting because they're probably going
to persist in the face of deer
better so as far as where deer were
excluded there were five introduced
plants strongly associated with with
that treatment and again three of them
happen to be three are considered highly
invasive and these are Japanese
honeysuckle bush Honeysuckle and
multiflor
Rose
and I have a picture of a bird on a
fence here because the birds might be
contributing to the presence of these
fleshy fruited species inside fenced
plot
Birds might preferentially land on the
fence because it's a perge point in
itself or within the plants that are
growing inside the fence which are much
the vegetation is much more dense inside
the plots so there are more perch points
so that might be one explanation why
there are fleshy fruited invasives
occurring in Forest understory mostly
Forest understory
plots so so far I had shown
six invasive plants that were associate
or three invasive plants associated with
no deer plots three associated with plot
with um the absence of deer but there
are 27 native plants associated with the
absence of deer suggesting that the
natives are more susceptible to Deer
brows than than the exotic plants and
these are some of the
more these are some of the more uh
frequent native species associated with
the absence of deer white ash spice bush
black cherry and even poison ivy
suggesting that deer might find these
species particularly palatable or in the
case of spice bush maybe birds are again
helping to disperse these species to
where deer have been excluded because of
additional perch
points so overall we're seeing big
differences in exotic uh introduced
plants and native plants the native
plants appear to be more impacted by
deer than than the introduced
plants at the community level I'm seeing
similar
results the introduced species richness
did not change whether deer were present
or not and a plant absolute introduced
plant abundance was also
unaffected and this corresponds to what
I was seeing in the indicator species
analysis results approximately the same
number of introduced plants are
associated with with each of those
treatments and there happen to be three
of each three in each of invasive
invasive
plants however deer had a big de had a
big negative impact on Native Plant
abundance and plant species richness
decreasing so deer decreased native
plant abundance in all three of the
abundance
metrics
and the again this is reflecting what I
was showing in the indicator species
analyses total plant species richness
and abundance also declined and mostly
that was due to the native plants so
there's a difference here in how deer
are impacting exotic plants and native
plants and it translates to a
proportional decrease or sorry a
proportional increase in the invaded
of um of plant communities so the
proportion of introduced plant cover and
midpoint is higher where deer are
present so even though deer didn't in
influence the absolute abundance of
exotic in introduced plants they're
increasing the relative abundance of
introduced plants so they're increasing
the degree of plant Invasion or in other
words the invaded of plant communities
this wasn't the same for plant stem
density and one explanation for this is
that deer might increase the foliage on
a plant but not necessarily kill the
stem so the stem might persist even
though the overall cover of that
individual's stem is is reduced so
there's a bigger deer effect on cover
than on stem density might be one way to
interpret
this so revisiting the hypothesis that I
I first laid out for this this
particular part of my research I did
find that deer alter plant Community
composition and a couple caveats in in
this second hypothesis deer facilitated
the invasion of some species and at the
community level they increased the
relative abundance of invasive plants
not absolute abundance and lastly there
were definitely reductions in native
plant diversity and abundance in the
face of
deer so my next question is whether deer
preferences can help explain some of
these patterns that I observed across
the
region so that's the second part of my
research I'm just going to show you show
this briefly I won't go through it all
but please uh ask me questions about
this particular project because this was
a really interesting and uh and fun
experiment I set up uh deer preference
trials at the deer deer pens at at Penn
State where they have captive deer and I
use 15 different plant
species offered to the deer in a
cafeteria
style uh multiple choice preference
trial so I used introduced species and
Native species some that were expected
to be palatable others that were
expected to be unpalatable for both
groups and and I'll show you an example
of the feeding let's see if this video
will
work they didn't always feed at the same
time but there were always two deer in
the pen they were too scared to be in a
pen alone as it turns out so they didn't
have regular
feeding you could see them
eating Blackberry here and honeysuckle
here
honeysuckle turned out to be one of
their
favorites
surprisingly so I'm showing you the
results here based on the El an
electivity index which takes into
account the total amount of biomass
offered within each trial and the amount
of biomass offered for each individual
plant and it takes into account how much
was eaten of each species relative to
the other species so a positive value
indicat Ates that the deer preferred
that species zero indicates random
feeding or feeding in proportion to that
amount offered and zero indicates the
plant was avoided so here I'm just
showing the overall
results and you can see that the
invasive introduced species on average
tended to be more avoided than the
native species which especially in the
spring were more often selected than the
invasive introduced
species but there was a an interaction
at the level of season and species so
I'm showing here the results the same
results but with
species uh you'll see the 15 species
that I included in the trials on the
bottom and within each group invasive
and Native I saw an increasing I saw
quite a quite a a range of plant palet
abilities and deer preferences for these
plants and I've arranged them here
according to Deer preference within each
group I could talk a lot about deer
preferences and the particular plant
traits but I'm just going to focus on
the most preferred and the most avoided
species so Bush
honeysuckle European privet and Oriental
bitters were the most preferred species
and again you'll notice these all have
fleshy
fruits and of the Native species red
maple was uh a little bit of a surprise
to find that it was the most palatable
of of the natives there in the
literature there have been suggestions
that it's not that palatable of a
species but again this is all relative
to just these species that I included in
the trials and the deer were not starved
just so you know they had plenty of hay
and regular food but so these were all
somewhat of treats given they were given
an opportunity to have some some real
plant material not just hay and
pellets so of the species that were
avoided Japanese stilt grass garlic
mustard and Japanese Barberry were
highly avoided and it seemed that based
on some additional data we collected of
the behavior deer behav feeding behavior
um it was quickly not the Deer quickly
learned that these species were ones to
be
avoided and this might explain why in
the across the region we're seeing that
these species increase in the face of
deer they're unpalatable they're avoided
relative to other species so they gain a
competitive advantage in the plant
community and of the Native species
hended Fern was the least palatable and
this is interesting because it it's a
species that has has been noted as a a
native
Invader and this is one of the 24 deer
research sites this is in Northwestern
Pennsylvania where you can see the fenc
plot kind of tried to outline that on
the left where there a lot more plants
shrubs and yet where deer are occurring
there's a lot of Hast ended Fern there
are no introduced plants at this at this
site but there is a lot of hended fern
so I think one point we might take from
this is that
deer can cause an increase in a plant
species whether it's native or
introduced if that plant is unpalatable
so the unpalatability seems to be more
important than the than whether the
plant was introduced or not so deer are
making choices at the species level not
at the level of introduced or
native so just to sum up this this deer
preference section yes deer feeding
preferences can help us understand
what's going on in the plant communities
across the region as far as plants that
increase or decrease in the face of deer
and deer preferences vary the species
level not at the native introduced level
and the process of plant Invasion can
really be informed by understanding the
processes going on at this very small
patch level
so at the in this last part of my
research I just wanted to share a little
bit of my findings based on interactions
that are occurring between deer and
Landscape configuration so deer aren't
interacting with plant communities in a
bubble there are other factors going on
surrounding these
sites so what is the importance of deer
given the context of landscape
fragmentation so I'm stepping back here
looking at the landscape scale and what
do I mean by
fragmentation well first it can imply a
loss of habitat changing landscape
composition such as forests being
replaced by AGG or developed land cover
and also fragmentation imp implies
broken apart landscape patches such as a
decrease in patch connectivity and
increasing Edge habitat which I
mentioned is something that facilitates
both deer and invasive
plants so briefly uh these are the
metrics that I used to describe
landscape fragmentation both landscape
structure and Landscape composition
metrics I think I should move on and not
talk too much about this right
now but again deer and invasive plants
are responding to landscape
fragmentation and it seems that
because year were're shown to have
impacts on plant communities across the
region that this is something we should
really consider what's the what's going
on surrounding the
sites so I hypothesized here that both
landscape attributes and deer would
jointly influence plant Invasion and
high deer density not just deer presence
or absence which I only focused on in
the first part of my research will
increase plant
invasion so I used the data the same
data from the 24 deer research sites and
each site had an independent estimate of
the number of deer per square kilometer
at each of the sites so I use those data
as well as national land cover data
which I and I used many so I used many
Landscapes um to describe the
surrounding fragmentation at each of
these
sites for instance this is the itha land
cover top
you'll see the airport the
mall and there's a deer exclosure site
located right here within this within
this
landscape the pink and the the red are
developed cover as you can see Cornell
is down here near the edge and yellow
and brown represent the agricultural
land cover while green represents
forested
cover so this is the whole range of
Landscapes surrounding the 24 sites and
you can see they range broadly in the
amount of forested cover agricultural
cover and developed cover some of them
are much closer to centers of human High
human population density and some are
very isolated from the influence of
humans some of these sites had no
introduced plants at all others had many
introduced
plants so I used several different um
approaches um to analyze this data um
I'm just going to focus on some results
from mix models and regression but I'll
give you a summary of of the overall
results um ordination visualizations
helped me see that there are multiple
invasive plants occurring at a lot of
these sites and the sites have or the
the plots are much more similar in
community composition to others within
that site than across site so each of
the sites are very different in plant
Community
composition um as far as what I found
from random Forest results um this is a
regression tree analysis-based
approach um to look at the relative
importance of different fact of
different
variables and I found that landscape
fragmentation metrics and Native species
richness were more strongly associated
with plant Invasion metrics than was
deer present
absence so that tells you something
right there at the landscape level
perhaps the effect of deer isn't isn't
as
important
and exotic species richness
interestingly was explained largely by
landscape factors but also by native
species richness and in this model I had
a very high r squar value so leads me to
think that these three factors are are
quite important in understanding the
number of species the number of exotic
species at of
sight um however there in the mixed
model analyses there were interactions
among deer presence absence the
fragmentation metrics and Native species
richness so I'm going to show you one
example of that
here um overall as agricultural land
cover
increases the invasion in in this case
it's the percent of introduced stems or
the proportion of the stems that are
introduced increased with agricultural
cover so overall there's there's a
there's a positive relationship
here but within each of the
sites the effect of deer plays an
important role this interaction was
significant between deer and
agricultural cover so at the sites where
AG cover is minimal mostly forested
sites we're seeing that the number of
introduced stems the percentage of
introduced stems is higher than where
agricultural land cover is much greater
so there's a switch you see the white
symbols are greater than the great
higher than the gray symbols where a
cover is low and the opposite where eye
cover is high so what might be causing
this
relationship one explanation is that the
Invaders the invasive species vary
across this across this gradient and
indeed at these sites where deer were
present Japanese stilt grass and garlic
mustard were the in were the Invaders
whereas in the agricultural higher
agricultural um land cover M um
Landscapes these species Japanese
Honeysuckle and multiflor rows are more
abundant where deer have been excluded
and again I think this might be a result
of bird dispersal um these species are
more common along edges and an open
habitat so it's not surprising that the
propal pressure of these species would
be higher in a landscape covered um more
by Agricultural and open open
land and to look at not just deer
presence absence but also to make use of
the deer Den density data that was
available I found that as deer density
increased so did the cover of introduced
plants and the percent of introduced
species this wasn't found for all of the
metrics that I used to look at plant
Invasion but it was um a significant
relationship here suggesting that deer
density does make a
difference um so overall um in
revisiting the
hypothesis landscape attributes and deer
present were both important and
considering landscape configuration and
deer preference and deer presence we can
more fully understand what's going on
with with uh uh plant Invasion
and just a couple final points here the
surrounding landscape composition can
help explain why some sites are invaded
and others are not and we get a much
better understanding of plant Invasion
by considering the factors going on at a
landscape
scale so in conclusion deer increased
the abundance of several invasive plants
but reduce others deer are indirectly
facilitating plant Invasion because of
the major decrease they have they have
in native plants and deer preferences
are helping to explain those
patterns and then at the landscape scale
both deer abundance and exotic plant or
introduced plant Invasion are linked to
the overarching structure and
composition of of the surrounding
landscape and Invaders differ according
to both the landscape and according to
Deer preferences so I think considering
both of these is is really important um
understanding the plant Invasion process
is strengthened when we examine it in
light of co-occurring multiscalar um
ecological patterns and processes such
as landscape fragmentation and
increasing deer
populations so perhaps Forest
fragmentation and deer browsing are the
ultimate drivers of a lot of the
ecosystem changes that we see in
association with plant
Invasion so it's just I think important
to think a little bit broadly about
whether it's really the plants that are
driving these changes or they or are
they just passengers kind of along for
the ride as a result of other changes
and lastly managing invasive plants
might be ineffective unless we're also
managing for changes in landscape
structure and composition and the
increasing deer
populations so maybe one way to ask a
final question is what's more desirable
having very little growing where there's
very clear browse lines and Forest under
stories or having introduced plants
growing so of course this is kind of an
exaggerated either or but I think
because there's an opp window of
opportunity in a lot of forest underst
stories because of the high deer
pressure the result is having invasive
plants but maybe the invasive plants
have some are offering some services
that we've we've overlooked and Anton
and I have talked about how that might
be uh an interesting path to go down
from here
on so with that I hope
there are minutes for questions but it
doesn't look like there are um if anyone
has anything they'd like to ask me now
or later I'd be
happy to answer
yeah if um honey suckle and and M FL
rows
are so desirable from the deer's point
of view why are they so abundant in land
yeah I've thought about that a lot um
over the year over the past few years
and one explanation is that there're
typically higher light environment
species and whereas I studied a lot of
I study the plant communities and forest
underst stories for the most part there
might be a difference there between
highlight and and low light environments
I think in highlight environments those
species tend to grow really quickly so
they might just be able to outgrow any
of the deer browsing that occurs in
those open habitats because I have
noticed in walking through Fields even
that there is deer brows occurring on
those species but maybe it's just not
enough the deer don't want to eat 100%
of their diet of one shrubby invasive
plant they can only eat so much of of
it I think one of the issues of deer
pressure is actually Forest regeneration
so are there lessons from your study or
that would
relate yeah definitely um I think the
high deer pressure
is a really big concern in reducing the
native the native species that we'd
prefer to regenerate the forests um
instead it looks like there are a couple
exotic trees that might are invasive
trees that might be taking the place of
our native trees um but yeah I think
it's my research really just supports
the the fact that tree regeneration
is a big concern native trees just are
at a disadvantage given the really high
deer
densities that's sort of a related
question
about
um you know the Regeneration of of
canopy trees and I'm wondering in your
analysis you know some of these trees
are too big for the be so they're
whatever is controlling their cover is
is not
um so I'm wondering in your analysis you
focusing just on under species that the
could actually yes yes I was just
focusing on what's going on in the
underst story although some of the
species were you know black cherry maple
and Oak in in the underst story but
those species were much more common
where deer were
excluded yeah I'm kind of related to
that I guess it seems like I don't know
if you explicit looked you just
mentioned High light environments but it
seems like you know the HED Fern is
coming in there there's light reaching
the fourth floor
right so I don't know if you looked at
that
independently I didn't specifically look
at light environment um yeah so the
comments I was making earlier anecdotal
um it seems that
highlight could increase certain
invasive plants um but a lot of these
unpalatable species that are more common
such as the Japanese tilt grass and
garlic mustard are tolerant of low light
but I think they must have those anti-
erbivore
characteristics in order to to persist
even in the face of
deer okay one last question
Janice
de um on your first point there there
have been some studies showing that deer
are dispersing a lot of these invasive
plants including Japanese still grass
which was a big surprise to me but
definitely the fleshy FL fruited species
they're dispersing those into the into
the forest across the landscape um as
far as which species to plant I mean
definitely put up a fence around
anything you find really prized that's
what we've resorted to
Steve a quick
question not be quick but uh what how
does your work compared to what's
happened out in other like out in the
west there's obviously different
invasive plant species there and de
having an impact there have you compared
this ecosystem with other ecosystems and
and what's happening
elsewhere um just looking at the
literature it seems like my research is
in support of or are um congruent with a
lot of the other findings deer generally
reduced the palatable species increase
unpalatable species and if the
unpalatable species is exotic it
definitely Garners more attention and I
think what my research suggests and
especially with the hended fern and
there's other other literature too to
back up the hended fern native Invader
um kind of point so um yeah overall I I
think they're pretty similar in
findings one difference might be if not
just abundant herbivores are considered
but just herbivores in general and
herbivores in general actually have
somewhat different patterns but with
deer in our case they're very very
abundant so it's a little bit of a a
different scenario when you consider a
highly abundant native um species such
as deer
but we can talk more about that too
great thanks we're up thank you again
Christine this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu