this is a production of Cornell
University for those of you that don't
know me uh my name is Jason and I am the
coordinator for the insect Diagnostic
lab and the collection manager for the
Cornell University insect collection uh
so the two jobs wrapped into one uh what
I'll do over the next uh little while is
is discuss some of the things that I've
been getting uh over the past few months
in here um that might be of interest to
you and then I'm I'm very keen to hear
what you've been getting um and I'd be
Keen to get any questions that you might
have uh so don't be shy uh there's no
such thing is a stupid question I get a
lot of really good questions um from
people that submit things so I guess the
first thing that that comes to mind for
me it's very fresh in my mind um is
hemlock willia delid with which I'm sure
many of you have been experiencing it
just finally spread to my yard a few
days ago or at least I noticed it a few
days ago um and I I live in a
neighborhood where the neighborhood
association sent out a a strongly worded
email um warning against treating your
trees for hemlock adelgid um and one of
my concerned neighbors thought it was a
little sketchy that they were so
strongly against it and yeah I did a
fact check on it and just didn't stand
up on many levels um but I you know I
respect people's right to treat or not
treat uh my neighbor and I share two
hemlock trees and we we chatted over
barbecue last night that we will treat
them um and that the the cost benefit
analysis sort of uh strongly uh weighs
in favor of of treating them um probably
with thematic cloid um or some other uh
neonic uh has anybody else been seeing
um hamlock willly delid uh in their
counties
recently this is Joyce from Duchess
we've had it for years um because
especially along the Hudson River where
it's warmer was where we first saw a lot
of damage on some of the stately old
hemlocks along um with some of the um
historical sites it's come out
throughout the county and about every
third year there's another article and
one thing I would like to say is when
the article came out last year an
elderly couple came in and they were
almost ready to weep that they had this
wonderful hedge and it was going to be
destroyed and what would they do and I
took them outside to the hemlocks that
are here at our Farm and Home Center and
we've had hemlock willia delid for 5 10
years it's weakened the tree but I was
able to show them what to look for and
ask them to go Scout before they hired
someone to spray so if it's new to your
area I would say that that people
shouldn't
overreact and they should understand
what it is they're looking for and
understand that it doesn't necessarily
kill the things
overnight in my thank thanks Joyce I I'm
really Keen to hear what the mortality
is like in certain areas um now the two
trees that we are going to treat are
pretty weaken to start with um they
might not even be worth saving it's
debatable um but do you see um much
mortality at all like if you had to get
rough percentage what would you say what
would you say um what we what we see is
they thin over several years and get to
the point where they're starting to look
ratty enough that people take them down
the ones here at our building because
it's a county building there's they're
quite thin with maybe a third of the
tops gone and the bottoms are still
green enough that no one has deemed them
to be worthy of damage you know that
they're going to fall down or at at the
risk of causing damage okay thank you
and Jason here as a as a hiker and a and
a person who frequents trout streams I'm
seeing a lot of mortality on these big
old beautiful Hemlock forests on the
North Slopes in in uh in these kind of
you know more um untended areas and so
they go they do die
yeah no okay um well thank you for that
I'm I'm I'm really quite curious to see
sort of where the h locks are dying and
as as I think you guys have mentioned uh
I suspect it's not 100% mortality um and
you know I guess sort of as we're
experiencing with things like beach bark
disease we're going to eventually select
for more tolerant genotypes uh that will
survive uh the outbreak um and it is it
is sad to see some of these really old
State hemlocks go um and I'm just
curious to see what the potential
introduction of natural enemies will
eventually do to it um for those of you
are unaware uh there's a small Beetle
called lar cobius um that's been
introduced that loves Hemlock will delid
um and there's also a little camay fly
that we're looking at introducing the
interesting thing with the canel lied
fly uh it's not been recorded for New
York state but we do have specimens in
the collection from Pennsylvania so it's
pretty close by so uh it's more of a
jurisdictional thing that we have to see
permission to bring it into New York
State even though it probably does
already occur here it's just our
knowledge of smaller flies is pretty
sparse um now I was going to unless
there's further questions about Hemlock
Willie deled um there is a comment uh
about winter cutworms and I was quite
fascinated um by that
because um most of you probably have
realized a fairly recent invasive here
called noctua panuba the common name
unfortunately is the large yellow
underwing it's not related to any of our
native under wings it is a type of
cutworm but it's got bright orange hind
wings with the black border uh the
fourwing is quite variable in pattern it
can be from a dull orangish brown to a
modeled uh darker brownish almost black
um that species was introduced into
Halifax Nova Scotia uh that would have
been I think in the 70s and it sort of
sat in Nova Scotia as as a number of
invasives have uh and then for some
reason or another just boomed Westward
um and then in the early 1990s it showed
up in Ontario um I that's where I was
collecting moths when I was younger um
and it just became abundant immediately
and then within a few years I think by
the year 2000 it had made it right to
the Pacific coast um I've heard from
people that were doing uh experiments
here at Cornell that the year that
species showed up it just wiped out uh
various experiments uh it's just a
standard cut where I'm just like some of
our other uh pest species um but they're
quite noticeable in that the larvae are
sometimes active midwinter if you get a
a bout of warm weather or bout of
freezing rain or something that they
seem to come out and March around now
they can be separated from similar
cutworms that are native uh by they're
usually a little bit bigger um overall
that's sort of hard to judge though but
the the key character to look at is the
markings along the side of the body
you're going to see series of black
rectangles that go from about um a third
of the way back right to the very end um
and those um black rectangles are quite
prominent they're the only really
distinct marking and if you've got that
you've got noctua panuba I just want to
verify was that the winter cutworm you
were talking about yeah this was Joyce
and um because my focus is um is
consumer I had a woman call and said my
my beagles are eating these cat these
caterpillars she called them cutworms
and they're throwing up what are they
and are they poisonous so I'm going in
my little Diagnostic lab and looking
them up and she sent she actually had
she brought in the um the samples and
they were fast little buggers once they
got warm it was in January and I finally
emerged all happy and I went down to our
agriculture colleagues who said oh yeah
that's winter cutworm so they knew it
from a a crop um Pest and I had to
figure out it out by myself but it was
because it was in someone's lawn and the
dogs were um eating it and I did find a
University of Michigan article from
several years ago I think they're just
so active it causes the dogs to throw up
so that's how I learned about the winter
cutworm interesting I really like that
common name uh as you probably know with
insects common names unless it's a major
pest species are next to useless uh they
vary from place to place and I like that
name because it actually makes sense
because it is a type of cutworm um and
their most prominent winter you can find
them sort of pretty much any month of
the year they're multiv volting here
they have several Generations a year but
the winter they just really stick out
like a sore
thumb um that's really interesting and I
I do wonder if they're chemically
protected they might be um but I suspect
they're probably not um I get a lot of
queries here uh in the Diagnostic lab
from uh a few different organic
producers um so they or especially
Distributors where they buy organic
produce they distribute it uh it's sold
a customer finds a bug in their salad
and they complain um and sometimes
threaten to
Sue and the question that the
distributor wants to know well there's
three questions they want to know first
question is what is it second question
is where is it from and third question
is how dangerous is it and the first
answer uh it varies if they can send me
something or not usually it's a grainy
cell phone pick of a black Speck that
may or may not be an insect
um if they send me a specimen usually
can get some sort of name on it uh the
second question where is it from
unfortunately the answer almost always
is wherever that crop is grown because a
lot of these tests are pretty widespread
uh and the third answer um that I say
sort of semi sarcastically is Choice
edible uh most of these crop pests are
perfectly edible and you're unlikely to
die if you consume it uh there's been a
few where it's like okay yeah that will
make your stomach upset if you eat it
however as soon as your tongue hits it
it's going to realize that tastes really
bad um and it it's it's sort of amazing
to me how some consumers just overreact
to a bug in their salad um and and I
think it's really unfortunate and we
really need to educate people that you
know it's it's meat you know it's if
you're as long as you're not vegetarian
or vegan you know um it shouldn't be a
huge issue you just either throw the
salad out or and get a refund or you
know just ignore it kind of thing
um not not uh winter MTH this year or
not winter moth I don't mean that um a
winter cutor but we have we are now
dealing with like this spring uh
emergence of things like Stone flies and
and huge numbers we have a lot of
rivulets and streams and wet areas and I
had a pest Pro come in yesterday with
some Stone flies and he um the customer
wanted him to spray the entire outside
of his house to kill them all and they
were just you know resting on the yellow
sighing so we do get that kind of we
don't know what it is there's a lot of
it and shouldn't we just kill
it thigh and yeah sadly as you can
imagine I deal with those as well um two
of the more amable recent ones uh there
was um someone submitted springtails
that were all over her deck uh last year
and she wanted to know how to get rid of
them it's like well you couldn't nuke
your soil but I really don't recommend
it you know it's they they are natural
part of your soil you know get used to
it once it dries out they'll they'll be
gone but the the most dramatic example
was uh a pest control company in New
York City called me up and said okay
listen we're calling you up by By
Request of of our client we don't really
think there's any need to do anything uh
they sent me a photos of it what it was
is the top floor of a skyscraper um
adjacent to Central Park that on the
outsides of the windows that are not
openable there were euman wasps and lots
of them uh and the people that were um
working in the top floor of that
building wanted the building sprayed
because there are wasps on the outside
of the windows um and it just it baffled
me I had a very interesting chat with
the pest control operator and basically
uh encouraged to give them literature on
what these Newman wasps actually do um
and that they're not dangerous at all
especially since there's no way for the
people to be even in contact with them
it just it seems like the sight of them
was was just enough so I think what I'll
do I'll open it up to uh questions does
anybody have any specific questions for
me what this is Joyce talk to us about
folks this experience with earthworms
and or invasive earthworms what's going
on with
that so that's a really interesting
topic and I can't claim to be an expert
on it but it's a a topic that that's uh
near and dear to my heart um in New York
state as I'm sure many of you know there
are no native earthworms um they were
wiped out by the previous glacial period
they would have probably eventually made
it back here um the expansion rate for
Earths is typically about a meter or a
yard a year um depending on the species
um we either on purpose or by accident
have introduced a number of species of
earthworms into New York State um
originally from Europe um um and more
recently several Asian
species um now in the garden in general
and earthor is a great thing you know
they're good decomposed they build soil
fantastic um there's some strong
arguments that earthworms can be quite
detrimental to certain Forest systems um
and where I used to work up in alanin
park in Ontario where again there's no
native earthworms you can actually see
the expansion ring of where Earths have
been dropped in someone's Bait Bucket uh
on some of the Lakes um because there's
very limited settlement history there
there were no Earth rooms and people
have dumped bait buckets and you can see
a ring where the inside of the Ring The
Leaf litter lasts less than a season
after that the leaf litter accumulates
for about three years now the effects of
this is is it does change things so
first of all when you get rid of the
leaf litter yes you do have that
nutrient pulse but it also causes the
soil to dry out in the later summer
which is a drier time of the year up
there um which can dry out some of the
the soil organisms as well as some of
the seedlings it does also change over
probably long periods of time the force
composition so with that typical um
three-year Duff layer up there um only
really big seeds get established uh or
really um uh um well nure seeds so
things like sugar maple and Beach are
the dominant trees other things like uh
Eastern hamlock Yellow Birch uh and
Eastern White Pine either depend on
disturbance like small ground fires or
getting established on rocks and logs as
they commonly are up there um so this is
changing the composition to favor um
some of these smaller seeded trees and
also uh further south and Southern
Ontario it's favoring things like ash
which now is being nailed by Emerald
ashbo so it's it's definitely having an
impact there in studies in Michigan
they're showing that certain types of
betrium some of the the grape ferns that
are quite rare are being negatively
affected by it they also depend on thick
Duff layers uh of leaves to to protect
them from competition from other sort of
smaller seeded plants um so the effects
depend on what habitat you're talking
about but definitely they are changing
my suspicion is that they're really
changing the invertebrate composition of
leaf litter in Forest systems um case
and point that uh before earthworms are
here probably the biggest macro
decomposers of dead leaves on the forest
floor were specific types of
caterpillars uh there's whole group of
caterpillars called heriones they're
called Leaf litter moths they're still
around they're still fairly common but
they probably were the major decomposers
but they're not as efficient as
earthworms this kept a very complex
intact habitat lots of habitat for
things like uh ground beetles and other
insects that live in the soil so I
suspect there's some huge effects now as
far as Earths getting um dispersed
they're very easy to disperse especially
you know bringing soil in things like
that but uh in studies done in Northern
Alberta they found that you can find
earthworms um speckled uh along the
distribution of logging roads and that
earthworm eggs really strongly adhere to
the tread of truck tires and so trucks
are Distributing them just by just by
driving from places with Earths to
places
without uh does that sort of um answer
your questions
this is oh Joyce did did you want to
answer thank you because for the others
listening it is interesting when someone
calls up and says on a rainy day and
says my lawn is moving what do I do well
healthier lawn I don't know it's
Earth well go ahead and you brought
something up Jason and as as we are
we're talking to folks about creating
backyard biodiversity and building
habitat things like ground beetles that
are great Predators you know they're
losing they're kind of losing their
habitat because of these worms and you
know understanding those beetles a
little bit more and knowing what they
like I think that you know it's part of
our part of our messaging how do you how
do you build good habitat in your
backyard and it sounds like they need
Brushy kind of cover um and loose debris
that they can hide and and hang out
in um and and I think uh there's there's
two points I want to make here um that
that uh discussion is spurred uh one is
um why you see earthworms crawling
around on the surface of the ground on
rainy days uh I used to believe uh as do
I think many other people that it was
because oh well it's raining they'll
drown down there that's actually not
true they actually can survive perfectly
fine as long as the soil is not
constantly saturated they can do just
fine uh in fact I recall going for a
hike back in my undergrad and just
pondering how do earthworms cross
streams and then looking down as I was
crossing a bridge and seeing earthworms
in the bottom of the stream wiggling
along it's like oh okay that's how they
swim um the real reason why they come
out on really rainy days is most species
use that as a time to mate and disperse
and so it's much more efficient to
travel across the surface of the ground
than underground and because it's
raining it's moist enough that they're
not going to get too desiccated being uh
above ground so that's the main
dispersal thing uh the second thing was
on ground beetles and um um I'm sure
most of you have seen them if you want
to see how common ground beetles are in
an area go out at night get a headlamp
and just shine at the ground they have
really distinctive ey shine it's two
dots that will look right back at you if
you see six or eight dots those are
typically wolf spiders also quite common
at night if you sample the uh ground
Beetles the cbids of your backyard
unfortunately what you'll find unless
you're out in a pristine wild area is
most of the dominant species are
European in origin uh they've really
taken over uh especially in in uh
Disturbed habitats uh and especially in
agricultural habitats now if you want to
promote ground beetle diversity in your
backyard basically you need a place for
them to hide most of the species that
are there um are nocturnal and during
the day they hide under logs and rocks
and what I always advise people when I
especially when I do Master Gardener
trainings when I talk about how to um
promote having uh beneficial insects in
your Gardens like ground beetles is have
a place for them to live you know
surround your garden by things like
cobblestones cobblestones are great any
sort of rocks any sort of debris that
they can go under during the day is
fantastic and and the cool thing about
that is for people that that are really
curious about what's there at night is
you can lift those cobblestones up and
have a look at all the things that hide
there during the day and the majority of
those things will be beneficial insects
uh or at least neutral now some things
like some of the cutworms will use that
but uh on the balance I'd say it's it's
generally beneficial to have places for
things to hide the number one enemy to a
lot of these beneficial insects is just
Lawns um Lawns are just biodiversity
deserts
really any comments or further questions
on that on that or something
else this is Joyce I'm sorry to be noisy
I have a photo of the cutworm if I could
share can someone give me the ball
interesting um see it yeah now to me
that actually might not be noctua panuba
it's hard to tell so it does have those
rectangles but they're just not quite
right that might be another one called
speed Lotus
clandestina um and the clandestine Dart
um I'm sure it has another common name
as well which is a native species I I'd
have to compare to literature on that
one when when I looked at them um yeah
when I looked at it I threw it out and
then when I called her I said send me
photos so these are the only two photos
I have but this is what her dog was
eating wow um so yeah I'm not sure um
I'd have to see cutworm identification
can be
challenging um it's probably not to a
perua yeah it's probably knocked to a
perua I we have a lot of folks emailing
us photos now
um we've gotten past the um asking them
to put the ants on the phone so that
they can tell us what who they are so
they're sending us photographs um and
then we oh generally we always try to
get them to follow up with a sample or
stop by um because I think that people
are going more and more to the internet
to just um you know they trolling
they're go they're just finding
everything and then they're getting
really confused and uh you know they got
this thing and then when you look into
it it's you know only from South America
and you know are you you getting a lot
of that too I mean I Jason are you're
getting a lot of samples via
photo uh absolutely um that's becoming
i' I've been here for four years and I'd
say even in that short time it's it's
drastically increased and I encourage
people to submit photos because uh quite
often we can at least alleviate some of
their fears um one of the most common
things people you know submit to the
Diagnostic lab is uh they are worried
about bed bugs and so they'll send a
photo of a dermed and right away I can
say okay no that's not a bed bug it's a
dermed you could submit it I can tell
you what kind and where you might want
to look for it kind of thing uh I had an
interesting question yesterday I was
giving a collection tour to a soils
class and one of the students asked me
okay so we have this lovely thing called
the internet and Google why should
people submit something to the
Diagnostic lab and
uh my answer was quite similar to yours
that well for some things absolutely you
got a big showy butterfly you can
consult the internet and probably get a
reasonable answer for it um especially
if you've got a background to entomology
you can sort of figure out or know the
reputable websites but you can find
there's as you all know there's so much
garbage out there um so for instance
when someone submit springtails I send
them a little blur back on springtails
and what to do uh you know kind of thing
um but always have to put the caveat by
the way springtails do not breed under
your skin and if you Google springtails
unfortunately you will find articles
that say yes they do you'll also find
articles that say they're government
conspiracies and that they're implanting
fibers in your brain and controlling
things now granted most people will sort
of laugh at the last few but there's a
few that go down that route and I spend
a fair bit of time on the phone um
especially in the winter with people
that have gone uh you know down the
rabbit hole and it can be really
challenging to convince them that well a
I'm not part of the conspiracy um and B
that some of these websites are you know
blowing hot air that there's there's
really nothing to it um say that I think
it is really valuable and and for some
people that submit stuff I'm just
surprised that they didn't Google it
like some of them are just so obvious um
like if you have
uh let's say a pest on your hibiscus uh
it's it's pretty easy to Google pest
hibiscus and there's a good chance
you'll get a reasonable answer um not
always but but usually um and some just
you know submit really distinctive
things and the ones that I find don't
use the Googles and talk to me first uh
tend to be sort of on the older end of
things and just not so internet Savvy um
and some of the the the ones that um are
are really susceptible to paranoia tend
to not even have email um so I have to
uh talk to them either in person or or
on the
phone I'll have one more with what seems
to be an early spring we here in the
Hudson Valley have all sorts of things
blooming and the Red Wings black birds
are back what do you think we will
see will we see more activity earlier
activity um what can we anticipate in
terms of calls and and um oh my goodness
what is this in terms of of early
spring oh very difficult question um so
as you know it's really hard to Crystal
Ball these sort of things um with an
earlier season what I would guess is
that certain migratory species that
become pests uh things like uh cornerer
worm army worm they might be able to get
here earlier and uh establish sooner um
now the big years that we have for those
typically correspond with really warm
Winters further south um and ideal
conditions for them that aren't too wet
uh and I think that's the case so we may
see more uh larger numbers of that
another one that sort of falls into this
pattern is Diamond Back moth where
they're also generally migratory there
are some exceptional individuals that
can over winter um further north like
even in New York state there are records
of that um but it's certainly not nor
this year might be different we only had
at least here in Tomkins County we only
had a few quite cold days but that might
not have been cold enough to kill off
things like diamond back moth so it just
sort of advances the season they might
be able to squeeze in another generation
uh and become more of a problem that way
um otherwise it really depends on how
much moisture because the other thing
that was quite striking about this
winter uh at least here um in Tomkins
county is the very little snow that we
got um and the cold snaps seem to really
hit the ground quite hard so you
probably noticed a lot of needle ice
this year if you have bare patches of
ground where you get these sharp uh icy
needles that pop up with soil capping
them that's basically uh a condition you
get when you've got no snow cover cold
snap and basically water through
capillar action comes up for the soil
and forms these needles that's really
quite damaging to a lot of insects that
just overwinter in the leaf layer uh in
years where you have a lot of snow cover
um and the winter is not exceptionally
cold you actually have insects and
especially spiders active all winter
long underneath the snow um and that
certainly probably wasn't the case at
least during the cold days um this
winter since there was essentially no
snow up here um so my long-winded answer
or the short version of my long-winded
answer is it's hard to say but I expect
a few more pests will get an early head
start this year what is the forecast for
blacklegged
tick ah um blacklegged ticks um also
known as deer
ticks um I don't know um I I found very
few this winter like uh in previous
Winters uh if I'd go out I'd get a few
on me e on warm days in the winter even
if it was just slightly below freezing
you'd still get the odd tick uh I've
seen none this year I know that's just
an anecdote I don't have any real data
to support that so I don't know um I
think the only way we'll find out is
just by experiencing it um I'm more
familiar with some of the other tick
species up north and the big things that
seem to knock them back um were uh the
fall conditions and I'm trying to
remember back to what our fall was like
um the fall conditions being
exceptionally cold and damp were not
friendly to to the ticks if they were
warm Dry Falls they seem to do really
well that winter I suspect it's probably
similar for blacklegged tick so I my
short answer is I don't know are there
any um any kind of hot pests that you
hope you don't get any samples of that
we should be on the lookout for uh hot
pest so we don't get samples out that we
should be of that we uh should be
looking out for um there's quite a few
um bark beetles um that I've been
showing up um it's I went to a bark
Beetle workshop two years ago in Florida
and it was disturbing how many new
species show up every year especially in
the Southeast but also up here um and
they can go undetected for many years um
so there's a number of bark beetles that
I would worry about but but quite
frankly at this point we have so many
non-native bark beetles here it's it's
um except for for specific ones I
wouldn't worry too
much um
down towards Long Island um Southern
pine beetle has seemed to spread North
and is nailing a lot of the Pines there
I don't know how far north that one will
get um that's really hard to predict
that and at least with the w Western
counterpart the mountain pine beetle
it's really highly dependent on a lot of
old
trees um and warm Winters and again this
is probably a fairly warm winter so it
it might have spread a bit further north
I don't know how far far nor it will get
though um as far as other things go um I
really don't know um there is a new
longhorn beetle that's has shown up um
near New York City uh in Westchester
County um and the unfortunate thing is
it's so indistinctive that the way to
key it out is it lacks all the
distinctive spe features of all the
other
species um and it's
it's been well established in that yard
um and I think it's probably going to
spread Now is it going to be a pest on
trees maybe uh it seems mostly be
emerging from firewood um but there is
some evidence at least in Utah where
it's established uh that it can affect
uh fruit trees
negatively um beyond that um your guess
is as good as mine I really don't know
and I just need to be we all need to be
prepared for anything that's sort of new
and when I'm asked the question okay how
do you prepare for the next invasive and
the thing I advise people is be familiar
with what's in your backyard and if
something looks different be suspicious
because these new invasives that become
a problem they tend to show up and show
up very drastically and suddenly and so
they'll stick out to to a lot of people
should we expect any negative impacts to
some of our garden beneficials due to
the lack of snow cover a good question
um I'd say probably yes and probably no
it all depends on the species uh the
thing with a really healthy garden um
the beneficial insects should be diverse
um both in diversity of species and
diversity of families and Orders of
insects uh if you depend on one species
let's say one type of ground beetle um
chances are some event will knock them
all back uh with this this weird winter
where we had almost no snow cover and
when it got cold there was no snow cover
it seemed um yeah some of the things
will be negatively affected the thing
with uh a lot of our native species
though is they are adapted to this for
the most part and yeah some will get
knocked back some won't um and insect
populations will fluctuate so that's my
wishy-washy answer of maybe maybe not
depending somewhat kind
of can you highlight some of the your um
preferred sites uh for Gathering some
information on their own so I'll point
out a few things so as l mentioned the
insect Diagnostic lab if you Google
insect Diagnostic lab Cornell you'll
find us uh we do have fact sheets um for
a lot of different insects um so you can
click on that and there is is
information a lot of different groups um
also there's information uh if people
want to submit samples to us or you've
got a client that wants to submit to us
um if it's a really difficult sample
here's the information for it how to
send it uh it's really key uh key to
emphasize that I need the information on
where it's from when it's from kind of
thing uh and also to package it
appropriately it's disturbing how many
people it will put an insect uh wrap it
up in a Kleenex put it in an envelope
and send it through the mail and expect
me to piece together a thousand pieces
of insect and try to identify it um so
always make sure they put it into some
sort of crush proof container so um
that's sort of the Shameless
self-promotion aspect of it um other
than that um bug guide um so bug
guide.net if you've never used this
website use it it's fantastic um my bias
is I am one of the editors on this
website but basically what you can do so
if you you're completely clueless you
have no idea what you can do go to ID
request um you have to set up an account
is free um and you uh basically add an
image you submit an image and depending
on what it is it can be identified in a
few minutes or sometimes a few years it
all depends um but usually someone will
move it to an appropriate place
how I use it a lot um is if you go to
the guide uh you can pick your your
insect group uh um let's say insects uh
be let's pick Beetles for now um you can
go to taxon pick the family that you
want um let's say you've got some sort
of scare Beetle and you want help
identifying it you can go to images I'll
just show you General images but if you
go to browse it shows you the different
subfamilies so you can can quickly
browse it let's say okay I think I've
got an aod IR uh dung beetle okay it
narrows it down further you can click on
that and go right down to species and
for each species you know there'll be an
in uh an image uh the info for it and
some of them will have elaborate
information on on it um and sort of
habitat stuff some will have a lot more
information some will have links and
this is where it gets really useful you
can see the links where you can get more
information for proper identification so
if you went to fods you'll see that link
is is the really good one to identify
things to gener and then the species it
depends um also for each species so you
can also Google let's say um you've got
something on
fraxinus caterpillar this sometimes can
work and so it gives you some of these
images let's say you go to this one okay
yeah it kind of looks like that look at
the range so where they've got specimens
from ah it's an Eastern thing it's in
New York okay that's reasonable here's
the the time you see it um sort of thing
so this is um I think one of the most
useful resources um for it um not just
uh that but also will link to other
useful resources so for this particular
species here's a link to moth
photographers Group which has
information another website so several
websites that have um further
information
um so basically beyond that start with
bug guide and it will if it doesn't have
the answer it'll link you to the answer
and of course you can always uh submit
to the insect Diagnostic lab um as a
general rule for um people related to
the
CCE uh if uh you don't want to pay the
$25 if you just want a yes or no answer
I will do that for free um but for a
what is this answer um I'll I do charge
for that um as long as if you're
expecting yes or no answer if if maybe
is an acceptable answer then then yeah I
can I can usually do those for free and
um especially if it's something U rather
quick like
that and you can find my contact info
through the insect Diagnostic lab or
just Google me I'm always Keen to hear
what um uh various Educators get in uh
other counties because for a lot of the
things that are easier to identify I
just I never hear about it um they just
don't come across to to me very often so
uh thank you so
much this has been a production of
Corell University on the web at
cornell.edu