good afternoon everyone welcome to the
7th of 12 Berry soil and nutrient
management webinar sponsored by the
Northeast sustainable research and
education program better known as
Northeast s and hosted by Cornell
University Department of horticulture
and Cornell Cooperative Extension my
name is Kathy Henrich and I'll be your
moderator for this
webinar just wanted to let you know that
today's speaker is Dr Mark pritz who's
professor and chair of the Department of
horticulture at Corno University and the
topic is nutrient management and
established
plantings
Marvin guess there's a delay in program
loading hang on and it should be up in
just a
second okay good afternoon everyone and
Welcome to our sixth webinar uh this
webinar is on interpreting foler
analysis and this gets a little bit
complicated and it's not something that
computers can you know we can develop
recommendations for very easily so what
we want to do today is uh walk you
through various ways of interpreting
soil analysis and give you a sense of
what you might want to look for when you
get these
results Just A Brief Review from last
time uh the time of lease sampling
varies slightly between the berry crops
but mostly it's uh Late July and early
August when you take the leaf samples
and send them in for
analysis uh in the last couple of weeks
I was able to find some data to show you
what happens to values of nutrient
concentrations of certain elements over
the growing season and this is old data
and an old slide but early on in the
season this is with Boron uh we found
that the levels start off pretty high
and then they drop during the season and
they stabilize somewhere after August uh
to a a level that's uh lower and more
stable for the rest of the
season and the same thing uh was true
for leaf zinc uh values start high they
go down and they stabilize later in the
later part of the season when we don't
have a lot of fruit being produced this
is up with strawberry so again that's
why we recommend at certain times of the
year we take the samples when we don't
have uh large changes in values from
week to
week there are standard Fuller nutrient
ranges for all the ber crops and these
are generally accepted uh no matter
where you're at they're pretty standard
across the board uh different climates
different soils uh that's makes it ni
for interpreting these things one thing
you'll notice when you compare
strawberries to raspberries is that
there's very little difference between
the two uh both are rosaceous plants the
accepted values are pretty much the same
for both of them so again it sort of
indicates that the plants are growing in
similar ways accumulating nutrients to a
similar amount and uh these are
indicative of healthy levels of plants
that are growing
normally blueberries are a little bit
different though if we compare those
with raspberries or strawberries the
critical values for blueberries are
usually quite a bit lower than they are
for strawberries and raspberries and one
of the things to keep in mind when
you're using a soil and leaf Testing Lab
that doesn't know much about blueberries
is they'll often use a standard that
would be appropriate for strawberries or
raspberries and and Truth me many other
crops have those similar ranges of
strawberries and raspberries for example
Alfalfa and they'll use those to base
the recommendations on but really they
need to be adjusted downward quite a bit
for blueberries uh blueberries just have
a much lower nutrient requirement than
many other crops they grow more slowly
they don't require as much nutrient
critical levels in leaves are are much
lower in most cases so just keep that in
mind if you uh see you know giving
nutrient recommendations that don't seem
right uh it maybe that they're using the
wrong standard that hasn't been adjusted
for
blueberries there is one exception in
the the blueberry side of things and
that's with manganese and uh it's not
going to have much of an impact on your
interpretation except you might see high
manganes values in blueberries
occasionally and for other crops that
might signal a problem like oh maybe
manganese is becoming toxic but in
blueberries it's not a problem
blueberries have evolved uh tolerance to
high levels of Manganese they take that
manganese and they stick it into vacul
and isolate it from the rest of the
plant so when you grind that leaf and
analyze it you see lots of Manganese
there but really it's not hurting the
plant and blueberries evolved tolerance
for that uh for a couple of reasons one
is if you recall a few webinars ago we
looked at the
availability of Manganese when the pH
changes and at low pH levels manganese
levels tend to be higher so blueberries
grow in acid soils so we would expect
more maganese to be available but the
other thing that happens is uh
blueberries evolved in soils that tend
to flood frequently and in flooded soils
you don't have very much oxygen oxygen
diffuses very slowly in water log soils
and when oxygen isn't available you have
this these electrons moving around and
if the oxygen is not available to be an
acceptor for that electron that electron
has has to go somewhere so like the next
thing that it goes to is manganese and
there's a in the soil a lot of magnes is
available in the form of four pluses one
of the veence states but when you throw
electrons at it it converts to the
manganese 2 form that manganese 2 form
is the biologically active form so all
of a sudden uh in flooded soils you get
a lot of this maganese to form and it's
rapidly taken up by the plant and it's
biologically active and blueberries take
that and they put it in a vacu and
isolate it from the rest of the plant so
it doesn't become
toxic so just so you know if you see
that looks odd it's probably not going
to be a problem unless it gets really
really high inside the
plant
now the foler analysis will give you
values of leaf nutrients that just don't
show up in the soil test remember we
sort of discounted levels of Manganese
iron and zinc and copper and soil is not
being very meaningful uh but the
probability of being
deficient uh is varies it's not the same
for all the nutrients some nutrients
you're more likely to see uh deficient
than
others so uh nitrogen uh we rarely see
it low uh most Growers fertilize fairly
well with nitrogen and in fact we often
see it above the critical value that we
need so Growers put on nitrogen often
times more than they really need and
leaf analysis comes back showing us a
little bit of High We R rarely see it
low same way with phosphorus and our
soils particularly in the Northeast
where there have been lots of dairy
farms in the past and people have used
manure to fertilize Fields phosphorous
levels are generally pretty high and we
rarely see it uh below the critical
value
potassium we sometimes see low on
lighter
soils excuse me calcium sometimes see it
low uh but not a real probability of it
happening a lot particularly if the pH
is within the appropriate range
magnesium that'll sometimes uh show up
as deficient particularly in blueberry
Fields manganese will show up as
deficient uh somewhat frequently
particularly in fields that were once
wet and then we're Dr drain for some
reason there's just not a lot of
manganese in those
soils iron um it's low um Iron is a very
very common element in the soil it's
rarely that there's insufficient iron in
the soil usually if you see iron
deficiency it's generally a problem with
ph Boron though is an element that is
frequently low in the Northeast in fact
the Atlantic Coastal Plain soils tend to
be very low in boron it's one of the
areas of the world where Boron tends to
be deficient um parts of Ontario and
Canada also
deficient it's probably the one we see
most commonly deficient in leaf analysis
is
boron excuse me uh zinc uh and when
phosis is high sometimes zinc is
low and in Copper you see it um low
sometimes deficient is particularly in
soils that are high or organic
matter there's a question about aluminum
aluminum is really sporadic um around
and so
it's toxicity U can be high in low PH
soils uh generally if the pH is within a
normal range we don't see aluminum
toxicity even if there's a lot of
aluminum in the soil where we tend to
see aluminum be a problem is when we
lower the pH for blueberries and we
release less of aluminum sometimes then
we'll see that becoming toxic
foler tests are really useful for
adjusting the fertility program uh but
only when plants are healthy and the
soil pH is adequate the foler test
doesn't really do much good if there's a
disease in the soil or the plants aren't
growing well it's a really good way to
fine-tune the fertility program but not
really make use that as a sole guide for
wholesale
adjustments we use a Fuller analysis we
want to make sure that the soil is
generally adequate in nutrients
the plants are growing well then it's
really good for making adjustments but
if you just have a soil analysis alone
it often doesn't give you enough
information to develop a recommendation
from what I do whenever I look at the uh
Fuller test results I go through a
series of about five or six
steps that um one after the other to
help with that and the first thing I do
is I want to ensure that the soil pH is
within the correct range if it's not
that'll throw off the Fuller testing
value so if you just looked at the soil
test you might say well I have to add
four or five nutrients to the soil
because my leaves show me deficient but
really a simple adjustment in PH might
correct those problems so you you want
to make sure the soil pH is right before
you jump to conclusions about what is
lacking in the
soil the other thing is make sure that
uh there's nothing else that could be
limiting the plant growth if you have
diseases in the soil or or something
eating the roots or something's just not
right uh the full a test isn't really
going to be that useful in helping to
diagnose the problem or making
Corrections plants have to be growing
relatively healthily uh for the Fuller
test to be
meaningful the third thing I do
particularly since uh we live along the
Atlantic coast and the soils tend to be
low on Boron is to check the status of
boron Boron we talked a couple webinars
ago about how Boron is essential for
root growth and root elongation so if
you have low Boron and your roots aren't
growing that means you can't take the
plant can't take up other nutrients so
the boron has to be adequate for the
other nutrients to be um taken up so
that's the third thing I
check then if all those things check out
then I'll look at the specific nutrients
in the leaf analysis and see if they
might be
deficient sort of the last thing I'll do
is there's a few interactions that you
might want to might check out to make
sure that things are in are in balance
and we'll talk about what some of those
are in a second but they can exacerbate
low nutrient levels and again this gets
a little bit complex at this point this
is why sometimes just looking over it
yourself is better than having some
computer plow through it and try to
tease these apart I'll give you some
examples in a minute where we can look
at that
we're going to cover three scenarios one
is when the leaf test and the soil tests
sort of tell you the same story and
that's good we'll look at a situation or
two where soil tests are low for
nutrient yet the leaf analysis is normal
how can that be what's going on there
well we'll talk about that and
conversely when the soil test is high
for a nutrient yet the leaf test is low
what's going on how can that be we'll
talk about some of the situations
so I've got 12 scenarios I want to go
through and most of these are based on
real soil and leaf analysis
tests so this is the first example
strawberries uh good growth and yield
and we want to look down here and uh we
have a soil test uh things look pretty
good in the soil Boron is adequate pH is
good organic matter is good Leaf
analysis is
normal it kind of tells you that hey
what you've been doing is working
everything looks appropriate and good
the plants are growing well so you're
fine just keep up what you've been doing
everything should be fine so this is
what we like to
see no problems everything looks
good uh go to a second example these are
blueberries and again we'll just look at
the leaf analysis here and see what's
going on here and we see normal npn K
high
calcium normal magnesium
but then we we see low maganese iron
copper and
zinc and when you see these four in
particular low that's a pretty good
indication that it's not that they're
low in the soil it's that they're in the
soil they just can't be taken up by the
plant because the pH isn't
right and if you look at the pH here
it's a little bit too high in
blueberries we need to lower that pH and
by lowering that pH it it'll basically
automatically increase the values of
zinc copper iron and manganese just
automatically because the availability
will suddenly go up and these levels of
leaf uh nutrients should go up as well
so don't be tricked don't think well
I've got to go out and find some source
of Manganese and iron and copper and
zinc to add to the blueberry planting
check pH almost guaranteed it's going to
be too
high strawberries
tyoga soil River Bottom soil this is an
actual Leaf analysis and when we look at
that normal values VP K uh everything
else is normal but we see low calcium
and magnesium H well what might be going
on here do we need to add calcium and
magnesium well sort of U but this is a
pretty good indication that the pH is
too
low so in this case we want to add
probably lime and probably high
magnesium lime that'll increase the ph
and also increase the plant's ability to
take up calcium magnesium but a pretty
good clue if you just saw the leaf
analysis alone that when calcium and
magnesium are low that's probably an
indication that the pH is too low as
well uh question came up is sulfur part
of a normal Leaf analysis no it is not
there's a separate test is required for
nitrogen and then a separate test test
that does all the other nutrients except
for sulfur uh the nitrogen test is
fairly expensive uh you got to have it
those since it's so critical the other
nutrient test is fairly expensive you
put them together it's going to cost you
about 30 bucks if you want to do sulfur
it's going to cost about another 15
bucks it's probably not worth it uh
because sulfur and nitrogen track very
closely together so most of the time we
don't do sulfur analysis particularly
because it's rarely ever defici
there's lots of sulfur around there's
lots of sulfates around sulfur is coming
down in the rain it's in most of the
soils it's in fertilizers that we apply
so it's just something it's just not
worth testing for for the most
part okay take another look here we got
blueberries we've got low
nitrogen in the leaves um soils look
pretty good nothing really low here
borons medium pH is
kind of on the high side for blueberries
not too high uh everything's normal but
we have some low iron and copper and
zinc the primary cause for the low
nitrogen might not again be we have to
go out and add nitrogen but in this case
here this a very weedy field and we have
lots of weeds that can suck nitrogen out
of the soil and give us a low Leaf value
now the grower probably doesn't have to
do anything different in terms of the
nitrogen management just manage the
weeds better and that nitrogen level
should go up the pH probably should go
down just a little bit and when the pH
goes down that'll increase the zinc and
the copper and the iron so looking at
this whole picture two things lower the
ph and manage the weeds a little bit
better and that's really pretty uh
simple thing to do and that'll mostly
most likely bring everything back into
balance okay example five raspberries
kinesia soil poor
growth go back to soil
test a few things are low here um
calcium magnesium
medium pH is okay organic matter is good
Leaf analysis everything looks
fine um but the plants aren't growing
well what do we conclude from
this well we conclude that whatever is
wrong with that planting causing a poor
growth probably isn't
nutritional so we look for something
else so again this is a case where the
leaf and soil analyses don't really tell
us much about what's going on with that
plant we've got to correct the other
factor that might be limiting growth
before the soil and leaf analysis tell
us any valuable information
okay let's look at some
strawberries uh a soil here and um we
look at the
soil everything's looking good
everything's fairly High am out um
boron's that's sort of like the
threshold for Boron pH is good organic
matter is pretty
good see what might be going on
here this let me turn this off
the here uh the leaf analysis is fine
but the plants still aren't healthy but
when we look at the field we can see
that the plants have black root Rod or
some Weevil or something like that
eating the the roots of the plant so
again this is a situation where the soil
test looks fine the leaf analysis looks
fine but it doesn't tell us what's going
on what happens most of the time when
plants are compromised with disease they
don't grow very much so the leaf values
generally are Norm more high in plants
that are diseased because they just
aren't growing so it's not difficult for
the plant to accumulate the nutrients it
needs but that doesn't tell you what's
wrong with the
plant that's why you have to look at
both the foler analysis soil test and
the health of the planning because
unhealthy plants almost all always have
good folar nutrient levels when there's
something else that's causing the poor
growth okay let's take a another example
here we've got medium levels of
phosphorus and potassium in the
soil PH a little bit low organic matter
is good what might be going on
here well let's look at the leaf
analysis and see if it gives us a
hint this is an actual test uh that we
got from soil and leaf and here Boron is
a little bit below the threshold before
we like to see it and the leaf Boron is
low and you can see that reflected over
here in the foler test results it's sort
of at the low end and because we don't
have Boron we don't have good root
growth often times that leads to low
levels of some of these other nutrients
that require good root growth to be
taken up at high
levels so in this case here the
recommendation should probably say uh
raise the ph a little bit and certainly
apply some Boron because that's what we
need to do in order to make this
correction okay example 8
here we have high levels of phosphorus
potassium calcium
magnesium and again based on that last
example you'll say oh boron's low and
yeah it is low here the pH is fine
organic matter is fine let's look and
see how that affected the leaf
analysis remember look up it's a well-
drained soil in a dry
year what the leaf analysis shows in
this case is that even though we have
high potassium and high
calcium the levels in the leaf are low
so high levels in the soil but low
levels in the
leaf why is that well uh probably a
couple of reasons one is boron is low
and we have low Boron we have poor root
growth we don't often have the uptake
that we would expect and secondly it was
a very dry year and a lot of these
nutrients particularly
calcium and potassium some extent get
taken up by mass flow so they get
dissolved in the water when the plant
transpires the water moves into the
plant and brings along the dissolve
nutrient in that water stream when we
don't have water when it's dry that just
doesn't happen so we end up with low
levels
so it's possible in many cases to have
high soil test values but low Leaf
values and usually it's because of low
Boron or inadequate water or sometimes
both
nitrogen is low in this case uh again we
don't test for that in the soil but here
they might be uh a need for an increased
level of nitrogen fertilizer in this
situation what impact would pore
drainage have on foler values uh what
that often does is uh poor drainage
sometimes increases the level
of the the copper and the zinc and the
manganese we talked earlier with the
example of blueberries how you have
water loged soils manganese levels go
way up almost to toxic levels and that's
one of the first things you see happen
in a planning where you have water log
soils or po dranes manganes levels get
really high that's one of the first
signs but otherwise uh sometimes you
know it stops the plant from growing uh
because the soils are water logged and
the leaf nutrients levels can come to
normal within normal range uh and you
look at it you say well I don't really
see anything wrong here the leaf levels
look normal but the plant's not growing
because the soil's water log that's why
I'm uh saying you have to look at the
big picture and not just look at the
foler analysis because that can be
normal when you have these other impacts
going
on okay let's look at uh another example
here raspberries kinesia soil very heavy
crop load exceptionally heavy crop load
of the summer
raspberries soil looks
fine everything's High Boron is
adequate critical value is around one
pound per acre uh pH is perfect organic
matter is
high we do a leaf
analysis everything's good except a
potassium is showing up as low so why is
pottassium low when the soil values are
high and this is reflected over here in
the leaf analysis again actual test but
if you
recall fruiting takes a lot of potassium
from the plant in years where you have
heavy heavy fruit
load and you test for folar nutrients
shortly after Fring you'll often see low
levels of potassium it doesn't mean you
have to add potassium fertilizer it just
means that you got to give the plant
time to recover and build back those
potassium levels so in this case here
probably the best thing to grower could
do is just ensure that there's adequate
moisture in the soil so that the
potassium levels can recover because it
looks like there's plenty in the soil to
be taken up the plant just needs time to
do that because it just went through a
really heavy uh cropping
load again a reason to understand the
big picture the cropping history uh
what's going on physically to the plant
as well as just look at the soil and
foler
test okay uh 10th example here's
strawberries they're exhibiting poor
growth but you look around you just
can't find any disease you can't find
any insect problems but the plants are
growing
poorly you look at a soil test you know
these are values are high high magnesium
is medium plenty of boron in the soil pH
is Right On Target organic matter is
reasonable um what's going on here why
do we have poor
growth uh we look at a fuller test and
we see you know some things are low
magnesium is low even though the soil
levels look adequate we have low iron
low
copper low zinc why do we have these low
values when the soil t show that most
things are
adequate well this is an example where
sometimes the soil nutrients can be too
high in this case um phosphorus is high
maybe from you know using too much manur
or too much phosphorous fertilizer in a
previous crop or in a previous year when
we have high levels of phosphorus in
particular phosphorus interacts with a
lot of these micronutrients and ties
them up it forms precipitates before
they even get in the plant there's even
evidence that inside the plant that
phosphorus can interact with nutrients
these micronutrients even after they get
into the plant uh phospher zinc is one
that's commonly written about in the
literature phosphorus is known to
interfere with iron uptake and copper
uptake
so more than likely in this situation
here this the high phosphorus is
actually causing problems and causing
low levels of these other nutrients
because of the interaction
these are some of the things you have
just kind of have to learn to watch out
for because the foler uh testing
recommendations that come back from a
lab aren't going to be able to give you
this level of
detail another negative interaction that
you often see is U real high calcium can
interfere with iron and this is
especially true in blueberries now this
example is strawberries but we talked
about this before that particular
blueberries high calcium is uh really
bad for blueberries it really does
interfere with iron not so much iron
uptake but the iron um when there's high
calcium on the iron is in the feric form
which is in the inactive form of iron in
plants as opposed to the feric plus two
form that's the active form so that's a
interaction that happens with the
veilance of the iron and it affects the
activity of the iron in the plant
but the phosphorus and the calcium are
the two you have to watch out for when
they come out at high levels uh that
could spell trouble for the
micronutrients so again soil tests are
important to make sure we don't exceed
the level of phosphorus and exceed the
level of calcium uh so we don't induce
these deficiencies later
on okay we're getting close to end here
uh blueberries poor growth okay here we
have both the soil test and the leaf
analysis results
looking through
here seeing what's going on
uh again uh this is one of those uh
interaction kind of things that we see
that in this case blueberries had poor
growth magnesium is low the leaves are
showing typical magnesium deficiency
symptoms but we really want to expect to
see that from the soil test because the
levels in the soil are
medium but we're seeing magnesium
deficiency and the reason for that is
that there are other nutrients that
basically compete with magnesium in the
plant and some of those are potassium
calcium and zinc to some extent
manganese will do it too because they
all have this you know calcium uh
manganese and zinc are plus two so they
will compete for bonding sites with the
Magnesium so this is a little bit more
subtle but again High values of certain
Leaf nutrients can suppress others and
in this case here it's what's going on
explains why we're seeing magnesium
deficiency in a leaf when there is
adequate magnesium in the soil too much
of other
things again it's subtle and it's not
really picked up with a recommendation
so you kind of have to watch out for
that
yourself and this is the last example I
wanted to review with you blueberries
very poor growth but again you look out
there there's just no disease what is
going on here uh soil test everything
looks pretty good everything is medium
or high Boron is adequate pH is adequate
organic matter is good
folar levels are normal or high for
everything you just no disease what's
going on how can you explain that well
when I see something like this that just
you know I can't figure out what's going
on with the nutrients I see I'll
sometimes go back and ask to look at
this complete soil test and the complete
foler analysis to look at all the
elements that are being reported uh so
I'm sorry the report you get shows you
essential nutrients but it doesn't show
you all of them and a question came up
earlier about aluminum like it doesn't
show a standard aluminum levels in
leaves or even soil in many tests but if
you ask for it often times the original
analysis has that number it's just not
reported on the report and you can go
back and look and see oh maybe aluminum
is present at really high levels and
it's actually causing a
toxicity so that's one thing you want to
look for sodium not so much in the
northeast or the Midwest but as you go
out further west you might want to look
at sodium levels again it's not standard
on a report but too much sodium can
raise Havoc with folar nutrient levels
and compete with sodium and cause all
sorts of problems and the same way with
soluble salts too much fertilizer too
much salt um can cause toxic problems in
the plant even though it doesn't reflect
it in the leaf nutrient values
so those are some of the examples you
might see and hopefully that is a a way
to help you interpret these foler
analysis that you get uh you can't
always rely on what the computer says it
doesn't go into the level of detail of
looking at interactions most foler
analyses don't tie back in with soil
tests so I can look at them both
simultaneously one of our goals at Coral
over the long run is to uh integrate the
soil tests with the leaf analysis and
include recommendations look at them you
get one recommendation based on both the
soil and leaf analysis and then can
account for some of these interactions
we talked about right now we don't have
that I don't know if anybody who does
that uh you kind of have to do that with
your own human brain and perform those
analyses and adjust the recommendations
that
way a question uh so soil compaction
have the same impact on foler values as
poor drainage uh not exactly compaction
doesn't alter the um amount of oxygen in
the soil as much as you might think I
mean it reduces it some but when you wet
it it really pushes the oxygen out of
the soil so you don't have that same
response with accumulating high levels
of magnes and stuff with compaction just
get poor root growth with in compacted
soils you know it's hard to predict what
you're going to get uh one outcome is
it's just poor growth but the plants
have adequate nutrients given their
small size uh and other as you'll see
deficiencies in certain nutrients um and
not others it's really hard to predict
specifically what the impact of
compaction would be I haven't seen any
consistent effect on folar nutrients
Alone by looking at
compaction the last uh PR principle that
I want to share with you is something
called the steam Burge
effect and this happens at low levels of
new nutrient and think about a situation
where you have a plant that has adequate
nutrients of everything except for one
nutrient let's just pick one at random
say say magnesium so very low levels of
magnesium and that's limiting growth
plants aren't growing well magnesium is
low so we start to add magnesium to the
plant or to the soil and the plant
starts to grow and we can see growth
increases as we add more and more
nutrient when the plant starts to grow
we often get what's called a dilution
effect and a plant grows so fast because
now all of a sudden it has magnesium
that foler levels actually drop even
though we're adding more nutrient to the
soil or to the plant the fer
concentrations drop that's because we're
stimulating growth so much and the
plants are growing faster than the rate
of uptake because that nutrient was
limiting before now it's not so limiting
the plants are really growing fast
so it sort of reverses and the levels
actually drop then uh you'll get to the
point where they start to behave
normally you go through the critical
concentration you reach a point where
not much happens as you add more and
more and more and as you get out a real
high end you get to be at the toxic
range where growth actually starts to
drop off again too much but this place
right in here is an interesting place to
be and we sometimes see this when values
are really really low we make a
recommendation a grower will add uh what
we tell them to do they come back to
next year and say and test again say hey
my foler values actually fell after I
did what you told me to do I don't know
trust you you know what you're talking
about well what's going on is you say
well how happened to growth well the
plants grew really well well that's what
happened the plants grew well diluted
out the levels of nutrient and again
until we're uh at a point where the
plants are looking good and growing well
and the yields are good that's why these
foler uh tests are better for these
fine-tuned adjustments than these
wholesale
changes so that's summarize what we've
talked about so test results don't
always correlate with foler test results
and we talked about a variety of reasons
why that might
be fer tests aren't really meaningful
for fertility guidelines unless the soil
pH is within the correct range and I
think by now you should understand why
that is fer tests are useful for
diagnosis but for detailed guidance
unless growth and yield are
good so when growth and yield are good
the Fuller test are really good for
detailed
guidance um and they're sometimes good
for diagnosis but there's major things
wrong besides nutrition the Fuller tests
aren't going to be that
helpful and as we just mentioned with
this steenberg effect applying nutrients
may result in a decrease in foler
concentrations under certain
circumstances so don't be thrown off if
applying a nutrient gives you a a lower
foler value the following year that's
probably a good thing because the plants
are growing
more and correcting deficiencies or
imbalances in these established
plantings based on the foler test is
going to be more difficult than amending
soils prior to
planning and that's going to be the
subject of the next webinar that we have
cuz it's going to be a lot trickier when
the plants are in the ground and they
have roots and you can't mix things in
with the soil after the plants are
already established and we have to start
reverting to uh foler sprays and uh
certain nutrients that are more
soluble so that's all I have for today's
subject I know was a lot and it's
somewhat detailed you can always go back
and uh review the webinar and go through
those examples but uh we want to stop
and not overwhelm you with a lot of uh
ways to correct that today we'll save
that for the next
webinar so at this point uh we'll see if
anybody has any questions they' like to
type into the box and uh uh it was Bob
trit mentioned that Eric Hansen received
a distinguished service award by the
Michigan State Hort Society at last
week's Expo that's really great Eric
congratulations on that and Eric will be
next uh webinar speaker so we're glad to
have him involved in this
series so questions go ahead and type
those in
I don't think it's coming it's not
coming through
while we're waiting for any questions I
just wanted to say some of you have not
yet sent me the demographics
questionnaire and the educator preest
please download those and send them in
and we'd really appreciate that thanks
yeah so um Mark made a comment that it's
frustrating sometimes when people send
you the tissue test and then you know
something's not right but you got don't
know what the soil pH is you don't know
what the condition of plants are so you
have to call them up and ask a bunch of
questions um hope that they remember and
give you the right answer and try to
figure that out so yeah that's a
frustration and uh I hope in the future
that's why we want to set up a system
where Growers submit soil samples
simultaneously with Leaf analysis and
fill out the form so we can get all
those uh all that information in one
place so we don't have to try to piece
it together later on yep it's a good
point uh do we ever see uh tin up of
nitrogen from straw mulch in lower foler
analysis
you not so much I mean um if you have
the straw mulch down first and or even
uh bark mulch like on blueberries and
you throw fertilizer on top of it
sometimes you have to increase the
amount of nitrogen you apply because
that'll get tied up on its way down is
it the bacteria that are breaking down
the straw mulch will grab some of that
nitrogen and hold on to it for a while
uh eventually it will get down into the
roots but it's a little bit more slow
because it's now is in an organic form
as opposed to the nitrate or ammonium
form uh it'll eventually get there but
if it's if it's underneath the straw uh
generally it won't tie it up it'll work
its way down it's mostly on its way
through when it's in close combination
with that uh organic matters being
broken
down the question is does there tend to
be more nutrient issues in blueberries
versus other small fruit crops I think
the answer is yes to that but it's
mostly because people are trying to grow
blueberries on soils that they really
shouldn't be growing blueberries on and
so they dump a lot of sulfur on there to
try to lower the ph and that's what they
need to do but that releases all sorts
of other nutrients that normally uh
aren't present at high levels and it
causes these interactions to happen that
you don't see with strawberries and
raspberries under a PH range that's a
little bit more normal for crops so yeah
we do see it we we don't see so many
nutrient problems on some of the lighter
soils uh where blueberries might not
grow naturally like in western Michigan
or New Jersey along the shore but in
Upland soils yeah we see a lot more
problems with nutrients and we wood with
strawberries or
raspberries yeah Mark says with
blueberries it's pH pH pH yep that's
exactly I would agree
100% and most of the time with
blueberries when you correct the pH um
that'll often times solve a lot of those
nutrient problems that you see but again
on these some of these soils that people
are trying to grow blueberries on they
just should not be growing blueberries
but they want to do it so they throw the
sulfur on there to get that PH down that
just starts a Cascade of other problems
that are
unintended don't think there are any
other questions and so we want to wish
you happy holidays and we'll see you on
the first week of January for the next
webinar in the series thanks everyone