hello everyone and welcome again to the
third webinar in the series of 12 on
Berry crop nutrient and soil
management we're very excited about the
program we still have people registering
for the first time we're up to 72 people
now if you have any colleagues or
Associates who might be interested in
participating they're still welcome to
join
us I just want to do a quick uh reminder
I want to point out to you in the files
box on the bottom right that the webinar
schedule is there that you can download
the demographics questionnaire that's
the registration form if you haven't
filled that out and emailed it back to
me please do that and then the educator
pretest for any of you who are new
there's a preest there please fill that
out and also e it back email it back to
me at mcm4 cornell.edu
if you would like to participate in the
webinar you are able to type comments or
questions into the chat box at the
bottom that's the same place where you
typed in your name and your
location other ways to participate are
up on the top of the screen you'll see a
person with their hand raised there's
several things that you can do you can
agree or disagree raise your hand to
indicate you have a question ask someone
to speak louder or softer to speed up to
slow down to laugh to applaud and all of
those little icons will show up next to
your name in the attendees
box on the bottom left hand side of the
screen you'll see some web links
Northeast s has its own website and it
has a link there uh Cornell fre fruit
resources berries is also there and then
at the bottom are the webinar archives
if you've missed any of the webinars in
the series they are recorded and you can
listen to the any you've missed by going
to that
link okay we're ready to start our
speaker for this week is Dr Marvin pritz
professor and chair of the Department of
horticulture at Cornell University and
our topic is soil nutrient management
he's going to discuss correction of soil
problems application technology
conventional nutrient sources organic
nutrient
sources oh I'm sorry that's next week's
topic lyming and pH reduction so now you
know what will be studying next
week Marvin was born in southwestern
Pennsylvania and got his BS in biology
from Bucknell and his Ms in biology from
the University of South Carolina he got
his PhD in Horticulture at Michigan
State University working with wild
species of blueberries he came to
Cornell in 1984 as the berry crop
specialist with an appointment in
extension research and teaching Marvin
Works primarily with production and Pest
Management Systems in strawberries and
raspberries including food safety issues
and has consulted with berry Farmers
throughout the world he became chairman
of the Department of horiculture in July
2002 he to teaches career Explorations
in the plant Sciences Hands-On
Horticulture berri crop production and
management and leadership development
for life
scientists
Marvin thank you Kathy and welcome all
of you to the webinar it's a beautiful
here in New York I hope it's nice for
you are as well uh what we want to do
today is talk about how to interpret
soil tests and the soil tests as we
mentioned before in previous webinars
are used before planting that's where
we're primarily uh using our soil tests
and the goal of soil testing just to
refresh is to estimate the plant
available nutrient levels in the soil
soil tests do not tell you how much of a
particular nutrient is in the soil they
estimate how much of a particular
nutrient ENT in the soil is available to
the plant so the
extractant sort of mimics what a plant
root might have available to them and
since you can't you mimic that perfectly
people have come up with these different
extractants to try to imitate what a
plant root might be able to extract from
the
soil once those values are obtained then
a recommendation is made uh to bring
those levels up to some Optimum because
we don't want soil nutrients to be
limiting typically plants respond to
soil nutrients uh in a curve that sort
of looks like a you know it's you get a
rapid response at low levels but as you
get up further on the curve the response
that more and more nutrients begins to
level out to where you don't get a
response at
all and the goal of soil nutrient
testing is to somewhat build up the soil
nutrient back so that there's never a
risk of nutrients being
limited but there are some philosophies
of soil testing where you want to just
apply enough to where the economic gain
from an additional amendment is equal to
the cost of the added Amendment so let
me maybe try to show you that
graphically in some philosophies you
want to try to be right here on the
curve where you're just starting to see
a a decrease in the response other
philosophies say well we want to be up
here because we don't ever want to be in
a situation where we want to be in a
deficient condition and different soils
Labs sort of give you recommendations
based on that philosophy and probably
not surprisingly soils Labs that also
sell fertilizers tend to be up here at
the top end and University labs and all
tend to want to be down here it's a
little bit harder with perennial crops
to be in this range here where the Green
Arrow is poting out because we don't
often have have a chance to go back in
annually and add a little bit of
nutrient to bring us up to where we need
so if you look at recommendations for
annual crops they'll often be down in
this range with berry crops and
perennial crops we tend to have to find
a happy medium between here and up here
because we can't go in annually and
replenish very
well so the ideal somewhere between do
we just can't go in and incorporate the
amount of nutrients we need after u a
year is up
so except for Sandy soils the eventual
nutrient Supply which is how much is in
the soil plus how much we add as
fertilizer should be sufficient for the
life expectancy of the planting and this
would be looking at you know maybe 5
years or strawberries maybe 10 to 15 for
raspberries without having to come back
in and annually apply phosphorus
potassium and magnesium calcium and so
forth of course nitrogen we do apply
that annually but that's very solid and
it can get out into the root Zone very
quickly these other nutrients phosphorus
in particular very difficult to move
through the soil profile so we need to
have that incorporated before we plant
that's why we have to maybe build up a
little bit of a bank particularly for
longer lived crops like raspberries and
particularly
blueberries so whenever these soil tests
are done and recommendations come out
every soil is probably going to give you
a slightly different response curve to
the crop of interest and we can't
develop response curves for every soil
type in your state uh so we have to make
some
generalizations and also the truth of
the matter is these response curves have
not been developed for strawberries and
raspberries and blueberries on all
different soil types uh often times the
agronomists have done these things for
field crops but not so much for food
crops so guess the point here is that
we're making educated guesses about how
Berry crops respond often based on the
response to some of these agronomic
crops we know a little bit more about a
one approach that's often used is to
find an agronomic crop that has a
similar response to a fruit crop where
there's a lot more data for and use that
as sort of a foundation for some of the
soil testing recommendations then a good
example would be alala which tends to
have the same sort of a response to
nutrients in the soil and soil types
says do strawberries and raspberries you
know Alpha Alphas are perennial
strawberries and raspberries are
perennial they have about the same
rooting depth they have the same pH
requirement for soil for optimal growth
so those are oftentimes used as a basis
for
recommendation of course people do
nutrient response curves for some of
these and this is an example actually
from Strawberry and this is looking at
nitrogen and these are looking at
various rates of nitrogen uh fertilizer
on PL plants and this is in a this is in
a liquid form so it's not quite easily
to convert to pounds per acre but the
point is at low nutrient levels you
don't get much of a response but as you
move up you get a higher higher response
but then the curve kind of flattens
out if we look at Leaf area we fertilize
with more and more nitrogen you know the
leaves love it and they really expand a
lot and grow a lot but if we look at
yield it's not nearly is
responsive to the increases in nitrogen
so that says okay the optimal rate is
probably somewhere around this uh 10n
situation here so we can do these
response curves to some extent and sort
of calibrate our soil test by
that so it's not that they don't exist
for Berry crops it's just that there's
not a lot of those out there to
calibrate
on some recommendations are based on
response curves that are dependent on
the soil type in other words to get a
good recommendation you have to input
the soil type so then the software knows
what soil type that is and can make a
recommendation based on that uh a Morgan
extracting is a good example of a type
of soil test that is you have to have
the soil type or at least know whether
it's a a Sandy LOM or a LOM or a silt or
a clay because the response curve and
the extracting is based on that soil
type you have many labs are getting away
from those tests that are dependent on
soil type and looking at other tests
that that's less important and the
modified Morgan is one of those tests
that is a little bit less dependent on
knowing the type of soil that you have
in there and a lot of this is due to the
amount of potassium that the different
extractants pull out of the
soil but you have to sort of assume that
this soil tests that you're using the
procedures and all are are good and
accurate and that the recommendations
come out are on target now a question
was asked like a a week or so ago about
organic versus conventional
recommendations the recommendations that
come out should be mostly the same
whether one's organic or conventional
it's not what's recommended that should
be different it's the
amount and the type of product that's
used that's different so a soil test
might recommend you know 50 pounds of
potassium but the source of that
potassium is what would differ then
between the organic and the conventional
grower there is some difference in
amount based on release rate some
organic nutrients are a little bit more
slower to release their nutrients so you
may have to apply more of that uh
because the release rate slower but in
general it's the total amount would be
the same
so when you get your soil test the most
important adjustment that we usually
make is to soil
PH if the soil PH isn't within the
desired range then the ability to take
up nutrients will be compromised so if
you don't have the pH right you can put
on a lot of a certain nutrient and it
might not even get into the plant
because of the ph and you probably all
seen this in soils classes back in
college but the amount of nutrient
that's available to the plant is very
dependent on soil PH and the optimal
range for most crops is a little bit
less than six up to about
6.5 and of course you all know
blueberries are the exception they're
down around 4.5 for the optimum but for
most of the plants that we're dealing
with with the berries and even vegetable
crops it's up around 6 to 6.5 because of
that range most of the nutrients are
reasonably available to the
plant
now if we have to make an adjustment to
the pH we use sulfur to lower it and
lime to raise
it often times in cataloges and
particular for homeowners you'll see U
aluminum sulfate recommended to lower
the ph and we do not recommend that
because aluminum is toxic to plants at
high rates now granted it provides a
rapid change in PH because because the
sulfur is already oxidized when it's in
aluminum sulfate form so it could go
right to work and lower that pH almost
right away whereas sulfur takes some
time but you don't want all that
aluminum so we don't recommend that for
lowering
pH and changing the soil PH after
planting is extremely slow and difficult
that's why it's so important to do it
before planting I have a couple of
photos here of people who have planted
and then realize that their pH is too
low
and tried to raise it with lime and you
can see it just makes a real mess in the
field it's really hard to incorporate
and get that lime down into the root
Zone where it has an impact so if you
can mix it in the soil before you plant
it just makes a world difference um
raspberry field same way how are you
going to work that line down into the
soil well enough to really change the pH
around the root Zone where those nuts
can be taken up better it's really hard
to do
that
so the amount of lime that you're going
to apply to the soil the change the pH
is dependent on two things and one is
the difference between the current pH
and your target pH so how big is a gap
between where you want to be and where
you currently are and then the second
thing is something called a c Caton
exchange capacity or the soil buffering
capacity this is the ability of the soil
to hold on to the catons in the soil
through these exchange sites they're
like negative charges on the soil
particles and it's the ratio of the cats
that are bound to these negative
charges uh
to charges that only have hydrogen
attached to them it's the ratio of the
cat to the hydrogen ions to determine
your
pH this is often called base saturation
or the percent of the exchange sites
occupied by the bases so just think of
it as a like a column the column has a
lot of NE of negative charges on it some
of those charges then attached to
positively charged cat such as calcium
magnesium and potassium those are the
major ones the remainder uh tend to be
populated with hydrogen ions and the
more hydrogen ions you have the lower
your pH remember pH is the negative log
of the hydrogen content or something
like that anyway um the higher the ratio
of the hydrogen ions to cations the more
acid to
soil so the more of these exchange sites
we have and if we want to change it and
knock some of those hydrogens off the
exchange site we have to add a lot more
base the negative charges on our soils
arise from either clay particles or
organic matter those are the sources of
the negative charges so the clay
particles and organic matter hold on to
those positive charges that are out
there SS that have a lot of exchange
capacity in other words they have a a
lot of negative charges are more
difficult to adjust the pH so if you
want to knock hydrogen ions off that
exchange sites you have to use a lot of
of line but once you make that
adjustment soils that are high and C
exchange capacity tend to be more stable
they a lot more resistant to change once
you make the change
so those are low are easy to change but
they'll revert back to a low PH as those
calcium and magnesium and potassium ions
Leech from the soil and then the
hydrogen takes over those exchange sites
and the pH drops
again so to reiterate it's easy to raise
the pH of a sandy soil with low organic
matter because Sandy soils and low
organic soils have low cat Exchange
capacities conversely it's hard to lower
the pH of a clay soil having a h organic
matter content because both clay and
organic matter contribute to these
negative charges in the
soil so the amount of sulfur this is
just estimates ballpark estimates to
lower the ph to a desired level of
4.5 depends the two things we mentioned
it depends on the current pH which is
over here
and of course the further we are from
4.5 which is our Target pH the more
sulfur it will take to lower it and the
higher our Canon exchange capacity the
more sulfur it will take to lower it so
in a sandy
soil not much lomy soil with more
negative charges higher cat exchange
capacity it takes more sulfur and with
Clays even more sulfur so when we're up
in this range here with a high pH soil
with heavy soil it's really really hard
to lower that pH uh to 4.5 even with a
lot of sulfur it just takes a huge
amount so often times soils up in here
aren't really suitable for blueberry
production so soil tests attempt to
estimate the amount of lime or sulur
required to bring the pH to within the
desired range for a particular crop and
it's based on this kind exchange
capacity soil tests do not measure Caton
exchange capacity directly in other
words it doesn't go in and directly
measure the amount of negative uh
charges of there and how many of those
negative charges are populated by
hydrogen ions they use indirect methods
to measure that it's an inexact science
different procedures are used in
different labs and a can exchange
capacity itself varies somewhat with ph
and other factors so guess what I'm
trying to say here is that often times
the lime recommendations we think of
them as being really really precise but
the truth of the matter is they're
estimates they try to put you in the
ballpark but they're not absolutely
precise the Canon exchange capacity
varies with various
soils Sands of course have low and loms
a little bit higher and Clays have
higher and you can see that reflected in
the sulfur recommendations in the
previous table humus or organ oric
matter and it's sort of broken down form
has very very high cat exchange capacity
so that's why soils high in organic
matter require a lot of sulfur or lime
to make adjustments to
them and we don't want to forget that
adding lime or sulfur to the soil does
not change the pH instantly it takes six
months or longer usually it's dependent
on the size of the particle of the lime
and the sulfur small smaller particle
sizes adjust more quickly depends on
soil moisture in dry soils you get very
little very slow oxidation conversion
takes a lot of time you have to have
adequate slow moisture to make sure it
happens relatively quickly and in
temperature in the winter time not much
happens in the soil that process of
oxidation is a biological process it
requires soil bacteria to make that
conversion so when it's cold there's not
a lot of activity also those bacteria
have to have Iration it's an aerobic
process and the soil has to be aerated
so all those things have to happen for
that pH to change after we add our lime
or
sulfate so now let's get into the Crux
of the matter here with that background
an interpreting soil test we're going to
look at soil
PH the macronutrients and micronutrients
and I'm going to run through seven or
eight examples and we'll work through
those and see how a soil test um might
interpret those and recommend those this
is just an example of a a soil test
we'll look at some of its various parts
the of course the reports that come back
vary a lot from Lab to lab but this just
assume this is sort of a general
recommendation the first thing you want
to look for at least I do is the
ph and we want to look and see whether
that's within the ballark range or not
and in this case here is for
strawberries the PH range that we use
before we provide a line recommendations
is between like 6 and 68 so the pH is
within that range so we wouldn't
recommend lme
here sometimes uh you'll see a different
pH number there and in this case here uh
there's this thing called buffer pH in
water and people say what is that does
that mean my pH is too low because it's
less than six well no in this case here
this soil testing lab is using something
called the buffer pH to estimate cat and
exchange capacity and the difference
between the buffer pH and the normal pH
in water is an estimate of the cat on
Exchange capacity and there's
complicated curves and correlations and
so forth but suffice it to say that the
greater the difference between the ph
and a buffer pH the greater the Caton
exchange capacity therefore the slower
or harder it's going to be to change
that pH if you had to change it this
case here we wouldn't have to change it
but the situation where the buffer pH
differ greatly from the pH in water that
would imply a high cat exchange capacity
so we don't worry about that for
interpretation we assume that the
software takes that into account and
spits out that line or software
recommendation based on that difference
and we don't have to worry about it but
it's often shown there uh so you can see
that it's there and it gives you just
some sense of when you're comparing
different soils what that cat exchange
capacity difference is if it doesn't
print it out directly on the form some
soil tests printed out directly this one
prints out that buffer pH to pH
comparison other thing I like to look at
is the organic matter content I like to
see organic matters you know 2% or
higher this one's pretty good
4.6% it indicates that this cat exchange
capacity is reasonably robust and
there's organic matter in the soil and
the plant roots tend to like that so
when the organic matter gets below 2%
then one of the things you would think
about recommending to a grower would be
some sort of a cover crop or manure
application or something to boost that
organic matter
content soil tests generally report
values for phosphorus potassium calcium
and magnesium we talked about those
curves before those response curves it's
usually they've been done for these four
macronutrients and not for the
micronutrients those are the ones you're
going to get results from
often times these micronutrients will be
printed out but they're kind of hard to
interpret um the techniques that are
used to analyze nutrients are often
times something called an
ICP they send the extractor through that
ICP and it prints out not only the PK
calcium magnesium but it prints out
everything else too so it's not unusual
to see a soil testing lab present
present values for zinc and manganese
and
iron even aluminum most of the time
these aren't really very useful like we
don't use those for guidance and what to
apply to the soil usually we use these
when we want to try to diagnose a
problem like a toxicity or some sort of
an imbalance that they're typically not
used to give recommendations on those
are usually just PK calcium magnesium
and any sort of pH adjustment Marvin we
also might see yes I'm sorry I didn't
mean to interrupt Jeff Jeff had a
question about pH when you're finished
with what you're discussing okay let me
read so the question is do we assume a
natural reduction in PH over time and
therefore apply lme to maintain a pH in
a range of that over a 5year period we P
so with normal rainfall conditions and
all we lose maybe you know 500 pounds of
catons from the typical soil a year so
if you have a lot of calcium in your
soil or potassium and so forth we lose
some of it but it might not be enough to
really knock the PH down even over a
5year period the time when we have to
worry about that is on Sandy soils where
we can't really build up the reserve too
much without pushing a pH too high so if
we puts the pH to 6.5 and we have a
sandy soil and we get a lot of rain year
after year after year yeah it's true we
could knock the pH Down Below a
desirable level and then we might have
to go back in and reapply but as I
showed earlier it's really difficult to
do that in something like raspberries
because they might live longer than 5
years strawberries you just wait till
the end of their normal life and reapply
the line but on raspberries it's kind of
hard to do that so we want to try to
make sure we get all that in there
before we plant so we don't have to go
back in and try to add later
on I wanted to mention that
the nitrates uh some soil testing Labs
present a value for nitrate but really
is is so variable almost from dayto day
it's not a very useful guideline for
making
recommendations so uh this lab here
doesn't even print it although they
would have it if you would ask for
it the other value we sometimes ask
Growers or to run or make requests for
is boron Boron is one of those
micronutrients that can have an impact
on plant growth and those values do mean
something so we will uh recommend it
Growers particularly of strawberries and
raspberries ask for Boron if it doesn't
automatically come with the test
sometimes it does sometimes it
doesn't this is just a diagram of the
different forms of nitrogen and the
different cycles that are happening
within nitrogen and it's just so
variable that anytime you do a nitrate
or a nitrogen test of the soil it's just
a snapshot in time it's so Dynamic that
those numbers really don't mean anything
so we don't pay much attention to them
when we get them Boron on the other hand
I mentioned is a an important nutrient
it's important for cell elongation and
if you don't have Boron your cells tend
not to elongate very well and so this is
a root of a strawberry plant grown in a
nutrient solution is complete has
everything in it the next slide I'm
going to show you is one where the Boron
was removed from the nutrient solution
and you can see how that roots are real
stubby and of course a plant without
boron has a difficult time taking up all
the other nutrients that it needs that's
why we want to make sure we have
adequate boron in the soil so you don't
get a situation like this where the soil
tests will show well you got adequate
potassium and phosphorus and magnesium
and calcium but the plants are showing
deficiencies in those values well it
might not be too low of potassium or too
low of phosphorus it might be that your
Boron is inadequate that's why we want
to look at that particular
nutrient okay back to the soil test the
other thing we want to look for is a
type of test that we've run in this case
here it was modified
Morgan but different Labs run different
tests so when you get the values under
there they don't really mean a whole lot
if somebody sends me values of a soil
test um I don't really have any basis
for knowing what's low medium and high
you have to trust that the soil testing
lab knows what low medium high is for
your particular CR
so here we have recommendations on what
low medium high is and again because
different Labs use different methods
different extractions you got to trust
that they know what they're doing
now and then you get your
recommendations printed out down here
based on the soil test levels
above mentioned you have to have
confidence in the recommendations
provided by your lab the best analysis
in the world is useless without a good
recommendation unfortunately many
analytical labs provide these General
plant recommendations that are good for
fi crops but they don't really fine-tune
them to the needs of the specific crops
that we might be interested in like
strawberries like raspberries and I
can't tell you how many times I've seen
soil tests come back for blueberries and
the recommendations look like they
should have been for corn or something
because the lab has just spitting out a
general recommendation for Gen crop on
that soil without understanding the
differences between these perennial
crops and some of the crops that require
a low PH so just a word of warning on
that you've got to trust that the lab
knows what they're
doing Marvin Jeff had a question on
Boron is it Mobile in the soil Boron is
very Mobile in the soil that's one of
those nutrients that you can come in and
apply any time of the year and you can
apply it right to the soil surface even
right over the leaves and it'll wash
into the soil and get taken up by the
roots and into the plant so that's one
that's fairly easy to correct uh even
after the plants are in the ground it's
not like some of the other nutrients
that are very difficult to move into the
root
zone
so let's look at a few examples here and
see what we can come up with this is a
example of a soil test strawberries on a
clay LOM soil
and we're going to trust that the lab
gives us the right values for what's low
medium high and they're reporting these
out uh medium phosphorus high potassium
high calcium low
magnesium boron has more than one pound
and a pH of 5.2 relatively High organic
matter so what do you think a soil test
recommendation might provide for this
particular example give you a second so
look at that maybe you might want to jot
that down somewhere and see what you can
come up
with so the first thing I would do
without knowing anything about the lab
really extract or anything is look at
the
ph and I see oh it's 5.2 so it's less
than the six or 6.2 to 65 that we would
ideally want for strawberri so I would
know that some sort of a pH modification
is in line
here I also would look here and and see
that phosphorus is a little bit low we
might want to raise that a little
bit I also know that a lime contains
Calcium but it also contains
magnesium now in this case magnesium is
low so one option I would have in this
case and the recommendation engine
should generate this is when they're
recommending a pH change they might want
to recommend high magnesium lime so you
can raise the ph and provide your
magnesium in the same
step so here the recommendation would be
damic line because it has high magnesium
and
phosphorus Arvin Glenn had a question
without n represented on the soil test
what is the basis for the N recommend
ation I'm glad you uh asked that
question the basis for the nitrogen
recommendation is sort of a ballpark
figure of what you would apply to a crop
in that particular year so for example
strawberries a standard recommendation
would be anywhere from 70 to 100 pounds
of nitrogen per acre just based on the
age of the plant based on the crop
itself we always have to add nitrogen
every year and that's sort of a standard
so it's not based on the soil test that
nitrogen recommendation is just sort of
a standard practice that a grower would
use um to fertilize to put you in the
ballpark we're going to talk in a couple
of weeks about using folar
analysis and one of the most important
uses of foler analysis is to adjust
those ballp part nitrogen
recommendations to fit your particular
crop
situation so the recommendation might
say well an established strawberry field
you know 100 pounds of nitrogen but we
can use that Fuller test to adjust that
up or down based on what the values are
in the leaves we'll talk about that
later so the recommendation of nitrogen
on a soil test for a perennial crop is
just ballpark figure this is what you
typically do the first year of the
planting Sonia is commenting that low
magnesium can also be exacerbated by
high potassium because they compete for
uptake
correct there is some uh item some
thinking that that can indeed happen
there's competition between these catons
for exchange sites so uh in soils that
are really really high in one of the
catons and really really low in the
other there's some sense that the high
catons can suppress the uptake of the
lower level of the catons in in low
Supply so yeah those situations are
pretty rare but they can happen and I'm
actually going to give you an example of
this in a few
minutes Dan is wondering on some of the
high lime soils in central New York
where the pH values can be closer to
seven if an application of sulfur should
be made to lower the pH for
strawberries I would say sure certainly
our Target pH would be you know 62 to 65
for strawberries and if you're up at
seven and you're in a pre-plant
situation I think softare would be uh an
appropriate material to apply to lower
that a little bit so that the nutrient
uptake can be improved and you get less
um precipitation form between some of
these nutrients that happen at high phes
where they become unavailable to the
plant
right let's look at a second example
this is blueberries on a Sandy LOM
soil and we have low
calcium we
have pH is just about right High organic
matter
so uh
what would we do in this situation here
potassium is high phosphorus is high
magnesium is
high we need it looks like we need
calcium but the pH is already kind of
where we want it we don't really want to
raise the calcium too much more what
would we do
here so in this case we might recommend
calcium sulfate instead of lime to
provide our calcium because calcium
sulfate doesn't change the pH very much
when it's added so it's a way of
providing calcium without a big change
in PH so again the soil test
recommendation should know that take
that into account whenever it makes the
recommendation so I see Jeff okay yeah
go ahead oh no I just gonna say Jeff had
a question about
sulfur yeah requirements for
strawberries yeah sulfur is needed by
alala but it's also needed for all other
crops as well so an essential nutrient
is part of amino acids so all plants
need sulfur and in our part of the world
sulfur is rarely limiting it comes down
in rainfall acid rain and there's
usually plenty of sulfur it's rare that
you have to add sulfur for the nutrient
value to the plant we might add sulfur
for the pH adjustment but usually not
for the nutrient value again there
sulfur around it's in the organic matter
there usually we're not in situations
here where we're usually very sulfur
deficient at least not in
crops take a third example raspberries
lomy soil here we're high and everything
the pH is Right would the soil test
recommend anything
here well it might and this goes back to
what Sonia asked about earlier sometimes
even though we have high values if we're
really super high in one nutrient one C
in particular it can depress the uptake
of of the other two particularly you
know calcium magnesium can interact a
little bit pottassium even though it's
low here that's not a that's actually a
pretty high value for potassium but
calcium relative to magnesium is low uh
that ratio of calcium magnesium is
around so higher than 10 typical soils
it would be around five five times as
much calcium as magnesium so in this
case here we actually might need to
recommend a little bit of magnesium to
bring that balance back up so it
wouldn't be unusual for a test like that
to have a little bit of magnesium
sulfate in the recommendation not so
much to change the pH this doesn't
really change the pH but it just adds a
little bit of magnesium in the soil to
bring that ratio into
balance okay example four
blueberries Sandy LOM soil we can see
that we're low in
phosphorus high in potassium low in
calcium magnesium is
medium pH is 5.9 and organic matter is
you know pretty low
here so what would you recommend in this
case or what do you think a soil test
recommendation should
say one of the things we would want to
do is try to raise that organic matter a
little bit blueberries like organic
matter 1. .3 is really quite low so we
want to do that um but the pH is 5.9 we
have to lower that quite a bit and one
of the things we know that About
Blueberries is that they don't really
require a whole lot of of some of these
catons they're really good at sucking
that out of the soil
so all we might need to recommend here
is just to lower the ph increase your
organic matter and those other nutrients
will probably take care of themselves
because we're measuring that a high pH
when we lower the ph the blueberries
blueberries become much more efficient
at taking these nutrients
up so I see a question here about how
strong is the effect of added nitrogen
on ph it depends a little bit on your
nitrogen Source if you use ammonium
sulfate as a nitrogen source which we
often recommend on blueberries it
acidifies the soil if we use Ura it also
acidifies the soil a little bit because
it's adding um nh4 plus to the soil but
if we add nitrate to the soil like
calcium nitrate it tends to either be
neutral or or raise the ph a little bit
so it depends a little bit on the source
of nitrogen's the impact on ph but
ammonium sulfate is going to have the
strongest negative effect on ph Ura
somewhere in the middle your nitrate
forms the nitrogen not much but we
wouldn't use nitrogen to actually try to
affect the pH we would use it to maybe
keep it at a certain level we wouldn't
use say ammonium sulfate to lower the
ph1 unit that would be way too much and
the question is can blueberries use
nitrate they can use nitrate but they
don't like it they're much more uh
preferentially use the ammonium form of
nitrogen and take that up if you put
blueberry roots in a solution that just
has nitrate available to it the roots
will turn black and a plal die if you
put
blueberries in the field and you apply
hydrate fertilizers to it the bacteria
in the soil under low PH conditions
which you should have if you're planting
blueberries anyway will convert that
nitrate into ammonium and where it can
be taken up more readily and used by the
blueberry plant so you get away with it
but uh nitrate is more leech and all so
ammonium is a better Source because it
not only lowers the pH but it's more of
a slow release more available over a
longer period of time and blueberries
can take it up directly so that's a
preferable source for
blueberries he just a couple more
examples here uh blueberries clay LOM
soil
were high you know medium and phosphorus
high potassium high calcium high
magnesium good Boron pH is pretty high
organic matter is pretty high
U what we recommend
here when to grow blueberries well if we
go back to that chart we looked at
before and we saw a ph up around six and
we see here that the Caton exchange
capacity is probably going to be pretty
high because the organic matter is going
to be pretty high we're already high in
calcium magnesium and we don't want a
lot of calcium magnesium in the soil
blueberries don't like calcium in
particular the best recommendation here
is probably just don't grow blueberries
the soil is just not appropriate for
blueberries
the Caton exchange capacity coupled with
the pH is so great that it would take so
much sulfur to lower that that it
probably won't be worth it economically
and that high calcium is going to cause
problems U for years on end because of
that couple more uh strawberries in a
sandy
soil low phosphorus low
calcium low ph
low
Boron low organic matter so this soil
test is probably going to come back with
several recommendations calcitic lme
because we were low on calcium some
phosphorus some Boron and some organic
matter and uh final example here
raspberries and alomi soil or
medium most things
fairly high in aluminum good Boron high
pH organic matter now most of the time
if you saw a soil test like this you
might say well you know I've got medium
values for most of these things um
organic matter is pretty good pH is in
the range I might want it probably don't
have to do too much here but in this
case here uh we might want to correct
that with a small amount of pnk but we
might want to add a little bit bit
higher rate of lime than was recommended
in the soil test and the reason for that
is this aluminum value is pretty high
and that can cause problems uh later on
and the higher we raise the ph the less
available aluminum is so we might want
to push the pH to the very high end so
that it makes the aluminum less
available to the plant and aluminum can
be toxic that's why we don't really want
it it can be toxic so in this case here
the aluminum value is providing diagnos
IC information to a plant uh to
understand maybe why those plants aren't
growing very well or why what we might
want to do to make a correction before
we
plant this is a a field of blueberries
this is a real situation and the
blueberry plants in this section
here uh weren't growing so
well and the other thing is the grass in
this section wasn't growing so well
either and yet down here at this end the
grass is growing pretty well now we took
soil tests from three different places
from plantings that were three different
ages uh in one place the plants look
pretty good the side was fine pH was
good
um aluminum phosphorus is okay uh the
other place the plants look really
pathetic the pH was a little bit higher
than average aluminum was pretty high
plants were pretty sick and there was
dead sod and here this is the
interesting thing the pH is really high
you think blueberries might not do so
well there and they were kind of fair
they weren't terrible and the sod was
living these plants with a higher pH
were a lot better off than the plants
that were sick at even a lower pH what
was going on here well it appears from
the soil test that in this case here
aluminum was really high and it could be
coming toxic to the blueberry plants and
as we raise the ph even though the
aluminum was up a little bit the higher
pH makes that aluminum unavailable to
the plant so the plants were able to
survive a little bit longer and do
better so um pH can react and relate to
a lot of different
things and looking at these values of
some of these microns can give you Clues
sometimes as to how things were working
out there in the
soil last last thing the last concept I
want to mention is that this nutrient
uptake occurs through uh three different
ways when we have nutrients in The Soil
Direct contact with roots so the root
surface actually like almost has direct
contact with the soil and the nutrient
just kind of jumps right across that
membrane mass flow which is a nutrients
dissolved in water that get taken into
the plant through the transpirational
stream or diffusion and diffusion is
sort of short distance transport of
these nutrients when they dissolve in
water the water actually doesn't move
through the plant like mass flow but the
nutrients diffuse through an aquous
solution from a level of high
concentration in the soil to a lower
concentration inside the root so there's
three different mechanisms and nutrients
that are primarily taken up by contacted
diffusion must be in close proximity to
the root itself the
root on average only has about 1% and at
most 3% of it of the surface of that
root is in direct contact with the soil
so nutrients have to be thoroughly mixed
in order to be taken up prior to
planting this is a this is with corn but
it it's appropriate for all of our crops
this is a mode of uptake for the various
nutrients based on this root
interception mass flow and diffusion and
different nutrients have different mods
basically being taken up into the plant
nitrogen is mostly taken up by mass flow
in other words nitrogen nitrate nitrogen
and ammonium nitrogen get dissolved in
the acous solution when a plant
transpires it moves into the root system
and uh and the water leaves the leaf
leaving the nutrient inside the plant
that's why you can put nitrogen on the
soil surface and it gets down into the
roots because it dissolves in the water
it's soluble it's taken up by mass flow
someone also asked earlier about um
Boron Boron also is very highly soluble
and taken up by mass flow that's why we
can apply Boron to the soil surface it
gets dissolved gets taken up by mass
flow no problem we can apply it after
the plants are
established but some of these other
nutrients uh are mostly taken up by
things like diffusion like phosphorus um
so it has to be thoroughly incorporated
into the soil it doesn't dissolve very
quickly it doesn't move through the soil
very rapidly so we want to have that
mixed in with the soil before we plant
same way with potassium a lot of
diffusion not that much mass
flow so that's why magnesium calcium um
not much diffusion some mass flow some
rote interception but certainly for p
and K we want to make sure we have that
mixed in with the soil very well
otherwise the roofs won't be able to
take it
up these tables of course are going to
be uh available to you to download to
print off and uh it should be right here
in this website in a few days when it
gets
posted now once our plants are
established and they're growing we don't
really rely on a soil test so much we
rely on a soil test to tell us what our
pH is but we don't pay much attention to
the levels of p and K and magnesium and
calcium after that once the plants are
underground we look use a foler analysis
to make adjustments and we use the pH in
conjunction with a foler analysis and
that's going to be the subject of an
upcoming
webinar next week Eric Hansen is going
to talk about these nutrient sources and
some of the characteristics of these
various nutrient sources that are out
there that you can use in a pre-plant
situation to both modify the ph and add
phosph there potassium magnesium and so
forth and look at it from both a
conventional perspective and a
perspective of of an organic
grower so that's uh what I have for the
presentation and uh there's a few
minutes left if anybody wants to type in
some questions we'll see if I can try to
answer
them thanks
Marvin
I just want to remind everyone that if
you haven't filled out the demographics
questionnaire or the preest that they're
available down below and you can email
them to me at mcm4 cornell.edu if you
missed either of the first two webinars
there's a link to them in the archive on
the bottom left hand side of your
screen and as Marvin indicated Dr Eric
Hansen from Michigan State Unity will be
our speaker next
week Jeff asks about organic sources of
nutrients and her characteristics that's
what the entire webinar is going to be
about next week so we'll save that for
Eric to talk
about an acceptable Boron level
generally you want um at least one pound
preferably 2 pounds that's sort of that
ballpark that we're looking at and
fortunately for Boron it's not so
dependent on soil test and it's also uh
most soil testing Labs use a separate
extractant for the Boron they use a hot
water extractant so they just put hot
water in the soil take it out run it for
Boron so the procedure for looking at
Boron is fairly standardized across Labs
so um we can pretty confidently say
between 1 and 2 pounds is where you want
to aim for this less pound you probably
have to supplement uh and that's going
to be a lot more standard among Labs
than most of the other nutrient levels
you're going to
get uh Jeff asks is there a
physiological reason for blueberries
aversion to calcium and nitrate that's a
really good question so blueberries have
evolved in these low PH soils and
nutrient levels are very low in these
low PH soils Sandy soils wet soils and
they've evolve some characteristics that
enable them to survive under those
conditions and one of those um
adaptations is this association with
endom micro risal
fungi that uh colonize the roots of
blueberries and then actually help the
blueberry increase the surface area as
they go out and grow through the soil
and the blueberry gives that endom micro
risal fungus some carbohydrate and in
return the fungus pulls in nitrogen and
phosphorus and gives it to the blueberry
plant most of the time the nitrogen
that's in the soil is in the ammonium
form of nitrogen and so some people
think because of this endom micro risal
Association the fungi prefer it and the
blueberries ended up just evolving a
preference for that because that is the
most available type of nitrogen in low
PH
soils um and actually when a a regular
plant a non- blueberry plant takes up
nitrate interestingly enough inside the
plant it converts it into the ammonium
form and moves it around and then
reconverts it into nitrate forms at
times because if you look at amino acids
and all that uh
comprise proteins they're in the
ammonium form so why I guess maybe a
better question is why other plants
haven't evolved at an adaptation to take
up ammonium nitrogen since energetically
it's easier to do that than it is to
take up nitrate and then reduce it back
down to ammonium and move it around and
in terms of calcium I'm not exactly sure
why that is I think it has to do with
inside the plant interactions with iron
and uh somehow it it maybe precipitates
with the iron inhibits it but high
calcium soils and blueberries just don't
go well together even if the pH is
low one of the things will recommend in
a soil test if the calcium level is
above a certain amount uh even if the pH
is kind of close and you can lower it
with sulur we might recommend look
someplace else this isn't a good soil
for blueberries you just know
historically high calcium and
blueberries don't go well
together uh does soil moisture content
at the time of sampling affect soil test
results not really uh not if you're just
looking at the nutrients because what
they'll do when they get the soil uh
back in is they'll often dry it down
anyway and uh so whether you send them
dry soil or it comes to the lab and they
dry it before they analyze it doesn't
make a huge difference there is there's
some debate uh whether uh there needs to
be moisture correction to soils when
they do the analysis but that has more
to do with some Labs scoop soil and some
Labs weigh it and the question is do you
get a different result when you scoop it
or you weigh it or you have it moist or
it's dried um so it can make a slight
difference not so much qualitatively but
quantitatively but Labs have not come to
consensus over whether it needs to be
dried or not most Labs do it
dry I think most Labs do it dry how I
feel about ammonium phosphates for
blueberry ammonium phosphates are if
you're low in phosphorus and you need a
fertilize the plant that would be a good
way of killing two birds with one stone
it provides an ammonium source of
nitrogen and it provides that phosphorus
at the same
time and do blueberries have a higher
iron content
I I don't believe they have a higher
iron content than other plants that's
not the case but for some reason uh iron
availability seems to impact blueberries
more than iron availability in other
crops again I'm not exactly sure why
that is maybe somebody out there knows
the answer to
that thank you very much Marvin I really
appreciate you speaking to us today
again next week our topic is soil and
nutrient
management um and we'll be looking at
correction of soil problems application
technology conventional nutrient sources
organic nutrient sources Lyman and pH
reduction with Eric Hansen from MSU a
couple more questions
Marvin
so um the availability of calcium
sulfate in New York it's gypsum I know
that there are um I'm not specifically
New York but a drywall for housing is
gypson and there are some places that I
know are crushing that to extract the uh
material from within the drywall and
then selling that for agricultural uses
and that's great source of
gypson and the high iron content is
related to the low PH like with
cranberry yeah it is if you look at
those charts where we looked at the
availability of nutrients with ph you
can see that at the lower end uh iron
availability goes way up for some reason
you know calcium inside the plant not
outside the plant the soil but inside
the plant has some impact on that
availability of calcium it could have to
do it's a little bit it could have to do
with the fact that active iron in the
plant is in a feric form and maybe with
too much calcium in the plant it
converts more to the I'm sorry it's in
the ferris form it converts more to the
feric form so it goes from fe+ 2 which
is active biologically active to fe+ 3
which is inactive and calcium may cause
the iron to go from one form to the
other in which case a leaf analysis will
still show you have iron in a plant
because it doesn't distinguish between
the two types it's just that the type in
high calcium soils is more in a feric
inactive form so that's uh that's that's
my hypothesis again maybe somebody else
knows all right if there aren't any
other
questions then I think we'll close thank
you so much Marvin for your insights
welcome thank you everyone and we hope
you'll join us all again next
week