this kind of program would best benefit
those people who wants a garden versus
actually going into the community and
trying to persuade people to garden
because that takes a different approach
and it goes beyond food security it goes
beyond food as a facilitator the
community's needs always come first and
it's hard to watch that because
we are also in an educational system
where there are sort of experts and
people who are not experts so as experts
we come in thinking oh this is what they
need but that's what it's failed for so
many years coming in with that mindset
so coming in with letting the community
decide what they want in the day is the
most important part
partnerships are very very community
specific so for example if you're
working with like a Senior Living Center
it's not a better set of the food that
grown it's about the type of spices it
reminds them of home it reminds them of
a time of their lives and it's in a lot
of seniors aging can bring about issues
of isolation loneliness so anything that
can remind them of home it's something
that they want and what we've seen in
Downton is become and some of the Senior
Living Centers is that more the gardens
are herb based and that's an example of
being community specific and
understanding community knowledge
because you're going into a population
that has knowledge of the old days and
they want to remember the old days and
under the old days so the partnerships
also about
being community specific it encourages
community involvement and participation
in all levels but then it also empowers
communities to commit to long term
change it seems because the bean plant
grows perfectly around the corner
doesn't suffocate the corn at all
actually they go together thinking about
see December facilitation
it's a partnership but it's not defined
based on what we think a partnership is
to be a lot of times we think it's a
50/50 thing when working with
communities is never 5050 it could be
eight its winning it could be twenty
forty I mean it it might mean it might
not even be a hundred percent and we
have to rid ourselves on the idea what
we think a partnership is and rethink
the idea of a partnership and that's
what cedar Supper is all about when it
comes to community development
you