well hi folks uh welcome you're logged
in the second of 12 Berry soil and
nutrient management webinars sponsored
by Northeast sustainable research and
education program and hosted by Cornell
University Department of horticulture
and Cornell Cooperative EXP ension my
name is Jeff Miller I'm call calling you
right now from onid County Central New
York and I'll be your moderator for this
webinar we'll be starting promptly at 2
pm Eastern Standard Time I do want to
direct you to the pieces uh of what
you're viewing right now off to the left
is the list of attendees and you can see
from the comments in the chat box in the
lower middle that uh there are people
from Penn State joining us UMass
uh people from New York state so we got
a good collection of people joining us
today uh and if you look to the lower
left you'll see a series of web links uh
one is the soil nutrient management
webinar so that's where you'll find a
lot of information about what's being
present today and in future
events and uh below it is uh publication
building soils for better crops and then
I'll direct you to the far
right where there's a file box and if
you haven't joined us before this is a
second meeting uh if you would uh
download the
demographics and the educator
pretests uh at your leisure you can do
that after this program today and if you
would fill them out and then send them
into Kathy Heiden Rick and she's her
addresses on those PC
and send them into her that would be
very helpful to fulfill our requirements
for the
grant and we're going to take questions
throughout the program um but we're
going to answer the questions at the
end so with that I'm going to switch
over and introduce our speaker for today
speaker is Harold vaness he's professor
of Soil and Water Management chair of
the Department of crop and soil Sciences
at Cornell
University his current research and
extension interests are in Precision
management of nitrogen soil health and
SpaceTime
statistics Harold teaches an undergrad
undergrad course in soil management for
sustainability and a grad course in
space time statistics he's going to talk
to us today about soil types accessing
soil surveys and soil physical chemical
and biological
properties and with that I'm going to
turn over to
Harold good day everyone I hope you can
hear
me um it's beautiful day here in itha
and um I see a lot of familiar names
here on the participant list so I say hi
to all of you it's uh it's a it's a
pleasure to be able to present this uh
through this format so today
um this will be more of an
introductory uh webinar as it relates to
to Berry production and in the more
subsequent webinars we're going to be
talking more about uh sort of management
approaches so today will be a little bit
more
conceptual and uh and we'll talk more
about the about the
principles uh so quick outline for today
uh we'll start out with uh discussion on
seral health Concepts we'll this discuss
uh the concept of inherent soil quality
and the use of soil survey
information and then we'll discuss each
of the the three Realms of soil Health
the chemical uh characteristics and
measurements the physical and then the
biological and and with the biological
we'll also talk um quite a bit about the
role of organic matter which is an key
component and then towards the end I'll
I'll just have a few slides About
Management considerations for for Berry
production basically as an introduction
to uh to the subsequent
webinars um so many of you I think are
probably familiar with this concept but
you know I'd like to uh refer to Cal
Health as the capacity of the serl to
function and you can think of a much
larger definition but it's all about you
know how the C functions uh we're all
familiar with the concept of human
health and and uh how we as humans
function and similar we think about uh
soils functioning in the context of of
uh this discussion of course the primary
function is for that soil is to to
produce a a good uh crop uh both uh high
quality and high high
quantities so what uh what are
characteristics of of a healthy soil and
in the same way we think of of a healthy
human being as as having um you know
blood pressure in a certain range 80
over you know 120 over 80 uh heartbeat
at a certain rate a cholesterol level at
a certain rate um so in terms of healthy
CS we can think of of all all of these
and this is certainly not an exhaus
exhaustive list so sufficient amount of
nutrients but not excess uh because that
can create problems environmentally or
or agronomically as well in some cases
good tail sufficient depth for good
rooting good water storage and and
drainage to get it through Dry and wet
periods free of harmful chemicals low
populations of plant disease and
parasitic organisms and uh Vice uh vice
versa higher populations of beneficial
organisms low wheat pressure resistance
to being degraded to say through
compaction or erosion and and a
resilient soil that that recovers
quickly from Adverse Events like uh like
excess water or hurricane or something
like
that so what's uh what's important to
sort of understand is is is our soal
health philosophy uh that we um that we
think in terms of the the three major
Realms the physical the chemical and and
the biological and and and the whole
point is that a healthy soil is is
balanced in in that respect and and
therefore provides for good growing
conditions and resiliency and and also
reduced
inputs um in general over the past uh
decades we've we've tended to
overemphasize the the chemical aspect of
the soil we've uh um and and and and not
to a fault necessarily but um we've
developed good testing procedures I
think most farmers and Growers know how
to how to use and manage the the
chemistry of the soil the the physical
aspects and especially the biological
aspect we haven't really paid nearly as
much attention to and yet these are also
very important component of of the
functioning of the soil so uh during
this uh this webinar I'm going to pay a
little bit more attention to the
physical and the biological
components so when we think in terms of
um the functioning of the soil we can
sort of parse that down to uh processes
so on this slide we uh we have the the
three Realms physical biological and
chemical and and to the site there you
see the different processes that are
critical for a soil to function well for
example uh physical support is is a
physical uh function irration is a
physical process water storage and
movement resistance to erosion root
proliferation and organism movement
those are all physical uh processes uh
that um that are affected by things like
compaction and um and aggregate
stability on the chemical realm the one
we're typically a little bit more
familiar with nutrient storage and
release soil reaction which relates
mostly to pH carbon storage and energy
which is the the important role of
organic matter that we'll discuss later
and then we have all those important
biological functions suppressing pests
and vice versa having beneficial
organisms nitrogen
mineralization organic matter
decomposition and uh supporting
microbial communities so we have these
these three Realms they do interact and
we'll we'll talk about that a little bit
later and uh but it's important that we
think in terms of the processes because
if any of these processes is compromised
for example if you have poor Iration and
there's a lot of lot of problems that
result from that for example more uh
more disease problems uh uh nutrient
deficiencies and and all those kind of
things so it's important that we think
in terms of
processes another concept that we need
to keep in mind is uh is that of
inherent versus Dynamic soil quality and
that not all soils are are the same that
way what do we mean with inherent soil
quality it's basically uh the idea that
soils are created differently that um uh
some soils are uh you know Sandy others
are maybe silt looms and yet others are
clay loms and this is really the result
of all these uh kind of natural genetic
C forming processes uh some CS are
naturally well- drained others are not
some are naturally high in organic
matter other are not so uh this is uh
sort of the the the basic soil quality
that is often also represented in the
soil survey information the dynamic soil
quality on the other hand relates more
to how uh how do soil uh has developed
as a result of management and we can
think of that in terms of both negative
and and positive directions so a a very
uh high quality soil may become very
degraded due to erosion or compaction or
a lot of intensive tillage over over
many years and so it may become a less
desirable and less well functioning soil
uh on the other hand you can improve a
soil as well you can take a soil that's
uh let say low in organic matter content
and over a period of five or six years
you can build that up to become a much
more high quality soil
when we when we talk about soal health
we primarily refer to this Dynamic soal
quality so uh that the part of the sore
quality that we can influence by
management the other component the
inherent sore quality is more more or
less a given you know you can't
necessarily change
that so uh again the inherent s quality
the results of some of these long-term
geologic biotic climatic and topographic
factors so this uh blue blueberry uh
field here is located in kind of a
valley environment with certain soil
types maybe grally or sandy soil as you
often find in the Northeast uh but the
soil say on this Hillside would be would
be very different they would have uh
quite different depth different organic
matter content different drainage uh
more susceptible to erosion Etc so
typically the the the first thing that
you want to do is is select a site that
has favorable soil conditions and you
can do that by using soil survey
information um the site selection I
would say is is is critical to
successful Berry management if you start
out with a soil that's inherently of low
quality you're just basically have an
uphill battle it's it's difficult to
overcome a lot of those
constraints um so what are some of those
inherent primary properties and I think
most of you are familiar with that uh in
terms of the physical ones Cal texture
of course is very uh very critical
whether you have a sand salt clay um or
anything in in between whether you have
a lot of stones and that uh that often
sort of sets the you know a lot of the
other important Cal
properties uh whether you have a problem
with internal drainage or not uh you can
modify that if you have a drainage
problem then you probably want to
install some drainage uh the depth of
the soil or presence of barriers for
example a
fragipan um that can sometimes be
modified but maybe a a major constraint
and then slope can also be an issue in
terms of the chemistry we have uh and
we'll come back to that we have a number
of nutrients that we're concerned about
pH is very important and even though a
lot of these can be corrected and and
modified um it's typically uh you know
if you start out with a soil for example
that's very
acidic it's uh it's often difficult to
overcome but another important point to
make of course is that especially with
berry production that that's that
certain uh crops favor a lower pH like
blueberries and others uh do not and so
uh that's all something that you have to
keep in mind salt accumulation is is not
as much of a concern here in in the
Northeast but in other parts of the
country or the world uh that can be a
major constraint very difficult to to
overcome and then we have a number of of
course biological components and
typically in terms of the the basic
primary properties that is expressed
through the the organic matter content
in the soil if you have higher organic
matter levels typically that soil is
healthier can support a lot uh more
diverse and uh and intensive biological
processes and we'll talk about that in a
few minutes
so much of that basic information on
these primary properties can be gathered
from s survey reports um this is um
selection of s surveys from the state of
New York uh some of them are are quite
old uh the early ones are from the 1930s
and then the most recent ones are from
the 1990s I think maybe even from uh
from uh Century um they provide you with
all that uh basic information about
texture pH available water capacity Etc
it tells you uh whether what the
suitability for use of Any of of those
soils is uh is it is it good Farmland uh
what are some of the constraints for
example uh but keep in mind that with
Insight variability may be a factor
these soils have been mapped uh by soil
surveyors but uh typically the the level
of detail that's uh that needs to be
considered for say the establishment of
an of an orchard or or or a berry
production field uh is is not quite
sufficient but it's a it's a very good
early start these Publications um are
available from extension offices for
from Soil and Water Conservation
District offices and uh natural
resources conservation districts and uh
and several other places often libraries
have them as
well uh but I wanted to point out that a
lot of this information now is available
also through the web uh through the
weburl
survey um site here's the the website
actually if you just Google web surl
survey you will get there and it allows
you to basically access S surfy
information uh for any location in in
the country what you would do is you
would start by uh pressing this uh
virtual button here that says start web
seral survey then you would uh get to um
through various screens you would get to
something like this let's say we're
interested in uh establishing some Berry
production on a field that we have
perhaps like here and um then we can get
a lot of basic information about that
soil from this web soil survey site so
on the left here you see uh this area is
an Ontario LOM 2 to 8% slope gives us
information on some basic
climatological information the uh
geomorphological setting of the soil
and uh some very basic
properties then we can uh get more
information uh for for this soil and
that's listed here on on the left uh the
basic chemical properties like calcium
carbonate content cation exchange
capacity uh pH gypsum level Etc now keep
in mind that uh this is sort of the
expected chemical properties is not
actually from this field it tends to be
from uh another C profile that is
representative of that field and it may
have been changed uh the previous user
may have changed the pH by lming or uh
the
uh the sodium absorption ratio may have
been changed so those are all things
that that at least you know provide a
starting point we see a lot of physical
properties they tend to be more uh
consistent so available water capacity
of bulk density allthough that may have
changed due to compaction uh organic
matter content uh texture Etc so there's
a lot of basic information also
including water table information that
uh is an excellent starting point that
you can access directly from the
web um now so that's uh that basically
relates to the inherent Cal properties
but um we typically want to get some
more detailed information not only uh
for it to be more site specific so
actually you know soal samples that were
collected from that particular field
where we're considering to establish uh
berries but also uh more uh detailed
information on the physical the
biological and the chemical components
of the soil and that's what the soil
Health test port Cornell soral Health
test basically attempts to do we've
selected
four physical indicators and physical in
our case is always indicated with the
letter blue or the the color blue
biological indicators also four
indicated in green and then the in
yellow The Chemical indicators the the
seral health test which will come back
to in later webinars of uh basically
uses the the standard seral nutrient
analysis and then has enhanced it with
uh four biological indicators organic
matter active carbon carbon potentially
mineralizable nitrogen and a root health
rating and then these four physical
indicators aggregate stability available
water capacity and heartness of the soil
in the surface and the
subsurface and then the test identifies
constraints and uh that then allows you
to uh take some management actions to
overcome those constraints so this is
just a basic introduction to that um but
one of the main points is that you know
the inherent
soal quality can be uh gathered from the
Cal survey information but the more
Dynamic soal quality or soal health you
want to get from from some more site
specific information like through a cal
Health
test okay so let's talk a little bit
about uh chemical uh processes most of
you I think are that's the area that
you're more familiar
with um there are a number of of
essential nutrients for plants on the
left we have
the uh the large the ones that are need
needed in larger amounts or
macronutrients including carbon oxygen
hydrogen which are basically around from
the air and water in the soil and then
we have the NPK nitrogen phosphorous
potassium calcium and mag magnesium and
sulfur that are needed in larger
quantities and any of these may be
limiting at any time on the right we
have the the micronutrients iron
manganese Etc and these are used in
relatively small
quantities um the the fortunate uh part
is that uh recommendations have been
developed over the past decades for the
management of all of these nutrients
typically what it requires is a is a
basic soil test and recommendations come
with that and uh it's a fairly
straightforward situation it's typically
relatively easy to correct any of these
uh deficiencies through the use of
fertilizer
uh pH tends to be a little bit more
tricky in in that uh Berry plants uh
favor different pH environments but also
uh the availability of various nutrients
is impacted by uh pH so on the right
here we have a scale from pH of 4 and a
half to eight and we see that different
nutrients nitrates potassium Etc are
available in uh more or less available
in different pH ranges for example
phosphates or phosphorus is not very
available either at very high pH or or
low PH calcium is is very available at
higher pH but not at the low PH where we
may have a lot of aluminum available and
in fact it may become
toxic iron uh very available at low PH
but not very available at high
pH um so at Etc so so pH is actually a
very critical component and and the
reason why I wanted to discuss this
separately is is that um from the uh
perspective of establishing berries you
need to address this upfront uh you got
to get to pH right uh from the start um
and before you establish the uh the
plans you have your your best
opportunity to correct any potential pH
problems again the soil test will
provide with the
recommendations um another concept that
we often talk about and those of you who
have taken a seral fertility class are
familiar with this is is the so-called
levix law of the minimum the idea is
that um that your yield or the the
ability of the of the plant to to be
productive is limited by the most
limiting nutrient so uh and it's
represented by this this bucket here in
our case uh nitrogen is the most
limiting nutrient
um and so the yield potential is limited
by the amount of nitrogen in the soil
this is here depicted by the the water
overflowing you can't get more water in
the bucket than the lowest level and the
most limiting
nutrient and so this is this is
generally generally true uh but there is
basically a broader perspective that we
now come to appreciate uh in the context
of soal health and that's basically that
it's not all about the soal chemistry
that it may actually be a physical or it
may be a biological process that is is
the most limiting factor in in the
production so it's uh it's not only
what's the most limiting chemical
element but it's all it's more what's
limiting otherwise so you may for
example have a very compacted soil and
there may be plenty of nutrients and you
may have actually applied a lot of these
uh these nutrients through fertilizer
but the fact that the soil is compacted
that the roots aren't growing well or
that you have Iration problems is uh is
then or has become the most limiting
element um Janet Fallon uh next week
we'll be talking about uh seral testing
and I won't go into a lot of detail uh
but an interesting uh point to keep in
mind is that that that a soil test is
basically an extraction procedure you
you um you you you basically extract
some of the elements through a solution
out of the soil that's you know being
filtered and then analyzed with various
equipment for example like an ICP or
something like that what's what's
important to keep in mind is that there
are uh many different so test solutions
that are being used around the country
even within the Northeast we have quite
a few uh different ones being used um
you know for example uh mik tree and
Morgan and modified Morgan are being
used uh around the Northeast it's
important to make the distinction
because the
interpretation of the Cal test results
and in this case for example it's for
phosphorus varies uh based on the type
of extraction that you use some of them
are more ex um aggressive extractants or
they're done at a different pH and so
you interpret the numbers differently
okay so for example um in a Morgan
analysis the optimum range is about for
Fosters is about 4 to 7 while the
equivalent for mik 3 is 15 to 31 so you
need to basically tie your soil test
results to the actual methodology that
was used in the testing procedure and
unfortunately For Better or Worse we're
using a lot of different procedures
around the region and and around the
country especially so keep that in mind
when you think about seral
testing okay let's move on to the uh
physical aspect aspects of the
soil so one of the the big factors
especially here in the Northeast that
that can you know limit the ability of
of of a of a a healthy plant is poor
internal drainage it can be the result
of uh either of local soil
hydrology uh because it's kind of in a
low spot in the landscape it can also be
because of impeding soil layers you may
have say a dense layer or a
fragipan that limits the percolation of
the water through the soil and thereby
causes poor drainage uh it's a big
problem poor drainage means poor
irration it uh tends to exacerbate
disease problems and all that and um and
if you are having or considering a a
field that has poor internal drainage uh
you either may may want to move to a
different field or you make sure that
you identify or that you that you
correct that problem through the
insulation of
drainage uh it is identif fing from
soral survey Publications I showed that
in one of the previous slides but I also
would uh always suggest because the
soral survey uh publication is is is
just kind of a first approximation to
also do some on-site s excavations if
you see modeling or you
know blotches of of iron rust or or
manganese which is which is it's black
blotches if you see that in the subur
you typically have a problem with the
fluctu waiting water table and therefore
you have imperfect
drainage um this will be a theme that
I'll be coming back to uh a lot of times
we ignore what's happening deeper in the
soil we tend to focus on on on the
surface oil but uh poor drainage is
often expressed a little bit deeper in
in the soil and so make sure you pay
attention to that we can of course
remediate uh poor internal drainage by
uh installing drain lines but also uh
race beds as you can see here on the on
the right now these are actually
Tomatoes um but I would I would suggest
with almost any type of um Berry
production that you want to use rais BS
um and and one of the reasons certainly
is to to improve the drainage or at
least during very wet periods it keeps
the um keeps the the roots of the of
your berries under aerobic conditions
and you prevent some of those problems
now keep in mind that in in in some
cases uh poor drainage is is not
necessarily related to soil layers or or
local soil hydrology but it can be a
symptom of of compaction so if you see a
lot of water sitting on the soil surface
um that maybe because the soils become
very degraded and compacted and it and
it and and the water doesn't move and
infiltrate through the soil uh which is
then a problem that you need to
separately address installing tile
drains doesn't necessarily solve that
problem you need to address that through
say organic matter additions or putting
in a cover crop or something like
that okay so um I always like to when I
talk about the physical properties of of
Cs I I like to uh discuss the importance
of of Aggregates um and here is a
picture of of a large aggregate uh
that's about of this
size um and uh as you can see that aggre
is made up actually of three sub
Aggregates okay as you can see
here and each of those three are then in
turn made up of other sub agregates okay
so there's typically a hierarchical
system in a well aggregated soil and if
you especially have a finer textured
soil like a like a silt or clay LOM and
this aggregation is very important
because it creates larger pores while
also maintaining these smaller pores
larger pores are important for drainage
and eration and for root
development small pores on the other
hand are important for moisture
retention and then we want some
intermediate pores as well so that we
basically have a range also important
for water retention a lot of the
biological functions lot the organisms
dwell in these intermediate Force so
what we'd like to see with a good soil
is this range of pores from large to
intermediate to small well what happens
when a soil becomes compacted you mostly
lose in that case these large pores and
so what problems do you then get well
you get problems with drainage you get
problems with
Iration and root proliferation becomes a
factor okay so um so compaction
basically uh creates a lot of problems
uh that in turn can create other
problems like higher disease pressure
Etc
okay
um a little bit about water availability
to to plants you know most of you I
think are familiar with the idea of of
you know a soil that's that has poor
Plant water availability like like a
beach sand because it only has large
large pores it doesn't have any small
pores um on the other hand you may have
a a clay Loom that has a lot of a lot of
small pores and so that has much better
ability to retain
water um so it is a function of uh
texture organic matter content however
is also a very important component of
this because organic matter can really
act as a
sponge thirdly rooting depth is
important if you have uh roots that are
constrained say to only uh the top six
Ines then they won't be able to access
the water and the nutrients that are
deeper in the soil so compaction is a is
a big problem in that respect it reduces
both uh root proliferation and water
access uh by the plants but we can
improve that and we'll talk about that
uh later in in the course we can use
things like deep ripping as you see here
this is a strip tail piece of uh
equipment uh we can add compost for
example to improve the structure and the
aggregation and and the rooting so there
are ways to to address
that hor soils in in our climates are
often associated with with good drainage
so like a grally LOM or or lomy sand or
something like that and they tend to
then have problems with with water
stress in most cases that's that's not
desirable only I think if you're growing
grapes uh you often want a little bit of
water stress but for most berries it's
not very desirable and that means that
you may have to in in in irrigation
there's some very good irrigation
systems available now um and a lot of
that requires some upfront
considerations uh so thinking ahead of
time of what the uh water storage
capacity of your soil is and whether you
need to invest in irrigation is is an
important
consideration okay so let's talk a
little bit about soil compaction uh on
the left you see a soil with good
rooting um The Roots extend uh both in
the surface layer as well as into the
subsoil and the deeper layers so that
means that this plant would have a lot
of water and nutrients available to it
also like to see you know fairly dense
rooting patterns on the right we see a
soil that has multiple compaction
problems first it has it may have a
crust on the surface which is uh this
often happens when the soil is exposed
to the elements especially the raindrops
and that reduces infiltration and causes
runoff and erosion problems it may also
have very tightly packed crumbs so we've
lost those large pores that are
essential for eras and water
transmission and um also it limits the
rooting so now we only have a few roots
and in this particular case We
additionally have a subur compaction
problem so the roots don't even go down
into the deeper layers and cannot access
the water and nutrients in those
layers so what are sort of the symptoms
well extended periods of saturation are
often a symptom of of compaction you see
that here on on the left that if you
have compacted layer you have the water
doesn't drain um standing water
following a rain or irrigation they all
may be indicators of plow layer
compaction um if the soil gets tilled
and of course you know you may only do
this uh at in the establishment phase
but if you see these big clouds uh
that's uh typically an indication of a
very compacted soil and uh that's uh
something that you want to want to
address um just tilling it and um and
you know say doing some primary tillet
but then say you know doing discing and
harrowing and pulverizing that soil
doesn't really address the problem
because soon enough that soil will
settle as you can see on the right here
it uh you know once once it gets wet it
will settle and it will become dense and
it will be hard and The Roots will have
problems growing through it okay so I
highly recommend doing some uh some
upfront work um and uh do a little
shovel take a shovel out or a
penetrometer or something like that and
and look and see whether you have any of
these problems because some of the past
management of that particular field you
know prior to establishing the the berry
plants uh may be uh may have caused
considerable compaction and you first
want to address that in
aate you know just there a little bit
more information on on that uh wanted to
show this to you uh this is actually
part of a video clip that I can't show
because of the limitation of the of of
the the webinar technology um but
there's two two important points one
that um a root is a certain Dimension
and especially the root tip and so you
need pores that are greater than2 mm for
a root tip to enter into a pore um and
it C first needs to wedge itself into
that pore and then it starts to push the
particles in the Aggregates to the side
and if that soil is very hard and it has
a strength of greater than 300 PSI then
it has great difficulty doing that so
for roots to grow well you need pores
that are greater than2 mm
and strength that is less than 300 PSI
and typically what that means is is a
well aggregated soil or a naturally
softer soil like a um like a Sandy uh
Sandy LOM or silt Loom type soil on the
right here you see an example of uh
where this was a problem uh there's a
big soil clot we see one root here uh
that sort of explored a little bit of
that soil it has some a few fine root
hairs but most of that soil is basically
not being explored by The Roots so the
water and nutrients that are in in the
rest of the soil volume are inaccessible
to the plant so that tends to cause more
stress for the
plant so what are some of the causes of
uh of plow layer compaction well
basically a loss of organic matter uh
and thereby aggregate stability uh
mostly from intensive tillage so so if
this field has a legacy of intensive
tillage maybe you know vegetable
production or potatoes or field crops
and low organic matter contents you're
going to have some of these type of
problems also of course if there's no
been been no organic matter addition so
if there's not a history of say manure
application or compost then you have
greater potential for problems if
there's been a lot of traffic when the
soil was wet a lack of control traffic
so basically the entire field was
compacted and if we had a lot of Cal
settling
from so those are some of the primary
causes and you may want to look at the
history of that field to see whether
that that was a problem so let's briefly
talk about uh subur compaction so now
we're we're considering not the the
surface layer but really the compaction
that's deeper in the soil and it tends
to be a little bit more difficult to
address and it's also it's very
invisible uh you don't see the subsoil
unless you really make an effort and you
dig down to
it um also a lot of people are not aware
of the causes of that and so uh if you
are in a field that has say a history of
heavy traffic like manure spreaders
especially on wet soils you may have a
problem with subal compaction of deeper
the deeper layers may have become very
very dense because the the the loads
from this heavy equipment are basically
transferred deeper into the soil and
when that soil is wet it can pack
them um this is especially a problem if
there's a poor weight distribution of
the equipment so some of the more modern
equipment have less of a problem um but
uh if this field has a history of the
kind of stuff you see on the left here
you probably have a fairly serious sub
compaction in addition to having
compaction near the surface
if there's been a history with uh of
plowing because a lot of plowing occurs
with the wheel in the open Furrow which
means that the subsoil is directly
compacted um so it's definitely
something to look into with say a
penetrometer
um some digging so it's important to
consider where the compaction is and
these penetrometers they're relatively
inexpensive tools it cost a little over
$200 something you can borrow them from
an extension agent or a or a sood and
water specialist are very valuable tools
and they are also an integral part of
our Coral seral Health test if you have
that uh deep Cal compaction maybe some
deep Tilles needed deep rooted cover
crop maybe needs to be established
before you uh you transplant your
berries um shallow compaction requires a
different strategy than deep compaction
and that's why it's important to measure
where the compaction is and we'll come
back to this in in
the seminars later in the
program okay so we talked about the the
chemical the physical and now uh let's
discuss the the C biology this is a the
component of the C that uh that that's
still very much at at the frontier of of
science uh CS are extremely
complex um and have very very able
conditions but we do know that most of
the biological activity occurs near the
surface the reason being uh that that's
where the most of the organic matter is
from uh basically often from the uh the
plant sources that that decay and the
organic matter decreases as we go
further into the soil and thereby also
the biological activity decreases
considerably we often and we I mean Fred
magdoff and I and we co-authored a book
that I'll I'll refer to a little bit
later we like to think in terms of
organic matter as as three General types
the Living Dead and the Very dead and
I'll talk about each of those
individually uh but all three are very
important in terms of the functioning of
the soil and to produce high yields and
healthy crops so let's first start
talking about the The Living
Part um oh no let's see there's a quick
overview of each of those I'm sorry I'm
getting ahead of myself so the the
living component of the soil is is what
is alive in the soil basically uh so
these organisms uh they play important
roles in making nutrients available
suppressing disease producing plant
growth uh promoting hormones creating
humus aggregating soils and there
probably a few other things we can
mention another living component is
plant roots they are also it's the below
ground part of the of the plants and
they also are are typically very
beneficial and of course they're they're
needed for the plants to
grow the Dead part relates to the
recently dead organisms and crop
residues that provide basically the
energy and nutrients uh for the so
organisms to live and function also
often call this active or particulate
organic matter okay so this is the the
food that sustains the system
the third component is is basically the
fraction of the organic matter that's
that's not as active biologically that
has become very well
decomposed but that is really quite
recalcitrant and we often refers to that
as as humus or the kind of black
material in the soil uh but it's also
very beneficial primarily in terms of
supporting some of the physical and
chemical functions it has a high amounts
of negative large so it allows it to
hold nutrients it allows it to hold
water and it also stores a lot of the
the
carbon so let's look at each of those in
a little bit more detail so the living
here and you know we can uh we can teach
an entire course on this it's all those
organisms like the bacteria fungi
nematodes earthworms mites springtails
moles and many other organisms that are
in the soil that all uh play a very very
important role in terms of seral food
web they all
interact in often very very complex ways
and then of course the plant roots as
you as you can see here on the left you
have the the
microorganisms uh on the right here you
have these these might call
Critters colon bone col balls the
spiders the mites Etc and then we might
even have things like earthworm or even
even you know macroorganisms like like
moles that of course also impact
soil these organisms use the resources
in the soil that's where they live they
decompose organic matter they cycle
nutrients and they influence plants and
and all the other
biota they respond to chemical and
physical environment so if you for
example have a very compacted soil so
unfavorable physical environment uh you
will have many uh you will have less
organisms and less diversity uh for
example if you have a soil like you see
here in in the middle picture very
compacted exposed to the elements uh so
therefore uh the organisms have to deal
with heat and moisture extremes as
opposed to a situation here where we
have compost on the soil and soil is
protected it's a much more favorable
requirement if you have say low PH or
high pH age that all impacts these
organisms but vice versa these organisms
also affect uh the chemical and physical
environment they can be beneficial for
example if you have a lot of plant roots
or you have a lot of um
um organisms that that decompose organic
matter that creates better aggregation
so better physical environment better
Iration better water transmission Etc so
it goes both ways um the organisms uh
respond to the environment and they
manipulate the
environment uh there's there's some
organisms that are are are particularly
not worthy one is micro risey and these
are those are basically uh fungi and
with with extended hyy as you can see in
this this picture that in a way you can
think of as a symbiotic relationship
with plant roots that can extend the
plant roots into to the soil and all and
basically facilitate better nutrient uh
acquisition and and use so they enhance
nutrient
uptake phosphorus nitrogen potassium and
micronutrients but especially phosphorus
is often very uh very much enhanced by
micro Rising uh they help at soil
aggregation form uh of defense against
pathogens protect plants against
phytotoxicity and enhance Fitness in in
so micro
rizy and especially in in soils that are
not Disturbed can be very
beneficial another important uh concept
is that of of suppressive
soils that um we often have problems
with certain diseases pythium phyra
ronia Etc and um if we create a healthy
soil with uh lots of organisms
beneficial organisms like camonis and
traderma um they actually provide an
ability to suppress some of these
calborn pathogens basically by either uh
a direct um suppression or basically by
uh a larger abundance and and sort of
out competing some of these pathogen
organisms so having a a rich soil uh
often can be very beneficial in terms of
producing
as
pressure so how do management practices
affect soil life well intensive tillage
reduces micro isic colonizations reduces
diversity of soil organisms so tillet is
often uh not favorable for healthy soils
organic matter application is favorable
it increases diversity density and
activity of these organisms fertilizer
application uh um affects the uh
various organisms it proliferates the
growth of fast growing Mar organisms
typically more bacteria but reduces say
fungi and it reduces say nitrogen
fixating organisms as well and
irrigation and drainage of course
affects the anerobic versus aerobic
organisms so we talked about the living
now a little bit about about the dead
organisms uh so that's basically crop
residues and and
dead plant roots and all that and think
of that as the food that sustains these
organisms in the soil these are
nutrients and and energy that help uh
feed these organisms that are so
important so the soil food web which is
depicted here uh we're not talking about
a food chain but a more complex food web
where um multiple organisms are involved
in um in the use of of basically this
organic matter so it's the or organic
matter in the soil uh that may be
applied through manure or compost or
maybe Dead uh roots or Surface material
that basically feeds all these other
organisms bacteria fungi
nematodes uh that in turn affects all
these other organisms like protozoa
arthropods and so you kind of go up the
food web and the food chain um but the
important point here is that if you
don't Supply this organic matter if it's
not there then these organisms cannot
Thrive and that's what often is referred
to as the bottom up effect or the
abundance of a resource affects the
abundance of its consumers and think of
it in terms of the human analogy if we
did not feed ourselves and get our
energy and nutrients we would not Thrive
either and so it's just as important in
in the
soil so the very dead component then is
the is is this well decomposed material
uh you often see that as sort of the the
black part of the soil the dark part um
and so it is very important for water
holding capacity but also to retain cat
ions um and um and so it especially in a
sandy soil increasing the humus content
allows for better water and nutrient
storage
an important point I think by now I
think uh has been that that we have this
interaction of the physical the chemical
and the biological so in the past
because we focused so much on the
chemical um we didn't have the all these
benefits of these interactions now based
on the discussions I'll give you five
seconds to think of any examples of how
each of these Realms interact
I wish I could ask you how many of you
could come up with one or two or three
but here are a number that uh that I uh
that I came up with and I've indicated
that blue is being a physical process
green being a biological process and
yellow being a chemical process so for
example hard soil a physical process
reduces
rooting ped soil suppresses beneficial
biological processes
also increases root diseases and
denitrification both biological
processes organic matter decomposition
of biological processes process
increases aggregation etc etc okay uh
tillage in the bottom here increases
bacteria and decreases fungi so there's
many ways in which these interact and I
think the the point is that if you know
with our past emphasis on the chemical
part we've often not given enough
consideration for these biological and
physical components so I think it's
become clear I think that uh adding
organic matter results in in many
benefits and this is a depiction it's
actually from a picture from Lori
drinkwater in the horiculture department
all the benefits of adding organic
matter it increases biological activity
and composition nutrient release
detoxifies harmful substances it
increases
aggregation uh it promotes hum humus and
other growth promoting substances
increases Poe structure improv soil uh
Toth and water storage and all in all
healthier plants okay so this is just
the general
that um so a couple more points I wanted
to make is that uh is is what has
happened over the past decades is that
it's been a different Paradigm in in
soil management um so in in the old days
certainly in terms of the natural
ecosystems they evolved with little
disturbance they were either forest or
grassland or something like that
nutrients were recycled through organic
materials like leaves and animal
droppings the decomposing materials
would be feeding the soil it would be
nutrients and carbon and stimulated
diverse biological activity and then
this organic material was then
mineralized by all these uh or organisms
and that in turn would feed the plants
so uh so the plants were in a way fed
indirectly the nutrients and the energy
came from the surface was processed by
these organisms and that in turn fed the
plants in modern agriculture with the
onset of the use of
fertilizer uh We've started to disturb
the soil through a lot of tillage and so
we accelerated organic matter
mineralization and we have now lower
organic matter levels in the soils and
we use chemical fertilizers where we
basically feed to plant
directly rather than indirectly through
the addition of organic materials and so
uh We've stopped feeding all the so
organisms so we've seen over the decades
uh a very big difference in terms of the
Ecology of the soil and that's why the
physical and the biological processes in
the cils have become very compromised
because of those
practices so few important points
inherent versus Dynamics or equality
okay so what we get is a natural soil
versus how we manage it and we're going
to focus especially on this Dynamic soil
health component physical chemical and
biological and I think by now I hope you
sort of appreciate the importance of all
of those components and they are equally
important a little bit about pre and
post establishment and I'll talk about
that in the next couple of slides
because that's an important
consideration from a management
perspective remember both the surface
and the subsoil are
important and also we have to think in
terms of short-term and long-term
management a lot of the chemical
management is short-term there's a
There's a constraint say low phosphorus
levels we apply fertilizer problem
solved with soil Health we often have to
look at a more long-term
approach so when it comes to Berry
production most opportune time for seral
health Improvement is typically prior to
planting uh installing drain tiles
correcting sub cural
fertility PHH maybe deep ripping or
other types of deep tillers compost
applications cover cropping all prior to
establishment that's when you have the
opportunity to address a lot of these
constraints and keep keep in mind that
subcell properties are not always that
visible or any constraint that you might
have okay but they are important for
perennial
crops and then of course you still have
opportunities for post establishment Cal
Health Management like for example
continuous supply of of compost using
mulches to protect the
soil uh to promote good uh biological
activity sometimes we can use the
interos for say cover crops uh as you
see in this particular case these are
grape Vines so we have to distinguish a
little bit between pre and post
establishment so this is my final slide
uh just some reference material here is
our uh the website uh for the seral
health program is listed here and uh
when you go there you see you get to
this point there's a lot of other sites
that that go with that you can download
the seral Health Training manual which
we'll refer to at a later point in time
and uh if you're interested in a broader
perspective on seral Health Management
this is a book that I co-authored with
Fred magdoff from the University of
Vermont titled building soils for better
crops which is really about about
sustainable so management or or soil
Health Management um it's available from
the sustainable EG Network it can also
be downloaded as a PDF file um from
their website and so with that Jeff I'll
hand it back to
you all right thanks Harold um and this
is where we enter our Q&amp;A period and and
I encourage you if you have any
questions to type them into the chat box
and we'll address them as they come uh
there were a few questions early on
Kathy asked the question what is soil
tilth uh soil tilth um um is basically
relates to the kind of the aggregation
structure of of of the soil
so a a soil that has good uh soil tills
is is not compacted it has these
Aggregates um and it typically if you
disturb the soil it it it don't doesn't
come up as clots but it comes up as nice
Frable material that's maybe the best
way to characterize that I think of C
tilt to some extent as as
aggregation okay and a second question
can a fragipan layer be fixed by
subsoiling um that's a good question yes
you can you can initially you know
depending on the depth of the of the
fraer pan layer if it's very deep uh
let's say you know uh 2 and A2 ft then
it's difficult to get down that far um
but if it's a shallow layer you can but
they do tend to reform so it's um if you
were considering establishing berries on
on a frag pan soil I would definitely do
that tillage the the the deep tillage
but they do tend to reestablish over a
longer time period and I'm talking more
maybe 8 to 10 or
years thanks Harold I have a question of
my own um you talked about surface
compaction versus uh uh compaction in
the in the deeper layers
and now there's you know a lot of
discussion about the use of cover crops
uh to deal with uh compaction issues can
you comment on cover cropping use for uh
compaction
modification yeah so um you know when we
think about cover crops we uh we have to
have to consider what really our
objective is with the use of a cover
crop so if we have a compaction problem
near the surface we might uh want to use
a very dense and fibrous cover a crop uh
like a like Ry grass or something like
that if we have a compaction deeper in
the soil we want to get want to use a
cover crop that has strong roots that go
deeper into the soil um for example
alala Roots do that um there's a lot of
interest in using say radishes that uh
that very aggressively grow deeper into
the soil as well um so so when it comes
to to cover cropping you really have to
think about what your primary objective
is and you know compaction relief is
only one of of uh several you may also
want to consider um adding nitrogen or
you want to use a cover crop so you get
some mulch um so like for example the
picture that I showed of the um of the
The Vineyard that had um that had um Ry
growing in the in the inter Rose they
use that then to uh they cut that and
they use that
to spread that over over the over the
Cal service um so you have all these
different objectives with with cover
crops which is you know an interesting
point in and by itself if you're
interested uh in in using cover crop
there there is a great
publication and I believe it's titled
managing cover crops profitably it's
also published by the sustainable egg
Network I know many of you are probably
familiar with it for those of you who
are not uh that is really an outstanding
publication and it it IT addresses the
management of cover crops from the
perspective of what your objectives are
you know nitrogen management compaction
relief you know uh surface cover Etc so
that's I'm sorry Jeff that's a bit a
little bit of a long-winded uh answer
but uh you know there's cover crops and
there's cover crops and you want to make
sure that you select the right one for
the problem that you're trying to
address well thank you very much and I
think Tom borkman also had has a
web-based tool that uh does a pretty
good job of describing the attributes of
different cover crops right uh Kathy in
the meantime had a uh a comment or
question related to subsoiling and its
uh use for crops like strawberries or
raspberries that have maybe a shorter
shorter time frame than something like
blueberries um can you cut yeah uh yeah
perhaps I'm somewhat misrepresented this
in that there's um there's various
components to it when you when you think
about
um subing to overcome a frag pan then
you you do allow those roots to move
into that frag pan and even though the
frag pan May somewhat re
reestablish once the roots are in there
they are there basically and um so the
subsoiling is is is is always beneficial
even though you know with blueberries
maybe you're looking at a much longer
time Horizon it's it's those first years
that are most critical so that you can
get those roots down there so uh I think
it's in almost all cases it's it's
beneficial do the sub soiling if you
have a fagy
pan thank you I have an additional
question you mentioned a couple of
situations tillage uh was one of them
where where you're favoring um bacteria
over fungi you also mentioned that the
use of fertilizer does the same thing uh
does does developing a cover crop
actually work in the opposite direction
of boosting the the fungi
population yes it it it it it tends to
especially if you don't do a lot of
disturbance you know I when we talk
about cover crops one thing you try to
prevent doing a lot of tillet to is
establish a cover crop so you'd like to
do it with with equipment that uh you
know like a noil drill or something like
that um I think with with with very
production of course you you don't do uh
much tillage maybe only early on but I
think what's critical is to think about
the history of that site so if there's
been a lot of P tillage then uh then it
has impacted uh bacteria versus fungi
bacteria being more common with with
intensively tilt and fertilized fields
and you know when you have uh say Berry
production you would like to like to see
you know more fungi because of the the
benefits that it that it provides it
will of course change over time because
once you establish your field and your
your your your berries you will um you
won't do much intensive tillage and if
you manage it well and you supply your
organic materials you will see a gradual
change in in the biology of of that soil
I'm waiting to see if uh an has a
question here Ann has a long question I
can
see oh she it's more of a comment for
everyone else yeah
yeah um and this is putting you on the
spot but you know that there are um a
number of companies that sell products
um I guess you would call them
soil amendments or plan enhancing
products uh and it's unfair to ask this
question but uh you you've talked about
the biology of the soil and how
important it is uh do you do you see any
research that shows benefits of some of
these
products um in terms of products that
are that are um you know more commercial
products um that are sold at maybe like
the regional or national level um you
know not very much I mean you know the
um if if the soil is low in in organic
matter content there are are a number of
ways to address that you know say
compost sometimes if you have uh manure
that's available say from a nearby dairy
farm or some other livestock Farm uh
that can be very beneficial as well uh
products that are more commercially sold
uh you know some humic assets are sold I
haven't seen any research really that
supports that in in a very significant
way and and I would say I would want to
compare that with say you know a compost
application uh you sometimes hear about
remineralizing soils be mineralizing
it's a kind of a diff difficult word um
where um where basically that's more
geologic material is it's is being
added that will only be uh you can only
justify that if you if you really do
have uh deficiencies in uh in some of
these plant
nutrients a lot of times it's it's uh
much easier to address that with
fertilizer if you're organic producer
and that's not an option you really want
to do some C testing first and see
whether those those elements are really
limiting before you buy something like
that and in the meantime Vern has a
question are there practical ways to
optimize micro rizy and Berry plantings
other than avoiding high PE and
tillage
um burn I think this is uh I'm getting
on thin eyes here it's it's a little bit
beyond my my expertise when it comes to
Berry
plantings um typically having a a
healthy soil with with with good biology
will
basically um favor the development of of
Ry in in a system that's that's not
Disturbed basically once you have that
established uh I believe there are
inoculant being sold uh but
um I you know i' really have to find out
actually I'm not an expert on that
perhaps some other people that are in
here maybe Marvin britz maybe knows that
people who have a little bit more
management experience with
this B perhaps you know you know
yourself uh I know Marvin is is is
typing right
now and while we're waiting for them to
respond I think we'll switch to
the last screen that we have for you to
view today and encourage you all um to
uh attend future meetings that we're
having coming up here
and if you haven't already filled out
the demographics or the pretest please
do
so and and I can see that Marvin's
response is here um not aware of any
strong data indicating that these
inoculant work especially in healthy
soils I do want to thank our presenter
Harold vaness thank you very much
Harold you're welcome our pleasure and I
want to uh tell you that the next
portion of this uh series is next week
on October 14th from 2: to 3:15 in the
afternoon it will be Janet Fallon she'll
be talking to us about soil sampling
procedures and soil
testing uh with
that we're going to be signing
off I will mention uh this one last
comment here uh from Glen ker and he's
talking about perennial CR such as fruit
trees a general guideline about
balancing between use of inorganic
versus compost as a source for soil
nutrient management thank you very much
Glenn right and with that I'm going to
uh end the
session I do want to say to you uh I'm
going to leave this open so that you can
download both the demographics and the
preest uh take the time to do that and
or if you want to check out the web
links link up to them save them for
future
reference uh and I hope to see you uh
next week thank you very
much
e
e e
Jeff and Harold I want to thank you both
you did a great job
[Music]
can you hear me Cassy
yes okay I I sorry I had already loged
off and U I had somebody outside the
door uh but yeah I did it go well did it
uh I I know I was a little concerned
that I was a little rushed or um or was
it not the case no I thought it was
great and I I took tons of notes so
there was plent there was plenty of time
to think about things and
whatever okay ex great excellent good
thank you so much I hope it set the
stage for uh all all those other women
Arts that are going to be following
absolutely
okay Jeff if you're talking to us we
can't hear you for some
reason okay I'm I am I'm going to log
off then all right thanks so much Harold
thanks a lot yeah I I'm glad it went
well it was it was fantastic great thank
you
okay Jeff I still can't hear you are you
there oh yeah I was answering a question
from room D oh
okay hey uh yeah it went pretty well
Harold did a great job yeah it went
fantastic absolutely all right so uh all
the bases were covered then we're next
week I didn't forget anything I guess is
my question nope I don't believe so