Hi, welcome. Thank you all for joining
today. Um, I'm really excited to present
on one health and you'll see why in a
moment of why I'm really passionate
about this topic. Uh, to get us started
though, get me my slides will advance.
There we go. I'm going to tell you a
little bit about myself. So, my name is
Sharon Toth. I'm a county for agent in
Hunter County, New Jersey, which I
realize when I say that that doesn't
mean anything unless you're from New
Jersey, but it's this little red dot
over here. It is uh borders
Pennsylvania. So, I'm about 15 minutes
from
Pennsylvania. And I work for Rucker
Cooperative Extension or Ruckers
University. That's our land grant
institution.
I received my bachelor of science in
evolutionary anthropology from Ruckers
and then my PhD in biological
anthropology from the University of
Pittsburgh. And I like to say that I
transfer lies by merging researcher
methodologies with educator techniques.
And I feel like I will represent that
through my talk today. And my background
always looks like why how did I get into
4 with an anthropology degree? But it's
because I was a lifelong 4er and I
really valued the experiences that I
learned in 4 and through extension and I
wanted to bring back that information to
my community that I learned in
school. So my presentation today is
going to have three main areas. I'm
going to define what one health is and
why it's important. I'm going to talk
about what I did during my research days
as a PhD student and then how I apply
that to being a county for
agent. So what is one health? We keep
using this term but what does it really
mean? It is a collaborative or intercon
in interconnectedness of human animal
and environmental health. It's a
multi-disciplinary approach that
recognizes that the health of people,
animals, and the environment are all
connected. We're not siloed from each
other. It brings to together experts
from all different fields from human
medicine, veterinary medicine,
environmental science, and beyond to
solve complex health problems like
zunotic diseases, food safety, and
climate change. So some examples that we
see of one health and how we see it
every day in our society is aven flu
that's very prominent right now COVID
rabies West Nile virus limes disease EC
coli salmonella lististeria climate
change contamination deforestation
pollution all these have an impact on
human health animal health and
environmental health they all
interconnect this ven diagram I believe
does a really great job of representing
what how one health connects
together. So here's a simplified version
I really like to educate with. It's
shows cows graze next to lettuce field
and cows can carry ecoli but still look
healthy. Then the E.coli from cow manure
in the nearby farm can contaminate the
lettuce field. And then people eat
contaminated lettuce and can become
infected with E.coli and then serious
illness or even sometimes death can
result. So this is just a really
simplified version of how those animals
health a human animal and the
environment all connect.
And one of my favorite examples is that
of the development of insulin for
diabetes. So this is a life-saving
example because of the anatomical and
clinical similarities in the dog and
human prank pancreas. It aided in the
development of
insulin. So in the early 1920s,
scientists studied dogs to understand
how the pancreas regulates blood sugar.
They discovered that removing the
pancreas caused diabetes and that
insulin from healthy pancreases could
restore balance and it was a major
medical
breakthrough. So this research directly
led to the first effective treatment for
for diabetes in humans saving millions
of lives. So early insulin was made
using pancreases from cows and pigs and
it was turning that fatal disease into a
manageable one people can live
with. And this has connects to the
environment though because early
production relied on h animal byproducts
linking insulin to agriculture and
livestock practices. But eventually
concerns over supply and sustainability
led to biotech innovations that now
produce uh synthetic insulin that still
today is used for millions of lives. And
then why people who have diabetes can
continue on living a normal
life and I personally like that model
because it does use a dog model and this
is what I used in my research when I was
a PhD student. So a lot of times when we
think of animal models, we may think of
using pigs. We see that a lot or maybe
mice, but different animal models exist
for different reasons. So for dogs, it's
specifically interesting because they
share 80% of diseases with us. And
mostly of the nearly 400 inherited
disorders characterized in dogs are
relevant to humans.
So they make them an excellent model for
numerous human diseases such as cancer,
osteoarthritis, aging, and for me it was
knee ligament rupture. So I studied the
ACL in the knee and I'll go into that a
little bit more and they have a very
similar structure. It is the gold
standard for us and it has it because of
the hisytological
similarity and also with dogs beyond
sharing similar diseases they are a
useful model due to accessibility. They
live in diverse environments like
humans. They share the same environments
with us. So they're exposed to the same
bacteria, pollutants and toxins and they
exhibit breed specific diseases some
that are very rare in humans like
sarcomomas.
They also have the appearance of
spontaneous diseases as opposed to being
induced like in mice and they age five
to eight times faster than humans aiding
in a disease timeline allowing for
observation of disease onset and
condensed study time. Dogs are also the
most physically diverse species and have
the most known naturally occurring
diseases of all land man land mammals
after humans.
So I use them to study the ACL and knee
because of all these similarities and
their usefulness in modeling human
research. So the main intention of my
study was to correlate biological
variables and ACL rupture patterns by
using comparative anatomy of human and
dog knees. The predisposition factors
for non-cont ACL rupture is not really
well understood. Basically the force
twisting motion of this ligament in the
knee does not produce consistent rupture
patterns. This research aids to reduce
future ACL rupture incidence rates while
mutually benefiting humans and medicine
uh human and animal medicine
further. So sometimes we hear the dog
term CCL versus ACL. It means the same
thing. They're called homologous
structures, which means they have
similar structures due to shared
ancestry. And comparable to humans, some
dogs rupture this ligament at a greater
rate than others. And 80% of ruptures
are non-cont, similar to that 70% in
humans. And we see that spayed female
dogs are at the highest risk of CCL
rupture. And both spayed or neutered
dogs, regardless of sex, have
significantly higher rupture rates than
sexually intact dogs. And the reason for
these rupture disparities in dogs is
unknown like in
humans. So why is this all important?
Why do we care about how about our knee?
Why don't we just say, "Well, we'll
brace it. It'll be fine." It's because
mo muskeletal conditions affect 1.7
billion people in the world and it
contributes to nearly 166 million years
lived with disability and make the
largest proportion of persistent pain in
all geographical regions and age groups.
Muscularkeeletal conditions are the
leading cause of disability worldwide.
And the reason for early leave or
retirement from work, contributing to
less financial security is also lack of
physical activity can contribute to
declined mental health and physical
health. Knee injuries are also the
second most commonly injured site after
the ankle with the ACL ruptures
accounting for over 50% of those
injuries.
Men account for the majority of ACL
ruptures, but women are more likely to
rupture it at a two to eight times
greater rate. While surgical
interventions and rehab or common
practice, only about 50% of people will
return to their full pre-injury injury
state. So this increase this increases
rehabilitation and surgical costs and
less chance of full sports into
reintegration or even mobility.
And as a female, I find this
specifically interesting because they're
at a two times greater rate to rupture
their
ACL and especially for ages 15 to 19
years old. And female sports
participation has increased more than
1,000% since the passing of Title 9.
that where all institutions that receive
federal money must offer equal access to
curricular and extracurricular
activities for men and women. And nearly
8 million students currently participate
in high school sports with continuously
rising numbers over the past 29 years
and female participation an all-time
high with more than 3.4 million
athletes.
This increase in female participation
suggests ACL studies prior to Title N
were really focused only on men and that
we don't have an equal
representation. And only in the past 30
years uh since 1993 did the NIH mandate
that their funds be used for women and
men in their
studies. And also women only represent
4% of orthopedic surgeons.
So throughout the study I use golden the
golden retriever lifetime study done by
the Morris research foundation and what
I found was that it was a
multiffactorial process. There was no
one cause for it and that it was hor
hormone regulations played a large piece
which is impacted by our environment and
that that impacted growth and
development on bone structure and how we
function and move. So that was a really
quick summary of what I did. But how do
I apply this all? What does that have to
do with extension? How do I apply this
to my 4 teaching? I'm so glad you asked.
So I implement one of the most popular 4
curriculum that we see, which is 4
embryology. This is very popular across
the nation and that is where youth hatch
eggs in the classroom to learn about
growth and development and this relates
directly to one health. So from the
animal perspective, they're getting
youth are getting investment in another
life. They're seeing the growth and
development of an animal. From humans,
they're also seeing the zunotic
diseases. They're learning about
biocurity and the importance of
maintaining a healthy environment for
the animals and themselves. And in the
environment especially, they're seeing
how the environment impacts development.
like I saw in my dissertation research,
how development impacts our bone
structures and hormonal impacts. That's
the same here with embryology just on a
smaller scale. They also talk about
sustainable farming and food systems.
So, how do we be sustainable farmers
while we produce food to feed our nation
and our people?
And then I also do a workshop called
bone vage exploring domestication
through bone. So my background in
anatomy and
osteology which is where workshops where
participants learned about
domestication. So from that animal and
human perspective they're learning about
the symbiotic relationship the shared
relationship we have with each other and
how we pro improved health with each
other. We helped animals improved their
health but they also helped us through
domestication processes. And then also
we talk about the impact on bone
preservation which is the term
tethphonomy. So why is it so hard like
you can see in this photo to recognize
when an animal has been
domesticated. It's not always easy.
There's no defined aspect that goes this
animal has been domesticated. So it's a
very gradual change. And so I do a
workshop where youth get to part work
with bones hands on. So right here
they're holding a horse femur and they
get to understand what the
anatomy looks like. And then we use
paper cutouts. So they get to create
their own animal after they make uh
their the original animal. So this one
here is a beaver, a rabbit, and a dog.
And they have to give the background
information of why they do
that. And then I have a pug here because
I talked about that improved health. So
dogs being that highly diverse species,
they being the mostly diverse species on
Earth, it's because we've bred them so
widely. Pugs have that flat face. It's
called brachiophalic and why they have
hard time breathing. And that gives us a
lot of information on respiratory
diseases. And if you don't have an
animal science program in your county,
that's all right. One health still
applies. So you can talk about one
health and for technology such as AI's
impact on society. So when you talk
about AI, you can talk about the
benefits and dangers to society, but
also the environmental impact. So the AI
data centers take a lot of water and
power to produce. So this talking about
while they might benefit us, it can
really endanger our environment. So it's
important to talk about this
all-encompassing product of human,
animal, and environmental health
together. We're not siloed from each
other. So thank you very much for
joining me. Uh here's my information if
you would like to contact me more. And
I'm just gonna quickly drop this link
into the chat if you don't mind. It's a
two question answer. I'd love for you to
take time to answer that. Thank you.
So Sharon, I have a quick question for
you. Yep. Can you bring to life uh the
contemporary issue of bird flu uh with
climate change and one health? Just sort
of give us that sort of synopsis.
Could you could you I'm sorry. Could you
uh rephrase? Sorry.
So, uh the bird flu and the environment,
how climate change and bird flu are are
coming together and as it relates to one
from a one health perspective of
analyzing it. Oh, perfect. So, the aven
flu being so prominent now, we know it's
a zunotic disease. It can spread easily.
Humans, birds, and swine can spread
through each other. While we don't we're
not seeing many cases in the disease
spreading to humans, there have been
cases even in our county where it was
found in feral cats. So the environment
plays a part because most of avian flu
is being spread by wildlife. So when
they fly over uh chicken coupe and they
they poop and it comes down into your
coupe that's spreading the disease
further. So by having precautions and
biocurity is the big thing of protecting
your coupe. So making sure if you walk
you go to visit somebody's coupe for
instance you are not wearing the same
type of shoes that you wear to your
coupe. Your coupe those are the only
shoes that ever go to your coupe and
that they stay on your property. And if
you ever go to somebody else's, you make
sure to sanitize and clean for the
safety and it reduces the spread of that
disease
elsewhere. Are there any other
questions? I hope I answered that.
Please let me know if I was not clear on
that.
This has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu.