this is a production of Cornell
University uh I'm very excited to be
here I'm also a little uneasy because uh
as Kevin mentioned I am uh very broad uh
broadly trained macro ecologist um
sometimes I think I'm a conservation
biologist definitely not a PL scientist
so uh bear with me some uh some
information may be uh spotty in terms of
uh maybe what is uh the core interest uh
for you so um to put to put my uh
presentation in perspective it's all
about new ways um to study or
investigate an old questions an old
question where uh why are species
distributed or found where they are and
I'd like to start with with uh an
inspiring uh quote uh that uh pushes
biologists or at least in 1985 IO Wilson
was pushing biologists to to take on
this Grand Challenge of trying to
describe and trying to uh to learn more
about about diversity uh in general uh
worldwide so uh in the words of IO
Wilson um this is a mission worth uh all
our effort so that was 1985 not too long
ago uh then in 2010 another great
enologist um came back to tell us that
it is uh critical it is very important
to try to study diversity on our planet
and maybe what we need is a a grand
approach the type of approach and the
type of of um um funding and resources
that uh NASA has so uh you know some
years ago 15 years after EO wison um
called uh all scientists to study
diversity and focus on that uh 15 years
later uh the message was uh very similar
or even uh Stronger now um another appro
another message that is related to
trying to understand trying to study uh
diversity and um and uh basically
provide a justification for this effort
uh is from the uh from the world of um
ecosystem science and valuation of uh
ecosystem services so the idea here is
we do want to know as much as we can
about species and it is uh worth
investing our time because our
understanding of species distribution
and function and ecosystems actually in
the end uh overall affect uh human uh
life uh quality so so basically put a
spin to our type of research that that
um makes the public more interested and
more aware of why we study uh diversity
uh
patterns okay uh just to give you a very
brief um schematic view of what I do and
then uh a cloud of uh of words that are
more uh common or abundant in in uh my
publication so far I am as I said
broadly speaking interested in
interested in species distributions and
uh factors that affect species
distributions and I use um several ways
of of um addressing questions that are
related to uh species distributions and
then um the uh understanding our
understanding of species distributions
does um Branch out into many different
fields and I'm just naming a few here
conservation biology uh biogeography and
disease ecology the more uh recent
ones okay so what I want to do today is
give you an idea of the kind of work
that I do and maybe spark some interest
in uh you're using some of these methods
for your your own research and my plan
is to go down uh spatial scale from
broad scale questions to maybe Regional
uh all the way to fine scale you'll
notice that I have one here the last the
fin finest scale uh question in gray
area uh gray uh font and that is because
we are just starting to work uh more on
this uh at this level on this scale and
we have more questions and more data to
collect can analyze than actually uh
giving you uh uh answers okay now to uh
in order to uh address questions at at
these various scales uh questions
related to distribution and uh factors
that affect species uh distributions uh
I'm using um two main um types of uh of
uh research uh uh techniques one is
ecological niche modeling and the other
one is remote sensing so I'll give you
brief very brief overviews on the two as
we go down the scale uh to these uh to
to see these examples these are plant
examples as I said um they may not be uh
very uh dense and informatively
informative bi from a biological
standpoint but hopefully you can help me
fill in the blanks uh in those areas
okay so ecological niche Ming or enm um
is a very um active field uh of research
but what I wanted to do first is start
with uh just uh an understanding of the
terminology because we know that Niche
uh can mean various things to uh various
people so you may be aware of the uh
over the EC the history of ecology you
may be aware of um definitions of Niche
provided by grenell in the early 1900s
Elton in the 1930s and then Hutchinson
uh in the 1950s and uh 60s so what how
do we make sense of all these uh
defition definitions um well um to me it
makes sense and to other people it makes
sense to think of the uh effects that
organisms have on environments on the
environments that they occupy versus the
uh responses that organisms have to um
the uh environments and the the kinds of
uh uh um requirements that organisms
have um where how they choose
environments in which they uh they uh
live and survive okay so if we think
about the niche from from this effects
versus responses or impacts of species
on the environments versus requirements
uh environmental requirements of species
maybe it's a little uh uh easier to make
sense of these uh
definitions okay and then uh trying to
put the uh the niche Concepts on
a uh Geographic uh scale we can think of
um questions that are addressed at small
scale extents geography extents versus
large Geographic extents and on this
sliding scale uh going back to impacts
versus
requirements uh think about at the small
Geographic extent uh when we talk about
species impacts what we are talking
about is the uh functional role of
species in that in that at that uh small
scale and for these kinds of questions
we usually use um uh mechanistics
mechanistic models that try to quantify
the uh the dynamic relationships between
uh between species think think uh think
of uh consumer uh resource uh Dynamics
so those are very different models than
what uh what I uh do which is at larger
uh extents and ecological niche modeling
is um more useful at these larger
extents I should point over here uh
where um the interest is in the uh
requirements that species have in order
to survive in a certain uh region so
that uh summarizes uh the geographic
Niche or the abiotic Niche uh of a
species and to do that uh we uh use
empirical models uh and I'll show you
one type of models that we use in this
broad umbrella of ecological niche
modeling and the big assumption here is
that the requirements the environmental
requirements of the species are stronger
than the interactions the biotic
interactions so basically the abiotic
interactions are more important than
biotic interactions in shaping the
distribution of species at these larger
uh
scales okay so how do we go about if we
are into the ecological niche modeling
field uh how do we go about measuring
estimating quantifying this abiotic or
or grenan niche as it is known in the
literature well there are three methods
that I'm aware of or three uh possible
approach approaches one would be
physiological experiments so we go in
the lab and we test the uh limits that
uh a species uh has an organism has to
let's say varying temperature um if it's
an aquatic species wearing salinity so
on so forth so uh we go uh into the lab
and we uh find out what are the
physiological boundaries of the species
which can then possibly be mapped uh on
geography this is really hard work to do
and if we are interested in uh mapping
the biodiversity of a little study uh of
a a study that has not been of a country
that has not been studied very well uh
we do not have time to uh develop
physiological models for many different
species uh for which we don't have uh
information then a slightly um maybe uh
mad scientist scenario would be to
introduce species in various types of
environments uh and figure out which
kinds of environments sustain uh allow
that species to survive in uh uh long
term this is obviously impr practical a
large large scale probably unethical we
don't want to uh change ecosystems by uh
doing these kinds of large scale uh
studies intro introducing species so the
third method that is widely used in
ecological niche modeling world is has
to do with
uh making use of information we have
available about where species are and
the environmental conditions that are
present at those locations so we build
uh correlation type uh models uh simply
put uh that quantify that relationship
between where species are and what kind
of environments are uh present at those
locations and just to give you uh more
um visual on the the um these
correlation approaches uh to estimate
environmental requirements we start with
uh species records uh these could be uh
Museum specimens this could these could
be surveys um any type of um of uh
occurrence data then we uh on top of
that we use various uh digitized maps of
uh environmental conditions and I'm
showing you just some examples here uh
precipitation um annual precipitation
annual temperature seasonality of uh
precipitation and temperature uh so on
so forth and then these form our um
calibration data or training data which
we use to uh build a model estimate the
niche of that species and there is a
plethora of um algorithms and approaches
to making sense quantifying this
relationship between organism uh
presence and environment uh I'm naming
just a few here and I'll uh I'll briefly
mention uh show maxen okay oops sorry
jumped one so once we have that once we
have the model calibrated with these
occurrences and environmental data what
we do is uh we then project this model
back onto geography so we take we we
take data out of the geographic context
the spatial context in this
environmental uh context we build a
model we calibrate the model and then we
take that model back into geography we
project that model and I'll get back to
why this is important this model
projection but what we get is an
estimation
of suitability uh across the landscape
for that particular uh species uh of uh
interest and I need to move a lot far
faster okay so one of the widely used
algorithms is Max send uh this the the
paper that uh was that promoted the use
of Max end or described uh this
algorithm was published in 2006 it has
been cited over 3,000 times now it is a
widely used uh methodology what we do
here is is uh basically uh contrast
known presences with the rest uh of the
environment so we have some occurrences
we have some knowledge of where species
uh is present in uh in um on a landscape
and we contrast the conditions at
presences with the conditions at uh
across the rest of the landscape and
that's one way of uh of quantifying uh
suitability we get a probability of
suitability more likely if the the
conditions are similar to presences and
less likely if the conditions are
similar to uh the rest of the background
so it's contrasting presence and the
rest of the environment okay so jumping
to the first uh example of uh the use of
n ecological niche modeling uh I put
this at the largest
scale but you'll see that we actually
varied the scale uh of the question uh
for this uh for this project and the
idea was uh can we create reliable uh
species richness estimates when we are
dealing with various uh Geographic
extents or the scale of of our analysis
uh
varies and this is an area of um intense
research because we use these uh
estimated species uh richness maps to
create for example hotpots for
conservation or for um future climate uh
effects so on so forth so knowing how
well we estimate species richness with
ecological niche modeling uh is of
importance uh for various uh reasons
okay so the question is do we um do we
get various estimates in terms of uh
quality various species Rich richness
estimates from ecological niche modeling
when the scale uh varies so that that
was the question that we tried to answer
um um AJ Harris is not a PhD candidate
anymore she uh she successfully defended
about two weeks ago so she's moving on
to a postto at the Smithsonian but she
was the main uh driver of of uh this uh
particular study and then her advisor uh
Dr Mike Palmer uh both from the uh
botney Department um at Oklahoma State
and we are working uh the journ the uh
the manuscript is in review hopefully uh
we'll have um positive criticism and
useful uh reviews back soon okay so what
was the idea here the idea was to um
compare uh correlate uh observed species
richness with estimated species richness
so the observed species richness these
data come from floras and the estimated
species richness uh um the data come
from uh stacked models so we build uh we
build basically um sorry I I'll talk
about the models later but okay so what
is the uh observed species richness our
this is what we consider the um standard
uh in the study so uh using um a large
amount of data from various uh floras
that um a lot of data came from the
floras of North America project but also
from checklists and um very small scale
uh floras across uh North America we um
well uh AJ mostly AJ amassed um a data
set of of uh caasi and pinac species in
uh North America North of Mexico so
excluding Mexico uh we didn't have uh uh
data in uh for for Mexico so what you
see are at the county level but the
floras had different scales but at the
county level you see the uh species
richness the number of species in uh
these two families that we decided to uh
compare okay and then uh based on the
the uh information that we had about the
floras uh we uh created six classes of
extends or um floras that were uh
generated at uh six different extents
starting from um 10 hectare uh between
10 hectare and 100 hectares all the way
to a million to 10 million hectares and
we try to have uh a very well balanced
um uh data set uh we uh split the um uh
the Flora information in the three uh
regions Arctic Atlantic and Pacific and
we had in each scale class we had the
same number of floras that we uh
considered for this study okay and then
for the estimated species richness we
applied ecological niche modeling
species by species we build models uh
for uh for the caas and pinac uh with
the same occurrence data environmental
data approach uh maxent ecological niche
modeling uh algorithm and we create
these predicted distributions for each
species which then we stacked for each
Flora okay so what did we get oh sorry
and I forgot to mention we had 24
species of caasi and 51 species of Pac
most of the data for the ecological
niche modeling Pro uh part of this
project came from the global
biodiversity information facility which
uh is a distributed uh database of uh
Museum records and
observation and then we had as
environmental data or variables we had
uh climatic data and uh soil data for
this uh project okay so we generate
these stack models uh to estimate the
number of species in each uh Flora we
considered uh at these uh um six uh
different
scales so then we put the two together
and we try to uh to see how well they uh
correlate okay starting with caasi what
we see is that uh if we uh pull all
extends those uh six or eight different
extents we have uh if we pull them
together we get um a good correlation I
would say uh
68 um deviation from the uh from the
slope of one quite big so it is okay
it's an okay uh correlation not not a
very strong correlation so correlation
between of observed species richness
through Flora uh and estimated species
richness through this U stacking of
ecological niche Modas
but when we start um separating by uh by
extents of floras what we see is at the
largest extent that uh uh 1 to 10
million hectares we have a high uh
correlation so at the largest extent
this seems to be a useful approach now
on the other end of the uh Spectrum at
the finest
extent uh abysmal let's not do this
let's not use ecological niche Ming and
the Stacked approach to estimate this is
richness because it's not really doing
good with pine the situation is uh not
good at all so at all extents definitely
not not working uh at the largest extent
somewhat working the res the uh
correlation is 56 somewhat okay but not
not a great approach uh the slope the
deviation from the slope is not uh is
better when we go to the smallest extent
as you expected do not do this let's not
do this let's not estimate species
richness with uh stacked uh with the
Stacked ecological niche modeling
approach okay so that was one way of um
informing the psychological Niche
modeling field of the um applicability
of this approach to estimating uh
species richness next what I want to do
is go into a slightly smaller scale and
talk about uh climatic uh Niche
dissimilarity for one plant species that
has two uh more morphs um so the the
question here was uh do we see uh a
climatic difference between uh
populations that have different uh
morphologies and this study is a
collaboration with uh botanists again um
um from botn from uh Genet STS from OSU
then uh Dana from uh and uh Diana and
naoki from um University of Alaska
Fairbanks and then geologist from from
OSU so what we did here is uh not me but
Janette uh examined uh two morphs of
arabidopsis Kamchatka uh and she used
the uh herbarium specimens available um
at uh at the University of uh Alaska so
the two uh morphs that she looked at and
that are common in uh in Kamchatka um
populations are the uh the tri Tri con
bearing leaves versus glabrous leaves so
uh smooth versus uh leaves that have uh
that have these um unicellular uh
Tricom so she was able to find 116
specimens for the triom bearing morph
and uh 23 30 specimens for the uh
glabrous uh morph and this is a map of
the uh distribution of these of these
specimens uh she Geor referenced she and
and Jeff Geor referenced uh many of
these uh occurrences okay so what did we
do with this we took the records for the
two morphs uh environmental data again
and we uh we build two uh models two
different models for the triom bearing
specimens based on the triom bearing
specimens specimens and the glabrous uh
specimens so what we what we see is
first look at these Maps is the Trion
bearing um has a narrower distribution
than the uh glabrous um coal I'm sorry
Co Coastal maybe uh yes yes exactly uh
this is more Coastal and this is more uh
Inland uh species a wider distribution
based on the occurrences and also based
on our uh estimated suitability for the
uh
globers okay but then so we have a
visual of the uh climatic suitability
for the two mors but we want to quantify
how different are they really different
these two uh suitability envelopes so
what we did is we uh used uh uh
background similarity tests which uh
allow us to tell if uh the two morphs
are ecologically more similar or less
similar than uh expected by chance and
to do that we create 100 we created 100
uh replicates of these models where we
randomized uh one um data set for one
morph and created models and then
randomize the other data set for the
other model
the other morph and created model so
basically we have Real Models based on
real data comparing that with um random
models based on randomizing um taking at
random occurrences uh not occurrences
taking at random locations that are not
presences for that particular morph and
then we uh use two statistics uh shers
shers and uh eye statistic uh they basic
what they basically do is they look at
the probability of suitability for one
um morph and then the probability of su
suitability for the other morph at each
location in uh geography uh and they do
slightly different things but uh overall
they should be uh quite they should
provide uh a unified uh answer if we get
different answers from these two
different metrics it means that we are
not doing uh something right so the idea
here is quantifying the suitability
probability for each pixel and comparing
between the two uh morphs so what do we
get what we get is that random this is
the distribution of random models and
this is where our observed um overlap
Niche overlap or similarity between the
two morphs is so this is number of
replicates obviously we have just one
for the real models and then we have a
number of 100 each uh for the uh for the
random model so this is telling us that
sign there is a statistical
significant distinction the two morphs
are less similar than expected by chance
based on this the statistic we did the
same for this other statistic and we
obtained similar results where the um uh
Niche dissimilarity between the two
morph the two morphs was statistically
uh significant compared to a a null
distribution of these of the of these
values okay so what we are saying is the
two morphs are climatically
dissimilar um the one other way to look
at this is which variables contribute
most to the two models the two real
models for the morphs and this is this
is a list of the variables that uh we
used and what we see is that uh in bold
um we have variables that uh
cumulatively amount to 70% or more
contribution to the model gain of that
for that particular um morph meaning
that the the um variables in bold have
the highest contribution the most
important contribution to a a good model
fit for that morph so what we see is
that there is a discrepancy between
glabrous uh morph which has the high uh
has um in that highest contribution me
mean dunal temperature range and temper
temperature seasonality is very
important but not the triom bearing and
then going down here we have annual
precipitation and precipitation
seasonality for the other morph the
triom bearing morph so this tells us
that one morph is more sensitive at
least from this modeling perspective one
morph is more sensitive to uh
temperature variation and the other one
to precipitation and elevation and uh
minimum temperature of the coldest month
was in common between the two morphs
okay next uh I would like to talk a
little bit about um discrimination of
trees and then habitat structure so
going down this scale moving to finer
and finer scales uh to get to this these
questions now we are switching to um uh
approaches that are based on remote
sensing of very very big field in
Engineering in uh and geography uh and
we are making uh use of it just a tiny
bit uh there's a lot of potential to
develop this field just to get everyone
on board we have some sort of sensor can
be a satellite or can be a on a airplane
and then the what the sensor is
recording is the amount of light that is
reflected off different surfac is that
the Bas that's the basic of remote
sensing why is this
important well uh for us it's important
because it allows us to get data from
above that we don't get on the ground it
is accessible data if it's satellite uh
collected by a satellite it's uh and
it's free like lanat we have access to
that data we have a greater temporal
resolution because the satellite keeps
uh orbiting the Earth um so we have a
really good temporal resolution and we
do have this potential in uh extracting
biodiversity data that is of use uh to
us and just to give you some ideas um uh
we detect uh surf type of surface with
with remote sensing data So based on the
amount of light reflected we have
different types of uh two different
types of vegetation and then uh man-made
uh let's think of man-made uh surfaces
so the amount of light that is reflected
is basically what gets used in these uh
L cover classif ification if uh if you
um look at the land cover uh map also
very important is the amount of light
that is absorbed or reflected by
different pigments in the structure of
the plant and this is where remote
sensing becomes extremely important for
for us uh biologists who are interested
in uh plant function plant structure uh
uh plant distribution um so this is uh
the uh important aspect of remote
sensing now one other important aspect
of remote sensing is that uh there's a
wide variety of sensor sensors
collecting this information this uh
light amount of light that is reflected
of uh various surfaces so a
multispectral um uh sensor uh splits the
uh wavelength the electromagnetic
spectrum in a few distinct uh bands so
think of landet for example we have a
few distinct bands the information the
sensor can only process access
information amount of light reflected
from this one particular uh band for
example here so that's multispectral now
hyperspectral refers to splitting this
electromagnetic spectrum in very narrow
bands uh 10 nanometer bands so we get
hundreds of bands uh these sensors are
provide a data Rich uh um yeah data
sources that are rich in uh information
okay so one way of using this um is to
try to uh look at particular reflectance
of um of different uh species and in
this case uh
trees so here the question is can we
pick out uh emerging trees uh big large
canopy trees that are standing above uh
smaller trees can we pick them out
spectrally from one of these uh uh
hyperspectral High uh density of of uh
reflected uh bands this work uh was done
in collaboration with excellent botanist
from uh from Peru and a field assistant
whose name I forgot I'm really sorry
this was a long time ago uh when I was
finishing my PhD so these are uh
botanist in the field then uh Greg Asner
um is um a scientist at uh Carnegie
Institution for Science and since I have
my botanist uh collaborators in field
mode I uh pictures I didn't have them in
more official uh pictures I decided to
go with field mode for everyone else so
uh Greg Asner then my former uh PhD
adviser and my collaborator from uh
World wildli fund and this is like I
said work that was finished as I was uh
finishing uh graduate school um so this
uh has been published some time ago the
study site was somewhere in Southeastern
Peru beautiful area uh also highly
diverse area in terms of uh tree species
and for me the interest was was a subset
a very small subset of of uh these Tre
species that are used by various uh
animal species as food resource so
ferous animals that need um um resources
uh well fruit prod produced by these
trees and um actually the seasonality
which I I will briefly
mention so these are the species of
interest um we have fabas species here
uh and I forgot the uh family for the uh
Brazilian nut I'm I apologize but uh we
have four uh taxa from uh fabes and then
the Brazilian nut and then a map of
showing uh location various points uh
for these uh for these species one thing
one thing to notice is uh low sample
sizes these these are hard areas to work
because they are start uh so diverse the
forest and you can walk and walk and
walk and not find a second emergent uh
AOA tree for example so the sample sizes
are less than ideal uh we also had um uh
satellite images these hyperspectral
high Bend density uh images from uh four
different times uh and you notice that
uh precipitation wise we had dry season
more uh uh more rain and then the wetest
part of the season of the um year and
then another from the dry so we had both
dry more dry and then one image from the
wet season which was quite impressive
and I was quite happy to get that one
because of the cloud cover it's really
hard to get uh images uh for uh for
these
regions getting the hyperspectral IM
imagy is exciting but then uh the
processing is uh really convoluted I
won't go into it I'll just say that from
all from that great
242 B data set we are down we were down
to 126 that we used because of various
reasons Cloud uh um atmospheric uh
problems uh poor signal to noise ratio
so so quality of information made us uh
reduce that initial data set by half of
almost and then we did various things to
it I'm not going to go into it but just
uh wanted to uh mention this 126
bands uh and just a view of how this
hyper Hyperion hyperspectral imagery uh
Maps so we have a crown here that is
almost an entire pixel 30 by 30 m uh
another one that is almost 30 by 30 m
and then we have a p a tree here that is
not a full pixel it is split uh between
uh four different pixels so we were
focusing on these pixels that
represented more than 40% of the crown
uh of a single uh tree and then this is
a a spectral profile with the bends
removed the one uh the uh uh remaining
126 narrow bands that we kept in the
analysis
okay so we did a linear discriminant
function analysis of these 126 bands we
initially did a stepwise uh selection
procedure procedure so we we used only
the most informative of these
126 and we got really good uh
classification errors um meaning really
low classification errors so what you
see is for one uh tree species that it's
actually a we couldn't identify to the
uh to the species level so we use the
genus um we have for this one taxon we
have uh classification errors meaning
that the linear discriminant function
analysis was not able to spectrally
identify uh the individuals that well
but we also had only four individuals so
it's pushing the limits of of this
analysis and then for the Brazilian
treut we had in one of the time frames
remember we had four different images we
had um we had
error okay and just to show you uh the
two profiles for for the um various
individuals but we this we do see
differences in the these uh spectral
curves we also see temporal variation uh
within a um a taxon so here is appoa in
July and in December different different
Spectra uh and that difference it uh was
Quantified with a canonical analysis so
what we see is that based on the uh
season that these images are collected
Spectra group in uh various uh parts of
the canonical space what this means is
we don't have a spectral signature that
is species specific at all times and we
can use that spectral signature to
identify a tree it is uh season
based okay lastly the habitat structure
this is going to be very fast because I
don't have a lot of information we've
just started to work on this and this is
with my PhD student Cassandra uh who
took on this challenge of learning how
to use use uh liar uh terrestrial liar
to uh quantify vegetation architecture
for one particular uh species uh bird
species that she's interested in so this
is the bird species this is a a general
view of the shrubland grassland ecotone
in Oklahoma and this is what she's
trying to
quantify um the uh liar or light
detection and ranging what what it does
is it sends pulses out and then uh
measures the time it takes for the HS to
to uh reach the um the sensor again so
based on that if we think of a laser a
lar that goes or laser beam that goes
from above uh this uh this particular uh
structure will have this form where
there's more returns um when it hits a a
part of the tree and less returns when
it goes through between uh two
trees now we can do this from above but
we can do also this from from uh the
ground and this is where we where our
interest lies for now how uh can we do
this terrestrial scanning of of bushes
and quantify vegetation structure and
some these are some of the variables
that we hope to uh take out of this
these uh clouds of points that we get
mean shrub height shrub volume folage uh
foliage profile
yes on the on this this is distance from
the from the scanner for
the uh this is how much time it takes
for the for the beam to get back to the
pulse to get back to the to the
sensor so it's time the time is um is uh
converted to
distance okay so uh we don't have any
answers this is what we we've been doing
this summer collecting data uh very
difficult Logistics we can talk about
later if you are interested but what we
are doing is we are scanning one way and
then scanning another way to get a full
360 view of of the vegetation uh from
this point uh all the way 500 M uh
distance and what we get are for now
pretty pictures uh this is a a point
Cloud where vegetation is classified so
we get rid of uh soil or any other um
atmospherics anything that is not
vegetation and this is a profile of uh
one of the uh stud sites this is another
uh pretty image so far no qu
quantitative uh information but this
shows um vegetation height classified so
the the lightest green is the highest
vegetation and the darkest or the brown
uh pixels are uh the shortest vegetation
so we can get vegetation uh height for
now from these
images okay so what I tried to do was
show you an example at Large Scale of
ecological niche model
um uh of uh estimating um species
richness and what we see is that at
least for the two families we studied uh
fine scale do not do this large scale uh
caasi works better than uh
Pac um then moving on to a more Regional
scale We compare the uh morphology of
one species to different morphs uh and
the uh potential adaptation to uh
different environments and what we
showed was was that uh we have two
morphs that are climat statistically
they are climatically uh dissimilar and
then here we were able to identify tree
uh Spectra well trees uh based on
Spectra but there is seasonal variation
so we cannot use one spectral profile to
uh just go there and uh and map uh
species it has to be uh season specific
and then habitat we don't know yet uh we
are still in the process of gathering
data and making sense of it
but in general what I want to close with
is say that these types of approaches uh
ecological niche modeling for example
allows us to basically extend the uh
amount of information we can uh we can
gather from from occurrent data and
environmental data so it allows us to
learn a bit more about ecological
requirements climatic requirements uh
for uh for particular species so we hope
that this improves our understanding of
species distributions why species are
where are and then uh at fine scale with
these remote sensing approaches what we
are trying to get at is more of the
species function uh locally and
interactions uh in um more of a habitat
uh plant animal uh interaction type any
questions this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu