this is a production of Cornell
University
there are three sources of fixed
nitrogen used in agriculture the first
in my far the most widely used sources
nitrogen fertilizer derived from the
haber-bosch process the second
biological nitrogen fixation accounts
for about thirty percent of the
agricultural nitrogen globally the third
and least important is a group of
harvested ermine sources such as fish
waste into layin nitrate in theory
organic farmers combine luminous cover
crops with small additions of compost to
maintain soil fertility this works for
some farming systems such as grain
production where biological nitrogen
fixation accounts for the majority of
newly added nitrogen however others such
as most fresh vegetable enterprises rely
on animal based compost as the major
source of nitrogen and are therefore
indirectly dependent on haber-bosch
nitrogen while recycling nutrients is a
fundamental principle of organic
agriculture the use of animal manures
for nitrogen is problematic first there
are consequences for the production
system including nutrient imbalances
excessive soil phosphorus levels
increase weed pressure and greater
vulnerability to environmental nutrient
losses from a broader perspective the
dependence on haber-bosch nitrogen
undermines claims that organic
agriculture is a more sustainable
production system the founders of
organic agriculture got it right when
they prohibited the use of haber-bosch
nitrogen and chose biological nitrogen
fixation as the primary source of new
nitrogen
biological nitrogen fixation is a
sustainable solar powered nitrogen
source that promotes soil organic matter
of cruel and restores internal cycling
processes in contrast production of
haber-bosch nitrogen is highly fossil
fuel dependent and significant
greenhouse gas emissions result from
this process
the amount of haber-bosch nitrogen used
is massive global usage for this year's
forecast to be 116 million metric tons
of nitrogen during this five minute
presentation 1100
tons of new nitrogen will be produced
furthermore haber-bosch nitrogen is
extremely inefficient on average half of
this nitrogen is lost to the biosphere
leading to eutrophication and greenhouse
gas emissions it's likely that we've
already altered the global nitrogen
cycle to a point where the extra
nitrogen is driving irreversible changes
in the biosphere
beyond these environmental concerns new
knowledge about the role of the plant
microbiome the microbial communities
associated with plants points the way
towards sustainable nutrient management
strategies plants and their micro biomes
have been co-evolving for seven hundred
million years and greater understanding
of the role of the plant microbiome has
overturned our view of plant nutrient
acquisition and biological soil
processes
decomposition is a case in point until
recently decomposition has been viewed
as a microbially governed process
occurring in bulk soil independent of
plants a view compatible with the
strategy of delivering available
nitrogen directly to crops it's now
clear that a continuum of plant
microbial associations govern
decomposition plants can stimulate
decomposition by providing carbon to
decomposers in exchange for nitrogen and
other nutrients the carbon provides
energy to subsidize the cost of
expensive XO enzymes decomposers must
make to free nitrogen
this exchange of carbon for nutrients in
the rhizosphere provides an efficient
means for delivering nitrogen to plants
so much so that even under optimal
fertilizer management regimes crops
still rely heavily on soil organic
nitrogen pools reflecting their
coevolution with decomposers for example
and conventionally managed grains
receiving recommended fertilizer rates
fertilizer nitrogen accounts for less
than forty percent of the night taken up
by the crops
to promote sustainable nitrogen
management we need to use systems
thinking that includes ecological and
evolutionary mechanisms as well as IRA
cultural knowledge we need to manage
nitrogen and carbon together and build
soil nutrient reserves so that crops can
take advantage of mechanisms developed
in the course of coevolution with
microbes this approach will lead to a
cascade of beneficial shifts in
agroecosystems
that support sustainable food production
organic certification rules need to be
modified to promote biological nitrogen
fixation is the primary nitrogen source
in organic systems the time is right to
begin weaning organic agriculture away
from haber-bosch nitrogen dependence