this is a production of Cornell
University hey thanks a lot Matt and
thank you all for coming out today um
it's a bit of pleasure it's been an
awesome trip I've been here since Monday
got to meet with a lot of you uh it's
excellent thank you so much for taking
the time to chat with me um a special
thanks to Natasha and Matt for hosting
me um I guess has been a wonderful trip
so uh I am going to share some research
with with
you if my clicker works but doesn't need
to so I am based in the Twin Cities and
with the other four million residents of
the Twin Cities metro area uh we don't
actually see Farmland every day um but
we do have an opportunity to see some of
the impacts of the our current farming
system um Even in our Urban environment
uh so this is a photo that was taken
about three miles from my house uh I
live back over here and um I'm sure
hundreds of thousands of people go over
the bridge every day that see this uh
and it's not coming through super clear
but this is actually the Confluence of
the Mississippi River and the Minnesota
River and if you can see there is a huge
amount of sedimentation coming in from
the Minnesota River phosphorus bound to
some of those sediments uh likely some
dissolved nitrogen in there as well and
entering the Mississippi River and which
goes to the Gulf of Mexico uh so this is
a major issue so why is this occurring
well here's the crop land data layer uh
of the landscape in Minnesota just kind
of the Southern half of it and here are
those two rivers roughly this is the
Minnesota River starts in the headwaters
up in itasa state park if you ever get a
chance to go it's absolutely gorgeous
check it out um and here's the Minnesota
River and you can see that the Minnesota
River is really surrounding Ed by corn
and soybeans totally dominated by corn
and soybeans that's the yellow and and
green pixels on this map and the
Mississippi largely flows through
natural habitat from the north down to
this
Confluence uh so along the Minnesota
River we see a lot of images like this
especially in the spring um there is
just no living cover on the landscape or
very little and as a consequence when we
get a lot of our precipitation in the
spring we see major erosion events and
like I said that erosion carries with it
nutrients and this super valuable top
soil um causing some major environmental
challenges and others we can't see like
greenhouse gas
emissions uh so this kind of sets us up
for the justification for doing this
research uh we need currently our
agricultural system is dominated by
these annual monocultures and they're
critical though for supporting Humanity
uh 50% of our Global crop land is
occupied by these five species and if
you look at these species two of them
are dominant seral annual
grains and most of these in a lot of
parts of the world uh are farmed with
annual tillage intensive use of
pesticides and fertilizers and other
inputs and largely as
monocultures so this is sort of the
situation we have we've created this
agricultural system that's really
productive and uh but at as a
consequence we've lost some of these
ecosystem services that were once
provided by our natural habitats and we
see some of these major
challenges uh so what we're working
toward is developing new agricultural
systems those that are perennial and
high diversity with the goal of
maintaining at least maintaining
productivity as well as providing some
ecosystem services and really I want to
push this system and see if we can
actually exceed productivity from our
current system because we have our
population continuing to grow and
getting richer and the demand for food
Fuel and fiber is
increasing so as Matt said um I have the
great pleasure of working in the
sustainable cropping systems lab and
this is our goal it's diversify and
perennial eyesee cropping systems to
improve productivity economic viability
and then eological
Integrity we do that largely by focusing
on perennial crops there's a list of
some of those that we work on here as
well as trying to enhance crop diversity
and that diversity can be enhanced
through time in terms of diversifying
crop rotations or in space via
intercropping which I'm going to talk
about
today and we focus a lot on agronomics
how can we develop these new systems
that farmers can actually adopt and
integrate into their practices how can
they be profitable and at the same time
we measure those environmental
impacts
uh so I'm just highlighted a few of the
topics that we're going to cover in
today's presentation which is largely
around intercropping you'll see a lot
about kza intermediate weat grass and
alala I'm not going to cover too much of
the environmental impacts we'll just
touch on the water quality um but mostly
talk about agronomics and and how this
system can actually be
feasible so why are we at all interested
in intercropping we already started
alluding to this it's a way to increase
biodiversity on the farm uh we can
increase plant diversity
within a field which there's a lot of
research that shows that that can lead
to higher diversity levels of other
taxonomic
groups agronomic efficiencies cover that
soon and also hopefully provide some
environmental benefits so in terms of
these agronomic efficiencies there's
been a lot of research looking at how
intercropping systems can increase water
use efficiency a couple of different
mechanisms for this um hydraulic lift um
just complimentarity of rooting systems
capturing more of the water that falls
with
precipitation could lead to more
yields intercropping can also um help
with pest suppression and disease
suppression physically alterate altering
uh the environment for pests to
move and a lot of these have been uh
synthesized and I think in a great way
presented in the paper um out of Matt
ran lab in 2018 check that out if you
want to see a full description of those
things
but then the other big agronomic
efficiency that we're really interested
here is the ability to provide nitrogen
to our grain cropping systems through
biological nitrogen fixation via legumes
and there's been a lot of work done on
this um these are just some rough
numbers from a few papers I was able to
pull and have citations for this
afterward if you're interested where
they come from um but atmospheric end
fixation by legumes 13 to 17% of that
has been observed to be transferred to
the grains up to 35% of the nitrogen in
a grain crop that's been intercropped um
has been found to come from BNF
biological nitrogen
fixation but the mechanisms are uh kind
of tricky to track as well so this
nitrogen can can come from the
decomposition of the above ground plant
tissues of legum tissues that can be
decomposed and nitrogen can be made
available for the cial crop roots and
actually the nodules themselves contain
nitrogen that can be decomposed and made
available to the grain
crop there are other maybe more direct
Pathways nitrogen transfer through micro
risal fungi through root exid
dates but all of this is in uh designed
to better synchronize the nitrogen
supply and demand of these cropping
systems and I'm going to talk a little
bit about how the potential um might be
enhanced with perennial
crops so what about yield what do we
know about the opportunity to increase
productivity and yield using
intercrops there's a couple of ways to
present this uh so and we can do these
intercropping experiments with different
designs there's a replacement design and
an additive design um so let's just take
a look at an example of how we might
calculate the yield benefit from an
intercropping uh in a replacement design
let's say we have our uh field of a
monoculture of a grain crop like maze
yield 10 units per per area we have a
soy bee maybe that's yielding four while
if we do a replacement design and do a
substitution of one row for another uh
this is what we'd expect right half with
half the amount of corn plants in that
field half the amount of soybeans is the
monocultures combine them this is our
expected intercropping yield but if
there's any sort of facilitation any uh
transfer of that lium inner crop to the
maze that benefits the yield we would
get this overyielding effect and this is
one way we can measure it um by
calculating this thing called a land
equivalent ratio if we're really just
focused on um the outcome of the grain
crop we can focus on what we call
relative yield and this is quite a
simple
calculation um and now here we're
looking at an additive design so where
we just have our
monoculture um keeping the population
the same and then adding a legum
intercrop to that not altering our grain
yeld population what is the outcome it's
simply yield of the intercrop over yield
of the
monoculture and you'll see this metric
used throughout my presentation so the
key here is that if the value is over
one we get a net benefit of the legum
inner crop to the grain crop if it's
less than one uh it's a detrimental
effect and I might refer to this as if
it's above one there's facilitation
going on it's below one competition
there's a little bit more to that but uh
those will be some of the terms I use to
describe these
outcomes uh there's a lot of examples of
intercropping out there around the world
I'm just going to show you a snapshot a
couple of these so there's uh sorghum
pigeon PE intercropping systems that can
be harvested for grain or for
forage um this one you might have seen
before here in New York um red clover
UND seeded into um spring
wheat and folks are even intercropping
corn and soybeans um it's one thing to
manage this for forage um but quite a
much more difficult thing to try to
manage this for grain as you can imagine
trying to harvest combine grain from
corn out of a stand like this could be
pretty
tricky so why don't we see these
intercrops if we know that they have
potential to provide environmental
benefits and boost productivity why
don't we see these a lot on the
landscape well there are a lot of
different reasons and there are some
specific agronomic challenges
so the two different species might have
very different needs in terms of
preparing a seeded or for establishment
the timing of seeding they might require
different fertility regimes in a lot of
cases the pesticides are
incompatible but i' argue that one of
the reasons is that some of the nitrogen
benefits take time and with an annual
cropping system we don't have a whole
lot of time um there's actually limited
time for these ecological processes to
play
out so uh this is just an example of a
timeline of a corn and soybean system in
the Upper Midwest really there's only
about four or five months for all those
processes production of the lium death
of the legum tissue decomposition of the
legum tissue transfer to some inorganic
source that could be taken up by end
those all can take time can it happen in
five months in the Upper Midwest uh
maybe but it might be more effective um
to give the system a little bit more
time by working with
perennials um we also have to think
about balancing this populations of the
two species really we're trying to
promote that facilitation and prevent
the competition um and that can be
tricky to
do so I think that uh by working with
perennials we have a potential to create
intercropping systems that achieve these
goals and there are some perennial
intercropping systems um we have alley
cropping with fruit and nut trees we
have a lot of intercropping that's
occurring in pastures and other forage
systems but until now there really
haven't been any intercropping systems
that really fit nicely within a
production row crop system and that
provides human consumable grains these
serial grains that are so important for
Humanity which leads me to intermediate
weak grass or kernza so intermediate
weat grass is a cool season Forge grass
perennial introduced to the US in the
early 20th century as a forage crop and
in the past 40 years folks have been
working to domesticate that and turn it
into a grain crop so breeding for larger
seeds higher seed
yield uh and it's proven to be uh rather
successful in some ways because it's
tolerant to a wide range of growing
conditions does require
vernalization um and the trade name for
the grain is kernza um so I'll try to
refer to the plant as intermediate weat
grass and whenever I refer to the grain
itself I'll try to speak to kernza but a
lot of times people use these terms
interchangeably so before I begin I need
to show you a timeline of a typical um
intermediate wheat grass production
system uh seeds are typically not all
the time but usually sewn in the fall
I'd say early summer or late summer
early fall the plants produce some
biomass just vegetative biomass then
they overwinter providing some cover on
the landscape that first year the
plantss come out of dormy very early in
the year for the Upper Midwest mid-march
sometimes um and begin vegetative growth
and they grow vegetatively for about two
more months and then stem elongation
begins in about the second week of May
in our region that's when the seed head
comes up flowering goes takes place in
around the Fourth of July and then grain
is uh ready to harvest Late July early
August and at that point all the grains
removed all the straws typically
harvested and then the plant continues
to grow just vegetatively for the rest
of the season and in Minnesota that can
actually be until early
November so now I want to just give you
a quick overview of the nitrogen budget
um give you an idea of how much plant
tissue and how much nitrogen is in that
those tissues in a typical intermediate
weak grass stand so these numbers are
not meta analysis averages is these are
just ballpark figures based on uh many
sight years of data for Minnesota so
typically we can see about 800 kilograms
of uh grain per hectare um which is
about 20% of the grain yields we might
see for spring wheat in Minnesota um so
nowhere near our annual yields but
that's what we're looking at and 3.4%
nitrogen content so in a field of kernza
we might have about 30 kilograms of
nitrogen per hectare the straw above
ground biomass about uh four metric tons
1.1% nitrogen we got 44 kilograms there
Roots uh we see a lot of variability in
root biomass we've had measurements up
to nine metric tons per hectare down to
a meter deep um so i' just say on
average here another four metric tons um
and then another 40 kilograms of n per
hectare so all in all we're looking at a
nitrogen need of about 100 kilograms of
nitrogen per hectare for this
crop so we have one of the first studies
we did with intermediate weat grass
agronomic studies was a simple nitrogen
rate trial try to figure out how much
nitrogen should be applied to maximize
grain yields uh we did this work at many
sites and years and identified this
Optimum nitrogen rate of about 60 to 90
kilograms per hectare Which is less than
what I just said in Med weak grass needs
per year um and just so you know the
average corn fertilizer rate in
Minnesota is almost 160 so we're talking
about 50% of what would be applied to a
corn
crop uh but it's kind of intriguing that
this n rate is less than what we just
showed you that the plant is actually uh
using in a given year um and what we've
noticed is that when we apply more
nitrogen fertilizer we get lower graani
yelds because of this lodging so the
plant is prone to lodging
one of the reasons it's using that
nitrogen to build taller stems and more
leaves um and at the expense of grain
production and then those plants topple
over and it's hard to harvest them so we
get a reduction in Grain
yield um but this is really important
because we uh are very interested in
identifying uh perennial crops to plant
in these ecologically sensitive areas
where nitrate leeching is a problem so
Minnesota has a big issue with nitrate
leaching to drinking water uh most
motans get their drinking water water
comes out of their tap comes from the
groundwater and we are seeing elevated
levels of nitrate in that drinking water
mostly as a product of nitrogen
fertilizers leeching into the the
aquifer and this has major human health
impacts uh the concept's pretty simple
we have these annual Ro crops that
require nitrogen in these aquifer uh
Headlands wellhe head protection areas
and we're applying anywhere between 140
and 160 pounds of end per acre and in
some areas of Southwest Minnesota it's
more closer to
200 and lots of lots of research has
been done on looking at nitrogen use
efficiency of corn um we're knowing we
know that only about 40% of that is
recovered into the Grain and many
Studies have documented the amount of
nitrogen that has actually escaped the
corn systems into the aquafer we're
looking at losing 25 to 50 pounds per
acre per year in corn again this isn't a
one value from a met analysis this is
kind of a range from various
studies uh and so we've been doing this
work with intermediate weak grass to
understand its potential to prevent
nitrate leeching we know it requires
less nitrogen for optimizing grain
yields we're not getting as much yield
per acre but less nitrogen's going in um
higher nitrogen use efficiency and over
and over again we're seeing a lot less
Nitro leeching to the groundwater
because of this extensive deep rooted
deep rooting
system so lots of modeling exercises
taken place done various field studies
comparing kernza intermed wheat grass to
corn to soybeans different fertilizer
rates we're seeing two orders of
magnitude less nitrate leeching uh
compared to our annual R crops okay so
where do this bring us though for
intercropping we are still interested in
making that um system more sustainable
by providing nitrogen to the crop via
biological nitrogen fixation it' be
really great to not have to fertilize
these current systems at all um we'd
also love to increase biodiversity and
potentially increase total biomass if we
can add another legum to the stand
increase total biomass and there's value
to that biomass that we're going to talk
about some of the challenges are though
balancing that competition and
facilitation establishing our legumes
and making sure that they persist give
the time required for those ecological
processes to play out um and I'll talk a
little bit more about whether or not
this is a sustainable
system so I'm going to show you some
results from just a couple of
experiments first um this is one of the
earlier studies and it was we really
wanted to screen what legumes could work
uh so we tested um these six different
legum species with intermediate weak
grass then we also had intermediate weak
grass mod no cultures um controls with
no fertilizer and then we fertilize some
plots with either 45 or 90 kilograms of
nitrogen per
hectare I am not going to go through all
the different traits of these lium
species um but just to kind of lump them
together we tested these two very common
uh legum forages alela and red clover
they have differences in their root
architectures their persistence their
yield so we wanted to see if any of
those might influence the competition
facilit ation
tradeoff we tested a few other not so
common legumes um but they also have
different traits white clover very
low-lying
um elide Clover and birds foot tree foil
and the last one we tested is actually
native to the Tallgrass Prairie um in in
the midwest that's Canada milk fetch so
we're just curious could we you know
potentially integrate this perennial
native perennial legum with intermediate
weak
grass all right so on to the data
this is the first figure you'll see a
few of these uh we're looking at the
relative uh
yield and I said anything above one is a
net facilitation uh there's more biomass
being produced by the intermediate weak
grass in the intercrop compared to no
intercrop compared to the monoculture
and with this figure we're looking at
total intermediate weak grass biomass so
the vegetative biomass and the grain
combined um and this is the first year
we did this study at three sites I'm
only going to show you data from one
site uh because it varied a lot across
sites and that's that'll just show you
even the variability within one site uh
so we saw a net increase in
biomass um as a response to some of
these legum species which was uh nice to
see some facilitation occurring in that
first year uh look at the red clover
which is a pretty common Forge legume we
actually saw some competition occurring
there less intermediate weak grass
biomass um alelo we saw some n
facilitation um but again this is
overall biomass so uh one could imagine
that in an environment with another
species and more competition turns of
intermediate weak grass might tend to
grow taller as there's more competition
for light and so maybe just that
increase in biomass is only coming from
the vegetation what we really want is an
increase in Grain yield um so this is
the first year and and just to show you
a snapshot of what happened in the
second and third year we got a lot of
variability there's no standout legum
here that consistently uh resulted in
overyielding in terms of total
biomass uh but let's look at the grain
so here's the grain relative to zero n
and this is what we're really interested
in are any of these legumes really
increasing grain yield when we intercrop
them and we are seeing some uh Lela um
red clover here did really well by the
third year elide clover but again
there's no real consistent pattern um
and then when you look at the other
sites again there's just no standout
lium species so there's a lot of things
happening occurring here and we got to
start to teas some of these things apart
so you also might wonder well M are
there actually legumes in those plots
where the grain yields are better or
worse like is there really a
relationship between the lium and the
intermediate weak grass one way to look
at that is simply by plotting legum
biomass yield against the relative grain
yield so as increase as there's more
lium biomass in a plot we're seeing less
grain yield um that makes some sense the
more plants you have in there the more
competition there's going to be but what
we're really interested in looking for
is this there's any points in this area
where we can get some legum biomass in
the plot but still have an increase Rel
in Grain yield relative to the
monocultures so we're looking for if
there's any area up in here and we see
some points and so we can start to
investigate you know why did those plots
have overyielding was it the species
what was the population things like
that uh and we're we're been thinking
that these legumes are going to benefit
the intermediate wheat grass via
nitrogen fixation and
transfer and that's tough to quantify
and um Evelyn Riley is a graduate
student on this project um worked with
Dr Jess guten who's at the University of
Minnesota she's a soil e colle ologist
and they did this work um tracking
nitrogen transfer using Natural
Abundance of nitrogen
Isotopes um and any asteris here
indicates a situation where there was a
statistically different difference in a
nitrogen transfer from zero so here we
actually none of these are statistically
significant um we didn't actually see a
transfer until the third year at this
site and only with three of these
species uh and if we look further into
this potential leg uh we can see that
year one leum biomass is actually
correlated with the year three relative
grain yield so plots that had a lot of
uh legum biomass in the first year it
appeared that there was actually some
competition in year one but that biomass
later translated to potentially being
beneficial for graani yields in years
two and actually year three when we
picked it up that it was because of the
nitrogen transfer now again there's a
lot lot of other mechanisms as to why
the legum in crops might influence grain
yields we talked about pest suppression
there's a lot of Water Dynamics
happening with these systems um so we're
just kind of getting at the tip of the
iceberg with
this um another question we have is can
a producer do something in the field to
manage these populations or to alter
this interaction between the species
um so we tried answering this question
um through an oi project that was led by
initially Steve Coleman and now Leo dice
at the Ohio State um Matt Ryan and Tim
Cruz um are also hosting this
experiment and we're looking at two
different legum species alala and red
clover um also comparing the results to
fertiliz intermediate weat grass with
Organic
manure and what we're really uh testing
here is different um procedures for
establishing the legumes so let me
explain a little bit more about that
everything I've showed you so far uh we
have established the intermediate wheat
grass and the alala at the same time in
the fall and I've showed you these
configurations where we have rows sewn
rows of the two
species uh so we did that in this study
we have our intermediate weat grass
monoculture no fertilizer sew it in the
rows and then uh one set of treatments
we introduced our legum with the
intermediate wheat grass within the same
R so we mix the seed um and we have our
alala and our red clover established in
the fall we have another set of plots
where we sewed the intermediate weak
grass into rows in the fall and then
Frost seeded our legumes broadcast that
seed over the top so we gave the
intermediate weak grass a little bit of
a head start before sewing or planting
our
legumes and then the Third configuration
is this really delayed legume um seaing
we actually let the intermediate weak
grass go through a full life cycle we
harvested grain really gave it a head
start and then we planted our legumes in
the summer uh we broadcast seed it in
between those harvested
rows and we also have monocultures that
we appli um manure onto at different
rates and we applied that manure in the
spring important to know um three
different rates from 56 kilograms per
hectare to
224 all right uh so that's just a list
of the
treatments um we're going to look right
away at the relative grain yield and
this is relative to the unfertilized
monocultures and we can only look at the
two establishment systems the the fall
sewing and the frost eating because the
summer wasn't seated yet in the first
year um we saw some overyielding with
that red clover it's kind of opposite of
what we saw in the first
study um by year two there's not much of
a difference in terms of yield and by
three we had a lot of variability so
here might be a good time to start
looking at the actual population of the
legum in the
plots some of these are not very
persistent like red
clover so let me back up so this is
relative to the unfertilized
monocultures now we could take a look at
these plots and ask well what's the
nitrogen equivalency of that
overyielding uh so we could potentially
compare yields of these intercrops to
fertilize monocultures which is what we
do here um so everything all the points
go down as you'd expect because uh the
monoculture fertiliz yields are a little
bit higher um but we can still see that
we're getting close to that that's at 1X
so that's 112 kilograms of nitrogen per
hectare so that can be a one way to
quantify that benefit of the
intercropping in that
system same plot as before I showed you
lium biomass correlated with the
relative grein yield so the
unfertilized seeing the same thing we're
seeing a as expected a reduction in the
relative yield as you get on the high
end of these lium populations but we're
looking for these spots right where we
can get a balance of high grain yields
and lium intercrop
biomass now for the first time I'm just
going to show you actual yields um
because we also have to think about this
from a farmer's perspective relative
yield is great and all but what's the
actual economic viability of these
systems um so this is green yield in
kilograms per hectare you know I said
around 800 is kind of this ballpark
figure that we see a lot of times from
our trials in Minnesota um so we have
our alala intercrops our red clover
intercrops and then the uh control and
three nitrogen rates year one pretty
similar yields for some of these inner
crops compared to the fertilized rates
we see this nice classic curve of
increasing nitrogen fertilizer rate you
get more yield um and we're seeing uh
yields exceeding those of the inner
crops in year two and we see this
classic also decline in Grain yield by
the 30 year this is ubiquitous in a lot
of our experiments um but for some
reason that high-end plot was a little
the yield crash wasn't as great which is
an interesting point in its own um and
then here's the same figure but with
total forage yield and now I'm calling
it forage yield because we are thinking
about using this biomass so this is the
mix of the alala and the intermediate
weat grass
biomass uh and we should really be
thinking about this uh in terms of
economic value that legu material has a
higher nitrogen content has more crude
protein has more nutritive value and and
actually has more economic value so as I
mentioned this is a dual use um system
we're looking at harvesting the forage
at different times uh going back to our
timeline of intermediate weat grass we
can harvest the
forage uh in late April early May long
as we do it before stem elongation
otherwise we take off the seed heads and
there won't be any grain that year uh
producers can Harvest that forage or
graze the field um there's also quite a
bit of value to the straw and I'm
calling it straw but it is higher nut
value than like wheat straw it's Greener
there's more nutrients there and then um
the plant as I mentioned continues to
regrow only vegetatively in the fall and
there's another opportunity there to
either mechanically Harvest or graze
that material so if you count it there's
actually four opportunities of revenue
for a producer spring graze uh summer
grain straw forage and then a fall
forage it's important to actually
quantify these uh which is what Mitch
Hunter did as a postto a few years back
and this is just um forage yield and
quality um at the different utilization
periods so spring forage summer straw
fall forage do in a nutshell there's not
much there in the spring but it's
excellent quality really high quality uh
straw in the summer there's a lot of it
there but it's pretty you know meager in
terms of quality fall fall right in the
middle
uh so it's useful to actually quantify
this um and we did this in a study where
we actually grazed uh stands of
intermediate wheat grass that was
managed as the monoculture with
fertilizer or with legum inner crops
it's replicated complete block design
you can't really see this very well but
there you can see the paddock um in this
picture and so these are the values
after a three-year production period um
so we have our intercropping system
system and then our monoculture the
intercropping we actually had to put
down about 50 units of n um in one of
the years because it was looking quite
nitrogen depleted um the other system
was over those three years was 450
kilograms of nitrogen were applied this
is the total amount of biomass removed
from both systems we had a little bit
more from the legum inter crop as we
might
expect um we actually measured the
amount of nitrogen harvested uh because
we looked at the nitrogen content both
the intermediate wheat grass and the
forage legume um and then we can see
what the soil n available nitrogen was
after the study um and substantially low
this is a really Dynamic number but um
we did see significantly lower available
then um in the
intercrop uh relative yields from this
system so the Green Point is uh relative
total forage yield so higher yields with
the inner crop compared to the
monoculture
but grain declined with stand age um so
in the first year there wasn't much of a
difference between intercrop and
monoculture um but the monoculture
yielded more grain in year two and
three so how do we yeah value this
addition of the legum to the system in
terms of the forage and what is the
economic cost of that reduction in Grain
yal by adding the ligu um we did a
simple Enterprise budget here and I'm
not going to walk through all the
numbers but some important assumptions
are the value of the grain we valued
that at $2.50 per kilogram um value of
the unit of crude protein
$122 cost of Ura was pulled from what we
paid for it and when we come down the
net return this isn't really a net
return because we didn't quantify the
cost of the Harvest but just to uh
apples the apples here a little bit more
of a potential return from the leum
incraft so to summarize that anything
that's above the line there's more of in
the in crop below is more of in the
monoculture a lot more fertilizer was
applied to the monoculture we had more
grain in the monoculture but we had more
forage and more protein was harvested uh
in terms of um you know potential
benefit for dairy
system and a slight increase in Revenue
Potential from the intercropping so this
all needs a lot of work and much more
replication but it's I think a starting
point for starting to assess this um but
in summer we've noticed that the
biological nitrogen fixation from those
legumes might not be enough um to make
up for all that nitrogen we're removing
with the forage nitrogen depletion is
probably one of the reasons why we saw
that uh grain yeld decline with stand
age in the indrop because it just wasn't
getting enough n uh and the value of the
increased protein from legumes seem
seems to be able to offset that grain uh
decline right now but again it's it's
going to depend on the price of the
Grain and the
forage um so I wish I had a whole
another seminar to talk about the
environmental impacts of this system but
I don't have much time left here so I'm
just going to give you a snapshot um do
lium inner crops affect yeah these
environmental uh issues that we're
concerned with um just talk about water
quality we measure water quality by
using lysimeters so we can sample soil
water beneath the rooting Zone and then
we look at how much nitrate is in that
soil water and we did this in
monocultures with without fertilizer and
then we did this with an alphaalpha in
crop but all of those in crops did have
uh 40 kilos of n applied to them so it
was the legum in crop plus
fertilizer just show you some results so
in the first year this is the
concentration of that nitrate in the
soil water um 10 parts per million is
sort of the magic number EPA set that as
the safe drinking limit um and so you
can kind of think about that number
there we saw some elevated nitrate
levels in the in the soil water beneath
the intercrop with fertilizer compared
to the no fertilizer control but it was
a lot less than our fertilized
intermediate weak grass uh to give you
some sense of how what this is relative
to annual row crops in our corn system
we often see the value between 25 and 60
so we're still substantially lower than
what we'd seen an annual um but then we
saw that decline with stand age and
actually by the third year um there was
less nitrate in the soil water even
compared to the
unfertilized monoculture so there's
potential there um for to mitigate
nitrate leeching while using these in
crops so thinking uh forward what's the
future research on this well um working
with Jenny Moore and others here um do
figure out if we can breed legums for
intercropping specifically in this case
Alfalfa there's a lot of different
Alfalfa cultivars out there with a lot
of different traits um so we want to
start to understand what traits are
important uh we're looking at alal with
different fall dormy values um different
kind of
phenotypes um we're also combining this
with different n rates and Megan's going
to be summarizing some of this research
you'll probably hear from her pretty
soon um on the other end of the spect
we're also looking at can we breed
intermediate wheat grass to be uh a
better partner in an intercropping
system what are the right traits of the
grass to help promote that facilitation
and balance that competition uh so we're
working with the Kern of breeders and we
have different lines with different
traits and we're intercropping those
with two different species alala and red
clover and also varying the uh
configuration just a little
bit last thing we're kind of interested
in is looking at mixtures of legumes and
this research is actually done we should
be writing this up pretty quick but we
did test different mixtures these
mixtures were actually handpicked from
farmers in the different states um based
on what they're interested in and used
to working with so it was really a
farmer informed study we're really
excited to be analyzing that
soon uh so I just want to acknowledge a
whole bunch of people who contributed to
this work these are past postdocs and
graduate students who've graduated um
since I joined the sustainable cropping
systems lab like 2017 current post STS I
really want to highlight research staff
um these are really hard experiments to
do and very complex and they do such an
amazing job um at making these things
work it just blows my mind every day so
mad props to the research staff and then
current students who are working on this
um also all the summer undergraduate
interns who uh sweat a lot and fight off
insects during the summer to collect
this valuable data um want to
acknowledge teammates at University of
Minnesota and then definitely the what I
call perennial crop Pioneers these are
farmers who I've had the pleasure of
working with um a lot of these folks
have hosted on Farm trials and uh meet
with to inform our research goals and
priorities um they've taken a big risk
in uh not just working with us but also
trying to advance this perennial crop
vision and thanks to the funders and
that's all I got so I think I take some
questions you have plenty of time for
questions
here you want to call people up yeah
just check in the zoom chat there's none
there yet
so yeah this was a really cool talk one
of the things I was curious about when
you were talking about the threee study
and you were talking about nitrogen in
your grain yield and how that
corresponds to protein did you ever
measure the protein in the grain
specifically compared with the
monoculture as opposed to just total
nitrogen and the biomass I don't think
we have and that would be a good thing
to do um the protein so because it's
really interesting kza does have higher
protein levels uh per unit of grain than
wheat so that's one of the selling
points of actually of kernza high
protein grain um so that should be
looked at I don't think we we analyzed
that it's a good point thanks for
that go ahead hi thank you thank you
very much I'm wondering side of the
nitrogen fixed BYU may not compensate
nitrogen
yeah if you I think those you are
thinking about biomass how about soil
nitrogen how about soil nitrogen as it
and what was the contribution of that to
the nitrogen that if you include soil
nitrogen
that yeah well I think um I didn't show
this but we did see a depletion in soal
nitrogen through time um so the it
appears that the intermediate weak grass
was using nitrogen that was being
mineralized from organic matter through
time um because we saw that uh and now
we have this spurred some new
experiments so we're actually now
quantifying nitrogen mineralization
rates in intercrop versus monoculture
systems um so that is sort of an
unanswered question that we're trying to
get at right now by collecting some new
data um yeah hopefully that can help us
uh understand this these outcomes a
little bit more
yeah thanks for that excellent
presentation J what do you think uh like
why do you think kza is so variable in
its responses to things like red clover
and and just management I mean you point
this out in your uh
presentation you know different studies
having different results and and that
can also be found things like mowing
oration like some sites certain
practices help
others it doesn't what makes so
variable it's an open pollinated uh
species for one thing and I think the
genetics are part of it it's there's a
lot of variability so this isn't like
wheat where you look out of the field
and all looks homogeneous and the same
you have plants that are different uh
sizes in terms of stature and um
different number of seed heads per plant
and there's just a lot of genetic
variability out there and a lot of just
variability in the phenotypes as well
and even a given field so I think that's
one reason um another is that not all of
these Studies have been conducted with
the exact same agronomics like seating
rate row spacing time of seating so when
we compare those some of those lium
intercropping studies from other
institutions and things we kind of have
to be aware of what differences there
were for just a basic agronomics um
Baseline soil nitrogen
levels uh there just a lot of things
that kind of that could confound the
treatments in these studies um there's
recently been one meta analysis that
just came out um from some collaborators
of mine at the University of Minnesota
trying to account for those differences
and all the studies that were conducted
in
Minnesota um so I can point you to that
paper if you want to dig into the weeds
a little
bit go ahead ch um yes maybe a bigger
picture question um so
we I guess curious um someone on the
Forefront uh where do you
see graphs uh going you know let's say
25 years like you know where you think
it will go or where would you like to
see okay yeah great question um I like I
think for the next five to 10 years from
now I think Growers should be thinking
of it as a three-year crop that would
fit into a rotation potentially
following an alala stand um preferably
in a situation where they can use the
for forage uh that's going to be an
economic safety net because the grain
market is quite volatile right now um so
in the in the near term that's kind of
where I see it producers who can use the
forage and are comfortable marketing
their grain or working to Market their
grain a little bit um and and there's
probably going to be a premium too for
organic regenerative organic
specifically uh longer term so the plant
breeders are thinking that if we stick
on this the trajectory that we're at now
for increasing C size um I think proban
said 23 years we'll have kernels that
are the same size as spring wheat in
Minnesota and that but now as the
breeding program continues diversity is
going to decrease so that rate might not
increase but if we could hold that rate
steady 23 years um so I I could see it
be becoming less of a niche crop and
more of a mainstream crop if we can
achieve those
yields
[Music]
okay
experim yes always have first
y
yep yeah I'm super happy you brought
that up um I do think weather is a
really important confounding variable
that's making it difficult to understand
how yields are changing with stand age
um we have some evidence that suggests
that too um but in terms of the
staggered start that's exactly where
we're heading and we we've we've initi
iated two experiments with a staggered
start design um and what this means is
we we start the experiment in one year
um in in a randomized plot design and
then the second year we plant the exact
same treatments again third year plant
the exact same treatments that way yeah
we could tease apart stand age from year
of growth uh so we just initiated this
and we're planting the third year we're
starting our third year of a study it's
pretty much a nitrogen rate trial Stager
start and we're we're quantifying um the
fate of the nitrogen more
comprehensively in this study and we're
hiring a postto so I'm really happy you
reminded me of that I brought the
announcement and I'll uh send it to Matt
and others and if that can be
distributed that would be great um that
job is open and um it's exciting time to
join the team because there's some data
there we got a couple more years of the
project to go so excited about it your
trials do you ever have any extreme
weather events so put itout yeah we've
had unusually low precipitation values
for probably two or three out of the
years that I showed you the data I
showed you Spann from probably 2017 to
2023 and I think there were two or three
years where there was uh like a
statistical drought um and that's yeah
tricky because we don't and not all
these experiments have our Stager start
um one of the motivations for doing that
um so can that the effect of that
drought be tease the part with
Statistics I think in some cases it can
and in a lot of the situations here
we've just tried to to analyze the data
based on the measure the response
variables you know from comparing across
treatments and then step two is to
really dive in a little bit more and try
to see if we can tease apart these
year-to-year
things yeah thinking along with line
lines of ecosystem Services yep at some
point did you ever measure uh soil
health or to organic matter Dynamics in
these two systems again thinking also
from the Qui question maybe with carbon
credit yeah becoming a thing yeah in the
next 20 years that be potential at peral
cing system the um the PO the folks who
are going to make products with kurza
and sell those are really hoping that we
measure that data soon because they want
to Market those environmental benefits
specifically those related to soil
health and carbon uh and we have been
measuring um some of those variables J
scoot connect my collaborator at du um
leads a lot of that work and um some of
those studies are are really close to
being published actually one was
published by maner rockar um egg
ecosystems environment
2023 and um she looks at enzyme
activities microbial biomass PL FAS all
that sort of stuff in response to kernz
on and annual crops there's one question
on the zoom can I take that one quick we
have enough time sure it's Sandra uh if
you have to leave it certainly yeah feel
free to step out if you have to as far
as forthcoming breeding work with kernza
which traits will be focused on as a
priority grain size kernel size is
number one grain yield is what we want
to maximize um but a couple important
traits include threshability so the
grain retains its hall right now for the
most part we want to have free threshing
grain and then we also want to reduce
shattering so it's still sort of a wild
plant and if farmer Waits too long seed
falls off loses yield and uh we actually
have recruitment in the field and that
causes some problems so those are the
main traits we're focusing
on all right let's get
Jak this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at Corel
l.edu