this is a production of Cornell
University thank you all for coming out
uh as Nina said this I'm going to just
talk a little bit about my drewer
experience I said impatience and
vegetables as the title but it ended up
being a whole lot of other stuff as well
so I'll see how much I can kind of cram
into 40 minutes and still hopefully have
more room for other things to talk about
uh before I get started though this was
one of the coolest dis phenotypes I've
ever seen this is tomato necrotic
ringspot virus on uh chili pepper and
they had a whole population of them most
of them look like most diseased plants
but there was one genotype that had this
just really unusual uh phenotype from
the disease and I thought I have to you
know preserve this for posterity so I
just wanted to share that um I'll be
taking you through my three main
internships I wrote the drewer for uh
the tropical vegetable Research Center
in uh kind of central Thailand uh Chaya
company in Western Thailand and then
Prince of saclaw University in southern
Thailand just north of the border with
Malaysia uh I'll get a little bit into
some of the side trips I did as well I
had to cut some of them because there
was a lot of traveling but just to kind
of give you an idea of some of the
horiculture that I kind of experienced
while I was over
there uh so for a lot of people ask me
where Thailand was so I thought this
would be a good kind of primer
uh it's right there it's not Taiwan that
was another kind of source of confusion
um and a people also asked me why I was
interested in Thailand uh one of the big
things is Thailand has a really strong
agricultural sector they get a lot of
government support for it the royal
family has poured a lot of personal
money into it they've set up kind of uh
what they call the Royal projects which
are kind of specific projects to kind of
push the boundaries of Agriculture
within Thailand they like to say that
they're self-sufficient for all crops
except wheat I've never actually seen
any figures to support this but it's
something they like to say um and it's
mostly because of the range of climates
within Thailand in the northern part you
have temperate areas where you can grow
things like cherries and apples and then
the rest of the country is pretty
tropical you can grow things like rice
and pretty much any other sort of
tropical food uh they did try growing
wheat and I met with a wheat breeder a
few years back there and she said they
could grow it during the middle of their
winter in the coolest part of the
country but otherwise it was a complete
flop they do grow barley though they
have a huge uh Brewing uh uh industry
there uh it's also a really uh a big hot
spot for biodiversity there's over a 100
native impatient species uh most of you
all I think know I did my PhD on
impatients and it's a genus of 1300 so
that's a pretty good chunk of them uh
there's also tons of other families it's
inji AC I mean lots of towns have two or
three native species that they use in
their cooking that adds kind of
different flavors and spices so it was
just kind of fun to be like walking
around and seeing all these species that
might be really really local to that
area uh nice climate good food you know
those weren't my primary reasons but
they certainly didn't hurt and also have
some personal history with Thailand uh
my ex of five years was Thai I speak a
little bit of Thai from uh being with
him and I've been to Thailand twice
before which kind of fed into a lot of
the internships that I have
here uh the first first internship I did
was with the tropical vegetable Research
Center but it was at kazet University in
at their cing sand campus and I tried to
put little red dots on the different
areas that I went to in Thailand uh so
this is about two hours West of bangok
uh casseta University is the Premier
Agriculture University in Thailand their
main campus is in downtown Bangkok but
their camp sand campus is huge they
refer to it as resort-like which I think
is kind of nice um they have lots of
bodies of water they you know even the
drainage canals are populated with water
lies and lotuses you know and canas so
it's a really beautiful campus just to
be wandering around um I happen to be
there during the loyo Town Festival
which is their kind of they build these
little altars out of biodegradable
material and put them on the water to
worship one of the water goddesses so uh
it's a really neat way to kind of see
Flor culture in action there this was
one of my favorite ones this is a banana
flow that they peel back and pinned to
itself and then they use banana stem in
the middle and put a Gina or globe
amaran in there and then you light
incense and candles uh iera the tropical
honeysuckle who's a really nice one I
mean I saw all sorts of different things
in the past they'd made them out of
different materials but now there's kind
of a eco-friendly um twist to it so that
the fish can finish them off and they
don't end up clogging up the waterways
but you can see it gets pretty crowded
this was towards the end of the festival
and this is again you know just one
University if you go into downtown
Bangkok I mean the entire uh canals and
rivers are clogged with uh these
different uh kind of floating
altars oh and there was a rhinoceros
beedle crossing the road I forgot to
mention um so the tropical vegetable
Research Center is a national uh
organization I got a lot of confusion
with the avdc or the world vegetable
Center and there's even more confusion
CU they're right next to each other at
the camp sand campus uh but it's a
distinct organization they have a few
different mandates uh germ plasm is one
of the big ones but they also do
breeding and they do a lot of Outreach
work it was a real eye opener for me I
mean I've lived in the tropics before
but just a huge incredible diversity of
species that they work with and work on
maintaining and improving uh things like
this is a relative of black pepper that
was a popular spice before Chili Peppers
were discovered uh gak fruit fruit it's
a relative bitter melon that you eat the
arrows they're high in carotenoids and
then lots of plants just growing
spontaneously around there this is a
wild clomi that's used as a vegetable in
parts of Thailand uh you use it with a
chili paste and eat it like that or you
can use a poot herb but it was
incredible you know I think of this as
an ornamental that you see them outside
the Cornell store but to see them
growing here as wild plants are really
mind-boggling uh as I mentioned they do
a lot of Outreach uh we LED several
tours for classes this was one Professor
or one teacher from a high school group
climbing one of the trees to uh bring
down fruits to distribute to the
students a lot of students you know
especially as urbanization kind of goes
on are getting less and less in touch
with the kind of like uh rural roots and
some of the indigenous knowledge so they
do a really great job in their
indigenous vegetable garden which I'll
touch on in the next slide uh trying to
educate people about some of the
different herbs and vegetables that you
can use it was really popular you know
everyone wanted to try it this the fruit
was terrible it's a Bimi I don't know if
any of you know it which is incredibly
sour from oxalic Acid I never eat it
fresh but everyone was excited just for
the new experience of it I think more
than anything else uh as I mentioned
they had the indigenous vegetable garden
and this is actually what had originally
attracted me to the tbrc this is um a
pretty nice Garden kind of on the edge
of their research facility and when I
was there before it had kind kind of
been just in the planning stages but now
they've really set it up into distinct
areas based on the different regions of
Thailand uh Thailand has the Northeast
area the North Area Central area and
South and they have kind of theme
Gardens based on those regions now each
with their own kind of herbs and their
own vegetables uh tassanai chipet was a
master student when I was there about
seven years ago he's now the head of
germ plasm and he has an encyclopedic
knowledge of every single plant within
that Garden you know he'd go and we'd
pass it and he could tell me the tie
name and the local dialect name and how
you could use it for food and what you
used it for medicine and scientific
studies it was just incredible uh in
this case he's eating the uh pedal of
one of the uh tarot relatives uh but
just lots of unusual plants and unusual
uses for plants that I've been familiar
with this is a torch Ginger I'd seen it
in Hawaii it's used as a cut flower it's
really nice cuz it lasts a long time but
in Thailand it's also used in soups uh
it has kind of a gingery Tangy flavor to
it you can also eat it fresh it's a
little fibrous I think to eat fresh but
in soup I think it's pretty tasty and so
you could have it as kind of a dual
purpose that
way uh their main claim to fame is their
pepper germ plasm they have over 200
varieties of Chili Peppers that they've
collected
[Music]
within since peppers are new world but
uh kind of naturalized varieties they've
them into different Market classes
they've done lots of breeding work and
lots of characterization as
well uh the two big issues for pepper
production are uh diseases and then
insects and they've developed one
variety that's pretty much immune to
insect uh prediction for the insects
that are a problem in Thailand so now
they're breeding for uh anthros
resistance is the other big problems uh
we did a lot of sorting of different
varieties into these are insect damage
those are disease these are the Edible
Ones and then taking data like that but
you can see a lot of variation they have
three or four different species uh that
have been distributed within Thailand
and they also have a duplication of the
uh AVR DC's uh Chili Pepper germ plasm
which is 3,000 accessions they didn't
grow all of those out but they do grow
out the taii ones and they also do um
some seed production this is a ghost
pepper breeding project that they're
working on
there uh the other one I mean they have
a lot of reading work but this was one
of the things that I thought was really
interesting since it's not a crop that
we see in the US that much this is Rosel
it's a hibiscus uh relative and
depending on the taxonomist you ask it
might even still be a hibiscus um but
it's if you have tea and the tea turns
red typically it's because they say it
as dried hibiscus and this is what
they're talking about in Thailand it's
used fresh instead uh it's a a crop that
hasn't received a lot of breeding work
but the breeder ma did a cross between
these two varieties and got a huge range
of variation whites pinks peaches uh
short tall all sorts of other things uh
it's really interesting at the top also
because it inhibits asparagus growth and
so people are trying to use uh kind of
capture that uh it's not as good with
the red one because it dies everything
red but there's some interest in using
one of the white varieties for things
like that and then they also put it out
and dry it to see what it's like uh for
creating briges so it was really neat
kind of seeing the kind of scope of
variation they've
created uh while I was there they also
had their annual cassette Fair cassette
means agriculture in Thai and this is a
huge event I can't believe they put it
on every year but they do uh in the
course of one week they had half a
million people come to the campus and uh
kind of visit around they just they grew
up this entire Garden within the course
of two or three months all sorts of
hanging vegetables and different herbs
trying to kind of use things that we
think of as Edibles in a more ornamental
uh application which was really great
people were taking selfies all over the
place and you know wandering around I
mean it was but it was a great
experience you know for people who
wouldn't get to grow the plants
otherwise uh they also sold seeds of
some of the varieties they developed and
they also have a pure seed initiative to
try to kind of make sure the farmers
have access to good quality seeds uh
while I was there I my big thing was
brewing tea they wanted to introduce
people people to um kind of native Thai
herbal mixtures I prepared one from
thundia Laura Folia which is used as an
ornamental but it also is um used as a
detox not in the kind of way that we
talk about detoxing here in the US this
is actually like a detox it uh can be
used analogously with activated charcoal
like they say if you're drinking it
don't take medicine because it'll absorb
the medicine um but there's also been
some really good scientific studies on
uh delaying of diabetes symptoms and
improving liver function which diabetes
is a huge problem in Thailand so it was
interesting chatting with folks about it
uh we also uh sweetened it with stevia
Stevia is not a native Thai herb so
there was a lot of interest in that we
sold out of our seia plants within the
first day or two because of it you know
but it was a really kind of interesting
way of interacting with people um and I
also run into several Cornell lungs this
is a prid and r Tang uh who uh pres did
his uh Masters in entomology here Rua
did her PhD in horiculture a few years
back and then that's T habanada who I
never actually met when he was at
Cornell but he was apparently in plant
freeding um so uh he's a professor at
casseta camping and so that was fun
chatting with him too uh the I mean the
fair takes over the entire campus I
could give a whole presentation just on
it but I tried to encapsulate some of
the more interesting things uh they have
a huge Orchid show as part of it and you
know I'm used to Orchid shows in the US
but when you can grow them in the
tropics and you have the ideal weather
for it I mean the scale just becomes
amazing you know an idium tunnel mokara
tunnel you know and then all of these
incredible installations this was about
maybe a fifth of the whole uh setup that
they had there and then they also have
some more traditional judging things and
they had orchids for sale uh that was
the other thing price-wise you can buy
what would be a $40 vand Orchid for
about six bucks there or a collector
nepenthes these are some of the rarer
ones they had a rare species was $6 um
compared to what you'd pay in the US of
like $60 $70 they had airplants for 30
cents uh lest you think it's all plants
they also had animals this was uh from
their uh cattle breeding program they're
doing a lot of work trying to integress
uh good genetics into the uh landas VAR
in Thailand and they also did some work
with chickens which I don't know a lot
about but I know my adviser is a big
chicken fan so I thought I'd throw the
slide in um after I finished there I
moved on to chaii Chai is a Thai owned
and run company uh based that has kind
of expanded to have a market throughout
most of uh Southeast and South Asia they
have huge Market penetration within
India and in Bangladesh and they work on
a really wide range of crops looking at
this I'm realizing I left off two or
three in addition to these they do
research but they also do production
they do seed and they've also started
branching out into agrochemicals because
you know it's the way that most
companies seem to go uh I'm not going to
go into too much detail because it's a
seed company and you know proprietary
and all of that uh but I did take a few
photos while I was there and uh this was
actually the Cucumber one of three
cucumber breeders there uh we went out
and met with some Farmers who'd been
growing bitter melon varieties and were
interested in trying some other
varieties from the company uh so we kind
of gave them seeds talked with them
about their growing conditions it was
really neat you know they they're a
household name within most of Thailand
but they're not really well known
outside of Thailand yet and that's
partially a branding thing so it's been
it was a really interesting
experience they have an alliance with
takai but I don't I don't know the
details of it so you know I got little
hints and bits here and there but you
know very hashash and all that so uh
they have two main stations within
Thailand this is gapu where I was for
most of the time this is Western
Thailand and I think most people from
the US may have heard of bridge over the
river Quay or qu I forget how we
pronounce it here um but that's kind of
what the area is known for it's one of
the hottest driest areas in Thailand and
I was there during the hottest and drest
time um but it's it's a nice area very
picturesque lots of you know buts and
platea and all of that which is really
pretty uh it's also a tourist area
there's not much there besides tourism
and large expanses of kind of
unpopulated areas uh but they've managed
to make melons into a kind of major crop
within the area everyone I talked to in
Thailand before I started this
internship said you have to try the
melons in Gin operi they're so good
they're really famous and they're really
delicious but they've sort of created
the market for them within the company
uh this was they have a small sales area
at the research station to kind of you
know build on that and they have things
like you know melon chairs to kind of
keep people interested they're really
uncomfortable because they're made of
concrete but you know people love taking
photos with them um and the if you drive
back from gantu to Bangkok you'll see
melon stalls all along the road the
entire way back because you know it's
become such a huge part of the
reputation of the
area uh their other research station is
up in changmai changmai is much cooler
than gurri or most of Thailand um it's
used to be a separate Kingdom so it also
has a different culture and slightly
different dialect because of that uh you
can grow a lot of crops up there that
you can't grow in most of uh Thailand uh
things like strawberries uh this is I
took a photo of this because instead of
using black plastic mulch they use Leaf
debris and put it down individually so
it's kind of a you know more
eco-friendly form uh I got to explore
the town it's becoming a huge tourist
trap there's been a lot of movies coming
out about it and so people are kind of
flocking there by the dozens but it's uh
still has an incredible flower market
where I got to see kind of what's hot
and what's not and then this was also uh
these are the native are the kind of
traditional thae arrangements of flowers
kind of garlands that are placed on
altars or hung from your rear windshield
uh uh mirror if you're more modern uh
but you know seeing different kind of
combinations of flowers which is really
fun I did oh um and I was also visited
by some folks from Cornell but I'll skip
about that uh after I finished with chai
I moved down to Southern Thailand To Hai
which is in sanla so it's like right
above Malaysia it's like yeah um Hai has
sort of a bad reputation unfortunately
with most of the world there was a
bombing there a few years ago and most
of the Thai people I told I was going
there had never been there and joked
about you know dodging bullets and
things like that I didn't see a single
gun you entire time I was there and you
know which is very different from the US
in some ways um and I also thought felt
incredibly safe it's a really
interesting area because it's near what
used to be a port town and so it has a
lot of cultural exchange a lot of ethnic
Chinese that came in about 100 years ago
so and also it was also a separate
Kingdom and so there's a lot of
interface with a local uh Muslim
Community that had been part of that
Kingdom as well so it's really well
known for uh good food culture and other
things uh this is the professor I worked
with aan
p uh he's a really wellknown within phac
cognacy pharmacognosy is the study of
making medicine from plants which I'd
never heard of before I came there but
it's a huge field uh he had grad
students from all over the world uh and
ongoing exchanges with even more
countries he spent a month in Hawaii
while I was there uh doing some other
research and so it was a really
interesting insight into kind of
academic culture uh
they do a lot of extractions of
marigolds and ginger and other things
trying to isolate out different
compounds and then testing on sometimes
animal models sometimes cell models so
you know it was just a really different
experience than what I'm used to I also
ran into adir Rong who did his uh PhD
here a few years back uh and graduated
uh in horiculture as well he's now a
professor uh doing a lot of the farm
program there all of the undergrads Who
start in agriculture or anything related
to that are required to spend their
first semester working on the student
run Farm uh and they grow uh all of
these different vegetables and it's
really fun you know some of them have no
background in it so you see them taking
selfies you know as the Cabbage gets
larger and larger and then they take it
you know to Market and they sitting
there trying to sell you on their
cabbage it's a it was a really cool
experience you know getting to see them
and he was kind of intrinsically
involved in that
uh oh the area is really nice as I
mentioned it's sort of near the sea so
there's a lot of like uh beaches and
other things this is one of the
emblematic things it's a mermaid kind of
like the one in Copenhagen uh and then a
Naga statue which is uh one of the
mythical creatures in Thailand uh I also
got to explore some of the wetlands
nearby which was really neat I didn't
know Thailand had Wetlands uh but I went
to one of the bio preserves and they one
of the things they had in uh kind of
payment for us getting a tour was they
asked us to replant a field of palm
trees the oldfashioned way using a stick
so all of the students you know these
were Pharmacy students with no
background in agriculture at all so
everyone was really excited to sit there
and pound the stick into the ground put
in the palm trees you know which was
really great uh I went there with a few
uh this is a postto from India Ahmad and
fan uh grad student from Pakistan and we
also got to try uh pure Palm juice while
we were there where they cut off the tip
of the male and fluoresence of the Palm
collect the sap and then you drink it uh
they also had Palm moonshine which they
were Muslims so they didn't try and I
took their share instead it was
incredibly potent but very interesting
you know I could see it catching on here
um my research work there was doing Leaf
resin extraction uh the idea that I'd
pitched to aan park was looking at
impatients uh for different compounds
specifically nether Quinones in patients
produce chemicals very similar to the
ones in Henna so they can be used for
dying but they also have methylated
forms and other forms that aren't found
uh within loone which is the uh plant
that hna is extracted from so we were
looking at them and trying to see what
we could kind of do with that uh this is
the dried leaves this is of the henna
tree they had one growing there ground
up and then extracting in methanol
evaporating it and then running thin
layer chromatography it was a whole new
experience for me you know as many of
you know I'm much more of a whole plant
person so this was kind of a fun
addition we had a hard time with the
process we ran both hlc and TLC and we
would get conflicting results about you
know we would find henna compounds and
impatients but not in the henna so you
know it was like there's still some
stuff that we're kind of sorting out but
we're talking about maybe doing that
down the road uh we did find a whole
bunch of compounds that hadn't been
described though so it's some really
interesting work for the future and it
could also be addressed for conservation
work for some of the Native invent
species um ah uh I took quite a few side
trips while I was there as I mentioned
uh these were mostly around Bangkok one
of the things you know since this is
mostly a plant crowd that I wanted to
point out is Bangkok You know despite
being pretty Metropolitan and developed
has really made an effort to create
green spaces this is outside one of the
bougier malls uh in Bangkok and it has a
really nice planting of ground covers
grasses there's a green wall nearby and
this is the second floor of a metro stop
you know so they've really like tried
made an effort for that this is the
eighth floor of another Mall uh they've
built an entire outdoor garden with
waterfalls and all sorts of other plants
so it was really kind of neat seeing how
they kind of push the green into an
urban landscape uh I took some
obligatory Temple shots I'm not really a
religious person but I mean they're
pretty great ornate uh this was a
Chinese temple that was in the middle of
one of the Thai temples huge Buddhas you
know like two or three stories tall
again you know I don't I have other
photos of them but it was a really
interesting cultural experience for that
uh one of the side trips I took in
changma was to the queen syit botanic
garden if you have a chance it's an
incredible Garden to visit uh I met went
there mostly because exan is the uh one
of the world Authorities on impatience
he's done a ton of research work he's
named countless species
um and he runs a lot of their research
program uh the garden itself is really
interesting they have a canopy walk and
like I said changa is a slightly
different climate so you get to see kind
of a whole different range of plants
they had a Rose Garden which is not what
I expected to see in Thailand but they
have cultivars that are really well
adapted to the climate there and tons of
people taking selfies with them and then
a lot of other plants as well uh bermad
house and a terrestrial Orchid breeding
program which I thought was really neat
you hear a lot of work
going on in Thailand about dendrobium
orchids and band orchids but they've
done a lot of work with this is kthy and
also FAS so it's something that you know
I think is kind of on the cusp EK was
sort of complaining though that he wants
to push impatience but he said orchids
are always considered so much sexier so
they get all the funding money you know
so hopefully that'll change in the
future uh I did find a ton of different
impatient species this was everything
that was well a small selection of what
was in flower at the time they have just
an incredible variety of them that e and
other researchers have collected from
different parts of Thailand in the
surrounding area this is a kingdong w
from me Myanmar uh it's kogus the
flowers is never fully open uh other
species you know again all of these just
growing within the area uh ones that
form cxes so kind of Woody sort of bulul
type things at the base of the plant to
kind of hang on through drought regions
there was one that was neon blue that
unfortunately wasn't in flower but they
had photos of um and they said one of
the hard things from a conservation
point of view is they don't have the
funding to really keep the accessions
going so it's just kind of whatever
grows kind of keeps growing and they
keep hoping it'll you know persist uh
we're in talks right now with the New
York botanic garden and striving uh
banic Garden in San Francisco to see if
we can get some conservation work going
on with these maybe some breeding work
but uh we'll see so it was just an
incredible experience from that point of
view too I took a side trip to Taiwan on
because my Visa ran out um and uh met up
with a a jaria breeder who I knew from
the US uh wwang Linn he's now working at
Bayer out in Nebraska but he kind of
showed me around I'd never been to
Taiwan and so I was amazed again you
know a lot of use of Green Space there
this is a park that's I think two years
old they've completely turned over what
was a slum before uh they we took a bike
trip through the middle of town they've
really worked on kind of building up
green spaces we hi to the top of the
mountain uh unfortunately it was near
the beginning of Chinese New Year so
everyone was hiking to the top of the
mountain but it was a really great
experience you know and really again you
know it's an interesting intersection
between Chinese culture and tropical
climate so orchids being utilized in
different ways uh really like
neat uh I also went to Malaysia because
it was a really quick hop from Southern
Thailand to Malaysia and met up with two
Cornell lanss from food science Adi
sikin and tjuan uh they're both
professors in food science now uh I'll
get into some of the botanical gardens
there although again you know I could go
on and on and on about that uh but uh
tangu works at a uh University next to
the ocean so I went and visited him
there explored the plant life and some
of the beaches a little bit uh but also
went around downtown gual lumur and
again I was surprised at some of the use
of plants there these are irises and
ornamental grasses that they keep alive
through throughout the year inside uh
they weren't In Bloom at this time but
I'm told they're really spectacular when
they do Bloom and throughout the entire
inside of a
mall uh the as I mentioned there's two
main Botanic Gardens that I visited uh
one inside gual lumur and one about an
hour South near one of the research
stations uh orchids are becoming a
really big thing in Malaysia there's
been a push to compete with the
Singaporean Market uh and Arandas which
are descended from this one this is a
arachnus uh spe species have become kind
of the go-to unfortunately while I was
there there was some construction going
on but they kind of had a nice Twist on
it and paid artists to create these
murals on the areas that were under
construction kind of like when the
commons was under construction they did
the same thing um but it was really nice
the things that were in flower were
really great and they had heliconia
species I'd never seen before at a
putraa uh both of them were more kind of
walking gardens than anything else one
thing I did see and I haven't seen this
as much in US Botanic Gardens is they
had a whole chart on how to read a plant
label which I think is something that
gets overlooked a lot but was really
nice and it's in English and Malay so
you know I saw a lot of people stopping
and looking at this they had this at the
different entrances so it really kind of
enhanced the uh experience for people
who are
visiting um I'll finish up here with
Singapore um for those of you who don't
know Singapore is this Teensy Little
Island right off the end of Malaysia
it's essentially a city state um and
it's one of the economic powerhouses of
Southeast Asia uh they've also managed
to maintain a pretty green presence
despite being a citystate this is one of
about five or six Gardens I saw in their
airport uh that they've uh they even
have a dendrobium orid that they've
named after the airport it's really you
know devotion um they have like uh
artist stations outside these to like
teach kids how to draw flowers things
like that really neat ways of engaging
uh with the public and Singapore is also
the only country in the world that has a
hybrid as their national flower which is
Papo Lan uh uh missim I think it used to
be called Vanda it's one of the
vandaceous
types uh I went to Singapore botanic
garden and it is spectacular it's been
around since the 1800s it's really well
established they have an orchid breeding
program that's I think at least 5050
years old if not older than that uh
they've registered thousands of orchid
hybrids uh maintain one of the few
chunks of native rainforest within
Singapore which was just spectacular and
have a lot of theme Gardens I I was
captivated by the evolution Garden
because I thought that would probably
lead to all sorts of outcry in the US uh
but it seemed to be a really well done
Garden there uh it's even this tree is
featured on the back of some Singaporean
currency so it's really integral to
Singaporean culture they also had a
banana and ginger Garden I'd never seen
a banana like this before and was just
so excited you know I think we should
have these all over the place and then
uh uh Orchid fountains as well one thing
that I did find really interesting but I
thought was kind of odd is they had
suggestions about oh this plant would be
great for home landscaping or oh this
plant you know could be used in this
sort of arrangement but Singapore
there's almost no Garden space because
it's mostly in apartments so I thought
it was a great effort you know I think
that would be something maybe areas with
more uh of a kind of footprint for the
housing would could really appreciate
uh I also went to Gardens by the bay
which is the other botanic garden there
uh full disclosure I just accepted a job
with them so I'll try not to like Wax
too like eloquent about it uh but they
are unique uh in that they're one of the
few Gardens that has a conservatory
that's cooled uh Singapore is right on
the Equator so they cool both of the
conservatories to grow temperate type
plants so that people in the tropics can
see them um they're they like to kind of
build themselves as kind of creating a
sort of Central Park Vibe they're in the
center of what will be the downtown
business district and they're expanding
they own several properties as well uh
there's a lot of really neat
architectural features like these are
they call the super trees which are
obviously not trees but they've put in a
lot of uh epiic plants to kind of create
that same sort of feeling and they have
a lot of uh crosswalks at different
levels to see different things too which
I thought was really neat uh one of the
conservatories is called the flower Dome
it has kind of seasonal changes
exhibits the funding is amazing and so
they bring in you know huge amounts of
tulips uh huge amounts of dalas from all
over the world uh I was there the first
time I think was around the Chinese New
Year celebration and they had just a
huge field of doia in the middle of the
Dome the second time was tulip Mania and
they had tulips all over the place um
selfie stations Garden is geared more
towards people who don't have a
background in horiculture and they're
trying to kind of bring people in so you
know it wasn't like some of the other
banic Gardens I've been to where it's
very kind of much more about like oh
this is a Botanical gem it was there was
a lot more spectacle but kind of trying
to attract people with that and then
kind of teach them whether they liked it
or not kind of thing so um they also had
brought in five full-size palm trees
from Chile several Thousand-Year old
olive trees from Spain I mean it's a
really incredible undertaking and the
garden's only 3 years old uh last year I
think they said they had over 8 million
visitors uh so it's really taken off uh
the other Dome is a cloud forest that
they've built inside uh it has sepal
waterfalls and then also walks going
around different parts of it it's I
think seven stories tall um and mostly
focuses on epiy and other things like
that but I found an impatient species
and was really excited in the middle of
one of the ponds though and so I kept
leaning over trying to get a better and
better photo and finally managed to get
pulled back before I fell in
uh but it was right in the middle of the
carnivorous plant area which I thought
was really neat too and they again they
try to get people engaged they have a
whole display of stalactites and
stalagmites that they've imported and
geodes to kind of you know add to kind
of the feel to it but people seem to
really appreciate it uh the outside
Gardens are really nice as well there's
a lot of water features because it is by
the bay um and it's it used to be
brackish water it's now mostly fresh
water uh and then it's also become a
very popular
spot for uh Sportsmen so a as I
mentioned they're kind of creating a
Central Park Vibe so a lot of joggers go
through and if you get there at around
6:00 in the evening when the work day
ends you'll get like almost a traffic
jam of joggers kind of jogging through
here uh it's gotten to the point they
now actually have host a marathon to
kind of Channel some of that I think uh
they have different restaurants around
the area as well to kind of accommodate
it but I think it's kind of a sneaky way
to introduce people to plants too you
know you get to see things they're
flowering at the same
time uh with that um I'll just finish up
a few people had asked me about tips for
uh applying for the Dreer and so I
thought I'd just mention a few things um
if any of you are interested in applying
uh one of the things I think that really
is important is having a focused theme
or plan for your proposal you know I've
heard several times and I think the
committee told me as well you know
making sure that you can really
definitively say something rather than I
want to go to Thailand you know know
just kind of like saying okay this is
what you're focusing on uh I personally
I think outlining your internship with
the folks at the place would be really
good I speak from kind of my own
personal experience here where uh I
didn't outline some of the things and it
was like oh you want to do that well the
person who would do that is out of town
so kind of making sure that everything's
kind of planned out before you go uh
figure out your visas early on so you're
not leaving the country every month
trying to renew it like I did for the
last four months um but if not use as an
excuse to travel uh write your reports
well in advance that's just something I
struggle with uh and take lots of Sid
trips uh I kind of felt conflicted
sometimes about like oh I'm in here I
should be doing more of this and more of
that but I also would say you know it's
important to take some time off to you
know there were times where you just
kind of sit in a coffee shop and
appreciate the fact that you are where
you are you know you don't have to be
filling each
moment uh with that I'll thank the
drewer committee thank you so so much
for this incredible opportunity I it was
really life-changing and not just
because of the job offer um and it's
just totally been uh eye opening in so
many wonderful ways I'd like to thank my
PhD committee since they helped me kind
of get pushed through the last part of
it and really held on to kind of hold me
to it to get everything in uh and then
I'd like to thank the people at the
different organizations who were kind of
in charge while I was there uh chaman
sunun who the head of r at the tbrc suat
meanon who's the head of plant breeding
at chai and then par
Pupa who's the uh professor at Prince of
s claw
University uh they all were just really
welcoming and were really
helpful so with that I'll take some
questions this was something I saw as a
souvenir and just thought that was
really cool so but anyway thank
[Applause]
you this has been in a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu