This is a production of Cornell
University.
Yeah, I'm basically going to talk about
uh what I've done so far and how I see
myself develop as a soil scientist
moving forward. So, uh I'm excited for
the talk. Uh so yeah I'm going to be
jumping around different research
projects that I've done in the past
starting from my undergrad
uh through my masters and then my PhD
work uh some postto work that I did uh
with Ryan lab and also I will give a
brief uh glimpse of what I'll be doing
uh in the coming year at Penn State.
So
uh I'm from Nepal. So uh it's a small
country. Uh I'm from a valley
uh which one of the biggest valley in
Asia. So and rice is our staple crop. Uh
I'm from somewhere here and this is me
and my brother while growing up. So
uh again uh lots of influence of
agriculture while growing up and because
it's a big agricultural country it's
hard to not uh think about
agriculture uh there. So again bit of uh
background I worked with bioar as Matt
mentioned during my undergrad I'll talk
a little bit more about that and during
my masters at the University of Tokyo I
worked with uh calsign phosphate rock so
this was a local phosphate rock
fertilizer that we are developing in uh
in coordination with a university of
Tokyo Jurkas and also people uh in West
Africa. So that was my main master's
project and we did some crop modeling
with ABSIM uh to simulate those data. Uh
my PhD project was mainly looking at
biochar and carbon nanoparticles as soil
amendments for coarse textured sandy uh
acidic soils in Florida. And we also
looked at different nanoparticles. It
was a more of a side project. Uh during
my PhD
uh one year around one year uh at Ryan
Lab, I got to work with uh some of the
uh soil health stuff uh soil health data
from the long-term experiment that we're
having and a bunch of different cover
crop uh systems that uh the cool work
that is happening uh with Ryan Lab. And
in my uh current project, I'll be
working mainly on uh using uh anorobic
soil disinfestation. So this is a kind
of like a a technique in organic systems
an alternative to chemical fumigant to
sort of restore or improve the soil
health of uh of organic soils. So I'll
be introducing that a little bit. So uh
back going back to Nepal where I'm from
we we have a big problem. Uh again we
call it the burning
problem. Uh so farmers especially at the
end of the season uh they burn a lot of
the crop residues because as as a way to
prepare their field for the next crop.
uh but this creates a massive issue
environmentally and if you look at uh
look at the NASA firms map during that
time of the season you can see a bunch
of fire kind of small fires and these
are not real fires but these are farmers
burning the residue uh especially the
the southern part of Nepal where a lot
of agriculture rice wheat based
agriculture is so and this affects uh
the environment and you can see the haze
uh pretty much and the beautiful
mountains that people go uh to see are
not really visible during that time. So
it's a big issue uh managing crop
residues. So yeah I think when we are
doing undergrad we are about five or six
people who are thinking about an project
how to address this issue and again
there's a saying in in our country that
sometime you need to have a solution
like the problem. So we we came up with
the burning uh burning solution idea. It
was so we we decided to uh get some of
the crop residues and prepare different
kinds of biochar from uh these residues.
It was yeah it was a locally kind of
like developed furnace that we used to
prepare these biochar and we did a field
study with garden pee and we found that
again different uh different feed stock
of biochar that we use have different
kind of effect on on the yield but also
uh on how the soil nutrient availability
and cycling uh happens. But overall I
think we could say that uh using
bioar uh was a good alternative
especially compared to burning those
residues. So moving on again I told you
I'll be jumping from one to another. You
can ask questions later if you have some
uh I worked in West Africa during my
master's program. So here like I
mentioned we are working with a local
phosphate rock fertilizer as an
alternative to the chemical triple super
phosphate or single super phosphate
fertilizer and we are doing uh field
studies with sorghum in four different
regions of of Burkinaaso a country in
west
Africa and what we found essentially was
uh oops uh was that uh it was again on
average about 30 to 50% and effective
compared to the chemical fertilizer but
that really depended a lot on the region
and the factor that was driving uh
driving that difference across the
region was uh was the environment. So uh
soil moisture and also the soil type has
had a major impact on how effective
these new uh phosphate rock fertilizers
were. So uh we did a bit of a crop
modeling with Absim. It was uh we were
able to predict or simulate the biomass
quite well but we were uh we're still
working on uh how to work or how to
accurately predict yield uh with appsim
because it was not really sensitive to
drought and uh that is something that
has been added I think since in appsim
so it's a lot more robust in terms of uh
simulating these systems uh apps as uh
compared to this was 2019. So
uh and then uh my PhD was at the
University of Florida where I worked
with uh carbon nanop particles and
biochar at soil amendments uh for uh for
the acidic sandy soils that that are in
Florida. So again the big question I
guess that most of us in this room are
working towards I believe uh is how can
we grow more food and again the how to
grow it economically and also
sustainably. So uh that was the idea
behind this project and again there are
different ways different management
practices different things that we are
all working on but uh one of the ways uh
that we can increase our overall food
production could be uh if we know how to
utilize our sandy soils. Uh currently
there is only about four to 5% of sandy
soils in the world uh that are
cultivated. So uh again if we can figure
out how to cultivate them uh there's
there's a room for expansion and there
are opportunities there but as you can
imagine there's a reason why these soils
are not cultivated as much because it's
not really easy to manage especially the
soils that are really sandy uh like like
those in Florida uh more than 90% sands
and and those that are acidic pH in in
the range of 4.5 to 5 5.5 and it's
really difficult to build organic matter
in these conditions because of the
humidity, temperature and everything. So
not not easy to retain organic matter
and nutrients in the soil. Uh it doesn't
help that these regions uh that have a
lot of sandy soils often also are in the
area that are quite vulnerable to
climate if we can still say climate uh
environment uh and all these kind of
pollution
uh that makes it really difficult to
manage.
Uh historically though I think these
soils have been managed quite
successfully uh thanks to the citrus
industry. Uh that was quite successful
in Florida. Uh but uh since 2010 uh more
than a decade now there's been a steady
decline and the industry is really
suffering from the citrus greening
disease. So there's a lot of interest
there's a lot of need uh among farmers
among different stakeholders to find
alternative crops to straightress uh and
because of that we are trying to see uh
if we can amend these soils to come up
with ways we can grow field crops in
that region.
Uh we looked at different soil
amendments, compost,
manure,
biochar, again different uh different
properties, compost and manure, more
readily available nutrients versus more
recalent carbon. So uh different
challenges associ associated with uh
each of these. And while we were
thinking about an idea, we also learned
about this new uh technology, new uh
term I guess uh called nanotechnology.
So this was driven by the United States
nanotechnology initiative that was
released in 2000 and there was a bunch
of different nanoparticles that were
being researched uh since. So again we
found that carbon nanop particle could
be one way uh of supplementing these
soils and amending to provide more
carbon so the nutrient can be retained
much more. And so we we started to
investigate on these product and we we
did some preliminary studies and uh
basically my PhD work focused on
comparing biochar and carbon nanop
particles uh for how they work how they
affect nutrient retention how they
affect crops crop growth and performance
and also if if and how we can optimize
these systems uh in the region. An
obvious question. What are nanop
particles? Uh basically any particle
that are in the range of a billionth of
a meter is known as nanoparticles for
people working in the soil. Uh the the
fine clay particles are also natural
nanoparticles. We're of course talking
about the engineered nanoparticles here
but just to give a
reference. So yeah basically something
that is available in nature but also can
be uh generated in uh through
industry. Carbon is a big component of
soil. We all know a lot of different
soil functioning especially nutrient uh
depends on carbon. Uh one way of kind of
like understanding these carbon nanop
particles could be to think it as
ultra fine biochar cannot uh not that
straightforward but just for visualizing
that and there are different kinds of
nanoparticles
uh mainly based on sape and solubility
and all these kind of things. Uh you
might have heard about uh single wall
multi-wall nano tubes bucky balls and
all different kinds of nanoparticle that
are used in different industry.
uh we're using the carbon black nanop
particles. So this was uh basically
utilizing the byproduct of uh the
industry and we wanted to make it water
dispersible so it can be applied through
the existing uh irrigation and
fertigation systems by the
farmers. And the idea behind using these
nanoparticle is because when you when
you convert these particle into such a
small size uh they they gain high jeta
potential a negative charge potential a
high surface area of course with the
size and uh they have been shown to have
some kind of uh bio bio- stimulating
effect to crops but it was still new and
not a lot of studies has have been done
in across different crops. So we wanted
to see how it behaves uh in the soils we
have down in
Florida. To give you a perspective uh
that it's not only about the size uh
when you uh reduce the particle size to
such small
uh dimension the property of the
particle also changes uh significantly.
So it's not only the size or the surface
area effect but the properties also
change and that could impart different
uh properties to plants and also in the
soil. So that's why we wanted to study.
Oh that didn't come out as I wanted but
uh so my project had three components
plant soil and environment. So we're
looking at how it uh how plants uptake
and respond to these particles how does
soil respond how does nutrient cycling
is affected and how does it affect
environment. So we did a bunch of
uh incubation and greenhouse studies in
the beginning uh some column leeching
studies to see how it's less in the
environment and how uh how long it can
stay in the environment. That was our
initial idea even though we could not do
uh during my time but uh the people at
UCF are now doing that uh life cycle
assessment. Uh we also looked at some
soil ecology especially how it affects
soil microbiome
uh bacteria uh and then we took uh took
these particles into field uh for some
field
trials. So a couple of greenhouse
studies basically we found that the
effect of these particles was dependent
on the application rate as uh as we
could imagine. We found that around 200
to 400 ppm or milligram per kg
application uh there was a spike in
terms of uh both uh plants on how how
well they were growing but also in the
soil uh in terms of uh how much
nutrients was being retained. But we
also noticed that as we increase these
uh application rates to higher rates uh
the the effects seized quite
dramatically at sometimes and even in
soil especially the soil microbiome and
uh biological indicators started to
drop. So we we kind of saw uh that kind
of response through our greenhouse
studies. Uh and then we did some column
leeching studies uh uh in two different
soils uh alysol and sportool. basically
differing in pads. I would say uh
sportool much more acidic around pH5
versus alphasol
uh p7. So we also wanted to kind of see
across both pads because uh these
particles have a low pads. So yeah, we
looked at uh different nutrients and how
they were being leased. Uh the bars that
are kind of red, yellow
and orange I guess are kind of like a
high input systems. So the they were
highly fertilized versus these uh they
were low input systems. So uh we found
that in general
uh carbon nanoparticles we used two
different uh treatments. So uh again we
we ran about 13 leeching events uh
accumulating about 2 years of rainfall
in the region and we found that uh 200
to 400 mgram per kg of these carbon
nanomart particles were were retaining a
lot more nutrients in the soil. So the
the cumulative leeching of of nitrate
from the soil especially in those
intensive systems were reduced
significantly throughout our uh leeching
events. Uh a similar effect in terms of
phosphorus but mainly especially uh we
saw significant effect uh in the
potassium. So uh as you can imagine
potassium is a positively charged ion in
the soil and when we have uh when we
apply these particles with a high
negative potential. So we found that
they were attracting these potassium ion
a lot more and uh even though we didn't
kind of nail down this but we we also
thought that because of this uh
potassium we also saw some bio stimul
stimulating effect on the plants was
mainly driven through this potassium
uptake uh with these nanoparticles even
though we couldn't kind of like
mechanistically prove that through our
study but uh recent studies have also
kind of like uh indicated that
uh we looked at soil ecology mainly
focused on bacteria here. Uh we found
that when we applied uh these nanop
particles there were a lot more unique
uh genera of bacteria that we that we
are seeing in the soil. Uh again that
alone doesn't tell anything. It could be
that there are new bacteria coming
because there's a new particle or it
could be that it's just enhancing the
diversity of the soil. So this work is
still a work in progress I would say. We
also looked at different film of of
bacteria that were that were in the
treatments and we found that both biotar
and also uh low application rates of
these nanop particles were uh
significantly increasing the
cyanobacteria in the soil uh which are
kind of responsible or related to
nitrogen fixation and also uh nitrogen
cycling in the soil. So we uh we haven't
done the functional uh stuff yet, but
that's uh that's something we're
planning to do hopefully
soon. Uh so yeah, we did a bunch of
greenhouse uh column leing and soil
ecological studies and then we we were
finally kind of confident enough to try
these in the field. Uh this was the
research field.
uh okay I could have given this a little
bit earlier but uh bit more about these
nanop particles so these are generated
from carbon black these have caroxil
functional group and they have pH in the
range of
5.5 high negative ga potential and a
particle size in the range of 20 to 130
nano meters uh compared to biochar so
these were generated from the oak wood
residue that we have in Florida much
more carbon and much more higher pets
compared to uh these nanop particles. So
we did a field study this was not a
rotation so two nearby fields with sugar
beat uh and corn. So I guess the only
main difference in ter in terms of soil
in these two experiments was uh we lined
the p uh lined the bead field before
study because a beet was a lot more
sensitive to low ps but also we wanted
to see uh the effect of these materials
in different ps. So it kind of like uh
and corn was not uh limed before the
study.
So and looking at the eels uh we saw
that again similar to what we saw before
we saw significant increase in a leaf
suit biomass and also root biomass here
in in terms of sugar beat with uh around
200 to 400 ppm application of these
particles. So roughly about 20 to 24%
increase in yield and uh as we we didn't
go as high this time but we we could see
that the the increase in yield was
starting to seize uh as we increase the
application rates. Uh with biochar we
didn't have a significant effect.
Uh and similarly in corn we also saw
that uh there was a spike in terms of
corn yields with these uh with these
nanop particles and we saw ill responses
up to about uh 400 mgram per kg for corn
and we're getting quite good yields of
corn with these particles. So uh I think
last year starting last year we had our
first onfarmm experiment with these
particles
and I'm hearing that uh the farmers are
quite excited about these particles.
We couldn't do that during my time but
uh anyways obvious questions what's
driving these eel eel gains with uh
nanop particles uh overall uh soil
biogeeochemistry especially how the
nutrients react to these particles and
how these particles are increasing the
nutrient retention uh in the soil
profile. We also saw that uh through our
field
studies. So uh we looked at soil pH and
EC. So uh different dates we sample the
soils 30 70 and 110
uh and different treatments
here. So the blue one here is what we're
comparing. This is the standard practice
and uh the black one here is bioar and
these four are uh the carbon
nanoparticle treatments uh with
increasing rates of application. So we
found that both carbon nanop particles
and
biochar ra soil pads uh in these in
these soils both in limed and unlined
conditions and it reduced uh soil ec
electrical conductivity. So basically it
increased the buffering capacity of
these soils and as a result of this we
saw that a nutrient retention was a lot
more increased with nanop particles not
so much with biochar even though there
was some increase we didn't see as
significant effect but especially during
mid-season we found there was a lot more
uh nitrate uh nitrogen with these uh
nanoparticle treatment and we I don't
present that here But when we look we
analyze the leaves of these corn and and
bead plants we saw a significant spike
of nitrogen in the mid-season treatment
as well. So it was throughout our
greenhouse and field studies and
different crops. Uh again we saw a
significant effect uh in
mid-season potassium especially and it
was really almost linear. So we could
really see that potassium was uh
retained in soil and it was being also
uptaken uh by by the plants. Uh again we
didn't uh look this directly but we also
saw an increase in potassium with
biochar but when we looked at our leaf
samples uh we didn't
see we didn't see a similar increase in
uh in uptake of potassium by the plants.
So again we don't know for sure yet but
I think both the particles were kind of
able to retain more nutrients but carbon
nanop particle was able to supply these
nutrient to the plant more readily as
opposed to biotar
uh in which was kind of holding more
nutrients but the supply was not as uh
similar to the nanop
particles. Again that could be also
because biochar kind of requires more
incubation time compared to nanop
particles because it's uh it's a much
larger surface area. Uh similar case uh
we looked at uh the microbial
respiration biomass all the biological
indicators we found a spike at low
application rates uh throughout the
treatments. And as we uh increase our
application rates, we could see that uh
these microbial indicators uh
consistently were being reduced at
higher application rates. So and that
could be because of a potential hermetic
effect which basically means that at low
application there's a positive effect
and that either seizes or you start to
have uh some kind of negative effect at
high application rates. uh pretty
similar in in case of uh the enzyme
activities although it was significant
only for the ura enzyme which is
responsible for nitrogen but we also saw
oops uh a decline as we increase the
rate in terms of the enzyatic activity
of the soil. So overall we found that
carbon nanop particles increased both
corn and sugar beet yields in the field
both enhanced the buffering capacity
uh of our soils. Carbon nanop particles
especially both particles also increase
the nutrient retention but carbon
nanoparticles increase the leaf uh
uptake of uh NPK and we found that at
higher application rates uh the
microbial activities was seized but at
lower activities there was an increase
in soil microbial activities and we also
did some uh ecological analysis here and
we found pretty similar uh results
compared like like the field
studies. So, uh that's that's about it
for my PhD
work. I joined Ryan Lab last year 2024
and I was involved in a couple of
projects uh different cover crops uh
based projects. So, I'm going to talk a
little about the organic cropping
systems experiment that we have and uh
this is the 20th anniversary. So
essentially we have four different
treatments here or four different
philosophies of how we can manage
organic systems uh high fertility
systems here we are increasing the the
amendments and fertilizer that we are
applying to the soil. So a lot higher
about 50% higher fertilizer than uh than
the low low fertility treatment. In the
low fertility we are relying a lot more
on the ecological processes such as
incorporating legumes to provide that uh
sort of deficient uh soil fertility. So
uh so two gradients of fertility and two
gradients of uh weed management uh
enhanced weed management. Uh here we
have more intensive weed management uh
multiple passes to control weeds versus
a reduced tage treat uh treatment or
philosophy where we're reducing the
tillage and trying to manage weed more
culturally such as u uh using a mulch uh
and things like that. So and uh so the
crops were
grown in rotation different crops. There
are two entry points. It's a little bit
complicated if I go through all of these
but what I was looking mainly was
uh we're comparing how these four
treatments uh lined up in terms of soil
health indicators and we were comparing
these to uh conventional corn fields. So
this was uh 80 years around 80 years of
conventional corn. Uh and then this
treatment right here is is the alley. So
this is the grass alleys in between in
between the treatments. So uh mainly
looking at uh the conventional corn
versus the four different treatments.
And we could see that compared to the
conventional oops that
was not the right click. All right. So
uh compared to the conventional corn we
saw a significant effect uh in terms of
soil aggregate stability with the
organic systems uh the letters are
slightly off here but uh irrespective of
different philosophies or treatments
that we're using we could see uh an
increase
in uh the aggregation and soil structure
throughout uh throughout these study. uh
not as clear differences in terms of uh
predictable soil protein and also uh
soil labile soil carbon the permanent
manganate oxidizable soil carbon but
overall when we looked at the overall
soil health score this is uh from the
Cornell uh comprehensive soil health
assessment we saw that uh compared to
the corn and even compared to the alley
the organic systems were consistently
irrespective of the philosophy reads
uh higher soil health indicators uh in
these studies. So
uh that was sort of the main thing that
I looked at from this experiment. Uh
another project that I was involved in
was using the integrated cover crop
experiment to control a white mold uh
which is a soybean uh disease and also
weeds uh in soybean and dry bean system.
So basically what we're doing is uh we
are planting the cover crop uh in the in
the fall September October cereal rye
and we had three different treatments
here
uh till two till
treatments one without cover crop one
with cover crop and one treatment that
has uh where the the cover crop is mowed
and a mat of cereal r formed uh for weed
and also we found that uh it was
effective
in uh disease suppression. So two main
crops soybean and dry bean different
seeding rates and we evaluated different
plant parameters and analyzed these uh
in
our I'm mainly going to focus on white
mold uh because that was kind of like
the most distinct uh results that we saw
from the study. So we here are the three
treatments the tills only without cover
crop uh cover crop till treatment and
cover crop mulch treatment. So we we saw
that uh compared
to both the the till treatments the the
treatment with the rye molds was able to
reduce the white mold by almost uh 70 to
80% uh across uh across soybean and in
both ears.
So, so what is happening here is uh this
is the pathogen of white mold. So, what
this is doing is by having the mulch
protect the soil or cover the soil we
are reducing the the functional
germination of these epothesia. So, uh
this is in the ry mulch treatment versus
this is the trill treatment. So and this
is uh why because of the reduction in
the spores produced uh we could we were
seeing a reduction
in white mold. Uh in terms of weed
biomass and density we saw an overall
reduction in white b weed biomass with
uh the ry mulch treatment. There was
some variation across years here. This
is the uh weed density. So uh we think
that some of these high numbers is
because uh there was a regrowth in
cereal rye which was also counted as
weed and and because there is uh not
really big difference in biomass. So
it's uh kind of like counting more small
plants but not really turning into a big
biomass that is competing uh in terms of
weed
pressure. Uh we looked at the eel there
was a variation across years. So in 2020
uh the yield were pretty similar among
the treatments versus in 2019 in soybean
we had uh about 20% yield reduction. So
uh and in dry bean there was about 20%
yield reduction uh in 2020. So again
depending on probably weather and also
uh there could be room for optimizing
planting rates uh in dry bin
especially. So that's uh that's about it
from my postto with Brian lab and now
I'm uh in my second postural adventure
uh with the vegetable crop science lab
at Penn State. So here kind of switching
gears into more vegetables and
horicultural crops uh and different
systems. Uh the main project that I'll
be working uh working at Penn State is
sort of regenerating or improving the
soil health of uh through anorobic soil
disinfestation
uh to manage disease weeds and soil
health in organic vegetable production
system. So this is uh going to be the
main project that I'll be working on.
We'll have a bunch of different
greenhouse and field studies. So
essentially what we're doing is amending
the soil
uh with readily decomposible carbon
source
uh and then muling the soil with kind of
like covering the soil with uh oxygen
impermeable film to to induce the the
anorobic condition in the soil. And then
we are irrigating the soil until
saturation and leaving it for about a
month and then opening the film and then
going with a uh a vegetable crop tomato
or cucumber and to see uh to see effect
in soil health uh and also crop
production. So yeah, another thing that
we are trying to kind of like add to
this uh from this year is uh to try to
use a more local locally available
carbon sources. So we're looking at
molasses which is a byproduct of sugar
can uh industry wheat mlings which are a
byproduct from wheat and also poultry
manure or chicken manure. So using them
as carbon and nitrogen source uh to to
optimize the anorobic uh treatment and
we're also trying to integrate different
cover crops. So we're looking at uh
tritical I think and crimson clover. So
two different cover crops uh uh to
induce uh to provide the source of
carbon to induce anorobic conditions.
So yeah that's about it because yeah
this is a work in progress. So overall
again bunch of different research one
direction to another. Uh but overall I
think uh what I was what is pretty clear
is that uh management how we manage our
soils is is really key to how it how the
soil fertility is affected but weather
environment also has a big role. So
whenever we are trying to model our
systems or amendments uh it is it is
critical that we we take weather into
account
uh there's not one single practice or
system that that that can be adopted for
for for one reason that you can say that
is universally successful or this works.
So yeah there's sometimes it works with
one practice sometime you have to
combine different uh different things to
get uh the desired results. Uh again
each system respond differently based on
practice. Uh similar stuff. Uh the big
challenge I guess uh I talked a lot
about soil amendments. Uh the big
challenge again is uh how do we provide
these uh amendments to the farmers is
always a big challenge. So whether we
talk about biochar or nanop particles to
scale up to actually make it uh
applicable in the large field context is
or remains a challenge. So I think in
this uh we might need more help from the
industry or uh kind of collaborate with
uh different stakeholders. So anyways,
moving forward sort of kind of where I
see myself uh going forward uh in terms
of my my ideas uh based on my experience
uh continue the soil fertility research
trying new amendments different
management practices but also uh sort of
look at the soil health uh together with
soil fertility is going to be important
and also uh I am really interested in
kind of like looking it from a system
point of view and sort of like uh work
towards building a system rather than
only kind of one management practice or
one
amendment. Uh again different ecosystems
different uh different amendments or
different practices respond differently.
In some systems bioar seems to perform
much better compared to even cover crops
while in other systems uh cover crops
per perform a lot better. So uh just to
provide a context as even though biochar
was not like really stand out in some of
my studies but there are some some
studies that have that show that biochar
can increase soil organic carbon much uh
better than even cover crops depending
on the management uh weather again in
the systems.
uh using ecological principles to to
look at soil fertility, soil health uh
but also looking at ways we can prevent
losses, reducing erosion and also
minimizing uh degradation of ecosystems.
And finally I guess uh sort of thinking
soil health uh putting the soil health
concept in in this whole one health
concept uh because we also work with
different diseases a lot of diseases and
I'm going to work with diseases in my
current project. So trying to combine uh
plant disease soil disease everything
into this one health concept. So that is
something I'm thinking more and more uh
these days. So yeah, with that uh we'd
like to take any questions.
Thank you very much for your talk. Um a
lot of interesting data. I was uh c
curious about two things. Actually there
were many but um you you said that the
carbon nanom materials were negatively
charged. Yeah. Did they come so out of
the box? Did you choose them? Because
I'm familiar that a lot of carbon
nanomater materials are not charged at
all and they shouldn't be if they're
just graphine sheets. There's no charge
on them. Or did you did you oxidize them
in some way and you Yeah. Yeah. These
Yeah. Yeah. these were oxidized to have
the caroxil groups. So that that's where
the charge is coming from. And you used
what? Peroxide. Uh oxidiz some kind of
oxidizer. I'll have to check on that.
But yeah, it was oxidized to have that
caroxil group and that's where the
charge is coming from. Yeah. Can I
follow up on yes question? I was excited
to see that the especially the carbon
nanom materials didn't have really a
high pH. You might have been
disappointed but I'm excited because
that excludes sort of pH correction from
the possible effects and you can really
focus on maybe nutrient retention. Yes.
Um but then I saw that your soil pH did
change. So, but they had 5.5. The soil
had five to six. So, why did the pH
change in the soil when you added
something that had basically the same pH
the soil was? What was that all about?
Yeah, that is something that made us c
curious as well and we did this study in
bunch of different ped soils to see if
that's happening. So, yeah, it was
interesting. We were seeing this effect
much more in these in more like like
really acidic soils and in those alpha
soil the increase in PS with these nanop
particles was not as much even though
there was some. So yeah, we couldn't
really kind of like pinpoint where this
uh increase is coming from. Yeah, it was
Thank you. Thank you. I said that to
you. I was like everybody there.
Um just another question on the carbon
nanop particles. Um make it sound like
it's very positive across the board
especially in coarse textured soils. Um
what are kind of the challenges and
limitations of using it? Yeah, I think
because we're seeing uh kind of like a
decline or negative impact in especially
in the soil
microbial aspect at the higher doses. I
think uh whether or not they accumulate
in the soil for longer time uh is going
to be challenged. So if you kind of like
keep applying nano particles for again
and again uh they might accumulate and
uh so I think uh that's why I think
having that life cycle assessment is
important and that's uh it's happening
currently at UCF I believe so I could
see that being uh something that could
be a concern but in terms of like seeing
seeing the effect we could see
throughout our studies.
sort of follow up on that sort of the
comparison of the biochar versus versus
the nanop particles in one of the graphs
that you showed you saw this for you're
looking at EC you showed that the the
the biochar had a dramatic uh effect on
EC lowering it much more than the the
nanoparticles yes and and yet you had
much higher levels when you rinse them
off with mic or however you did that
Yeah. Higher levels. So what was going
on there? I mean were did you have
different CECs? I mean clearly you had a
measurement of what their charge was.
You have a a measurement of their total
charge per volume.
No we didn't measure that total charge
per volume. No. So the CC sort of base
saturation component was not there. So
this could have been effect of just
nutrient efficiency and fert fertilizer
could be fertilizer. Yeah.
Good point though.
Thank you. You told me the carbon
particle increase the corn yield and
that's very useful information for the
corn production systems. So I'm
wondering which parameters either
parameters could be increased for number
of cops or grain corner numbers per cops
or corner weight square. Yeah, I think
uh we did that study but I think overall
we we saw the uh how to say the the
sizes of the of the kernel was the was
the thing that was most increased across
the treatments. I would
say should have that data somewhere so I
can check that.
Kind of a basic topical question but
when you started the presentation you
mentioned about the burning problem uh
and the emissions of like burning all
this rice residue. Uh how does the
production of biochar compare in terms
of emissions? Is it does it lower
emissions and improve air quality of the
ovens that you use or
Yeah. I mean one thing it does like
directly is that if you burn something
in the field you you affect the soil
also soil microbes and it it goes
directly into environment as opposed to
biotar it's much more controlled so it's
a controlled
burning but in terms of like comparing
the exact
numbers I don't have that
basic question the black the source of
That
what what is that in terms of
resourcing? Yeah, it is
basically in in a layman kind of term,
it is something that that remains in the
industrial kilm when you burn uh
something with carbon. So if for example
if you burn a crop residue for example
uh so basically how they're the the
wolves company is the one who is
processing that and they're kind of like
outsourcing those carbon black that is
that gets stuck to those kils and
they're using that to pre uh oxidize it
to to make these particles. So that's
kind of like one way. There are
different ways they're they're doing it,
but this is kind of like the cheapest uh
way to produce things. They're burning
the other material. What are they doing
with the other material that's not stuck
to the kil? Uh that is probably used for
other things that I I don't know this.
Why? Yeah. I mean, yeah, I was trying to
figure out what
the source situation is and how that
applies to get then sounds like the more
minimal amount of material that's being
used for this other process
and quantifying it to go to scale. Yeah,
that's a big challenge. And yeah, we're
doing some like cost analysis also uh to
see if it like stacks up. And that's why
I mentioned the the scrapping of the
kiln thing cuz that was the only thing
that looked kind of like economical in
terms of what we can use as a source
longer term. But yeah, where exactly
they get that uh carbon black particle
from I don't
know but yeah we're working with this
company and they were yeah they were
giving us these particles and they're
trying to scale it.
So good question. I could maybe ask like
from a sustainability perspective. I
think that would be an important Yes.
Know what the other things are going on
that create the resource that they gave
you. Yes.
Can I bring it back to the the
nanoparticle? Yes. The the nutrients
that you were So you're having you have
negative decharge.
So the responses that were associated
with the nitrate versus the ammonium,
what differences did I didn't see it
quick enough that Yeah. What kind of
responses were you seeing that were
different there? Yeah, we it was
interesting, but we were seeing a lot
more nitrate than ammonium. We're
expecting more ammonium to be retained
because of the positive and negative
charge, but we are seeing a lot more
nitrate compared to ammonium.
Is that more like was it associated with
the moisture component of it? Yeah,
that's what we think because of the
humidity and yeah the moisture did you
measure water holding capacity uh with
the amendments versus non amendments?
No, we didn't do that.
No. Yeah, that's yeah, that's one thing
we also noticed. I mean especially with
the biochar treatments that it seemed
like the the structure and and those
components were a lot better with
biochar but we didn't measure those.
Okay, if there are no other questions
let's uh thank Jay and
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu.