this is a production of Cornell
University so um yeah so it's a pretty
broad topic and um we're I'm going to
present a piece of it that we've been
working on and by we I mean there's been
a group of us and it really is a group
effort and that's myself Liz Carter
Susan Ria and Steve Shaw with input from
Peter
Woodburry and um I should say that there
several groups around the world that are
that are really doing great work in in
this area we had a seminar a couple
weeks ago from a person from Australia
Scott Chapman who uh is with csro and
he's U associated with a group at
University of queens and that is really
doing great work on um on uh uh trying
to um uh help uh agricultural producers
in Australia deal with impacts of
climate and that's important there
and uh
so so why maze why climate impacts and
how do we get involved so the kind of
global answer to the first question is
ma is a big crop it's the leading Cal
crop in the world demand supposed to
increase by 50% over the next 50 or or
75 years and over that time temperatures
are supposed to be increasing by at
least two or three degrees C potentially
so that's kind of the overarching reason
uh and why climate impacts because we're
expecting these increases in in
temperature and and we don't potentially
changes in
precipitation there's been a number of
papers over the past 10 years primarily
from folks who are not uh their primary
U area is not
agriculture where they have done yield
projections using statistical modeling
and they've really they've suggested
pretty severe impacts of increasing
temperatures on May's productivity both
historically but also in particular into
the
future several years ago Susan and Steve
kind of looked into this and and had
some questions about the methodologies
and results and that led to a paper
where they did some initial work on
looking at irrigated maze production to
see whether they could detect a
temperature impact on on irrigated Maze
and they were unable to in the in the
they looked at but that led to a hatch
proposal that that was funded and
allowed us to look
more in you know intensively at at the
impact of climate on maze with
particular emphasis on temperature but
it it kind of evolved into additional in
additional
impacts so I'm just going to try to go
through some of the kind of climate
impacts on maze uh maze yields so so the
the cap on yields is solar radiation so
I don't have that here but that any
given location for any given soils is
going to be solar radiation but the next
most important impact despite all the
emphasis on temperature actually is
precipitation I think every most
agronomist and crop physiologists would
agree that that's the main limitation
climate limitation on on maze production
so I got this quote from Tom Sinclair
the thousand pound gorilla and crop
response to climate change he's
referring to precipitation
that's partly because maybe to emphasize
that you know it's it's precipitation
more than the the more recent emphasis
on temperature but also the fact that we
don't projections of precipitation are
really uncertain so we really don't know
what's going to happen that's going to
have a Major Impact but there are direct
temperature impacts on Maze and probably
the most well documented is on phology
that means higher temperatures
accelerated rate develop M reduced
cumulative um intercepted radiation in
lower yields and that's been that's been
pretty well documented there also are
physiological
impacts um reduced pollen viability uh
loss of membrane
Integrity uh inactivation of of some
heat sensitive enzymes particularly in
photosynthesis and in um starch
synthesis um and uh increased
respiration
but those you know at the temperature
it's 38 to 40° C um and keep that in
mind because we'll be getting coming
back to that in a bit there are what
have been proposed these indirect
temperature impacts and primarily that's
that there's going to be an increase in
evaporative demand it's going to cause
more frequent um bouts of water stress
in Maze and reduce yields I'm going to
actually spend a fair amount of time on
that and I'll I'll get like I'll get
back to that in a bit there are
complications and that's these
interactions for climate the intera the
problem is is
that high temperature drought higher
high evaporative demand are all highly
correlated they often they at least in
the US Corn Belt they they occur all at
the same time so it becomes very
difficult then to isolate which are the
factors that are most responsible for
impacts on yield and that's something
that um Liz has been wrestling with
quite a bit recently the second thing
and I'm not going to really talk about
this but it's I I think pretty important
is there's not really clear information
on when maze is underw
stress how will higher
temperatures impact yield in other words
is what kind of interaction is there
when the crop is already in stress from
one say say drought how how will then
elevated temperatures imp have an what
additional impact will they have and
that's it's something that there's not a
lot of literature on and the literature
that's there is not real clear on that
but it's important because it'll it'll
it'll give information on what are the
impacts on the thresholds for damage
from say temperature or or water
stress so just to kind of do a very
simple very brief kind of overview of my
sense of the literature on the more
recent literature that I mentioned on
statistical modeling is there was first
an early focus on temperature and this
was to the to in precipitation or or
drought was considered secondary in this
in these studies and they reported
pretty significant impacts both
historically and in in projected into
the future as I mentioned but not the
thresholds that they were using to where
they expected damage to occur reduced
heals was around 30° C that's in
contrast to the to what we saw before
for the physiological
damage more recently they I think as
they become became associated with more
um agriculturally oriented people let's
say uh they shifted their emphasis to
that the impact of higher temperatures
climate change was going to be by
increasing evapor demand as I mentioned
before and this this is something where
again they're project ing pretty
significant impacts and this is I'm
going to try to get to this and explain
it a little bit better and I hope I'll
be able to do that uh because we have
some serious we have some questions
about
that also in these more recent kind of
statistical studies they've understood
that there's acclamation that occurs in
maze to high temperatures that could
modify or mitigate the impact of
temperature there's also one has to
account for genetics management soil
factors and that there are impacts by
grow stage these genetic management soil
factors are really important because
they not only impact yield independently
of climate but they interact with
climate to to um uh to um affect maze
yields and another quote from Sinclair
which I thought was quite good is right
here temperature increase imposed on
current crop systems without management
or genetic changes is often predicted to
decrease yields but is highly likely
that cropping systems will remain static
and I think I'll be able to show
some it's often predicted but it's
highly
well he was saying that there they'll
remain static the deals won't be
affected the the temperature they're
projecting decreases actually it's a
good I'm glad you brought that up Peter
because actually we can I think we can
show at least in some of our data that
management can actually increase yields
even with increases in
temperature so these are I'm just going
to go through a series of
questions uh and um to try to address
this and uh the climate impacts and and
this one on the
vpds I just wanted to say right now
there's two aspects to this impact of of
VPD on on on on yields or uh increase of
Apper demand one is whether there
actually will be an increase into the
future in the US corn Bel and the second
is how if there is what is the
interaction between BPD and the
processes of interest that would be EV
APPA transpiration and carbon
assimilation and Maze so I'm going to
try to get to that and hopefully it will
be a little clear um so this first
question we address by
um uh using statistical modeling uh of
both irrigated and rainfed Maze uh
yields and I'll get to that in just a
second that's work that Liz has been uh
primarily involved with and in fact gave
a seminar last uh spring on the
irrigated component of that um so the
advantage we had here is we had access
to a a data set from the National Corn
Growers Association uh uh for both
irrigated and rainfed uh uh categories
or
classes um this was from 2005 to
2012 it was focused mainly in the
western corn Bel but in the rainfed we
included Iowa also we have other
additional States we haven't started the
analyses on those this is under um so
the advantage is it's optimal management
so the limitations on yield are going to
be due to whatever the local factors
like soils might
but other than that it's going to be a
climate impact and that's what we were
really trying to um get at was what is
the impact of climate there were a large
number of of values uh yield data that
we had and then we had the real nice
thing is we had all this additional
information so this is both management
and genetics information that was really
quite useful and and trying to explain U
the impacts on on um maze yields both in
the irrigated and in the rainfed uh data
sets and those were used to define
growth stages that were used um that
were used to um both look at seasonal
impacts but also impacts by grow stage
again Liz
gave gave a seminar on the irrigated
part of this um work and the the main
findings there is that there was
evidence for
acclamation there was no impacts of
temperature with even in 2012 when we
had near record or record temperatures
across the the US corn Bel um there was
uh also evidence that by agronomically
realistic adjustments of management you
could actually increase yields so there
was room for for actually improved
yields in the irrigated uh uh maze in uh
in in the cornbelt so so I'm not going
to so that's all I'm going to talk about
for the irrigated again because that was
been presented and actually that uh uh
work has been submitted and for public
for Publications under review right
now so this uh is um kind of a summary
of the precipitation and grain yals over
time for for the rainfed and and just
for uh to contrast I have the irrigated
here so the main
main thing to note with the
precipitation is you know pretty steady
but 2012 was a very very low precept
year um by mid June or so prip shut down
and there was very little after that
particularly in in uh in the western
corn
Bel um this was associated with very
high temperatures and very high uh vpds
I'll I'll explain a bit more about that
no impact on irrigated yields like I
just mentioned in fact 2012 was the
highest yield uh uh highest yielding
year um uh uh of the period that we
looked at and this period included I
should I didn't show the temperature
data but this period included quite a
broad range of temperatures so both
higher and
lower the rainfed yields are here so
you'll know I think anybody who's aware
kind of somewhat aware of of grain
yields will note that they're pretty
high
so you get it's important to keep in
mind this is a yield contest so these
Growers are selecting their best sites
so even
where there may be it's you know a
precipitation it may be getting to the
edge of the of the of the kind of
rainfed production agriculture they're
still selecting very very their their
best sites
so uh there's going to it's going to
maybe shift the yields a little bit
higher than what they would be normally
but in 2012 there was a reduction and
this reduction the percentage reduction
in yields in these yield contest data is
pretty much the same as what the overall
reduction in yields were in the midwest
in 2012 that's reported in the National
agricultural statistics so even though
the the absolute values are higher the
magnitude of reduction 2012 was was
about the same and I'm going to focus on
2012 because of the uh the climate
extremes that that occurred in that
year so this is kind of some summary
data and most of what I'm going to show
is descriptive because we're still in
the
preliminary part of um of this these
analyses the top panel is grain yield as
a function of vapor pressure deficit
this is for rainfed for Kansas Missouri
and
Nebraska so you note that there is does
appear to be a Rel relationship where
whereby at higher vpds you do get lower
yields important to keep in mind though
that the there's a there's correlations
among the climate variables here and
we'll get to that so you so it's not a
maybe so much of a surprise that the
statistical modeling that's been done
might show that BPD is a factor in
impacting ma Fields but I think what
we'll try to show is that it's much more
complicated than that we look at Iowa
Iowa is interesting the rainfed data
same thing grainfield as a function of
vapor pressure deficit there was really
no no impact partly because the climate
was not as severely impacted in 2012 as
it was in in uh in the western corn Bel
so we never got the really high bpds low
pre as low prip and as high
temperatures this is the irrigated as a
as a comparison
um shows that when you eliminate water
stress there's no impact of vapor
pressure deficit or high temperature on
yields so getting to this correlation
that I've been mentioning so this is
this is the kind of uh combined data
from for all the the yield data for the
rainfed from 2005 to 2012 showing the
season average
TX as a function of season average vapor
pressure deficit and you Can See Clearly
there's a relationship the higher the
temperature the higher the vapor
pressure deficit there's a color code
here for precept for June July and
August total precept you'll note
that the higher precepts are in at the
lower vpds lower temperatures as you get
to these higher
values uh you that's where the lower
precipitation uh is occurring so again
important to keep you know this this is
important to note so it makes it more
difficult to identify these drivers this
is another way of looking at where we
plotted grain yield as a function of
growing season
precipitation where we color coded for
vapor pressure deficit here so darker
colors are higher vapor pressure
deficits so you note up until about down
to about 300 millimeters of of June July
August
precept yields are scattered but they're
not but they're all fairly high but
about 300 and lower you get quite a
range of yields and you start getting
some very low yields these are in
particular where the very highest vapor
pressure deficits are are were
recorded this was interesting these were
interesting data because of the large
range and I'll try to explain why you
might at least what we is one factor
that might be responsible for why you're
getting very high yields but also very
low yields here but again just pointing
out this correlation among these climate
factors that are important in in
determining May's
productivity
so I didn't I was going to present some
data initial data on the statistical
modeling that Liz has done but I decided
not to because I felt like it uh I I I
wasn't confident enough of my knowledge
of that modeling to do that but I did
want to present one thing one first to
note that in the modeling that she's
done so far all the climate factors were
significant so
BPD
precipitation temperature and the
temperature thresholds that we looked at
the indices that we looked at all came
out to be having significant impact on
on maze
yields the biggest impact though
interestingly enough was planting
rate and uh my interpretation of that is
that
um what what it appeared to be is is
that in the yield contests The Growers
were were actually too conservative in
their planting rate what we found when
we looked at the rainfed data for the
four states we looked at is
that and under all scenarios under all
vapor pressure deficits you did better
by increasing your planting rate so you
got higher yields no matter whether it
was uh no matter what epd
I think again this comes back to the
fact that these these Con in these
contests they're um picking their best
sites so these sites are going to have a
maximum water holding Capac soil water
holding capacity and I think they for
2012 uh in that year they were just able
to they had enough stored soil water to
to produce a a pretty good yield That's
my kind of interpretation but we're
still analyzing these data but again
note that even
uh at very high planting
rates uh you know that's where you got
your maximum yield at all vapor pressure
deficits I should say that you know
we're focused on rainfed maze here and
and humid production humid region
production this is not dry land
production dry land production the
recommendations for planting rate are
much lower than um uh than uh what um uh
we're showing here in part that's to for
uh I think to for for the because
Growers tend to be risk averse but also
the the uh the the seed companies are
predicting or not predicting but um
prescribing lower planting rates in part
because they don't want to have the onus
of having a total crop failure but
that's not what we're talking about
we're talking about rainfed humid region
production here
so a couple of the problems that that
that Liz she's settling on an
appropriate methodology for variable
selection and coefficient estimation and
modeling statistical modeling the
problem that she's had is a correlation
that I just mentioned among the climate
variables but also that there's a
spatial correlation between management
and climate variables and that's uh Liz
is I think getting to a point where
we're close
rightz it's been long process but she's
done an excellent job on
it
um so I'll move on to the second
question which is this gets back to the
vpds is there evidence to support this
Assumption of higher vpds in the Corn
Belt under climate
change now this is really out of my out
of my Waters here but this is what I'm
I'm understanding is is
occurring the precipitation most most of
the precipitation for the US corn belt
comes from systems coming out of the
Gulf of Mexico they come up the
Mississippi Valley and they they and
produce
rainfall when that doesn't there are
occasions though where you get these
episodic droughts this occurs when a
high pressure system embeds in the
midwest it blocks the transporter
precipitation of these systems up from
the Gulf of Mexico and and this has
occurred in
1983 1988 and then as I've been talking
quite a bit about in
2012 the sequence of events is important
here because what it what as far as I
understand from the
literature the main instigator is reduce
precipitation so there's less
rainfall this reduces Regional evapo
transpiration that means that more of
the incoming slower ations getting part
partitioned to sensible heat which
atmospheric heating let's say higher
temperatures and these higher
temperatures lead to the higher vapor
pressure deficits so the the real
instigator is not that there are going
to be higher vapor pressure
deficits as a blanket you know as a
blanket statement for all future
climates it's only going to be during
these episodic droughts and the
instigator is going to be reduced
precipitation
it is unclear whether these episodic
droughts events where you have these
high pressure systems embedding in the
in the region whether it'll be more or
less likely to occur with climate change
I did think it was interesting that um
one of the candidates for the geospatial
position Nathan
Mueller from in his work uh the
prediction was that this they will not
be more frequent that in fact it's
there's likely to be higher
precipitations
precipitation total precipitation during
the growing season in the in the midwest
but that there's still on some
uncertainty about that so with respect
to whether there'll be higher vpds I
think based on this I would say it's not
if they're are if they are higher
they're not going to be significantly
higher and the only time you'll get them
is during these episodic
droughts so then they'll move on to the
kind of uh the third question is
can we what can we say about the impact
of climate on key processes in Maze and
for this I'm going to um move more to uh
um uh to a little more in depth on the
impact on on on the crop and in
particular focus on the dial dynamics of
of evapo transpiration in particular uh
not so much on carbon assimilation
although we did that but look at dial
Dynamics at the field
level um of those processes in relation
to
temperature and vapor pressure deficits
or evaporative
demand so the way I'm going to do that
is by by talking about work that we've
done using flux Tower data and AD
covariant methodology to look at fluxes
of so latent heat flux or VAP
transpiration and sensible heat fluxes
in other words
heating
um and then in in with additional data
look at some some other things including
changes in canopy
temperature changes in aerodynamic
conductance I won't talk about that but
that's one of the key factors that is is
um is um involved but then in particular
focus on canopy
conductance um and as a function of
these climate variables dially and at
the field level we mainly focused on uh
aerlex Towers in me
Nebraska and we looked at the irrigated
maze towers and I'll explain a little
bit why we did
that we also had a Tower in Aurora
ourselves in Aurora last year which
actually produce quite good data I won't
be getting to those data uh I just don't
have time so we focus mostly on the me
data so uh this is hopefully going to
help set up a little bit of what I'm
what I'm going to talk
about when we're talking about um these
fluxes latent heat and sensible heat
fluxes the amount of energy coming into
a a
field to the to the surface of the
canopy is the the described here is
incoming solar minus reflected uh R
solar
radiation plus the difference between
long wave in Long wave out we're we're
calling that the net radiation so that's
total energy coming into the top of the
canopy that energy has to be dissipated
somehow in order to balance the equation
it can either be lost as a vapo
transpiration or it can be lost as
sensible heat sensible heat just means
you have an object at a higher
temperature
and a lower temperature and it's the
energy transfer from the higher
temperature to the lower temperature
when we're talking about a crop this
almost always during sunlight hours
means the temperature of the canopy is
higher and we're transferring energy
from that canopy to a lower temperature
atmosphere um
so the way you can think of how the crop
impacts this so there so so there are
two Factor fa s that that affect how
this energy partition between vapid
transpiration and sensible heat loss one
is
VPD so that will affect it higher vpds
will shift it more towards evapo
transpiration less towards sensible heat
loss but the plant has control over that
through crop
conductance so it so at higher crop
conductances you have the same effect a
shift towards more uh VAP transpiration
under any given set of conditions
at lower crop cond conductances in other
words like underwater stress you shift
the um energy uh is shifted more towards
sensible heat loss in other words the
canopy heats
up so I hope that that helps a little
bit when I talk in the next few slides
but another thing to note is that
globally about 80% of the net radiation
is dissipated through through evapor
transporation so that when we're talking
about increases in temperature increases
in evaporative demand the there's a
limit set by the amount of incoming
energy as to how much can be shifted how
much more evapo transpiration can occur
if you look at this example if we're if
at we're averaging around 6 millim per
day of a vapo
transpiration where 80% and that
represents 80% of the total net
radiation the most you can get
most increase in that that you can get
is about 2 7.5 millimeters per day so
there's a real limit so you it's not
like um uh you know you can you just are
Capp by the incoming energy so that's an
important thing to keep in
mind so here's some kind of uh just a
look at some of the D dial Dynamics in
kind of broad terms these are data from
from one of the ameriflux towers at me
just showing a typical kind of dial
sequence of of um of changes the this
kind of orangish bar is the incoming net
radiation the green is the evaporate
transpiration or latent
heat and the red is sensible heat this
is for a well-watered canopy so you can
see that most of the incoming net
radiation is account accounted for in in
by a vapo transpiration and very little
by sensible heat uh uh
transfer one thing to note is that the
blue dash line is a is vapor pressure
deficit so the key thing to note is that
the highest vapor pressure deficits are
actually occurring later in the day when
net radiation's low of APPA
transpiration low that will come back to
that in a
bit so this what this is a kind of a
typical water stress canopy then same
incoming net
radiation but because we're beginning to
get stod closure or reduction crop
conductance the shift and partitioning
of that energy is now more to tensible
heat and less to latent heat or less to
evaporative evapor transpiration so
what's the what's the impact the impact
is that we look at air temperature
versus canopy temperature for that water
stress example we're now getting canopy
temperatures that are sign ific above
air temperature and we'll we'll I'll
explain more about that a
bit so this is these are data from uh
the
me tower towers for irrigated maze for
2010 11 and 12 so you might wonder why
we're using irrigated data here when
we're I'm talking about rain in part on
about rainfed bze it it just so happened
fortuitously for us but maybe not for
them so much that in 2012 they basically
weren't able to keep up with the
irrigation so they actually had
essentially a deficit irrigation they
were getting water stress in their crop
and so that actually turned out nicely
because uh we were not able to get uh
rainfed data from those Towers in 2012
they didn't they were in a a soybean
maze rotation and um that year they
happened to be in soybean for the for
the rainfed
towers so the first thing to note is you
know what we what we see here is vapor
pressure deficits over the course of the
day this is for the for the growing
season this is from canopy closure to
the beginning of sence so it's time when
there's a full canopy but no syence
these are the compiled data over that
time um for the different hours here so
the vapor pressure deficits remain
fairly low during the the two years
where there was good irrigation there
were not and they were not drought years
during 2012 like we've been talking
about the vapor def vapor pressure
deficits increased
considerably and
um and again that have we we saw that
earlier in some of the uh data that we
showed from um for the yield contest
so this is interesting because this
shows latent
heat evapor Transportation as a fra as a
fraction net
radiation over time for these for the
same three years so keep in mind net
radiation is appr approximately equal to
latent heat plus sensible heat or vapor
transp Transportation plus sensible heat
so you can see through most of the day
we're at about 08 so that's about well
as I was pointing out
for globally about 80% of the of net
radiation is accounted for by by a vapo
transpiration and that's pretty and
we're so this is pretty consistent with
us and that occurred in all three years
but note later in the day this is when
the vpds are increasing we do see an
increase in all three years in the
fraction of net radiation that's
accounted for Via vapa
transporation and it goes up again in
all three years what was interesting is
that is
2012 so in 2012 it actually went above
the ratio went above one so how can that
be well that happens because the canopy
is actually being cooled to the point
where there's now the sensible heat flux
is reversed you're actually getting Tre
heat transfer energy transfer from the
atmosphere to the
canopy the question is from a kind of a
production standpoint
with respect to these drought periods is
is is this a good
thing we're we're losing water here and
it's and it's occurring at a time when
net radiation is going
down uh there's not that much
photosynthesis crop photosynthesis is
actually declin pretty pretty pretty
steeply
then what if we were able to stop this
could we conserve water in these drought
years and potentially you know get a
higher yield under those conditions
and I'll come back to that but that's
something to
consider what was all so this is shows
the crop conductance and it shows that
so this is a typical pattern that we see
for
well-watered um uh crop conductance over
over the period of the
day so 201110 2011 2012 was lower by the
time crop canopy closure occurred in
this s in these uh in these fields there
are the drought was already in place
they were not keeping up with the
irrigation so we are already seeing
evidence of that by lower crop
conductances in
2012 so even though conductance is going
down you'd think would be would then um
reduce evap transpiration the very high
vpds that we saw earlier
here were were high enough to counteract
that and create you know actually result
in this where we were getting evap
transpiration at such a high rate that
we were actually getting canopy
cooling so and this this this shows what
the kind of net result of that is is
that instead of showing that instead of
that canopy being much higher than air
temperature than the temperatures that
we see in the irrigat years it actually
was being maintained pretty close to
those and really not in in a Range where
we'd expect any temperature
impact is so is this a good thing you
might argue that it's better to keep
temperatures it's better to lose a
little bit of water and keep those
temperatures canopy temperatures a
little cooler if your main concern is
temperature if your main concern is
water you might go the other way and say
well let's have some more stomato
closure and and we'll sacrifice a little
higher temperatures but we'll save some
water so this shows was just kind of
kind of a summary graph where we're
looking at a vapid
transpiration in millimeters per hour as
a function of vapor pressure deficit
color codes the same we have blue for
2010 Green for 2011 and red for
2012 so the thing to note here and this
gets back to how much total vapid
transporation can occur when you're
tapped by the amount of limited by the
amount of energy coming in you can see
that at about two kPa vapor pressure
deficit basically you you can't
transpire any more water that's kind of
it
um you can see the impact of lower
conductance in 2012 in that at any given
VPD we're getting higher vapid ET rates
in 2010 and
2011 but you'll see at the higher
highest vpds we are that those are
occurring in 2012 and we're seeing those
out here there's quite a scatter of
points here and I'll show this in a bit
but this is
because net radiation is going down at
the time the highest vpds are occurring
and so you're actually getting uh even
though you're at a maximum or above Max
you know the vapid transformation as a
fraction net radiation is actually above
one the total amount of water loss is
actually not that
high so now I'll get to the last
question which is this issue
of what what do you want to do in terms
of trying to to improve crops improve
maze hybrids for uh these episodic
droughts and what Pioneer has has opted
to do in their breeding is to come out
with so-called drought tolerant
varities and those drought tolerant
varieties one of the it's clear that one
of of the traits that has been
introduced is
the that they have made them sensitive
to vapor pressure deficit so above a
certain vapor pressure deficit the
stamata begin to
close and the idea is you're conserving
water uh during those drought years so
that you uh have enough water to get a
decent yield at the end of the growing
season and these are so I'm calling
these kind of reduced transpiration
hybrids
so they've opted for the water
conservation and not for any impact that
there might be on as a result of that on
temperature so this shows some some
modeling uh results to that were uh from
a paper and journal of experimental
bodney uh by P the Pioneer folks
primarily to try to demonstrate what the
value of this trait might be they have
their drought tolerant and drought
sensitive is the dash looking at changes
in soil moisture over the growing season
and you'll see that early on with this
trait of reduced transpiration trait
there was less water extracted from the
profile and more water towards the end
of the growing season in the drought
tolerant Co D drought tolerant variety
when they looked at total biomass and
yield with this in this modeling
exercise you'll see that up to a certain
point they were both the same but then
late in the season because the more
available water deeper in the Pro in the
soil profile with a drought on that Vari
was able to use that water and produce
more yield and more total
biomass so what we did just to kind of
take a quick look at this was we did a
modeling exercise where we looked at
York Kansas in
2012 a very again very hot very dry uh
um
period and we looked at two scenarios
one was where we had crop conductance
independent of vapor pressure deficit
and one where we allowed it to be
dependent on vapor pressure deficit
Based on data from a paper that was used
as one of the kind of um U kind of
foundations for this introducing this
trade into these drought toer varieties
or or trans
sensitive reduced transpiration
varieties so the first thing is the
total amount of ET that
occurred with when it was independent
was 2117 millimet over this month versus
182 millimeters when you have made this
crop conductors dependent on BPD so it
does save water at least based on our
our uh our work here if you you look at
vapid transpiration hourly as a function
of vapor pressure deficit these kind we
saw this just just in a few slides
previously showing kind of a cap around
kPa what's interesting is the blue are
pro before 3 p.m. the red are 1 to 3
p.m. and the green are after 3 p.m. so
this just illustrates that even though
the vpds were very high uh later the
total amount of water loss was not as
high as earlier because the net
radiation was
lower so this is for the indep where
crop conductance is independent vapor
pressure deficit where it's dependent we
actually cap this at a lower um ET rate
So at around 7 millimeters uh 7 millimet
per
hour so we get the we get the savings of
water and that's a that's a good thing
if if you're in an you're in a drought
situation and you want to um uh have uh
you're willing to sacrifice maybe a
little bit yield uh in the really good
years but you're going to get more yield
in the drier drier
years the problem is here is is
temperature so in this scenario we had
air
temperature we looked at canopy
temperature with no VPD dependence and
canopy canopy temperature where there
was a dependence of CR conductance on
BPD got a little screwed up here but the
the air temperature over that period the
maximum air temperature was around 37
C no VPD dependence the canopy
temperature was around 38 degre C when
you hadn't made a VP dependent you were
saving water the result was that you
increase your canopy temperature so the
question is what do you want you if you
you have this trade you'll save water
but you're going to get higher canopy
canopy temperatures you're going to
start getting canopy temperatures
presumably into the into the yes
well
I the what they did when they they they
they they looked at a large range of
genotypes and this this initial work
that was done on this and they just did
it was growth chamber work and looked at
imposing different paper pressure
deficits and at what point did they
begin to get a shift in in transpiration
indicating a a sensitivity of stamata to
vapor pressure deficit a lot of
genotypes didn't show that response but
there were some that did so that kind of
apparently was the foundation for moving
to to uh to trying to um include this
trade into the into the
hybrids
um so again again you know you you can
save water but you but you potentially
are pushing canopy temperatures pretty
high paper just recently came out in
crop science where this they you know
there was some recognition of the
problem with this and so what they've
tried to identify and they think they
have identified are hybrids that are
sensitive to VPD so they shut down or
they reduce transpiration at higher vpds
but at a certain temperature they lose
that and they to open up and so they
been to cool at around and this seems to
be around 38°
c i i i mean that that needs to be
looked into because what I tried to
point out is these high vpds CO coincide
with droughts so the stamat are already
responding to a crop W to a soil
moisture stress I don't know how much
more uh this trait you know this this
this you how this might interact with
what we know is already going on but
that's that was interesting that there
began to be recognition that this could
be a potentially serious issue
here so that's just a very brief and
very uh kind of cursory overview of what
we're
doing and we hope to be able to continue
this work particularly uh extend the
statistical modeling uh to include other
regions and also do more work on our
Edie covariant and crop growth growth
modeling uh looking more into these
interactions between the climate and the
crop I want to acknowledge the the group
I mentioned before and these other folks
uh for all the work all the U input that
they provided for us um in particular uh
Andy schwier at me for the marlux data
Paul Sakowski and staff at Musgrave for
the flux Tower uh couple of folks at
Pioneer for information on their
cultivars and Tim for some helpful
discussions and that's our fux Tower
from last year and
Aurora so
thanks thanks je um just a quick
question on the drer variety
yields
back like
[Music]
sorry toward the end
are theyed to withraw
[Music]
well I believe they
don't I think again we are looking at
the best the
best know that's a good
point as far as I know they're not not
oated
we did find quite low yields in the rain
so it's not
like we don't
get explain this but my
understanding sign is not much of a CR
person was that the key he determining
Factor around and corn is basically
around tling so and so when I look at
that top graph if you are the Dr
cut basically by shutting Stone doesn't
it sort of increase and the effects of
the Dr I'm surprised that you that you
don't that you get higher yelds when you
the stress during thetical
time well so so do you increase the
stress dur critical
time I think the the reading is such
that um and I didn't show this graph but
reading is such that the varities that
show this are still are still performing
well under both well watered and and um
and
conditions if you if you the response
was so
great that you were shutting down for a
sens and
you I don't think we're talking about a
big a big difference we're not talking
about because these this is occurring in
dpds that are above about
2k so it's not like um it's it's it's
you know we're talking order 30 mm in
water so it's not
imposing I don't know if I'm answering
this but it's not I don't think it's a
significant stress and not during during
that
critical um if they you know if it was a
very significant loss it was
very strong ruction
I mean in the in that show some cond
in2 at every hour of the day was lower
so remember
that so it could be
that by allowing the to regulate that
then it would you know just have normal
conductiv
shedal throughout the times of the
day yeah well I mean that was water strs
was causing that so that I didn't show
this but what interesting about that
that if you look at the the carbon
exchange it actually wasn't all that
much impact they were pretty simar on
all three years and in facts that they
got in all those were not that much
different we were pretty close so even
though it showed this response in 2012
that they clearly not keeping up and we
Hader back to the slide that shows the
uh effective deficit at different
planing
densities I me to say that that
it was counterintuitive to me and I
wonder if you
can so in other words it shows that at
low planting density the yield suffers
more as as V goes up than high
planting I know it doesn't it
doesn't but I
think I think what we're looking at is
the quality of the SS so I think these
sites there's not we're not seeing as
you notice the yields were quite High R
familiar
withs you know 14 or 15s that's pretty
so I think we're talking about really
good size it's important to important to
keep that in mind
about so actually they were were these
rat were too low they were losing yield
by because they were not getting enough
out were the optimum density for that
for those
conditions so they could put more plants
in there they were they were below the
optimum for p were getting the
maximum wouldn't think that would be the
case it was I mean at any given
BPD yields go down at any given planting
go down you
increase well not much at 100,000
so so so the plants at 100,000 they're
maintaining the per plant yield even as
BPD doubles seems
amazing that's that's again my
interpretation of that is that is there
yield contest okay okay so that's that's
what
I'm some of this correlation or
relationship is driven by
non-independence between planting
density and the and and the location
yeah people with really good soils they
plant high density and yeah but
also the the lower densities were more
in the western part of the
Corn where were
H could you also say that at low
planting
densities the at low planting densities
if the plants are not under VPD stress
they can kind of
compensate but if they are under VPD
stress they they can't compensate for
the low density does that make
sense actually actually we're looking
the whole idea issue of lower
planting how much water you actually
save that's something that
[Applause]
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu