this is a production of Cornell
University I'm going to talk about what
I did on my summer vacation actually so
this is actually I mean this in a sense
that um in just a few months I'll be
fully retired and at that point I'll be
asking for the faculty to grant me a
Meritus status so I have to prove that
I'm still actually doing something
useful and that's what this is all about
today so I'm going to talk about major
question which is how novelty arises
it's a probably the fundamental question
in evolutionary biology and I'm going to
talk about it in several ways one is
about species and how they arise and
evolve secondly how structures uh evolve
how they originate and thirdly at the
cell level how does cell types evolve so
all three of those so I'll tell three
short stories essentially the first is
about speciation and its consequences
turn that one off okay and uh in
particular couple of short stories about
soybean relatives which I worked on for
years and also rice and then uh after
that the evolution of nodulation
symbiosis and finally talking about Gene
duplications and the EV evolution of
cell type
diversity what these things have in
common other than novelty is poly and
suang mentioned that my research has
been about poly whole genome duplication
for many many years
now so polyploidy I think is everybody
knows here is everything above the level
of two sets of chromosomes in a
Cell It's a phenomenon that is very
common in nature at the at the
organismal level endopolyploid is a
common phenomenon as it mentions here in
this review paper indispensable for
normal development and organ formation
across various organisms from fungi to
humans and plants of course as well
Adrien rotors work on giant cells in
seil of arabidopsis for example so
there's muscle cell two nuclei and then
also it's a very common phenomenon in
cancer cancer is a says here is an ugly
consequence of Endor replication and
polyploidization but I'm not going to be
talking about Endo polyploidy today I'll
be talking about whole organism
polyploidy where whole organisms are
duplicated duplicate their genomes and
polyol occurs throughout the entire tree
of life U all of us in this room are
multiply polyploid along with all other
vertebrates based on a very long time
time ago polyploidization event all the
way back here in the Cambrian
explosion other commonly uh common lab
organisms such as yeast are
polyploid and uh if you like salmon for
example and trout you're eating
tetraploids recent
tetrols but plants really do polyploid
in a big way and this is uh from the
1,000 plant transcripts thousand
different transcripts of different
species among on which there were 244
whole genome duplication events
identified some shared many of them
shared but also unique ones at the tips
of these branches of the trees and if
you look over here on the side at the uh
distribution of the number of poly
events whole genome duplication events
and the ancestry of all of these
different TXS so what you'll see is that
many of the common angiosperms so the
rosids and the asterids for example so
legumes asers all of those things have
an average about four whole genome
duplication events in their evolutionary
histories that you see in the
genome so my friend Jonathan Wendell
published a very nice paper on this some
years back and he calls it the wondrous
cycles of polyan plants it's for us
enthusiasts about poly we think of it as
a wonderful sort of thing but what we
see is this cycle here all a whole bunch
of different poly events across the tree
of life and we have all sorts of events
that happen and concominant to that and
finally this whole cycle of duplication
and uh Gene loss balanc biased
fractionation or Gene loss of different
G sub genomes genome downsizing so loss
of repeated sequence for example
rearrangements and then you've produced
a functionally diploid plant through
this process involves many different
individual processes that are called
lumped together as
diploidization so this diploidization
cycle Follow by another round of polyl
gives us the complex genomes that we see
in flowering plants today
so the first of my vignettes is about
speciation I'm not going to talk much
about this this is um an area where a
lot of my research has been over the
years um but I'm just going to mention a
couple of things excuse me that we've
been doing lately um so long-term
project actually look at the uh
evolution of the soybean relatives that
you see down here perennial soybeans
native to Australia Jacob Landis has led
much of this work in recent years and so
collaboration with Ching Lee Leu at
senta and and Andrew Farmer at National
Center for genome resources in Santa Fe
this paper um I think Jacob just
submitted it what a week and a half ago
something like that so this was one of
the main things we worked on during the
summer was uh understanding this Legacy
of poly ploying ingression and looking
at it across 2300 different nuclear
genes from from genome resequencing done
by
senta um a second project that was
working on quite a bit this summer was
mainly led by Janu
here um jenu and her Mentor S at the
Botanical Institute in in
Beijing uh have been working on rice
alop polyploids for many years and this
particular uh project was a Genome
Project in which looking at this race
that you see here this Ariz of minuta 48
chromosomes derived from these two
diploid species here formed around
700,000 years ago traced the genomes
using philogenetic methods and
everything and here you'll see the
circus diagram showing the sub genomes
of the polyploid and they're virtually
identical in terms of synony and their
organization with the genomes of the
diploid however when you dig a little
bit deeper you'll find that the
diploidization process has started in
this paper is about how uh different EP
different parts of that diploidization
are either episodic some of them
occurring right away after polyploid
formation and others are more gradual
for example the acquisition of
transposable elements has been a gradual
process as opposed to Gene loss which
has been much more episodic so this is a
a project that I'm not going to say much
more about just to let you know we're
working on
that so one of the questions is why is
polyol so common across plants
particularly and the idea is that polyol
is a generator of novelty U both at
pretty much every possible level this
classic paper by Don Levan someone Bill
knows very well yeah smiling here in the
front uh is real classic in terms of all
the ways that polyol can create
evolutionary novelty uh on paper by Mike
freeling a little bit later Gene balance
duplications are a drive to increase
morphological complexity so this has
been a a recurring theme in the poly
Ploy literature all
along uh Jeremy Cod who was a student
here many years ago has been one of my
top collaborators for years now uh and I
wrote this paper on auto a little essay
really on EP autopolyploidy is an
epigenetic macrom mutation so a macrom
mutation is a single event poly in this
case with many different phenotypic
consequences so it qualifies there and
epigenetics are molecules and mechanisms
that can perpetuate alternative gene
activity states in the context of the
same DNA sequence so this is one of many
definitions of epigenetics it's one that
suits my purposes so I grabbed it
basically if you make a synthetic polyl
just double the chomosome number using
culine you have a plant that's isogenic
with its diploid progenitor so it has
the same DNA sequences so but it also
has many phenotypic consequences when
you do that that's the maum mutation and
the same DNA sequence is the epigenetic
part so an autopolyploid is an
epigenetic macrom mutation and that's
the source of all of that novelty from
The genome doubling part uh I did I
mentioned also Alo polyploids the rice
for example and Alo polyploids add
another component which is hybridity
heterosis those kinds of effects as well
but pure polyploid as you might call has
it has been called autopolyploidy is a
matter of just doubling the same genome
and so it by itself can create
evolutionary novelty that's the point
here Jeremy and I explored this at the
cell level becoming trying to get caught
up to cell biology modern cell biology
and wrote this paper and all these lines
and everything show you we're talking
about two different phenomena right
increased dosage when you double the
Genome of course and also increased bulk
amount of DNA this is something that's
rather controversial something called
the nucleotype people are familiar with
genotype and phenotype very few people
are familiar with the nucleotype which
is just um correlations with various
different uh characteristics of the
plant or animal such as cell size
nuclear volume things like that that
follow from increasing the DNA content
and it's not clear yet at this point
whether or not uh this is causality or
correlation only but it's a intriguing
thing that you see this trend across
many different traits where
autopolyploids or just plants with
larger DNA contents even show these
trends of having larger cell size
nuclear volume and those sorts of things
and this is thought um in many ways to
be the source of all the other phenomena
that follow from that all these
different lines that I'm showing here
complex
relationships the key point of this for
this talk is just that this also does
lead to morphological changes
physiological changes and even
ecological changes as well and that
brings me to my next uh section of this
talk and that's the origin of nodulation
symbiosis so nodulation is a symbiotic
association between some flowering
plants a limited number of them and
diverse soil bacteria and the bacteria
are house in these nodules which you can
see here which then fix atmospheric
nitrogen to form ammonia so fertilizer
for the plants the nodule is a
morphologically and anatomically and
biochemically complex evolutionary
novelty it's not found in other
plants its most associated nodulation is
with the legume family but it's neither
confined to the legume family uh nor is
it Universal within the legume families
I'll show you in a second
question that's been asked for many
years is what is the nodule exactly well
we can look at it and see what it is
it's on the roots usually the roots
sometimes the choots of a plant but it's
what does it where does it come from and
so uh Ann hirs at UCLA and Tom Laro used
to be up the road here at Boyce Thompson
Institute years back asked is it a
modified root or modified stem or a
completely novel organ an organu
generous early ideas about nodule
Origins uh included horizontal transfer
of different com uh components such as
leg hemoglobin and those of you who eat
impossible Burgers may be familiar with
leg hemoglobin as the the red color that
you're seeing there that substitute for
myoglobin and
hemoglobin anyway um so I I could say
more about it we had I just gave this a
talk for Mark Mark Sor in the background
there the poly the polyol talk yesterday
for your class Mark and one of the
students pointed out that when you look
at the impossible Burger um what is that
stuff there in a real Burger is it is it
blood when you get the red Stu and there
was a big debate about whether it was
actually blood or not and it turns out
someone looked it up and it's myoglobin
it's not hemoglobin it's not blood that
gives you the juice of a hamburger
apparently but I didn't know that on
this burger it's it's leg hemoglobin so
it's a vegetarian item anyway to get
back to the talk uh the evolution of of
Ruda symbiosis
involves this nodule structure and U
Martin parisy and Katherina Markman
asked this question how novel Really Are
nodules and so this gets back to the
original question about what it is what
is a nodule so it turns out that most
everything that is happening in
nodulation is a matter of recruiting a
pre-existing function or structure from
some other program already present in
the plant and so my colleague Makoto
Hayashi and Takashi soyano a asked this
question and reviewed this some years
back now and so basically what
nodulation has done is recruit uh Gene
regulatory modules from arbuscular micro
risal symbiosis from lateral root
development from nitrate responses and
maybe from other places as well from the
whole infection process there's all
sorts of things but almost nothing about
nodulation is itself novel on the genes
or anything
else so here at the heart of it all is
something called nin and uh this recent
review paper nin is a transcription
Factor called nodu Inception and so if
you look at what happens during
nodulation you have the Ryobi Ryobi
being signal by the plant and exchanging
signals infecting starting an infection
thread infection thread growth uh
proceeding into the CeX initiating
nodule formation and eventually forming
a complete nodule with uh this outgrowth
from the from the plant and eventually
then becoming functional involving in
nitrate responses and all that so every
one of these steps is uh controlled by
nin and so basically nin first of all
had to acquire some sort of binding
sites for key elements of the signaling
process were recruited from micar risal
Sy biosis including the cyclidia binding
site which you see down
here and then the other thing that had
to happen was that nin targets must have
acquired nin binding sites now there are
about 145 direct interactors of nin at
least one that's one estimate maybe an
overestimate but still a lot of
different genes have had to come
directly under the influence the control
of nin so all of those had to acquire
binding sites from n and U so one of the
questions a big evolutionary question is
how in in the evolution of novelty is
how do these kinds of binding sites are
they if they're truly novel how do they
evolve even if they're not truly novel
how do they get brought under the
control of a novel transcription Factor
system so this is a major question we'll
return to that in a bit so I haven't
told you about polyol yet um the polyol
angle here is that people have
speculated for many years that
polyploidy within the legumes which had
been known to exist to occur had been
implicated in the evolution of
nodulation so this is the medicago
genome paper
2011 and U when the mitochondrial genome
or sorry the metago genome was sequenced
it was found uh not surprisingly because
of previous work that the The genome was
structured showing evidence of a whole
genome duplication at and shared with
other legumes as well so when soybean
was then was sequenced it showed it had
that uh that whole genome duplication as
well so looking at this people
speculated well okay so this you've got
a whole genome duplication
in at the base of this whole group of
legumes we know that whole genome
duplications can spur novelty nodulation
also seemed to be unique to legumes or
at least probably evolved there as one
of its uh one of its sources of
evolution and so the speculation was
well okay so this is what's happened
we've had polyol either causing
nodulation to occur or doing something
to uh modify it if it already existed so
about the same time this paper from Rene
GS and his group a whole genome
duplication has occurred at the root of
the legume piloid this is the bean-like
subam so soybean and um Lupin and things
like that we hypothesize that Gene pairs
originating from this duplication event
have evolved symbiotic functions and
then a couple of years later another
paper came out talking about it may have
uh led to enhanced root nodu symbiosis
in the piloid the bean-like legumes
and you see evidence of that this is a
paper from some other colleagues of mine
that came out just recently looking at
the flavonoid synthesis and biosynthesis
genes in the legume family and showing
again there's some novel genes found
only in the legumes uh many of these are
due to Gene duplications and that are
unique to the legume family so this is
supports the idea that um that whole
genome duplication has led to increasing
the repertoire of genes available for
nodulation so I mentioned already that
it's not necessarily found only in the
legumes so in fact uh nodulation is
phenetically scattered and until 2018
which I'll explain in a moment this was
explained by a combination of
convergence and loss so it turns out
that nodulation once thought to be
widely scattered in the flowering plants
early on in the year of phenetics was
shown to be concentrated in one CA
within the flowering plants and this is
called the N nitrogen fixing clade or n
nodulation fixing clade um and within
this clay though you'll see that it's
scattered so the light blue or dark blue
here that you see dark blue means that
entire group uh is invol has nodulation
symbiosis light blue means that it's
scattered within that group so in
legumes for example the green is Rial
symbiosis these other ones are actinal
symbiots it's a different group of
bacteria
within the legumes you can see again
dark green means that that entire group
every one of those plants will nodulate
with one or two exceptions where it's
been lost but in other groups you'll see
light uh light green and that means that
it's scattered within those groups so
you have this distribution where um
everything is concentrated in one Cay
but then within that entire group you
have origins or losses it's just a very
complex pattern and again nodulation is
phenetically scattered and mostly it was
uh explained as a combination of
convergent gains and then independent
losses the question was always how many
of each so we were pretty confident that
there were multiple Origins but we
didn't know how many and how many times
it have been
lost so um why do we care about this I
mean I care because I'm an evolutionary
biologist and so this is certainly an
interesting question sort of curiosity
driven research question but the bigger
picture for people who are interested in
applied sorts of things is that um
generating the F generating fertilizer
for agriculture is a very expensive
ecologically expensive as well as
monetarily expensive uh proposition and
so wouldn't it be nice if we could
engineer grasses for example crop plants
that don't do n this symbiotic nitrogen
fixation to have these kind of
Partnerships make nodules make their own
fertilizer essentially and so um if
you're thinking about that you might ask
the question how easy is that going to
be
and if it's in evolution it was happen
multiple different times that would be
an easier proposition perhaps than if
you uh had only it had only happened one
time ever in all the history of
flowering plants of course even if it's
happened multiple times it's happened
only in that one clade so something is
unique about that clay that we have to
figure out if we're going to make
grasses uh do this kind of thing as well
right and that uh predisposition people
called it has been really elusive nobody
has figured out what is that makes that
clay different from everything else
that's sort of a a Holy Grail kind of
thing as well all right so um chasing
unicorns why do I say that well because
it was everybody kept talking about this
but it was very hard to figure out how
you would actually test these different
hypotheses and uh so proving or testing
whether or not nodules across different
uh nodulating species are homologous in
other words they have the same origin
and they come from a common ancestor
that was the big question how can you
tell that apart from a convergent gain
right so one of the things we thought
about this was following other work it's
not unique to me my application to the
to the legumes or to nodulation was
maybe unique but um the idea was out
there in other areas might the genomes
of non-nodulating taxa Harbor fossil
evidence that they once
nodulated so that would help us to
distinguish between primary absence of
nodulation and secondary loss uh and
focusing on non- nodulating species
instead of nodul so instead of asking
whether nodules are homologous we could
ask for evidence that some plants that
no longer show nodulation had actually
once been able to nodulate that's what
we're trying to
do so in 2018 that was a seminal year
for this two different groups came up
with tests of this and uh both of them
came to the same conclusion and this
first paper discovered signatures of
multiple independent loss of function
events in the indispensable symbiotic
regulator nodule Inception nin and and a
number of different holy sequence
genomes and in this paper taken together
results challenge The View that
nodulation evolved in parallel raises
the possibility that nodulation
originated approximately 100 million
years ago in a common ancestor of all
nodulating plant species and then was
subsequently lost in another group
so this was great and nin was almost the
only Gene lost there are a couple of
other good candidates that sort of are
lost here and there but basically nin is
the one thing that's really unique about
nodulation in terms of the of
genes so what did this look like well
here's a
philogyny um here's the single origin of
nodulation the stars or losses and here
is see I think I've got an arrow for nin
showing here this is the presence or
absence of nin and if you look down this
column and compare it with nodulating
and non-nodulating species you'll see
that there's a very good correlation
between the presence of nin and
nodulation or the absence of n nin and
non-
nodulation and so here's again what
things look like in the genomes you've
got in legumes vgna fasolis soybean
pigeon P chickpea things like that I've
all got a functional copy of nin uh
nissolia shown here is a legum that has
clearly lost the ability to nodulate and
it is lacking in entirely so a good
correlation between a known loss and the
absence of
nin here is a plant that's in the
papilionoid family but near the base and
it might or might not have lost it
secondarily we don't know but the data
here suggests n is just gone completely
so it's probably a loss and up here is
the red bud tree which those of you may
not know it's a legume it's in the bean
family but it's one of the first
offshoots that its subf family is sister
to the rest of the legume family and in
h cerus the red bud nin is present but
it's a pseudogene so it's been
inactivated so again it's not always
lost but inactivation also shows you
that this critical Gene involved in
nodulation is present in a non-
nodulating species but it is just
nonfunctional and we followed up shuen
Chang is a good colleague of mine
uh and he he has been also looking into
this further more genome sequenced we
see the same pattern whenever that
happens uh any the cor strong
correlation between absence of nin and
lack of
nodulation so um Robin van velson and
Renee Garretts um LED this little uh
essay type thing in trans implant
science here's again the pattern that
we're seeing all these black things here
black clades are places where nin where
sorry where nodulation
does not occur and again we're saying a
single origin of nodulation followed by
Massive parallel losses so the weakest
link in any argument about having a
single origin was always it took so many
independent losses to account for this
that it was never going to be a
parsimonious argument and as long as
parsimony was your Criterion for judging
things this just was never palatable at
all as an as an ongoing argument so how
does this U new hypothesis deal deal
with that and the answer is so you're
asking what could cause so many
independent losses and it has to do with
uh atmospheric CO2 levels and so in what
has happened is that Global atmospheric
CO2 levels have generally been
decreasing in the last 100 million years
uh since the time when nodulation is
hypothesized to have
risen and
consequently U because nodulation really
requires a lot of carbon in the form of
making the nodule but also giving
photosyn to the bacteria in exchange for
the nitrogen they they produce when you
have a situation in which CO2 levels are
decreasing carbon becomes increasingly
expensive and the cost benefit ratio
between nodulation nitrogen fixation and
the expense of the carbon changes and
shifts so you start out with a carbon to
nitrogen cost benefit ratio it's
positive at the beginning of this whole
era but it declines as CO2 levels
decline in the atmosphere becomes more
more expensive and so what the
hypothesis says is that as that happens
different genotypes different species
and remember this is a genotype of the
plants by genotype of the bacteria by
environment kind of proposition G byg by
e as that happens carbon becomes too
expensive and nodulation ceases so the
plants just shut it
off so absence of nodulation is not loss
at least not initially right so
nodulation is plastic and actually if
you look today if you look at field
legume crops if you fertilize that field
the legumes don't bother to make nodules
it's too expensive they get free
nitrogen from the fertilizer so they
don't need to do that so it's a plastic
response if you keep turning if you keep
everything turned off after you've
ceased to do nodulation however
everything starts to Decay as you remove
the genes from the uh from positive from
selection and so purifying selection is
relaxed and you'll start to accumulate
mutations in these key genes so that's
why cerus for example the red bud still
has nin but its nin has decayed it
doesn't function anymore other Gene
other plants have lost nin
completely so this is what happens also
with cave animals cave animals when they
go into the darkness the eye becomes
dispensable and usually mutations occur
pretty quickly to eliminate the eye and
uh there even are scenarios that are
suggested somewhat controversially
involve positive selection because even
the Machinery that's involved in in
making eyes even if you're not using
them is also expensive and so there may
be some selection pressure to actually
get rid of the eyes
entirely so this single origin massive
parallel loss hypothesis became very
popular in the community actually uh in
those two papers that I cited before
that's like 90% of the top players in
the nodulation community were involved
in one of those two papers so there
people really are pretty invested in
this hypothesis but then as I say here
this paper came around now it's been in
BIO archives for a couple of years it
took it a long time to get through but
finally published just a few weeks ago
actually um and so in this paper what
they did was they made a philogyny of
12,000 different species of nodulating
and non- nodulating uh plants in this
whole CA primarily all much of it from
herbarium material by the way this is a
shout out to the herbarium because you
can use her Baran material to actually
isolate DNA and use that in a study like
this they updated the nodulation
database of which species nodulate and
which ones don't they then used hidden
Markoff models to test the fit of
different evolutionary transition rate
models and reconstructed ancestral
character state so this is
state-of-the-art phylogenomics basically
this is what people do with big
phylogenies they test hypotheses like
this and they looked at root nodulation
symbiosis whoops that happened wow uh
and their results showed that they the
best models were 16 independent gains
and 10 subsequent losses so we've gone
back to now the state-of-the-art
hypothesis on a philogyny is now saying
16 Origins the one that everybody in the
nodulation community likes is one origin
so what's right what's the truth okay
now truth and science that's a two words
that you don't want to necessarily put
together all the time the question is
how do you test the homologies right
we're back to that question back to
where we were before 2018 saying okay
maybe there were multiple Origins but
how do we test that now and how can you
test homology if recruitment was
convergent this is a big question this
is what's called Deep homology and I
didn't mention that when I mentioned the
recruitment process in nodulation but
those things that are shared across
nonhomologous Origins right are them
elves homologous so um lateral root
development using scarecrow and short
root for example that's something that's
common to all plants right and that
module is going to be homologous no
matter how many different times it was
recruited by in different origins of
nodulation so looking at that is never
going to help us answer that question
not just the presence of that the use of
that particular module developmental
module so what if all the components are
homologous how do you test this all
right so because what we really want to
do is the uniqueness of the assembly
that is what we want to test so how can
we figure out whether the same thing was
built a couple of different times that's
the question we're getting at so back to
nin again here's nin our friend uh our
nin binding sites homologous across
putative Origins remember that nin had
to be recruited n the targets of nin had
to recruit this binding site all these
different genes that you see here right
had to independently in that model in a
16 Origins model 16 different times all
of those genes had to recruit nin
function all right so how do we tell
that well can fossil nin binding sites
be detected in non nodulates so here's
an idea this is a paper we're writing
now is sort of a not a rebuttal to that
new paper but really just exploring how
could we can actually test these
hypothesis
um people involved in writing that paper
by the way are best man at my wedding um
and my academic grandson is the main
author and so it's kind of a I'm not I'm
not angry with these people or anything
like that I just want to get to the
bottom of things so n nin binding sites
is positional criteria for
homology imagine a gene here's a gene
Gene X in an ancestor XA it has a couple
of different binding sites for different
transcription factors now nin comes
along this Gene becomes recruited by as
part of the nodulation process to and
binds nin so here you have a nin binding
site I've conveniently put it between
these other two sites this is a
nodulating species one suppose we
sequence another nodul from a different
group of plants and we find the same
position that would be consistent with
homology of that site it's the same
sequence 8 to 15 base pair more or less
binding site and it's in the same
position but if we sequence some other
different genomes from other plants and
we find that these nin binding sites
even if they are the same site because
that's what nin binds across different
groups if they're in different places
that would be consistent with
non-homology so that's the idea there's
not a lot to go on here but this is
about the best I think we're going to be
able to do and so we certainly know in
binding sites this paper just came out a
couple of few I guess a month ago or so
I just saw it a month or so ago and
anyway this uh there are binding sites
some of these interesting sites here are
found across both nodulating and non-
nodulating non- legumes as well so they
exist we don't know the context I don't
know the context yet but that's
something we can look
at okay so um philosophical questions
continue to be raised about the nature
of homology so for those of you who are
evolutionary biologists have been
hearing the word homology forever since
you first started reading about anything
about evolutionary biology and it's a
major controversial topic how to define
homology and what it means and how to
test it and everything else gter Vagner
who's an author on this paper has been
writing books about this for many
different years and here's um character
identity mechanisms are something that
this group of authors has come up with
and I can't explain them to you because
it's more philosophy than it is biology
actually I think but there's something
uh that integrate information come to
this kind of hourglass structure this is
where the mechanism sits and then has
different readouts from that the best
example I can give you is actually for
the origin of cell types and this is
another paper this paper from 2016 gter
Vagner was the last author on this paper
the idea being that there's this
integration mechanism here the core
regulatory complex that takes all the
inputs synthesizes that and reads it out
to uh coordinate the efforts of all the
different transcription factors involved
in this regulatory complex and that
combination
combinatorial um factoring of
transcription factors and their outputs
is what makes a cell type specific to
itself it is the the defining feature of
a cell type I guess I say it that way is
better all right so that's what's that's
the classic example of one of these
character integration
mechanisms um at the level of the cell
and then they talk about in this paper
things at higher hierarchical levels
again being analogous to that so why do
I mention that that's my next thing um
first of all here's Giles ID's paper
again this is one you saw already but
they and summarizes this very nicely
rather than novel emergence of new genes
the evolution of nodulation appears to
have involved the r networking of
pre-existing processes principally
controlled by the master regul regulator
nin told you all of that already he goes
on to say they go on to say we need to
understand not only how this this
happens but also also how it's able to
activate such diverse development in the
different cell types so now we're back
to cell types not only do we need to
know about cell types philosophically
but we need to know about them
practically speaking to actually get to
the bottom of this mystery and that
brings me to my last vignette which is
dup Gene duplications and the origin of
cell type
diversity so Jeremy and I've been
interested in in cell types for a little
while mainly because it turns out that
the effect of poly varies with cell type
and so some cell types respond by
becoming much larger other cell types on
the other hand don't and so being a cell
size is one of the key factors involved
we think in pretty much everything
Downstream of poly fluidization in
creating novelty this is an important
thing to know and um so we ask the
question well first of all what's a cell
type and guess what people don't know
don't agree on what a cell type is so um
this is 202 2 2023 hqu Zang is the head
of the Allen brain Institute where they
work on neurons and neuron cell types
where hundreds of if not thousands of
cell types these authors are tops in
their field what's a cell type this
paper was just from a week and a half
ago and um it's a little review P not
review paper a little popular piece in
nature and so um I was actually
interviewed for this paper um but uh
it's so it's still a question of what
this actually means what is a cell type
and so yeah I was at interviewed because
I've written a little bit about it
because I was trying to figure out what
in the world a cell type was and how
deal with it likened it to species which
is a very bad thing to do because
species nobody agrees on what a species
is and um worked with Mark Lio you'll
see him in a second again to just talk
about this in a recent paper last
year mark is one of the leaders in the
field of s cell biology and plants and
um I'm fortunate to be a colleague of
his on a on a grant that we have
together along with Jeremy and Andrew
farmer whose name you saw in relation to
gini this is a talk that we gave this
summer actually presented at our botney
meetings in in uh
Michigan a single cell perspective on
duplicate gene expression and this work
is asking this is ongoing project we
haven't published anything yet on this
uh and soybean at least to what extent
does cell type and cell State diversity
provide niches for duplicated genes so
what do I mean by that so duplication of
genes is really frequent if you look at
this this is a classic paper here Lynch
and connory 2000 you're looking here the
number of pairs percentage of pairs of
duplicated genes as a function of time
right so this is K KS down here so it's
a aoxy for time this you'll see this
kind of L-shaped pattern in all
different taxa what this is these are
small scale duplications so single genes
or a few genes at a time and what this
is showing is that um duplication Is
frequent you have lots of pairs at time
T equals zero essentially and not much
else beyond that meaning that these
things are duplicating turning over copy
number variation and Gene Gene copy
number and then loss almost immediately
okay now arabidopsis looks a little bit
different and that's because this peak
down here is a whole genome duplication
that a arabidopsis the most recent of
the whole genome duplications that
arabidopsis has experienced it's a
little bit different but the same idea
occurs you have a whole genome
duplication followed by lots of losses
of gen in that diploidization process I
mentioned at the beginning so we have to
account for why gene pairs get kept ever
because most of the time you think about
it these are redundant genes at the time
of their formation you don't need them
the plant was perfectly happy with just
one copy before and now we have to
explain why does some get kept and other
ones don't you've probably heard of
neofunctionalization this is
partitioning expression by function so a
gene that had a single function this
duplicate copies have the same function
initially but then one of them acquires
a novel function and that gets
maintained once these genes are
partitioned by function there's reason
to keep both copies essentially being a
little an anthropomorphic here so that's
partitioning by function
subfunctionalization is also involving
function but usually we think of it as
being partitioning of expression
involving location so in this model a
gene has multiple functions and then
these are partitioned such that some one
gene is doing some of the functions some
doing the other this diagram is not as
good I think as this one here this is a
little simpler and if you think of
something that a single copy Gene was
expressed in Limb and brain and then
after duplication one of the copies
loses the ability to be expressed in the
brain the other loses its ability to be
expressed in the limb now you have an
indispensable two copies you need one of
each of those copies and they're
maintained okay so this is involving
location of the expression as much as
anything so looking at expression of
location at the Single Cell level we
have bulk tissu cell types cell states
of a single type and then single cells
within that we have a gene duplication A
and B copies we can ask about expression
whether one or both or neither are
expressed and if we look at the bulk
tissue the root might be expressing one
copy predominantly the leaf the other if
we now look at the root expression at
the cell type level we see the same kind
of pattern where some are some cell
types or or cell clusters are expressing
some cell types are expressing some one
gene some the other some both some
neither and now we break out the
epidermis cells for example and look at
these as they develop becoming mature
again the same kind of pattern and even
at the Single Cell level we may see
variation in terms of which Gene is
being expressed um this level of the
single cell is probably Beyond kind of
for various reasons beyond our ability
to really work with very clearly and so
we're really talking about cell clusters
a mixture of St State and
type couple of years ago we looked at
expression partitioning of duplicate
genes in arabidopsis 11,000 different
different duplicate Gene Pairs and this
we classified them as you can see here
if neither Gene was expressed in any of
the cell clusters was a class zero one
only one copy expressed and that's what
we see here in copy one and class one
both copies expressed but always both
were present no fixation in any of the
cell types uh in this class three we
have um uh both copies expressed and in
some cell types only one was expressed
in other cell types both were expressed
and then
here we have a case of what really looks
like subfunctionalization we have
partitioning of expression in different
cell types or cell clusters between the
two Gene
copies and this is what this looks like
uh one of the subfunctionalization cases
your two genes that are derived from the
whole genome duplication in the Rabid
opsis and you can see here one of them
is expressed here and this is endodermis
and down here the other copy is not
expressed there but it's instead
expressed in a couple different places
as well so this partitioning has
happened presumably following Gene
duplication we're now looking at soybean
in this project at 10 different organs
and you can read the details over here
120,000 single nucleus sequencing 187
cell clusters a lot of annotation this
is a project involving Mark Libo and
some of my other
colleagues um looking at 60,000
duplicated Gene pairs by the type of
duplication and you can see the numbers
here main thing I want to show is that
this involves also two whole genome
duplications one that I've mentioned
before is found in all the bean-like
legumes the other one is a much more
recent duplication only within the last
say 10 million years or so and that one
is in in soybean only the other one is
about 60 million years
old so if we look at the ex evolution of
expression patterns following
duplication what do we expect to see
here's a single copy Gene expressed in a
number of different cell
clusters or number of different genes
we make a simplifying a very simplifying
assumption that everybody makes
unfortunately and that is that
immediately following duplication
duplicate copies are identical in their
expression patterns and their functions
and there's some logic to that but it's
um it's it's a pretty tricky one to make
but everybody has to do it for
evolutionary purposes there's not much
else you can do because we don't have
access usually to the progenitor
species so following duplication you
have two copies where you had one one
before and if there're you follow that
assumption they are all doing the same
thing which means they're going to be
class two that's what this is showing
here and that's at time T equals zero
you let this go further 10 million years
or so later you now have some of them
still maintaining this uh class to but
other ones have evolved to different
classes depending on which genes are
being expressed in which tissu some are
silenced some are retained uh some might
be lost entirely so that's what we have
for prediction and so the expectation is
that over time we should see a depletion
of this class 2 type of Gene where both
are being expressed well what do we
actually see here's some data um first
of all class zero is the one that's are
not expressed these pairs are not
expressed at all anywhere so in every
organ most Gene pairs have at least one
copy
expressed most of the genes the largest
single fraction are these class two
genes 20 to 30 30,000 pairs where both
genes are expressed we have only one
duplicate copy expressed uh by loss or
gain of been seven to 12,000 pairs some
fixation of one copy and it's always the
same copy in these cases 7 to 15,000
Pairs and then that little tiny bit up
above here expression partitioning
within organs and this is what that
looks like a few hundred genes at the
most and I'll just call your attention
to the nodule because I'm going to loop
back a little bit to nodulation here at
the end of this
talk so basically there's
differentiation in the location of
expression for about 50% of Gene pairs
after their
duplications so if we want to look at
this time course we can compare the old
duplicate the old whole genome
duplication 60 million years with the 10
million year duplication and our
expression is that there's a depletion
of class two genes over time and what do
we see this is exactly what we see here
if you look there's much more of this
class 2 Gene in um in the recent
duplication than in the old
duplication and this we see this also in
terms of the expression of
subfunctionalization as well this class
four all right my last thing here is to
talk about co-expression networks um
this is function now and uh Gene
regulatory networks are involved in
function I think everybody would agree
with that and Gene uh co-expression
networks are proxies for Gene regulatory
networks that's the point that's being
made here Chandler who's a postto with
Jeremy coat looked at this reconstructed
gcns for all these genes here's some
data 400 800 modules per organ uh 40 to
100 genes on on average per
module and the question here is how
often do both members of a pair belong
to the same module right so what we're
saying here is this is from the Rabid
Ops interactome paper some years back
initially following duplication all the
interactions of a gene that was single
copy or maintained by both copies so
again this is same the idea kind of that
I mentioned before or location of
function but over time we have
interaction rewiring and these two uh
genes can now belong to different uh
networks okay so what we found was that
80 to 90% of duplicate genes in this
data set belong to different modules so
a massive amount of rewiring has gone on
across the board so extension extensive
functional differentiation of duplicate
copies and looking at this thinking of
this as a Time course we have the module
in which one homeologue one of the two
duplicated copies uh exists and the
module in which the second copy exists
initially we should see them belonging
to the same modules and all the genes
would be shared no change at all
following duplication
and over time we should see migration
away from this nice diagonal into the
other parts of this module space that we
see
here what we actually see is pretty much
that note the much stronger diagonal
still not great but stronger certainly
than this here in the recent duplication
versus the old duplication so we're
seeing that process of migration away
from being in the same uh modules over
time this is what the these modules look
like both duplicates in the same module
this is one of the nodule modules it's
hard to say that but and here's nodule
module 108 which is just the opposite
where only one duplicate of is in is
present in the module for most of the
genes right and to come back to this the
nodule is is a novel organ as we said
and you might think that a no novel
organ would provide more niches for
expression
subfunctionalization and in fact that's
more or less what we see if you look at
this look at the comparison of the whole
genome duplication two whole genome
duplications the nodule is always uh on
the high end at the highest one in terms
of the number of subfunctionalized cases
of Gene pairs that we
see nodules do not appear to differ in
the amount of partitioning that we get
looks pretty much like everything else
but if you look at um cell type specific
modules in this these gcn if you look at
everything else all the other organ look
fairly similar here this is the cell
type specific modules here the nodule is
very different in terms of that and why
might that be it is because the cell
clusters that are showing the most of
that sort of effect are actually novel
cell types infected cell types within
within the nodule so all right so what
I've shown you from this last part is
cell types and States within organs
provide apparently inexhaustible niches
for refinement of duplicate Gene
expression single cell resolution allows
us to track evolution of cell type
specific expression over time and the
nodule which is a relatively young organ
provides insights into the evolution of
novelty and the role played by
duplication and fueling Innovation so
there are my three vignettes poly
generates diversity through speciation
and genome Evolution it may have been
involved in the origin or refinement of
nodulation and then these wondrous
cycles of poly can be observed in the
occupancy of expression nishes at the
Single Cell level by duplicated genes
and with that thank you
questions uh so I had a question about
um essentially like synthetic biology
with uh this n group so has there been
has there been any attempts to your
knowledge of taking those groups that um
because they would be closer like the
ones that do have the motifs for this n
binding but they their n gene or or set
of genes is deactivated there been any
attempt to sort of reactivate that and
see if they make nules or um conversely
or I guess like in addition that any
more difficult aspect of like
engineering this n plus motives into
yeah so there's a lot of questions there
right um the the first answer is no
nobody has reactivated a non-nodulating
species by putting a functional copy of
nin in I'm guessing that Renee gz has
probably tried that with Trea this
parasponia group is actually in the in
the Cannabis family uh it's weird plant
that grows in new calonia and and anyway
it has close relative Trea that doesn't
nodulate and so they're they're really
closely related so either it's a very
recent gain of nodulation or a recent
loss of nodulation depending on which
way you go that would be a wonderful
system for trying that experiment I
can't believe Renee hasn't done it but I
it's not reported anyway so let's see
other questions uh using nin and other
ways uh people have actually shown that
you can take the nin from one nodulating
species and go all the way to some other
clay completely put it in and it it'll
compensate for mutations and Lotus
japonicus for example you actually
putting in from this parasponia that
cannabus thing and put it into a mutant
of lotus japonicus and get it to
function in nodulation again so they are
really
interchangeable um as for looking at The
Binding sites themselves uh people have
done dap seek and things like that
trying to find where the the the sites
are and what's interacting and
everything but the noise level and these
things Mak Makoto Hayashi I've talked to
him about it and he said they've done
the experiment they've got thousands of
hits and he he thinks that even the 145
direct interactors with nin is probably
an overestimate and he said other people
are looking into this to really refine
that more um so it's pretty complicated
but certainly people are interested in
in doing that kind of
experiment Randy I think you had your
hand up I thought about the cost of
running no have people done an economic
analysis in like yield per dollar and
what it cost to to yeah for example
nitrogen fixing versus right that's a
good question I haven't seen an economic
analysis of that um but people have and
there's a lot of sort of information
around that a sense like for example
that someone did a really neat
experiment of trying to replicate carbon
atmosphere from a several million years
ago and showed that nodulates would have
had a much bigger Advantage then than
now than in more recent carbon
atmospheres so there's that's economics
but of a different kind than you're
talking about actually what people are
looking at now with with engineering
Giles oldid who mentioned a couple times
here um he they they and others he and
others have been thinking about what are
the components of nodulation short of
making a nodule could you get into
grasses and actually have that be you
know a little more realistic to try to
do that than than get a whole nodule on
the plant and there's some neat things
that people are finding Jamel an at
Wisconsin found um I mean he's not the
one who found it I guess a raise a land
race of maze in the mountains of Mexico
where uh that accumulates biofilms of
nitrogen fixing bacteria on the roots
and actually derives a serious benefit
from that so that's another thing
another angle people are looking at so
no Randy I'm sorry I don't have an
answer for the dollars but yeah okay
I'll just take the dollars just take the
dollars and run garv and then yeah so uh
regarding the last result about
duplicate Gene diversification so we
also see similar results in enzymes as
the ks increases uh it the corelation
decreases but I mean it makes sense but
the altern explanation is that
duplicates that tend to diversify
quickly are the ones that are selected
and are retained for longer time
duplicates that overlapping functions T
to get lost MH I'm not sure how to
distinguish between that hypothesis and
what time the diverse hypothesis yeah
well there's a lot going on under the
hood right with those those curves um as
you know because you know a lot about
polyl one of the other mechanisms that
actually preserves genes in polyploids
but not in in single duplicates is
dosage balance constraints right so
there's a lot of of of um Nuance
basically to those graphs that I don't
get into here at all in fact that's one
of the things we're exploring is can you
see correlations between D dosage
sensitive genes versus preservation and
there's a whole lot of things we did
that in the Rabid opsis paper to some
degree and we'll probably do that again
here but yeah there there's a lot lot
happening with that Laura I just
thinking about more about these
assumptions underlying the Gen duplicate
have those assumptions been
experimentally tested so Laura is asking
whether the assumptions of um of of
shared or preserved function at
duplication could those assumptions be
tested I'm not sure you even need to to
know that they're really wrong in some
cases frankly I mean so for examp I
didn't get into this in the seminar but
if you think about the difference
between just trans just um duplicating a
gene right in suu versus transposing it
to someplace in the in the dark matter
of the genome where you know you're
around a bunch of transposable elements
there's no way that that Gene is going
to be the same function and yet it's
considered a duplicate right the other
one is a
retrotransposon kind of situation or
when you actually um you chop out the
intron and everything and you're going
to put that Gene in there call that a
duplication and is that really going to
have the same function so I don't know
um one other complicating factor is that
when we talk about autop poly so when we
talk about poly often people think just
make the Assumption it's just
duplication of the genome right but an
awful lot of poly probably all poly
involves
hybridization either in the systematics
and evolutionary biology sense of being
between two species or in the plant
breeders sense I'm looking at the plant
breeders in the audience here who think
of a hybrid as being between two
varieties of maze right so almost
everything probably when polyploids
originate involves some kind of a cross
different genotypes are involved now to
say in an era when we know that there's
a Le specific expression differences in
pretty much every Gene right to think
that those are going to be identical no
probably not I don't even think you need
to test that assumption it's a bad
assumption but it's the we can do for
something that happened millions of
years ago yeah okay thank you so
much this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu