this is a production of Cornell
University but I'm going to start this
talk out differently than ever
before uh so who in this room likes
landscape
paintings who doesn't like landscape
paintings I was somebody who didn't love
landscape
paintings um but I have turned around um
and you'll see why I'm talking about
this in a minute but I mean my work is
all about biomass but um the Hudson
River School of Art right was in the mid
1800s they were American painters uh
whatever that meant to be an American in
1800 um they were landscape painters and
they the school was sort of along the
Hudson River um but they also went out
west uh some famous names are Thomas
Cole Friedrich Church Albert stat Asher
derland and George
NF so what do you think of this one
what's what's what's the feeling in this
image EP epic God
Grandeur immense huge hunting
wild what's the feeling in this
one for
boing Heat
ominous oid
oxidation I should do this more
often um how about this one what's going
on in this
one yep agriculture of course you're the
first to say that the first time
impending doom impending doom and
there's also this little umbrella that's
forming and a little Top Hat down here
how about this one what's going on in
this Oney
windy battle there's a battle what do
they wearing those people in Battle Red
Coats there's
smoke how's this one
feel peaceful
bucolic tick what tick infest tck not
yet that comes later
how about this one how's this one
feel
what expansive prospecting maybe right
some
civilization how's this one
feel
settled and how does that settling feel
compared to this
one this is indust industrialization
right it's running on cold the trees are
cut off there's like it's not just
bucolic landscape it's like the
beginning of a
city and then this
one right this is on the
Hudson right the industrial action of
the
Fisheries so the Hudson River School of
Art reflect on three themes of America
in the 19th century Discovery
exploration and settlement and covers
these ranges of experiences of you know
you come here and this diabolical fear
of nature this heavenly admiration of
nature the coexistence with nature the
utility of Nature and the Mastery of
Nature and since my talk is about
biomass I'm fundamentally talking about
the Mastery of nature but I want us all
to remember that all these other
experiences of New York I showed you in
these images you could think of them as
just Fantastical paintings but they are
actually documents of other ways of
being on this same landscape right and
we are making real choices here
as uh environmental scientists about
structuring the next generation of what
our landscape looks like because
certainly New York City where I live
doesn't look like any of the images I
have just showed you right horizontal
line it's like the first thing I do for
the first hour on the bus when I'm
coming here it's all I'm looking for is
the horizontal line and that doesn't
happen any New
York
um and the reason why it's happening
right
is we're at such a huge population when
I was born in 1973 there were like half
as many people as there are now so we
have the same land mass but we have
twice as many people as when I was born
and those paintings I just showed you
were when we had you know between one
and two billion people
and that's the whole earth when you came
to the new world when you came to
America back
then there were some real ethical
questions about what to do I mean it was
so beautiful but then there were all
these resources that you could utilize
and so there was a battle between
becoming wealthy whatever that means and
keeping it
pristine
okay so here's now the you know the
formal part of the talk but I wanted to
frame it that
way so how do we manage our landscape
for food feed fiber and Fuel and this
goes back to my early work with John
Duxbury and what I'm continuing to do
work with
Peter and specifically I'm going to
focus on the fuel
component
so uh a couple years
ago uh with Peter and many other people
uh we did did a analysis of the New York
State biomass feed stock
production um sustainable feed stock
production uh and it was based on land
availability land suitability and
biomass
yield and you know we applied all these
different constraints I'm not going to
go over them I'm sure um you know Forest
will stay as forests protected lands
meaning state and federal are not used
right existing Wood Products were Main
mained dead and 35% of tops were left in
the forest for biodiversity right we
didn't consider equan use not all land
owners are going to want to grow biomass
right so only 50% adopt or roughly you
know herbaceous will remain
herbaceous you know we had all of these
factors that we put into this in order
to get this biomass feed stock um number
that could be sustainably produced in
New York state
so here's that graph in sum it's 14.2
terram of biomass for bioenergy per year
this is our existing production it's
roughly the same amount and this is what
we think we could sustainably produce in
okay so this is you know if this is what
we're producing in the state already and
we're doubling it it seems like a kind
of a large Endeavor it's going to change
certain things and practices but
to give you some context of what 14.2
teragrams of biomass is this is the New
York State energy flow chart from nura's
2015 publication but it's based on
2013 New York State
consumes
3,665
uh Terra BTUs so funny I use the T all
the time um and then you have these
conversion and losses which is basically
only considering the electricity so that
our net consumption is
2,655 all
right uh you know this is petroleum is
purple natural gas coal other fuels
which has nuclear Hydro wind these are
sort of proportional shapes so you can
get a sense of what's going
in so this 14.2 teragrams if we just
convert it to a BTU
value right just as raw
biomass accounts for
7% of this
number
okay so all of our sustainable biomass
7% of our current energy
consumption so what we did was instead
of looking at Returns on investments we
looked at how much how we could look at
the processes that this biomass would go
through to do the most work for society
right you can make gallons of ethanol
you could make kilowatt hours right
those are products in themselves but
what we want to do since we've got this
finite land base with this finite
biomass on it we want to do the most
work for society so we this whole
analysis is about uh fundamentally
focused on the work so it's a simple
sort of input output analysis we use the
basic unit of the jewel it is a measure
of comparing the quantity of energy and
it misses something of the quality of
energy right not all energies are the
same when you compare them on a jewel
basis right they might have the same
Jewels but you can do a lot more with
electric Jewels than you can do with
heat Jewels right so just keep that in
mind and then we looked for two types of
Works two types of work um heating for
homes or buildings and transport as
measured by distance traveled in a
vehicle so what are the steps in the
boundaries well we have to plant and
grow and harvest the biomass then we
have to move the wet biomass to a
processing plant then we have to convert
the biomass to a usable form and then we
move that energy product to the
consumer so there are many Energy
Products right that we could get out out
of the cellulosic
biomass um it could be ethanol pellets
grain
electricity but then we do one more step
which is we convert that energy to work
to think about the end use
efficiency so for growing and harvesting
just to give you an idea I mean this
list is really long I'm not going to go
through the whole list with you I'm just
showing you three attributes of
comparing you know what happens with
maze versus Willow you know you have to
plow maze a year you you plow for the
grass one every 10 years and that
affects the energy for the plow and the
boded energy in the
plow so those are some of the attributes
that go into looking at the energy at
growing and harvesting the
biomass across the different types of
biomass then we have to look at the
moisture content of the biomass cuz that
affects the weight when you're
transporting it to the processing center
we look at the btu content or the gigle
content of that biomass to you know
calculate our raw energy resource these
are the Harvest cost that I just sort of
alluded to in the last slide and then
distances that the biomass is
transported okay to uh a site so you
know you can see that maze grain was
based on our two ethanol plants so we
only have two ethanol plants in the
state so there's a farther distance that
the corn has to travel whereas um in the
other scenarios we have
24 smaller biomass plants around the
state so they have a shorter distance to
travel right but I'm just giving you
some of
the um and this calculates this
translates into how much of the dry
biomass is spent towards Transportation
energy right I'm just there are many
attributes but I'm just trying to give
you a sense of what's going on then you
get to the processing plant um we uh
there are two existing maze grain
ethanol plants but you could also use
that same maze grain for pellet stove
there's one existing uh combined heat
and power plant that uses what wood
chips in lionsdale New York so you losic
ethanol this was in collaboration with
our group for the analysis for
nerta um which is a Next Generation
cellulosic ethanol production and but
then you could also use that same
cellulose and make pellets which could
go into a pellet stove or you could make
those pellets go into a combined heat
and power plant to generate electricity
so these are some of the scenarios that
we saw for this
biomass or processing
scenarios what you need to know about
these scenarios or these processes is
that they have different numbers of
steps right and the more steps you do in
a process generally you lose
energy so maze grain is interesting
right because at its 15.55% moisture
content you could just pop it in the
stove you don't have to do anything
before you get heat but all you're
getting out of that product is heat
right you're not getting electricity so
it depends on what you
want some others were one step so
biomass was pelletized for pellet stove
the wet wood chips were combusted in a
real plant to generate electricity and
that um plant was 22% efficient in
generate electricity the maze grain is
converted to ethanol or the cellulose
biomass was converted to ethanol again
one step in the you have a product that
people can use and then we went one step
further and we did two steps where you
take that pelleted uh cellulose and you
generated electricity at 30% efficiency
or you put the ethanol in to generate
electricity at a slightly higher uh
conversion
efficiency
oops um so once you have your product
whether it's megawatts it has to go
through the grid and it loses 15 percent
of its energy through the Grid or you
use a truck to take it to the
Distribution Center I.E gas station
whatever um that was
calculated and then you have to look at
the end use efficiency and this is kind
of where the Crux of our analysis comes
down I hope you'll see it later but you
know we put maze in a 75% uh efficient
pellet stove the cellulose pellets we
put in an 80% efficient stove um the
ethanol and an 80% efficient home boiler
electricity is 99% efficient in
generating heat in a
home uh for distance we did ethanol in a
20% efficient internal combustion engine
and uh we did Distance by you know
electricity and a 75% Efficient Electric
Car
okay in addition there are potential
co-products and I say
potential because there's always
products whether or not they're used and
considered products is another matter
right we call it waste generally because
we have very poor imaginations we use
waste very frequently so maze ethanol uh
makes dried distillers grains uh that
has a high value for feed animal feed
but remember this analysis keeps
everything on the jewel level we're
comparing everything with jewels so even
though this might have more value in
terms of producing beef or milk or
whatever this is just kept in terms of
jewels as pellets that could go into a
pellet stove okay cellulosic ethanol has
a small amount of electricity that's
generated as a
co-product um and when you generate
electricity in a power plant you
generate tons of heat um and you could
potentially capture that waste Heat so
the lionsdale biomass plant which runs
on wet wood chips up in Lions Fall New
York and it's only 22% efficient it used
to sell its waste heat to a neighboring
paper plant and it would dry the paper
at the paper
plant something happened and they no
longer do that and the paper plant now
has a natural gas heater to dry their
paper so even though these two companies
are close proximity again when energy is
cheap you don't have to cooperate right
uh you don't and that's a very real
reality um The Maze grain has no
co-product right you're just combusting
it straight for heat uh and same thing
with the pelletized uh cellulose for
heat um
so the summary table that's coming up is
based on these five characteristics so
I'm going to try to go through
this I mean just
this is important is what I guess I'm
trying to say um so we start out with
this biomass right it's it's got a
volume it's got a character it's it's
got so many BTUs in it uh has a certain
moisture content
whatever and when we want to convert it
uh we're going to go through some
processing losses okay it's just that's
what's going to happen it's going to
lose things in the
process we also had to put things in
right we we had to use energy to apply
nutrients to the field we had we had to
transport it by car right so those are
external inputs
okay then we want to do work with that
biomass right we want to heat our homes
and we want to travel
distances that's the end goal that's the
product but when we do that we lose
energy right you lose it's not an
efficient system turning you know
ethanol into miles driven it's an
inefficient system so there are these
end use
losses and then there are these
co-products that I just listed that
could be used but if we don't use them
then they're wastes right so these five
attributes that I'm talking
about um oops I guess it's coming
up not next I'll come back to it um
I I want to just talk about the scale at
which we're we're doing this these
analyses because you know scale matters
so one scenario is just Greenwood chips
an existing power plant of 20 megawatt
um and it has a simple conversion
efficiency of
22% um maze grain to existing power
plants right it's 54% efficient and when
I say simple conversion I mean you're
getting you're getting
all this ethanol out without thinking
about any of the inputs that went into
it okay so it's 54% of the biomass BTU
but not of the total Energy System BTU
right it just means you put in this much
corn you got this much ethanol out but
you also put lots of other things in so
I'm just giving you these simple
conversion efficiencies to show you the
range at the very first step without
considering any of the other things so
of course mayze grain in a pellet stove
right you're not talking about the
energy that went into making the maze
grain it's 100% efficient because you've
got the corn grain already in the form
that you want or you need to use in your
pellet
stove
um and this is just sort of a
summarizing chart also of inputs and
products
so there's the biomass energy content
this is the energy within the biomass
that we harvested and this is the
supplemental energy that we had to add
to it in order to be able to make the
products okay and then we get these
primary products which is you
know uh electricity ethanol grain
pellets electricity ethanol and
electricity and then these co-products
that I was just talking to you about
before oops so here's the chart and I'm
going to do it in three doesn't have
labels because that comes in the next
one I'm just trying to orient you to
this graph
so each one of these bars is is a megag
or a unit of
biomass when it's above zero it's work
that is accomplished by by Society for
society like distance traveled or homes
heated when it's below zero it means
that it's been lost somewhere in the
process right it either was lost as an
input it was lost in the processing it
was lost in the Nu sufficiency
all right and to orient you again these
are all about transportation and these
are all primarily about your primary
product being heat okay so next slide
adds more
information
so this is the processing loss while
you're converting um The Maze grain into
ethanol this is the process loss this is
how much product you make
okay whenever it's all this green
whether it's striped or not that's the
amount of product you make so when
you're making
ethanol I don't know like
50% right I said 54% for Maze grain so
this is 54% of the biomass it's turned
into ethanol however you had to use this
much energy input so I'm sort of
deducting that even though you could
sell that ethanol you actually need it
to make the next generation of
ethanol this is when you take that
ethanol and you put it in your car and
you go miles but it's only in a 20%
efficient internal combustion engine so
that means only 5% of the Corn grain is
going to traveling distance in
miles the rest of it is going off as
waste heat into the atmosphere or maybe
heating your car in the winter right
now this is the co-product if we don't
use this co-product it should come down
here in most of these scenarios we don't
actually use the co-product but this is
the potential in this case it's dried
distiller grain and it is actually used
for animal feed
okay so the point
here is that these numbers right here
that's the proportion of the biomass
that it's actually doing work for
society so if you and then this up here
is the co-product that could do work for
society if we're clever about it if
we're not already using it
okay so clearly using the maze grain or
the pet pelletized cellulose is going to
do the most direct work from the primary
product okay 64 or 69% of that biomass
is going to heat
homes you know using 5% of it doing
Transportation if it's ethanol cor
ethanol all right if we pelletize this
cellulose and we put it in a combined
heat and power plant and we generated
electricity 19% of it could go towards
driving
now if we would just use the waste heat
right the whole Collective would be 60%
utility for society now we have two
products we've got heat products and
transportation products all right we
like this potentially if we would use
right because electricity is very
versatile it's a really powerful fuel
type right if we could just be effective
at using the waste heat then this would
be a great percentage that's like 62% of
the biomass is going to products for
society but it requires some
coordination so that that waste heat is
actually used so even though this is
like the bigger number it's a bigger
number for heat
products right
so the value the quality of the energy
is very
different all
right uh this moved down but this is
supposed to be highlighting this line
but basically the same biomass um can
use 5 to 19% of its photosynthetic
energy to drive miles versus the same
biomass can use 12 to 69% of its
photosynthetic energy to heat homes
right if the objective is to do work for
society how do we want to move what
kinds of things do we want to support
and move
forward so to bring this home and a 25 M
per gallon car I think the average was
23 recently I don't know
I uh meant to check on that
but at an average of $323 this is
averaged across uh the last three years
okay now I recognize when I took my bus
it was $157 in New Jersey so you can
divide this by two and get your number
but I don't think a157 is forever but
anyways gas at 323 a gallon electricity
at 18 cents per kilowatt hour ethanol at
$3 a gallon and E85 at 294 a
gallon would cost
$12.78 to use gas to go 100
miles versus
$67 to go 100 miles in an electric
vehicle okay now I just reduce this by
half $157 so right now they're equal in
terms of the cost
right uh but I you're getting it
right look at it at a different
perspective so if we took all the
cellulose all the sustainable cellulose
from New York
State and we converted into
ethanol and we made this many gallons of
ethanol at $3 a gallon it would cost the
consumer 4.2 billion
to buy those gallons right if we pallet
all the cellulose for electric cars and
we converted it to electricity at 18
cents per kilowatt hour it's $3.7
billion to the consumer kind of the same
price but you can only drive 35 * 10 9
miles versus 60 * 109 miles on the same
price right is everybody kind of getting
this
so these are my modest
conclusions our biomass only accounts
for 7% of primary energy consumption we
could increase efficiency and all kinds
of levels but in this particular case I
hope it makes it clear the electric
vehicle versus the internal com com
combustion
vehicle and then thinking about
diversity of end use right we're moving
away from just fuels for transportation
and thinking more cohesively about the
whole system and what we want to deliver
to
society meanwhile we have to think about
seasonal um changes and be sensitive to
climate changes and how this
intensifies the land base and what are
the competing uses for this land base
right we could all go back to the colic
images of the Hudson River School that
would be a choice or we could get really
inefficient cars and have that right I
mean we have many choices um there are
there's tons of competing land uses
um and generally less conversion means
greater social benefit um uh but it's
remember it depends
immediately
uh and more salable product does not
mean more societal work right that's
kind of the point and this last one I
apologize I just couldn't help myself
but I'll just move
on um so that is that um I would love to
entertain questions thank
[Applause]
you for New
York I at this point I really like the
pel
C right
um because even though it doesn't get
the maximum out of the
umuse in the biomass it gives us two
products
and I think uh I think that's two very
important parts heat we live in a
freezing cold Society we need the heat
it's a serious necessity right it's as
important as food right um but
electricity is incredible it has so much
capacity so while the easy answer is to
say you know pellet stoves and and P you
know for porn or for pel cellulose
I I live in New York City um I grew up
with a wood stove I have no interest in
necessarily going back to Wood I think
it's a lovely thing but a lot of people
aren't going to accept that but this
electricity is very useful so we just
have to be clever we've got all kinds of
industries that could use that waste
heat right or we could just uh have
smaller combined heat and Power Systems
all over the place and looking at a
bonson New York City he and I met with
norta a couple of weeks ago to figure
out how you identify locations that have
combined he and Power Systems so that
your electricity is cogenerating your
heat it's very simple and in fact New
York City was based on combined heating
power back in the day but we used coal
which made so much particulate matter
that it was actually powerful to
everybody but we have other fuel choices
and what does it mean when you generate
your electricity and you use your waste
heat you've just reduced your impact by
50% because you lose so much off that
rais teeth right you don't have to lose
another energy source to heat that same
are so I I am very much of the mind that
to provide heat and power not just for
biomass products but for all of our
Energy Products it's a very I don't know
why we
can't um yeah with sort of with the way
that this is set up with growing biomass
and
expg it raises questions for me about
nutrient Cy
um meaning extracting nutrients from the
fields or the for these are okay so in
our analysis that we did at the very
beginning of this presentation and fora
we do replacements for those systems
what that means though at the consumer
end like happens to the nutrients in the
combined he power plant Ash or in the
pelis of Ash that is not Incorporated in
this analysis right so it's not fully
cycling it's just getting nutrients from
another source to maintain the
quity a question about this simple
question one from the right has some
byproduct or product and yet it's used
for PE and sure what that would
be okay so you're talking about yeah the
one that says 26
on right so all of this all of these
co-products up here could easily be
added down here because we're going to
use them okay this is a Hy so the green
is what actually is a product that we're
using in society this could be a product
we're using so like the cellulosic
ethanol
it makes electricity that most
definitely is getting used that's not
the specifically on the heat there are
some like
[Music]
one7
could the is he oh this is waste he
waste heat so in these two scenarios so
the windship plant it used to use the
waste heat to dry paper of a neighboring
paper plant and it doesn't and and then
this scenario um so this is based off of
a combined heat and powered pellet plant
that is done in
as Canada I don't know but they don't
use the waste heat but it's an
industrial site and it could it could be
used J I think what might maybe what
you're getting at is what's the
difference between the primary and the
secondary product for that is cu it says
heat up top
oh okay confus
H so the transportation is it's green
part right here um uh transportation is
a screen part here and then heat is the
green part here and then these are
co-products which are variable according
to each system and they may or may not
be used so in this case the drve dis
stealer strands are used in this case
electricity is used uh
in this case it would be waste heat that
is
not just just for the one he picked out
just explain what the actual scenario is
right okay what what's the product
what's the primary product on the
secondary okay so in this scenario okay
wait I see I
see okay in this scenario we take peled
cellulose we turn it into electricity
you move it through the grid it comes to
your chome and you convert it into heat
at 99% efficiency in your home so that's
the green part this is for clone Heat at
the power plant where you converted it
there's all this waste heat on that all
right and I'm just trying to point out
right this P cellulose right here for
electric ke is the same thing as the p
and cellulose for an electric vehicle so
this column and this column are the same
electricity process and product but
different and usess okay so we're using
19% here in Jing miles and 26 here for
getting deliver to your home
okay I I still think you I mean it seems
like you should
probably um also reduce even the height
of the gray bars according to to the
efficiency of whatever system would be
used for the waste products because that
I think that's a little bit misleading
because if you I mean if the efficiency
for for heat for some heat is only 26% I
mean maybe the efficiency for the waste
product is only 26% that doesn't look as
attractive you know understood saying in
in okay so then I'm opening this up for
suggestions on improving this
graph because actually I love this graph
your s all right um and I did this in a
light gr sort of match this grade
because for all intens and purposes you
know this should be adding up down here
okay CU most of the cases it's not even
being used this is a potential use and
yes there are going to be efficiency
losses but I don't know what those are
but this is the range I get the
criticism I'm totally on board with it
um
that's why the green is
darker yeah so it might be possible to
add another bar in the upper gray if
there are cases where this
is you can identify this is
freeable you know this is actually sort
of this is being done now kind of cost
effectively that might be one way to
say there's some evidence of some small
wheel function with a
laral what is the major limitation as to
why that secondary is not why why are we
calling
it uh
well I'm just going to go back to the
one scenario that I know which is so why
so why did that power plant not why
can't they use it for papers you know I
there was a time when I was really very
long those guys was really fun and
um uh and they just they just wouldn't
they wouldn't doubled and so I don't
know but I think that they really must
something disre because the paper plant
was using the r heat to dry their paper
I mean can you imagine of course when
you make paper it's going to use lots of
heat in order to get all that moisture
off to make papor what a brilliant thing
plus all your waste wood product you go
straight into the biomass net to
generate more electricity I mean it's
it's an industrial
area
gasal
gas yeah I don't I don't know but still
there should be some negotiation about
the price of that was te give so it
seems like there needs to some better
understanding what's going on there why
that they're not going if it comes down
to Greed they're not going to be putting
in gas furnaces to drive their paper if
they can use this at a che okay but the
other scenario I can tell you is for New
York City which used to all be CHP
com but we're running on full and we
moved it out because of a particular so
there's a reason why it's not being used
right that's the reason why it's all
being made at remote power plants where
who cares about
this is exactly my point these are the
problems in doing now meanwhile so the
14th Street in New York City right the
one that went out when we had sanding
and the whole lower half of Manhattan
had no electricity right well that 14th
Street power plant all the way up to
60th Street all the way down to
Chinatown all the we heat the steam
Heats all those
buildings
okay it runs on natural gas so it
doesn't have a particular matter b
and you know it also happens to be very
close
to which is why was a problem you just
made the case of why it is being used I
would like to understand why it's not
what other efficiencies so that was in
the context of historically in the St
in New York City you had all kinds of
combined power plants but they were cold
and the was making too much smoke in the
city with the high density population so
it
out right that is a reason why they from
those old cold PL and longer in the city
we could put in others that are not how
about
smaller Corel Corell comp find heat and
power PL right I mean there's all kinds
of locations there's there's an there's
a ex military building in New York City
which is provide heat power because it
was built in the'
40s and it's 3,000 units and they're off
the great they don't have
oh absolutely but you could also think
that it's a good strategy instead of
having 60 power plants you've got 200
power plants they're smaller and they're
all over the place they're getting much
better overall efficiency you're
collectively burning less fossil fuels
cuz probably for the most part it's
going to be fossil fuel so if you're
using if the waste heat typically is
like 50% of the biomass or the energy
product that goes in is waste heat
you've just reduced your energy Bud
budget by a half because you're no
longer reduplicating the heat lost from
the Electric Plant and the heat used to
hit your Ro so are you saying that
theoretically part of this problem is
because we're power plant that P yes
okay so this is really a locational
problem PL located where they actually
could use that
generation it's also
[Music]
econom they think
so you know I
mean that wood chips why don't we use
the to drrive
chips I think the volume which the chips
go in come out I mean I think they run
out of chips I think that plant has lot
of I
gu operation
years
ago you always had
excess the problem was what you do with
this
heat problem do
electricity but that means that society
and
[Music]
to me what this indicates right is that
this much F or some
fraction if you want to address clate
change right this is a really fast
effective way of doing it I will tell
you for New Year this year I was walking
in my heart and I picked a ro I know I'm
that's in my part but it was an
extraordinary situation so I afforded
myself freedom of picking the rose in my
Park on New Year's Day because until
that
moment I had never conceived of being
able to pick a rose on my birthday now
my birthday is on on New Year's my
birthday is on the 10th and so for the
first time my entire life I maybe I'll
be able to pick a in my birthday didn't
happen we had a huge free spell and all
the verses but the point here is that
we're living in a conceptually different
moment like it was absolutely
inconceivable for me to think the on
myth or on on my birthday it is no
longer an inconceivability because the
system is rapidly changing so if we want
to address climate
change I would argue that looking at the
waste heat from our electricity system
and I don't mean it necessarily has to
be from biomass right clearly I hope you
recognize that all of this biomass right
we could have bucolic Landscapes instead
of 7% of our energy don't you think you
could out 7% of your energy to have
callic
Landscapes right I I I you know these
are real choices that we can actually
make and we're not making those kinds of
choices speaking of choices how do you
put a price or a cost on the ethical
issues of burning
corn so let's burn our food so we can
have M I have no problem with burning
formn because you walk out there today
and if I had to choose like I have
enough calories on my body right now to
make it through the next couple of days
but if I had to be out there with no
heat I would really like to burn that so
like I don't have that issue but I think
the issue is is that corn is so energy
intensive to produce that you could
produce all other kinds of things
alternatively so I don't really think
there's a food and fuel
argument right there's like you could
have corn or you could have corn ethanol
to run in a Hummer you could have an
emaciated dog and he could Chase his
tail seriously that's what we're talking
about so can I just add to
your maybe or maybe I'll subract
kind I mean on a sort of a literal sense
so the calculation of the this large
potential
biomass that's in addition to the food
feed and fiber we're producing in the
state already so we' be growing this
Mar they're not
growing so well it's yeah so it's it's
growing on land that's not currently
producing the product all right now that
doesn't
mean you're still making a choice to use
all that land to produce biomass instead
of additional you know food or food
within within the food
with
theity cor c a
COR okay
yeah corn price wood
pallets and other energy sources and
forms
of but then I well Steve's argument
about using you could sort of extend
that to say using nutrients to produce a
fuel you don't need nutrients in a fuel
but you do in a food or F so could we
change that so then I look to see any of
G anybody in G is
looking breeding corn plant or any grain
you get a lot of grain but no
nutrients so that's the advantage of a
tree right is that the
trunk is it's
not and and this is the disadvantage of
the Agricultural Parts because we them
and actually there there has been a
little bit of done you know starting
workout just
one but I could I got
frustrated I could find no nothing
relevant to L Lang
I mean what you want
[Music]
is we should stop it
here another
hand this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu