this is a production of Cornell
University the library is liaison to
Cooperative Extension so I do a lot of
work with extension Educators around the
state um basically trying to help them
find the information they need to do
their jobs um one of the and what I
think I might do just
briefly um is just show you um an online
guide that I've created it's sort of a I
think it's I think I still call it a
portal but the term portal is like it
sounds like 1995 or something I mean
it's a little but the idea is that it's
a um it's an online resource that's easy
to get to that sort of collects together
a lot of the resources that are
available uh two extension folks um
through through Cornell and through the
library and through me so I think what I
might try to do is share my screen just
to show that briefly give you a kind of
a quick overview of it and then I'll
just open it up to questions and
conversation so here's here's the here's
the portal um which is pretty easy to
find um it's just the URL is up here
guides. library. cornell.edu
CCE uh SL ccore portal you can also do
Cornell Cooperative Extension man
library and I think it'll just Google it
and it'll come up but and I won't go
into too much detail here some of you
actually may have be familiar with this
already but what I try to do here is
collect all the resources and services
that um extension staff have access to
um both um the online resources which
you know I think most everyone in cor
extension unless you're really new you
understand that you are considered a
um a full Cornell staff member in terms
of access to the Cornell resources so
there are a lot of electronic resources
that we Cornell provide
um uh pays a subscription to um and you
can get access to if you're current
Cornell faculty staff or student so that
includes
um all Cooperative Extension staff
members um with a net ID so uh just
again it kind of goes through what you
can do in terms of finding books and
journals a lot of this a lot of these
resources are available online the other
thing to remember for what it's worth is
if you search the Cornell Library online
catalog and find books that are in print
we still have a lot of really high
quality resources that are available in
print um if you find those
uh using our catalog and they're here at
man Library you can actually um order
those and have them delivered through
the mail for free um so it's not just
the electronic resources but they're
actual the print resources the the books
that we have um if you need that and you
you know it's uh not readily available
in your local library um that is an
option and so I think that
is uh overviewed and the it there's
further explanation in the document
delivery section right here there's a
link here under Library services so I
won't go into too much detail about um
that and the final section of and there
you know there's a lot of information
here so when you have some time just go
through it I think you know ultimately
let me go switch back here so I'm kind
of going back and forth um this link my
picture here with my link actually if
you click on it you you can send me an
email so I think if all else f salse or
even from the beginning you're like I
just need help finding information for
this grant I'm putting together or this
you know this program I'm putting
together or I need to do evidence-based
programming that seems to be a big one
um send me an email and I'll I'll either
know the resource uh or the answer or
I'll be able to help you find it um and
I'm going to so that's just on the first
page here it's jpk 15 it's not some
great secret or anything um and then
under tutorials here at the very and
this is where um I I put together this
top 10 things every Cooperative
Extension staff member should know about
the library and this is something I do
in person for new extension uh staff
when they come those who come to campus
um I'll do this in person and kind of go
through it I think for the interest of
time I I won't um what I will tell you
is that each one of these is a link um
to a variety of resources that I these
aren't everything you have have
available obviously you know it's just a
scratching the surface but I think
there's some of the the more important
ones to know from the beginning
including my email right there um I've
also put some guides here which can be
useful uh very specifically focused
guides some of them I've created some of
them U my colleagues have created one of
them
um is this finding funding and this
seems to be in terms of the um training
the web the Outreach I've done to Cooper
extension staff in the last couple of
years the the funding piece not
surprisingly seems to be one of of great
interest and so I I'll just click on
this link here and I I've just recently
let me see if
this um so I've recently just updated
this to
include uh crowdfunding sources of
information which is a relatively new
phenomena um but it's a way of um
basically passing the hat virtually
online and there the Corell library has
some electronic books that you don't
have to check them out you don't have to
order them from the library you can
actually just log on and read
crowdfunding for dummies um so that's
another source traditionally I've
focused on New York State uh US Federal
and private philanthropic um sources of
funding um and I do webinars on the
foundation directory which is the
primary index
to um private and corporate funders the
ones with you know you think Gates you
think Rockefeller um those the big
funding the big sources of um M and
actually the smaller local foundations
um which can have money as well so the
foundation directory is the the most
important source for that sort of
information um and so that link is there
that's a subscription database so it's
not freely available you everyone in
Cooperative Extension does have access
to it um it's it's not that hard to
learn um and there's some online
tutorials and um actually I think we oh
yeah in
2012 I think I gave one of these
webinars and I recorded it so it's like
30 minutes and it I I walked through it
I can't guarantee that it's the most uh
professionally done thing but it gives
you the the basic sense of what it uh
does and of course if you start to use
it and have questions um let me know Jim
hi this is Jen I was I was in a I think
a program program leadership development
cohort and you did you did you kind of
did a sit down with us and helped us um
look through the foundations directory
and set up alert yep yeah because I
think that a lot of us are now spending
a good chunk of time either searching
for funding writing grants or
administering that those grants so I
think um I don't I can speak for myself
that a little bit less time now on
programming a little more time on um
finding funding but then you brought up
a great uh great point is that now as we
are engaging in this funding it is
really important to be able to find
things like evidence-based practices and
that kind of support material for the
grant uh writing that you're doing so um
I I don't even know where to begin with
that you
know right I know it's it's you know you
need the
you need the grant funding to do the
programming and then you need to be able
to um
have you know a plan with evidence of of
your program to get the fund so it's
it's almost this Catch 22 you know like
where do you start do you look for the
and you have to do them both yeah I yeah
absolutely and I think the the
foundation directory and those other
sources are really great to know about
they exist and um you know in terms of
doing the evidence-based and finding the
evidence um I I certainly can I can help
folks with that as well that it's it's
not easy I mean the research I tried to
tell Cornell undergraduates this um and
you know I'm not sure it might go in one
year and out the other but the research
process takes time to do it well to
actually find things it gets better the
more you do it but you know doing
finding that evidence can it's not just
like type it into Google and you know
the top three hits are exactly what you
need to to uh you know right support
what you're doing um but it does get
easier and I I can certainly help um
with that process and maybe save you
some time too okay I think that I think
and also since we are working along you
know within our mission within our
priority areas that sometimes you start
to build
a uh a kind of system of knowledge or a
bunch of ideas of practices and and be
able to follow those down there you know
to try to build a what am I trying to
say almost a library of ideas that you
have now um drawing from for for grant
funding and writing writing those grants
so yeah I mean I I think it's um there
is a there is an opportunity and a
challenge here to tap into the
collective experience of all the
Cooperative Extension Educators across
the state or even Beyond you know about
how is it you successfully go about in
terms of specifically in terms of the
funding how is it that you do that you
know and sometimes you can one of the
things you can do and I think I probably
showed you guys this um for your
leadership cohort you can go into the
foundation directory and um find what
other you know other
County Cooperative Extension agencies
what what grants they've gotten and for
what um so you know but there is this
there is a possibility for this
Collective like you could said a library
of knowledge about how how to do this
well or or even relevant you know papers
that really speak to what we do and um
because there's so many there's so much
out there how do you find you know it's
a
right no it's a huge thing and they're
actually um they're now it's so
important I know here at Cornell I mean
I'm not really knowledgeable about the
whole the the the scholarship behind
like evidencebased methodologies but
they're now offering I think in the
College of human ecology they're
offering a minor in evidence-based
research so it's you know it's like wow
so it's you know it's something that is
obviously being
um you know it's it's being considered
really uh more seriously at that level
well we had recently had kind of funding
uh questions from Partners we work with
and they're coming down kind of above
from from their funders saying you know
we don't really want to uh follow
through with this project if there isn't
an evidence-based practice and they're
not just talking about something that
was just researched they are looking for
something kind of like a cookie cup
program that has been um instituted
somewhere has got good research behind
it and good evidence that it worked you
know that kind of um yeah yeah yeah
right right with a different meaning
than evidence-based that Oh I thought
you know so yeah that is that is really
interesting and the other thing I again
I'm I'm I'm outside the the loop on this
but it also just seems that what works
for in terms of an evid Evidence based
programming for a say a 4 program in
Utah isn't necessarily going to work for
the same 4 program in onandaga county in
New York I mean I just there's all
manner of the notion of a cookie cutter
and one it's it's it's an ambitious um
idea certainly yeah and and conversely
it's kind of throw the baby out with the
bath water if you have a promising
practice something that looks like like
hey you know there's a lot of good
research Behind these ideas let's try it
out but because it doesn't have some
evidence-based um template uh to follow
it's like oh no that's not gonna yeah
exactly I mean I I do this all the time
with my um with my teaching that I work
with faculty um in the two colleges um
cows and human ecology you know and it's
like we're being asked the the library
and the Librarians are being asked to do
more um assessment of what we do do you
know to to actually assess how effective
they are and for
me when the faculty member says if I
talk to the faculty member after the
class and they say you know that's great
that really worked well I mean I think I
can see uh the Stu it was really useful
to the students for me that's that's a
really very that's a primary piece of
assessment of what I did it doesn't
that's not a rubric it doesn't it's not
something I can put in Excel and show
somebody and say 85% of the students who
took my workshop did uh you know uh s
significantly better on their final exam
that's not the level you know but for me
that more qualitative assessment of the
of the word of mouth from the faculty
member is all I need thankfully my
funding is not based on needing to get
those numbers but I think and a lot of
time if people are giving you money they
want the numbers they do they want to be
able to report back and
say so everybody can check off their
little box
yes it's that's a strange uh yeah yeah
not necessarily useful I I understand
what it has to do but in the real world
that that getting getting to people is
what we're we're after right right if
other people are also spending time
Gathering
research um to support their work you
know is there a way we can um uh share
that uh in in a in some Forum or is it
already being done no could right there
you know what I and and the the sharing
what you're basically doing is sharing
um published research on the on this
topic you know
basically um Journal articles is that
what um key research findings is that
the yep so that will be that will be um
okay so what um yeah what I would
recommend and I've worked with um a
number of other either lab groups or um
groups on campus to do this what you can
do is you can start and if you had a
group you don't even have to be in the
same office you don't even have you can
do this online there's a um there's a
program um called zoto it's a free
online program zo t o.org
I and I can I can pull let me actually
see let me see if I can show you an
example
um
Cornell uh uh what's the
um well actually there's one the
um there's oh not survey research that's
so funny um system of R intensification
okay so this is um this is through cfad
and international programs but what they
actually have done is and I've helped
them do this they put together this
online database of research so this is a
not to get in too much detail but the
system of R intensification is a is a
system of increasing the yields of rice
it's fairly controversial um and one of
the things this group wanted to do was
show the evidence speaking of evidence
um from published research on the
effectiveness of this system of growing
rice called SRI or system of rice
indentification so what they did and
I'll actually just do a search for Rice
because um so this is zoto and what
they've done is they've put together
this online library that and they're
probably two or three people in the
group who are administrators Who oversee
this and add material to the library um
and then it's completely open to anybody
in the world um and what it
um it's not the world's greatest
interface but it's very logical that you
know you can organize these the
libraries organized into some subfolders
and then um each one of these is the
link to an article depending on how you
want to do it you can include the full
text of the article um as well and
there's no limit in terms of the number
of people who can be in this group so I
it it works it's a it takes a little bit
to learn program but I think for the
kind of program you're talking about
this this could be a very effective
solution and I if you if you want to
explore it I'm happy to to help you get
um going with
that thanks that is helpful and so is
this a good way if somebody's trying to
research a topic um to sort of uh gather
you know their effort yeah exactly so
what you could do is if there are you
know what I possibly could imagine if
there's a core group of you in the in
your group who are doing the research on
you know a particular topic within your
field um and you wanted to produce
collaboratively this database and share
it among yourselves and then also with
the general public um that's exactly
what you could do so the the
program um let me actually open up um
I'll open so what you do is you have the
program on your individual
computer um and I'll slide this over
here so it's a desktop
program um let me slide this over
here and you work on your own computer
and you you would do your research in
whatever database you like um so this is
my desk this is my desktop version of
zoto um and I've got these folders here
and if I scroll down here when I get
into this section here these are the the
group Library so I can the other nice
thing about this is I can have my
individual research that I collect here
this is only for me and then under here
I have these group libraries that you
could share so if there are say four or
five or six there's no limit on the
number but if if there were four of you
who wanted to create a group Library you
could have I could add um I could do my
own research on this uh you know here's
the group on be's um and if I did my own
research and imported these references
I went and did it um I would add them to
the library here and then the the
program you can see this little arrow is
circling over here what it's doing is
it's syncing with the cloud so what
would happen is the um this B group
online which is what everyone could
access um would be a place where people
could then go and see the results but so
it it works these group libraries work
very well for collaboration between
people and then also sharing that you
can make it you could keep keep it
private if you wanted to and just share
it among your small group um but it it
sounds like you you might also want to
make this um open to the public not that
they could add or edit it but they could
see it and they could download the
program it's you know it's actually very
and you don't need to have the program
uh installed or even know how it works
to be able to go in and um see these see
the results of these you know this is
again this is the online version this is
the this is the desktop version
so one of the questions we often have is
our our um gardening topic area can sort
of Go in all sorts of directions is
there people who could uh you know guide
us on how to sort of
organize um the you know do we have one
big folder or do we is there a
structural way that that seems to work
better than others so in terms of the
you're collecting all the research
yeah because you know we could be in
lots of different fields um you know one
you know we bees is a is a common
pollinators in general as a common topic
and then we can go to the uh a different
area where um as Jen was suggestion you
know childhood obesity and and growing
vegetables
right yeah I was I was going to say I um
I can tell you what the the program can
do here so for example um in this
Cornell conservation agriculture this is
actually the Cornell conservation
agriculture is another example of one of
these working live databases from a a
cow's program um so they create a master
Library called coron conservation
Agriculture and then within that they've
created all these
subfolders that and it can range on
anything um and you know and you can you
can actually so if I look at this this
level if I highlight Cornell
conservation agriculture I'm looking at
everything in the library which is
probably at this point thousands of of
citations and then if I click on one of
these like if I click under cassava I'm
only looking at the uh citations that
have been stored in cassaba you so you
can create all these subfolders and then
you can actually um put a single a
particular citation so this is a journal
article right here um this this
reference could be in more than one of
these folders so you could you could
have as many of these subfolders as you
wanted to um you know I'm not everybody
is tempted to have a folder called
miscellaneous which I think is um
dangerous because it's like I don't know
where but let's put it in miscellanous
and it just ends up being so anyway um
it the the the tools for organizing it
are there um I'm not I would love to be
but I am not personally a a a
particularly organized person so I'm not
sure how that best works it's probably
something for your group to hash out how
this might how this might work but I
think zoto in itself kind of gives you
the ability to at a certain level be um
to be fairly organized about it and then
just to um let me actually see so here
is the system of rice intensification um
and again I'm this is on my desktop what
I'm showing you right now this is the
desktop program
but here's the master folder and then
here are all the subfolders and
everything's doing and then if I go back
here there's exactly so this is this is
the online view this is sort of the
shared view that everyone sees this is
exactly the same thing so here's the
master library and then here are the
subfolders that um have everything there
and you know again you can choose to
make this um include the full full text
of the article if you do that you can't
make it um for copyright reasons
obviously you can't make the folder a
fully public one um you would need to
make a public view would not include the
full text so that's that's a small
consideration but uh but I have a
question about that Jim then would
people be able to like people who are in
the folder be able to print those out or
would they just use them as a reference
and then go find
yeah no they could they could um you
know if they wanted to
um if they wanted to take these you know
if you had the zoto program you could
you could join the group that's the
other thing is you could make it so that
people could join the group and download
um this into their own folder but a lot
of times people are just they they don't
want to be bothered with that so you can
see here I'm pretty sure um if I marked
all these records S I could then export
them and here are different options let
me actually H that may not be the best
that's actually exporting it in a format
let me see if there is a
way to I I think there should be just a
way
to um to print them out if you wanted to
or you know or email them to yourself um
I'll have to look into that but there
there's
definitely um oh this is interesting
um oh okay huh so you can if nothing
else if you wanted to you could do this
quick you could select a style like APA
style and then um do a oops if I
did okay I could just copy them all and
paste them into my you know like a Word
document or something like that but
there has to be an email function here
somewhere I'll have to look into that so
yeah people could print them out people
could email them they should be able to
email themselves and then go um go and
go and find them if they're in the
Cornell Network it's pretty easy to do
it sometimes the like in this case this
is a publicly available um PDF so they
could
just huh well doesn't always work the
way you plan
it yeah
so right URLs
change but a lot of this stuff is
available right through the through men
Library yes Port absolutely yep yep so
that's really cool
yeah I could see that being helpful to a
lot of Educators if that was essentially
it's kind of curated by our needs you
know we we right and each other we
figure it out um but then as we uh come
across these things they could get added
not that we have another another moment
of time to do anything exactly but if
you did I mean if you're doing this
anyway um it will actually save you a
lot of time because all you would then
need to do is and the nice thing is you
can go into your database of choice like
um schol like if I went to to Google
Scholar and I did um uh you know let me
just I'll say community gardening or
something like that I don't
know be helpful if I spelled it right um
but then the nice thing about the the
program is so I'm in Chrome on a
windows-based computer um and I've got
zertero installed and there's this
little folder here so I click on this
and then I can just grab all of those
citations and bring and where they'll
end up I'm not going to bring them in
right now but where they'll end up is in
here so and then I dump them there and
then it's so all I need to do is go to
my database do my search these are
probably things you're doing already as
part of your workflow um you know click
the import which is just clicking a
button uh point it you can either if
you've got the folder highlighted when
you do the import it'll just dump them
right in there and then when you when
this thing syncs which it will do
automatically what so those records I
brought in from Google Scholar um will
then end up in my online library here
automatically shared so you know if
you're just doing a lot of these things
anyway in terms of curating and
collecting the references um it would
once you learn the program and get it
installed and figured out the the
particularities of doing the shared um
management of this you're not really I
don't you're really not adding much in
terms of your workflow and then you're
saving in terms of the export and making
it publicly available and sharing it um
you're saving all your time and not
having to do that part of it um it's
pretty much automated
well I turn it out to to the rest of you
what do you think having that kind of
information like the garden-based
learning page already has some and we I
think a lot of our us as Educators have
tapped into those um articles that are
referenced there but would would having
something like this be helpful as we you
know a defend kind of what it is that we
do you when we talk to others about what
we do and then also as we're writing um
writing Grant
proposals question
mark the other thing I would say just
and this is definitely a conversation
for all of you to have among yourselves
whether this would be an effective tool
um you might want to think about doing
it on a very small scale like create
just like a proof of concept for
yourselves create a small like one
folder with 20 references in it and put
it up and see what it see what it seems
to does it seem to work
um and does it seem like you would want
to put everything you're doing into this
database so you might want to start in a
very small um part of it the other and
um I sound a bit like an infomercial
except I'm not actually selling anything
um the the thing you can also do with
the program which is really nice so for
like grant-based programs is once you
get your um references in here then if
you needed to or if in any situation
where you needed to share these
references um so I'm just going to take
these particular ones here I go if I go
create bibliography from items and I'll
just take
APA um and then if I go
into uh so here's a blank Word document
let me slide this over here um so I
copied those and then I just paste them
in so I've
created you know on the really quickly
um and you could have an annotated
biblography you want but anyway it's a
list of your sources that you could
include in an annual report or a grant
project or whatever you want so once the
information is in here um it's really
easy to produce formatted lists of all
or some of those
references so it's another nice little
uh part of the the workings of the
tool and and on a limited basis we could
just start with um what we already have
on our garden-based learning site and
change that from a list to uh this
actual format uh as it as they did on
the other website I right it might not
be that hard it's it's not I mean what
and again I think what um what I would
encourage you to do and I can help you
guys do this if you want to is take some
of the I mean I think the one that the
thing that would be the um take the most
time and it really wouldn't be that much
time um and it's certainly not
particularly hard is to take the let me
go back to your um so if I go back here
and um if I
am if you're putting together these um
lists of evidence and I'm assuming
down to somewhere do have like a a
bibliography of
these no okay all right so I mean the
other thing too is you can um you okay
so you could create these could all be
yeah um if you're putting these up
anyway and you wanted to make you know
they look like they're basically very
well annotated um citations you could uh
recreate that pretty easily um and the
thing to First do would be to say um you
know you need to get this article from
Ratcliffe from the health promotion
practice uh journal on here and that you
know this is how this would be the only
thing that would take a little bit of
time is you would probably need to go
you could probably just do this
um so there's there's the citation in
Google Scholar um and I would just grab
it
um and bring it in and so you might need
to go a piece at a time um and recreate
your I think it yeah so that that would
be the thing that might take a little
bit of time but how how big is how big
is your library right now many you know
50 to 100 yeah I don't think it's that
big but what I think is happening is um
some Educators might be you know
creating their own little pile of
references and we're not um we don't
have an effective tool to share um and
so if we had that tool like go if you're
doing something already you know share
it with the whole um I'm sure Jen has
done a lot of of of research related to
her pollinator project and you know we
don't have it um in one
place right yeah like Jim does too he's
got a lot in there too I I was like
trying to look oh look at all that stuff
yeah I know it's like it's really easy
to add it's like then you're like oh my
gosh and there's no unlike like your
your front hall closet there's no
shortage it's like was there too many
shoes in here it's just like nope you
just you don't run out of room you just
keep putting stuff in there which can be
a curse as well as a blessing I guess
right um so I mean and the other thing
too is if you've done all that really it
looks like um you've done uh great work
with these annotations so you could you
could pretty easily copy these so in
addition to the like the basic citation
information that you would import here
um you can add your own field you could
add you that exactly you could go into
zoto and put in let me cancel this you
could put in your own
um so here here actually is the article
let me get this a little more okay so
here's the article and
then
so here's the citation over here and
then you could put it in um like in the
abstract
field
um you you just copy and paste it in
there this would be a I'm it would be a
really good project for like an intern
yeah that's what I'm
thinking interest just and then you
would just use a a uh a style on your
website that would have that would
include include the abstract and you're
it would kind of be there it wouldn't
flow as a narrative like this does I
mean that would be the one thing
obviously is I me um you know this is
has a nice narrative flow to it um this
would be more like citation uh abstract
citation abstract but you know people
can live with
that I suppose so so if you guys want to
I know talk among yourselves and see if
that might want to work um I'm you know
send me an email I'm around um and I'm
happy to you know help you get started
um it's it's not it's not particularly
hard there's a little bit of um a little
bit of things to figure out um and I
know everybody's really pressed for time
but I think if you're putting these
things together anyway right um
especially if you have this feeling that
there might be other people out there
who are also collecting this information
you could just add them if you wanted to
if you trusted them you could add them
as editors to the um the library and
then they could um add to it um or they
could just send you what they have and
you could add it um as well so okay um
we're we are kind of experimenting with
something along those lines already in a
small scale to see if that would work
because we are all working on the same
things and it's crazy to keep
Reinventing the wheel um and I know that
initially there would be that big time
output you know outlay but then time it
would become more and more efficient and
hopefully we'd see that on that back end
when those resources are all gathered
for us right right and the other nice
thing too is if you're putting this all
like all these list of
references um in a in a essentially a
database so if your if your website
changed you again you're just pointing
to this online site that's not going to
change um so you could just link to it
and yeah so
thanks I think that was really helpful
uh um sure um to get us organized on
that on that level and basically you
know we're always um eager to find ways
to make it easy for people to explain
why we are
important right right right that's an
ongoing right you guys know you're
important but exactly one of the things
that we have which I think is kind of
it's it is essentially a credibility
checklist I'm going to back and I'll
just I'll show it to you quickly and um
this everything I'm showing you now is
you know it's open it's an open resource
so you could either modify it and adapt
it to your own use or um just point
people to it there's this section on
evaluating credibility which you know we
we teach this to undergraduates and
actually it's it seems a little
simplistic but it's amazing how if you
just tell people okay so you pulled up a
website um can you identify the
author um of this particular article and
what is his or her credentials just by
asking them to ask themselves that
question you realize most of the time
they don't even ask that they don't even
say well it's like oh well it's a
website it's like well who wrote this
and if you can't find an author um
that's probably a red flag and so you
kind of go through and the authority the
currency the purpose the bias the
accuracy of details and you can this is
kind of a a really kind of a mini thing
that you could you could put this
together in a little Tip Sheet um and um
say if you find a reference on the web
just do this five part checklist and see
what you can do if you wanted to go into
more detail um UC see Berkeley let me
see I haven't looked at this in a while
see if the link still works yeah their
Library goes through this in like
extensive detail so this is sort of the
the full um the fullon way to and this
is usually for evaluating credibility
for um web-based resources it you know
it's not really so much for you found
you were searching in a database and you
found a scholarly article it's more like
you Googled the topic and you came
across this and it's just a way you sort
of keep it in the back of your mind it's
like what's the authority what's the
purpose what um when was this is there
is there a list of references there is
there a date it was last updated um
those so there's little things there
that um that exist I I'm I don't know if
that helps but that's that's there and
you can feel free to borrow as much or
as little of this um so if you wanted to
create a little Tip Sheet for uh the
public on this and you included here's
your here five questions to ask in terms
of credibility and then you could add
the tip that and I think some people
know this but a lot of people people
don't um which is that there is
um
uh there's an advanced Google search
where if you go into this you can
actually so it it allows you to string
your search together a little bit better
which is helpful but the other thing too
is you can
um you can
actually go and search by specific
domains so you know for example if you
were looking
for um compost if I looked for compost
and just did a Google search I'm
probably going to get mostly sites that
want to sell me compost correct um or
something like that but one of the
things you can do um if I limited that
to just as an example um if I limited
compost to do edu you're mostly going to
get know in this case I'm getting um
either EPA or Coral Cooperative
Extension um sites that or the
University of Missouri um so if I if I
limit it my search to an
edu um I'm gonna I'm G to filter out
immediately um the commercial sites that
are selling compost and and you could
ALS you don't even have to send them to
the advanced search you could just say
um you put in your search and at the end
do
site.edu
if people get into the habit of just
instead of throwing the net out in the
lake and pulling back whatever they find
is like oh why don't you throw out the
net that will only bring back.org stuff
or only edu stuff with visual resources
how to um use those resources in a way
that U makes
you safe and legal in terms of fair use
and those kind of things so that would
and I can this this is actually a
subsection of a guide um oh here's yeah
actually I think this is actually quite
useful this is the one I was thinking of
image is a guide defining visual
resources so this is this is fully
available public anybody can get access
to this and it includes a section on um
copyright um what is fair use the other
thing you can do in terms of if you're a
staff member if you're actually a um if
you're Cornell Affiliated there's also
if you have specific questions so this
this kind of gives you the guide and you
can walk through this and it'll answer
most of your questions but if you had
maybe a a a more specific question and
wanted some guidance there is actually a
um there's a visual
resources uh working group within the
Cornell library that will answer that
would be happy to work with any coop
operative extension staff members um
those image databases we could freely
use from yeah exactly I mean they're
going to tell you some of these are
going to be subscription databases and
some of them are going to be um freely
available um databases um oh I guess if
there's subscription if there's
subscription does Cornell have the
subscription right exactly okay yep and
so an educator could could get access
they yes and so anything here Cornell
specific or not like art store is a
database that you need to be affiliated
with Cornell to get access to um but
they have this whole section on open web
which these are all freely available uh
anybody can get access to them if you or
anybody else um has any uh questions and
then specifically about setting up the
Zoro database when you uh if you think
you guys want to do that um I'm I'm
happy to uh get you started this has
been a production of Cornell University
on the web at cornell.edu