this is a production of Cornell
University okay thank you Bill and thank
you Liam for the instruction and also
thank you uh everybody for coming to my
talk so here's the title of my talk
understanding the molecular mechanisms
underlying Al luminant resistance in
plan uh so my topic is about aluminum
toxicity aluminum toxicity is tightly
associated with acid soil the reason is
that aluminum is the most abundant
metals on the earth Crest and neutral pH
aluminum is tightly BN to the soil CLS
which is not toxic to
plant however under acid soil condition
the toxic Al luminance species so that's
al3+ will release from the soil clim
into soil solution which is highly toxic
to plan root growth here shows the map
of word ay soils so you can see the acid
soil which is in red color is widely
distributed around the world with a
significant fraction in the de uh
developing countries in the Tropic and
subtropics so there is really a need to
understand the molecular magnetisms
underlying or magnets underlying
aluminum resistance in crops in order to
further enhance resistance to acid soil
for
crop so this slide shows the toxic
effects of aluminum on two wheat l so
when it's a ETA that's aluminum torent
and Esa this aluminum sensitive as you
can see under neutral pH there's no
difference uh in R growth between these
two lines however under A6 so condition
you can see this sensitive line the root
gr was completely
inhibited with stuned and damaged root
growth so the problem of aluminum
toxicity is so privileged in developing
country so it is the major limitation
for cor Crop Production on acid
soil so also from this slide you can see
U the genetic variation in terms of
aluminum resistance so this is the focus
for our study and this is also the uh
basis for plant breeding
purposes so in today today's talk I will
first briefly introduce the
strategies adopted by plans to cope with
aluminum stress and then I will
highlight some efforts in my group to
unveil how plans use these strategies to
achieve aluminum
resistance uh okay so here's the diagram
of a plant so this the RO and the above
uh part and this part is a um
magnification of the root especially the
root tape region so root tape is the
target for aluminum toxicity so it's
most sensitive to aluminum Jazz so
here's the risos spere and here's a
diagram for the uh root epidermal cells
with a plasma membrane the membrane of
VOR and a cell world
so the widely and most uh
documented magnet for Al luminant
resistance is the exclusion or avoidant
avoidance magism which prevents aluminum
from getting into the root cells so this
is done by uh the release of the root
cells of uh organic acid such as melee C
CH into the risos where the organic
gases can form
non-toxic uh OA aluminum complex that
cannot be get into the cell so it's like
exclusion so that's the first magn the
second
magnet uh the second magism deal with
the aluminum that enters into uh the
root cells so this aluminum can be
either sequestered into the vacu or can
be transl located from the roof to the
shoot so the shoes is less sensitive to
Al luminance
ja so recently increasing lines of
evidence indicate that modification of a
Cell World structure and function could
be a uh critical uh step for Al luminant
resistance in plants so I also focus on
that in my later talk
so here comes the second part of my talk
so I will uh highlight some effers in my
group
for for the uh aluminum exclusion
mechanisms in Swan and true aluminum
resistant uh in abodes and finally I
will uh report on some of our progress
in understanding the regulatory or
signaling pathway involving resistant to
low ph and aluminate stress in
arabidopsis so here comes the first
part so this shows uh the root growth of
two San lines one is tolerant
SC2 83 and the sensitive
br7 on the uh low PH plus aluminum
solution so you can see
the root growth of the T lines has no
effect but you can see stunted and
damaged rout for the sensitive
lines and this is the work done by
Jura uh mes so he's a former PhD student
uh for lion and um now he's a close
collaborator for for our group
also so also he found that the
um the very close correlation between
the uh aluminum activated C release from
the torrent
line and aluminum resistance so there's
no uh or organic acid released from the
sensitive line Wass the uh the T line
and this Line's very sens sensitive so
here the summary for the relationship
between uh alumin Torrance
and uh root SE tray release so here
shows the uh the torrent line growth uh
with or without Al luminance so this the
control and the treatment in a period of
uh six days aluminum treatment so you
can see the first day uh the root growth
of even for the root growth of the
torent line
so it was uh inhibited by about 50%
compared to the uh control so it
continued being inhibited at this level
but on the third day of treatment you
can see uh gradually uh increase of root
gr and by the fourth day you see there's
no difference between uh the treatment
and the control and this process very
closely and positively correlated with
the root uh C release in the torent line
so you see without aluman you don't see
any c release but with aluminum so the
uh you can see gradually induction of C
release so by the I mean the third
day uh there's much more C release and
then this correspondent to the increase
of root growth so by the time of the six
day the huge amount of
uh SE release from the root tip and you
can see fully recovery of the root
growth in the torrent line in conest in
the sensitive line you never seen any uh
C release from the root with or without
aluminum and actually the root grows
never recover from the
treatment and based on that uh Jura he
did a uh K mapping project and he
actually um m
the aluminum resistant Locus into one
single bag so then I uh come into Leon
SL and Jura graduate and so we further
collab on collaborate on that project
and also by the way I mean uh he also
did the uh correlation analysis for uh
Cate release and aluminum Torance for a
small panel of swans so this 10 a
section what he found is the SE trate
release is positively correlated with uh
aluminum Torrance among the uh this ass
section and
also so we finally CL the the gene the
resistant Gene it encodes a swan a
member of swan MJ and toxic compound
Extrusion so Gene so we demonstrate that
uh so this SP made Gene actually encode
the alumin activated C transporter in uh
in Swan and the expression of s SP is
positively correlated with aluminum
Torance as well as C release in the same
uh Swan assession panel I mentioned in
the previous slide
so here comes the problem
so what is a trade out for using SE
trade as a weapon for aluminum
resistance it's very obviously that's a
carbon cost so uh so for plants best
benefit is to use minimum amount of
C uh to achieve maximum um uh aluminum
tolerance so that's deal with the carbon
use efficiency
uh so how can swan achieve this the
one way is
to uh specialy the expression of s Spate
gene expression so we can see uh SB ma
is only is made Express in the root tipe
region so that's the the region most
sensitive to aluminum and that's the one
that need most
protection and not only that I mean if
you uh we also do the um imun
localization and LCM the laso dissection
microscope uh real time PCR actually the
as B made protein and uh transcription
is only expressed in the very defined
region like uh epidermal cells and the
first layer of uh cortex so that's
Define the sitro release only in that
part of the plan uh rout
issue so is that enough so
the uh question is not the reason is
that the acid soil is on uh in reality
is not a uh
homogenous yeah property actually is
quite hetrogeneous uh in distribution so
here shows a an acid soil uh field in
Australia so the red color indicate that
uh the soil is highly acidic but you see
not far away mean there's some uh
some s region that's high either neutral
or even alkaline so so that's in the XY
Dimension but if you look at the the
Third Dimension the vertical Dimension
so you can see also very uh lot of
variation usually I mean the top soilers
are less aluminum uh toxicity than the
Deep Cell uh deep soil and
also when the plants grow from the top
soil into the deep soil so so plant
roots are grows as a tip growth uh Mana
so whenever he goes it's like constantly
meet uh the change of soil
environment so the question is how do PL
R since the
frequent uh changes in aluminum toxicity
and how it
react so that's the uh question we want
to
address
and so to answer this question in in
swen I actually um transform the spma
gene into East East has no homologue of
SP mag in is a genome so without
aluminum you see no uh with without
aluminum signal uh C release which is
mediate by SB made but with the SB made
expression is you can see the uh
constit is uh release of C trate with or
without aluminum so this is very
different for what we have seen in h
Swan so which uh so the six release is
actually activated only activated by
aluminous G test so no release uh under
control so this suggest there must have
some uh negative regulator for SB
made uh in plans so that's lead to uh
led to uh my
second uh work here so so I think and
then I decided to use the split ubiqutin
is two hybrid systems so be because I
use that uh because SP Spate is a
membrane protein so I have to use this U
syst is to hybrid system to screen um a
library that made from the s r tip and I
found a very strong candidate uh
interacting protein so it's a putative
metal binding protein so here we call in
as
MBP as a strong candidate for the uh SB
made interacting
component so what happen if we co
transform uh these two component into
East actually we see the um
reconstitution of aluminum activated SEC
release as we seen uh in
Swan so here is the single SB made uh
trans
transformed and you see constitu large
amount of C release was the uh very
controlled and aluminum activated C
release in the uh double
transforming so the question is uh the C
is the I mean organic acid that binds to
aluminum so it's a foundation for
aluminum resistant so what what's the um
aluminum Torance of this two line with
this one has higher amount of cated
can achieve higher degree of aluminum
resistance or not so here is the next
experiment for uh
testing uh relative growth or aluminum
Torance for three different east line so
this the uh East just transform with
empty Vector so you see that's very
sensitive to aluminum but the uh single
transform that uh the growth geometric
increase but it's not as good as the uh
double transform so we remember I mean
this line has huge amount of citrate
released so we thought oh it could be re
reach a higher degree of aluminum
resistance but actually it's not the
reason is that the carbon cost that's
too much and then actually inhibit uh
cell growth
very sensitive so here comes uh the
working model for how this two component
work together to achieve aluminum
activated uh C isolation so here is the
plasma membrane of the loot epidermal
cells and sbma is a uh C
transporter and MBP is a negative
regulator for SB mate so without Al
luminant it tightly binds to the uh
permeation pathway of uh the C
transporter so which can block the C
release from sale uh the cytool into uh
risos speld and nppp is a aluminum
binding protein under acidic condition
you uh npv binds to aluminum and change
its uh confirmation and also its
Affinity to
um s spma would be decrease and this
will lead to um dissociation or partial
dissociation of MBP from the sbma so
leading to opening of the C isation
perme permeation pathway so leading to
the exultation of um C
release okay so so next would be to uh
to address this model we need to confirm
uh yeah three things one is MVP is
aluminum binding protein and also the
binding to aluminum can disrupt the uh
MVP and SB made
interaction so here's the work by uh
Michael Lee so I think he's also in the
audience and so here's is the P down
essay to demonstrate that uh MBP is a pH
dependent aluminum binding floting so
here is just the beads you see there's
no uh binding of aluminum to uh to
binding of the MVP to the beads so that
mean any binding here is specific and
also uh under uh the treatment we only
see The Binding of mbp2 um aluminum the
aluminum beads at the low PH but not in
the neutral pH so
that's uh confirmed that MBP is a pH
dependent uh aluminum binding protein
and second we need to demonstrate that
uh aluminum binding to MBP can disrupt
uh mppp and SB made interaction so here
is the invidual pull down essay so you
can see under the neutral pH so it with
uh with the in presence or in absence of
aluminum so there's always strong
interaction between SB mate and um SB
MVP here right however under the low PH
without aluminum we can see a little bit
decrease of uh interaction of these two
component but when Al luminance was
added you see there's no interaction
that mean that's completely dissociated
with these two uh uh two
component so that's invivo and then I
did uh the invivo
BFC uh interaction so that's a system
that tested for interaction of two uh
proteins if there's protein protein
interaction you will see fesen and if
the interaction was disrupted you will
see decrease of the uh florescent signal
so so that's the uh BFC and then uh this
movie shows what happened after aluminum
was added so this the tobacco epidermal
leaf
cell yeah I mean it's quite rapid
process about 2 and a half hours you see
almost completely dis uh disappearance
of the uh floresent so okay what's the
uh control so this a control that just
um eject the buffer but without aluminum
and with the same period time of
recording
yeah see the difference so
uh so that demonstrate that uh the
interaction
of uh Al luminant I mean uh SB made MBP
was disrupted by adding aluminum so so
in previous slide we demonstrated that
MBP is a uh aluminum binding protein and
binding of aluminum could cause
dissociation of MVP and SB made
interaction so pretty much d uh confront
our
hypothesis so here comes the uh the
second
of part so it's deal with the true t in
alop
CICS so so it's this part so deal within
uh remove Al
luminant from cell into cytosol so cell
is a very important organ for in in
aluminum Torance so it's estimated that
90% of the AL luminant in Roots was
accumulated in cell world so in
increasing number of um
increasing uh blindes of evidence
indicate that modification of cell World
components could be a very important uh
plays a very important role in alumin
resistance so um the true
Torance magnet inward like two parts one
is move aluminum into the um cytool
followed by
uh
sequester sequestration into the VAC or
translocate into um the above ground
tissues so in fact in in plants there's
a specific class of um uh that actually
they like aluminum so this the So-Cal
aluminum accumulate plant species so
including like uh tea buckweed and hyena
so they tend to uptake larger amount of
aluminum from the soil and um
translocate into
the uh shoot tissue and store the
aluminum in the
VAC
so so this photo shows
um Hyer plant in the uh in front of
wagamans in the next early spring yeah
so you can see there um the some of them
produce uh blue flowers with some uh
sometimes red flowers but I can tell you
they all have the same genetics so that
mean the flower uh color change is due
to environment environmental effects but
not genetic effects actually it's it's
on the uh assist of soil so the the one
on the left that's grew in the acid soil
so that produce uh the blue flour was
the neutral pH uh soil you see the uh
produce red
flow so so here's a close up for the
very beautiful I think yeah and actually
the only difference uh there's a a group
in Japan they they are horticulture they
actually analyze what's going on here
they found that actually the uh only
difference for for the these two flowers
is that uh this one the the blue one
they accumulate high amount of
aluminum in the uh seot I mean what we
see actually is a seot is not pattern
atse the uh the red red color
flow and then actually they um the
reason is that uh under neutral
pH so this the uh ening accumulated in
the VAC so called uh they fing 3
glucoside so it has a native red color
but under soil acidic soil condition
aluminum will be accumulated into the uh
V which combines to the aning and turn
its color into blue that's the uh secret
of that magic and actually they CL this
two uh transporter so one is responsible
for the uh moving of aluminum into the
cytosol so that's plasma membrane
localized they called um part or plasma
membrane localized aluminum
transporter and the the one responsible
for um Vora transporter is called V or
Vora AUM
transporter both these genes are belong
to um the eoin gene family so
aquaporin it's a very large uh Gene
family in plants so like they have 35
members in idopy and 33 in
rice and also EOP tend to transport uh
neutral solo
um because and also I mean uh port and W
are the first members of EOP poring
demonstrate that um be able to transport
aluminum so that's the uh quite
interesting for us uh working on
aluminum uh
resistance so the question although they
demonstrate that this genes function in
aluminum transporter but they we don't
know if they have any function in
aluminum Torance imp
plant and because the part is the plasma
membrane localized uh aluminum
transporter and which is could be a
critical component for uh aluminum
uptake in uh in Roots so I we decid to
focus uh to study the the port homolog
in
arsic
and hm p is closely related to the nip
sub family in uh in apopsis nip stands
for the nerine 26 in chinc
protein so this uh work was done lead
led by H1
and also we screen the library for the N
member of the nip nips in epops and
found out that uh nip 1-2 actually has
the hypers sensitive
phenotype uh to aluminum just when it's
Bress in East so here's the uh control
and the treatment and also we include uh
we included and red one so it's a famous
uh aluminum
transporter uh localized in the r cell
plasma membrane so this word are been
done by Jon in Leon
SCP and we can see hyper sensitive of uh
nip 1-2 to aluminum but it's the
sensitivity is not as strong as um the
Andro one indicated that but probably I
mean the nip 1-2 the capacity is lower
than uh And1 in terms of aluminum
transport and also each test the
aluminum accumulation in the three east
line we can see um the hyper
accumulation of aluminum in the uh nip
one- two expiration east line but the
amount is not as high as uh the and one
further indicating that the capacity of
nip 1-2
transporter aluminum transporter might
be it's lower than and red
one also uh each test the subed
localization of nip 1-2 he made uh the
gfp fusion protein and this slide shows
the
uh localization of diffusion protein so
it's in the plasma membrane and this
further demonstrate by the uh di dii
stain so it's very clear localized on
the plasma membrane for this
protein and nip one-2 is only made
Express on the root but not in shoe so
that's the uh
rtpcr and also this the real time PCR
and see the induction of of nip 1-2 is
brushing by aluminum so after 4 hours of
aluminum treatment so it reach the
maximum level and uh decrease a little
bit and
also nip 1-2 expression is specifically
induced by aluminum treatment but not by
other metal uh stress as well as by the
low uh pH
treatment so here's the uh teaches
specific localization of uh nip 1-2 so
this the gas uh analysis so you can see
uh nip 1-2 is mly Express in the root
tape region of uh the main the primary
and lateral root and so also the you see
the gas stainings was enhanced by
aluminum treatment so you can see the uh
not only inhance also but the region I
mean going up and down
so what's the phenotype for for the nip
1-2 mutant in uh in terms of
aluminum uh Torance so here shows that
the nip 1-2 so we acquire three
independent tdna insertion line from ABC
and can see uh all of them are hyper
sensitive to uh to aluminum treatment
compared to the wild type
so here is the wild type and the
significant decrease of uh the root grth
for uh two representative
line and so we try to understand the
magnesense why nip 1-2 it's can uh it's
function in aluminum Torance so one
thing is so we U measure I mean
stain uh the wild type and nip one-2
mutant with uh hoseline so this the D
that stained aluminum in the cell only
in the cell but not in the cytosol what
we can see there's almost no staining
without aluminum but strong staining in
the root uh tip region for the wild TI
but the uh the strength of the standing
much um higher in the uh mutant line so
that suggest there more aluminum was
accumulated in the mutant than the wild
type so here is the quantification for
this uh experiment we see compared to
the wild type and the mutant uh the
mutant tends to accumulate more aluminum
in the side uh C but in the cyos it
reverse I mean we see less aluminum was
transported into the um cyto so that
suggest I mean uh
nip 1-2 is a aluminum transporter
responsible for uh uptake of
aluminum into the
cytool uh so here's the working model
for uh for this
part yeah so
the and nip 1-2 responsible for aluminum
uptake from C wall or from the
um risos spere and then move
to uh to the pericycle through the same
plastic FL so we don't know if n u nip
1-2 is also responsible for the silent
uptate or it could but it could have
some other components but definitely
it's uh involved in the aluminum
translocation from rout to shoe I didn't
show the slide I mean we we found that
actually the uh aluminum content in the
shield for the um mutant is less than
than the in the wild wild
tydee yeah so this slight summarize alop
aluminum tance actually Aldis has adopt
the exclusion mechnisms that's involve
the release of Mele Cay and also we
demonstrate that uh the true Torance
magazines also function in arabidopsis
and also um in shaen Jen group in Jang
University they have done lot of work on
the S part so so it's a small plan it's
not very tolerant to uh aluminum but it
has almost every no mechnism for
aluminum
resistance okay the last part uh I will
briefly report uh our some progress in
dissecting regulatory Pathways uh
involved in resistant to low ph and
aluminum stress in
apopsis so in apopsis in kayamas group
they identify a um mutant that
highly um sensitive to low PH so only to
low uh low per that's what they screen
uh for and then they colog this G uh it
they call the stop one it's encodes a
sing fingle transcription Factor
actually it's a master transcription
factor that can show many of uh the now
very very now alumin resistant Gene like
uh at amt1 that's a melee transporter
and at M is C transporter and A3 also
very important but we don't know exactly
how it function so probably it's
function in the junction of alum Torance
and
fosho uh deficiency yeah resistance so
it's a master uh
signal uh transcription fact Factor so
in this part is this work is led by F
Jang who is a uh twoyear visiting uh
graduate student I mean it's very
amazing as you can see uh in later has
made lot of progress so the this the uh
the possible signaling pathway for uh
for the St on
controlled uh system so we we know stop
one if you knock it out it's hyp
sensitive to low PH but also all these
genes are are knock down knock out
and and there also hypersensitive hypers
sensitive to
aluminum uh toxicity but we know these
two process are independent the reason
is that uh all of these mutant they are
not hypers sensitive to low PH so they
are separate so and in this word we try
to find uh the some component in any of
this uh
path so we're using traditional
um classic genetics to screen reverance
for the uh s the stop one uh phenotype
phal type so here the result I mean this
a wild type under low ph and uh the stop
one mutants hypers sensitive to to to
low ph and this the stop one revert and
you see uh it's not completely revertant
but as says 80% or 70% are are reverent
in terms of root
growth and here's some of the uh
putative
mutant uh for the revertant
and then we try to test their response
to different uh stress one uh like
aluminum you see some of the rant it's
actually it's more resistant to um to
aluminum compared to the uh it's
parine and some of hyp sensitive to
sodian and resistant to C cium compared
to the even to the wild type but some of
this are very sensitive to camian so
there we don't know what what's going on
now and then uh fan decided to uh clone
one of these genes with the uh n gam
sequencing approaches so this the the
reverton so Andross with the stop one
mutant and in in the F2 population so
for the long route was the uh short
route and exra DNA make Library
sequencing n and sequencing and can find
the U putative
snip to uh associate with the different
phenotype and the last step would be uh
verif verify the uh if that's really the
positive snip so here's the the the
result the W type and uh the hyper
sensitive of stop one and root growth at
the low ph
and this the uh the
revertant so and so we know this Gene
and then we can order U the tdna
insertion line on this uh for this Gene
and actually uh the TDN is not sensitive
to um to low PH stress so what if we
incorporate the tdna the dis mutant into
the uh stub one background could we see
any reverting phenotype as the uh the
EMS M mutant mutation yeah actually it
is I mean there's almost no difference
between uh the EMS generated mutant and
the tdna uh insertion mutant in the St
one background so pretty much we think
we we uh find out this
G and finally that's uh the last slide
and I would like first thank Leah yeah
that's I mean I can express more my uh
opeation for him so first uh I work with
as a poster as he uh mentioned and also
he had me as a uh s and work on this
project I mean we have 10 years work uh
experience but I'm sorry he's living but
I think we are still um collaborate I
mean close uh collaborate in the F
future and here's the work I mean uh
the the member in the group that work uh
in this project I'm sorry I cannot uh
present all of their work and also Jang
and Arif uh his um and also thanks for
the collaborator and the F founding
agency
and and also uh I can so this the
Michael he work for the uh most of the
protein part of work and Y uh he led the
uh nip 1-2 project and fan is a two-year
visiting uh graduate student from
Chinese Academy of Science so so he's
living I mean in the summer but he let
the uh the stop one reverting project so
it's very amazing yeah only two years
yeah yeah thank you for your attention
so I would like to answer questions
[Applause]
is there uh any indication that um that
there's any sort of signal from the
shoot coming back down to
the uh that's a tough question yeah we
we haven't looking that yeah yeah um no
I I don't know that yeah yeah could be
but mainly I mean the um the toxicity of
aluminum is maybe Target at the
Ro region actually Shield is much much
less sensitive to to aluminous ja and
some and I know some of the pl species
like uh the aluminum accumulator like
tea like baky they actually like uh acid
soil they grew better in in the acid
soil environment what they did is like
uh upate large amount of
Alum uh from the soil and then
translocated into the shoe like uh the
VAC of shoe tissues so I I don't I think
I don't know how this shoes signal can
coming back to yeah probably more
important for for the root than Sho yeah
knowing your your field of research um
thinking not just signal but photosynthe
for the situ organic acid releasing
we've always wondered if you know you
get more photosyn going to those roots I
think we can finally look at that
um I where I'm going to have we can C1
label plants have aiss tography so we
can image the carbon coming
photosynthetic going to the roots at the
same time we can image you know roots
and challenge them aluminum and see if
that or say just a specific room see if
that CH that you see because I've always
wondered is that going to turn on lot of
signal but photosynthate coming down
there so because you are losing although
the plant as you said
minimize how much it loses by having it
just in that little area so but it's
something we're going be able to look at
how much is it I me what what what what
amount of carbon is being exported into
the soil do you have any
idea um so we haven't I don't know if
you have any quantification but uh
actually we we saw indirectly yeah uh
the carbon loss
actually affect R growth yeah because we
have the over expression line or the uh
melee or C release and without Al
luminant so the growth actually is not
as good as the uh nonch genic line
suggest uh it has some NE yeah
definitely has a negative impact on the
gluc
so fact varies from spe to spe sorum
seems to be really localized rabbit op
seems to be more spread out so like us
rabbit opsis overexpresses these
Transporters without it's still release
a mod they don't grow as well well it's
depend on sink strength
and you know I think the biggest the
most dramatic I don't needan to you know
example of this though is the lubens
under efficiency in the in the hairy
Roots they can release 30% of the carbon
citrate but that's not a crop plant
though you know it's a it's just
survival shut
up so this might be a silic question but
does the when PL roads in acidic
conditions does the pH of the epidermal
cells in the root change does it drop do
epidermal you mean oh yeah I mean the
morphology does lots of morphological
Chang not the morphology but the PH does
it all when you're releasing the citate
yeah I mean that's that's a tough
question so we really wondering what
what's the pH what's the form of
aluminum being transport uh from so to
uh cyos definitely I the aluminum effect
has to be uh at the low PH that but we
don't know I mean the probably the micro
environment could be very different so
here as to um the idal C so it would
seem like the interface of the membrane
would have to be acidified for the
effect to
happen think about
your acid
chemistry you got that citrate sit a pH
7.4 C so it's actually least is the
Bas on the outside but once it comes out
it's if anything's going to bind yeah
yeah see this is something I yelled at
marshner about in his text actually I
have a book autograph from Leon remember
none of us are right all the time or
something like that because he says
organic acid release acidifies and it
doesn't because you're not releasing the
acid you're releasing the base it's
already lost its protons in the
cytoplasm anything might raise them by
releasing the protons in the cytoplasm
de cify the that region of the cytoplasm
you
think some seem to prefer a set of pH
like blueberries um do you think they
use the same
mechanisms the blueberry for they prefer
low low PH oh I didn't could be I mean
some of the um
yeah aluminum could have some beneficial
effect I I read some paper
yeah don't
anybody T too t yeah t yeah that's also
I I that the um aluminum accumulation in
tea mostly in the old V so you buy tea
by good
quality that might explain some of the
behavior of the British
that actually
concern scare about
that I know a lot of the tea in China
like gr around University that's
yeah that's green tea so it's the fresh
the young green tea yeah I mean the
younger they actually less
any other
questions join me in
thaning this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu