this is a production of Cornell
University good afternoon everyone thank
you so much Katie for the introduction
um and I would like to thank the chairs
for the invitation uh unfortunately I
couldn't uh do the seminar in person but
I'm excited uh to be sharing with you
today our uh ongoing research on the
secure ecosystem engineering and design
to mitigate the impacts of uh non-native
fungal path
on manag
ecosystems um so as Katie already
presented I'm an early career staff
scientist at oid National Lab for those
of you who don't know I put the map uh
the lab is located in East Tennessee and
I put as as reference Atlanta which is
two and a half hours drive uh from okd
um and here's a picture of our um C
campus where Cutting Edge research meets
uh natural beauty um I want to just give
two fun facts about uh ORNL um so the
lab has played an important role in the
discovery of tennessine adding a unique
element um to the periodic table also
it's the proud home of Frontier which is
the world's fast
supercomputer um so at ORNL uh we focus
on delivering um scientific discoveries
to ensure um the United States security
and prosperity by addressing uh
different challenges uh rang ing from
energy environmental and security
challenges another fun fact many are
surprised to learn that at ORNL we
actually conduct fungal research because
when they think of National Labs ORNL or
other National Labs they think that just
do like nuclear science nuclear
engineering or Material Science uh but
the fact that we actually have a
bioscience division is surprising for a
lot of people um actually my colleague
Dr Tomas rash who I actually met at w
medicon he was also in the Plant
Pathology Department uh with Katie uh
and and I we both corun the fungal lab
and the fungal program at ORNL uh
tomas's research mainly focusing on
fungal interactions and biotechnology
whereas my research as a fungal
geneticist and biologist focus on
developing Advanced genetic engineering
tools to UNL to unlock the potential of
fungi for sustainable application PS and
here are pictures from our busy lab this
past
summer um the research I will be
discussing in my seminar today is part
of the secure ecosystem engineering and
design short for seed Science Focus area
so in this SFA we drive Innovative
Science and Technology to be able to
understand and man manipulate how
microorganisms can either be bacteria or
fungi which is our Focus are able to to
establish spread and how they are
impacting ecosystems that are critical
or of high importance for the US
Department of energy so here's the
outline of my talk today so first I will
start by giving um a brief overview
about the pathos system that we focus on
within our csfa trying um to further
understand it I will highlight the
critical knowledge of gaps mainly when
it comes to understanding um the
molecular mechanisms of responsible for
the pathogenicity of um our pathogen and
how we
are in my second part I will talk about
uh how we are driving Innovative genetic
research um to be able to elucidate the
mechanisms driving the violence uh but
as well as developing genetic strategies
uh to better control the spread of
fungal
pathogens um so first uh why popular so
poppers are vital uh crops for the
Department of energy and because first
they are like fasted growing uh tree
species uh but also because they serve
as a foundational feed stock for
producing biofuel bioenergy and other
biobased chemicals at orl we focus
primarily at polar uh just because uh it
has um a fully sequenced genome actually
it was one of the first three genomes to
be published and it was uh this work has
been done by by a scientist at orl and
it made it to the cover of science on
September 15
2006 but we also valued working with
popper due to its genetic tractability
so it has a transformation system and
strong hybridization potential which
made it a prime model to be able to
advance research
efforts however this crop is um limited
to be used in industrial application
mainly due to the fungal diseases that
are caused primarily by the pathogens
ferina miva or known for the longest
time as septoria miva which is an asisd
fungal pathogen so this pathogen was
first described in 1884 on popus
deltoides in New York States but it has
later been uh uh spread unintentionally
by human activities uh as it will and it
was recently introduced and established
into the Pacific Northwest of North
America and now it's everywhere so in
this figure on the right show I show the
propagation
sorry I showed the propagation of um
this pathogen uh that spread across
North America and we saw that there was
like distinct
population um so we have uh the
Southeastern US population we have the
US Canadian subpopulation and we also
have a genetically distinct British
Columbia population so I'm bringing this
population right now because they will
come up later in my talk which we're
going to talk about them more in dep uh
um but just note that we actually have
122 isolates of each of these population
that were collected and we have the
genome sequence for them and that has
really been very helpful to invance our
research
efforts so this pathogen is responsible
for the septoria leaf spots and stem
caner diseases on susceptible pop
genotypes so while the leaf spots are
mainly um just of reducing the a static
values of popular the caners are uh the
one that have the greatest industrial
impacts due to the fact that uh a single
infection can kill a whole tree and snap
it in half uh and that would reduce uh
the yields and the use of poppler for
industrial
applications here's I'm actually also
showing uh additional pictures that were
taken by Tomas in our local blound
County popess field where most of our uh
field experiments take place so on the
left I'm showing how a diseased popular
look like and um help healthy so I put
it in quotes healthy because although it
is a resistant genotype it can still be
infected by sperina and that we've seen
that several times where the pathogen is
actually endophytically living inside
the plant but it does not cause uh
diseases because the genotype is
actually resistant uh to the symptoms
and the disease
development here's also other um uh
pictures showing uh canker disease
propagation uh and how the caners um
look like when it's a la8 stage canker
um just want to note that those caners
although we were able to isolate sperina
from it we cannot necessarily say that
they're adjusted du to sperina because
we were able to isolate other pathogens
that cause cankers as well but just
wanted to show you how a caner disease
propagation um look
like I believe a lot of you are already
familiar with fungal pathogen
classification um so as we know uh
pathogens um their pathogen it uh have a
a spectrum ranging from biotrophy uh to
necrotrophy so biotrop are closely
associated with living host cells um
they extract the nutrients and grow and
reproduce without killing the host but
that doesn't mean that they are uh not
able uh to cause damage um which the
great example is uh rust fungi that
cause uh significant uh damage on crops
we have also the necrot trro that would
rely on uh that host tissue uh to
extract nutrients and they release
enzymes and toxins that will actually
break down the cell wall and will kill
the host cells we also have and the
greatest example is uh Bettis we also
have a third class which is where our
sperina pathogen Falls in which is the
Hemi bioto pathogens where they begin uh
their life cycle um as um as botro uh
but then later they would transition
into um into an necrotrophic uh phase
and they will um
sorry into an necrotrophic phase where
they will actually uh kill the tissue
and extract nutrients and
reproduce so here's a brief overview
about the life cycle of sperina miva so
the infections actually starts in Spring
where the pathogen release ascospores
where they will enter the popular leaves
through the stomata and they will uh
develop lesions three to four weeks
after Bud burst then during SU
there will be secondary infections where
the spores will spread to other parts of
the plants they will enter the stems the
branches um and other leaves and
creating secondary infections then
during fall the leaves that are infected
with the pathogen will fall off the
ground and then the sexual stage will
begin with the formation of the sexual
fruiting bodies Pia and then the cycle
will start all over again in
spring in terms of disease management to
mitigate ASAS infection uh there has
been like use of fici sdes but just as a
preventive approach because uh once the
pathogens actually established there was
no chemical treatments that were shown
to be effective but as I mentioned
earlier in my presentation uh popler has
actually um a strong hybridization
potential uh which actually uh made a
substantial amount of research focused
on the host side either by identifying
and planting resistant the genotype or
through breeding uh program efforts
aimed at developing new genotype that
can be resistant to the
pathogen other management approaches
aimed at preventing the spread of this
pathogen has focused on biological
control so um as I'm showing here in
this first study in 2003 they were able
to show that when they spray stomy
strains in the field they were able to
suppress leaf spot diseases a more
recent study in 2021 a research were
able to identify uh other basilis V
sensus trains that were also shown to
have antagonistic activity against s
ferina uh but the problem of those uh
biocontrol strategies is the limited
longevity of the bacterial strains uh
when they're used imp
Plantation the pathogen in this path
system has been overlooked for the
longest time in terms of disease
management and this is mainly due to the
insufficient understanding of the
molecular mechanisms that drive esas
penic but also this intertwines with the
absence of genetic manipulation
manipulation tools where there's a lot
of genetic tools as I mentioned on
popper for the longest time we did not
have any genetic tools to be able to um
manipulate uh this pathogen um so that
made it like our primarily objective
within the csfa is to develop a crisper
genetic tools for this pathogen that
aims not only at advancing uh the basic
research elucidating Gene functions
implicated and pathogenicity but also at
advancing applied research um towards
the development of crisper enabled
technology uh to be able to um control
the disease and um ensure like
sustainable population
management so for the second part of my
talk um I will discuss the progress that
we've made so far into developing
synthetic biology and genetic strategies
for combating Esa and mitigate its
impact on pois plantations and I will
divide this part into uh three subp
parts so first I will talk about uh how
we were able to develop chis procast
tool to genetically manipulate uh this
pathogen and then later how we leverage
these tools to uncover genetic
determinant of pathogenicity and other
um genes that has ecological functions
and how we are taking this another step
further uh to develop um crisper enabled
the gene drives for population
control but first for for those of you
who are not familiar with uh crisper
crisper stands for clustered regulatory
interspaced short palindromic uh repeats
uh it's a natural defense mechanisms
that was found in bacteria and that
helped them in protect against viruses
but later this natural occurring
mechanism has been adapted for synthetic
genome editing in a groundbreaking way
and in a lot of organisms
so crisper is often referred to as the
gene uh scissor why because it caused a
double strand DNA break in a specific
sequence in the genome so this Gene uh
this tool actually is composed of the
cast nine protein which will unwind and
cleave the DNA double strand break and
the second component of the crisper is
the guide RNA so it's the RNA component
that is composed of the Tracer RNA and
the crisper RNA so the TR RNA um it will
bind to the cast 9 protein whereas the
crisper RNA will hybridize to a specific
uh region in the DNA so to any Gene of
interest that we want to knock it out or
delete it um so the crisper RNA is the
part that we actually uh designed based
on our uh Gene of
interest uh so the Tracer RNA and the
crisper RNA will uh fuse uh together to
form what we call the guide RNA and the
guide RNA will form a complex with the
cast
9 then this guide RNA and cast 9 complex
will go and will search for the sequence
of interest that we want to knock out
and the nuclease would be the nucleas
domains of the cast n would be activated
after the guide RNA hybridized to this
specific uh region and it will generate
a DNA cut or a DNA double strand break
then this double strand break that was
created by the guide RNA cast 9 complex
will be repaired uh in a prone in an
error prone way generating multiple
mutations or what we call indels
referring to insertions or deletions
because they are randomly repaired and
most likely those mutations will um will
result in the gene being knocked out
because its open reading frame has been
um cut in the middle and repaired in an
or error prone way containing a lot of
mutations
so just to give you a brief overview
about the advanc sorry uh the
advancement of uh crisper cast systems
uh into in in fungal research so this
tool has revolutionized actually fungal
genetic engineering in both yeast and
filamentous species enabling precise and
efficient genetic modifications and it
has been used for various application
that range of from uh genome engineering
primarily in yeast species to create
yeast libraries or to construct
synthetic yeasted chromosomes as well as
for metabolic engineering
transcriptional regulation um and we
also uh recently saw that crisper has
opened up new avenues for actually
detecting and controlling fungal
infections in Plant Pathology
specifically the applications of crisper
cast tools are also rapidly expanding so
these tools her help improving um plant
disease resistance by targeting both the
crops and the fungal Pat pathogens have
helped deepening our understanding of
plan pathogens interactions and has also
enabled the development of innov
innovative diagnostic tools uh for early
pathogen
detections so as a first step in our
efforts I worked on developing a crisper
cast n transformation system in our
non-model fungal pathogen asmea so here
I'm showing how the esa spores look like
and then uh how after digesting them we
a mix of different um digestion enzymes
how we are able to generate those bubble
looking uh structures that are called
protoplast so those are cells without
the cell wall uh and then we use those
protoplast for the delivery of the cast
9 guide RNA uh complex uh to be able to
generate the double strand DNA break
that I already talked about it so as a
proof of principle for the success of
this um tool in Esa I targeted uh an
oxitop Gene called per G because it
allowed an easy screening on foa plates
in CA when this Gene is actually knocked
out and then randomly I selected the 20
transformant from this transformation
and I did a sequencing of the region
where the guide RNA is supposed to cut
and I aligned those uh sequences from
the different transformant to the while
type and I was able to see multiple
insertions and deletions that actually
resulted in the mutation of this Gene
validating the success of this
transformation and the success of this
tool in
Esa so now that we have developed the
crisper cast 9 tool in Esa I wanted to
leverage it to identify genetic
determinants of pathogenicity and in
fungal plant pathogens pathogenicity
determinants can be either carbohydrate
active enzymes that are involved in the
degradation of plant cell wall which are
a key part of the pathogenicity of many
fungal pathogens we also have eector
genes which are secreted molecules that
directly manipulate the host cell
function and allowing the fungus to
successfully infect the host and uh
suppressing its immune responses and
lastly we have secondary metabolites
that are specialized molecules so
secondary metabolites unlike primarily
mole primary metabolites that are not
essential uh for the growth and
development but um they provide
Advantage for survival of the pathogen
for the pathogen and they can act as
virence factors and the production of
those metabolites are are usually
regulated as shown on uh the bottom
right by a cluster of genes so these
genes are clustered together uh and they
have um different function some of them
can encode for um accessory accessory
enzymes um and coordinate the synthesis
and modification others in codes for
Transporters um that are responsible for
the transport and um uh the actual
secretion of those metabolites and we
have also transcription factors that
regulate the expression expression of
those Gene in the cluster in our study
we focus on those two classes
identifying effectors and secondary
metabolites that are that can be
regulating the pathogenicity of sperina
Misa
so to identify fector genes we
collaborated with Dr Jared leales at
Oregon State University to conduct a
transcriptomic analysis on ASA during
stem caner
formation um so we collected RNA at two
and three weeks post inoculations with
the pathogen uh and this analysis have
enabled us to reveal 70 genes that were
differentially expressed at two weeks
and 110 genes that were differentially
expressed at three weeks between um the
stem caners like the RNA extracted from
stem caners uh and the control which is
uh fungus growing on am
media and among those genes that were
differentially expressed the gene that
had the highest expression at two weeks
and the second highest at three weeks en
code for extracellular protein 2 or
short for ecp2 which is predicted to be
an effor protein it was characterized in
other fungal pathogen and shown to be
responsible for pathogenicity it was
found as I mentioned to be highly
expressed during infection and when we
did an um an infiltration of this
protein uh on popular leaves we show
that it invokes hyper sensitive response
in some of the susceptible
genotypes so using our crisper tool that
uh we were able to develop uh but this
time instead of having a random repair
um we inserted with along with the
crisper cast 9 uh complex a donor DNA
that has a 1kb homology arm that
correspond to the cut site of the guide
RNA in the ecp2 sequence and contain a
selectable marker hph that encodes for
hydy which will allowed us later on to
select those mutants on hygromycin uh
enriched media so this is the structure
of the guide RNA that was designed to
cut in the ecp2 sequence um and after
doing the transformation
we collected randomly 20 mutants we did
the PCR confirmation and we selected of
those positive PCR mutants uh three uh
independent mutants uh that we performed
whole genome sequencing to make sure
that we don't have any cast 9 of targets
which is something that could happen
where the cast 9 would generate Cuts in
other parts of the genome and would also
have mutations not only necessarily at
the targeted low side but also in other
parts of the genome so we can confirmed
that in the three mutants that are
independently uh selected we did not
have any cast nine of Target and we have
a cut in the ecp2 sequence and a repair
integrating the hydy selectable marker
in those mutants later we use those
mutants and we perform pathogenicity
experiments uh by spraying different
popular genotypes that represent a broad
spectrum of susceptibility so some of
them are known to be susceptible to Esa
where others where uh
resistant and as we can see here by
looking at uh the coner developments per
centimeters uh we were able to see that
The Knockout of ecp2 resulted in a
significant um um decrease of caners per
centimeters in certain genotypes uh but
interestingly those genotypes were the
same genotypes that when we did
infiltrations were also showing hyper
hyper um response um so also when we did
when we looked at the Leaf Disease
severity we were able to see a
significant reduction of Leaf Disease
severity uh when the plants were
inoculated with the Delta ecp2 compared
to the wild do strains so using this
crisper cast mine tool we were able to
validate the function of the
necrotrophic effector ecb2 that is
involved in necrotic caners formation uh
on PO systems and this effector can
actually serve as our first Target for
the development of the chain drive
but besides the factors secondary
metabolites were also our Gene targets
of interest uh and they and they also
play a key roles in pathogenicity so to
be able to identify secondary
metabolites that are potentially
involved in ASA pathogenicity uh we used
anti smatch which is an online tool that
is able to predict biosynthetic Gene
clusters in fungi so when we rent this
tool on the genomes of all 122 isolate
ASA that we have from our collection we
were able to identify and that I'm
highlighting in red here a few
biosynthetic Gene clusters that were
either truncated or absent in the
British Columbia subpopulation that I
talked about earlier that is uh
genetically different than the others uh
population and interestingly uh when
those clusters um Clan 3030 and Clan
3571 were absence in the subpopulation
of British Columbia we also saw that
this um
subpopulation have also a reduction of
caners formation which made us think
that those clusters might be the good
targets and might be implicated in
pathogenicity so I had two of my
graduate students Joshua Sparks and Cole
Sawyer who actually graduated last week
uh working on uh characterizing those
two clusters and doing The Knockouts of
their backbone genes to validate uh
their implications and
pathogenicity so the work work on the
clan 3571 is still in its earlier stages
and it's known to incode for an unknown
metabolite so it's a little bit more
challenging than the work on Clan 3030
which I'm going to be focusing on uh
today because this clan is predicted to
encode for a metabolite that is known
and identified in other fungi but not in
Esa to be appenine like B synthetic Gene
cluster so Cole has worked on
characterizing uh this cluster uh that
is predicted to be uh um um formed with
11 putative biosynthetic genes and of
those genes as I talked earlier there's
a specific transcription factor which is
Gene highlighted in pink AP andh so what
is the role of this specific
transcription Factor when a cluster of
genes contain a specific transcription
Factor it works as a switch so when this
genes is expressed the rest of the genes
would be expressed and when it's knocked
out or not expressed the the rest of the
genes would be turned off and therefore
we won't have a production of this
metabolite so using the crisper tool
Cole was able and this is the guide RNA
sequence that he designed he was able to
knock out uh this specific transcription
factor and later he conducted the
transcriptomic analysis to confirm that
the rest of the genes are also turned
off when this um uh specific
transcription factors is
deleted and yes we actually confirmed
that all the genes in the cluster were
significant ly downregulated in those
mutants we also conducted metabolomic
analysis to confirm that this cluster
actually belong and encodes for appenine
uh by running it through a standard that
is the appenine uh commercialized the
standard and as we can see here the wild
type is able to produce appenine whereas
the three independent mutants that uh
Cole has selected um did not uh produce
atpenin on both tested media PDA and GMM
can confirming that this cluster is
encoding for AP penine and all the genes
are downregulated when the specific
transcription factors is knocked out we
also later conducted pathogenicity
experiments so similar to what we done
in the ecp2 mutants um we conducted
those pathogenicity experiments by
spraying uh different popular genotypes
with the spores collected from the wild
type and the mutants and to our surprise
we were expected to see a significant
downregulation of the disease severity
as as well as the kers per centimeters
but to our surprise um we did not see
any differences between the wild type
and the mutants inoculated plants uh
which actually um kind of contradict our
original hypothesis that this compound
uh could be implicated in pathogenicity
but since atpenin is already
characterized as an antifungal compound
we wanted to look at since this pathog
this metabolite is not implicated in
pathogenicity what is actually the
ecological function of this compound is
it really regulating the microbiome so
to test this hypothesis call has
selected different fungi that are
associated with popper uh here I'm
showing just results from uh two
pathogens uh sorry two fungi that were
uh selected and were isolated from
popler we have Laria bolar and
tricoderma gamy which are beneficial
fungi and as we can see when the fungus
is growing alone we were able to measure
uh the growth and we also did pairwise
interactions or co-cultures uh where uh
Cole grew his um mutants and his wild
type along with um the wild type of
tricoderma gamy and the Cara byor and as
we can see when um the appenine is not
produced by the mutants we did not see
any reduction of the growth whereas when
we grow it with the wild type and aine
is actually produced we saw a
significant reduction of the growth of
both um
uh fungi in tricoderma and Laria by
colar we saw significant uh decrease of
the
growth and then here after that we
confirmed that adenine is not a verance
factor uh we were able to use this
crisper tool and characterize an ancient
biosynthetic Gene cluster that was found
to be Pro providing a competitive
ecological advantage to our pathogen
over other uh popular Associated
fungi so we also beside looking at anti
smatch predicting what is absent what is
present in uh some of those 122 isolate
of Asa we used also another approach to
identify secondary metabol that might be
implicated in pathogenicity and this
approach rely on modulating the
expression of global Regulators so as I
as we have like specific transcription
factors we also have a global Regulators
or Global transcription factors uh and
they are commonly found in all fungi and
they regulate the production of seconder
metabolite by regulating the expression
of specific biotic gen clusters and a
lot of those metabolites were found to
be implicated in pathogenicity or in the
interaction with neighboring
microbes and in the past when I used
this approach in my uh PhD and in my
postdoc um I was able to identify
different metabolites that were able to
either playing a role in regulating my
microbiomes or in pathogenicity so in
this first study uh when I did a
knockout of f which is a global
regulator uh I was able to identify
serotine which is a compound that I was
able to find that is playing a crucial
role in regulating the chees rine
microbiome and a different a study when
I did it on a penicilium expansum which
is a post Harvest PL pathogen and I did
a knockout of another Global regulator
Crea I was able as we can see on this
apple um the mutants were nearly
avirulent and when we did metabolomics
and transcriptomic I was able to
identify two biosynthetic Gene clusters
one that is encoding for pyin and the
other one for citrine that were
essential for
pathogenicity um so we decided um since
this approach has been proven to be very
effective in other pathosystems to use
this approach on sperina missa popular
pathosystem to see if that would help us
pinpointing to certain metabolites that
can be implicated in
pathogenicity so we did a knockout of Le
a in ASA and when we conducted
pathogenicity experiment we showed as we
can see here a significant reduction of
a leaf disease severity across all the
genotypes tested except for one and we
also saw a reduction of uh caners per
centimeters in certain genotypes but not
in the others um which indicate that
that could be an actually very effective
strategies to looking at or identifying
or characterizing uh biosynthetic Gene
clusters implicated in pathogenicity and
we're taking this uh to doing
metabolomics and transcriptomic Analysis
that would help us seeing what are the
Clusters that are down regulator in our
L A mutants and what are the metabolites
that are not produced which could be
like good targets uh for pathogenicity
and of course later we have to do a lot
of other um validations like what I did
in my previous studies
so while we are continuously working on
identifying genetic determins of
pathogenicity that could serve as
targets for the development of the genan
drive um we actually decided uh to start
working on uh advancing um This research
and actually started developing the gene
Drive um on uh I'm gonna talk about it
later on the PKS Gene of the melanin
pathway but first what is a gene Drive
so when we have an irregular mandelian
inheritance and we have an alter Gene
this Gene will only have a 50% a chance
to be pass to the progeny and therefore
after many populations and multiple
progenies this Gene would actually be
diluted and not present anymore whereas
when we have this alter Gene compined to
the cast 9 and the guide RNA which what
we called a dri's train during the
meeting the cast nine would be able to
generate a cut because the guide RNA
will guide the cast n to this specific
region on the wild type chromosome and
then this cut would be repaired by hom
homology directed repair transferring
this drive Machinery to the wild type
chromosome and therefore the wild type
strain would also becoming a drive
strain and that that Gene would have a
nearly 100% chance of transferring to
the progeny so that's how a crisper cast
9 Gene Drive
function this tool has been widely used
used in disease vectors to eradicate
diseases like malaria and zika so it has
been developed on mosquitoes and other
disease vectors but it has never been
done before on a filamentous fungal
pathogen um but to be able to develop a
gene Drive um the organism of Interest
has to be having a sexual reproduction
or ability to mate uh and as I mentioned
already in the sperina life cycle if you
remember uh it has actually part of its
life cycle when it's on the leaves it
has a sexual reproduction uh stage
therefore this approach can seem
particularly promising for effective for
Effective population control in this
organism so as a proof of principle of
the gene drive applicability before we
actually go right away and test it on
genetic determinance of pathogenicity
which is our out um overarching goal we
decided to start working on a gene that
would allow us to see an easy
phenotyping therefore we decided to
Target the melanin pathway because when
the PKS gene or the backbone Gene of the
melanin pathway is knocked out the the
the fungus would have an albino
phenotype so instead of looking a dark
green or black it would look it would
have a white uh phenotype and that would
be easy for us to screen the progenies
coming from this mating so we decided to
Target um this Gene and uh there's
something I did not mention earlier when
when we have an active Gene drive when
the cast 9 the alter Gene and the guide
RNA are localized next to each other on
the same Locus we have what we called an
active Gene drive so even if it's uh
generating traits that are unwanted it
will be so active and it will spread
over multiple generation so in this case
since it's a proof of principle we
didn't want to design an active Gene
drive so we decided to design what was
called a safe guarding Gene drive so we
decided to insert the guide RNA at one
Locus which would be our PKS Gene uh to
interrupt its uh expression and we
decided to insert our cast line at a
different Locus um and that's in that
way the gene Drive won't be active
enough and it will be uh kind of like
safeguarded and
contained um so this is how our uh
design for the genan drive um are so
first we're going to do a transformation
to insert the guide RNA at the PKS Locus
and we have another transformation on
the strain to insert the cast
9 at the pure G Locus because it will
allow an easy screening on foa
plates but a crucial Pro a problem for
synthetic a gene Drive is the evolution
of natural resistance against them so if
we have a mutation in the wild type
strain at the guide RNA site the guide
RNA won't be able to hybridize and
therefore the cast 9 won't won't be able
to cut to so as a first step forward
towards the establishment of this Gene
Drive uh we decided to look since we
have 122 isolates that are sequenced we
decided to leverage from that and we did
an alignment of the PKS Gene and we were
able to design three guide RNA that are
on conserved regions uh which can help
us predict what's going to happen in
nature uh making sure that those guide
RNA are not in regions that have natural
mut
patient um and we later tested those
three guide RNA on a substitute of this
population because it's a lot of work to
test it on all 122 isolates so we
selected based on um uh on this tree uh
a subset of this population so we tested
them on 29 uh isolates uh selected
across North
America and when we tested those guide
RNA so how does the test work we
actually sequence a region where the
guide rnas would be able to cut and then
um we hybridized the guide RNA and the
cast n to form a complex and we use them
kind of like a restriction enzyme to see
if they will cut in the sequence or not
so it's kind of like an invitro test for
the ability of the guide RNA to test to
cut and as we can see on this table
guide RNA 1 was able to cut in all the
tested strains whereas guide RNA 2
although it is uh designed in a similar
way uh considering efficiency
specificity and other criteria that are
essential for guide RNA design it did
not cut in any of the strains guide rna3
was able to cut in almost all of them
but not in all of them so from this um
uh quick screening we were able to see
that guide rna1 is the actual best
candidate to go further with in our uh
Gene Drive design so Josh was able uh to
take this guide rna1 confirmed sequence
oops sorry
sorry for that okay so after confirming
that the guide rna1 was our best
candidate Josh took this guy RNA
sequence and he designed a construct
that will cut in the PKS and he
performed the First Transformation and
here I'm showing some of the plates he's
actually still screening them by PCR and
whole genome sequencing but just wanted
to show how the phenotype of the wild
type look like so it's like uh sometimes
it's even darker green than that that's
how the wild type look like and that's
how the PKS phenotype look like and as
you can see like um they have a weird
phenotype which is we're really excited
about because that would help us uh
later on in the screening of the progeny
uh once we do the mating experiments so
do EST strin after Josh gonna confirm
them that they are uh correct they have
no cast nine off targets and any
anything like that he would use them to
introduce the second components of the
gene drive and the strain would be ready
to be tested in our uh mating essay that
we're actually working on developing so
just to give you a brief background on
how um we came up with this uh meeting
essay we were first able to see if we
were able to meet uh the esa strains in
vitro but we were not successful we
tested uh The Mating on detached leaves
but also that was really challenging
that because the the leaves were dry out
uh and the meeting was
unsuccessful uh until we came out we
came across uh this bioarchive
manuscript in zos septoria species which
is a closely related species to
Etha um and if you remember in the life
cycle where we showed that uh the sexual
reproduction actually occur on fall on
fallen leaves on the ground where the
sexual fruiting bodies will develop so
this essay actually we're trying to
mimic the natural uh conditions for uh
for mating uh so we will use plants we
will spray them with two opposite mating
types uh and we will let the plants go
through their natural sence then we will
collect those sleaves uh and we will put
them under sterile conditions uh we'll
use like velcro to have a plates upside
down uh plates that have the selection
uh for our genetic events um and then um
those sexual spores will be able to
shoot and the cols will be forming on
those open plates and then later we will
be able to uh look for the asport
derived colonies under the microscope
and we will for we will perform whole
genome sequencing to confirm uh The
Mating and the success of the
drive so this mating assay is actually
ongoing right now we don't have results
from that yet but just wanted to show
you the approach that we're following
where we are actually really mimicking
the natural conditions for sexual
reproduction and this
pathogen and I would with that I would
like to conclude um I was able to show
you that uh how we were able to advance
the development of crisper cast 9
genetic tool in this non-model
organism how we used this crisper tools
uh and how we are still leveraging this
tool um to uh pinpoint to crucial
genetic uh factors influencing disease
severities including affector genes and
secondary
metabolites how we are taking that a
step forward towards the development of
the first crisper enabled Gene Drive
aimed at eradicating uh Esa to protect
and sustain popular plantations and
although this approach uh offer Insight
mainly on the ASA populis pathos system
but it has the potential to be applied
to other pathos system either in forest
ecosystem as well as an agricultural
settings and with that I would like to
thank the ceds sa for funding This
research I would like to thank our
collaborators at Oregon State University
uh I would like to thank my uh
collaborator at ORNL and my research
group and I would like to thank you all
for attending this seminar and I would
take any questions you might
have thank you so much Dr Tannis that
was wonderful um so yeah we're gonna
open it up to questions now um so please
feel free to either uh raise your hand
directly unmute raise your hand or type
in the chat and I will
read go for it gallan thank you very
much
um can you compare crisper
driven homologous
recombination
with uh non crisper approaches
to homologous
recombination you mean when we use a
crisper for homologous Rec combination
where we where uh we don't use crisper
and we use like a standard
transformation
sorry is that the question yeah yeah so
in the past actually before joining orl
I was always using a standard
transformation where we design our uh
construct that have homology arms of 1kb
to the C to the to the region that we
want to
transform um but after using crisper I
really see a great improvements in the
specificity because before when I was
using without the crisper to generate
the cut our construct although designed
to be specifically going to this
specific region we saw that it was
inserted in other multiple places in the
genome so when we perform either whole
genome sequencing or Southern blot we
saw that our construct is like being
inserted in different other places uh
crisper has really improved the
specificity because it actually generate
a cut and most of those um donor DNA
that we're inserting in our
transformation would go towards this cut
to repair the DNA double strand break so
yeah we saw a great Improvement in h
specificity and after we we do a whole
genome sequencing we rarely find
insertion on other
lowai
thanks
um second question have you regarding
mating have you tried uh m
both Partners on siness and
poer so take H CEST leaves and try it on
yeah yeah no we did not try that because
um yeah that's a good question but
there's another thing that we tried and
we did I did not mention here we
actually think that there's something
coming from the leaves either an acate
or something that is probably secreted
during sinin that could be driving the
mating uh so that's it was actually
tomas's idea um he took sinast leaves
and he did a metabolite extraction by
Sol by using organic solvent and he was
able later on to lyophilize this uh
crude extract from sest leaves to see if
there was any metabolites that could be
secreted and be essential and he used it
in an invitro setting so he used those
crude extracts coming from CEST leaves
into a media and try to do ating but we
were we were we're still not successful
so I don't know if it's actually really
the plant material that is essential um
not just metabolite uh that could be on
those sinast leaves um but yeah we did
not try it on sinast leaves we we
decided to go with the the actual
natural cence going on rather than like
take CEST leaves and spray them but that
can also be an approach to
take thank
you I have one um that so it's uh it's
not directly related to your
extraordinary scientific content um but
one of the things I was wondering if you
might uh reflect on for the sake of our
graduate students in the audience um
what your experience is working at a
National Lab environment um you've had
diverse experience at different types of
universities and I was just wondering if
maybe like to their perspective Ive you
know they're exploring different career
options um what's it like to work at a
national lab and how might they best
prepare themselves for that career
option if they're interested in pursuing
it sure yeah um I was actually so
interested in academic Physicians before
joining ORNL uh I did a post dog at U
which was like um yeah an academic post
dog um so after working at ORNL I I
really liked the environment and the
dynamic uh the next thing I really liked
about orl and I believe a lot of
National Labs are the same is that uh we
have like within um so under the same
umbrella of ORNL we have different
expertise so we have uh so in within the
bioscience for example we have the
computational science uh we have um the
analytical groups so they they do all
our lcms uh we have like the genetic
group um so that really helped instead
of uh going and seeking for external
collaborators um to be able to do
everything under the same umbrella and
same institution uh and that like we
find it that it it saved us a lot of
time and a lot of uh efforts um and it's
kind of like each one would focus on its
expertise so you don't have to be doing
everything um sometimes for certain
people it's good for certain people they
like to be doing everything from A to Z
so in Academia for example I was the
person doing the genetic the analytical
um the pathogenicity experiments uh and
sometimes like the bioinformatic and
computational um I feel like in at orl
specifically um we have this like a
inter teams collaborations where
everyone works towards the same goal So
within the stas sa for example uh
there's a teams of uh bacterial
geneticist uh fungal geneticist uh
fungal biologist computational science
analytical and that's like with within
one Science Focus area and a lot of
other projects are the same way and we
find that that really Advanced the
science uh in a speedy
way I don't know if that answered the
question oh it totally does awesome um
is there anything that you might
recommend for um a graduate student
perhaps or a postto talk that might be
interested in pursuing a career um at a
National Lab like oid is there anything
in particular you'd recommend they do or
Reach Out resources uh so we all like
for a graduate student they would have
to be associated so uh we're all
associated with uh the University of
Tennessee Knoxville to be able to take a
graduate student so they will take their
classes at utk but they do their
research at ORNL um for graduate
students I meant like if they would
wanted to be in a position like yours
one day like what they might okay as
like a post for example so we always
have yeah like post do positions open
sometimes when we go to conferences like
and we have a position that is open uh
we'll try to like um like talk about it
and what are the expertise then like you
would apply to every open positions
there's a lot of positions that comes
out every week not necessarily in our
division but there's several
directorates at ORNL and each one would
have open positions uh and as a post
talk usually it's for two years up to a
renewal for a third year um in terms of
transitioning from postto to staff
scientist
um it's not always like it happened
because at orl they usually don't hire
people that do the same thing so for
example for me and Tomas we both are
fungal people uh but each one of them
each each one of us actually does
different things so to be able to be
hired as a staff scientist you really
have to distinguish yourself from other
um existing scientists or staff
scientist um so where Tomas for example
he does not do genetics at all I'm the
only fungal geneticist at RL um I don't
know if that
answer the question no I certainly think
so thank you um and I think we have time
for one more question from the chat we
have um Isabelle jackmont Parks asks um
she says hi amazing talk I agree I
really appreciate your Insight you
mentioned there are some resistant pop
genotypes do you know if crisper is
being used for the pop genome to address
pathogens rather than the fungus yeah
actually the the research on the plant
is way more advanced compared to fungi
and that's what I mentioned earlier like
uh we have a sci us at orl that does a
lot of crisper work on they're they're
actually developing biosensors right now
to be able to detect the pathogens at
early State at early stages um so yeah
the the research on the crisper on the
plant part is way more advanced whereas
when I joined as a post dog we did not
have any genetic tool to even manipulate
the fungus was like really a non-model
organisms even if you look in terms of
Publications there was barely like three
Publications on the pathogen um so it
was really challenging at the beginning
to start like from scratch uh whereas
for popular the research is on on
another high
level wonderful thank you so much for
joining us presentation so either like
you know Round of Applause or just Kudos
so weird and please if if everyone if
anyone have questions or something that
maybe I did not touch on during my
presentation for the limitation of the
time please feel free to email me and um
I would be happy to answer any questions
you might have wonderful thank you again
thank you so much uh Katie and Gan and
Lori and thank you for everyone for
attending thank you thank
you this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu