this is a production of Cornell
University thank you very much for that
overly generous introduction Margaret
and I wanted to say uh I'm super excited
to talk to you today uh I want to say
thank you first of all to Lou and Kelly
for organizing my schedule and making
the arrangements and everybody else who
puts on these seminars and makes it
possible to share ideas is with the rest
of the world
um I I really uh as I was saying am very
excited about this talk because I feel
like hunger in Africa malnutrition in uh
parts of Africa and the rest of the
world really is one of the most pressing
uh issues of our day and that makes it
important but what makes it more
exciting is that I believe we can now
solve these problems I look at the the
UN development goals number two is
ending hunger basically by 2030 we could
do
it uh and we could do it using maybe not
just exactly the kind of things I'm
talking about today but many of them and
uh and it's a shame that there's not
more money being put into them um the
battle is not won by a long shot and So
for anybody contemplating a career in
plant breeding
uh I'm not saying that you know you're
too late uh there there's there there's
there's a lot to be done still but we do
have some good Notions about how to end
Hunger in parts of the world that really
can't produce enough food at present
time so let's dive in but first I want
to acknowledge my co-authors isuk apran
and Irene Mogi who you see there on the
slides Irene Mogi is senior program
officer with seed systems group where I
live in Nairobi Kenya and Dr Isa fu
kapran is a sorum breeder and he leads
our program in West Africa we have a
regional office in
L so first slide start with some data
it's always good to do that by the way
this will be the least scientific uh
seminar given probably this decade here
at Cornel so bear with me but I I did
want to show some trends that I think
are pretty interesting and these show
the correlation between the supply of
improved seeds specifically ma seed in
Uganda and Kenya over a period of about
15 years and then looked at what
happened with maze yields in those
countries over the same amount of time
and I think you can see that the
correlation is not perfect but it's
pretty good
and uh anytime you can get data at a
national level in Africa which show a
trend you're in a a pretty fortunate
situation because data collection really
isn't that uh uh that good so when it
shows up on FAO uh data sites you know
you you feel like you've done
something um now I always use this slide
when I'm talking to uh agricultural
ministers and leaders in other countries
that we work in now because it for me
was a real point in time when I learned
that here in the United
States uh for a long time we struggled
with maze yields as well and if you
convert these yields I think this data
is gathered by Purdue University um from
1886 right up until the mid 1930s our
maze yields were stuck at about 1.5
metric tons per Hector and 1.5 metric
tons per hectar is a pretty good average
yield for Maze across the continent of
Africa wouldn't you say it yeah yeah um
and then what happened here in the US
was the introduction of hybrid Maze of
course originally double cross hybrids
and then single crosses and then
everything else that has come on
since so you know it's not like we never
had this problem we did for a long time
and it wasn't we like we weren't trying
to solve it we had developed the land
grant universities they were breeding
opv maze during these times there were
names to those varieties and we had
developed the extension service and
still we couldn't make yields bud until
the Advent of hybrid
maze so um why focus on seed systems um
again we we feel like we have proof of
concept now on uh the development of
seed system which is really what this
talk is
about um by the way the subt of the talk
is the 10 Things I wish I knew before I
became a plant breeder and we'll go
through those too and I hope um you find
those useful but uh what we did at at
the end of a f 15 years of work at Agra
was to measure rice and Maze yields in
10 countries where we had worked and
where we could vouch for you know the
attribution issues if anybody wanted to
call on it and then compareed those with
10 similar countries where we had never
worked on seed systems and you can see
the big difference in Trends in yields
of those crops over that period with um
up to at least 2020 those countries we
had assisted advancing quite quickly and
in the rest of Africa not much happening
so if you're in one of these countries
in the orange uh line there life is not
good as a farmer you know population is
growing Africa's population is still
growing at a steady clip in the
countries where we work it's about 2.8
up to 3% and some countries like ner are
over
5% so you know this is dwindling
resources this is subsistence
agriculture subsistence agriculture is
not sustainable this is an urgent
problem and if you look at other authors
just to cite another publication that
looks at yields on a big scale and you
know again if you're in my field you
look for small positive signs and that
is a very nice positive upward Trend
that had not happened for a long time in
many of the countries where we
worked so again addressing uh those
people who may be interested in a career
in plant breeding or International Plant
breeding and in International
Development in general I would
say uh reviewing what it took to be in a
position to put money toward this work
and do it in a practical way we come to
my first
lesson uh lesson number
one international agriculture
development is a fairly topheavy field
and that's being a bit um you know
politically correct I think if you read
me correct or well and farmers are often
the last to benefit um
there's a whole lot of money spent by
Rich countries on develop and the Big D
development absorbs a lot of
resources so you might expect that since
the biggest problem that we're working
on is farmer productivity at the basic
level that most of the money would be
going there but I'm using this graphic
and I don't have any data for this I
hope you know and this is offer authors
rant not for citation as you see at the
bottom there but you know the amount of
money that gets spent on Administration
and conferences and then big rural
development projects that honestly uh I
don't know where the money goes I do
know where the egg research money goes
and to be frank I think we're still
topheavy in terms of expenditure on
Research versus expenditure on delivery
at the farmer level I don't know why it
is a lot of donors some governments
don't really think that's a interesting
problem we happen to believe it's a it's
an interesting problem um the breeding
work I'll talk about a lot today that
money has done some good but we're still
fighting for enough resources down at
that bottom end of that funnel which is
where Farmers actually get to benefit
from what we're
doing I've just mentioned a lot of the
the breeding initiatives that I think
you know the donors have to be
recognized for African governments as
well uh simmit has done a great job with
stress tolerant maze some of you may be
aware of that work uh there are a lot of
uh rice varieties available now from
Africa rice and Erie uh a lot of the
national egg research institutes also
have uh a number of good varieties some
of them are willing to share so there's
exciting work that's been done in
breeding
and um and so it's it's there we we have
one breakthrough that we can really use
to deliver benefits to
Farmers but very few of those varieties
have reached have reached the farmers
they there there seems to be a cycle
wherein you know money gets poured into
research people can spend their whole
career and that's kind of a cautionary
tale for anybody I think studying plant
breeding today is that you need to be
careful because you could get into a
career in research thinking that you're
going to be able to help farmers and you
can get caught in that cycle of research
and never get involved with actually
helping farmers and you wouldn't want to
have that happen to you so lesson number
two uh it's a hungry World it really is
uh I'm probably more convicted of this
because we work in what we call the Left
Behind countries but I can tell
you I can assure you that uh there are
millions and tens of millions and
hundreds of millions of people yet in
Africa that have never had the
opportunity to grow a new variety or are
suffering from the effects of never
having been able to grow an improved
variety and again with population growth
and reducing Farm size that's becoming a
bigger problem every single
day so it's an a matter of urgence for
more people to become plant breeders if
you've chosen this field
congratulations um I I really feel like
there's there's there's so much you can
do to make the world a better place just
to cite a few examples what we've seen
in terms of breakthroughs over the past
couple of decades we have reliable
resistance to R ymv and bacterial blight
and I see Susan mcud in the audience I
won't go any further because I'll
embarrass myself but we have really uh
great rice Friday we don't have enough
you know I was just talking to some
graduate students and one of them comes
from a Highland region of India another
one comes from Nepal and I'm asking do
you have any
Highland uh cold tolerant rice varieties
that we could introduce into madag Gasco
so we still need more um you know
resistance to maze streak virus big
breakthrough in breeding of maze tum
Leaf light these were diseases that
killed maids in many countries made it
virtually impossible to grow maze
productively in Uganda for example and
large parts of Kenya
until group people I know and work with
and even little old me uh got busy and
bred a new generation of uh F uh hybrids
resistant to folar diseases I was in
Northern Togo last week and I'm afraid
there may be a new strain of ma streak
virus so yeah as borlock always said the
wolf is always at the door with these
diseases and we need to keep working on
them but there's been great resistance
to anthros grain moles big problem in
sorghum head buug resistance as well cop
Leaf brought in Rosette virus disease in
groundnut a big problem we have
resistant varieties now they haven't
reached Farmers uh acmv African casava
mosaic virus huge problem Brown streak
virus as well that out broke broke out
about 20 years ago in Northern MOS can
cause famine conditions in parts of mosm
Beque um we now have resistant varieties
to those thanks to some breeders I can
mention but yeah beans has been a big
success story uh the advancement of
folar disease resistance damping off uh
uh shoot maggot in beans has has been a
big
breakthrough um and uh Downey Miler
resistance and the development now of
hybrid Pearl Millet is super exciting I
don't think any farmer has gotten hybrid
Pearl Millet yet but we're going to work
on that we've got it in um test
production plots in Northern Ghana right
now and hopefully we'll start to get
some seed out starting next year um
resistance to striga in cpy and other
foler diseases so if you want to know
what this looks like on the ground
that's a land race of sorghum from uh
the sahelian region of Mali and to the
right uh an intermediate Guinea
uh hybrid of sorghum the farmers
said oh when they saw that you know they
said oh but you've made a big mistake
because we need the stock to feed our
animals we said well just try the star
and see how the animals like it and they
loved it because it's actually much more
digestible lower Lian contents in the
stem and it doesn't have to be so high
ligant because it's not as tall so that
was a in um as I said Bean varieties
that are extremely uh way better than
the local R that's a local Bean VAR in
Rwanda can you imagine if you're a
farmer growing that and you get a chance
to grow this one well yeah the breeder
did their job uh there's David ell in
the background standing there
proudly surveying his improved groundnut
variety here where this farmer is
standing and that's the farmer's variety
on the right so as you can see big big
differences again this is uh Bean in
southern Sudan we stole this one from uh
Uganda and brought it across the border
that's the local variety any breeder can
see the big differences that are
available lesson number three though is
it's a lot easier to develop a new
variety than it is to get the seed of
that variety to scale and I was a once a
neoy in this field after we had released
our first uh series of maze hybrids in
uh Western
Kenya I asked myself for the first
time what do we do now uh I think it's
time to get off the research station and
uh and Gary Tennison said he was my boss
at the Rockefeller Foundation he said no
problem J jump on a plane we'll go see
the guys at Pioneer and we went to
Pioneer you know we signed all those
non-disclosure forms and we got inside
the interner sanctum with the big shots
and I made a presentation like this to
them and I said so I think you guys need
to come into a big collaboration with
the Rockefeller
foundation and there was silence in the
room that became a bit of a distraction
until somebody said well I think we
should take a
bio and the guy met me in the hallway
and he said he said Joe nice
presentation great stuff you're doing
doing out there we're not
coming um yeah there's more to that
story than than that but that was the
that was the answer we got at that time
that was in about 2001 but on the way
home uh I had an idea which I'll tell
you
about
but nobody ever tells you when you're a
breed student that you might have to
look for your own funing maybe they tell
you though but did they talk to you
about variety release committees and how
political that can get
uh do they tell you about anything like
uh White labels which is under the plant
Health inspectorate uh did you ever
think about how to scale up from breeder
to Foundation seed and transition that
to certified seed growing um who's going
to train out Growers for the seed uh do
you even have a seed company interested
I'm always asking Cornell breeders so
what do you do after you release a new
variety say well we we license it to
seed companies you dope uh but you know
it's a it's it from where I come from
and Ed knows what I'm talking about it's
a legitimate question there may not be
any
seat um licensing agreements uh field
inspections again from plant Health
inspectorate uh who has the processing
equipment to produce clean seed and
who's going to do The Branding packaging
and get this out to Farmers those are
the issues that a breeder faces when
you're working in a developing country
system and so the real thing I came here
to say is is on this slide and I say
this to a lot of people and then I say
it only took us 30 years to figure this
out basically what you have is the
public private producer model for seed
systems development which needs to be
done I don't know where it doesn't need
to be done but we still need to put more
resources behind this either to increase
productivity of a few main crops that
are going to save lives or to diversify
uh seed supply systems so that people
can also diversify their
diets uh but it starts with public
reading and it shifts very quickly to
seed
companies and the interaction between
seed companies who are looking for a
profit by selling producing and selling
seed to small holder farmers and the
scientists there's magic there I don't
need to explain it but then that all
happens in isol
and the farmers don't even know you're
doing any of this and that's a big
problem because the African landscape
for agriculture is endless and they're
out there and they don't know and so we
needed a methodology for raising farmer
awareness and we have one now it's
called a village based advisor which is
kind of like a volunteer Health worker
and small pths don't do demos don't do
big demos at least don't put a lot of
money into them because you know the
farmers will stand there politely and
they'll say thank you can I get my Coke
now uh and then they'll go home and they
won't adopt it's sad you know because we
did that for a long time we don't do
that anymore the element of doubt that
was an agronomist who planted that field
my soil is poor I live a long ways from
here that briy is not going to work on
my farm it's not because they're not
interested it's because of the doubt and
the
risk a small piece of land grown with a
tiny amount of seed that's 50 g that's
50 gram of a maze streak virus resistant
hybrid variety do you see the quality of
maze crop this woman has been
growing that's her that's the farmer
that's her maze
prop it's a
no-brainer and then distribution through
these mom and pop shops small just you
know a couple meters square of of real
estate where farmers can go and get
their seeds
number four if you're thinking this is
too daunting I don't want to be a plant
breeder anymore or I think I'll go into
biotech and study I don't know something
really you know esoteric um you're in
luck because farmers will pull you
through and they do make this system
work if they get half of a chance how
does it work this woman grew a small
pack of maze on her farm and you can see
she's not a young farmer that's her land
raise of Maze and this is in the
Southern Highlands of Tanzania and do
you see the size of that year what you
don't see is that it's about 14 feet
tall and that's a cimm
hybrid it's got a number and I asked her
after we visited her plot I said well
what are you going to do now you know
this seed is that's not free that's a
small pack you know it's just a demo um
you said oh no problem I'll sell a goat
I'll sell some chickens and then I
thought
well how is she going to know the name
of the hybrid when she goes to buy it
and then she took me by the hand and she
led me to her Hut and she said that's
the name of the hybrid
Tesh T I can't read the 5 538 yeah it
got released it's available
now uh when I was first sent out uh by
Rockefeller Foundation the real agenda
was to develop
biotech after a couple years I realized
the real revolution in agriculture for
the next 20 plus years was not going to
be in biotech I'm not dissing biotech we
we need it we need we need GM ma
yesterday in in Africa that's a
political
question but I could see that the
Revolution was really
here farmer participatory bre reading
can you believe that for decades before
this became
the state of the art for developing new
varieties breeders weren't asking
Farmers their opinion now what you see
here
is is amazing input from these brilliant
Bean farmers in eastern Congo and that's
the bean breeder and she's taking note
of everything they say about the new
varieties and you can use gender based
selection methods now
um this is under a farmers's field and
it really greatly reduces the likelihood
of missing the Target in terms of the
new
varieties the fifth lesson is you know I
again nobody nobody told me that I
needed to work on my people's
skills uh I was trying to become a plant
person and yet and I am not a a natural
born manager by any means I'm still
learning but but I saw some
incredi
Adept people managers and nurturers and
when I went to Africa who also happened
to be plant breeders and I took a note
uh from how they operated and realized
you know they would never be successful
at all if they didn't know how to work
with teams and I think this is a
universal rule for plant breeders if
you're going to become a plant breeder
at any level
you really need to be a good people
manager as well go take a course that's
what I eventually
did they'll teach you everything you
need to know but here's some of the
teams that we work with today this is
sier Leone that's
Madagascar Monica Parker famous uh
potato scientist anybody know her this
is Northern uh
Togo as John mcrobert in a field in uh
in uh in Bundi
that's my colleague Isa Fu in guine BAU
laying out some plots and this is the
other team from Southern
Togo lesson number six extremely
important lesson I want to say somehow
I'm a socialist at heart that's the way
I was
born and that's the way I will
die uh but I was born at the wrong
time uh to be a practicing
socialist and so I want to say almost
any breeder uh if you don't want to work
with private sector forget ever
achieving anything at any kind of scale
because you need seed companies they
need you but you need them just as much
and on that trip back from United States
when we' got shut down uh
by Pioneer did I mention the name of
the they they no longer exist so the
cortiva guys are great and they're
moving ah but the DuPont uh Pioneer
marriage was a Rocky one I think at that
stage and that's probably what
influenced but as I was steaming there
in my plain uh seat I looked out the
window and I asked myself you know was
there anything that we saw there in
Johnston that looked all that
complicated that an African Pioneer uh
entrepreneur
couldn't do I mean basically what I saw
them doing was growing crops and putting
them in Sea in packages and selling them
to Farmers and that really made all the
difference because I came back and I
said you know what we don't need Pioneer
we need African entrepreneurs to create
their own
pioneers and Ed came on the scene at
that point with just about this same
modus operandi and started to train some
of these pioneering seed comp companies
and you just they're they're an amazing
Innovation you can't imagine what this
kind of an institution this is green
Horizon seed company with a CEO in Juba
South
Sudan because unlike MC multinationals
these guys will send sell any seed
Farmers need the multinationals are just
in it for the hybrid Maze and eventually
BT cotton
probably uh but right now it's just
hybrid maze
and women tend to be really good at
running these seed companies go
figure and we see many of them
succeeding uh Against All Odds so just
to name a few maslaha Seed Company in
Nigeria these are not shade tree seed
companies these are industrial
vertically integrated seed companies
producing all these different crops of
seed and improved varieties uh Tonio in
equator seeds Northern in Uganda same
story uh
Felix uh of peacock seeds is also a
parliamentarian sometimes helps to get
seed policies passed but he's a seedsman
and that's his uh seed company producing
uh hybrid maze seed and a couple other
crops fok Caba that's myuna kibali she
won the Africa food prize for her work
as uh leader of of fok Caba Seed Company
and she's she's tired now you know she
created a seed company it's successful
it's got it running she handed it over
to her daughter so there's
sustainability in this model as well and
eventually thanks to the generosity of
many people uh The Gates Foundation the
rockfeller foundation where I work we
went on to create about well many many
more than 114 seed companies and uh we
are still creating seed companies in
Africa and uh
and and we need to keep going as fast as
we can uh so lesson number
seven uh is this face-to-face extension
still matters and the uh with a nod to
John Prime um also known as your new
mobile phone app won't get you into
heaven
anymore uh I've seen so many of these
apps and I know they're well intended
Farmers need proof of concept there's a
a accountability issue here it can't be
boiled down to a 4 in phone
screen uh and so that's where our friend
uh Paul seaward uh came through for us
because he was trying to get farmers who
had never used fertilizer to use
fertilizer and fertilizer is only sold
in 50 kg bags at some point he decided
you know I think the problem is the size
of the
bag and so he made one Kow bags of of
fertilizer and immediately sold all all
the stock that they had that was in
Western Kenya where Farm size is very
small and farmers are very poor and that
was pre- introduction of hybrid maze so
farmers were really poor and really
hungry and couldn't afford anything any
kind of Technology now go to Western
Kenya and it's like it's it's a True
Green Revolution scene but the idea here
is that as I've already said let the
farmer try don't make them take your
word for it let them go home and take
some of the seed with them and instead
of a few demos we get hundreds of
thousands of demos uh this drives demand
for improved seeds so that the seed
companies can stay in business and
Achieve what they came to
do aggro dealers uh really can't say
enough of them they didn't really fit
into one of the lessons but I think
they're kind of a no-brainer you don't
buy your your toothpaste from the
toothpaste company and Farmers don't get
their seed from seed companies you've
got to have distribution at scale and I
asked somebody recently how many aggro
dealers you suppose there are in Kenya
uh I had been hearing 3,000 and he said
no the latest data show there's probably
around 10,000 10,000 aggro dealers uh
selling seed and other inputs in Kenya
you know how many there are in
Togo about
six and they're all in the big cities
right so farmers don't have access to
seat that's a big problem uh but we're
training uh aggro dealers today well
last week that's why I was in Togo we're
we're training aggro dealers to become
small scale vendors of improved seed and
today right today we're doing the same
thing in bukavu in eastern
Congo lesson number eight you know the
best seed systems are not private sector
driven I don't think we have the best
seed system here in America I absolutely
believe in the public involvement the
Vitality of the public sector in a seed
supply system and that means I believe
in it for the whole food system and the
whole agricultureal system for first
stop Agriculture and then the whole food
system because just take the example of
you know the narrowing of our diets uh
when you just leave the decision making
up to the seed companies and the big
ones especially they're only going to
produce those crops that their
shareholders want to see them produce
and there's no private Seed Company ever
going to breed a new variety of bombara
groundnut uh and it's a really important
crop in Africa so I'm just showing a few
photos here this is in aritra and those
are the wheat
breeders uh who've got who've done a
fantastic job uh here this is a private
seed grower in Burundi producing in
collaboration with the public breeder
from isabu and that's the first hybrid
maze seed production plot ever in
Burundi that photo was taken just two
weeks
ago so as a result of the work we've
been doing over the past 25 years or so
there has been a lot of progress and
it's more than you can see in the data
on the ground we see big changes in
Farmer productivity in in these
countries and that's quite a number of
countries so you know it's it's it's
been exciting but we need to turn the
page because there's kind of
the you know mirror image or CIS image
of that uh map now on the other side of
Africa and that's composed of 21
countries where there really are no uh
progress has been no progress and that's
about 370 million people almost half the
land mass of Africa and to .8% annual
population growth that means it's
doubling every I think 20 23 years or so
um probably around 40 million uh Farm
families don't have access to better
technology extremely high rates of
absolute poverty and uh around 30 38%
average child malnutrition stunting and
that's chronic
malnutrition so the lesson number nine I
had a great conversation with The
Graduate students and ask them all
what's your minor because one of the
best things about Cornell is they make
you take the
minor and I want
to take up an issue because they were I
learned today in the discussion with the
students that if you had a master's
degree you only have to take one
minor so why did you guys make me take
two
minors anyway the point is there and I
and I benefited from both my mins
tropical soils and a eon by the way um
but it helps you to be able to reason
better I think when you go and meet with
leaders who are unconvinced about the
importance of this technology in their
countries read outside your Fields is
the is the main lesson I think I learned
here and um and be able to make this
case when the time comes and the time
did come because uh in 20 2019 Cor
and Seed systems group and a and a
couple of brilliant guys from an A
consultancy called sat Guru came
together and we fann out across Africa
and we studied the seed systems in all
these countries and we put together a
business plan and it's only costs $95
million over five years so if anybody
need knows any billionaires roaming
around the streets of itha I'm here
until
Friday and uh I've got a business plan I
want to talk to them about
there's some of the outputs our our our
uh our report card if you will uh every
every nonprofit has to give their impact
or their report card and that's ours so
far you know we've reached uh all right
around 7 thou these these these data are
a little bit old I think we're about
750,000 Farmers reached so far in those
countries and uh produced about uh well
by the end of this year it will be well
over 5,000 metric tons of seed and what
we're also very proud of is the training
we do a lot of training some of it
degree based most of it short courses on
everything from breeding uh to seed
production to running an aggro dealer
shop yeah I just want to show some
images of what this work looks like on
the ground and then I'll wrap up but
that's the work in Burundi a very
important producer of beans an extremely
impoverished country uh with Farms very
small Farm sizes becoming hungrier by
the day average child malnutrition over
50% it's one of the highest in the world
and it's a green country there's no
reason they can't double the yields of
all those crops and and malnutrition in
Brun uh jibuti strange country um you
know
uh very Aid no rainfed agriculture but
they do grow forages and a bit of
vegetables and and we're in there thanks
to some funding from ea uh Dr
Congo very exciting country to work in
uh we're in on U hybrid maze seed
production and uh biofortified Bean uh
seed
production and uh Eritrea Wheats the big
crop there te as well and uh we D the
government had been importing about uh
three containers per year of hybrid maze
seed at great cost and you know arria is
a bit of a Hermit Kingdom they don't
have much Forex to go around and so they
said you can teach us how to produce
hybrid Maze We Said Yes we can and so
now they're producing hybrid maze in
nraa as well and reducing their Forex
expenditures um
Madagascar can't say enough about how
important the work is there extremely
impoverished country also 45 50% child
malnutrition
about 80% absolute poverty um and we
need to work on all fronts in Madagascar
very hard to raise money for that
country and uh lesson number 10 is
probably a little bit unexpected but I
just wanted to point out as breeders we
have to realize sometimes the local
varieties are better and that is the
case in in Somalia we're working on
sorghum there and I really have serious
doubts we're going to find anything
better than the local variety I think
that's true for certain varieties of low
non- irrigated rice around Africa
sometimes the local variety wins and
that's okay you know but do we stop
there no we can also introduce other
crops and so yeah we continue to work in
Somalia on uh on other fronts South
Sudan already mentioned Sagal Togo thank
you very
much for this wonderful talk I'm
wondering where uh for improved ities
are coming from are your leaders working
at public or government funed or these
coming from CGS where are you doing this
and is there an effort make a big consum
or Club
thats it's a great idea that last one
you know if I was a little
younger I would tackle that you know
just get these African governments CH uh
sharing varieties is hugely powerful and
they don't realize um that they that
they should be doing it but yeah a lot
of them come from the CG a lot of them
come from leading Nars I can mention a
few Molly has extremely talented
breeders Uganda there's Natural Born
breeders uh
Tanzania um yeah so we move around
we uh we work with those breeders who
have good materials and are willing to
share which is not always the case with
the
CG I don't want to get into that
so you got to have a plan B yeah that's
a big scramble you know how do where are
we going to get that that new rice
variety for you know Togo yes uh I just
want to ask what is something You'
worked on that's been really frustrating
or challenging and also what's a project
that you've done or are doing that
you're really excited
about okay that's a great couple of
great questions I would
say sorghum really kind of beats me you
know it's a wonderful crop and I wish it
was easier to convince Farmers to take
an improve variety but there's just
something about that Exquisite
adaptation it's had the time to develop
in certain
ecologies and you can show farmers
everything and they just they
just not going there the other question
where I'm most excited about working
right
now I would say guinea B
you know because it's just one of those
classically forgotten countes and it
rains in Guinea BAU and the soils are
fine and child malnutrition is is is
extremely high so they haven't done any
variety testing since
right we can we can bring in varieties
and we can get them into production so
yeah it's very exciting we're being
funded there uh by the world food
program
yeah
yes I want to know how would you
describe African government's support
towards do you find
your it's so it's so schizophrenic
that's not the right term but it's it's
just Case by case you know uh we work in
countries where I'm worried right now
where I'm standing whether we're going
to deliver they are so on it and so in
partnership with it we work in some
countries where they're like go yeah
whatever you know have fun you know we
don't know why you're here and that's
frustrating uh so it's just kind of
everything in between you um generally
speaking I would say if you can
communicate well to the people on Top
This is the importance of a
participatory Society in a
non-participatory
society sometimes it's only really one
guy or a person taking all the decisions
and if you can't get to them you're not
going to get far but if you
can uh yeah then you know I don't I
think we're living in a day and age when
nobody gets to go out public and and say
don't give my people new seed you know I
think that that would not work even in
some of these totalitarian governments
or countries and so that's what makes it
the right time I think to get in and
actually do this work thank
you a formal informal flow of that
farmers look like if you sent variety A
and B upet about both of them people you
know variety a ends up being
sold and ab fails how do you figure out
yeah
um it's messy uh it often passes through
aggro dealers or or the village based
advisors to the seed companies but
there's nobody in charge of that
communication you know I've got a team
we're about 30 people there's I I don't
have somebody who's in charge of that
and and so what you need is a volume of
of transaction you know enough people to
involved in the transaction so that at
least one of them is going to say hey
your variety
sucks
and and the seed company hears it you
know or the Breeders hear it you know so
that's that's the way I would say you
need that's why we try to work at scale
because if you don't have a certain
scale then that that critical
communication just gets gets stifled you
know yes you raing
awareness yeah well what I can tell you
is what they are not is probably easier
they are not leader farmers and we run
into that kind of language everywhere
and a leader farmer tends to be the guy
with a car you know he's up there in the
church uh tends to be
male and you know just kind of kind of
kind of the big guy uh and that's
absolutely death for promoting you know
new uh kind of controversial technology
because nobody listens to them they've
always had all the advantages and they
associate you and your technology with
the elite sector of society so we go to
a lot of
pains along with Paul Seward's team the
farm input promotions group and here I
have to give a major shout out that is
not our intellectual property they
invented that Lock Stock and Barrel we
actually have a non-disclosure agreement
with that so um we're we're obliged to
to work in partnership with fips fips is
like literally uh you know a sister
organization to us and they figured out
that Mo that model who the BBA
is is someone who loves Agriculture and
is a good
communicate those of if I could sum it
boil it down to two characteristics you
know that we're looking for is somebody
who really loves Agriculture and so and
then and would would care enough to go
around and talk to Farmers about
it so one question onine I think
indirectly answered it but it was how
many people are employed
by you know a full-time staff uh in our
two offices about 30 but we work we
through uh local National coordinators
quite quite a bit and so you can not
double the number but at least add
another 15 or so people and uh they do
the day-to-day management of our work on
the ground they're part-time and some of
them are are are breeders working for
the Nars who get an agreement from their
Institute to work with seed systems
group and so they're on our business
yeah we don't want to become big we're
not we we're we're fighting to stay
small Susan
it seems
like
of so they get to know each other
across that part of the go that that
because I would think that local nwork
very powerful
terms Bas
butross yeah yeah you know it's it's
expensive uh
and we we have an obligation to train
the people who are doing the work you
know so that they understand what
they're doing we often neglect to inv
invite important people that's probably
you know partly my fault um
but uh we're going to do that in
November we're actually going to bring
all of our practitioners together in um
in Nairobi in November and have one of
those kind of sessions where we actually
have a few important people in the room
and they can talk to each
other
excited reason I mentioned how important
was the kind of training I
re without that honestly without that
Network my own Cort yeah not the leaders
of Rockefeller oh you're talking about a
community of practitioners kind of thing
yeah oh totally yeah no that's that's
the other objective of the of the
November meeting is errans are going to
be talking to Le and they're at the same
stage of development of their seed
system very exciting yeah they'll learn
way more from the each other than they
will
from this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu