this is a production of Cornell
University so I've been the leader of
Nua for about 10 years
um and uh it's been it's been
interesting it's been
exciting so what is
Nua it's a knowledge Network essentially
Farmers share data through the network
providing us with feedback and guidance
of how to use that data and better
presented on the web to them the weather
data is collected every 15 minutes and
tabulated in hourly and daily summary
tables we're collecting precipitation
temperature dupoint temperature humidity
Leaf wetness solar radiation wind speed
and wind direction and now uh the
company that provides the weather
instruments rainwise Incorporated has
allowed people to add two optional
sensors and the most uh popular shall we
say Are soil temperature and soil
moisture we designate sister stations
within the network to plug in data where
we have missing data so that for
instance if we're accumulating degree
days we don't have an oops you know a
week or so of missing data and the
degree day value would be erroneous and
we extrapolate 1 hour gaps in our
data essentially what we're doing is
we're we're creating with that data
decision support tools for IPM and Crop
Production so a little bit about noa's
history it was created in 1996 by Kurt
petol who was the vegetable IPM
coordinator in the New York State IPM
program it started out as an
association with membership levels
different pay membership levels today
it's free access with land grant and
grower support
to provide some funding we initially
were using sensor and Campbell
instruments sensor was bought by a
company called sensotronic those
stations became Obsolete and today we've
got rainwise Incorporated weather
instruments onset instruments we serve
up airport location data as well as
state climatology mezzet through our
Network initially we were going out and
manually downloading the data from
computers putting that data into a fax
and faxing that information out to
Growers or we were recording messages on
what was called a Koda phone for those
of you who might remember those days uh
and then Growers could dial that number
and find out what the report dour was
but uh then we went to modems and we
were collecting data every day and
serving it up on a website today we've
got a few instruments that are still
connected in through file transfer
protocol or FTP
um we're trying to phase that out
rainwise wrote that software for us the
majority are connected in through the
internet through an internet interface
that comes with the weather instrument
and uh rainwise just launched launched a
cellular data plan and has a cellular
modem instrument as well we now have as
of yesterday or the day before 375
active weather stations in the network I
think a total is probably pushing closer
to 400 but they come and go as they're
taken out for maintenance or what have
you as as you can imagine these are
instruments on the ground collecting
data and we're we've got a footprint in
20 States primarily in the East
Northeast and into the Midwest we have
10 member states plus some individual
members growers in non-member states can
now join so Nua is open access providing
data in real time query based decision
support models with built-in biofix or
the ability of Growers to enter their
own biofix information for for the
models the models are interactive with a
a user
interface this is just to give you a
snapshot of the homepage nu. cornell.edu
I don't really you know this is kind of
like the sequencing slide you don't have
to read this it's okay so uh basically
the key is that there's a blue menu that
follows you throughout the website and
you can access
weather data pest forecast station Pages
crop management models and some crop
pages that we have to serve up IP
information and other information of use
to the grower as well as some
information about weather stations so if
a grower wanted to buy a weather
instrument they could and they would be
able to learn how to do that um the Blue
menu on the website provides the
interactive
tools and a a neat thing that I've used
quite a bit is up here in the corner is
a National Weather Service little query
box um so you can put in your city and
state hit go and you'll go to the
National Weather Service site and you'll
be able to find out what the forecast is
for your
location as of now as many of you know
the internet knows where you are at all
times okay so big brother is watching
and this map will save to your location
and send enter the next time you come in
on where you're located so um you know
for a lot of you Millennials and stuff
that's really cool you're excited about
that for people like me it's
like somebody knows where I am I don't
know if I can handle it so but anyway
it's kind of cool because then you know
it basically centers the map for you and
you don't have to move it and and
whatnot there are station Pages for
every weather station in the network and
these provide quick links to Tool tools
they are built on default biofix dates
based on historic records that faculty
have for Apple insects grape phenology
stages things like that or typical
planting dates for onions or potatoes
Etc so um although these aren't
interactive you can still get to the
interactive results but these are quick
links for Degree Days daily and hourly
summaries and then pest forecast quick
links gives you a lat lawn elevation
tells you the station sensors the last
good download date uh that occurred at
that station
location so this gives you a snapshot of
noa's current
map um I grabbed this snippet off the
website I think again day before
yesterday or yesterday and this is
zoomed in here on New York
um this is the entire map here and it
shows that we're now reaching into
Minnesota we've got individuals in the
plains Nebraska Iowa Illinois and then
most recently Virginia became a member
and North Carolina so uh we're moving to
the South which kind of makes for a
little nail biting of you know are the
models really useful down there so we do
a lot of discussion with the faculty
that are requesting expansion of NOA to
make sure that it's going to be
applicable
so why am I here well number one I
contacted Jeff and I said hey Jeff can I
give a seminar on NOA everybody's been
telling me I got to get the word out you
know I got to tell Cornell University
about this so I said okay let's do this
and he said all right so how might Nua
benefit programs in soil and crop
Sciences well Nua basically now is
operating the weather stations on your
research Farms the Aurora
station the willsboro station and the
station at shayz minor are the stations
that are on your research Farms Musgrave
research Farm willsboro research farm
and wh minor Institute so um I've worked
with the Cornell um facilities the
Cornell oh my gosh a experiment station
yes Julie I'm at the New York State a
experiment station you guys are the
Cornell University egg experiment
station so I've been working with the
facilities director to get these weather
stations plugged in on the various
research Farms that Cornell operates
right now we really don't have very many
tools for agronomic crops we do have an
alala Weevil tool that is built on a
degre day model that Ray CRS developed
uh back in the day and then obviously
we've got a number of degree days that I
think might be of use to uh agronomic
crops so the two main reasons that I'm
here one is to stimulate your thinking
about developing and utilizing NOA to
benefit agriculture how might that
happen what is your vision contact us
let us know and also to raise awareness
of what Nua has to
offer so to that end I'm going to give
you a little sampling of the predictive
models or what is increasingly these are
being called tools now I always used to
call them models so if I say models or
tools you'll know that it's a
transitioning terminology and I
basically mean the same thing so we've
got phenology models for plant diseases
and insects crop management tools and
weather products again they're realtime
query based decision support with
built-in biofix or an interactive user
interface where they can enter the
biofix this is the pest forecast menu
right here off of the web and basically
we've got 14 plant disease Tools 11
insect phenology tools these are now
increasingly most most of them are
providing a 5-day forecast look into the
future so that a grower can prepare if
they know they're going to be at risk
for a certain disease or insect
developmental stage they can get their
spray set up and go out and apply that
spray in a timely fashion they can
assess that risk learn IPM info and get
decision support through these tools and
again they're
interactive so this just gives you a a
snippet of the great forecast models
that are available in NOA most of the
models that are served up on the website
have a little utility here on the left
hand side of the page where you would
select a disease or insect for grapes
everything is on one page so you would
select we have grape Berry moth grape
diseases or DM cast which is a
simulation model for grape vine Downey
mildew available from this page we are
building now because we're in so many
states we'll have a state select the
state and then the weather station
location is selected we default to the
current date but you can go back in time
so you can select a historic date as
well obviously I needed to do that to
create this snippet by going back to
last spring when you first go onto the
page the map tab is active so if you
don't know the weather station location
you'll when you select the state here
will be the IM of the map centered and
you can zoom in on that so that you can
then decide well I think this is really
the geographic region I'm interested in
you click on the icon on the map and the
name of the weather station location
plugs in there so after you've decided
your ending date you hit calculate and
the results pop up on the results Tab
and then there's more info we might have
fact sheets uh information on how to use
the model more effectively that type of
thing in the more info tab
so here you can see a pretty common
format that we use is a table showing
the two past days the current
date and the forecast days on this one
we actually tabulate three diseases of
grapes phomopsis powdery Milo and black
rot a little bit of information about
those models is here what the models are
doing what they're
calculating the grower can change the
phenological state age we're estimating
that 10-in Chute growth is where we're
at on May 29th of last year this is
based on
conquered a variety of grapes that is
grown for juice it's probably the
largest number of acreage of any variety
of grapes grown in New York but in this
region most Growers are growing wine
grape varieties they might be growing
Chardonnay
reeling and so they can change the
phenological stage the other thing is my
colleague in IPM was telling we were
talking about how spring is kind of
we're all nail biting because spring is
here and yet it's not really April so
one of the things that can happen is you
can go from 3in Shoot growth in grapes
to 12in shoot growth in grapes in a
matter of 3 days if it's really hot and
so this gives flexibility to the model
and changing this may change the disease
management messages so these go you
would scroll down the page and then you
would get to the disease management
messages for each of the diseases in
this model so that gives you a
perspective on how most of the models
work some of the crop management tools
that we have not that many we have three
primarily focused around
apples they again are assessing risk
providing decision support and they're
Prim arily are focused on crop load
management
irrigation and freeze
risk this is the Cornell Apple
carbohydrate thinning model again
there's the utility on the left to enter
the weather station it'll have the state
selection
soon the current date or the date of
Interest would be selected the results
tab will show up and the grower would
enter their green tip date in the h
Valley were already at green tip and
apples not yet in the Lake Ontario
region
thankfully they would enter their Bloom
date and then there's a button here and
they would click calculate this table
then builds
below this utility to
provide these data related to the tree
carbohydrate
status starting from the green tip date
down to the current date that you've
selected which is the green
row light blue rows above tan rows below
are building the forecast down in time
and then below this is the carbohydrate
balance of the
chart and the end user can scroll along
this and little popup boxes will show up
saying the date and the carbohydrate
balance so giving basically what is
being shown at that point on that graph
the take-home message for your purposes
is if the tree is in deficit if it's in
carbohydrate balance deficit it's going
to be easier for the grower to thin the
apples off the tree so they have to
reduce their thinner rate if the
carbohydrate balance is in the PO on the
positive side on the plus side it's
going to be harder to thin the apples
off the tree has a lot of reserved
carbohydrate they're going to hang on to
all that fruit they're going to be able
to ripen that fruit so it's going to be
harder to thin and that's what this
model does it's going to tell them to
either increase the chemical thinner
rate or decrease the chemical thinner
rate this model is probably the biggest
driver in terms of end users putting
weather stations on their Farm it is
huge in terms of crop quality crop value
if you thin your crop too much you don't
have a crop if you under thin you don't
grow premium quality apples that are big
and bring a premium
price this is a new utility that was
developed by Arte atano the northeast
regional climate center that is
estimating 2in soil temperature across
the Northeast so these tools that are
developed by the climate Center provide
outputs like this they're colorcoded
maps that generate this graphic and you
can see here as a of two days
ago the soils were warming in the Hudson
Valley but they were still kind of cold
in the atex up in Maine and then to a
certain extent along Lake
Ontario what are some of the weather
products that you might be interested in
so on the weather product menu what I've
done is I've highlighted this because
this is new as of this month we just
rewrote the degre day calculator that
art ello and I had created about I don't
know 12 years ago or so 8 years ago um
and when we migrated our database the
programming language wasn't compatible
so we've just kind of resurrected this
and we're really excited about it but
basically under weather data you can get
degree day tables for 11 base
temperatures and they accumulate from
January 1st March 1st April 1st 1 and
May 1st again based on end user requests
these base temperatures usually
are uh borrowed from the models that we
have that we've built in Nua so um for
instance this 32 is for apples scab
ascospore
maturity um I think 4C is for cabbage
maggot this bizarre one is for grape
Berry moth because the research was done
in degrees Centigrade
and the translation ended up being you
know
4714 f um we will serve up our hourly
data in tables summarized and these are
month-by-month tables providing daily
summary tables and then again the degree
day calculator so I'll spend a little
bit more time on this because I think
this is an area that is growing and I've
been explaining this to our end users
and they're seeing how important this
can be to document issues that have
occurred if they've particularly got
crop insurance or something like that
and they need these data they need to be
able to document them and print them off
or what have you so it was a mild winter
right yeah it was a mild winter except
for um Valentine's Day there was a
significant freeze event on Valentine's
Day and in Highland New York which is in
the Hudson Valley the the Data Logger
the weather station recorded this event
so in the hourly data you can see how
the the tables are presented and you can
see each hour how cold it
got if we look at the daily summary
table for this same event you'll see how
the minimum was
-10.6 de f with fairly cold weather each
day preceding and after that event but
before that it was actually really mild
um my colleagues in the Hudson Valley
have been out cutting buds on Peach and
sweet cherry and pretty much the peach
crop down there is toast most of the
flower buds were killed and the sweet
cherries the jury is still out on that
so this again it gives the grower a
perspective they can look back in time
and see how cold did it get for how long
to know whether their crop whether
particular varieties that they know are
Hardy or not Hardy were damaged
on the other end of the spectrum when we
talk about severe rain events I was Dow
giving a talk in North Carolina which
again is is a new partner for newa and I
said hey you know what was a weird event
that that that occurred that I could go
back and grab the data and and share
with the Growers and show them how they
can access that and they said my gosh we
got like 5 Ines of rain in three days in
October and we were trying to harvest
and it was impossible and we couldn't
get out to harvest so I went and sure
enough uh this weather station that went
in last year Hendersonville North
Carolina went to the all- weather data
utility this really should say October
but I think I was just too lazy to
update it for the purposes of that but
these are the October data this is the
hourly table for that event and you can
see a third of an inch of rain to almost
a half of an inch of rain was being
logged by The Tipping bucket every hour
and then when we look at the daily
summary sure enough there's that 5 Ines
of rain I'm not sure what might have
fallen on the 30th of September but I
didn't want to try to patch that
together again these tabulate by month
so uh yeah that was significant they
couldn't get out to harvest their fruit
some of that fruit starts to drop and
there's a lot of crop loss associated
with that
so building
capacity what can we do and what have we
been doing to try to build capacity um
as of 2010 we lost all of our funding
support for Nua and it
was coincidental that a lot of my
colleagues in New England wanted to join
NOA and so it presented with a challenge
and an opportunity at the same time that
we could build this partnership and they
could help fund Nua and sustain it into
the future future our partners including
the northeast regional climate Center
and rainwise Incorporated were also
absolutely essential during that
downturn so the northeast regional
climate Center Partners with us they
house the new a climate database they
provide model programming into the pi
design tools so the principal
investigator decides what they want this
tool to be and they help the programmer
decide how to program it with the data
that we have they provide data quality
control meteorological expertise and
guidance and the nice thing is that they
have a high level of interest in
agricultural applications of climate
data as many of you
know they have also helped us create
automated outage reports that go out to
weather station contacts and I have
gotten a lot of emails back initially I
thought oh no they're going to be mad
we're telling them their weather station
is down but for the most part they're
really excited about getting that
report this is our slide of Partners and
you know it's a good thing it's starting
to get really crowded so we have two
apple grower associations one in
Minnesota one in North Carolina that
partner with Nua Penn State Rutter
University of Connecticut University of
Massachusetts and University of Vermont
our partners and this year New Hampshire
and Virginia Tech have joined
these Partners pay ,750 per year to be
members of Nua that's our subscription
fee rainwise Incorporated has been a
fantastic partner they have helped even
with software programming putting Leaf
wetness sensors onto their stations and
developing their stations so they
actually fit the needs of our Network
and this is a uh just the menu for the
about weather stations and a snapshot of
the weather instrument this is leap
wetness sensor it currently actually is
attached over here to the Tipping bucket
so that it's facing north at a 45° angle
which it has been shown to be the best
for the
Northeast so this chart is pretty
exciting and also a bit
daunting so um I became lead in
2005 we launched the current website
that I've shown you in 2009
and the number of instruments in the in
the system has just grown significantly
over these last 7 to eight years we now
have 10 Statewide
members and individual farms and
actually it's only five other states
because one of those States is now one
of the 10 Statewide members we ingest
airport data and we've put into place a
humidity and correction factor because
obviously the situation in terms of the
microclimate near an airport is quite
different from an agricultural field so
we have a relative humidity correction
factor and we also have a leaf wetness
estimate in place for those stations and
we're partnering with uh the state
climatologist in New Jersey for their
data that's this green bar
here so pretty exciting in terms of
growth in the number of weather stations
over the last s to eight
years our farmers and multipliers again
we have the individual farms in Illinois
Iowa Maryland Nebraska and
Wisconsin Soil and Water Conservation
districts have written grants to fund
small mesonets we have a a Mesonet
funded by them in Sena County in the
wine uh wine grape growing region County
and Regional extension programs have
partnered with us suffk County on Long
Island probably most notable they have
about 20 or more more weather stations
in their Network again primarily on
Vineyards but also in on apple farms and
in vegetable potato Fields down there we
have a couple of arboretums and
Wilderness areas obviously the airport
locations and state climatology mezzet
so we're essentially crowdsourcing our
data and pulling it
in the priorities of our stakeholders we
pay pretty close attention to and
obviously sustainable funding for most
of us we know how crucial that is um
we'd like to rebuild our website it's
going on 7 years old now and it would be
nice for it to be responsive so whatever
size your screen was or your device was
it would adjust for that um we'd love to
have more weather station locations and
one way to do that very quickly would be
to use the national digital forecast
database of grided data and serve up
virtual station locations our end user
users would like apps that reside on
their phone that could interface with
some of our data uh alerts and alarms
for frost uh heat events things like
that and they'd also like for us to be
able to cach their biofix
data they want more models and tools
station maintenance and troubleshooting
has been a big uh emphasis of mine in
the last year and a half because of a
funded project um and then I'm here to
promote awareness because so many of
them have been saying Julie you've got
to tell the story you you've got to get
out and tell the story about
NOA so in terms of research and
development uh on weather data we
developed the leaf wetness estimator
essentially the simplest and least uh
prone to errors on the negative or
positive side was using an hour with
relative humidity above
90% as well as an any hour that would be
raining
obviously um I arano has written and
done research on data quality control
for
precipitation and when he finds that a
tipping bucket has either over recorded
or under recorded rain as based on what
the grided data is saying around that
instrument he will send an email out to
them saying hey you know we think
there's something wrong with your uh
tipping bucket rain gauge again we'd
like to build these virtual stations and
if we do we can compare back and forth
between the on the data and the virtual
data a really nice fertile ground of
research would be would be developed and
I heard from Abby Sean just um yesterday
or the day before that she and R Deano
are going to be looking at that soil
temperature estimate map and comparing
that to sensors actually placed in
different soil types across New York so
they can see whether there's um an
impact of soil type on that
it product development we've been
looking at an enua email alert we beta
tested this with apples in 2011 and it's
been running for three years now with
grape Growers they really like this and
we'd like to develop this into a
subscription based product essentially
for any location they choose they can
get the email at a time of their
choosing and it gives them the results
of the models uh basically in an email
format they don't have to go into the
website and click and click uh to get
the information we've got that degree
date calculator that basically you put
the start date and the end date and
it'll give you the degree day
accumulation for that range of dates uh
for that particular location we wrote a
grant recently to develop a cache for
end user inputs uh first trap catch
dates screen tip dates Blossom dates
things like that but unfortunately it
wasn't funded so that's going to remain
on the drawing board um we also had this
in a grant but this also we did not get
that Grant um but art Deano and the
climate smart farming group are moving
forward on this uh piece so that's
exciting and we are still on the drawing
board on our responsive web
design we are currently upping the
vegetable and apple insect tools all the
vegetable tools with the 5day for cast
data in the Apple fireblight tool we're
incorporating an epithetic infection
Potential from a third-party software
called Mary blight art Agnello has
written a San Jose scale model for
apples that should go into uh be
implemented this year I was doing a
workshop with apple Growers and we were
looking at the Apple irrigation model
and it became clear that we've got some
work to do on that model based on some
input from that Workshop
um and we're always open to end user
suggestions for improvements and over
the last six months we've created a list
a wish list of over 40 different models
that are out there in the literature and
the scientific literature that that we
could incorporate into this
system so what's the
impact NOA is transforming weather
information and knowledge into tools
farmers are being able to share
resources for weather data collection
analysis distribution And archiving
through integration of all these
networks via cloud computing we're
pushing forecasts out 5 days in
advance so big deal what's the impact
before we even launched this website
before we even grew to where we are
today we did a survey in 2007 and we
asked growers in New York that were
using Nua and these were Apple grape
onion and potato Growers
primarily whether Nua using tools
reduced
sprays improved spray timing alerted of
pest risk or enhanced IPM and all of
them virtually all of them agreed or
strongly
agreed sometimes if it's a bad year for
diseases you won't get that reduced
spray because if it's rainy and wet all
season long you're going to be chasing
that disease all season
long these same Growers reported on
average that they can save
$119,500 per year in spray costs and
that was 2007 costs and save 264,000 per
year in crop loss again these are high
value Horticultural
crops 99% of end users of Nua at that
time would recommend Nua use to Farmers
and I think that underlines why this has
been so popular and why it has grown so
much uh in recent years we
now have over 2 million page views per
year in
Nua some anecdotes I use the newest site
almost every day early in the season the
orchard was largely scab free for the
first time in several years the manager
depended heavily on Nua and could see
differences between their on-site
station and the one they had been using
two New Jersey Growers of apples last
year had the best thinning results ever
using our tool so the outcomes are
better IPM reduced pesticide use
improved Environmental Protection better
crop management improved crop quality
improved yield and definitely enhanced
decision
support so in the
future we've got some new partners and
some new directions to consider we've
just recently embarked on a partnership
with envir weather which is a similar
program based at Michigan State Unity
University and I've got a call in to
talk this up and see how we can move
forward to collaborate we have models
they want and they have models we want
and could really benefit
from we've been embarking on
conversations with two other state
climatology mesonets North Carolina's
econet and Delaware's Doos I probably
killed the pronunciation of that but
deos a New York state mezzet is going in
some of you may be aware of this
125 weather stations are going in across
New York funded with FEMA dollars in
response to Hurricane
Sandy uh tropical storm Irene and I
think uh lee uh so we are also
discussing with the the Mesonet on how
we can partner in the future the climate
smart farming group part of the Cornell
Institute for climate change and
agriculture is another area that's rip
for collaboration and we'll be uh
partnering with them and discussing how
to how to move forward and we've also
been discussing how we can partner with
ag radar at the University of
Maine again our stakeholder objectives
we keep these closely in mind I've
talked about pretty much all of these um
we've got a newad data product for
thirdparty
software uh called rimo so we just
launched that this month so that may
bring in some revenue for that product
and I would love to create a developer
sandbox so that developers could go in
on the web and plug in their messages
dates when those messages should occur
uh base temperatures key risk
Windows uh you know length of wetness
that type of stuff and that model would
just essentially autogenerate you'd be
able to Val validate it in research mode
make sure it was working and then
potentially implement it wouldn't that
be
nice so the challenges and opportunities
going forward funding funding funding
obviously is Big we know that
Cooperative Extension and land grant
universities are losing funding across
the US and that's why our yearly fees
have gone down down down we've tried to
keep those as low as we can State
climate tology mezzet are in the same
boat in terms of funding and I'm working
with them to figure out how on our
website we can attribute that data to
that specific uh State mezzet and I've
got like two or three really good ideas
going forward that I think may work
we're going to have to figure out how do
we blend with existing systems like msus
and viral weather what is the geographic
reach of our models and and how do we
validate that it would would be really
great to have a model for leaf wetness
Leaf wetness sensors stink they're the
bane of plant Pathologists Across the
Nation we can't stand them we need a
really good algorithm for leaf wetness
and there are scientists across the US
and in Canada that have been working on
this for for some
time we'd like to obviously utilize the
national digital forecast database and
realtime mesoscale analysis data to do a
better job with precipitation humidity
and leaf wetness in those virtual
locations obviously data quality control
is always a challenge and very
important and we want that website
upgrade and responsive web design the
New York State IPM program is looking to
staff a newa coordinator full-time if we
can get the money to underwrite that
position and we would love to have a
programmer also in the New York State
IPM program to to help us build these
various
tools so basically Nua is access to IPM
decision support providing for the
sustainable management of pests using
methods that minimize environmental
health and economic
risks we use plant disease epidemiology
insect phenology plant phenology and
crop management to generate these
phenology models and forecasts we've got
40 plus tools on our wish list
we want more station locations better
end user cach and alarms better quality
control and support and that developer
sandbox would be pretty pretty cool I
think we are doing a really good job in
fruits particularly tree fruit and grape
in New York and across the Northeast
we're doing a pretty good job in
vegetables for onions and potatoes we've
got some sweet corn products a cabbage
maggot prod
product we've just put a grant in to
look at uh insect phenology models in
Christmas trees that could spill over
and help the nursery trade in New York
and across the area that that NOA
reaches into but we could do a lot
better job in field crops and livestock
could we do anything with that Don rutz
professor of Veterinary entomology when
he was director of the IPM program said
absolutely Julie of course and I expect
that you're going to do that so Nua
again is open access real time query
based decision support with built-in
biof fixes and an interactive
userfriendly
interface and with that I'll end and
thank you very much for your attention
today and open it up for any questions
you might
have this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu