this is a production of Cornell
University hear me thanks Lynn for that
for that wonderful introduction and for
uh Decades of of friendship and
professional collaboration uh and thank
you for the opportunity to share uh our
research program at the Danforth Center
uh with with with Cornell and everyone
who's doing some fantastic plant science
here um you might see some familiar PL
uh familiar faces some references to to
Cornell folks um as Lynn said I'm the
director of the X-ray Imaging facility
at the Danforth Center uh and if you are
not already aware uh the danforce center
is the world's largest uh nonprofit
independent plant science uh Research
Institute and uh we have the fortunate
position to really look into a lot of
issues in plant science especially food
security that that other places don't
really have the freedom or the support
um to
do um I'm a research scientist in Dr
Chris Topps lab Chris is the pi and he
started the lab in 2013 using
phenotyping to look at root biology and
that has expanded to include not only
roots and genetics but everything
surrounding the roots so there's a wide
range of expertise that we share and as
I expect many of you here are starting
to realize that no one lab will have
nearly enough expertise to get
everything done you must collaborate you
must find ways to work with your
colleagues to really pull more of the
science out of all these projects so you
can see the list on the left plant
genotypes and uh genetics and
phenotyping my background in microscopy
and imaging there's cell biology there's
a engineering chemical engineering and
perhaps most importantly is
computational science because all the
beautiful images are mostly just
greeting cards until we can actually
pull some of that biological information
back out the other end of these these
really cool 3D
volumes so a couple different um
headings today um this is lab based
x-ray microscopy as opposed to working
at a synchrotron uh the lab base makes
it very very accessible there's of
course uh tradeoffs compared to
synchrotron Imaging uh so I'll cover
x-ray
tomography folks often say it's microct
or nanoct or macro now that's just the
resolution you're dealing with it's all
the same instrument so we have an x-ray
tomography instrument we have an x-ray
microscope which generates images in a
slightly different way um there is
specific application in volume electron
microscopy that is using xrm as a road
map to show you where in your resin
block you want to go for organel level
volume Imaging with with a Serial block
face sem or or a fibsem other the the
instrumentation that does uh tomography
at the nanometer
scale uh we've done some really sort of
exciting pioneering work looking at
micro risal fungi in situ which is a
really big Challenge and uh we've been
recently getting into looking at uh
x-ray Imaging of field soil to try to
see what can we understand about the 3D
structure of soil uh at multiple
scales so to begin with uh coming up on
eight years this August week took
delivery of a large format industrial
scale uh x-ray tomography instrument
this has been collaboration with veent
bioscience uh biosciences who make a lot
of of biorationals and and micro Ral
micro risal products for the commercial
Market in addition to uh part of an NSF
Grant now these large scale industrial
instruments are frequently found in
automotive and Aerospace Boeing will
probably have a dozen of these to look
at aircraft Parts they have to do
non-destructive Imaging of aircraft
parts to confirm that they're they're in
good shape and having taken two
different flights to get here I'm glad
they do that they know the parts are
working but they have to certify that
all the parts are good so they have uh
very large cabinets they can handle very
heavy weights they have a lot of
interior space to work with and these
were the advantages that we found uh in
the large format
instrument a quick review of how we
generate image data using um x-ray
tomography the setup is relatively
straightforward you have an x-ray Source
sample sits on a turntable in the middle
and you have a detector which collects
the image we uh broadcast x-rays through
the sample that impinges on the detector
we'll rotate that turntable over uh
typically 360 Degrees we'll collect
thousands of images from around all
those
angles and then computationally
reassemble all those images into a 3D
Volume that we can now explore
electronically um a lot of the
animations that you'll see today uh
certainly the colorful ones were done by
my senior technician uh Clara Libo she's
been developing her uh undergraduate
degree in art her master's degree in
electron microscopy and combining them
to really make some stunning and
striking ways of of presenting these 3D
volumes the Practical offshoot is we can
study these things without tearing them
apart if you wanted to count every seed
inside this pepper you could do that
digitally without having to hack it
apart um some of the very first work we
did was uh actually in collaboration
with Jason Londo who's at uh Geneva
hopefully you're online there Jason
hello
um they provided hundreds of of grape
ruses these are the stems Left Behind
after the berries of the grape are gone
and if you want to improve grape
varieties you can't just focus on making
big berries you need to understand the
underlying 3D architecture of what's
going to hold those berries and the
enormous amount of variability that
already exists in these
systems so certainly with our eyes we
can look at all the different grape
bunches and see that they're very very
different but how do we quantify these
differences so what we did is we scanned
hundreds of these um grap ruses and when
you are fortunate enough to work with um
an applied mathematician like Ma Lee
whose one one of her expertise areas is
looking at topology how do you evaluate
a 3D structure and so she uses something
called persistent homology which takes a
geodesic distance that you measure from
one end of a complicated structure to
the other and the timing at which
various components fuse into one another
or disappear can be mapped as a barcode
and this animation illustrates as you go
from the tips down into the central
trunk and down the various components
start to disappear and get melded into
one and these can be portrayed as a
barcode and so what's what that allows
you to do is take many different
complicated branching structures and
mathematically distinguish them using
this barcode sort of architecture again
this is Mao's expertise certainly not
mine so I am exceedingly fortunate to
work with such experts Margaret knows
knows ma very well also um yes the
pepper that you had up there before
assuming that the instrument everything
is all set up how long does it take for
the machine to to do the scanning to
generate the information which then
ultimately leads to the video yeah so
the question is how long specifically
that bell pepper scan how long does it
take to image and for that particular
bell pepper it was about 30 minutes it's
relatively non-dense relatively easy
Imaging so a 30 minute scan typically
3600 4 4,500 projections we can do it
shorter it will be lower resolution we
can go longer higher resolution so
there's a window within which we work
but for something low density like that
uh 30 minute scan covered
that so jumping it back into persistent
homology it's a way to uh
measure all these unique 3D scans of all
these hundreds of of GRA uh ruses that
we l
so I provided all the 3D data to m she
ran these 3D shapes we extracted uh
surface volumes she put the surface
volumes through a persistent homology
measurement tool that she
engineered and then used linear
discriminant analysis to group these
persistent homology
measurements based on their
characteristics and what turned out was
this LDA grouping of all the phenotypes
all the different 3D measurements of the
grae ruses corresponded very nicely to
the actual genotypes and it mapped very
very well so the very broad range of
shapes actually linked very nicely to
the differences in the
genotype so Mao was really the the
spearhead of the analysis side of that
again I had the easy part I just kept
putting gra rases in and scanning them
and getting these wonderful data back
from ma showing what we were learning
from it uh but the other thing we wanted
to learn was you know can we use this in
a predictive sense can we scan actual
grape bunches and start to incorporate
the size of the berry and the
distribution of the berries along the
grape rakus to start to come up with
modeling rules for how does a bunch of
grapes form what are the rules that
govern the shape does it stop at a
certain point does it stop when it
contacts does it stop at a certain
weight and these are some of the the the
measurement data that went into this
paper that that Ma again wrote and and
Jason was part of I was a part of Dan
Chitwood a number of folks who really
contributed to understanding more about
the how these these objects occupy 3D
space um and so again this is just an
animation that Mao put together that
that illustrates using these rules how
berries might grow and how they form but
it begins with mapping the racus itself
and then adding the modeling component
that we got from the
berries sorghum panicles sorghum is a
very important crop for food Security in
many areas of the world it grows often
in in places where corn does not um from
the image here you can see that its
tremendous variability in panicle
architecture uh when I started at the
Danforth there were a few scientists who
had collections of hundreds and hundreds
of of different panicles from an
association panel and so we realized
that that an X-Ray Scan of an entire
panicle would give us a really data
Rich uh information to work with so not
only could we see every individual grain
but then we could also o see the
underlying architecture of of the
panicle itself all the branches that
hold on to the grains so again if you're
breeding sorum and you want more grains
you need to understand what the impact
is on the supporting
architecture and again we're very
fortunate to work with very talented
postdocs um Mao again was part of this
but Ray Shia who's now a scientist at
venan in the Netherlands um they took
all the data we scanned over 900 sorghum
panicles
and what they were able to do was to use
these scan data to as you can see from
this graph graph map where along the
panicle the most grains were deposited
was it most in the middle most at the
ends and how did that vary across the
900 in the
population zoom in and actually analyze
the shape of every individual grain how
round were they how spherical how
ellipsoid and how was that shape range
distributed across the 900 R uh
varieties and
then electronically remove every single
grain not by hand but electronically and
then leave behind the branching
architecture and map that so now these
are all mappable measurable 3D trait
data phenotype data that can be compared
using multivariant statistics amongst
all these 900 different varieties and
what they found that the conventional
wisdom was the shape of the panicle
dictated the genetics and in fact that
was not the case you could find the same
examples of panicle architecture across
all the genotypes so that was not the
measure of interest and again working
with with all stars like Toby Kellogg uh
in the field of grass and grass biology
is just one of the benefits of being at
the Dan for surrounded by just really
phenomenal people that raise your
game far more important than that is a
Distillery located in downtown St Louis
where a friend of mine d Wards makes a
really spectacular sorghum whiskey so if
you ever get to St Louis you have to go
to this Distillery it's just four blocks
from Bush Stadium if you go to the Ball
Game U and and he'd love to give you
samples of the Sorghum whiskey and you
can see off to the side uh some of the
Sorghum panicles so always some
practical input from from the Imaging
that we're
doing again I told you the top lab
started out looking at uh corn roots and
corn root biology so how does one
actually measure and phenotype maze
Roots When obviously everything
important is happening below ground
so we've been breeding plants as humans
for thousands of years but only breeding
what we can see and improve and along
with that came root traits they are
there they vary but we've not been able
to work with them very efficiently so
when you look at these uh 15 different
maze root crowns it's a very informative
region right where the Roots come
together the Nexus right at the soil
line they were all grown in the
greenhouse in an artificial medium in
great big tree pots so the environmental
conditions were as identical as we can
practically make them so you see the
huge variety evident clearly the genes
are playing a big role in making Roots
decide how to occupy 3D space we want to
get a handle on those genes we want to
find a good strategy for doing that so
for us it begins with measurement so
we'll plant breeding populations out in
our research fields and then the whole
lab goes out there with shovels and lots
of coolers of water and and and all
sorts of bribes and it's literally
shovel oming a shovel will dig up a
useful volume right around that root
crown and then they all get brought back
to the lab they get washed we have
washing stations and dried and that
gives us really a very rich data source
that describes 3D architecture because
the maze root crowns are relatively well
signified at this stage they hold their
shape pretty well so comparison
between genotypes are are
valid so what we can do is a very rapid
three minute scan because we're not so
interested in the internal details but
it gives us a great model of the 3D
shape and that's what we're interested
in how can we get 3D trait information
about how Roots occupy 3D space and
again I get the easy part I get the fun
part I get to scan stuff and then dump
terabytes of data on our poor
computational science s who have to pull
information back out and what they've
been able to do is generate a number of
trait extraction pipelines these are
computational pipelines the first one
looks at overall how does that root
Crown occupy 3D space so n and Mao and
Tim and and Ry develop this this
computational pipeline which in stages
takes a 3D Volume and then bizes it
skeletonize it and then allows it to use
the geometry
tools available in many software
packages to map how this complicated
structure occupies 3D space and any
difference we see there we can assume
relatively equivalent environmental
conditions we can start to have
measurements that differ across
phenotypes the more measurement
differences we have in phenotypes let's
compare that to the actual DNA sequences
where we can obviously see differences
but we don't know which are the
important ones to what degree can we use
multivari statistics to map the measured
phenotypic differences onto the observed
sequence differences and start to zoom
in on potential genes that control root
architecture um we worked with
colleagues at Washington University in
the computer science program uh T's lab
and uh this was Dan's uh PhD work to
develop too rout which is a different
type of pipeline that starts with the
same data but now starts to look
individual High uh High Fidelity root
traits how are they branching where are
they branching how many branches and so
we have sort of different scales of
these pipelines to pull as much 3D trait
information out the other end as we
can it is possible to do live Plant
Imaging again we have the large
industrial scale
instrument and Alex actually got his
undergraduate degree here at Cornell
he's a PhD student in the lab he's got a
really interesting mutant that is um
altered in its ability to make nodal
Roots so we want to see where do nodal
Roots form or don't form if they don't
form did they never even start or did
they start in abort what's the Fate
what's controlling what's the morphology
of that so we can actually do in Vivo
x-ray Imaging because these are
relatively non-d Den tissues so that's a
living corn plant this is actually we
did this last week we're looking at that
region right at the soil line because
Alex is interested in nodal root
formation right in those first few nodes
right in under the soil and then the
first node above the soil so that's live
Imaging the scan was just seven minutes
long relatively low
energy but what it gives us is such
incredibly Rich detailed 3D information
that Alex this week is looking at Tiff
Stacks that go through all this and so
he has high resolution data through this
entire complicated region which will now
be pretty straightforward for him to
evaluate how many and where nodal roots
are or are not between the wild type and
the mutants so this is an example of
what we're doing immediately and and we
were fortunate enough to put together a
book chapter specifically on phenotyping
using this large format x-ray tomography
instrument but of course we're a root
lab we want to know what's going on
underground but short of our tornado
it's difficult to just sort of Peel back
what's going on to look directly at
what's happening without fundamentally
changing exactly what it is we want to
measure so we're devising systems to do
insitu imaging of
roots uh and this is what one of those
setups look like it's it's foam core PVC
it's relatively non-dense not the heavy
stuff for for construction but much more
lighter weight for for food and water
transport and we use a variety of
diameters um but when you look through
it this is an example of a live image
this isn't live but it's it's a a single
2D shot of a radaph and it's really hard
to see anything in this kind of view so
we'll take again thousands of images
through the entire volume and then use
computer reconstruction to rebuild the
volume so this is a flyth through
looking from top to bottom and with our
eyes it's relatively easy to spot the
roots certainly the primary roots and
the secondaries but trying to find the
laterals it starts to get more difficult
and that's always going to be the
problem is resolution I'll get to that
shortly but what this allows us to do if
I can see the roots then there is
software out there that allows me to
iteratively teach a computer how to find
and identify the roots how to identify
the soil how do I identify the air how
do I identify the sides of the pot
because I want everything removed except
to the roots because if we can do that
now we have effectively a root Crown we
have existing pipelines we can put that
root Crown in situ scan through that
Pipeline and start to pull out 3D root
trades
so that is the biggest purdle that
anyone in tomography has is segmentation
how do you teach a computer to only
measure what you want to see and
discount everything else we're getting
there I did this particular segmentation
but utterly impractically it took me
about three weeks for one volume um part
of that is the scan size this is about
45 G gabes because you need all that
information the more information the
better you can train the model but the
slower it goes so if you downsize you
now lose the resolution that you need to
train a model it's it's a horrible
tradeoff so one of the most frequently
asked questions I ever get
is what resolution can be achieved well
on the left on one side is a big pumpkin
that's very large on the right is an
acorn much much smaller uh the answer of
course is it depends the bigger your
sample the lower the resolution that's
true for all Imaging and microscopy uh
but specifically if we're talking about
insitu root Imaging the bigger the pot
the more dense the material the lower
the resolution so effectively what we're
going to do is choose different pots
based on the biology we want if we just
want to see where primary roots go we'll
use a big pot we'll never see laterals
to see laterals we have to use a much
smaller diameter but that is as unusual
as possible because the roots
immediately hit the sides and they
bundle up and and so you have to take a
variety pack way of approaching
different questions so resolution in uh
varies inversely with pot
diameter um scan time increases with
higher resolution like I said you can
increase the number of projections you
get better
resolution but you get gigantic file
sizes at least 40 gigabytes per volume
and and that's just a lot of heavy
lifting in addition to the massive
problem that we have have with data
management data storage we've got
hundreds of
terabytes just it it's we're actually I
think we're over a petabyte now just
with the X-ray stuff um and then what do
you grow the plant in ideally you want
to use field soil but that's really
dense so the more dense something is the
lower the resolution because you have to
blast more x-ray energy to get through
so you use various artificial media
which are less dense but sort of
departing from from a natural field soil
so again lots and lots of tradeoffs
resolution versus size versus time
versus um the growth
medium and ultimately we want to get as
much as possible we've got this lovely
kelbach volume and the the handdrawn
images are just spectacular but again
we're getting a tiny Glimpse whether
it's excavated root crowns or a little
inue pot that we grow for two or three
weeks it's a proxy for what's actually
happening so we're always dealing with
tradeoff so root Imaging we can get lots
of useful information and we keep
sneaking up on what's actually happening
in in the field but we'll never get
there there's never a physical system
where you're going to be able to
grow field siiz plants inside the
cabinet of an x-ray chamber it's simply
you simply can't so we have to find as
many proxies as possible to inform um
inform what we're
doing the large format instrument does
hit a resolution limit when you want to
see very very fine details and this is
exemplified by this um soybean axillary
bud system so the live imag is on the
the the phone imag is on the left it's
about the size of a a dime maybe but
it's very complicated it's a
very complicated uh intricate structure
lots of different small things going on
all in one small space there is no
microscope that will show you what that
looks like in 3D if
intact any light microscope you'll have
to slice it squash it make it small
electron microscopy embed it in resin
and cut the little tiny blocks you'll
never get that intact structure and
that's where the X-ray microscope
absolutely
shines so we have this is what the
inside of the system looks like uh again
veent and their parent company sum Tomo
chemical were very interested in micro
risal fungi root soil microb
interactions as well as carbon
sequesteration so they've been uh
generous supporters of the lab uh in
addition to the danor center itself
funding a third of of this
instrument and in fact you can see uh by
by the labels that there are actually
objective lenses that you swing into The
Beam path in order to magnify some of
the Imaging so it it's important to
compare
um how conventional xray tomography
generates an image uh with with the
X-ray microscope so recall that
conventional is just basic geomet R of
source sample detector and varying those
distances changes your magnification and
your
resolution the X-ray microscope you
still also have an x-ray source which
projects x-rays through a sample but
what that does is the x-rays strike a
scintillator the scintillator converts
x-rays into light and that's mounted on
the front of an objective lens so that's
where you get the cator X-ray to light
mounted on the lens and that's how you
generate the 3D image it's un
fortunately for the lab based systems a
relatively inefficient process so the
scan times take much much longer again
always trade-offs but what you're able
to get out the other end is uh I never
get tired of it every single day I come
in I get to see something that no one on
the planet has seen before and often
it's just stunning so if we look at this
um uh the soybean axial Bud typically
it's fixed and contrast enhanced so it's
not typically live Imaging but with a
large format instrument this is about as
good as you get to look at it with the
X-ray microscope you just get a
different Universe of
data I've seen beautiful paintings and
drawings of of plant Anatomy throughout
my entire career but it was not until I
sat down at the workstation and saw my
first soybean fluet scan when I
actually
appreciated how the anthers are
distributed in 3D space right around the
stigmatic surface and how principle that
was but you never get that in 3D but
here you do developing ovules there
pollen packed anthers distributed right
around the reproductive surface it is
Contra it is fixed and contrast enhanced
so the only way you can do sort of
Developmental studies is if you fix them
over developmental time so Time and
Relative Dimension in Space for any
Doctor Who fans
Tardis um is is part of of what we have
to to try to get developmental series
using this this uh imaging
technology um I was talking to Margaret
earlier about how striking some of the
3D volumes are they're very impactful
but not necessarily scientifically
useful other than putting Zooms in
context of the whole organ but what
those 3D volumes represent is what we
call a flyth through you're looking at
an arbitrary Dimension slice by slice
and seeing every single angle through
this very complicated structure in very
high resolution Rich detail you can do
cell level resolution in a 3D space
using this kind of Imaging again it has
to be fixed and contrast enhanced and on
the side there are some pretty typical
contrast agents which with my background
in electron microscopy are routinely
used phosphotungstic acid iodine osmium
um yanic stadler's lab in 2013 was the
first one to publish any kind of survey
using a a lab based x-ray microscope and
they looked at a few different plant
samples and we use that as a jumping off
point to really expand what they first
introduced and really explore a wider
range of of plant samples and improved
instrument technology so yanx lab was
the one who started it and we sort of
benefited from their pioneering work to
really Branch out into into other things
um it's also very important um I was
telling Lynn earlier that I went to a
Botanical microscopy conference where
everybody there was a plant scientist
and an Imaging specialist so a pretty
rare group all of them knew who I was
they'd seen the papers in fact we
recognize each other on the plane over
this is at at the John inis Center they
knew what was going on they read the
paper but they still didn't get it until
I actually stood in front of them like
this and showed them the animations and
showed them how a sample gets presented
to the instrument before they could
realize what was possible so I want to
really spend some time showing you how
samples are prepared and how they're
presented to the instrument so you
understand the tremendous value of the
Imaging data that comes out the other
end so around the Dan forest center we
do not have a corporate lawn we have an
authentic Missouri Prairie which is
fantastic although the neighbors
complained that when are you going to
cut your lawn they just didn't get it um
now it's beautiful wild flowers and it's
much more mature but we have a scapus we
have milked everywhere so it was a great
example to illustrate
the the step-by-step process so if you
want to look at something again this is
about the size of a you'd cover that
with a
nickel large complicated flour that goes
into in this case uh an ethanolic
solution of phosphotungstic acid the
ethanol gets past all the hydrophobicity
of a plant sample and penetrates very
very well although it takes weeks this
is minimum about 21 days for the
phosphotungstic acid to penetrate and to
contrast well and then how do you
present this really delicate flimsy
tissue paper like thing to a microscope
for 12 hours and not have it move around
low melting point
auros in all of our Labs we have plastic
tubes of a wide range of sizes so you
pick the tube that fits it best fill it
with melt and auros drop in your sample
after a quick rinse and it holds that
delicate complicated structure in place
for a long Imaging
scan and what you're able to do is
generate again very very rich 3D volumes
where you can do multiscale imaging
without leaving the samples so low
magnification scan of the whole thing
identify a region of interest and then
zoom in for a higher resolution
scan never having touched the sample you
just leave it in the instrument and let
the computer do the work um again the 3D
Volume rendering has a great impact for
for getting people to remember what
we're able to do to illustrate the
multiscale Imaging putting a high mag
region of Interest within the context of
the whole thing but much more impactful
is the flyth through you get that cell
level resolution of the entire structure
but totally shocking to me the beautiful
symmetry of the sample itself just
looking I get mesmerized watching this
movie and and it just makes me think of
spy graphs growing
up so a lot of the the the volumes I'm
going to show you will have the 3D
Volume rendering followed by the fly
through to to impress upon you how data
Rich these volumes are um this is from a
paper we published in 22 um looking at
uh nodule
formation these are our soybean nodules
formed by um Brady rium and again the
multiscale nature we can zoom in on
individual bacteroids and then put that
Zoom scan within the context of the
whole nodule where all the bids and the
vasculature are really really easy to
visualize and again with a competent
comput AAL
scientist you can identify all these
features once they're computationally
identified you can measure them and
start to then compare these measurements
between nodules between time points
between varieties you now have
measurements to go along with these with
these phenotypes and Gus did a great job
um segmenting
this um some of the other ranges of
studies we look at again that the Dan
for Center is very um well positioned to
look at Food security crops and TEF is
one of them it's very popular in Eastern
Africa great salt tolerance great for
Drought lousy agronomic traits a very
willowy stock and shattering is very
very bad the seeds quite understandably
want to disperse as easily as possible
but that's lousy if you want to actually
collect the seeds for Harvest so
shattering is a trait we wanted to get
rid of so the seed would stay put so the
Growers could Harvest and shattering is
a trait that we studied here again in 3D
uh in ways with intact samples that you
can't do just by embedding and
sectioning um luciia was a postto in
Malia gan's lab she's now across the
street at buer she's got a great job
there but she developed some mutants in
quinoa that showed some very good heat
tolerance and it's the inflorescent
structures and the pollination timing
which is often most bad negatively
affected by by heat stress so what we
want want to be able to do is first map
out in 3D what does normal look like the
normal complicated inflorescent
structure and then if you blast it with
heat how does that change the structure
and then if you have a heat tolerant
mutant how does it survive that all to
inform what heat tolerance genes can we
get our hands on how can we improve all
these different plant varieties by
identifying the genes that that are most
important and again the 2D flythroughs
just provide so much Rich detailed
information you can measure things now
you can answer questions using these
data you couldn't even ask before doing
this kind of work so it's really really
powerful
um will will Viana is got some great
Sater mutants he works in in Jose Den's
Lab at Stanford and they have some
mutants that are altered in their
ability to make uh root primordia in
sataria so what we're able to do is scan
the entire Nole that really important
Junction at the soil line where all the
vascular is coming together and look for
the origin or not of of root primordia
again a 3D Volume is great for context
but the power comes from the 2D slices
what they're going to be able to do is
segment every single cell measure and
map every single cell in the wild type
and the mutant and compare all those
measurements that is just a Priceless
way to get at phenotypic information
where you can link to sequence VAR
uh the top lab is getting into more
cover crop biology because of its its
potential for aiding soil health and of
course cover crops make beautiful
nodules great for nitrogen management to
what degree can we use multiscale xray
microscopy Imaging to inform nodule
development um again situating the high
magnification scan within the the full
3d volume is cool but the data the real
information comes from these 2D
slices
uh this is plant biology I'm not allowed
to get away without showing something
arabidopsis related so these are
developing a Rabbid opsis seeds inside
of selik um again just to illustrate the
the unique data that is available using
this kind of imaging
technology this is for Margaret this is
one of her samples that she left with me
before she left the Dan forest center
this is a two we old tomato seedling um
it's a flyth through but again what it's
telling you is if you're interested in
graft biology and graft whether it will
take or not graph compatibility this
will give you a road map of the
vasculature if you have a competent
computational scientist to map all the
vasculature but this is something you
have available
now sataria shoot apical marem again now
just examples all the different kinds of
biological tissue in 3D that we have
access to Young arabid Ops of seedlings
you want to do Fen in of an entire
structure this is
available um developing sataria panicles
um anything that used to be 3D with or
us used to be with scanning electron
microscopy where you just get a 2d
photograph of a really cool 3D structure
you now have a full 3D map inside
outside upside and down any angle you
want to go through you have the 3D
information uh again important to sort
of remind you and point out the
different ways in which samples are
presented to the microscope it helps to
understand what the geometry is to see
how will it or perhaps won't it apply to
the kinds of questions I want to ask you
wouldn't put an ear of corn in there as
such but certainly a kernel it does have
the capacity for large things and I'll
show you that later but there's a range
of things that we can put in here so
this was uh a soybean root nodule it's
it's suspended in
auros uh we looked at uh Penny crest is
a very popular cover crop these days
we're working on uh with a company
called cover Crest at the Dan for Center
to breed Penny Crest to take advantage
of the agronomic traits and these are
dry seeds they're just sort of wedged in
the end of a pipet tip with poster putty
all sorts of creative ways just to
present your samples to the X-ray beam
and of course resin embeded resin
embedded plant tissue is is going to be
a main stay of what we do certainly for
volume
em uh we do have a flat panel in the
instrument we can do in Vivo root
Imaging so again we grow plants in these
PVC pipes this flat panel will allow us
to map the entire root structure at high
resolution in this case 26 micrometer
voxal resolution you'll definitely get
laterals with that and then if you find
a region of Interest swap in one of the
objective lenses and look at high
resolution High mag at a region of
interest uh we're hoping to use this
system now to adapt to looking at micro
risal fungi in these larger systems and
I'll show some of the earlier work we
did with that uh shortly um I'm often
asked about phase contrast Imaging
certainly from the synchrotron folks
because phase can be very powerful at a
synchrotron when you're dealing with
samples of low uh low density and low
differential density we do have the
capacity to do phase contrast Imaging in
our system but we take a big hit in
resolution um and Zeiss does develop uh
they've developed some AI tools to help
sort of clean up the noise that is
expected but still
this was a sample this was a a soybean
flower that was only fixed in ethanol
that immediately imaged no contrast
agent so it's possible to do imaging but
clearly you take a big hit in what you
can see relative to uh to contrast
enhanced
material a lot of my goal is to get more
people to think about and to take
advantage of of this technology and this
is actually a white paper that's that's
free to download you can go to the Zeiss
website and download this uh it tells a
lot of the nuts and bolts of the methods
and the sample development for doing
x-ray microscopy specifically for plant
samples
because many plant scientists have
access to core facilities but don't know
how to present the sample to it core
facilities have x-ray microscopes they
never work with plant SS I'm hoping that
the Publications that we have will will
bring a lot of that together and really
expand what everyone is in a position to
do um with with x-ray imag
little over a year ago nature came out
with Technologies to watch in 2023 and
volume em volume electron microscopy is
one of them and that is using
various um electron microscopes where
one can do physical sectioning in order
to generate a 3D Volume at the nanometer
scale so there's serial block face
scanning electron microscopes where you
have an actual physical microtome inside
the instrument so you'll take a Diamond
Knife you'll cut one section image cut
image and get maybe
hundreds and you can get down to about
50 60 nanometer in in section thickness
the other alternative is is a plasma
focused ion beam where you can actually
use a laser to ablate the surface image
ablate image and you can get down to
about five or 10 nanometer section
thickness so you can generate a
beautiful 3D Volume at the organella
scale and so volume em is something we
want to use as a road map to
drive volume em so what that looks like
here's a sample of actually a tobacco
leaf disc embedded in
resin mounted in the X-ray microscope
and we'll do a scan of the entire Leaf
disc to get a road map and then you
bring in some of the world's
leading plant tissue specific Imaging
folks this is Kirk zimic he was a postto
in lab I was at a Dupont he's now the
director of The Imaging facility at the
danforce center
and it's never just the instruments he's
got some of the most talented
microscopists in the world working with
some of the best instruments on the
planet so you bring expertise and
instrumentation together and and what
you can do is astounding so uh NASA
genri and Lolita are just are brilliant
so we're able to do some marvelous
things um so this is a flyth through of
the low magnification X-Ray Scan through
the tobacco leaf
dis and what Kirk and his team did was
take my 3D scan and identify in green
this region of
interest and
so we worked together I took the sample
back and then did a much higher
magnification scan of that region of
Interest take the data hand it back over
to them and they use it as a road map
and they want to look at just these
misil sections of misil cells indicated
by the yellow box here and so that went
actually to the um the sem which had a
back scatter electron detector which you
can actually use to invert the black and
white and it looks like a
tem that region of interest and then
using their technology they zoom in on
features that they want to look at like
the purple box
there and with serial block face Imaging
they went zooming through this region
and I think they collected about 250 or
300 uh sections each as it indicates 50
nmet thick and again you have a 3D
Volume volum at very very high nanometer
scale resolutions so again computational
science is everything a good
computational scientists now can
identify and measure individual features
so that you can see and measure
distribution in 3D space total volume
amount different changes uh everything
is now measurable and accessible again
the publication is out there the
information is out there please please
look into it as something that you might
want to take advantage of um it is there
uh I promised some specific work on what
we're doing with mro risal
fungi um most of you I'm sure understand
that micro risal fungi form beneficial
interactions with most plant roots in
the in in the world they exchange
nutrients and water with the plant for
photosynthe photosynthetic sugars
beneficial relationship for
both from an Imaging standpoint we're
interested in the purple bits all the
fungal structures that are out in the
soil that colonize the root and then
start this nutrient exchange there has
been some genuinely
spectacular scientific research looking
at the genes that play roles in
governing these relationships the the
the exchange of carbon who's benefiting
Who's Cheating who's holding up their
end of the bargain there's some really
fantastic work that's been done all in
vitro um there's been some great Imaging
work Jen mol's at uh she's finishing her
pH HD at Cambridge and she designed this
beautiful microscope slide where the
plant grows on the edge and you can
train a single root that comes out
between two glass slides very elegant
you can do great Imaging work um and in
real time do Dynamic Imaging work with a
lot of the the fluorescent tools
available but it's always in vitro this
is a difficult system to look at to
understand how these things are
naturally distributed in as sort of
natural a system as you can energ
engineer the hyy are transparent they're
difficult to see these are a pack of hyy
just stuck in auros at the bottom of a
tube so how do we make these transparent
structures contrasty enough to see with
with the electron microscope with with
the X-ray
microscope and so we I we look back at
our experience with using uh x-ray
micros using electron microscopy and
making things contrasty so osmium is is
is clearly something that although
challenging to work with is very very
effective at making transparent things
contrasty so with our invitro carrot
root culture we were able to very
clearly show that that the fungal
structures both inside and outside the
roots were very well contrasted so we
applied that to what we're calling a
microcosm we can grow Alfalfa or braap
podium in small 20 mil syringe barrels
Roots will be
colonized uh fungal structures will grow
out into the Sur surounding medium and
we can contrast them and image them so
what you're seeing here in
Orange is uh fungal spores and vesicles
both inside and outside the root in the
surrounding growth Medium as well as
intra radical hyy and extra radical hyy
so we've demonstrated this can be done
um I'm going to speed up a little bit
just to make sure we get through in time
for questions um again at the Dan for
Center we're surrounded by some
fantastic scientists and Armando's got
great experience in Michael risal
biology so he's developed a braap Podium
system along with his with his senior
Tech uh Mallette and so we're using that
to look at colonization again in these
microcosms
how the better the Imaging the more
successful we can actually train a
computer model to identify the features
we want to see so everything in yellow
here is both internal spores as well as
V
inside a root we can quantify the amount
of fungus that's inside a colonized root
in situ so now this opens up some some
really huge Avenues to start exploring
basic biology to what degree can we
quantify fungal
biomass in a given genotypic interaction
particular maze genotype particular
braap Podium genotype how does that
normal change with less phosphorus more
phosphorus more nitrogen how can we
change the environment and alter these
measurable traits um we're also
exploring other things in addition to uh
osmium to see can we get away from a a
heavy volatile toxic heavy metal as
something to to visualize fungal
structures so we're looking at at
nanogold conjugates we can always
conjugate things to to fungal structures
can we stick enough gold particles on it
to be able to see with the X-ray
microscope and of course we're prepping
um a methods
manuscript uh I'm going to wrap up with
with a switch from the plant the roots
and the fungi to actually the medium
within which within which they're
growing and that's the soil with the two
instruments we can do a lot of
multiscale Imaging so we can use the
X-ray microscope to look at the
microbial scale we can look at soil
Aggregates and and again I was telling
Lynn you know we're constantly learning
new techniques and new Fields um I've
had to learn soil uh physics over the
past couple years and soil science so
I've learned that the aggregate is
essentially the lowest the smallest
currency of agricultural soil if you
took a shovel and scoop big agricultural
soil and just shook it around the
smallest naturally occurring size of
Chunk that comes out is a soil Aggregate
and the size and the stability of that
aggregate tells you a lot about the soil
health so we can look at uh the actual
structure of soil aggregate with the
X-ray microscope and then we can look at
a soil core from the same area put the
context of the aggregate into the core
and then the core into the field so
across scales we can study a lot about
the
structure of of actual agricultural soil
we've got some great collaborators at
Kate uh Chuck Rice's lab has been around
for decades and
Carlos uh was spearheading this work as
a PhD student he's actually he's just
finished um and then Cody Mae Sarah and
Clara are the the Dan for scientists who
are working on this as well and we're
comp comparing it to what would be a
gold standard the kza Prairie it's about
3500 hectares of undisturbed Tall Grass
Prairie in eastern
Kansas and so what we want to ask is
what can we learn about the 3D structure
of soil across scales so Chuck's lab has
been monitoring and managing some
research fields for now over 34
consecutive years they've been using no
till compared to Conventional tillage
they've been using conventional chemical
fertilizer uh compared to using a high
organic manure as a fertilizer so they
collected soil cores and soil Aggregates
and sent them to us for Imaging from all
these different
treatments so this is a typical soil
core inside the large format x-ray
instrument and and a typical image of
what you'll see uh we subsampled the
middle to avoid some of the cracking
artifacts on the side because we want to
measure pore space those cracks are
obviously going to to bias things
um and so what we're doing and this is
work in progress um we're using these
very high resolution 3D scans of a core
to map out pore space can we
differentiate between poor space and
soil organic matter mostly the answer is
no and this was always shocking to me
I've gone to soil science meetings where
everyone's saying here's all the poror
space and here's all the soil organic
material they've never seen the X-ray
scans where the overlap is way too much
to actually differentiate the two so
they're losing a great deal so we're
we've turned Ma Lee loose on this
problem so if anyone solve it she can
but we're trying to map out what are the
differences that we can observe
structurally between the different field
management
practices and then drop down to a
smaller scale look at an entire soil
aggregate again map out the POR space
map out the organic material and look at
that over scale to what degree does the
POR space map in the aggregate compare
or not to the equivalent treatment but
at a larger scale in a soil core is one
predictive of the what can we learn
across scales um we've embedded some of
the Aggregates in resin and we'd like to
we've sent some samples off from x-ray
fluorescence and ideally maybe work with
a synchrotron to do some some Zanes to
look at very subtle differences and and
Elemental mapping uh but then also we
could use these for for volume electron
microscopy and again that's so that's
what some of this is the work is ongoing
we want to compare soil pore networks
across these treatments we have an
elementar um Mass Spec system in the lab
so we can look at and measure absolute
amount of carbon absolute amount of
nitrogen uh and and Cody's really the
one heading up um this manuscript and
that was I could Lynn knows I could talk
for hours but I won't I will spare you
and I will stop here and happily take
any questions so we're checking the chat
to see if there are um questions from
online otherwise we'll look here in the
room yes really great presentation
I was just wondering if this allow you
to see at a cellular level or is it more
struct so the question is um can we get
to the cellular level and the answer is
yes typically the samples have to be
smaller but for example this sataria uh
nodal plexus that sample was maybe 3
millimeters tall by a millimeter in
diameter easily achieving cellular
resolution there with the soybean uh
developing
flowers you can see the entire structure
but we could zoom in onto the developing
ovules we could see synergids we could
see polar nuclei so it is possible to
see at the cellular level in that regard
a lot of them a lot of these cells in
the plants are actually quite large um
so a lot of the stock segments a lot of
the grafting stuff um a lot of the
inflorescence development there's a lot
of complicated material there but is
relatively large so we can achieve
cellular level resolution there um the
root nodules were another one um but at
the same time keep in mind that this is
just a microscope the most powerful lens
we have is just 40x and even your
tabletop microscope you multiply that by
10 times from the ocular lens we just
have a 40x lens so you will never see a
bacterial cell you will see a bacteroid
which is essentially a plant host cell
that's been sort of taken over you will
not see a bacterial cell we can see AMF
spores if they're contrasted um it's
difficult to differentiate the Hy if
they're there unless they've got a ton
of osmium on them so that's sort of the
the the Fade Out
range how how rapidly how rapidly um can
you screen the little tubes with the
braap podium micro
isal fungi that were in there is that
does that take a long time to do that
scan yeah so the question is about the
the microcosms looking at braap podium
um and and also alphalpha how quickly
can we scan those so what I'll end up
doing is I can do a relatively short
scan which is 3 to four hours but that
shows me the entire
microcosm low resolution but enough for
me to see the bright spots of fungal
material and then I'll set up a a higher
magnification scan that will be 10 to 12
hours at least so those scans are quite
long it's not good for high throughput
or even medium throughput but it is
genuinely unique in being able to see
the distribution of mic risal structures
in 3D in an undisturbed insitu rig it's
not the field but no one else is in a
position to do this kind of of 3D Inu
Imaging and are you flooding that whole
um syringe with OS yes and we're also
taking advantage of the fact that osmia
has a great uh Vapor potential so you
can use osmium Vapors to also contrast
material but the other benefit of that
syringe barrel system is it's got a lure
lock and so I can lock that I can parap
film the crap out of these things and
make sure that it's very very well
contained um what I am doing right now
is I've got some some microcolumns that
I flooded with uh ethanolic phosphonic
acid I had done in vitro that's
beautiful you can see individual
arbuscules it's fantastic but it takes
weeks and weeks so I've set these up it
is absolutely flooded there's there's a
miniscus on the top I mean it is
absolutely flooded in ethanolic
phosphotungstic acid I'm going to look
at it in a couple months from now
because if I can get away from osmium I
definitely want
to but short of not being able to image
at all um the other step is going to be
as I mentioned using um gold conjugates
so Nano gold so lectin are very good in
vitro at sticking to micro risal fungi
and in vitro we've shown that we can
stick enough uh wheat germal glutin in
conjugated to Gold nanop particles so
that we can see in vitro I don't know if
it's going to be enough to see in situ
it's just a bigger system and much more
dense question online so I know you said
there are resolution image issues with
the large scale x-ray tomography what is
the cut off does this extend to find
roots and that's that's again that's a
great question
so we can engineer the pot to be able to
see the biology of interest that we're
interested in so if we want to see
lateral Roots we'll grow something in
nothing bigger than say 4 or 5 cm
diameter pot and we might just even get
away from using field soil we use um
ground up Clay like profile or turface
these are commercially available
artificial growth
media we will be able to see lateral
roots in in in that example if we look
at a larger pot we will never see
lateral Roots so we can adjust pot size
and growth medium to allow the
instrument to show us what's possible
there is an o excuse me there's an
overlap between the large format
instrument and the X-ray microscope both
have a flat panel option so you saw one
of the images in here where I had a
small corn plant in the X-ray microscope
that panel is higher resolution than the
one in the large format instrument so
even in that same 3 cm diameter PVC pipe
we'll get better resolution in the X-ray
microscope it's a longer scan and it's
60 to 70 gigabytes again always the
trade-off if you want to see small roots
in a big thing it's going to cost you
but it is
possible Margaret um I was just thinking
about your your last part on field soil
composition and your early work on root
architecture and the plasticity of roots
are
you like thinking about a system where
you can start looking at how the
heterogeneity of real soil systems is
influencing that plasticity or is that
yes absolutely abolutely and and I I was
hoping to get the chance to say that
we're working on a top soil in Chris
Topps lab um we're working on an
authentic field soil that is
reproducible that we can use all the
time because up till now we've only used
the artificial media because that has
been less daunting for segmentation
field soil is so much more like a root
itself it's just diff more difficult to
teach the computer to find the roots but
that is our goal this year especially is
to demonstrate that in a number number
of diameters we can grow two different
maze genotypes where we know the root
structure is different the root
architecture is going to be different
can we get good enough at segmentation
where we can pull out those 3D volumes
now they're root 3D volumes with nothing
around them and plug them into our trait
extraction pipelines and actually see
that the the trait differences we can
see by I we can also measure from the
Inu x-ray sces so we need to demonstrate
that we can do that and then we can then
step forward through all the different
bi basic biology questions from genotype
to
environment one last question one last
question
yes is there any work being done to
build functional PL models things like
that uh using especially like
architecture
data yes there are computational
scientists and modeling scientists who
are taking some of these data and and
sort of developing into different
questions these are collaborators we
have at at St Louis University as well
as uh Washington University both in
downtown St Louis so they are in
computer science programs and very often
they are starved for data sets we've got
hundreds of terabytes of data sets
please do as much as you can with these
and a lot of that is modeling um T's lab
really developed and this was again Dan
xang did a great job developing a
skeletonization protocol that sort of
got around the problem of loop where
things would loop back against one
another and you would the computer would
lose it and so they've been able to
convert that 2D into 3D where you could
actually track these these looping
structures so yeah a lot of that work is
being done we've got great colleagues
who are following that
up all right thank you
everyone this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.com
EDU