this is a production of Cornell
University yes so this is a a campaign
stop for
me uh trying to get your vote uh to
renew my joint appointment in plant
breeding so all of you plant breeding
faculty vote early and often uh because
when we vote we
win okay so I'm going to really give uh
two seminars in one
today uh and they are both chapters from
George Stack's dissertation uh which he
completed last year uh and also a lot of
work on the powdery mildew project from
Ali kala a PhD student in Chris smarts
lab and uh yeah I will go ahead and
recognize my collaborators here because
many of them some of them are in the
room so stepen Snyder you're going to
see some beautiful sem that he did in
Jos Rose's lab
I have collaborated with
uh uh Jenny Moore's lab for quite a
while now and uh also we were fortunate
to have uh to be able to work with ping
Wong in entomology in Geneva you'll see
that those data and uh I was on
sabatical at Colorado state for a year
and got to know John McCay very well and
he was very generous to share a
segregating population with us uh that's
the heart of the second half of my talk
and uh we got canab noids from Nick
jackits at serona Labs a startup company
uh that was based in
Geneva so I'm going to talk about hemp
today one of the five crops that uh we
breed in the lab uh and hemp is a very
interesting crop because it has multiple
Market
classes uh there was a
1937 Popular Mechanics article that came
out saying that EMP would become a
billion dooll industry that Henry Ford
built a car entirely made of hemp and
that we can make 25,000 products out of
hemp and that's probably true uh but not
all of those products are viable in the
marketplace or competitive for price in
the
marketplace so hemp is an emerging crop
because it was only truly legalized by
the 2018 Farm Bill
uh prior to that it was considered a
schedule one narcotic like heroin uh we
initially had to have a DEA registration
to be able to schedule one DEA
registration just to handle the
seeds uh but now it's totally legalized
and if you work on hemp you better like
roller coasters because it has been a
serious roller coaster through the CBD
Market uh so that is our top Market
uh uh grown either in controlled
environment settings or in high
intensity Horticultural settings right
now all of the interest is in fiber and
when we say fiber we really mean either
the long strong Bast fibers on the
outside of the stem or the inner Woody
herd uh those are two different product
streams leading to two different
markets uh and we are going to see a
real uptick in Grain because uh the FDA
recently approved the use of hemp seed
meal as an animal feed ingredient for
laying hens uh so that is going to
stimulate the grain market over the
coming year and uh actually that this
bottom machine is actually a dual
purpose Harvester that can combine the
grain from very tall hemp plants while
also harvesting the stems uh for fiber
products so it is a diverse crop there
are cultivars that are bred for each of
these different Market classes uh but
still in New York we only have less than
200 acres of hemp being grown uh I grew
35 Acres on our farm plots in Geneva
this year and that was about a third of
the acreage in New York state so it is a
very early emerging
crowd but I think it has a lot of
potential uh we're waiting for for the
farm bill the new farm bill which
hopefully will further relieve some of
the regulatory burden on Farmers a lot
of that is based on
THC
uh THC in many people's eyes is viewed
as a very bad
thing uh and so we are one of the goals
in our breeding program is to breed for
low or no THC to try to basically
eliminate that risk for Growers no
matter what the regulatory
landscapers we think there is a market
for uh the protein and grain whether
it's for animal feed or for human food
uh for human food we're looking at uh
the functional properties of the seed
storage proteins as well but right now
it's all about fiber mainly for building
materials and uh technical
products uh and in order to separate
that Bast from the herd that is a
process called
decortication and and uh we need to have
varieties that are easy and efficient to
decorticate and separate that long fiber
from the
herb uh hemp has been notoriously
difficult to establish in direct seated
plantings uh germination is typically
rarely over
50% uh and there are very few herbicides
that are registered for hemp so early
seedling establishment and early
seedling bger is a major trait right now
uh to ensure farmer success and as a
part of that one of my students here
Luis monserate is particularly
interested in breeding for large seed
size and our large seed and cultivars
seem to help to solve that early
establishment problem and the other
issue we've had is that all of the
current H cultivars have been bred in
Europe pretty much uh or Canada and are
not well adapted to Southern latitudes
we have been bringing in material from
uh tropical and subtropical China which
will address that
issue but all of that material tested
hot
so uh so these are our challenges in
hemp breeding uh we started from scratch
in 2017 so where do we get germ
plasm fortunately we have the USDA AR
hemp germ plasm repository in Geneva at
Cornel agratech and Zach stansil the
curator there has done a fantastic job
of very rapidly accumulating a large uh
assembly of germ plasm both uh working
with foreign repositories and bringing
that material to the US but also working
with folks to collect uh fural hemp from
across North
America we've done a lot of work to
better understand the genetics of THC
production I'll talk about some of that
we've done a lot to develop genetic
mapping
resources uh I'm not going to talk about
that too much today one of our main
focus right now is understanding the
genes involved in flowering time uh and
again maybe that's for the next talk
what I am going to talk about today is
pest and disease
resistance and going to start out with
powdery mildew uh so this is a project
that we did jointly between my lab and
Chris smarts lab uh powdery mildew is
caused by the fungus renom myces
ambrosier uh you can see some beautiful
pictures here from Bill Welden and David
gor's lab and uh it is a big problem in
controlled environment production of
hemp and
cannabis and in our climate in New York
we also see quite a bit of powdery
mildew in CBD hemp uh grown in again in
this intensive Horticultural
setting so right from the outset in 2017
when we started growing hemp uh we
wanted to better understand the traits
of the cultivars I'll say that with air
quotes cultivars that were available so
we were very ProActive at trying to
reach out to everyone who had seeds and
put those into small plot trials and at
that time it was all about CBD
so these are pictures of our 2019 uh
trials with 30
cultivars uh one in Geneva one at
Bluegrass Lane and these were a lot of
work uh a lot of cannaboid analysis that
Steven did in Joss's
lab
uh but you learn things by looking at
all of this uh variety of of germ plasm
and one thing that we consistently saw
was uh essentially zero ratings for
powdery mildew disease in this variety
FL
58 uh so this is a graph of percent
disease uh from ratings that were done
by Ali Calla from those trials and you
see we were getting uh pretty good
levels of powdery Milo and some
cultivars but again
consistently this cultivar
f58 uh was
resistant so when you look at the
resistance mechanisms to for powdery
Milo uh we see either R Gene based
resistance and there was a paper
published in
2021 uh describing the first R Gene from
Cannabis sativa they called it
pm1 uh we would expect this to be a
dominant and race
specific uh mechanism we don't know
anything about the races of uh howder
Milo powdery
MW uh so that's still an open
book I'm just going to say this has been
an extremely frustrating situation uh
because this Gene was discovered in a
high THC variety by a company called
Dewey scientific a spin-off from
Washington State
University uh Mark Lang started that
company together with one of his
students you may know him and they have
refused to send that material to us uh
they claim that they've bred it into a
hemp variety so it should be compliant
but even
still uh they will not send it to us uh
to look at and to compare with uh the
resistance that we have in our hands
it's been extremely
frustrating I'm going to continue
calling him out for
this uh because I I don't think it's
right that they should publ publish this
in a peer paper and not then not share
the
material the other mechanism we can uh
we can look at is a susceptibility gene
mediated mechanism this should have
broader Spectrum resistance and would
typically be recessive and there was a
nice paper published in 2021 by uh Pepin
at all describing the mlo milu Lo Locus
o Gene family and Cannabis sativa with
two strong genes uh as candidates for
powdery milde
susceptibility so we have here some
Frameworks for what we might expect in
terms of mechanism of powdery M
resistance in that FL
cultivar so we took that FL 58 and
crossed it with a susceptible line one
of our favorite uh varieties called TJ
CBD uh pretty
susceptible and uh then looked at the F1
and the
uh F1 had variable levels of
susceptibility we only looked at a small
handful uh but again these are now audpc
area under the disease progress curve
graphs uh on the left from a mistro
inoculation that Ali did and on the
right from a field trial again you can
see FL 58 resistant in the field trial
and a range of susceptibilities across
the
F1 uh so that uh immediately sort of
rules out that dominant R Gene
hypothesis uh pretty much I think uh
because we are seeing a range of
susceptibilities we pick two of those F1
individuals and self them and hemp is
dous but you can trick a female plant to
make pollen allowing you to
self-pollinate
it and uh generated two segregating F2
populations uh both with about three a
little more than 300 350 individuals and
planted those out in a field trial in
Geneva in
2021 and Ali again very rigorously uh
surveyed this population to generate
these very nice audpc curves and I have
shown the two different F2 populations
here in different graphs where we see
that 25% of the F2 are scored as
resistant essential essentially zero
audpc
aligned with the ll58
parent uh TJ's is again moderately
susceptible but across the other 75% of
the population we see a range of
susceptibility
okay so that does fit uh this model of a
single Gene
recessive uh susceptibility
Gene so we genotyped those 700ish F2
individuals we used uh an aluminum array
array that was developed by phos
bioscience uh even though there were
55,000 Snips we only had 2700 that were
useful uh for George to build the
linkage map I'll just say these two
individuals we have now sequence these
and have highquality phase genome
Assemblies of them FL 58 is highly
inbred and very
homozygous and TJ CBD looks like it is a
true F1 hybrid cul of art uh so those
were interesting choices in terms of the
genomics and and George has a manuscript
we're about to
submit uh that describes some of the
interesting uh comp comparative genomics
that we're working on right now anyway
the phos array work pretty well for us
uh spread across the genome even though
it was designed to hiy THC
lines and uh when he did the qtl mapping
we saw a very highly significant uh
single Peak on chromosome
one and then some other smaller minor
Peaks on chromosomes 2 48 and
N uh
so looking at that Peak again we had
pretty tight and strong uh support for
that
interval and when you look at the
genotypes and line them up with the
phenotype it does point to a recessive
mechanism for a lack of
susceptibility uh while among the other
uh the heterozygous and
homozygous uh
susceptible Al there is quite a range of
AUD PCS across the rest of that
material so a pretty strong effect of
this Locus on chromosome one and lo and
behold uh within that or very close to
that confidence interval is this CLA 5
csm1 Gene that was predicted by the
Pepin paper as being a good candidate
for susceptibility very close to our p
marker so uh I mentioned we sequenced
those two parents FL 58 and TJ
CBD uh did pack bio sequencing and omnic
uh to get a nice phased
assembly and again lo and behold uh in
the uh resistant FL 58 cultivar there is
a large insertion in that mll1 Gene
about 6.8 KB a portion of it looks like
a transposable element and that
insertion does result in a different
differentially spice differentially
spliced
transcript which would have a premature
stop codeon and disrupt function of that
susceptibility
protein uh the interesting thing we were
pretty concerned about this early on and
I'll show you in the next slide how we
resolve this when we started doing rtpc
R of this Gene we were also detecting a
fulllength open reading
frame uh so that caused us some concern
how can how can
this uh cultivar be resistant if it has
if it's producing functional
susceptibility
protein so we spent quite a bit of time
working on this and uh did
rtpcr uh from both uninoculated and
inoculated plant so that's the open bar
versus the hatched bar but really I want
you to focus on the green bars which is
the proportion of transcript that has
the premature stop cat on uh so the
disrupted transcript and when we looked
at FL 58 yes we can just we can detect a
very small amount of that full length
transcript but the vast majority of
transcript that's being produced is the
def the interrupted version of the
gene uh I'm going to show you on the
next slide we've developed some markers
uh to detect that insertion in the mll1
Gene and those markers pointed us to
some other germ plasm that we had which
was
heterozygous and so you can see again in
a heterozygote for that insertion we're
seeing about half of the full length
transcript and about half of of the
transcript with the insertion and at
least in this line we do see an
upregulation uh upon inoculation of the
expression of that ml1
Gene so now we have uh a few good
markers linked to that mll1 oal that has
the insertion which is a effectively a
knockout of the susceptibility gene we
can now use those markers to
integress that uh Locus into other Elite
germ plasms both we like to use Pace
markers uh so we have a couple of
different pace markers as well as gel
based markers where we can clearly see
the segregation of that
insertion so I that was a very nice
story it it all wrapped up everything
makes sense it all wrapped up into a
very nice package uh as a chapter in
georg's dissertation the next step we do
want to do additional more detailed RNA
seek uh to look at the expression of
that M1 Gene and the other CA 5
M1 uh mlo Gene which is
mll4 uh my student Lou venal will is
working on on all of these follow-up
questions uh we're very interested to
see if it will confer resistance in
other genetic backgrounds and whether
that mll1 knockout uh confers any uh
debilitated phenotype because that's
often the case with these susceptibility
genes we have not seen that so far with
FL
58 and we're also very interested in uh
the resistance mechanisms between hot
powdery mildew and hemp po powdery
mildew and whether we have resistance
genes to those alternate pathogens uh
resistance to hot powdery mildew and
hemp or resistance to hemp powdery M do
in hop so that's something that Lou is
working on as
well uh so we are she has been
ingressing it into other
backgrounds and uh making crosses to get
it into the homoa state and we have also
been working with the USDA germplasm
repository to screen other material and
search for other sources of powdery M
resistance maybe we will find that pm1
Gene in other genotypes and won't have
to go back to Dey scientific uh to beg
them again for
that uh I'll pause here any questions
about the powdery milary story before I
move on to
herbivores
okay so again I a benefit of doing all
of these small plot variety trials it
was a lot of work it's a pain in the
butt uh getting the seed from all these
companies and and doing all the f typing
is yet you do learn interesting
things and again in 2019 we planted out
all of these grain and fiber varieties
in small plot trials and the observation
that George made was that some of them
were really getting hammered primarily
by Japanese beetle which is a pest that
we have a lot of that they don't have a
lot of in some other big hemp growing
regions like Colorado and Oregon
uh they really preferred these four
varieties shaded in Blue uh which happen
to all come from the breeding program in
Ukraine and the other feature of those
four is that they are all cannabinoid
free so that's a pretty strong
correlation that the four canabo free
lines uh just get hammered by Leaf
feeding beetles whereas pretty much
everything else that's making
cannabinoids uh has at best a low level
of
herbivory there are reports in in the
literature that canabo uh may have some
effects on arthropod health and
feeding uh so again I think we had some
good hypotheses that we could test uh to
see what the role is of canabo on uh at
least this this type of leaf feeding
herbivore so I have to give you a short
background on can aboid
biochemistry uh if you're a hemp or
cannabis scientist uh this is a a lot of
what we all think about is canabo uh on
the med medicinal
side uh but here we're we're looking at
these on the field crop side uh so this
is a very simple diagram of the
biosynthetic pathway combine gpp and
olivetolic acid to make what they call
the mother of all cannabinoids CBG and
then depending on which synthes enzyme
is present in those
tricomes uh you will either uh use that
CBG as a substrate to make
CBD or if you have thca synthes uh you
can convert that CVG into
THC uh so again those it depending on
the combination or the expression of
those two enzymes we have different
cannabinoid chemotypes as we described
them if you do if the plant lacks active
cbda synthes it will only make thca
synthes we call that chemotype 1 that is
uh the adult use uh drug
type but you might have plants that are
expressing each enzyme and if you have
both enzymes present in those tricomes
they will make about an equal ratio of
CBD and THC we call that chemotype
2 it is also
non-compliant uh so it's still not
classified as hemp in that case hemp is
uh chemotype 3 uh so it is not
expressing any active thca
synthes it only expresses active cbda
synthes thus we get cbda
CBD uh the twist here is that that cbda
synthes is promisc promiscuous and makes
a little bit of THC in a about a 25 to1
ratio so hemp does make THC and if you
do that calculation when you get to
about a seven or 8% by dry weight CBD
line it will exceed the
0.3% THC
threshold then it's no longer hemp uh so
as John McKay says hemp is a phenotype
think about that uh we can also find
lines where both enzymes are knocked out
and then we see the accumulation of the
precursor uh so CBG dominant lines are
chemotype
4 uh and so we now know that those two
synthes genes cbda synthes and thca
synthes sit very close to each other on
chromosome 7
at a region that we call has been named
the B
Locus uh we have not detected any
recombination between those two genes uh
so we can effectively treat them as
alals with and they display melan
inheritance and we also have lines that
again either have a knockout in the thca
synthes gene we would we calling that
bt0 or BT null a knockout in the cbda
synthes we can call that BD null and we
also find lines that have the entire
region
deleted uh so we call that the B null
Al so then you can uh look at these
different ala combinations again
typically hemp would be homozygous for
the cbda synthes it would be chemotype 3
but if it was heterozygous for the
active cbda
and some knockout it would also be
chemotype 3 you have to be homozygous
for that b null or one of those other
Knockouts to be cha Type 4
okay and then finally we can also find
Knockouts in the Upstream enzymes in the
pathway for example Knockouts in all AIC
acid
synthase which totally eliminate
cannaboids so we're not making any CVG
either and that is chemotype 5
cannabinoid free okay and that is
determined Again by a single Locus that
has been named the O Locus so if you're
homozygous for uh the little o alil you
are cannabinoid free if you're
heterozygous you make very low levels of
cannabinoid and you have to be
homozygous for the bigo alal of that
olivetolic acid synthese to be truly
canabo
company so uh John mccay's lab Patrick
Woods in his group uh generated a
mapping population by Crossing one of
these canabo free cultivars Uso 31 from
Ukraine with an Italian fiber variety
carola and generated a segregating F2
population which he shared with
us and uh it turns out that that F2
population was was very nicely
segregating he used a single F1 and self
that so it was a true F2 population and
that F1 was heterozygous at both the B
and the O Losi so we have very nice 9
to4 to3
segregation uh if of of cannaboid
competence and production of CBD versus
CBG so let me walk you through
this uh so this is is a log scale of
total cannabinoids so high cannabinoid
on the right and essentially cannabinoid
free on the
left and that makes sense when you look
at the little o homozygotes here the
light blue down to the light yellow are
all in this canabo free
group uh so those are the chemotype 5
plants and then if you look across this
line the homozygous B null genotypes are
going to be chemotype 4 they're going to
make CBG so the vertical scale is the
proportion of
CBG uh so all those High CBG lines the
chemotype 4 lines are at the top and the
rest are uh the chemotype 3 uh CBD
dominant
lines so that gave us a very nice
segregating population to look at the
role of cannaboid
competence and we could also compare CBD
versus CBG uh from this
population so George planted it out in
uh paired field trials one in Geneva one
in Ithaca in 2021 he rated herbivory
weekly uh which and then generated what
we call area under the herbivory
progress
curves and we also uh measured folar
cannabinoids by hplc
uh and Stephen again looked at
differences in triome density and
morphology in a subset of these
plants uh this is a nice phenotype you
like to see right I'm I'm not a stats
expert but uh I don't you don't really
need stats when this is your result yeah
we do need stats but I'll show you those
next so the plant on the right is
chemotype 5 cannaboid free uh just got
hammered by some Leaf beeding herbivore
probably Japanese beetle but it could
have been slugs it could have been
something else we're not entirely sure
of that and the cannaboid competent uh
CBD line on the left relatively little
herbivory this is a graph on the scale
of herbivore damage expressed as the log
a uhpc plus one okay so keep that in
mind mind the bottom line is that we do
see a significant difference in area
under the herbivory progress curve
between the cannaboid free lines in this
F2 population versus either the CBD
dominant or CBG dominant lines there was
much more herbivory in itha than there
was in Geneva I that was a local
environmental
effect uh but still significant uh
difference between the Canam 3 and
cannaboid competent
lines uh again here we're graphing the
log of total canabo so high canabo on
the right low canabo on the left and in
both sites uh we see a significant
negative relationship between
herbivory and uh cannabinoid
concentration but that's all in the
field again we didn't really know
exactly who was chewing on those
leaves uh so we wanted to try to counter
any criticism about that by bringing
leaves inside and putting them in a a no
choice
bioassay uh this is where we got the
help from ping Wang he provided us
cabbage Looper from his colony and
George picked out six CBD dominant wines
and six cannaboid free
lines uh and did three reps of feeding
with one cabbage Looper per leaf
and then measured mortality position on
the leaf area consumed and final mass of
that
cabage so again they perform much better
on cannaboid free
leaves uh
significantly more Leaf area consumed of
the cannabinoid free lines a
significantly greater mass of the
Cabbage Looper on canabo free lines and
significantly I think this is
significantly greater mortality on the
CBD leaves than on the cannaboid free
leaves all of that
fits and the other interesting thing is
that uh these cannaboid free lines
normally
these uh cesil glandular tricomes are
the site of cannabinoid
biosynthesis you can see in the
cannaboid competent leaves they're very
swollen this interesting observation
that Steven made that they seem to be
collapsed in the cannaboid Freel line
also that there's a much higher density
of tricomes on the leaf on the abaxial
side
uh uh on the bottom side then on the top
side the ad axial side and when George
looked at the position of those cabbage
Loopers that fit right so there were
much they were much more likely to be on
the abaxial side on the cannabinoid free
lines than they were on the canabo
competent lines uh because that's where
all the CBD
is uh on these CH chemotype 3
leaves okay so again just these are
whole leaves maybe there were
differences in the toughness of the leaf
when you talk to entomologists right
they want to know what was that
toughness of the Lea Leaf what was a
nitrogen content in the leaf what was a
water
content okay so we'll do artificial diet
assays then eliminating all of those
sort of tissue effects so we worked with
this company cerona Labs who had a nice
water soluble cannaboid Emulsion
Incorporated it into the insect diet and
uh George did both an incorporation
formula and then also painted the canabo
on the surface of the DI
uh and again the Cabbage Loopers grew
much less on the diet with cannabinoids
integrated into it and there was a
significant effect on Final Mass uh with
higher levels of CBD and CB well this is
not significant but numerically
different uh the surface bioassay
actually worked a little bit better and
gave us the ability to do a little more
range of
concentration and we did see a dosage
effect uh with only 0.01% CBD no
significant difference in percent
survival but if you go up to 0.1 uh
significant decrease in survival and uh
we killed every all the Cabbage Loopers
with 1%
CBD and most of them with 1%
CBG uh so all of those data fit the
story uh leading us to to this
conclusion that herbivory damage is
related to cannaboid
concentration uh
that uh our our cabbage Loopers perform
better uh so it wasn't just something
happening in the field it wasn't
something about Leaf
toughness uh because we we also saw the
same effect with artificial diets and we
came to the conclusion that probably
breeding cannabinoid free
cultivars is a bad idea not a good
idea but we can breed for high CBG lines
this chemotype
4 which produce essentially no
THC uh so they will be essentially
cannabinoid free uh sorry THC free but
not canabo free and should still be able
to defend themselves against herbivores
now I want to I'm showing a picture of a
corn earworm
because uh corn earworm goes right for
the high CBD
flowers
so the hypothesis there is that corn air
worm don't care about CBD uh because
that's where we find them in the plant
uh same thing with cannabis
Aid uh so cannabis aphid is very
abundant in the top parts of the of the
CBD flower at the end of the season so
I'm not going to say that this is a
silver bullet for all insect problems uh
but it does seem to have some effect on
those Leaf feeding
herbivores uh so I will wrap things up I
need to thank uh the very generous
funding we've gotten from New York State
through primarily through agen markets
but also also through uh office of
cannabis management and Empire State
development
uh we have had uh grants from industry
and this project on Powder Milo was
funded by FF in cooperation with
Scots and uh please email me or check
out our website if you have any other
questions so I would be happy to take
questions
now about 10 minutes for Larry to see
how we are going to vote as a faculty
yeah first question from a gr
great to see
you I was wondering about the like
there's tradeoffs invol that
out uh yeah so that that is often often
by knocking out the susceptibility
gene you see an impact on Vigor in other
systems and uh we have not seen that we
don't really know what the function of
those S Gene proteins
is uh yeah it's still an open
question would you
ever a type
of fiber or would you ever that those or
yeah so there are some very mature hemp
Industries uh in Europe and in
China
and we I think we in the US are only
just beginning to learn how those mature
Industries are
performing uh I was just at a conference
where I heard a talk from the president
of the largest hemp company in the world
in
China and they grow grow hemp in a very
specific way and harvest it and process
it in a very specific way to get textile
grade
fiber uh it doesn't go to seed so no
they're not going to get textile grade
fiber and grain from the same
plant and uh they don't get any herd
either because they're harvesting before
the accumulation of any
herd in contrast uh there is a mature
grain industry in Canada in Manitoba
Alberta
Saskatchewan and they have they have
never collected any of the straw they
only their crop grows about four feet
tall they combine it with their big huge
wide
combines uh and they are the largest
producer of EMP grain you could buy it
in the store from Manitoba
Harvest uh called hemp parts
uh so those are two mature hemp
industries that are single
purpose so whether we can develop
multi-purpose crops that are profitable
and actually meet the needs of the end
users we do the economic modeling of
that and it comes out beneficial but uh
what I understand right now is that the
end users are not going to want those
products from Dual Purpose crops
I think I tried this in Parts visited
you that one time
tasty High Am protein yeah omega3 and
omega-6 fatty
acid chickens love
them yeah so uh sorry I should be
repeating the question so the uh
question is uh there only about 200
acres of
hemp uh I don't know the exact numbers
of how many acres of cannabis there are
I would
guess I'm going to guess somewhere
probably around four three or 400 Acres
of outdoor grown
cannabis
uh so what is our Outreach strategy
uh my Outreach strategy is to provide
knowledge to Growers and allow them to
make the choice of whether they want to
grow hemp there has to be a market first
and we do not have any hemp processors
in New York state again I have a
decorticator and I am the only one in
the Northeast with a hemp
decorticator uh so we need some
investment in hemp processing before I
would ever suggest uh a hemp farmer to
to plant the hemp but I think now we we
have we have uh delivered Field Days
every year since
2017 the high the best attendant
attended one had about 260 people this
year we had about 150 people so there is
definitely interest and we show people
how to grow hemp
effectively uh for fiber grain and
CBD uh we just need the processing
infrastructure and uh we need less
regulation that's also true
okay so we had a lot of CBD hemp growers
in 2019 we grew about 2,000 or 2500
Acres of CBD
hemp the market crashed but then New
York State this was the only state in
the country that did
this uh authorized our experienced hemp
Growers to then get a cannabis grows
license so everywhere else in the
country you cannot have both licenses
you can't grow hemp and cannabis on the
same
Farm uh so New York was pretty unique
and saying okay hemp Growers you can now
start growing cannabis go for it and so
all of my
clientele uh then started growing
cannabis pretty much and uh we are not
allowed to provide extension to uh still
schedule one drug produc
users all just Qui question for the New
York State Office of
cannabis is do they oversee hemp as well
so they do oversee uh not the licensing
but the uh product side of
CBD and sales of
CBD years ago at the height of f of CBD
marketing
fromr identified
what does it look like
now yeah so the the question is uh for
me to describe uh the roller coaster of
the CBD
industry yeah so again hemp people
started being able to grow hemp in after
the 2014 farm bill and States had to
pass their their pilot program every
state was different but it really was
the 2018 farm bill so some early States
Kentucky Colorado Oregon got started
ahead of everyone
else uh we got started our plan was
passed in late
2016 uh we started planting grain and
fiber hemp initially but then in 2018 it
became clear that CBD was going to be
the thing and 2019 after the 2018 farm
bill pass people went berserk
uh I'll give you an
example uh there is a probably the best
seed producer for CBD hemp was a company
in Oregon called Oregon
CBD and estimates I've heard is that
they sold 300 million seeds in 2019 at a
dollar a
piece dollar a piece wow you're in the
right
business so that the owner Seth Crawford
of Oregon CBD is a very clever guy very
scientifically oriented he was a member
of the FF hemp research
Consortium he bought a pack bio
sequencer and started sequencing genomes
working with Kelly Vining at Oregon
State and Todd Michael at
sulk and uh they have now leveraged that
all of those data into a Pang
genome uh so we now have 75 B
uh genomes from that era thanks
to the estimated $300 million that he
made in
2019 people were paying uh you know if
you're planting 2500 plants an acre
you're paying $2,500 just for the seed
per acre and some people were planting
acres uh there were 60,000 acres in the
state of Oregon in
2019 uh based on all that
overproduction processors we went and
visited uh Charlotte's Web a company in
Colorado uh when we were on sabatical
they were still processing pemp that was
grown in
2019 in
2023 so what we're being told is that
the processors are finally now have
finally gotten through all of the
backlog of biomass from
2019 and uh there is now finally an
uptick on the grower side for the price
of CBD hemp and people are actually
planting CBD hemp again but now the
market is so thinned out that really the
only survivors are companies that are
vertically
integrated that have a solid seed
supplier grow their own hemp process it
and Market it under their own brand we
have a couple of very good ones in New
York uh
Beacon skiff near
Syracuse they have so many different
companies right they have fantastic
apple orchard where the kids go and pick
apples and pumpkins and things and then
they have a fantastic cannabis
company on the farm PL land for the
whole family for the whole family yeah
they and they make cider and uh it's
it's an incredible company so they are a
Survivor and a success story uh
but very few other success stories in
that
industry uh we probably close here but
just remind people as sarin had said
there's a meeting at 5m on the which
room was it Bradfield
1102 there there's one question in the
chat uh from Syria uh any idea whether
spotted Lantern fly feeds on him uh and
he wonders if there's a similar story as
cabage Looper uh so that's an excellent
question we also share that same
question for hot uh so spot and Lantern
fly is coming in from the south is a big
threat to our Vineyards for sure uh but
we have not seen damage on hop and we
have not seen damage on hemp so far
so uh yeah but we need to wait until the
populations are bigger for sure but uh
at least for now
now it does not seem to be a huge threat
specifically to him great let's thank
Larry this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu