this is a production of Cornell
University okay so I'm going to be
talking about the pushpull systems um
which are in in subsaharan Africa um and
it's I think this is a really
interesting example of ecological
intensification as an approach to
solving um the challenges of production
and so many of you know that um this
really is my first time being involved
in research in a developing country in
small holder subsistence farming systems
I've traveled to you know many countries
for workshops but um this is what I
decided would be really interesting to
become involved in for my um yeah so I'm
going to just speak briefly about
ecological intensification as a as a
framework and an alternative path for
addressing some of the challenges and I
culture an introduction and a a tour of
push poool systems um some of my
preliminary research results so This
research is so far being conducted on
full bright funding which is you know
rather limited for actual data analysis
and then some future directions and and
the collaborations that have have come
out of this so we know we' facing some
big challenges in agriculture and I
really don't have to go over them for
this group um and there are many
solutions that are being proposed and we
can sort of you know think of them as a
Continuum starting with a more crop per
drop so the idea that we continue on our
current path um and improve the
efficiency of the resources that we're
using um another alternative that's
proposed is ecological intensification
so this idea of restoring ecological
Integrity as a way to address some of
the problems and and there's many sort
of a Continuum in the middle and in
reality we're going to need to draw from
both of these approaches so I don't see
them as mutually exclusive so I'm I'm an
ecologist so I'm particularly interested
in looking at ecological intensification
and trying to learn more about you know
how far can we push these
approaches and the central hypothesis of
this approach is that we could use
biodiversity um to enhance and restore
some of the ecological processes that
that support yields and productivity and
be be able to reduce the fossil fuel
based inputs that we're using so address
some of these issues of environmental
degradation and also food security at
the same
time so there is some evidence that you
know in going in this to in the
trajectory towards intensification and
the you know amazing increases in yields
that have been achieved that there have
been reductions in in biodiversity
talking mostly about plant diversity
which then has these cascading effects
on arthropods and the below ground
communities so one graph is from the
midwestern us the Corn soyan Belt over a
number of
decades and then another is some work
that was done in Germany looking at
plant diversity on a somewhat smaller
scale um and this trend can be found in
many other Landscapes that as you
intensify you increase the tendency
towards monocultures either you know
continuous monocultures or maybe
alternating to crops but you have
extensive landscapes in mostly in the
same species or one or two
species and this kind of intensification
was enabled by replacing the ecosystem
services that were once delivered by
plants for example nitrogen fixation or
weed control so as perennials and other
species are removed we can use um
fertilizers we can use herbicides to
actually increase yields even in that
you know without using that plant
diversity for those outcomes and so the
question is can we go in the opposite
direction can we increase plant
diversity and have an impact on how much
energy and I'm using it as a proxy for
inputs on the inputs that we're using
can we can we go in this direction can
we get tangible benefits by managing
plant diversity at multiple scales So
within the field the farm and across
Landscapes and there are some evidence
that's L that links biodiversity both in
in space and time to improvements in
yield they a few studies that have
actually looked at some energy
biodiversity relationships I'm just
going to put up three examples here
one's in um in Africa in the same sort
of region um where they were looking at
biodiversity both in terms of
intercropping and rotation and its
impact on
yields and um another study is that came
out it mainly focuses on pollination and
I would say that pollination as an
ecosystem service and the impact on
those crops that require pollinators is
probably the best example and the most
studied um case where we can link
biodiversity across Landscapes and at
Farm scale to concrete benefits in
yields and you know we can go in either
direction some people study Landscapes
and look at you know how homogeneous
does a landscape need to become before
it impacts yield negatively they find as
you get to Landscapes that have fewer
and fewer kinds of species plants and
habitats you
um reduced abundance and um numbers of
pollinators and reduced yields in the
pollination dependent crops these are
going the opp Opposite Direction and
then the most recent study which was
carried out across many regions um on
you know multiple continents found this
very um strong relationship between
plant biodiversity pollinator diversity
and abundance and yields and it did vary
depending on the size of the farm so
there's some intricacies in here that
the entomologists care about U but this
is just suggesting that we need to
understand more about these processes
and look at how far can we push it and
how can we use these methods to
complicate to complement the inputs that
we're using and this is particularly
important for those small holder systems
where you know they don't have the
resources at this point to purchase all
of these
inputs so um I have been aware of the
push pool intercropping system for a
long time I used it in my agricology
course as an example of um where
multiple ecological mechanisms are used
to manage pests and this is uh Zar Khan
who's the scientist who's been working
on the system for 20 years and he
developed it along with a number of
collaborators some at rothamstead in
particular and um this this system was
developed by the by CPE which is a small
NGO that's based in Kenya Works in this
the region of subsaharan Africa so he's
my sippi is my host institution in Kenya
and zaran is my main
collaborator so just a little geography
here's Kenya straddling the equator i'
had never been there before I went to
actually start working and visiting
these Farms um aipe is located over in
Western Kenya with the red X's right on
Lake uh the shores of Lake Victoria
and that that's their second research
campus they also have an office in
Nairobi and then the area where they
work is this this region of Western
Kenya which is a a humid a semihumid
tropical climate there's there's quite a
lot of variation in the the rainfall um
that actually occurs there anywhere from
800 to 1600 millimeters and in most
locations it's a bodal distribution so
there's two growing Seasons however very
far up north there's one long rainy
season up near um catali in the sort of
their Northern most border of the area
they work in so um there are uh Farmers
using push pool systems in other parts
of Kenya and also in in other subsaharan
countries but the the most of them are
concentrated in that um let see if I can
go back in this this region of Western
Kenya okay so what are the challenges
that these farmers are facing stemborers
are a big uh problem and there are many
different species of stemborers I forget
there's there's more than a hundred I
forget exactly how many um there are so
that that's the major arthropod pests
there are others but that one is the the
biggest one that has the be the largest
impact on yields and then the other
serious problem is striga which is a
parasitic
plant um and striga
actually um in addition to you know
taking nutrients and carbon from The
Maze plant striga is is pathogenic so it
it actually injects compounds into the
plant that CA that disrupt its
metabolism so the stunting of growth
that happens so here's the Str that
actually attaches right to the maze root
are largely due to this disruption of
metabolism and sort of you know actual
disease
develops stria has a huge impact on
yields I mean it just can decimate
yields once it gets into a field it
produces lots of seeds and it can just
keep spreading so these are the
challenges and the the push pull system
is is basically the the idea is to
manipulate the plants both in the field
and sort of on the borders of the field
to address these um constraints that
that are impairing yields and the work
began in the 1990s and at that point the
focus was on the stem boards and it
began with screening a bunch of
especially grass species to look for
plants that would serve as trap crops so
that would attract the pests and plants
that would repel the arthropods they
were looking for both of these and this
is why it's called a push pool is sort
of named after the the main focus of
managing the insects and this idea of
push pull systems has been around for
you know before the 1990s and there was
some work done in Australia um so this
is not the only case where this approach
is being used but it is an example of an
extremely effective um
case so by accident um zeran discovered
desmodium he he was just you know
collecting seeds he got some seeds for
it and he would screen you know whatever
plant species he was Finding and it
turned out that desmodium not only had
um a a sort of a repelling effect
towards the stemborers but it also
helped to control the striga and and
this was a huge Discovery because when
they first began promoting the system to
Farmers as a as a way of managing
stemborers the far and it it is a
ecologically it is a somewhat complex
system to manage so Growers need to
learn how to how to actually manage it
and they do and they also have
contributed to some of the Innovations
and I'll talk about that later um they
the farm said look this is great that it
controls stor but you know if you can
get rid of the striga then we'll
consider intercropping and you know
doing this so it it's really a good
thing that he found a plant that could
actually effectively control the striga
because it by far is the you know
greater has a greater impact on yields
and is of more concern to the farmers
and of course desmodium is a legum it's
a perennial legume so it has the added
benefit of fixing
nitrogen and there's been a lot of
improvements over time um to the system
from you know the beginning so there's
now multiple species that can be used
and the farmers have pushed some of this
Innovation by giving feedback on what
they
need so here's just a diagram of how the
system works and there's been a huge
amount of work on the chemical ecology
the entomology in the system and and
very little work on on the soils um so
the desmodium is planted in between the
maze rows they plant their maze fairly
far apart so you don't they don't have
to adjust the spacing in order to
intercrop they normally intercrop um
food legumes commonly so common Bean for
example or groundnut um so they they
plant the desmodium in the middle this
to the arthropod smells like a damaged
maze plant so that's I mean there been
like 11 to 13 chemicals that are have
been identified that mediate these um
exchanges between the plants and the
arthopods
so those act as the repelling plants the
stemborers when they go out of the field
find the napor grass which is planted as
a border around the field that is a trap
crop that attracts the stem bers they
lay their eggs in it it's a super duper
trap crop because it actually ends up
killing 95% of the larvae when the
larvae hatch out on a Napier grass plant
they get stuck in some of the the um the
Honeydew that that the plant secretes
it's got like some sticky goo that it
secretes near the base of its leaves so
many of them end up dying um so it
reduces the the population and then the
desmodium also releases some root exat
that stimulate germination of the striga
however it's a suicide germination the
striga germinates but it cannot elongate
to connect to the maze Roots so it ends
up dying and why can it not elong
why can't it elongate the seed tube I
forget the technical name of it well the
chemical that's produced by the
desmodium is for some reason stimulates
to germinate but then there's not the
next step that allows it to elongate and
I I don't that's about as far as I know
because it there are a lot of um
mechanisms that are involved I have a
slide of that but I left it
out so yes um so that's the main part of
the blowr work that's done though is on
the the disodium control of the striga
so these are just I'm going to show you
some pictures this is at the research
station there's several long-term
experiments there you can see the maze
with the desmodium which is quite a
vigorous grower and it's managed in ways
that reduce the competition with the
maze in terms of the timing of cutting
this is also a forage Napier grass also
serves as a forage and you can see that
it's also susceptible to the striga the
purple flowers of the striga and what's
amazing is these this is only like about
a you know 5T and there's there's
absolutely no striga in this field the
desmodium is incredibly effective at
controlling the stri this is one thing
we're wondering about is will there be
some over time some adaptation in the
striga to be able to overcome the
desmodium but so far there is no
evidence for that and I want you to
notice the size of this Napier grass
because it's rarely on a farm do you see
the grass get to this this size this is
one of the issues that the farmer are
harvesting Napier grass and the
desmodium to feed their
livestock so early in the season so the
the desmodium is cut back quite
drastically when the maze is planted so
it's it's very small when the plants are
small and then as the maze starts
growing it it begins to cover but you
can see it's much smaller than was under
the large plants and then by the you
know the time the maze is large it can
be a very thick carpet and sometime
sometimes even grow
upright
and this is out in one of the Farms so I
want you to notice here's the you know
very highly harvested border that's
almost
unrecognizable and many farmers are over
harvesting these accessory plants so
this is one question that we want to
look at is how much harvesting pressure
can these systems bear and still Garner
the benefits of the the um desmodium and
the grass borders and then this is an
adjacent field is another one of those
Farmers fields that she hasn't um
transitioned to pushpull and you can see
the difference there
so the benefits have been documented
extensively by work out in farms um in
terms of yield
increases um the control of striga and
simor and and very a little bit of work
on soil fertility most of the
conclusions about soil fertility are
sort of anecdotal or indirect and based
on yield improvements and the plants
look more vigorous and we know nitrogen
fixation is going on and that's why one
area I'm very interested in trying to
actually document um there are
significant improvements in livestock
production because now there's better
quality fodder for them and and also
more of it so both of these plants serve
as fod and this is a very important
outcome and benefit and one reason why
farmers are interested in adopting this
system um and as a result um there are
some economic benefits usually the
yields go up sufficiently so there's
extra maze for selling and there's work
going on now looking at how this all
pans out in terms of human
nutrition so at this point about 96,000
Farmers have adopted the system mostly
in Western Kenya but also in Uganda
Malawi and uh Tanzania particularly in
areas where strike is a problem that's
that's you know and also some of the the
areas that are a little drier where
there's there's other challenges um and
zipe has been instrumental in um
disseminating this they have a
demonstration garden at the farm where
they have the system at different stages
and this is I thought some of the
extension folks might be interested in
this because this is a complex system to
manage and um they can bring Farmers
there for intensive trainings and they
can show them you know at this stage you
need to do this and at this stage you
need to trim this is when you trim the
desmodium and they can actually get
practice doing some of these things um
so they they um plant they have
irrigation so they have at least sort of
six plots that are at different stages
when you would carry out different
management and they have a whole other
sort of system of Educators and
materials however beyond their efforts
Farmers have played an incredible role
in disseminating this technology which
is probably important in the case of
something that is this you know complex
to to manage and one of the most famous
Farm Farmers is Sarah Obama who I met I
thought they were kidding me when they
said they were going to have me meet
Sarah Obama thought oh they probably
have a grandmother all over the country
and they tell Americans you're going to
meet Sarah
Obama but then I got there and I saw the
sign so I and I saw the military
guarding her farm so she she was active
at one point in in um some of the you
know the pushpull dissemination efforts
but she's pretty low-key right at this
point um yeah so uh I want to show you
some I think this is where yeah I want
to show you uh just if the video works
we didn't get to test it because of all
the technical issues so now so you're
going to see two farmers and these these
two farmers Have Been instrumental in
disseminating the system um one of them
organize Mary first one you're going to
see is organized um groups where they
you know meet periodically talk about
what's working talk about what they need
to improve they bounce you know ideas
and problems off of each other she's
going to talk briefly briefly about
striga and then the next farmer is
called the grandmother of pushpo by many
of the um farmers in the region because
she adopted a bunch of farmers were
invited to this meeting and she was the
only one that came none of the men came
so she got trained in pushpo and she's
been um you know training farmers in her
community so the pushp farmers tend to
be in clusters she's going to talk in
her own language uh about the push pool
and just but I
can't um but show you two of she's got
two Fields a push pull and a non- push
pull I'm going to have
to
yes five is
local
yes and did you have strier here before
yes that was strier huh
hey to be beautiful with I don't yellow
pink pink flowers flowers
flowers yes
okay and how long
[Music]
has
I know I know she is and you know how
much she put
on amazingly small
amount yes so she has had pushpull
Fields since 1999 she took out one and
and S and you know rearranged her fields
and that field has been Push Pull since
I think 2004 2005 and you know sometimes
they try to do experiments so she did an
experiment she put fertilizer on her
push pool and she's convinced that that
helped her yields that's what she said
was however she put like five kilograms
on the whole
field at least that's what we can
understand so this is the challenge of
doing un on farm work because um we
suggested well what if you you put
fertilizer on both of your Fields
because many in many many cases we see
Fields where they are putting fertilizer
on all of their fields and on the field
station they put fertilizer on Push Pull
and non-push Pull and it seems like the
striga is the main one of the main
issues okay so um I'm working with
pretty much all enologists in this
system I'm very interested in what's
going on with the desmodium it's a
perennial legum there's a lot of
questions about how the nitrogen is
being delivered to the maze there's two
possible
Pathways and the entomologists are
convinced that this is the important
pathway um just because they know that
legumes can you know transfer nitrogen
to non- legumes um but I you know I
actually think this this may be
important early on but this probably is
the major pathway later on because we
know that you know nitrogen's going to
contribute to building organic matter
and that's another mechanism for
delivering nitrogen so these are the
kinds of questions um that started out
with I was really interested in looking
at how the disodium in crop defects the
flows of nitrogen and building organic
matter and then also looking at some of
the other related benefits of building
of the organic matter and then
understanding some of the sort of the
Ecology of nitrogen fixation in the
system there's several desmodium species
there's a lot of variation in
environment and also in management
history um and if we can understand this
then we could actually make
recommendations to the farmers about
when they might need nitrogen fertilizer
and when they may not need it um what
the evidence is that farmers are
applying nitrogen fertilizers sometimes
at high rates mostly at very low rates
and that they're they're you know
they're not really discriminating
between their pushpull and their non-
pushpull field so they may put just as
much fertilizer on the push pull Fields
where the legume is when there other
fields really might be nitrogen starved
and in we were seeing some evidence that
adding nitrogen suppresses nitrogen
fixation when we look at the desmodium
in fields where they put on a fair
amount of nitrogen we would just find
very few nodules and not you know
active um and then some questions about
how they use their land and how much how
heavily they harvest these um crops
especially the desmodium and when can
they start harvesting it
heavily um so I'm going to go into some
preliminary result results um I started
with sampling on the field station and
these are just results from three of
their long-term experiments showing
about a 30% increase in soil nitrogen
this is from the 20 cm dep so basically
the tillage
layer the kind of a surprising finding
was this difference in extractable
phosphorus so both the pushpull and the
non-p pushpull systems it's a tongue
twister have received the same amount of
phosphorus
fertilizer um but when you do
extractable phosphorus there's this
significant difference between the
pushpull and non- pushpull soils and we
haven't looked at the fractions and
exactly where the phosphorus is but
that's something we're very interested
in following up on did you look at
differences in
PH uh um there I've measured
P when I got there there had been
absolutely no soil measurements done
even on the experiment station so the pH
um does not show a significant shift sh
from Push Pull to non- pushpull except
for in one experiment which is the
non-replicated experiment the oldest one
and in that one I think it's because
some of the manure they added probably
has some calcium carbonate in it um but
it's very patchy patchily distributed um
and then you know we would expect these
differences in the organic matter pools
to show up most significantly in the
active pools so the particular organic
matter and these are very important to
look at because they do have the
greatest impact on soil structure um and
on uh nutrient flows so the particularly
the uded particular organic matter could
be an important source of nutrients and
for people that like to see this so this
is from the top 5 to six CM just the the
sort of the difference in the amount of
residue going into these soils um this
is from the longest experiment so that's
the the free particulate organic matter
and and we took these pictures for
extension purposes and then the uded
particulate organic matter which this is
a you know a big difference to be able
to see differences in these fractions is
is just a sort of a testament to how
profound the you know the impact is of
having this perennial
legume so um I was very interested in
collaborating with them to do some work
out on farms and see how this this
practice actually affects the the um the
farmer soils
um because their practices I mean on the
field station we could make critique
these are optimally managed they are not
aggressively harvesting the supporting
plants I mean they are harvesting them
and they are using them for fodder
they're harvesting them in the
recommended way um which is not nearly
as as aggressive as some of the farmers
who have small land Holdings and really
need fodder for their for their um
livestock are doing so um the first the
the cluster that I've been focusing on
in this initial work is located near the
village of Bea and this just gives you
an idea of the landscape and this area
um has a rainfall that's sort of in the
you know higher to medium in of 1,00 to
1200 millimeters it is is
bodal um and this in this region Farmers
have some very small Holdings fractions
of hectare so the the size of the Farms
varies with the region some of the
farmers in this region have a tenth of
an acre or so
um but on the plus side this is an early
adopting region meant to say that um and
that's partly because striga was a very
severe problem in this in this area so
and you can still see you can see lots
of striga and non- pushpull Fields out
in this in this region and there's some
you know Fields a lot of fields started
in two between 2002 and 2005 so to do
this on Farm research um we took fields
and div divided them into at least three
replicates and sometimes if it was a
large field we would divide it in half
and then divide those into three
replicates so the design because there's
some rolling topography and there are
some changes in soil types that are you
know occur on a fairly small scale our
first priority was to try to match the
soil
types um and so the analyses will be you
know viewing them we'll use them as
pairs um in order to compare Push Pull
and non-push pull effect so I have some
of the data from the Farms but not all
of the the non you know sort of the
background texture and all of that
information I don't have that yet so um
we went out divided them into these
replicates and and collected soil
samples from 20 cmers usually and made
composite samples at least you know six
to 12 cores depending on the size um we
interviewed the farmers briefly and I
was really dependent on the extensionist
to help me because a lot of the farmers
do not speak English Mary is one of the
exceptions um and so our findings on the
farms are similar they're they're
similar to what we found on the
experiment station but much more
variable as you would expect given the
the differences so five out of eight
pairs showed an increase in the soil
nitrogen and or organic matter um in one
case it's it's reversed and and what we
hope to do is to look at how
environmental variation and also
management practices so the you know
severity of the harvesting how much is
being harvested relative to you know
remaining in the fields and how that
impacts um these
Dynamics um we also found the same
result with the extractable phosphorus
and I do know that in this pair because
these farmers are neighbors that she
applied phosphorus fertilizer and she
did not um and the others it is very
hard to get accurate fertilizer
information
from Farmers and I think we've finally
figured out a way to do it I won't tell
you what it is but we've had better
success when I went back um this past
June at getting information that we feel
more confident so that's kind of where
we're going with that and the last thing
I'll show you with these preliminary
results and this is some of the early
work to look at nitrogen fixation
Dynamics and I'm in the process of
trying to find funding because it's
pretty expensive proposition to do the
isotope analyses that are needed for
this but I did do a survey and just
looking at the Delta n shift so this is
the Delta n and as it gets to be more
positive in the desmodium so in the
nitrogen fixing plant we can conclude
that nitrogen fixation is being reduced
so it's it's the you know A reduced
proportion of nitrogen is coming from
the atmosphere that's the interpretation
and we do see this positive relationship
the longer the farm or the soil is under
pushp we know the nitrogen fertility
goes up and we would predict that that
that would suppress nitrogen fixation
the legum down regulates and we we see
evidence for this um a pretty good
relationship there's some outliers and
this would this is where you know we we
would assume uh oh my Line's in the
wrong place if it was at zero that would
be 100% nitrogen fixation which we you
know don't normally see how' that line
move a mystery all right do I still have
five minutes is that it okay now I'm
going to talk even faster no
so future directions I'm going to talk a
little bit about the challenges because
the farmers are playing a really
essential role in overcoming some of the
challenges um and one of the major um
challenges is access to the seeds or to
the materials for these accessory plants
and I'm talking about the the Napier
grass the braia braulia grass which is
the other grass and the desmodium in
particular the green desmodium which is
a more drought resistant um species if
had a very difficult time getting it to
produce seeds in the you know in the
climate in Kenya they're you know sort
of a problem that they've been wrestling
with and here again the farmers have
been playing a crucial role in this this
is Elizabeth Elizabeth um oh dear I'm
forgetting her last name oh well um I
have it written down um and so she has a
um a nursery for the bararia grass so
she's been propagating this and you know
as part of her Outreach work um
disseminating this so some of the
farmers are actually hired they receive
a stapen from aipe to perform these
roles of Outreach and they occasionally
take it further and actually do problem
solving such as this she realized a
major issue is the Farmers can't get a
hold of the of the material and I'm
going to try to play one more video of
uh oh I'll show you her picture of Ura
Ura metho and um her Farm is pretty
amazing um and when you're watching this
video you might want to just watch her
expression while the extensionist is
translating because um she's
barely hanging on to not cracking
up farm so here's her farm
and and we're I'm at the lower push pool
field and they've
planted a lot of green doz moing
at the bottom of this field which is
overgrown the braulia
grass and it is full of flowers and
seeds and we took some pictures of the
seeds but um I think they're having some
very successful seed
production yes so we don't know if it's
the material they started with or
something about the
environment
this is Rachel
who is okay yeah so these are SE
for from her the SM Feld she's trying to
B to see if she can get seeds out of the
gra of so this is the seeds that she has
been able to harvest from um just a
small part of her Farm where she's
trying out this and um this is just part
of it she's going to uh Harvest more
from her field so this one she's going
to put it to dry up before she can try
to extract the seeds out of it yeah and
that was Rachel um she's the
extensionist from aipe that I work with
most of the time and she was also my
translator she did a lot of the
interviewing she engages in the social
science research that they they carry
out and um extension
Outreach okay so future research
directions I promise I'll cover it in
two minutes um so in in terms of the
work that I'm pursuing I'm very
interested in trying to do some more
detailed work on nitrogen cycling in
these systems to try to understand the
flows and and and um transfer of
nitrogen to the maze um and I'm also
working with some collaborators to to
look at some broader questions relating
the below ground changes that take place
in push pushpull and how those affect
the arthropods that are interacting with
the plants so particularly Andre
Kessler's interested in how plant
secondary compounds might shift and that
may impact these interactions and then
um we there there's a group of us that
have been formulating an idea to do some
research on the long-term
sustainability um in the pushpull
systems because there's a lot of
questions that come up about the
longevity and how affect you know how
these systems can continue to be
effective Ive over time um and these are
so this is sort of the core
collaborators there's um Kata peda and
Andre Kesler who are the two Cornell
faculty they're both entomologists that
I'm working with and then the folks at
aipe there's Professor KH um who some of
you may have he's sort of periodically
had appointments at Cornell um Dr
Charles modega and um Charlie um oh
shoot P pitar what Jimmy Jimmy Jimmy
pitar me and my name
and so um and he's the carries out the
social science research so looking at um
the sort of dissemination of knowledge
and how this impacts things like labor
demands and they're sort of getting into
collaborating with some nutritionists so
we're especially concerned about two
issues one is over time as you increase
the proportion of the landscape that's
in these systems how will that possibly
impact the herbivores are these
arthropods going to become resistant you
know are you're just going to overuse a
mechanism and they'll adapt um there's
many questions with that and um and also
climate change and how that's going to
impact them over time and the climate
change issue is tied into this this
question about harvesting how much
pressure can you put on the system and
have it still function um and and so
those those are are tied together we see
those as sort of the key pieces of the
sustainability issue and so I'll stop
and say thank you and be happy to answer
any questions or listen to comments you
have
thank no they're they're all rainfed
yeah they for the most part there's not
a means to irrigate so in some cases
they may you know have water for
irrigation that they'll preferentially
put on their home gardens some of the
Intensive vegetable crops right near the
house but not
maze Sor fascinating story I just have a
comment try to Gras if your sanal
hypothesis mhm
more likely get higher
right higher yields and what well I mean
the central hypothesis is sort of tied
to energy and inputs yeah oh okay but um
it seems to me is the diversity is not
in diversity it's a managing diversity
oh right yeah yeah we should reflect
that that should be reflected in the
right and I yeah so um this idea that
just any old diversity will be good and
you know is is not that's not really the
way we view it so there's a whole
literature and and this you know the
hypothesis comes out of the natural
ecosystems or unmanaged ecosystems work
so there's different metrics that we can
use for diversity and so functional
diversity and philogenetic diversity
those are two they're sort of replacing
species richness you know just simple
number of species so good point thank
you well I concur with they Ling that
there was fascinating presentation both
about drink water history and push pole
system um my question is have you given
any thought to the applicability of this
Push Pull system to American or North
American
agriculture well actually you know I
asked the entomologists about that and
so from The Pest Control angle and if
there's an entomologist here who wants
to add to this or correct me I I think
that it's probably not an option right
now mainly because of the the maze
genetics the material we have that we're
growing for you know corn because let's
see the um the signaling and the
communication between the stemborers and
the Maze has been
lost so the stemborers from what I can
understand from katata the stemborers in
the United States do not recognize the
signal of hey I'm a damaged corn plant
anymore at least the same yeah with the
so the specific
could right well the specific system you
know and then there's other issues it is
you know with trying to add a perennial
in between the maze rows and how that
would work so we have genetic material
here that we're using that's really
adapted for the system that's in place
which which is you know has these
cascading effects on the structure and
I'm not going to kind of go anymore go
into that anymore but the broader
question of using plant species I think
is definitely an option that we will
want to consider in in um you know even
in int intensified High yielding
agricultural systems there there are
some you know problems that we're
running to like especially in the
pollination dependent crops where even
under high input intensive agriculture
yields are being impacted by the lack of
diversity in the landscape and the lack
of pollinators and it can't really be
overcome just by moving honeybees around
and and you know it doesn't seem to be
and I think that if we want to try to
expand the ecosystem services that we're
going to get from agricultural lands
that this is is one approach that we
want to consider and we want to think
about you know where do we really want
to use nitrogen fertilizer because we we
do need it but we could be strategic
because there's definitely systems where
there's enough rainfall enough of a
growing season to grow some of our
nitrogen and then we would acrw these
you know these other benefits so
thinking about how do we you know I
think we just have to be strategic about
where we you know how we blend ecology
with the inputs that have been
developed thank you yes one more
question uh two really quick ones one um
the the desmodium perennial but is there
any sort of uh resal inoculation that
happens or is it
just yeah so far they haven't really
been using an ulation I don't know if
that's because it's you know
promiscuous um there are some native
desmodium species that are are in Kenya
and actually now so the two they're
using are from elsewhere the most
prevalent silver and green leaf there's
two pardon
thatum yeah so there's two desmodium
species that are are native of of
subsaharan Africa that they're
evaluating right now and and I think
that you know taking advantage of these
different ecotypes in Des modium and
also the different species of grasses
that can fulfill this function is a good
strategy that was actually my second
question in terms of the diversity
of is there variation for the
am down regulation
mod yeah that's a good question and
that's something I'm very interested in
we don't really know so you know we
would the right now the desmo green desm
moting is being heavily favored because
it's um
resistant and you know we don't really
know enough about the Ecology of these
species to know when might be beneficial
to have the silver relief like what is
the what is the difference in these in
terms of how they perform in an in crop
some farmers are ending up with a
mixture which I think is probably a good
way to capitalize and you know U because
they've lost some of their silad modium
because of drought and they've replanted
with green but they've left the silver
that's there so I think that'll be
interesting to see how that
pans out so we're over time but I want
to thank Lori and
great this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu