this is a production of cornell
university
okay so the title is i guess already
confusing learning circles and the hour
clutter ride so i'm an engineer so it
would be very easy to put me in a box
with nice square sides you know it's
made up of lines and it's also also very
tempting to think of
our education as linear
as a line you know you you start out as
a freshman you take some courses and you
build and eventually you graduate as a
senior and it's linear and so i i threw
the word circles up here to get you
thinking about how maybe it's more
complicated than that um and then the
hour clutter ride i should define the
abbreviation ride is research invent
design and power
i had a student give me this at
graduation last year and
it's
one of my favorite sayings has been that
it's a short walk to the edge of
knowledge she turned it around
and
i'm wondering how many of you noticed
that there's an interesting word inside
the word knowledge
now what'd you see
yeah
so what's funny is i
so you're a lot smarter than me i i had
been
talking about this phrase for for years
and had never made that connection and
then when
she created this little graphic and gave
it to me it's clear that those shoes are
about to walk off the edge and there it
is so anyway it's a short walk to the
edge of knowledge
and that's part of my philosophy and if
or something that i believe dearly and
my sense is if if you think it's not a
short walk to the edge or if you haven't
gotten to the edge you've not walked
very far
i think in any discipline you don't have
to go very far before you get to the
edge where there are things that you
don't know and i think
letting our students know that is really
important you know it's it's very
tempting to let our undergraduates think
that we know everything
and it's more fun to let them know that
we don't know everything
i've been doing aguaclada since
2004 2005 and so trying to figure out
how to talk about it is one of the
challenges because it's it's like
everything i do so i'm going to give you
three slices a perspective from honduras
a global perspective and then a cornell
perspective so in honduras the problem
that we're working on is there are there
are water supplies where honduras is
mountains okay everywhere mountains
everywhere and so almost anywhere where
there's a human settlement there's a
mountain that's higher and there are
streams up there and
the rainfall in honduras many places is
half decent and so there's often streams
that are running year round or springs
and so what they do is they go up in the
mountains they find a spring or a little
mountain stream or maybe even a river
depending on where they're at and they
take a pipe down to a distribution tank
and then onto the town and so you get
water out of your tap in your household
and
do you know about millennium development
goals
yeah okay so millennium development
goals one of them says that we should
reduce by half the fraction of people
that don't have access to
improved drinking water
and we just met that goal
okay naturally cool except that the word
was improved and this is improved
because it comes out of the tap in your
house even though even if it's river
water okay and our clotta is working on
solving that problem of having
dirty river water coming out of your tap
we think that's actually not safe we
know that's not safe
and even though i understand why it is
considered improved it's not the end
goal
so what we've done is we've developed
technology that would treat that water
and since 2005
our partner in honduras and
has built these plants
eight plants in seven locations
you you think i can't count it's okay
there's seven pictures up there um
here's what a plant looks like in a cad
drawing and
my little bragging here is this is
the result of
i don't know 10 000 hours of
of cornell undergraduate and a few
master of engineering students writing
code so that you can go onto our website
and request the design for a plant you
give it the flow rate that you want to
be able to treat and you get this cad
drawing and it's generated automatically
so technology that
i don't know of other places where
they're doing that kind of automated
parametric design that where everything
everything scales the way it needs to
scale to handle the flow rate this is
now the real thing looking inside one of
our plants a 12 liter per second plant
serving four villages
four poor
rural villages in
southern honduras
here's another picture of plants what we
do is we take very dirty surface water
and we turn it into clean water and we
do it all without electricity and it
seems amazingly simple and in a sense it
is very simple
and as part of doing this we've done an
awful lot of research in our labs to get
a better understanding at a very
fundamental level of what are these
processes what controls how well they
work and how do you make them
faster
and more cost effective and easier to
use from the operator's perspective
okay that was a slice of what's
happening in honduras and then let's go
to the global perspective so
here we are at cornell here we do
investigation innovation education and
design all of those things so our cloud
r d here at cornell
we are in the process of forming
aguaclada llc that is a business that
will
provide
the education sorry that will provide
the engineering services
for
the partners who end up building these
facilities and countries so
our cloud llc will work globally and
provide services to partners who work at
a in a country or maybe even in a region
in a country at building these
facilities
and then go down one step further there
are the organizations that actually
operate the facilities so it might be a
community elected water board that runs
the water treatment plant collects a
tariff
and makes sure that hires the operator
and then there's the people at the
bottom
the people that drink the water okay
this makes it look like this is all a
hierarchy
and i'm a little bit troubled by that so
let's mix it up so here we go um
so it's really like this they're
we're all there we're all interconnected
and we all talk to each other and
there's sharing of knowledge and
i
i get really excited about feedback
feedback is how you learn
we were talking about
are your kids an experiment right as
researchers when you have children are
they an experiment and
and either
you acknowledge that they are or you
pretend that they're not
because of course they're an experiment
right if you're a child
do you want to be experimented on by
your parents
what's your answer
no
or maybe yes and here's a pitch for yes
because if your parents don't admit that
they're experimenting on you it means
that they won't learn when they screw up
right
that's what feedback does you learn
based on your mistakes and so as you
know when i teach i i often admit to my
students that
they're guinea pigs in this situation
right i'm experimenting on them i'm
trying out educational techniques on
them and
i'm intending to learn from that to make
sure that i can do it better the next
time so
maybe being experimented on isn't such a
bad idea
within reason okay
okay feedback so i get really excited
about feedback feedback is one of the
reasons that agua cloud of plants in the
real world produce clean drinking water
and why many of the other technologies
that have been put forth
have not worked nearly as well and it's
because we use feedback we learn from
our mistakes and we make them better
every time and we'd look at what causes
systems to fail
and hence how do you eliminate those
failure modes the next time around and
i don't know this arrow could go in
either direction there's communication
that's happening
is it connecting like it means that
if a plant operator in honduras has
difficulty running a plant
there are mechanisms by which i will
hear about that
and that could turn into a research
project for my students to figure out
how to fix that problem so that it's
easier to operate or on another story
we were designing a new layout for our
water treatment plants
and we send
a cad drawing of this new layout to
honduras
to
our implementation partner
and the technician
at that organization not the engineer
but the technician looks at that drawing
and says ah but that's not going to work
because he gave me some reasons
and he was absolutely right
it would have worked but it would have
been unfortunate for the operator
so i got feedback and so we never ended
up making that mistake we never ended up
building that design because before it
was built we had feedback
okay so that was two slices that was
that was
what do we do first
we did honduras okay and then we did
like the big picture oh we didn't do
this part so all these guys so
there's one of these there's one of
these well okay there's a couple of
these right cornell's around the world
but really there's there's one in ithaca
sorry geneva right okay
and then
there are implementation partners so
there's one partner in honduras now and
we're spinning up another partner in
india
and there's
it'll eventually happen in other
countries as well so there will
ultimately be many implementation
partners around the planet that are
building our cloud of plants
and then each of them will be working
with multiple water boards and each of
them will be working with many customers
okay so it just
i guess it's a big pyramid scheme but
hopefully in a benevolent sense
okay so now at cornell
so
this is now getting closer to the
nitty-gritty of the program and this is
where you can start thinking about how
might you generalize this
oh my goodness okay so there's research
and event design and power
how do i want to talk about this
oh my goodness okay so a freshman coming
in can take my introductory course it's
an intro to engineering course and right
off we mix things up because in that
class i call it a design class a
freshman design class does that make any
sense
how can they design when they're
freshmen right like our pedagogy says
you have to wait until your seniors to
do design work at least in engineering
that's what we think of it so anyway i
call it design
and they actually
design and build a lab scale water
treatment plant that is computer
controlled and that produces clean water
and they have sensors to verify that it
meets
us drinking water standards when it's
done
they do that in small teams
and and i know that they don't
understand everything that is all the
theory behind it but i give them a taste
of that of the different theories so
they have a little bit of a sense of
what's going on enough
that it makes sense to them by the time
it's done
so this is doing things completely out
of order
and i think it's really important
because
then
later on when they take a theory class
they've already seen it and they know
i'm not pulling their leg about how
things work because they've seen how
this worked and they know what was
important in making the system work
and then the theory makes more sense
i'm this is the circles like um fluid
mechanics is one second
fluid mechanics is one of the hard
courses in in engineering curriculum and
i've always said you should really take
the course twice
because the second time around there are
things that are taught at the beginning
of the course which will now make sense
to you that didn't make sense because
you went down a line and the stuff in
the beginning you just couldn't figure
out how to wrap your head around it but
after you learned the stuff at the end
you come back and it makes sense and i
think all of us who have gone through
multiple levels of courses there we've
experienced that where things that
didn't make sense now beginning to make
sense yes
this is a three credit course this is a
three credit actually everything three
credit okay
so
freshmen do this
juniors or seniors can do this i
actually had a sophomore do this once
and she did great
all out of sequence
okay then
over here is the project
so this is where students are working on
the project they're doing
research or design work doing research
in the lab and there are graduate
students
there are
project courses that are for
freshmen and sophomores who have not yet
taken
or juniors who have not yet taken this
course
and then there's a senior level course
that is for
people who've already taken this theory
class
they're in the same project but now they
can get design credit for working in the
project whereas these folks
they don't actually get any credit
that's worth anything
okay sorry they know that
and then there are master of engineering
students who are taking the course or
the project for their design project
but what i do is i
i wrap a circle around that whole thing
and students from those three entryways
into that course all come to the same
room
we all meet together and then we split
them up into teams and we split them up
into teams very carefully actually and i
don't do this i delegate this to my team
leaders they figure this out they split
them up into teams and there are
mixes of
student abilities mixes of ages of
students or
location in their degree program
all mixed together
to create these small teams
okay there's also a summer internship at
cornell we have this great program
it's no money no credit come work for us
and what's amazing is
is that students do this we we have like
20 students come and work every summer
as part of this so it's amazing what you
can make cornell students do
sorry but i know that half of you are
cornell students so
okay and then there's an engineering and
context course where i take about 20
students to honduras for two weeks
during the january inter session
this currently there's no credit for
this and it's not officially connected
with any courses it's just something
cool to do and
i see it as an integral part of the
program
i have one here
i pointed to this
time in honduras as learning and i've
pointed to this stuff as service just to
reverse things for you because in the
service learning model you tend to think
of what you do on campus as a learning
time and what you do
at the project site as as service
and i actually think in in this case
it's more reversed they're doing the
useful things that will help our folks
our partners they're doing the useful
things here at cornell
and then when they're in honduras
they're mostly learning
okay anybody want to ask a question
about this
oh one more thing
don't tell my director
wait
can i trust this many people
but i i give two lectures per semester
in this course
that's not per week that's two per
semester um and
uh
it's it's team time it's time to work in
i think it's time for some pictures
no it's time to go
alt tab
will this work yes okay so this is a the
wiki for
that project course and
we divide up into teams so i didn't want
to make another powerpoint slide so i
was lazy so here's all these topics that
are currently being researched and each
of those would link to another wiki page
where
they'll describe what they're doing and
they'll be posting their their reports
as they as they work during the semester
and there's a little blurb about each of
them which you could read on forever
so the point is that's what's happening
in that course students have a design
challenge or a challenge that they're
working on a research challenge or a
design challenge and they're working on
that for the duration of the semester
and they're
they're writing
reports every couple weeks
and we're evaluating them
and who evaluates them okay so here's a
teams of three to five i said some of
this before
range from developing new theories
optimizing performance developing new
fabrication methods creating design
algorithms all those things are
happening
all under this overarching create safe
drinking water
the leadership structure okay so i'm
director of the program and
i describe this as servant leadership so
my job is to provide the resources so
that the team members can be successful
so that's there there are undergraduate
graduates and faculty who work together
to provide feedback to individual teams
i have
undergraduates who actually read some of
the reports and evaluate them and give
them back i have
a graduate student who's doing some of
that and i'm doing some of that we share
the load between us
i have student leaders who organize the
training sessions for the tools that are
used there are there are research tools
that we've created over the years that
make it possible to automate
the operation of experiments and it's
one of the ways that make it pop makes
it possible for
students who
can't spend 40 hours a week in the lab
to actually do meaningful research they
can automate their experiments and so
they have to learn how to use that
automation system and so my
students
create the tutorials
to train the new students coming in how
to use that system
and i don't do any of this
my students do this
my i have a student leader she creates a
syllabus
and says what's happening on each day
during the semester
and she tells me what to do she says
you're giving your tip your talk on this
day
and that's an undergraduate by the way
and she's been she's been great she's
been doing for the last two years
and then the graduate students
have a completely different experience
too i tend to have about two graduate
students
only two for this program and
they end up having this experience of
basically being a pro managing a program
so they get to do what faculty normally
do normally faculty run a research
program
my graduate students
effectively run a research program where
they have multiple students working
under them
in a servant leadership kind of way
working on different research projects
symposium so in the middle of the
semester we have this symposium system
where
we used to do
powerpoint presentations and we all sit
there and watch them and we realized
after a while that that wasn't the most
effective way to learn about what each
of the teams was doing so the point of
this symposium is that you want an
opportunity for all of the teams
to figure out what all the other teams
are doing so there's sharing of
knowledge between teams because they're
doing very different kinds of things
each team is a very different kind of
research
so they give short presentations
right next to their experimental
apparatus so they can actually point to
it and explain how it works demonstrate
it
and
they do it in relatively small groups
and we end up spending
four
class periods for 75-minute class
periods to rotate all the teams through
all the stations so that everybody gets
to
tell everyone else what's going on and
also gets to see all the other
teams that are doing their thing
so that's another example of peer-based
learning
this is now going to honduras so some
pictures from honduras uh
students getting to see the hour cloud
of plants getting getting the talk
interview the
the operator find out what works what
doesn't work what kind of problems
they've tended to have
and just fully engage
and another thing that we do
so this is where
the learning and service are really
closely tied together so this is a
filtration system that
students had developed over the previous
semester and
now they're
attempting to deploy it in honduras
and the goal of this is it's not going
to be used yet it's in the it's
oh no and it's it's going to be
it's like this is like a first
deployment let's try it and see what
happens
and
why do we do it it's so our partner in
honduras can see what technologies are
that we're working on
and it'll get their ideas spinning about
well where might this kind of technology
actually make sense
in their context and they'll give
feedback to us and and given that this
was the first time we deployed this
filter it also had problems
and so we get feedback about what failed
and that goes back to our lab to fix the
next semester so that was one example
we also get to look at our plants and we
get to see how they how they work
so this is looking at a sedimentation
tank and they're taking it apart and our
students are getting to see how this
really looks
they had opportunities to see pictures
and to see autocad drawings you know in
previous semesters but they all comment
that there's nothing like
actually seeing the real thing and
seeing how it all fits together
okay this is now
the world that many of us live in where
there's there are these three spheres
there's research
there's teaching and there's service
and
marshall made it clear that apparently
i'm doing something that is a little bit
uncommon it i hadn't fully realized this
but this is what i did i took them
and i sucked them all together and
and i think i confused my director
sometimes
because
he's like is that research or is that
teaching and i'm like yes
actually it's a
it's a real like there's accounting
issues
i don't know there are accounting issues
that drive them crazy because like what
was that researcher teaching
like well how would i know i mean it was
research that's part of a course so
what's that okay so there it is
community scale drinking water is is
what i'm working on and what has been my
focus for the last eight years
and
all of it fits underneath that
so a few reflections it's hands-on
learning it's mixing up application in
theory
so many of our students are incredibly
highly motivated to do something to make
the world a better place and if you can
tie tap into that
you've got a really powerful connection
you can you can make them work hard not
make them you can invite them to work
hard and they will deliver
they provide an amazing volunteer
workforce
yeah
so does it work
so four papers per year published in
decent journals
over the last two years that are
research results coming out of this
lots of students engaged in
20 students in the summer 35 students in
the fall
this is in the in the project courses
and 55 students in the spring
many inventions were open source which
makes it open source is so efficient
because when you invent something you
just throw it on the web and you're done
you don't have to do anything you don't
have to talk to
the c-tech you just throw it on the web
and nobody else can patent it and
anybody can use it and you're done
i i think that labs that are so tied
into making sure that nobody else can
use it they end up wasting a lot of time
making sure that happens
this is simple
our students write their reports and
when they rewrite their reports every
two weeks those are immediately posted
on the web so stuff that they're
developing during the semester is
protected from
somebody trying to patent it right away
so okay we have many inventions we have
a new theory for flocculation you don't
want to know about flocculation but
anyway we have a new theory for that
that's that will eventually hit the
press it's going to take a little work
to debunk old theories there's 30 000
people with safe drinking water in
honduras there's an hour clouded llc
spinoff
and
i think we have an incredibly cost
effective research model in that we can
generate lots of results with a few
graduate students
and on
a tight budget
this has been a production of cornell
university on the web at cornell.edu