this is a production of Cornell
University thank you Mark it was a
wonderful introduction I really
appreciate it and I appreciate everybody
who's here either virtually or in person
um to listen to this presentation which
is not about Bara mclen for a
change um this is a a Pres presentation
that stems from work that I started many
many years ago and I'd like to uh give
you a perspective on that
work um the background for my story
began in
1985 while I was searching for
Publications to document my first
edition of the plants of San Salvador
island in the Bahamas the picture of our
cover of our first edition is on the
right side of the screen
I um was invited to the Bahamas in the
early 1980s to actually teach a class
on um the botney marine
botney and I had a little bit of
background on picology and so I started
to do that while we were down there my
students kept asking me what's this
plant what's that plant on the
terrestrial land and I didn't know and
uh so I thoughted to try to find
Publications to try to help them and
myself and from that the director of The
Field Station asked us to write a common
plants guide with illustrations because
there wasn't anything available at the
time for the non botanist so the class
was a general education course for non
botanists and uh from that uh we began
looking for published papers to include
in our common plants guide which was
actually illustrated by one of my
students uh Tony
Kowalski uh in 1995 while I was waiting
to board the plane to attend the first
Symposium on the botney of the Bahamas
on San Salvador Island which is
currently called the natural history of
the Bahamas um I met Dr Hardy Esa and
here's a picture of Hardy on the right
that I took many years
later uh so who is this guy and why is
he so important to my story uh party was
a cornelian and an Indiana University
PHD who later became interested in the
Bahama
Flora uh at the at this 1985 Bahamas
conference that we were going to he
presented an unpublished distribution
map for plants that were compiled by
William Thomas Gillis that he had
actually found in the herbarium at
Michigan State
University now on the right hand side of
the screen you can see this distribution
map one of many hundreds that were uh
that are currently in the Michigan State
University
herbarium and what Gillis did is he
began looking and became interested in
the Bahama Flora in the early 70s
actually the late 80s and he began uh
documenting the distribution of all the
plants at the Bahamas on these
distribution maps and each one of the
little dots there represents a plant
that had either collected or he had
found in the literature or he came
across in a herbarium so this really
helped us figure out well what were the
plants that were on St Salvador by
looking at gillis's
Maps so during this time we as I said we
were looking for to P to find
Publications and we came across this big
book that had just recently been
published by Carell and Carell called
the Flora of the Bahama archipelago
and this book was basically for uh
taxonomists it was not a book for the
general public it had descriptions in
Latin and um we got a copy of it and
slept it in our backpacks down to San
Salvador on a regular basis while trying
to uh to describe the plants of the
Bahamas for our
book and um what we noticed was in the
preface to this book was an
acknowledgement to the National Science
Foundation for for funding the
publication of the book and the other
thing we noticed was that there were no
or very few references to Dr gillis's
Publications so I said to Hardy why was
gillis's work ignored in the Corral's
recently published Flora of the Bahama
archipelago
well party oh where am
I sorry going the wrong
direction there we go so hardy suggested
that I contact Associates who might know
the answers to my question and one of
the people that actually worked with
Gillis on his um interest in the Bahama
Flora was Richard Howard of the Harvard
University
herbaria and he provided many leads to
finding the answers to my question so I
drove up to Boston and a Cambridge
actually and I interviewed dick Howard
in
1993 at the Harvard University herbaria
to try to get some answers and
documentation on what was going
on so the search to solve my question
precipitated finding documents revealing
a lack of Ethics in Grant proposal
reviews and a story of to my to our
horror dishonor which is the subject of
this seminar now Hardy and I have
published are have written a manuscript
that was submitted and accepted for
publication that gives the absolute
background of the whole story and I'm
just going to give you a brief review of
that the the publication should be out
in the we will promis that it would be
out in the spring of 2024 in Huna the
Journal of the ban of Botanical
history so let's talk about or let's see
what we found the National Science
Foundation had um conflicts of interest
problems with grants to short-term
employees um these short-term employees
are known as
rotators and in
1979 the United States General
Accounting Office which is currently
called the US general Accounting Office
began a review of the National Science
foundation's policies and procedures for
precluding conflicts of interests in its
Grant award process specifically when
NSF former short-term Rotator employees
were involved the review was
precipitated by a request from
congressman Carl D purcel a republican
from Michigan who he who had submitted
this request in May of
1979 Congressman pcell had made a
request to the government office on
behalf of a constituent now I want you
to know that this proposal that or this
review that they
made uh did not reveal any names so
please keep that in mind so he he um
made a request on behalf of his of a
constituent who unfortunately did not
live to see the outcome of their review
a draft of the GAO 1981 report included
a proposal for identifying conflicts of
interest and the National Science
Foundation imple implemented that
proposal which concluded quote should
provide greater visibility to potential
conflict of interest situations
associated with grants involving
rotators and to resolve conflicts in
accordance with statutes and
regulations additional specifics of this
case that regarded Purcell's unnamed
constituent purcel had asked for review
of National Science Foundation policies
and procedures for awarding Grants to
former National Science Foundation
employees he specifically requested
clarification whether these policies and
procedures including Provisions for
their
waiver adequate adequately prevented uh
prevented conflicts of interest and
whether NSF complies with them this is
actually published in that
report the
investigation as summarized
here pcel Purcell's interest in the case
was brought to his attention by a
researcher unnamed in the report from
his home District whose proposal NSF had
declined to fund although it later
funded a similar project proposed by a
former National Science Foundation
employee the government office
investigation focused on the special
problems of processing grants from
short-term employees the rotators who
work for National Science Foundation for
one or two years and to assess NSF Grant
award process as it relates to Awards
made to scientists who are being
considered for or are serving in or have
completed short-term appointments in the
National Science
Foundation they found 39 problems in
Grant activity for 24 past and current
short-term NSF appointees recall this
was the begin this uh investigation
began in 79 the report was done in '
81 23 individuals in the sample
including the National Science
Foundation appointee in the case
involving Congressman perel's
constituent contributing to the problem
were decisions on this grant activity
made by Associates to the NSF appointees
and often the relationships were between
supervisors and
subordinates additional specifics
questionable circumstances surrounded a
waiver of post-employment restrictions
and proposed
review Purcell's con constituent had
submitted a proposal that the National
Science Foundation declined but the
decision on which to judge whether the
constituent proposal was treated fairly
was limited did because all files
relating to it had been destroyed by the
time of the government's
review that's a quote now I'd like you
to please keep this statement in mind
especially what I state in the
highlighted dark brown
lettering I'll repeat it again all files
relating to it had been destroyed by the
time of the Government review
around the time the constituent's
proposal was rejected another researcher
began a two-year rotational appointment
at the National Science Foundation in
the program office that had rejected it
the NSF appointe applied for a waiver to
submit a proposal upon leaving
NSF after leaving NSF the appointe
submitted a proposal it was the same
subject as the
constituents what did they find they
found conflicts of interest the former
NSF employee submitted his proposal to
the program that he had
directed The Proposal review was
completed in three months according to
their findings it actually was six weeks
it usually took about five months to act
on the
proposals so it was reported but it was
actually eight months for the
constituent's proposal to get his review
back the National Science Foundation
program officer who made the award
recommended for the former NSF program
officer had earlier used the NSF
appointy as a reference on his own
application for his own employment at
the National Science Foundation and he
had also worked for the former employee
appointee these were the findings from
the
usgo now with the help of Richard Howard
among others we track down the grant
proposals the 1993 in 1993 myself and my
husband located all of Purcell's
constituents research files including
copies of both National Science
Foundation Grant
proposals the files were archived at the
Michigan State University
herbarium and at the Fairchild tropical
garden herbarium and library
archives the documents at MSC Michigan
State University herbarium and at the
Fairchild tropical garden herbarium
revealed that the NSF appointee was
Donathan Carell program director of
systematic biology and the co-author of
the 1982 Flora of the Bahama
archipelago and who they had funded
twice and which was in their preface to
their book Purcell's constituent was WT
Gillis the guy who did all those
distribution maps and was a former
Fairchild tropical garden employee and
the author of the original rejected
Grant proposal
Carell's National Science Foundation
Grant propos proposed writing an
illustrated vascular Flora of the Bahama
Islands he submitted it from the
Fairchild tropical garden on October 1st
1973 two months after he had left the
National Science Foundation appointment
and it was approved six weeks later on
15 November
1973 much of the text was derived from
the grand proposal previously submitted
to the National Science Foundation by
Gillis from the same
institution here's the case as was
summarized by the
usgao in
1981 the National Science Foundation
awarded the former NSF appointee more
than
$90,000 over five years within the five
years he requested and was granted an in
increase that brought the total award to
more than
$100,000 during the six years he was
awarded about $40,000 in additional
funds and the grant period was extended
to a total of more than S and a half
years one of the major arguments made by
reviewers of gillis's 1970 National
Science Foundation grants proposal which
we found at the Michigan State
University herbarium was to prepare a
manual and a flora of the Bahama
vascular
plants and the argument was that the
cost was too
high yet the usgao report revealed that
Carell received over 75% in funding for
one investigator himself and for fewer
years of support than Gillis had
originally requested for three
researchers himself Dr Howard and Dr
Proctor of The Institute of of research
in Jamaica who was also researching the
Flora of the
Bahamas well the question is is this
really a plagiarized Grant
proposal revising and submitting a
Bahama Flora Grant proposal might be
justified by assuming the project was
the purview of the institution where it
had been
initiated that's all well and good
except that the um argument doesn't
really fly because it wasn't the
institution that started this but it was
actually the researchers within that
institution whose idea it
was Carell's October 1973 Grant proposal
misrepresented what actually happened
they said gillis's involvement
initiating the project in 1968 at
Fairchild tropical garden they did not
include the fact that Gil 's involvement
initiating the project in 1968 at
Fairchild tropical garden they
misrepresented it as a institutional
proposal which it was not it was only
signed by the institution director but
his he had nothing to do with the grant
proposal Gillis and collaborators having
priority and partial funding for the
Bahama Flora Project was ignored they
did
not cite any of the previous or current
Publications that Gillis had done they
it was not part of the grant
proposal and they did not acknowledge
that there was priority that someone
else had started this project years
before what was the priority for writing
a Bahama Flora in 1970 Gillis began
collecting and published his first
report towards writing a new Bahama
Flora the publication came out in 1970
and we C it in
1991 with Richard Howard and and uh dick
Proctor Gillis continued the project
until his he died his untimely death in
1979 he died on June 20th 19 in 1979
approximately two months after the
investigation began by the US
GAO picture on the right on the bottom
shows Howard and Gillis with the
students uh doing research in the
Bahamas in the early or the mid
1970s the National Science
Foundation had
recognized that it has been less than
successful in addressing the unique
problems associated with the Rotator
program that's a quote the United
States government organization report
had sensitized NSF employees to
conflicts of interest problems in the
Rotator program program they reported
and accordingly the National Science
Foundation will take steps to address
new conflicts of interest
policies with respect to the case at
hand meaning the issue with the
constituent the National Science
Foundation planned to issue a directive
that all staff in grades gs12 and above
who are leaving the National Science
Foundation be especially counseled by
the ethics
counselor the ethics counselor is in the
office of the general council at NSF
about post-employment conflicts of
interest
restrictions further they report that a
former employee is precluded during
oneyear period after National Science
Foundation service from submitting a new
proposal to the National Science
Foundation as principal investigator and
from receiving compensation under any
NSF award other than one on which he or
she suspended work when coming to the
foundation that appears in their
appendic the final
conclusion I say yet the National
Science Foundation believed that none of
the basic rules that they used to guard
against conflicts of interest involving
rotators was violated in any of the
cases s Ed in the draft report that's in
appendix 3 so NSF is still denying that
they did anything
wrong the usgao believed that their
final recommendations to the director of
the National Science Foundation if what
if it if they were
implemented would resolve conflicts of
interest questions for the National
Science
Foundation the
enforcement of the National Science
Foundation policies might have reassured
Bill Gillis that a case such as his
would not be
repeated as I said unfortunately he
didn't see this decision because he died
in
nevertheless our findings revealed that
basic rules from the NSF had been used
to guard against conflicts of interest
involving rotators
were
violate so when we did our research when
we found the
documentation it was clear to us that
these interests were definitely violated
although NSF denied
it so our conclusion within keeping
within historical perspective we may
recall the words of the Roman historian
tacitus the principal office of History
I take to be be this to prevent virtuous
actions from being forgotten and that
evil words and deeds should fear an
Infinite infamous reputation with
posterity now this is an interesting
conclusion only if
one can get the information out that
proves that there was a
problem Hardy and I have been trying to
get this paper published for 20 20 years
and no one would publish it until last
year acknowledgements I would these are
all the places that we visited talk to
zillions of people to get the
documentation for our
story The End thank
you I would like to entertain questions
if you have
them hold on do you have a question Judy
question it has less to do with ethics
and more to do with the biodiversity of
Bahamas Judy can you hear
me me to come up can you hear Judy yeah
I can hear her okay good biodiversity of
the Bahamas you said something about
concerned with hurricanes slamming the
the Caribbean that there are some FL
that may be at
risk
what's the question question was are you
concerned about H
hurricanes um hitting the Bahamas and
and wiping out species oh absolutely um
yes um we we lost uh we lost a lot of
plants uh during Hurricane Dorian um and
uh one of the things that's important
for the herbarium is to document the
plants that were there and what and any
that might have been lost so right now
we're in the process of doing that and
Ethan freed and the Bahamas National
Trust is working on uh that project um I
haven't been directly to the Bahamas in
a while but but I have colleagues who
are working on S Salvador and uh
fortunately the the hurricanes on S
Salvador haven't been as devastating as
ones in uh the uh the more the more
Western Islands but uh sure we we are
definitely concerned about the that and
I've written a recent article on the
Bahama
endemics uh as has Ethan freed and um
we've published the importance of the
endemics On and On which Islands they
are and the one we the publication that
we recently wrote was uh about the
endemics that we found on S Salvador
which are fortunately still safe um but
I just learned recently that the Duke
University herbarium was is being closed
and that is such a shame because um how
are we going to document loss of of uh
diversity if the herbaria are not being
kept kept up so um yeah it's it it is
definitely a concern uh but uh but the
other thing that's important is to plant
uh trees like uh or not not definitely
necessarily trees but but mangrove trees
uh specifically along the coast so that
they can protect the Inland Coastline uh
and when the when the mangroves get
destroyed or are cut down uh that causes
uh a big problem uh so we've we've um
advocated for replanting Bahamian
species of mangroves that have been
destroy taken out and they are doing
that um in many places right now so I
don't know if that answers your question
or not but those are my comments yeah
she says it answered your question I
have a question as well are there any
invasive species that are causing
problems in in the Bahamas oh absolutely
yeah we have a list of invasives and um
there's really not a lot that we can do
about it I mean you know it's just like
in haw they've been going through places
and pulling them out and um you know we
do that on St Salvador too fortunately
St Salvador is like way out there and
and so we don't have as many invasives
as some of the other Islands if I go
back to this uh
picture do you see my screen or not I
need to share again oh never mind okay
so anyway Sans Salvador is way out there
um and and is one of the islands that
actually I don't know if you know the
are familiar with San Salvador Island
but it was the first one that Columbus
landed on when he came to the New World
um and um there's if you go to his log
you can see all the trees and plants
that were on S Salvador when Columbus
first landed and we we now know how many
of those have been destroyed uh you know
because uh because what happened in in
the 1700s is that people from the United
States came to the Bahamas to establish
plantations and um they took out a lot
of the trees and shrubs and when they
did that all the top soil ended up in
the ocean so the plants that are
left um are ones that can survive in a
zerotic environment and also um can uh
have an an association mostly lots of
legumes because they have an association
with the fungus um that can provide
nutrients so um that's what I can tell
you we have several questions um Sam hey
Lee thanks for a great talk I hope you
can hear me okay but I'm curious if
you've seen ethical issues in funding
from other organizations other than NSF
maybe like Public Funding through the
USDA or private funding to The Gates
Foundation or something like that I have
not uh looked elsewhere one of the
things I can tell you is that NSF now
has a requirement that all rotators take
a
class on conflicts of interest they have
to take one there NSF offers a class
monthly and rotators have to take at
least one every I forget what the exact
number is every every couple of months
or at least once a year to uh uh
understand conflicts of interest and if
you find a conflict of interest or if
you think there is one you can report it
to the uh counselor um and um so they
have they have ways to do that now and
all that stems from this paper from this
investigation back in
1979 that um that Gillis brought to his
congressman and said look you know this
grant was stolen from me and and I want
you to investigate
it
um
yes um I was just curious if you think
uh the current conflict of interest
policy is sufficient or do we still have
ways to go and and what your suggestions
would be to improve the policies around
conflicts of
interest yeah I
mean I personally have not I personally
have not
um been involved with an National
Science Foundation as a ma matter of
fact I have to tell you that that when
when Hardy and I first started this
project and we wanted to get we did get
one paper published uh in rodora about
this guy's gillis's contributions to the
Bahama flora and we wanted to say
something about what we found with the
conflict of interest and the editor of
RoR said you can't do that you can't
publish it you have to cryptically you
have to cryptically write it so that
it's not obvious so we modified the
paper and he published it but the other
thing he said was if you publish this
paper you will never ever get an NSF
Grant that's what he told us the editor
of rodor told us that now that I mean
that didn't happen because I do have
have gotten NSF grants but we were
warned um that if we publish anything
about this we would not be granted
funding in the future and it's been over
20 years we've been trying to get this
paper public published and we couldn't
get it published until very recently
when the people at the hunt Institute
said yeah we'll publish
it so I don't know what I mean I can't
answer your question uh I do not know uh
if there have been recent conflicts of
interests in Grant proposal
reviews
um but if there have been
then people have now have recourse to
report them where they didn't have that
before does that answer your question
yes thank you yeah a question over here
can I uh can I just jump in here this is
Larry smart hi Larry uh so I was a copi
on an NSF project that was led by Matt
Olsen uh at Texas Tech this was in the
dimensions of biodiversity
program uh it included Matt as a pi
myself Steve defasio at w know Steve
yeah and
uh uh another colleague at University of
Wisconsin and the original four-year
Grant I thought was very successful I
thought we published a ton of papers it
was in the US China program so our
Chinese collaborators also published a
lot and then when we went to renew the
project and continue it Matt decided to
rotate at
NSF and then Steve decided to rotate at
NSF so neither one of them could be
listed as pis
on uh and even beyond that when it went
for review it had to go to a different I
think even a different
division uh for the decision because
Steve was rotating in that Division and
it couldn't they couldn't make a
decision uh within that division because
he was there uh and in the end it wasn't
renewed uh and I partially blame those
guys for rotating at NSF because uh they
could not be listed as copi on the
renewal proposal uh even though I
thought it was a fantastic project but
you know that's life these things happen
but well now has some background on why
that
happened and now you know it's Steve is
still at NSF so oh yeah yeah yeah I know
he he was in he was in the biology
Department in at West Virginia
University and now he's at NSF yeah
yeah thank you for your talk oh you're
welcome your question it's related to
the previous questions already but um
just curious how you count your case
from 1981 in temporary time and how we
should be especially as early
researchers be looking out for these
conflicts of interest in the NSF and
other granting agencies and yeah just
like the stealing of ideas
Etc I I didn't quite hear the whole
question I'm sorry it's about early
career um
researchers uh how sh how how should you
be concerned about uh conflicts of
interest is that yeah how how this case
from 198 one can be situated in
contemporary time oh well yeah okay so I
teach a graduate genetics seminar here
at at West Virginia University I co- te
it and we um actually presented
this this uh story to my class uh as a
practice seminar uh a couple weeks ago
and um they were they were very
concerned they said that that they these
are graduate students so they said they
really wanted they were very happy to
hear the story and were very interested
in knowing about how to preclude
conflicts of interest uh in in proposals
and reviews and not only that but in in
reviewing papers as well so I think that
the thing to do is use it as a lesson in
a graduate seminar maybe um to teach
graduate students as we're doing here um
about the possibilities to prevent
conflicts of
interest does that answer the question
or
not yeah she says yeah okay thank you
thank you very much Lee can you hear me
yeah okay yeah when you first wanted to
present I didn't realize oh my goodness
uh historian can present something
fascinating at least for me I don't know
for all of you online I felt you're not
only a historian almost like a
detective
I almost felt can be used as a script to
make a movie I won't be
surprised thank you well if if you think
this is an interesting story you should
uh look forward to reading my book about
Barbara mlto where I've uncovered a
whole bunch of documentation that
reverses a lot of Mythology so that
should be out in June I'm just giving
you a little bit of
a a warning a
warning related to that I felt 20 years
you have been so uh devoted to this
publication almost on a mission so yeah
go ahead yeah so I'm wondering when you
origin asked that question that was
completely without any uh background is
just uh just a question you already have
some uh hint some information so you
were no I did I didn't have any hint at
all all I knew is that I was looking for
Publications to include in my book from
that which was published in
1991 and um uh in order to document the
the uh Publications that had been
already
uh done for the island of San Salvador
uh I wanted to make sure I found
everything that I could include in my in
my
bibliography um for my students so that
they could go to the primary papers
because from at one of the things loved
about learning at Cornell is that
Cornell always required when I was
taking classes required us to read
primary papers rather than reviews uh
and and every class that I took we' get
a handout with primary papers to read
and and so I took that as a as a a way
of teaching and and and whenever I write
a paper or you know wrote my books I
always tried to find the primary papers
and so I was looking for the primary
papers and they weren't listed in this
book and and so I said to Hardy how come
they're not listed why were they
ignored and uh the answer is that uh you
know this guy the Corrals didn't want
any part of Gillis they didn't want him
involved in in their project at all it
was a coverup I
think so that's you know like I I sort
of this project it just fell into my lap
and Hardy was wonderful in collaborating
with me as a matter of fact the first
paper that I tried to publish on his on
the contributions of Bill Gillis when I
sent it to the rodora the editor did not
want to publish it at all as I mentioned
and so I called Hardy on the phone and I
said he at the time I think he was the
president of the Botanical society and
so he picked up the phone and he called
the editor and he goes what is the
matter with you why don't you want to
publish this and he was afraid to
publish it because of what we had found
and so um I said to the editor well what
if I put Hardy's name on the paper and
he goes well that might help so har I I
said to Hardy well if you if I'm going
to put your if your name is going to be
on the paper then you have to do
something you have to write part of this
paper or it's unethical for me to just
stick your name on the paper so he went
back and looked through his files and
then he added some stuff to the paper
and then the paper came out in uh 1993 I
think it was uh contributions of Bill
Gillis to the floor of the Bahamas and
it it's by kassen
esba any other questions those of us
that have worked with Lee know for for
sure that Lee is one persistent person
and so um just keep that in mind uh lee
I just recently read Daniel Stones book
The Food
Explorer about David pchild oh David
Fairchild the anti-semite yes and uh
sorry that just came
out the Fairchild Botanic Gardens um I I
assume that you were you visited that oh
absolutely yeah yeah yeah yeah really
love to i' really love to see it I heard
it's a a beautiful a beautiful garden
there it's an incredible place and as a
matter of fact there's a living Bahama
collection there uh that the director at
the time when Bill Gillis was working
there uh had put together this living
Bahama collection which uh he was
collecting Horticultural varieties that
were zeroic that you know that could
survive in a in a Florida
environment and um so he wanted to plant
these uh these Horticultural varieties
in the Bah uh in in Florida which he did
and if you go there you can find them
you can see them um and and that's the
only connection that uh the director at
the time had to the Flora of of the
Bahamas as a matter of fact Bill Gillis
was so upset with him because every time
he would collect a specimen and put it
in the herbarium he wouldn't make a
label for it to say where it was
collected when it was collected you know
all that stuff that a taxonomist does
when a taxonomist collects uh plants and
makes a label for the herbarium he never
did that he just was interested in what
color the plants were and so when Bill
Gillis established or the the Bahama uh
the I'm sorry the um herbarium for the
BAH for the Fairchild tropical garden um
in 1968 when he was hired there he be he
started the herbarium and um and um and
then decided that he wanted to do a Flor
of the Bahamas and the the director
whose name I'm not mentioning uh of the
of the uh project uh said you know
whatever you want to do it's up to you
you're the you're the researcher and he
said I want to do a floor of the Bahamas
and he said okay fine
and and Dick Howard said well you should
put a uh you should put a recommendation
in a proposal into National Science
Foundation and so they submitted it in
1970 and and the director's name was not
on it except the cover letter which said
yes he's working at my institution and
it's okay for him to to submit this
proposal uh but years later then he says
no it belong the The Proposal belonged
to the
institution so questions for Lee we're
getting close to
running out of time there's one CH
there's one in the
chat okay you want to read it to me
please because I'm not doing very well
with
this what's the
question anything known about
professional relationship between Gillis
and Carell strong Mutual dislike
preceding the uh NSF proposal what is so
striking to me Beyond plagiarism is the
subsequent ignoring of gillis's work in
Carell's book and this is from
okay so I I can answer that um all right
so Gillis was working at the at
Fairchild tropical garden and he was
fired he was fired because he didn't get
along with the
director and the director uh fired him
and then he went to Harvard to continue
the project of the Bahama Flora at
Harvard and um the director of the
Fairchild tropical garden then
contacted Carell who was at the time
program director at NSF and while he was
program director he and his wife went to
the Fairchild tropical garden and had a
meeting and it's all documented that
they met and said we're going to write a
Bahama flora and so then the director
took the grant
proposal and uh rewrote it along with
Carell and his wife
and when gilis found out that they were
going to redo or submit the grant
proposal and had gotten it he said he
wrote letters to Carell zillions of well
a couple dozen letters to Carell and he
kept saying I'm here to help you I'm
here to help you what do you need and he
and every time he published a paper he
would send the paper to Carell and I've
got a stack of papers that was signed by
Bill Gillis that was sent to Fairchild
tropical garden to Carell saying here
are the papers I'm writing about the
Bahama Flora none of them are cited in
his
book all right well well that's the
background I can tell you between Carell
and and
Gillis let's give uh lee a hand for a
wonderful
talk and AD J yeah I think that's the
take home message for all of us thank
you thank you thanks for your help with
the
technology this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu