this is a production of Cornell
University hi welcome to the Cornell
Turfgrass video log we're here at the
Beth Page State Park in early June and
one of the things we're starting to
notice on the greens and I think we're
noticing this all over Northern climates
is we've come through some heat and then
some cool weather the spring growth
surge is just about behind us now and
it's about time that the the two grass
systems we manage on putting green start
to react a little differently you'll
notice we've got uh a much more in
starting to get an increase in Bank
Grass as the heat is coming on and it's
starting to get a little bit leggy so
that may need some additional cultural
practices top dressing vertical mowing
but you've got to be really careful
because if you start to do that
aggressively the annual Blue Grass which
will not like the heat will not take it
as well and you could set yourself up
for additional problems especially as
we're approaching the summer equinox and
we get to that climatological maximum ET
where Sun's highest in the sky and we're
losing about a 10 2/10 of an inch of
water a day we'll have to really keep
track of our stressful practices while
the bent grass might need it the annual
Bluegrass might suffer from some damage
if you try to be too aggressive so try
to find that sweet spot and getting that
bent grass managed to provide a good
putting surface without adding
additional problems to the annual Blu
grass this is Frank Rossy for the
Cornell turf grass video log this has
been a production of Cornell University
on the web at cornell.edu