this is a production of Cornell
University thank you Bill for the
introduction um and good afternoon
everyone I thought that I would start
with an introduction of the program that
made the experience that I'll be telling
you about possible so this previous
spring I was a teaching assistant with
the Cornell prison education program or
cpep that's how I'll refer to it it is a
program that was founded at the
University in 2013 and and really
motivated by the same founding principle
of the University that I would found an
institution where any person can find
instruction in any
study and to that end they are dedicated
to supporting incarcerated person's
academic Ambitions and their preparation
for successful
re-entry and cpep operates in facilities
that are managed by the Department of
Corrections and community supervision or
docs that's how I'll be referring to it
currently they
offer um Associates of Arts degrees to
men who are incarcerated at four
Correctional Facilities they're shown
here in green um all are within an
hour's Drive of main
campus and I wanted to to emphasize just
how uh Humanities dominant the program
is for the students in a given students
program there might be five stem classes
that they could take to get their
Associates and unsurprisingly Plant
Pathology is not a staple course in
their curriculum sort of depends on
Bill's
schedule it is a medium security state
prison for men capacity it has just over
a thousand incarcerated individuals or
IIs and that's the docs
terminology and in a given semester
there could be between 30 and 40 IIs who
have applied for and are accepted and
enrolled in
cpep and also unsurprisingly there
aren't a lot of publicly available
pictures of the facility so this is a a
Google Earth image that I I put here to
try to illustrate what it could be like
to be there um you can see the wall
around the grounds uh this is the
parking lot where if you were a
volunteer or a staff member you would
park and you'd enter through this
Administrative Building
um go through a thorough security
screening process metal detector get
your prison ID and then be escorted
through a series of gates onto the
grounds and then as a volunteer you are
immediately escorted directly to the
school building here and this would be
the only building you would
see before starting as a teaching
assistant there were two trainings that
I had to complete one through docs and
one through cpep and and they're really
designed to set the tone really to to
scare you um one maybe more than the
other I think as you'll see um but I
wanted to share the most impactful U
lessons from the training um before I
get started with the rest so first the
the docs
training upon entering the facility you
will be directed to pass through a metal
detector you will be handstamped and you
may be subjected to additional Sur
procedures all items will be
inspected matters of discipline are the
responsibility of the security staff
under no circumstances should you
interfere do not bring into the facility
any items that might be defined as
Contraband promoting prison contraband
is a felony offense this includes
anything that is introduced with the
intent to transfer to an II with without
the permission of the
superintendent and I later learned that
it's not always a felony offense it's at
least a misdemeanor if you bring in
prison contraband um but it it can be a
felony
offense and you will not be working with
students you will be working with IIs
who are taking a
class then the cpep
training prison is to Outsiders a
foreign country it is wise to be quiet
observe listen learn the language and
identify the values of the prison
culture don't be afraid to Define
yourself clearly you are not required to
conform to any stereotype I eyes may
have about you even if you even after
you have clearly defined yourself expect
to be tested again and
again expect to meet many tremendous and
valuable people in prison
expect also to meet some Champion
manipulators do not be surprised if
these sometimes turn out to be one in
the same
person prisons have proven that people
do not learn very much from punishment
but more from example what you do in
prison is more important than what you
say there a broken promise to an
incarcerated person is even more painful
than in normal life and it is an act of
Cruelty and
if after an initial exposure you find
yourself fearful of the prison
environment you should not continue to
go into prisons this work is not for
everyone so I was pretty apprehensive
after the trainings um but I had already
signed up to work with Bill we had
talked about the the plans for the
semester and and I was really reassured
by the fact that that bill was a
seasoned cpep volunteer
so the the class that I was a teaching
assistant for was plsi 2225 healthy
plants healthy planet healthy people
taught by our very own bill fry and
there were three major learning outcomes
for the class first that students would
acquire a broad understanding of plant
diseases their pathogens and how to
manage them to explain plant disease
Dynamics at the cellular organismal and
population s and in the end to
illustrate their understanding and their
knowledge in a term paper describing
five important and diverse diseases on a
crop of their choice and and how to
manage them in an integrated
way and I also had a personal goal for
this experience and it was to to
determine what role I want teaching to
play in my career I'm in the last year
of my graduate program hopefully and um
and I've had some teaching experiences
before at NC State and here at Cornell
um but comparably you know in in ideal
environments
with inexhaustible resources and not
really but sort of and um and
professional students and so I I wanted
a different representation of what
teaching could
be so we we met once a week on Tuesday
Mornings for a um long and engaging
three-hour period from 7:50 to
10:50 um some days some days we could go
in um like on Mondays depending on
cancellations or if we were going to do
a study hall but usually it was just
once a week um it's hard to hold
attention for three hours it's not
necessarily a class that I would be
excited to take um and and I wanted to
emphasize how limited of a classroom it
was so we had no
PowerPoint we had no internet so no
screen
or computers or phones and absolutely no
samples so no microscopes no
slides you couldn't bring in plant
samples they couldn't even bring in
rotten produce from the meshall there
was nothing to point to um other than
our chalkboard and these four resources
here so we could bring in these
printouts of PDFs you know conversions
of PowerPoints as the lecture material
and we had these spiral bound readers as
companions to the lecture material they
were filled with
articles each student had a disease
compendium for the crop on which they
were writing their term papers and then
every student had a copy of the agrios
text so this was our
classroom um for me on first glance it
doesn't really look too different from
your regular sort of under underfunded
public school classroom it kind of looks
like where I went to high school um uh
but there are bars on the Windows here
and what you can't see here is a wall of
Windows for
observation but you can see the
chalkboard and the Really the total lack
of modern resources in a
classroom we had five students in the
beginning
um but one dropped out about halfway
through the semester and these were the
three students who were comfortable with
their photos being taken so we had their
permission um they were around between
30 to 60 years old and outside of cpep
they had no experience with college
level education or
agriculture but I found that what they
did have ample experience with was how
frighten the prison environment can
be you know I can't speak to what it was
like outside of the school building we
can
imagine but I found even in the school
building it to be a very intimidating
place to
work especially for a young woman you
can
imagine um correctional officers have
every Power to question your motivations
for volunteering and demand response to
that to deny you
entry and to interrupt class with a K9
unit and pull the students out and frisk
them along the wall of
Windows standing there watching you from
the
outside so knowing that all of that was
going to happen to them in the school
building they still registered for for a
class let alone a Plant Pathology class
and most of the students said that they
registered because they needed it to
graduate uh or they heard that it was
challenging and they wanted to
challenge but there was one student this
student who said that he registered for
the class because his mom is a Master
Gardener in
Oklahoma and he wanted to spend more
time on his weekly phone calls with her
talking about what she was interested in
and he thought that our class could help
him do
that so knowing all of this bill and I
took a an intentional approach to this
semester what we did first and very
often uh was emphasize that everything
that they will be learning is
real all of the the ridiculous
scientific names that we were asking
them to memorize and Spell correctly and
the diseases that are caused by those
organisms the econom OMC losses that
result from those diseases that all of
that is very very real and we can't show
them but we're asking them to trust
us we also used phyra infestin as a
teaching model and this was in large
part because of Bill's career-long
expertise with the system so we had a
lot of material to pull
from um but we also thought that if we
stayed within one system to teach major
Concepts like Cox postulates and life
cycles epidemiology poost resistance and
management that for people who were
hearing it for the very first time but
that might make more sense um especially
then when we transition to talk about
other
organisms and we also had them read the
first two chapters of the evance of the
fungi before we even met which that they
all read um and and if you're familiar
with the text it it really it sets the
tone for phyto festes a devastating
pathogen and I think helped sort of
establish where we would be for this
semester we followed a sort of standard
layout um for each class over the course
of this semester we always began by
answering what questions they had um
ideally about the lecture material but
that wasn't always the case and that
could take a while um but we had three
hours so um then we would review a list
of important important terms and summary
notes and Bill and I would compile the
terms from the previous week and and
hand them out to the students the
following week just to make sure to
clarify you know this is the information
that we want you to know and and to make
sure everyone had access to the same
information and these are just some
examples of the summary
notes then uh we spent the rest of the
time discussing lecture material and a
reading if there was one and I always
ended with a debriefing with
Bill and there are two sort of
strategies that that we utilized a lot
in the semester that I wanted to share
with you all uh the first was that we uh
we sat in as much of a circle as we
could the classroom was small so we
couldn't quite arrange our our desks and
chairs that way but we did it as best as
we could as this picture shows and we
would take turns going to the board and
so in many cases no one was standing up
front we were all in a circle sort of
equally participating in whatever
discussion we were having and if bill
went to the board then I was asking
questions of him as a student trying to
model for the others you these are the
kinds of interactions that we are hoping
that you have these are the kinds of
questions we hope you're thinking about
um and in the end I think I thought we
were successful in getting a dynamic
classroom where students appeared to to
feel very free to share when they were
frustrated and Confused then excited to
help each other to challenge each other
and to challenge us um and and I think
in the end really as I was hoping that
this picture would show for you all that
we had a lot of
fun and and that felt like one of the
most important things that we could be
doing the other strategy that we used
well I guess problem we were trying to
address was how to give the students
Hands-On learning experiences in the
absence of a
lab and what we ended up uh relying on
was getting students to come to the
chalkboard as much as possible to
diagram like a life cycle is the case
here um or to you know draw a disease
progress curve and the idea was that if
a student were at the board they were
not solely responsible
for diagramming whatever they were
diagramming they were relying on the
people in the classroom to guide them
through the process so it was a low
stakes environment for the person at the
board and a mentoring learning
opportunity for people in in the
classroom and we came about this not
because we thought of it on our own um
but because in the second week of class
we had sort of volen told the student to
go to the board to diagram the p and
fest's life
cycle um which he did fairly
begrudgingly um and with some amount of
pain uh but then when he was on his way
back to his seat he stopped and turned
to us and said that was the most I've
learned in this class so
far and so we could you know come up
with all of these what we thought were
Innovative and creative ways to teach
the information but at least for that
student What mattered was going to the
board and and drawing something and not
to illustrate understanding but to
cement
understanding and I had mentioned that
um that after um the course bill and I
would have our debriefing session and
there wasn't an office for us in the
prison right we couldn't stay we were
escorted out at the end of class and so
we went to our next best option um which
was a Speedway gas station a couple of
miles down the road because it had this
manyi Dunkin
Donuts um and it had literally just two
tables and so um every Tuesday late
morning this is where we would be
um debriefing about what we had
experienced mostly because you know it
was jarring but
meaningful um this is also where we
would grade quizzes and come up with the
summary term list for the next week um
and and an unlikely place to for me to
realize the sort of mentor that bill is
and and to develop a relationship with
him um so at a gas
station um so anyway that was happening
over the course of the semester and then
at the very end we had the term papers
do and we asked the students to give
presentations on the term
papers and we told them that we wanted
lightning talks 5 to 10 minutes you know
no more than 10 minutes that should be
sufficient for them to introduce the
pathogen the five pathogens on their
crop and how to manage them in an
integrated way and on average each
student took about 45 minutes to give
their
presentations which we did not
expect um and uh so it took two classes
to actually go through the four
presentations um and and we we realized
that this was probably for many of the
students the first time that they gave a
presentation to a respectful and
attentive audience so that was
okay and the student whose mother is a
Master Gardener in Oklahoma wrote his
term paper on the biology and management
of peach tree diseases because that is
an important crop to his mom and he
wanted to connect with her um throughout
the
project and I was really touched by by
her involvement in his success in the
class he had her mail him these printed
color photos of
symptoms um of the diseases that he was
studying and
as in his
paper so Not only was the student really
invested in his success but also his
family um in contributing something as
well and so that was was very
impactful I wanted to um spend the rest
of the time talking about some lessons
that I learned from the experience and
then close with uh some Reflections from
the
students and I wanted to say first that
this was the single most impactful
experience that I've had all in grad
school and I would encourage really
anyone at Cornell because of CPAP here
but really especially graduate students
to say yes to an unlikely teaching
opportunity like this despite the
challenges I learned the importance of
trying to be precise and concise and to
seek narrow specific and unambiguous
words and that this was especially
important when the students you're
teaching are learning it for the very
first time and have little to no ability
to check you on anything that you're
saying I also learned that I should
admit often what I don't know and that I
thought I knew things that I
didn't my ego got in the way very
quickly in the classroom in the
beginning I was very concerned with
seeming like I was a good resource to
the students like I knew all the
information really really well um and
found that I could be are more effective
as an instructor to them if I were more
honest than I was inse
Secure um and so in light of that I have
a vulnerable anecdote um about thinking
that I knew things that I didn't that I
wanted to
share um about a third of the way
through the semester Bill asked me if I
would teach the students um mitosis and
meiosis give a lecture on it and I said
sure you know I I've studied subjects
years now that deal with some element of
mitosis or
meiosis um I feel comfortable giving a
meaningful lecture to the
students and as I was spending the
couple of weeks preparing for the
lecture I was thinking about what are
the what I would say are the Core
Concepts of cell division that come to
mind very quickly for me and maybe
that's how I'll inform the lecture and
that's what I'll share with the students
and one of those Concepts was this
notion I had that meiosis results in the
production of
gametes and um I thought that that would
be a a core concept I would teach them
and because we had used pinfest as a
model up to this point I thought I would
teach the subject through the pinfest
life cycle so I got up to the board and
I drew the scaffolding of this
table um comparing and contrasting
mitosis and
meiosis and I I told the students I'm
going to walk through the life cycle and
at each stage talk about how mitosis or
meiosis plays a
role and so that's what I did but really
I I distinguished the two here um saying
that in this system meiosis results in
the production of gametes and mitosis
does not and I thought that was concise
and precise and I think the students
also thought that um and that was where
we left
it and Bill didn't say
anything and then a couple of weeks
later bill was introducing askam my
fungi to the
class and he was walking through the
generalized life cycle and he got to
sexual
reproduction and he said something like
you have compatible hyy that undergo
plasmogamy and you end up with multiple
haid nuclei in a cell and those multiple
haid nuclei undergo rounds of
mitosis and then eventually two haid
nuclei fuse and very briefly you have a
diploid
nucleus and that nucleus undergoes
meiosis and then eventually there's
another round of mitosis and you get
four sets of twins your classic haid
eight ascospores
and the life cycle
continues and I was nodding along and
drafting my summary notes like yes of
course this is what I've always learned
and and then I was thinking about what I
had been telling the students previously
about mitosis and
meiosis and I was looking at this and my
notes and looking at this and I was
like
wait in askam mys meiosis does not
result in the production of gametes it
happens in the
zygote and because meiosis happens in
the zygote the dominant nuclear State
for the rest of the life cycle is
hloy and how fundamentally different
that is from all organisms where meiosis
occurs before parental nuclei are
donated and and and I I was like surely
I I knew this like how did I get to this
point in graduate school and this is
just now making sense to me like it's
now feeling very important to me why
don't people talk about this all the
time this is so important there's this
is a level of difference that I didn't
appreciate between organisms and and
because the students had created this
environment where it was not shameful to
admit having not appreciated something
and now appreciating something um I
couldn't help but do the
same and and so I I hope I'm
illustrating to you the dynamic in the
classroom um it
feels very vulnerable to admit this to a
room of very real subject matter experts
um
but anyway that was an experience I had
where I admitted what I didn't
know I also learned that
teaching added dimmension to my research
I don't think that it hindered I think
that it only enhanced the experience for
me and there's a another little anecdote
I wanted to
share uh related to this so Bill had
mentioned that for my my research part
of what I do is I I am characterizing
diseases of rhubarb primarily those that
we think are the most um common in the
Northeast and really that has led me to
characterize a single fungal path that
causes Leaf spots that look like
this and so this is you know going on
before M and while
M and maybe two-thirds through the
semester Bill asked me if I would teach
the nematology
lecture and I agreed um with some
hesitation because I thought I should
admit that I didn't really know anything
of the subject to give a meaningful
lecture to these students
um so I spent a couple of weeks
preparing and while doing so and then
while giving the lecture I realized that
I found dagger nematodes and their
ability to transmit nepo viruses to be
really interesting like like somehow I
had ignored this in previous Plant
Pathology classes like how did I not
know that this was very cool it's very
cool to me now um and then at the same
time our lab started growing out a
number of rhubarb BC sessions in the
greenhouse that were previously in the
field so I had sort of closer eyes on
them and while they were growing out I
realized that in a single accession in
our collection um there were these
curious symptoms that initially
resembled the leaf spot symptoms that I
had seen before and these are clones of
each other these two plants and and so I
tried um to isolate from these Leaf
spots the same pathogen that I know
causes these Leaf spots
unsuccessfully and I approached Mark
fuks and asked him if he thought that
any of these were worth screening for a
number of viruses in my experience I
have gone to Mark fuks many many times
with what I think a really cool symptoms
hoping that it's caused by some virus
and he always says no it's not worth
testing so it was very exciting for me
when he said that's interesting let's
screen them so we did and what we found
has resulted in a new project and a
collaboration that I would have never
thought that I would have as a graduate
student studying fungal pathogens of
vegetables so we we found tomato
ringspot virus which is a NEPA virus in
this sucession causing uh or showing at
least these
symptoms um and and that motivated a
further collaboration um with members of
Mark's lab um and a collaborator at an
institution that I didn't think that I
would be collaborating with um a high
throughput sequencing of RNA project and
we have some interesting results so our
next step is
validation um and I guess I'm not trying
to say that it's because I was realizing
that I was interested in nepoviruses as
a TA that I happened to find a nepovirus
in rhubarb um but it was that I had
learned enough to be interested in the
subject that it it made something like
this seem worthwhile last minute as a
unplanned project
so that was something I
learned I also learned that any
expectation I have of the students I'll
have of
myself so if I want the students if I
expect them to be interested in
something I have to demonstrate that I'm
interested in it if I want them to spend
time on something I should demonstrate
that I have spent time on
it I also learned that I should expect
an experience to be interesting and
meaningful and then I may be better
prepared to appreciate it when it likely
will
be and I learned that I should be
affected by the people I
teach and to let them know that I'm
affected by
them in a written reflection at the end
of the semester one student said I've
never wanted to get out and bump into
two people more in my life so I can
shake their
hands not only for what they did for me
academically but for treating me like a
human being I'll never forget
them so you know it mattered what we
were teaching them and how we were
teaching them but I really think that
we could have been teaching them
anything it was that we cared about them
that mattered the
most so some students
comments you started this class by
telling us that everything we learn is
real I
agree potato spindle tuber vroid it's
amazing that I know that I would have
never thought I'd say that before taking
this
class and one student in um talking
about preparing for an
exam do you know that I can walk the
yard with murderers and thieves and have
less anxiety than I do in this
class it's really not what we meant to
have
happen I'm using the disease triangle to
explain recidivism with my re-entry
program
mes they came here because of some
interaction between their behavior their
needs and their support system they have
to change at least one to keep from
coming
back I will never look at a piece of
fruit vegetable or food the same way
again knowing that a Grower's many
efforts somewhere along the line have
made that resource available to
me
and I would love to show my family
liness
I'm happy to
report that a number of the students in
our class graduated this
semester and those who are still
incarcerated will continue taking
classes through cpep as long as they're
offered I care a lot about this
experience and I really really
appreciate the people in this picture
with me especially bill for making this
possible and you all for your
attention and I'm happy to take any
questions are there some questions for
Li
get a started I have one how would you
compare your Cornell
undergrads with CCF
undergrads so how would I compare the
students in the cpep program with
students I've I've taught at
Cornell there is
a May major major difference in the
background
education um with the students at
Cornell versus students at cpep it's not
surprising
um uh the understanding of of plant
science of of DNA of of biology broadly
um uh that was a a surprise for me the
students at cpep did not have um a
strong
understanding um but
they they had almost no desire I think
to prove themselves to each other
perhaps in the way that I've observed
with undergrads here the what I had
found really meaningful about the
experience is something I had talked
about was
that the environment in the classroom
was it was very free and willing um to
to admit when you didn't understand
something and I think as a ta at in
Cornell classes I was would have been
very scared to say to anyone that I had
just appreciated
that meiosis occurs in the zygote in
asamy um but that was totally welcome in
a CPAP
classroom is there a prison program for
women so if if there's a prison program
for women my understanding is that cpep
currently does not operate in women's
prisons and I don't know if there is a
reason for that in addition to maybe
they are too far away for people to
volunteer at um yeah I don't know where
the nearest women's prison is but there
are um other universities have prison
education programs at Women's prisons um
in New York state um Brown operates in
some um columia has a program but not
for
now
yeah talk and I want to follow up Bill's
question actually comparing the students
so if I understand if I understand
correctly this students uh in the prison
are not probably having the type of
background that's probably needed to go
into advanced topics and you're actually
teaching them pretty like specific terms
and uh terminology and stuff like that
how in your observation do these
students react to like the frustration
compared to other like like on grass
have more backgrounds and stuff and like
are there any incidents where their
frustration could like lead to like
stopping the class or the getting the
guard
okay so so eag your question was about
um comparing perhaps how students react
in in cpep versus Cornell to not
understanding a concept and if their
frustration ever elevated a situation to
a point of concern um I would say that
there were many times where students
were frustrated by not understanding a
subject um but we would just slow the
class down and um and with five students
it's and eventually then four it was
very easy easy to make sure that
everyone was on the same page um they
often turned to each other for support
so they would tutor each other outside
of the class if they had recognized that
someone wasn't understanding something
um uh there was never any concern that I
had about safety in the classroom once I
felt comfortable not at first but
eventually after I learned the students
and um knew who they were um uh but but
they handled
frustration with the subject I think
similar to how I would have um expected
oral students
do yes copy I noticed that some of your
early summary notes had graphs in like
area under the disease progress curve
and I'm thinking of like my magical
mushroom students that if I put up a
graph I have to be like okay like like
how how did you explain the area under
the disease Pro
uh how did we explain yeah the charts
and figures I there was a lot of
repetition at the chalkboard and getting
the students to draw it out themselves
you got it I think so
some
yeah yeah um there there were examples
where um I mean we spent maybe two weeks
on on disease progress curve
and exponential growth and um and trying
to compare um exponential growth to
maybe how they might have thought about
their finances before and what happens
in a savings account and and that maybe
wasn't as helpful as I thought it would
be but um um but walking them through
individual calculations getting them to
sort of debate each other on what they
thought the outcome would be and then um
and argue their case yeah we did that
can I can I say one more thing like I
really liked your reflection on
intellectual
humility you want to say that into the
mic for the zoom folks
okay you have the floor I think this one
is on I'm not giving this seminar but I
wanted to say this is Kathy Hodge I
wanted to say that I really liked your
reflection on intellectual humility and
I think um and I think it's a really
good attribute to have right and when
you think about it like we all we're all
just learning all the time and in fact
that's like why we're here right we
we're curious about the things we don't
know but I think when you first when
students first graduate often with a PhD
I think it you feel like you should be
an expert on things and I still feel
like I'm supposed to be an expert on
things but in fact I I got here for the
very opposite reason that I that I
didn't know anything and I just want to
learn more and more stuff and I just
think that intellectual humility like
you've shown is just a beautiful way to
like let people in and just recruit them
to the process of science you know like
there's so much we don't know and so if
somebody asks you a question that you
don't know the answer to it's like
that's a beautiful moment if you can say
that's a really good question and you
know like I don't really know so good
job to say anything I that was lovely I
don't know if I can
follow but that was I think very much
the dynamic that I experienced in the
classroom yes I want to just say one
thing uh when Libby first started I
really did not know that you were
apprehensive about going into the prison
I guess I'm not very observant um could
you compare your just describe your
experience early on with that later on
and maybe could stop with that one okay
um yeah
so in the first month or so of this
semester I tried really hard to hide
this from you I guess it worked um but I
didn't I didn't really sleep the nights
before going in um
and I was very afraid of what version of
a correctional officer I was going to
meet at the gate I had heard sort of
horror stories about uh previous
volunteers this didn't happen to me but
um you know your your shirt was too
tight so you can't come in today or
you're wearing a white shirt and it's
going to rain so you can't come in today
um or are you sure you're a volunteer
because we don't have your name on the
list even though you've been there for
weeks and and need to have someone come
over and look at your you know
identifying information to make sure
that you can go back and so I was really
scared simply to enter the
facility um I remember the the first
time that you took a bathroom break in
lecture and I was sitting alone with the
students and I it was our first class
and I didn't know anything about them
and they didn't know anything about me
and I was so afraid that all they could
see was that I was young and a woman and
um and I was very wrong about that um in
the end um by the end I think somehow we
achieved like
a another sort of classroom Dimension
that didn't exist in the prison like
you'd walk through the prison but get to
class and it was a classroom and that
was awesome and it
was could have been
anywhere
um so it very much changed by the
end okay me thank you very much
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu