this is a production of Cornell
University okay so welcome to the grand
opening of the reborn Liberty hide
Bailey
Conservatory uh I'm Alan calmer the
director of the school of Integrative PL
science and uh I have the honor of
meeting the thanks uh to those who
developed this wonderful resource for
our
community I Begin by thanking the
capital programs managers and directors
who unfortunately could not be here uh
they are John gurny director State
University Capital program management
Scott Lewis Regional director of capital
program management and Bill penck
Capital program manager for
Cornell uh I should note that uh Glenn
Evans in a second will introduce or
acknowledge some other people who were
involved uh more locally with the
development of the of the concern to uh
I also want to thank the Liberty High
Bailey Garden Club and its president Ed
cob oh thank
you for donating for donating the
wonderful plaque that gives special
meaning to the
conservator right um a unifying theme of
the school is Discovery that connects
and the new Conservatory provides a
Nexus for many
connections first in state-of-the-art
design connects us with a future of
Energy Efficiency and closer connections
between plant growth and
Engineering the conservatory along with
many other important resources
maintained by the Corell University
agricultural experiment station uh will
be described by Glen Evans the director
of operations for the experiment station
who will also uh acknowledge the staff
who make everything
work uh a second speaker uh will address
the conservator's collection connections
that connect us with the world of plant
diversity and enable us even in the gr
cold of a ethic of February or May Day
uh enable us to stand in TR tropical war
and see the sweep of plant
Evolution and look at an amazing plant
and then hold up a mobile
device and uh learn the life story of
that
plant uh which is a cool thing and uh so
Kevin Nixon who is the chair of the
conservatory committee and also a
professor in the hortorum the Liberty
High ba hortorium will uh next speak
today the
conservatory connections with
history which begin with Liberty he High
Bailey the Visionary plan scientist who
established our
college has served as its first
Dean Ed cob who is chair of the SS
history and archive committee will
address the conservator's
history and finally the obervatory
provides a starting point for
visitors a starting point for
visitors uh to explore plant science
destinations across
campus and these include the student
designed uh Urban needen plantings right
here next to us and Elsewhere on campus
uh led by Nina B's class uh soil
monolith collections in Bradfield Hall
uh soon become a paleobotany fossil
fossil display on in plant science as
well as the Cornell plantations and many
other sites so I invite you to explore
this on your own which you can do uh
with the aid
of this guide which is available
inside and with uh your mobile device
which you can use to uh open up maps and
and all sorts of other resources
uh so for that I want to thank Magdalene
linderberg and Craig
Kramer and I also want to thank tar Reed
uh for providing
sound and uh and refreshments and you
know events planed uh so I would now
like to turn it over to uh Glenn Evans
the director of operations for the
experiment
[Applause]
thank you Alan okay so I just want to
acknowledge a few folks and inevitably
I'll miss a few but I I want to
acknowledge as many as I can who've
really been instrumental uh uh across
the experiment station with really
making this structure a reality and also
you know preserving the Integrity of
these 500 plus species that we have here
so it's really uh you know it's nice to
see where we're at now I think those of
you who have been at Cornell a while
you've seen sort of the the process that
it took to get to where we are now and
can probably appreciate it uh better
than most uh just how many steps are
have to go through uh to get something
like this into place and so uh there's
two areas I really want to express
thanks and and and the first is with the
plant material um so in the interm in
the absence of a conservatory while this
was being built and discussions were
being held about the future of the
conservatory all that plant material had
to be taken care of um and for anybody
who's ever had a house plant and had it
die well times that by 500 or a th000 or
maybe a bit more and that's really the
the the level of complexity that our
Greenhouse Growers and Greenhouse staff
had to do to move the plant material to
care for it to to manage the pests and
diseases and really keep it in a fine
shape so that when its new home was
finally built that everything looked
really well and so I really want to
express thanks we first of all to uh our
Tower Road Greenhouse crew and and I
know some of those are here today we've
got Trey and Merritt uh we've got Josh
uh I want to express uh thanks to Paul
Cooper and in particular uh Paul's the
head Greenhouse grower and really you
know throughout this process in in
managing this collection and maintaining
it in the fine shape that it's in uh you
know his expertise has been truly
invaluable and I also want to express a
sincere thanks to Melissa breckner uh
Melissa is the the supervisor for that
range and and manages these folks as a
team uh you know it really takes a team
of folks uh to manage this plan material
uh to keep it uh to keep it going and
evolving U just as we like to see it uh
the other area that's that's really been
uhu important throughout this process
has been in the structure itself and in
figuring out all the bits and pieces uh
so that they work together appropriately
and so anybody who's ever had a home
repair had a roof replace or re new
siding you know how uh things don't
always go quite the way they're supposed
to and they end up costing just a tad
more than maybe they should well this
structure is not exception to that it
really takes someone with a a Keen Eye
and attention to detail and really a
team effort to go through the entire
process of Designing it putting it out
the bid having all of the the
contractors and and folks on the job uh
put things in place so that inevitably
it'll be a long-term structure it'll be
successful uh and really functional and
geared to the the plant material and the
teaching purpose that this serves and so
I think you know we've been very
successful in that you know we've very
minor bugs left to work out at this
point Point uh and a few folks to thank
uh right here at C's facilities up in
Kennedy uh we've got a really good team
of facilities folks uh including Peter
paradise and Bill d uh in our
infrastructure properties and planning
which is sort of our Central facilities
group uh we've had really good project
management throughout the process uh
from Cass hotori and and art fivs and
and these are the guys who are really
are in and out of the project uh
throughout the build phase and really
making sure those bits and pieces come
together and last but certainly not
least I want to thank Andy lead Andy
lead is our our plant growth facilities
manager Andy's just an incredible
knowledge uh base uh throughout this
process really kind of catching things
in design um that would otherwise be a
major issue now and and and really uh
helping to evolve the design so as you
go through the structure you know please
don't just look at the plant material
take a look at the structure there's
some really cool features there
everything from energy saving uh shade
curtains some some high efficiency see
supplemental lights uh appropriate
Shades and Mist systems a really
sophisticated environmental control
system uh so all these features that
have to work together uh so that the
plan material is happy and so that
inevitably uh we're happy as well um so
that I'd like turn it over but I want to
say again thanks to all those folks
wouldn't mind give them a round of
applause they welld
deserved next uh thank youbody next have
next
one hi uh my involvement in this is
basically as manager and sort of curator
of the plant collection um of course I
need to thank a whole bunch of people
first most importantly would be Paul
Paul Cooper I couldn't have done
anything in here without Paul and um he
acts not only as a horticulturalist but
also just to bounce ideas off of in
terms of how to the plants do all that
kind of stuff um also Devon and Trey who
helped to plant this little Forest we
have in here and daily will take care of
everything Melissa Andy uh very
important in this whole process and I
know I forgot oh Craig Craig hasn't been
mentioned yet Craig has been deeply
involved in this the whole time of
course Ed uh Ed I don't think this would
be standing here right now if it wasn't
for Ed car and the students who really
put up a fight to get the conservatory
here so I I think it's a really a big
Community effort and um my involvement
goes way back with the old Conservatory
but this is we're kind of taking a new
uh approach here so what we're going to
do is have a very carefully managed
collection the old Conservatory there
were probably six or eight different
faculty members who had some kind of
involvement so just kind of was an
amorphous thing that went in various
directions so I am going to be the
curator and I'm I want to take any kind
of recommendations and advice from
anybody who would like to see things go
into the conservatory in other words I'm
not going to try to restrict what's in
there but I am going to try to augment
and develop a collection that has a very
wide uh uh birth if you will of
diversity right now we have 44 families
in the conservatory we have
347 Genera of plants and guess what I
forgot to count the number of species
but it's somewhere around 600 or more
the thing is we're numbering in the 800s
right now in terms of the accessions um
so one thing I'm going to be doing is
developing connections with other
conservatories particularly the New York
Botanical Garden there already
propagating new stuff for us to bring in
so I think we're going to have an
exciting time here of adding things my
intent is to add stuff that's
educational that fills uh uh you know
that it's a interest to a variety of
people from people who are interested in
evolution systematics
Horticulture house plants visitors can
see things here that they won't see
elsewhere and in that sense you will
start to see some things
disappear from the conservatory because
there's no point in us you know
cultivating a Bonia that you can see
every time you go to Lowe's so um with
that said the important thing about the
conservatory from my standpoint is that
it it is a biological collection and
since I'm curator of the herbarium we
already have a lot of experience in
terms of curating Collections and we
have a big database structure in the
herbarium and so I kind of taken that
idea and we've developed databases and
uh interfaces that will allow you to
actually interface information about
this collection on your cell phones or
tablets or you can do it from your
computer in your office as well uh some
of you are probably familiar with QR
codes so you in order to use a QR code
you need to go either to the Apple store
or the Android store or the windows do
anybody have a Windows phone
no I'm sure there's one for Windows and
then maybe even black I don't know if
the Blackberry has one okay but at any
rate it's you can get a free app whereby
you just take a picture basically
through the app of this QR code which
there's one on your pamphlet there and
then it will bring up the web page that
we' set up that accesses the database
about that plan that particular plan
um we're just developing this some of
these aren't going to have a lot of
information yet they're going to be
expanded but for instance if you if you
do the QR code for the carnivorous
plants you it actually links you to a
video showing a carnivorous plant eating
a little uh
arthropod so um there are various things
like that we're trying to add lots of
links in the the the information is thin
on some of these things but it will be
increasing as you go into the from the
other end and come up the center aisle
there on your right we're just starting
to put in an evolutionary sequence for
land plants that goes from liver warts
to angop sperms along that side but we
still are missing some things we need
some different Lop POS and things like
that so we're working on that um so I
don't know that there's much else I'd
like to say again I'd like to thank
everybody who's involved and who has
been involved and who will be involved
and any students who want to get
involved we're always looking for people
who want to work in the conservatory oh
which means I forgot to thank Nick and
Patty who are the ones that you'll see
in
there I'm glad I
didn't you'll see them we have it set up
now so they can actually enter data
through their cell phones and so it's a
good reason they just hang out now down
here entering data and so for instance
there's a little app they can enter data
so every time they go through
they check not every time but often
they'll check to see what's in flour and
they can just hit a little button it
says that's in flour so how many things
do you think are in flour right
now daddy knows
134 134 is that what it is I thought it
so there are 134 plants in here well a
few were in the purple house but most of
them were in here that have flowers on
them right now you might look sometimes
they're hard to see some plants don't
have very attractive flowers so at any
rate I'm very happy to be here and I'm
hoping that we'll be able to really
develop this into something great thank
you very
[Applause]
much so our next and final speaker is Ed
C so I've been to National meetings and
I always wonder why the historians pull
out a piece of paper and actually read
their
statements I don't
[Music]
so um greetings everyone glad you could
come today for this nice B me weather in
the springtime but you know well it's
not raining not raining and it's nice
warm in the greenhouse we'll be there
sir so um there have been four
Conservatory green houses built on the
Corno campus the first Conservatory was
built in 188 2 and was attached to the
botney wing of sage College a smaller
Conservatory was built near this site
just this way um in
1909 it was designed to house tropical
plants for the new College of
agriculture in
1931 another Conservatory was built on
this exact
site when plant science the plant
science building was constructed
construction on the conservatory before
today was completed in late
2015 during Cornell's sus Centennial
Year yes
got only of the two buildings that can
be logged in for 2015 us and claran Hall
so uh Liberty High Bailey the first dean
of the still very active College of
Agriculture was involved in selecting
the curved glass design of the previous
Conservatory constructed by Lorden
Burnham starting in the 1920s
Dailey traveled extensively collecting
and studying Palms some of the very
first plants that were moved into the
new Conservatory in 1931 were palms and
we even have a glass slide that proves
it yeah shows the plant of in this
actual the previous
greenhous um so the plants were moved in
at the new conservator 1931 which Palms
as we know require special conditions
especially for survival in itha hosel
Winters
research on Palm anatomy and palm
taxonomy continued in the structure for
over 75 years with plants being
maintained in this
Conservatory so today this is a grand
day for Cornell and the plant Sciences
we have many people to thank for the
state of art state of art
structure after over 75 years of
continuous
use plans were drawn up for renovation
or rebuilding of the previous Liberty H
Valley
Conservatory however in the fall of 2010
it was announced that it was to be torn
down and not replaced particularly on
this
site uh this resulted in a Grassroots
movement within the Cornell Community to
save the conservatory in this location
for easy access by students and the
community Heather Holi president of hes
form at the time circulated a petition
to restore the conservatory or have it
rebuilt in this
location within less than a week over
800 members of the paral community
signed the
petition and during that time Carol
Bader a long a longtime caretaker of the
conservatory BL brought the plight of
the structure to the attention of
President David
scorton who event
influenced the decision and saved our
conservatory at this
site it is my hope and the hope of
everyone here today with proper care
this conservatory and the collection of
plants contained within Will Survive
into the next Century for the benefit
and pleasure of generations to come
thank
[Applause]
you uh if uh
and Ed and Len can come help me uh can't
do this by
yourself we can uh enable open this up
and enable you all to get into the war
got do it one two
[Applause]
three officially
open good job Patty we open
yeah hang this has been a production of
Cornell University
on the web at cornell.edu