this is a production of Cornell
University uh so my talk today is on the
fossil record and evolution of water
Ferns and I'm going to be talking about
work that I've done on Patagonian
fossils and North American fossils
you'll see some European fossils um so
all parts of the world just a little bit
about myself first um so there are a lot
of Institutions and people who have made
this work possible collectors fossil
collections uh Jennifer spiko who some
of you might know has has been working
in Alejandra lab and has helped with
some of the Imaging but I especially
want to highlight my collaborators on
the projects I'll be showing today so
these are my co-authors um Dr alahan
Alejandra Gandolfo of course has been my
longtime collab collaborator and I was a
postto in her lab years ago uh from
Argentina Ruben coo Mari zamala and also
fundo de Benedetti had been working on
these projects and then Nathan Jud who
was also a former postto in Alejandra's
lab and uh is now a professor I believe
at William juwel College in Missouri um
was also a co-author on one of these
studies all right so a little bit about
where I'm coming from and what I'm doing
at Cornell uh I work at the
paleontological research institution
which is located across the lake it runs
the Museum of the earth and the kuga
Nature Center a lot of my job is is
involved in Outreach and I also do
research so in terms of research and let
me ah I do have a laser pointer uh I've
been working on the gray fossil site
from Tennessee this fossil site is about
4.5 to 4.9 million years old if you were
here a few years ago I gave a talk on
that fossil site which is H fruit and
Seed Flora I also do a lot of Outreach
projects especially on the web I've been
involved in digital Encyclopedia of
ancient life writing about embryo ites
uh putting together the regional Guides
of earth science in here on Earth and
also working on a website on grasses for
the evolution part of uh Earth at
home so here at Cornell I've primarily
been working on Patagonian paleo Flores
like I said I was a postto in
Alejandra's lab a number of years ago
and that's where I got my start on this
project I've done fieldwork in Patagonia
a number of times uh this photo and this
photo is from our recent trip which is
in was in
December um I've also uh worked on a
number of studies on these floras
primarily Laguna Delo which is eosine
and some Cretaceous material uh recently
I worked on this paper that Teddy Mattel
was also on he was an undergrad in
Alejandra's lab and he's now at the
University of Michigan and we're
continuing to work on a report on uh
fossil plants from the national parks
that's sponsored by the paleontological
society and right now with her I'm
working on this on name Dixon so uh
fossils from the Cretaceous of
Argentina and I'm also working with the
Cornell University py Botanical
collections so one goal for this
collection is to try to enhance its
curation uh the collection is right now
held in Emerson Hall uh there are a lot
of fossil cabinets and drawers so we
want to get this unpacked and organized
and get cabinets for the
collection so before I begin uh talking
about the fossils I think a lot of
people here probably are not
paleontologists and don't deal with the
geological time scale a lot so uh I'll
be talking about a lot of geological
time periods the geological time scale
is a relative time scale the furoic is
uh the Eon in which most of the fossil
record occurs so most of the complex
macro fossils we think of I'll be
talking today primarily about fossils
from the Mesozoic and cenozoic eras so
they're younger than 252 million years
old uh the Mesozoic Era is the time of
the dinosaurs it ends at 66 million
years ago with an asteroid impact that
killed the dinosaurs so this is known as
the end Cretaceous Extinction the
Cretaceous paleogene boundary or in
older literature the Cretaceous terer
boundary and then after that we have the
cazic so this is when we have the of
mammals um also the Flora starts to look
a lot more modern so I will also show
some fossils from the cazic era as well
uh if you haven't memorized this whole
time scale I've tried to put in a lot of
numerical ages to help everybody uh stay
oriented in
time all right so water ferns what are
they uh modern water ferns or extant
water ferns are in the order Salen ales
their Le oriate ferns this is the most
diverse group of living ferns uh they
are heterosporous so I'll return to that
in a moment but basically they're
producing two different sizes of spores
large megaspores smaller
microspores uh modern salven Alis are
divided into two families one of these
is the marcelia this is the water Clover
family uh marcelia has three living
Genera pilia ridium and marcelia these
plants have Ryon and rooted in the
soil the other family is
Salinas modern Salinas consists of two
gener of floating aquatic
plants so some of the characteristics of
these ferns um I've already mentioned
their growth forms in general compared
to what we might think of as a typical
or stereotypical Fern Leaf they have
relatively simplified leaves so if we
think of this stereotypical Fern leaf is
a large pinely compound leaf um in these
groups the leaves can be simple uh they
can have two leaflets four leaflets or
in the case of pilia way over here there
are no leaflets and and the leaves just
look like these little stocks the ferns
are heterosporous this is unusual most
modern ferns are homosporous so in
heterosporous ferns they produce two
different types of spores megaspores the
mega spores give rise to the mega aites
which produce the eggs the microspores
are smaller they give rise to the
microphytes which produce the sperm
megaspores are produced in capsules
called
megasporangia uh each megasporangium
produces only one megaspore so there's
monom measor in the in these ferns uh
the the micros sprang are the capsules
that produce the microspores and each
micros sprum produces more than one
microspore the sorai or the groups of
spanga can be either heteros scate and
marcelia this means they're producing
both megaspores and microspores or they
can be homos and Sven which means
they're only producing megaspores or
they're only producing microspores and
this will come up
later all right so what can the fossil
record tell us about these ferns what
does it tell us in general and what does
it tell us about these ferns
specifically the fossil record is
physical evidence of past life it
actually shows us the physical
structures of ancient plants that are
now extinct and this is the only direct
evidence we have for these plants
obviously we can make inferences about
character Evolution for things like
through methods like biogenetic analysis
but the fossil record is kind of a a
reality check on that what was really
going on in the past so the fossil
record of water firms plausibly there
are some older records starts near the
Jurassic Cretaceous boundary so this is
about 145 million years ago the record
largely consists of spores and there's
been especially uh an emphasis on
megaspores the megaspore record in the
Mesozoic it's not only important for
understanding the evolution of these
ferns some of these things can be
important bio stratag graphically so
when you're looking at the ages of
sediments the environment things like
that so what do these fossils tell us
they can tell us about characters that
are no longer present in the modern
ferns so the ones I have highlighted in
yellow are things I'm going to talk
about today the ones that aren't are
some things that I'm not really going to
talk about they aren't projects that
I've worked on um but I have examples of
them over here so one thing the fossil
record can tell us is that some of these
plants may have had more complex leaves
in the past so an example of this as
hydrop aridium this fossil over here you
can see the plant reconstructed here
with these more complex leaves uh this
is from the lake Cretaceous of
Canada they can also tell us about some
structures that are no longer present in
modern Gena so one example of the this
is floats on salvinia spor aites also
mini floated aola
megaspores uh heter heteros sprit sorai
and svenia so these examples I'll talk
about later and that some of these
ancient ferns may have produced more
than one megaspore per megas sprum so
that's based on a study that de benad
denal did in 2020 reinterpreting these
spores and Spang of paleo vaza
patagonica so you can see this megas
sprum here very clearly with two
megaspores um in this fossil form and
the plant that produced these spores is
unknown so we don't know what the
sporify looked like uh the fossil record
can also tell us about the sequence of
evolution of characters and I'll talk
about that a little bit when I get into
U
marcelia all right so I'm starting with
Marcel AC the water Clover family uh as
I mentioned before this this family has
three extant Gena one thing that
distinguishes the extant Gena is the
leaf type so marcelia has the most
complex leaves they have four leaflets
they look like little clovers hence the
name water Clover regium has two
leaflets per leaf and pilia has no
leaflets so again they just look like
stocks and this is sort of an idealized
version of of what one of these plants
would look like with a ryome The Roots
the leaves and then these little round
structures or bean-like structures are
sporo carbs those are the reproductive
structures all right so let's take a
look at the sporocarps the sporocarps
and merceli are interest they are
probably some sort of modification of
the leaves um you can see in the
center uh sporocarps on a living plant
in the upper left and upper right are
longitudinal sections a fresh section
and a fix section and down here is a
detail of the sporocarp wall so each of
the sporocarps has multiple Sor the Sor
sorai are these oblong areas and within
the sorai are the spria so these Sor are
mixed they produce both megaspores and
microspores um the sporocarp walls are
thick and scarified this is a section in
this case the the sclar Ina hasn't
really developed the thick walls so it's
not that clear but um there would be
multiple layers of of sparids here and
then when the sporocarps open they
release this gelatinous kind of
structure to which these sorai are
attached and the break down and release
the
spores one other important thing to note
about marcelia is it's not just the
leaves that distinguish the Gena it's
also the spores and with a particular
emphasis here on the megaspores so here
are the megaspores of the three Genera
uh you'll notice pilia and regium have
these
appendages at the tips of the the megas
uh these are called acryi they're LED in
the case of regium they're also sort of
Twisted and then in
marcelia the acry has actually been
reduced to just a
rim so spores with these acry lelli can
be found in the fossil record in the
modern forms there's also a gelatinous
layer involved in the formation of the
Acela and this is all involved in in
fertilization of the mega
gapy
so the fossil Spore record is really
important in this group these are some
examples of Mesozoic Spore types so
these are extinct Spore types so the
Spore record goes back to about the
Jurassic Rous boundary that's 145
million years ago uh the mesic megaspore
types are arsoles so this really
spectacular looking Spore is an example
of aroles there are a lot of different
species of this the plant that produced
these spores is unidentified it has not
been found um it's assumed to be related
to Marcil AC because of this really
spectacular appendage at the tip which
looks sort of like the modern ones the
other megaspore type is mosora uh you
can see the acry very nicely here uh
mosora looks very much like the spores
of mod excuse me of modern
regium uh particularly Moser Lata some
other species of mos have different
ornamentation there are also microspores
Kellis varieties down here is one of
these which is somewhat regium like uh
the other one that's usually associated
with the group is gabos sporus and then
at the end of the Mesozoic these foror
types are replaced by spores that are
placed in the modern Gena so marcilia
pilia and
regium and in 2013 Collinson at all said
that these meso Spore types probably
really go extinct because there have
been some records of the meso spor types
continuing into the
cazo okay sporophytes are what I'm
mostly interested in I work on plant
macrofossils the sporify record of this
group goes back again about to the
Jurassic Cretaceous boundary there is an
older record from the Triassic I think
it's pretty dubious so I haven't really
included it here uh the record consists
largely of plants so whole plants also
leaves and detached leaflets that's
mostly what's found in the record there
are a few sporocarps and even fewer of
these have spores this is an interesting
phenomenon that's been noted by
paleobotanist because these These
sporocarps are so resistant why aren't
you finding them in the fossil record
nobody really knows um there are a lot
of identification problems historically
and continuing to the present day with
these ferns a lot of things are
misidentified into this family
all right so the first uh projects I'm
going to talk about are the LA Colonia
Marcel AC so la Colonia is one of the
formations that I've been working on
with Dr Galo and collaborators in
Argentina um these are three of the
papers two of them are from La Colonia
one's about mercel AC if you want to
read more about these projects so I'm
going to give two examples one's a
fossil taxon that's similar to a modern
firm almost IND distinguish
the other one is a fossil taxon with a
unique morphology so both of these come
from the law Colonia
formation so a little bit about this
formation and the context for these
fossils and I should say this map is a
little bit weird uh South America was
not tilted on its axis in the Cretaceous
so North is kind of somewhere up over
here um the important thing though is
the lack Colonia formation occurs down
here in modern chibo Province at this
time it was very near the coast so
sediments from this formation some of
them were deposited in Marine settings
some were deposited in terrestrial
settings there are a lot of vertebrate
fossils knowing from this formation
probably the most famous is Carnotaurus
this this guy up here but there are
Marine vertebrates there are many other
things uh and this is just an example of
what the formation looks like
today but in the past it looked very
different it was a very different
environment so again the left two
pictures show the formation today uh the
formation looks like what we might call
in the US
Badlands there isn't a lot of vegetation
it's very dry it's very eroded uh on the
right is a reconstruction of what the
vegetation might have looked like in the
past uh this is from a paper we
published in 20 uh
2014 so there aren't a lot of
macrofossil plant macrofossil localities
from the lock
formation uh the three are Coba which is
up here kodon rupe
and uh we think that these localities
represent Coastal Lagoon environments so
these are essentially freshwater
environments near the coast and there
are three categories of plants that are
preserved in these environments some of
which were growing in the water so these
are the things like the the water ferns
I'll be showing uh the lumbo there there
is also a floating aquatic angiosperm
that's maybe somewhat like
PSA uh there are lowland Wetland plants
growing around the lagoons so the Dixon
aous ferns that I showed you before
would were part of this portion of the
vegetation and then there are plants
that are growing even further away so
there is a macrofossil flora there's
also a poino flora so pollen spores LGA
things like
that all right right so the first
example I'll be showing you from this
formation is fossil
regium uh modern regium the leaf and the
megaspore are shown here on the left so
remember the leaf with two leaflets the
megaspore with this nice acry Lela this
map summarizes the modern and fossil
distribution of regium so the present
distribution is in a very small portion
of East Central South America so
Northern Argentina Uruguay uh Southern
Brazil um uh and the fossil record is
kind of all over the place sparse but
widely dispersed so you'll notice a
bunch of Spore records here these are
the red circles in Eurasia and then a
few scattered macro and misof fossil
reports so down here is an example of
one of these fossil spores from
Kazakhstan with a nice acry Lela uh
here's an example of fossil leaves these
are from Russia and then this fossil
spor Carp from Georgia in the United
States which doesn't look like much but
it had very nicely preserved spores in
it so don't judge it by its
cover all right so here are the fossils
from La Colonia so again moderns on the
left Center are the fossil are the macro
fossils and then on the right are
dispersed spores from the sediments so
this gets us to one problem working as a
paleobotanist in general plant organs
are often not found in a
attachment and uh plant pollen and
spores are often not found in situ so
they're not found within the organs that
produce them so we have not found spores
of
marcelia within the organs of the regium
macrofossils we're assuming these two
things go together because they're found
in the same deposits they're coming from
the same family everything else fits in
terms of the morphology so this plant
was probably producing these
spores so you'll notice the macrofossils
have pairs of leaflets to their leaves
they look almost exactly like the
moderns here are some romes here the
venation is very similar so regium has
these dichotomizing veins and also a
marginal
vein uh near the the apex of the leaf we
see this in the fossil as well the
dispersed spores look very Bunch like
modern ridium spores and you can compare
the mega spores here to here they look
very similar so as a paleobotanist this
is the easiest scenario it looks just
like the modern plant there's not really
much to
say but the next example is a little
trickier and before I get into it I just
want to talk about marcelia a little bit
uh so these are some examples of
marcelia again with the leaves that look
like fourleaf clovers uh modern marcilia
probably has 50 or more
species uh distributed all over the
world
they produce nice sporocarps which
sometimes have these projections called
teeth and the megaspores do not have
these uh a very uh elaborate aamel on
the tip it's reduced to this
Rim all
right so marcelia tends to be fairly
problematic in the fossil record it's
probably the most problematic member of
of Marcel AC maybe svenes in general and
one of the reasons for that is because
there are things that look like marcelia
in the fossil record that aren't
marcelia these are some examples of of
marcilia lookalikes that are probably
angiosperms the reproductive structures
haven't been found but the leaf vation
looks angiospermous so one of these is
Marcel ailum John Holi from the DOR Goa
formation of Kansas uh notice this has
three leaves or leaflets and a whirl
kind of a similar structure to marcelia
Lea and then over here for tunar cides
uh this comes from the upper Cretaceous
Talos of western Canada and the United
States so there are lookalikes in the
fossil record it does complicate things
a lot also marcelia leaflets have very
simple venation it's easy to mix them up
to with other reticulate veined things
in the fossil
record so this is uh after a review I
did in 2019 what I think is the uh I
guess legitimate fossil record of
marcelia uh you'll notice that marcelia
is spread around the world not in the
southern hemisphere so much but in the
northern hemisphere um in terms of its
fossil record there are a lot of spores
in Eurasia and some sporify reports
based on leaves from North America and
also Europe uh the leaf records come
from the upper Cretaceous and also the
es one of the interesting things about
this record is that all of the Spore
records are younger than all of the leaf
records and one debate in the literature
about marcilia is whether ancient
marcelas produced a different Spore type
maybe a Spore type that was similar to
that of modern
regium as it turns out we don't know
because no marcelia spores have been
found in the same sediments or marcelia
spores have been found in the same
sediments that yield these leaves so
this is still an open
question so in the lot Colonia formation
we do have a plant that's a little bit
like marcelia but it's a little bit
different so on the left are some Modern
marcelia are pictures of modern marcilia
leaves and leaf bation on the right are
mirita
ensus uh leaves or leaflets so the
vation of mirita ensus is very similar
to the vation of marcelia the veins
dichotomize and the an asmos and they
form these closed
Aerials what's different is first of all
the form of the leaflet so you can see
this extended leaflet base and maybe
more of a fan-shaped leaflet NEOS Solita
versus these OB deltoid leaflets in
marcelia the whole Leaf structure was
also probably different so here we have
two leaflets in attachment here we have
a whole bunch of leaflets on the surface
of a rock and it's hard to tell how
they're related to one another so we
interpreted the leaves of this plant as
having two leaflets so somewhat
different from Modern marcilia but with
some
similarities uh just for completeness
here these sporocarps occur co-occur
with the mosola leaves so another
problem in paleobotany again organs tend
to be detached we did not find the
sporocarps in attachment with the
leaflets so we give them different name
even though we think they probably come
from the same plant uh over here in the
upper right you can see one of the
Molita leaflets near some sporocarps so
they occur very close to one another
there are also mosor spores in these
sediments so it's possible that this
mirita luigio Maria plant was also
producing mosor fores that's really the
only candidate right
now all right so to wrap up this section
uh late Cretaceous regium was similar in
form in terms of its leaves and spores
to Modern regium so maybe an example of
some extreme stasis going on there from
over 66 million years ago to the
present but in the Cretaceous and
possibly even later marcelous plants may
have had characteristics of more than
one modern
genus and or they may have had unique
characteristics not seen in modern
marcelous plants so this is what we get
out of the law Colonia
formation so for the remainder of the
time I'd like to briefly go through some
projects to do with salvin so aola and
salvinia these floating
Aquatics so I'm going to uh go through
two scenarios here one involving svenia
that has sporify characters not found in
the extant plants uh this study is
actually not published yet it's
something I'm working on with fundo Dei
and so we did an abstract GSA last year
and then the second one is a published
study from 2019 on aola spores and
spores from the LA Colonia formation and
the younger salanka
formation all right so a little bit
about svenia just to get us acquainted
with this plant uh svenia plants are
floating Aquatics uh you can see here
from Q the modern distribution of svenia
they're native to large parts of the
world but they are also introduced to
large parts of the world where they can
cause some problems so one thing svenia
is KN as is an Evas in as is an invasive
aquatic
plant uh the
plants uh grow on the surface of the
water uh they have horizontally growing
Ryon or stems that bear leaves in groups
of three so they have uh pairs of
floating leaves which isn't really well
visualized here but the floating leaves
occur in pairs they can occur flat on
the water surface or somewhat folded up
and then each of these is associated
with a submerged leaf and the submerged
Leaf is a root likee looking structure
so these plants have no true roots and
it's the submerged leaves that bear the
Sor uh the floating leaves have
reticulate Leaf vation so the aiel is
formed by the ve
tend to be elongate rectangular to
hexagonal in shape and svenia is really
known particularly in the literature and
materials research for his
hairs uh some Cenas not all of them have
egg beater hairs so here's an example of
these egg beater hairs these are
hydrophobic hairs which with hydrophilic
tips and they help the water if you drop
a a drop of water on a surface of a
salvinia leaf it'll beat up and it helps
air hold air against the surface of the
leaf so this is probably an adaptation
to its
habitat so just a little bit more about
the reproductive structures I mentioned
that they are on the submerged
leaves remember that the Sor are homos
spria so some sorai had meas spria that
produced megaspores other spria have um
other sorai have microsporangia that
produce microspores so megaspores and
microspores are separated into different
Sor uh these are just examples of the
megaspores and microspores I'm not
really going to talk about the spor
structure today note the megaspores are
much much larger than the microspores so
these pictures are not to
skip in terms of the fossil record of
svenia I kind of feel like this is maybe
the neglected record of all the water
ferns uh there actually is a pretty good
literature in this case on the scor
fites
interestingly enough so the map up here
shows the fossil record or distribution
of the fossil record of
svenia um notably there are some
Cretaceous occurrences so in North
America here's one that is not described
so again we have one of these groups
going back to the Cretaceous and these
pictures just show some of the variety
of fossil Cenas um all of them look very
much like the modern forms in terms of
their overall
structure oh and I should mention not on
this map there are some reports from
Africa including a late Cretaceous
report and some much younger
reports okay so the fossils I will be
showing today come from the Hattisburg
formation of Mississippi this is also
known as the buoy River Site uh the site
was first reported in the literature in
detail in 201 2019 by mcol and
paleontologia Electronica if some of you
were here when M Alfred was a graduate
student he was on that paper so you may
remember him um one of the interesting
things about this site is it's one of
the few neogene fossil plant macrofossil
localities in eastern North America so
there are very few neogene plant
macrofossil sites in the eastern part of
the United States the neogene is 23
million years ago to 2.6 million years
ago so this part of the fossil record is
really relevant for understanding our
modern Flora understanding modern plant
disjunctions and things like that uh the
best neogene record in uh in our country
in the eastern part of our country is in
the Gulf Coast Area so you'll see sort
of a cluster of sites down here these
are the major sites there are other
sites um that are maybe a bit more minor
or haven't been worked up so Hattiesburg
yields leaves fruits seeds and
pollen and it yields
svenia so this fossil might be a little
bit harder to interpret than some of the
ones I showed previously it's not quite
as well preserved The Matrix it is in
falls apart if you even look at it um
but you'll notice there are pairs of
floating leaves here there's another
Floating Leaf here that's preserved sort
of face on so it's a little bit easier
to see there's a submerged Leaf down
here the branches are visible
there um and there are there's a sorus
here so there are some very nice presure
of sorai on these and then there is a
poorly preserved structure here called a
float so you'll see the corresponding
structures on a modern svenia plant
except for the
float because it turns out floats are
not seen on Modern svenia this is
something that's only been documented
from fossils so here on the a ARs and in
this this blow up in the center are some
other pictures of the floats in this
Hattisburg svenia these are also called
literature inflated structures which is
maybe a little bit more neutral nobody
knows exactly what the function of these
things
are um but they have been found in other
fossils so here are some fossil svenia
from Colombia uh here's the actual
fossil here's a drawing reconstructing
what's going on these are some floats
from uh esine svenia so this is older
than the Hattisburg material up here are
some examples from Europe which are
slightly older to about the same age as
the Hattisburg
material so this is sort of an
interesting observation not sure where
it's going to go
yet the other thing that's interesting
about the Hattisburg svenia are the
sorai so in these
fossils the mega spria marked by m
and the micros spria marked by Mi occur
in the same
sorus so the Sor are heteros sprang
they're producing both megaspores and
microspores in modern svenia the typical
case I guess there have been some uh
observations of of very occasional
observations of heteros sprang Sor but
the typical case is this one where
there's a micros sprent sorus producing
the microspores and a megas sprang sorus
producing the
megaspores
um peteris brate Sor and svenia have
been documented previously in the fossil
record so again this is a character we
don't really see in modern
taxa all
right final example quickly is aola the
mosquito ferns so aola are really tiny
floating ferns you can see uh in the
upper Center there a picture of one of
these on somebody's finger so they're
very small ferns they have horizontally
growing stems or ryom that bear simple
leaves that are imcat so the leaves
overlap one another and they have roots
that hang down into the water
column um like svenia the sorai in aola
are either meas sprang or micros sprang
so in the herbarium specimen here you
can see some micros sprang sorai the
micros sprang at sorai are often more
conspicuous because they have multiple
microsporangia the meas sprent sorai
only have one megasporangium producing
one megaspore each and they're sort of
ooid in shape uh the leaves of aola have
cavities in them that Harbor
cyanobacteria these are nitrogen fixing
cyanobacteria uh this is one of the
things that makes aola economic interest
because it can be used to help enrich
soil uh this is the distribution of
modern
Zola uh the species boundaries of some
of these are a little bit fuzzy but it
just gives you the idea that it occurs
widely throughout the
world all right the spores of aola are
also really really interesting so the
microspores occur in groups in a matrix
and these groups are known as mulite and
the mass
actually have hairs on them these hairs
are sometimes called
gidia and a lot of AAS the hairs have
these anchor-shaped or Arrow shaped tips
on the end and some they don't and some
the tips might just be pointed or
especially in the fossa record you see
some that are cers it so they're curled
almost like a young
Fern the megaspores are also pretty
spectacular they're very complex uh
they're sometimes called megaspore
apparatuses so so the megaspore has a
megaspore body sometimes it has this Rim
called a collar and at one end it has
these structures that are called
floats in modern Isola there can be
three floats in one tier or nine floats
in two tiers on the megaspore
apparatus and there is sorting in aola
by Clay the three floated species and
the species with anchor tipped gidia
occurr in one clay section aola and the
nine floated uh species that either have
no hairs on their mascula or simple
hairs so not anchor-shaped hips are in
section risos
Sperma so the fossil record of aola is
um
extensive the map up here just shows the
sporify record notice again we have a
lot of records from the northern hemis
isphere not a lot from the southern
hemisphere this is really probably
reflective of of collecting effort and
publication um opportunities more than
it is maybe
reality um so the Spore record begins in
the late early Cretaceous the albian
interestingly there are a lot of multif
flated species of aola megaspore
apparatuses so these would be
apparatuses with more than nine floats
and they occur from the lake Cretaceous
to the
eosine so maybe this gives some
impression that there's a little bit of
directionality in the evolution of these
species um the sporify record is known
from the lake Cretaceous to the Meine
and they're about 14 species so the two
I'll show today are from South
America uh the first of these aola
coloni Anis comes from the LA Colonia
formation which I talked about earlier
with regium and
Molita uh on the left are the
sporophytes I don't necessarily have a
lot to say about these um they're not so
different from Modern aola and their
structure there might be a slight
difference in the leaves uh you can see
uh a mega sprang sorus here and micros
sprang sorai down here one of the
interesting things about this uh species
is that it's associated with these
spores so these are linked under the
same name aola coloni Enis but the
spores have not been found in C2 they've
been found dispersed in the sediments so
the megaspore apparatuses have many
floats 18 to greater than 20 the
microser masul have these uh hairs with
anchor-shaped tips and these were
described by De Benedetti at all in
2018 there's another species of aola
from a slightly younger formation this
is the solomona formation it's danan in
age so about 66 to 61.6 million years
old
it also comes from tribut Province
Argentina so the same general region as
the LA Colonia uh uh the LA Colonia
formation the interesting thing about
the sporo fites of aola CA is that the
uh Roots occur in fasal so they occur in
these big groups on the sporify and
they're very much like a modern species
called aola nilotica which is native
only to
Africa the spor the megaspore
apparatuses have uh six floats and one
tier unfortunately these could not be
directly observed because they're under
a cap so this interpretation is based on
impressions in that cap the microspore
masculi have these spin like hairs so
they don't have the anchor-shaped
ends so one of the interesting things to
note about
this is
uh the complication it presents for
understanding the evolution U of aola so
in addition to AAA and aola nyoa there's
another fossil species with these fasold
roots a Sola shopi that comes from the
paleos scene of Canada so it's a similar
age to the Argentinian material but this
aola has multif flated megaspore
apparatuses so what these things are
suggesting is that there really isn't if
they're part of the same lineage which
we kind of think they might be because
have these fic roots and some other
features that are similar there isn't a
clear directionality in the number of
floats on the scores we've got 15 to to
more than 20 in this one six in this one
and then nine in the
modern all right so to conclude this
part of the talk uh fossil aola and
svenia species have some characteristics
not seen in the modern forms and the
fossil record of aola really complicates
our understanding of morphological
evolution in the genus so I guess to
conclude the fossil record adds a lot of
richness to our understanding of the
morphology of the water Ferns and
potentially uh to our understanding of
their evolution particularly the
morphological character Evolution but
there's a lot of danger maybe in over
interpreting things or in misidentifying
things especially in Marcel AC so um I
think with that I'll take any
questions
yes do you think that the S of floats
might be involving sybis given you know
AA has that Sant bacteria in in the
leaves um it's an interesting question
and I have no idea and the flows this
supposedly a leaf structure or they look
like a leaf-like structure so if you
look at them they have uh like a very
thick mid VIN on them and they have
reticulate vation so they do look like
sort of some sort of modified Lea
yeah yes do you know the fs you talked
about are in greeding or out Crossing
and if that depends on which spce they
produce um no I do
not so I'm sorry I can't answer that
question
but yes have to question very nice thank
you so the what's the function of Thea
how does it work for fertilization just
curious my first question and second one
is like um Mar Marc had this parallel
veins but the Salin has more it is
possible that the extinct plants had
this gestal gestor had different kind of
a Nation so might be not just parallel
might be something different because the
Sister Clay has a different time of the
nation right so
um I'm not sure about about the solid
acry Lela to address your first question
if I can get out here or maybe I can
anyway um I was going to go back to one
of the earlier slides so the the
gelatinous spell there is a sperm Lake
inside where the sperm gather uh prior
to fertilization and there's really nice
paper on it I think by Schneider and
prior that talks all about the
Fertilization in these FMS so I'm not
sure how much the solid AC Lelo is
involved in that um the other question
was about the venation so marcelia
actually does have reticulate venation
the venation in in svenia is more
complex certainly and regium has
dichotomizing um so in terms of the
ancestral
Fern uh my guess would be it's probably
dichotomizing but yeah there isn't there
isn't a clear stem member of the entire
order in the fossil record so far
so where is the
hydrum place the a lot of the analyses
place it as a stem member of salvin AC
although an alternative plement is as
stem salvin Alys at least in one
analysis that one is rooted right yeah
so that one that one's a little bit more
Marcil Acy like in its structure yeah in
terms of it's rise
yeah yes so
um weird rootlet
things so those are
leaves that is the interpretation yes
can you figure out how many are involved
is
it I mean is it one kind of stem that
leaves on it or they coming directly off
the upper one or I assume that all those
threads are like different parts of one
leaf right yeah I that's what I think it
is interpreted as yeah so you think it's
a single leaf comes down or is there
more than one no I think it's a single
leave a single leave
yeah
interesting okay thank
you this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu