this is a production of Cornell
University again my name is Loreno
caponiti I'm a farmer in uh in central
Italy this is part of the landscape that
I can look at from my place which is not
a bad landscape at all but is
um but is uh somewhat
challenging uh in a barious of in a in a
in in a number of ways uh again we are
based in a little town that is called
tuscania which is about 50 miles north
from Rome uh tuscania is not in Tuscan
today but used to be about the same
thing about 2800 years ago then some
type of accident happened but anyway
again this is uh this is where we are
this is lake brano lake P Lake bolena
this is all a volcanic bridge and we're
just at the edge of it just where the
volcanic soils end into onto the penic
uh um uh Clays below we have 125 Acres
of total surface uh very different
topography though again you can see here
all all of this it is all Cliffs where
the lava come to an end so our so oil is
very different from the top part of the
farm to the bottom part of the farm
which is good of course because
diversity is always good but it's also
challenging in a sense because you know
sometimes you want to deal with just
what you know and the more you have and
the more you have to know but uh but
that's good this is the other side of
the landscape that we have again this is
looking out of the ridge where the main
house is this is the valley we have a
little river stream of water that is per
but we don't pump any water out of it
because it's so overexploited we are
trying to be sustainable if we can but
again this is to show how our topography
sometimes is very uh peculiar we have
all this type of cliffs that are very
vertical and you can see the Tua rock
that is a volcanic rock the volcanic uh
type of formation that is very light and
very porous and is ring a lot of water
but it ends abruptly with these Cliffs
and all these Cliffs have been worked
out in the pasing Centuries by mankind
to the point that we had this single
Standing Rock that that that this is all
that remains of a cliff that was there
that was completely hollowed out either
to carve out materials for building or
for any other kind of purposes that we
can think of like this is again on the
farm sorry about this
this is a little sort of a open ear cave
this is manmade this was C by the atrans
that is a pre- Roman civilization that
was using our grounds let's say like
that uh some 20 28 to 27 to 2600 years
ago basically this was carved out in
order to let a road go by the atasan
were very peculiar in in and very good
at modifying the graphy especially for
having roads go by and this is the oh
thank you
the um the the track of an ancient road
that was part of a system of road that
later became one of the first road to
ever be paved by the Romans now it's not
that everybody in this world has
something like that in on his farm you
know and uh and um yeah I know it sounds
sexy but it's not that easy sometimes
when you have to deal with it you
know one one of the tombs these are
Graves dug by the same people the sth
and the 6th Century BC was kind of the
peak of the truscan civilization in in
our in our region and they used to dig
all these uh underground cavities to use
as Graves that they wanted to look like
houses and they were decorated as houses
and um and this is the main Legacy that
we have of them because their actual
houses were built in mud and and and um
and wood so we have very little left of
it while we have this nice underground
cavity this is all on the farm this is a
colum bium this was this used to be uh a
deposit of sary ears so they were buing
the people or they were incinerating
them but it's kind of funny you look at
all these Peak marks you know you can
still see today
what the people have been working on and
this is that's the same part but but you
can you can have those Peak marks that
go for miles all all around and um this
is a part of the archaeology map of the
farm this is the northern part of the
farm we saw this is the Little Road
Track that I show you we have another
one that is bigger one this is the one
that was actually paved we have here the
paving stones that are still on site and
each of these dots is meaning something
each of this dot is one ruin that has
been there you know for a few thousands
of years again the most of most of the
tombs were uh installed by 7 6th Century
BC but then in the middle age all of
those were used as houses so has been uh
a continuous flow history basically that
I feel on me while farming this piece of
land and this is one of the most
according to me most interesting
features that we have so up there is one
little tomb but down here this is the
entrance to a water
tunnel that was again dug by the same
people about the same time of course
it's hard to exactly tell when but we
can say for sure that is pre Roman we
can we can probably date it to the same
time frame you
know I will say 8th Century BC though
it's uh it's more a matter of picturing
a Time time frame between the 11th and
the 7th Century BC that's when the
atrasan civilization converted a wild
set of marshes and woods that was
Central Italy into one of the most
sophisticated agricultural system of all
times their farming system was I mean
it's a lot closer to what was you know
maybe 100 years ago than what it is what
we're doing now is to what we were doing
100 years ago and this is something that
uh has struck me but a long story short
these are water tunnel that are cut
directly into the bedro I had luck a few
years ago to be participating in with a
group of experts that were studying the
same type of devices in different 12
different countries across the
Mediterranean in the Middle East so it
was very interesting for me to start
from something that I have out on the
farm and be able to compare with what
people have and what people are doing in
other parts of the world a long story
short these are underground cavities
that are man-made that creating um a
cavity so is a depression into into the
bedro they car directly into into the
bedr mainly around the world are used
for water collection especially in AR
countries in um in um in uh in our
geology is they serve a
multi-purpose uh surfaces is water
collection but is also uh land
reclaiming from on top diversion of
water from the streams and they use the
the trust can they used it to modify a
lot the uh the orography of the of the
of the of the terrain this is a plan
section of an ideal canut which is
basically the same type of devices we're
talking about a
subhorizontal tunnel underground tunnel
that is duck directly into the Bedrock
with walls that are unlined and let the
water seep in or out of the tunnel into
the into the into the Bedrock and then a
number of shafts that connecting the
tunnel to the um to the to the surface I
think this is quite the whole thing is
quite interesting this
is this is a passive system of course so
water is collected from the underground
into the tunnel and it automatically
flows naturally flows onto the surface
so there is water coming up to the
surface available for human activity
that wouldn't be there whether it not
for the people who had dug this type of
devices even more interesting is the
fact and I was in the beginning you know
was I was kind of uh giving it for
granted when we bought the farm 20 years
ago the guy we bought the farm from he
took me there and say you know if you
don't periodically go in there and do
some maintenance this thing will clog up
and water wouldn't come out of it
anymore I said okay you know one more
task to do but then if you think of
it if you think of it is not banal that
water is coming out of something that
was carved almost 3,000 years ago that
is
sustainable and by going into and doing
some repair work I'm the last one who
joined the club that is a club who
started 2,800 years ago so that's again
that's not banal and and why is the
water coming out of it because this is
sustainable water collect collecting
it's sustainable because it's passive so
it will never be over exploiting the
resource is sustainable because there
are a multiple M multiplicity of factors
that are coming in action in order to
make this water available that is water
condensation water collection from the
Bedrock and all that kind of stuff uh
again a cross-section of a canat you can
see that there is exchange of water
between the underground and and the and
the inside of the tunnel that goes both
way so sometimes the water is draining
into or sometimes the water is draining
out of it and replenishing the water
table and this is particularly important
in our geology when we have multiplicity
of strata that are you know superimposed
to one another because our volcanic
activity went on uh for a number of
about a million years and but this is
also quite important for contrasting the
effect of climate change in our climate
climate change is concentrating
waterfall more and more into Peaks and
alternating with droughts and our soil
is very porous our Bedrock is able to
retain about onethird of our rainfall so
we can weend the trust can actually use
that in order to infiltrate title flow
into the underground then will be able
to be used again in the past um in um in
a future and late at later
times this is the this is the map of the
tunnel that we have we it's actually
getting the exit of it is aligned with
the church actually is the church to be
aligned with the exit of the tunnel
since the tunnel was there firstc
there's a meaning of the church is that
again these type of devices are water
producing so you walk into the tunnel
all the length of the tunnel you don't
see a spring you don't see the water
coming in but you see the water coming
out which is pretty magic that's why it
has always been um associated with um a
metaphysical uh thing well I did a study
there are a number of those around our
area this is uh this is the one this is
the farm this is the natural con consy
of
tuscania um again very different geology
this is the study that we did around the
tunnel in order to understand and
actually determine that the water tunnel
is not hitting the water table so that
water is sustainable even because it's
not part of a common I mean is a it's a
resource that is shared that is very
limited in in regard to the community
who is using it and is related to a very
limited part portion of land that's why
the water tunnel the the water that is
coming out of the water tunnel is is
unpolluted while we got plenty of
nitrates in this one okay because this
this is a much vaster resource H you
know but but the vaster the resource and
the vaster the community who is using it
and the more likely there will be
tensions you know so this is not the
case for a water tunnel and and again
I'm happy to do maintenance this is a
friend of mine actually from New York
City who is helping me out
sometime and it's good to know that the
club who started with the at trasan 2500
years ago can unlist people that are
willing to be part of it and so we are
still having water today and also this
is this is not on the farm this is Lake
vco but is just to remind how the atrans
were able in managing the the territory
this lake has a an artificial Emery
which is underground which is a tunnel
which is giving water to the city of
ronon that was cut basically to lower
the level of the lake so that all this
northern part of the crater could be put
in into cultivation the the atrasan did
this in a number of different cases and
it's kind of extraordinary
to think of what they did in terms of
again creating called arable land and
cultivat land and also this is not the
legacy of the at truskin maybe not
everybody knows
but it's them who started to select out
of a Cardon an AR choke so this is in my
garden and I'm happy to have in my
garden something that is going that is
keeping going that is is still a legacy
of that land not because of the
Topography of the land but because of
the people who used to live there at the
same time these are some of my o
trees these are some of the younger guys
and um these are out of my of my place
and this is also a legacy of the atrans
because it's still the atrans that by
converting you know all that in to an
agricultural system they started the
cultivation of ol Tree in in in central
Italy and this is a very important uh
concept for me especially speaking with
olive tree you might wonder why you know
is the Olive Tree that is quoted 76 time
in the Old Testament alone and it's not
a plum and you might you might wonder
why it's two branches of AIT tree that
is into the logo of the United Nation
and it's not just you know a palm well
the reason is that
a tree is of all cultivated plants is
the one that has the longest lifespan it
can stay there and produce for a
thousand years and when you're planting
something like this the first time you
want to be well settled you don't want
to be a nomadic Gathering anymore you
want to be settled in a society that is
giving you the power to defend your work
if push come to shop which means that
you planting something that is going to
stay there you want to be identified in
society so family names and private
names concept like property private
property of land uh a structured Society
with somebody to refer to if you're in
trouble uh structure society means that
of course the that Community is able to
farm in a way that is creating a surplus
or it wouldn't be possible to have a
structur society but the structur
society is also implying differentiated
architecture and so we end up with the
city but also writing these are all
features of what we call the urban
revolution of the atrasan between the
11th and the 7th
Century BC they introduced all of these
elements including the Olive Tree and
including the water tunnel these are all
part of a of a big picture in which is
impossible to determine the relation
between cause and effect but it's
amazing to see how they were able to put
all this in action and how are we still
dealing with uh with the legacy of this
again all tree lives so long if you look
at this twig this is another uh
peculiarity of the Olive Tree the olive
tree has buds even in grownup parts of
the plant and is the only plant that can
survive being chopped off the ground and
transplanted even when it's big but this
also has a different meaning because if
you let it go in its so I I said it in
its Soul anol tree is a shrub because it
will just not have one main trunk but it
will have a multiple uh shootings which
means in turn that the trunk there is is
a man-made thing thanks to 200 years of
clipping of this clipping so this also
is a good metaphor for a you know a
legacy and and and an alliance between
man and uh and nature and this is
another part of why the Olive Tree is so
looked upon you know it's kind of a
symbol of all the western civilization
if we if we want to you know the Greeks
and the atrans they started to divide
people between civilized or barbarians
whether they were cultivating or not the
ol tree and the and the grap Vine
sorry about this uh and
yet this is not the only these are not
the only legacies that we are dealing
with while farming in Italy you know
this is all yellow but it wasn't so in
the past this is all green but it's not
necessarily going to be green in the
future you know it's uh kind of
striking this is three
charts
sorry three maps on the it's called
aridity index I don't know if my
translation is good enough but anyway is
the combination of the amount of water
and the state of soils that we have okay
and this is
1950 and this is 60 to the ' 90s and
this is 71 to
2000 now my farm is exactly here exactly
on that line between that yellow and the
green and that line wasn't there 40
years
ago
sorry okay but anyway
um so what can we do about all this
um uh okay what can we do about this
this is how we are managing the farm
today of course all the different colors
are have a meaning but uh basically
houses olive trees these are the blue is
where the animals are or where you know
those pads that are mainly for Animals
our animals are horses and cows
basically and then we have a few pigs uh
the green is the uh vegetable gardens or
future Orchards uh the red is arble the
yellow is those land that can only be
pastured even because they're Woods or
you know pasture and all that kind of of
stuff so we are trying to our concept is
as an ecological concept we want to add
as many uh items into elements into our
into our ecosystem so instead of doing a
monoculture of course we are we're going
to oh okay I'm sorry about that um add
more uh uh elements to it of course you
can this is easy to read for everybody
uh but this is kind of an outline of all
the stuff that is going on in the farm
is basically we're working basically on
four different levels one is farming
proper one is tourism one is education
and one is nonprofit and I believe that
the sustainability of the whole Farm
will come from the interaction of these
four different levels among themselves
hopefully one day but so what have we
done so far dealing with all these
legacies um
well it came
easy I was lucky enough that it came
easy for me to start with dealing with
the olive trees I didn't have a clue
what an olive tree was when I started I
didn't have a clue of how to prun it I
didn't have the clue on how to harvest
it and yet these guys were still giving
me one of the best product in the world
I was happy I was lucky enough to start
traveling in this part of the world and
meeting with some top- knot chefs and
they are the one who I owe the fact that
I recognize how the value of this thing
again in the beginning you know you're
in Italy and everybody in Italy has an
olive tree you know you're a farmer and
everybody is farming Olive Tree so you
think well it's a l tree you know and
then you start traveling in New York
City and you got your product
acknowledged and you find out that
simply by harvesting something that is
on your farm and pressing you're doing
something that is unique is not the best
in the world in terms that they might be
potentially
other product that are just as good but
different it's it's amazing you know I
just have to go get it you know and uh
and I think we've gone a I I I've gone a
bit far I mean it took me 15 years to
understand how to p a tree but I'm
finally finding the way to put those
back into into action we found out we
put in Action a few things like of
course all of our Groves have grass we
are mulching the clipping right on side
instead of burning like everybody else
is doing around us honestly I don't
understand why they keep burning because
it takes a lot of more energy and a lot
more you know time and is all carbon
going to feed the greenhouse effect
instead of of feeding the of feeding the
um of feeding the Earth basically the
ground I'm proud to say that we have
orchids in this or CH because we never
till you know and um um and then again
we Harvest we prune and we uh sell I'm
happy to say that I was able to reach
again a few chefs in New City they're
buying from me uh a couple of the
biggest most famous restaurant in this
part of the world which of course is
helping me out if not directly done
under the economic point of view which
of course helps it helped me out because
I wouldn't be here today if it wasn't
for that you know it helped me out in
building you know something around that
uh this picture is also to to remind
that this might also the whole thing
might be a risk climate is changing and
the climate change is going to affect
the production of our
trees particularly in two ways I mean
milder climate through the winter might
inhibit uh blossoms and especially
there's a the olive tree has very
peculiar water needs that are basically
coordinated so far with how the season
goes in terms of r we have two peaks in
the spring one in the spring one in the
fall and this long drought in the summer
that's something that the olive trees
like as long as they have rains in the
fall or they have rains in that
particular moment in the in the in the
spring if that shifts then the whole
thing might be might be affected this is
particular particularly true with olive
oil that is a peculiar substance I like
to be a producer of olive oil because
it's the only uh substance it's the only
food that comes to the table after being
processed that is still alive there's no
heat no fermentation involved in the
making it's just a squeezing which means
that the enzyme that are into the olive
when the olive is on the tree they don't
get killed during the processing which
is a blast because it's like I mean
figure that you're growing tomatoes you
would wish that all of your customer
could eat the tomato right out of the
vine in the middle of the Garden in
August that's what I do with my olive
oil I can do that even in New York 5,000
miles away or 6 months later because
this keeps being fresh because again I
don't need to process it I don't need to
pasturize because there's no bacteria
that can grow in it but the the the
other side is that anything that is into
the oil is not there because of me but
it's there because of my plants and my
ter if my terror is changing because the
climate is Shifting I might not be able
to um to do that anymore uh just another
picture just briefly go through um olive
oil making this is the
some of the olives getting into the into
the olive meal the picture is taken at
night because again it's all a matter of
enzyme so we want to inhibit certain
enzyme to start working and that's we
why we Harvest during the day and we
press at night and um and all that um I
have other things to say so I'm going
through and then maybe at at the Q&amp;A if
anybody has more question about it I
would be happy to uh to come to come
back at it but again this is to say that
one of the this is how we deal with one
of the legacies that we're dealing with
on on our farm I'm I'm really happy I'm
grateful to be dealing with something
that made me famous in New City and I
just found it there I just had to you
know pick it up put in in action in a
way that would be sustainable uh for for
me and uh and I have a a great product
that is taking me you know all around
the world
um
how
else did we deal with these legacies how
else is did those legacies uh Inspire
what we're doing today on the farm well
definitely the water tunnel was a great
inspiration again in the beginning I
didn't care about it you know it's just
a water tunnel you go in and they silt
it but then you start realizing that hey
you know this is not banal so I started
to try to understand how is it possible
that something that was done 3,000 years
ago is still giving us water today and
again there are a few keys to the
sustainability of it and again one key
is the passive function so it's led by
gravity another key to the function of
it is that it it it allows for water
exchanges all the way through the length
of the tunnel and the reason why you see
water coming out of it and you don't see
the water coming into it it's because
the water that is collected there is
basically there because of what we call
Hidden rains we call Hidden rains
because you don't see it but it's just
basically a condensation of micro
quantities micro droplets of water that
could get condensed or could gather you
know a micro droplet per every square
inch multiply per T of meters or
hundreds of meter of length of a tunnel
end up in something tangible so
basically these two concept you know
water d by gravity and the combination
of very small quantities multiplied by
very large numbers that are at the base
of uh of the function of the of the
water tunnel and based on these two
principles I was able to
reconsider all of the water management
system on the farm so now we have a
little pump that is operated by the sun
and a number of containers that are
you know this pole that are put on
different places and different height of
uh on the hill flag the concept is that
the PV is operating a pump that is the
only pump that can go straight into a PV
system because it's a non- rotative it's
a piston pump that is hooked up directly
to the PV system and is starting to pump
as soon as the sun is out and it will go
on until the sun is not there anymore so
this goes on and on and on but of of
course the quantity per minute is small
but the minutes are a lot of them so we
can lift a lot of water every day as
long as we have somewhere to story but
the somewhere to story again this is I
this might all sounds banal it wasn't
banal to me to put it in action the the
concept of storing water is a concept
that implies where do I store it and
what do I need it for so we ended up
having five different containers right
now that are get filled each is filled
every day and each is filled by the
Overflow of the previous one and if
you're feeding each tank with the
Overflow of the previous one it means
that you want to know in advance where
your water where you want your water to
be and what are your needs so the first
tag is for portable use the second is
for drinking for the water for the
drinking water for the horses and the
animals and then we have three that are
feeding our Gardens that are at
different heights uh this is one of my
collaborator checking on the quality of
water I'm sorry but I didn't have any
other picture of the of the of the tank
and then there are three tanks that are
feeding through our garden and then we
are just it's not that we want to be
something that is stuck in the past
we're using modern technology but I like
the fact that this technology this way
of using modern technology was inspired
by the past because it's somewhat
holistic again the one choice of
changing the pump has brought me to have
to invent where to put the containers
and the way the containers are
distributed along the hill flank and all
that um and so I'm proud to say that now
we're running on zero emission in terms
of water management for the gardens and
and all the animals on the
farm
lastly how did we deal with these uh
with the Legacy again we want to share
so we combine with the local count
government who is running the
Conservancy we the only Farm who was
able to actually build a trail and is
open to the public anybody can come and
see our farm 5 days a week between 10:
a.m. and 1 hour before the sunset this
is just open because we feel that a tomb
doesn't belong to us it belongs to
mankind you know we don't want to be
closed we want to be open and the same
time this is bringing people to the farm
which is good because we want the people
to be there because you you know so this
is just briefly something that we had to
build for uh for the trail this is a
staircase that is parting partly held by
trees we had this U uh these are the way
we since part of it is on bedrock and
parties on the trees we had to invent
this system of letting the tree swing
this was a nightmare to design but it
was so much fun to build so I'm proud to
say that it's there now and uh it's free
of access uh also so this is a piece of
A Shard of pot that was found on the
farm this is actually a dolum which is a
big base that the Roman used to store
wine or oil so there's there's a legacy
in there another way of leg of dealing
with that is we're hosting we are
actually holding uh archaeological
excavation every year so we're cleaning
up with the help of a community of
people including the government we are
cleaning up a piece of you know these
are this is some of the this is kind of
amazing this is one of the beds you can
see the pillow and the bed leg it's kind
of cool and um and we're hosting uh
seminar and events on the farm and um
and and so that's all the part that was
inspired by the by the legacies but of
course you know where's the food coming
from you know these are all nice ideas
but these guys need to eat these guys
need to eat and these guys need to eat
as well you know so there's there's more
than that the farm
um I told you in terms of agricultural
production we have uh about 10 acres of
olive trees we have about 30 horses on
the farm we have eight cows we have a
few pigs for us we have about couple of
Acres of gardens we're looking into uh
being more and more self-sufficient as
much as we can even because there's no
point in wanting to output on the market
some of your production if simply the
Market is not able to pay for it you
know uh in order for you to make uh to
make uh to make money enough to make a
living but anyway this is just very uh
you will know I mean grass grass can be
Graz grazing can be considered an
intercropping but grass is also
protecting soil from soil erosion is you
know uh holding uh moist and water so uh
of course the cows and the horses are
grazing in two completely different
system because one is a polygastric one
is a monogastric so one like the Tall
Grass one like the Short Grass one like
the uh grasses and the other one likes
legumes and and each of the two are able
to uh interrupt the cycle of the
intestinal parasite of the other so they
can they can actually help each other
out um this is also to show how big our
trees are right now these are guys that
were planted in early 50s uh they're
still fairly young in terms of a trees
and still a tree like this can provide a
solid 250 to maybe 300 lbs of Olives
every year which is not bad um also
where's the food here's some zucchinis
zucchinis with a view they grow happy
you know and uh this is uh the layout of
the garden and what will be the Grove
this is not actually there yet but but
the garden is uh organized in 20
different fields we actually have a
10year rotation which might sound a bit
too complicated but it's okay because we
have arti chokes and alpha alpha in it
that are staying you know for a total of
almost 5 years so half of half of our of
our soil we don't really have to look
after um what are we doing okay we have
we're going the other way so we got ARS
for two and a half year we chop the
aroke off what we're doing is actually
we take these plants off after they
finish producing most part of the people
they will leave it until October in
order for them to spring back so that
they can take clones out of it what
we're doing we're just taking the whole
plant off and Transplant it you know and
then let it come and then we transplant
it in the next field so we actually are
able to use this field in the summer for
brasas uh or winter squash whatever is
still still available there and um also
what we're doing then we we got we got
of course the reason why we have 10
rotation is because the bulk of our
summer crops is night shades so we have
two twice the size for night shades than
for the other families and that's why we
have a 10e rotation so that they come
basically back uh every every five and
what we're doing for especially for
tomatoes it works really well because
these are coming out of the alpha alpha
they don't need but for tomatoes what
we're doing we are planting the hairy
vetch ahead of time and then we just cut
it and use it as a mulch so we are
transplanting on S instead of
transplanting on till land this is kind
of important in our climate because this
uh allows us to anticipate the tilling
before the rainy season instead of after
which is good because that is saving us
a lot of water uh then we're doing
lettuce then we're doing zucchini and
cucumber and melons and then we got the
alpha alpha so basically we
have uh a few fields that are in alpha
alpha a few fields that are in AR chok
the are these are perennial this is of
course a luminos but we got luminos in
here also we're what we're doing we're
planting uh Subterranean Clover
underneath the the the arok and this is
supposed to act as a perennial at the
same time I didn't get there yet but the
plan is to build a movable chicken cop
and graze the the chickens onto the
Clover and onto the alpha alpha so that
that will even boost even more my uh my
nitrogen uh again I'm going through
quickly but then after if you want to I
can I can come come back to to it this
is part of our uh another thing is that
we have where is it um like here we got
Clover this is not Clover actually is is
um Ry grass or something like that
because we're coming but anyway we got
one species two species three species in
in in a year sometimes even more you
know in the same field which is not bad
and this is part of the concept
alternating you know permanent crops
with uh with uh with crops that
are temporary we're getting into
starting our own seedlings this is
something that I'm fairly new at but
we're starting to save our own seeds of
course though I mean this is bit hazy is
is the picture it's not the climate but
you you know these fennels are looking
pretty happy to me in any case um
radicul that are getting in uh cabbages
we got
this this is kind of a funny story we
had way too many cauliflower this year
not because we planted too many but
because each of them was 15b we couldn't
eat it you know it's I call it a
Catholic Catholic Family you know Garden
you have to have 12 kids to go through
the whole thing but anyway so this is
some of the garlic we of course do rows
we alternate the garlic and the carrots
and so there is some part of this uh oh
this is this is
the young tomatoes in a mulch and um I
think these are the same guys but bigger
so what we're doing again here you see
the the clear soil but this is soft this
is not tilt so it can go through the
summer quite easily you know and this
continous struggle I have two employees
and one of them is the guy and he said
every time there's something complain
say Hey you know this is not the way of
doing it and I said okay I don't care I
do it this way in any case and then he
said hey you know there's no grass at
all in this garden thank you yes wonder
why these are some of the some of the
Arctic chokes again we Cho the whole
thing off we try we pot it basically so
that we can concentrate the water we
water is very limiting factor in our
climate so we want to make the most of
it and at the same time this is clearing
the field so we can we can put uh you
know the cabbages in earlier so it makes
sense to me to have a bit more work uh
and these are the AR finally going uh
going in you can see the Clover was
planted about one month one month before
one two months before and uh just
following the the season and these guys
are pretty healthy today I'm I'm happy
about it this is one of the secret
weapons that we use for the
garden some of you might be familiar
with it this this is a a sper this is
the picture that I took of it the day I
bought it I bought it I bought this from
a neighbor who didn't know what it was
he used to have it in his yard he was
going to throw it away I bought it by
the pound and I was very lucky and I was
very happy this is the way it works it's
very it's kind of very heavy piece of
equipment it dates back to 1971 and it's
still working so that's sustainable also
and and above all it's I was kind of
amazed this a picture that I took when I
bought it I mean with one strike it goes
from this to this which is wow I mean
they all discarded because you have to
go so slow but yeah I could go slow if
that's the result especially the way it
chops everything which is kind of big
chunks you know it's um it's it's really
good and of course this is the other
secret weapon you know uh even here
there's a lot of work but it pays off
you know so this is manure and okay we
we till it under and and we yes we do
till but also you might want to consider
that with this we can just back and just
plow a little strip so that might be
minimum tilling also you know minimum
tilling might be also to just
concentrate the tilling to where you
need and when you need it um we're
running out of time so
outcome uh I was
asked several times if I think that
organic being an organic farmer will be
more diff more difficult than being a
conventional
farmer and I say no I think it's a lot
easier it just depends how you measure
your outcome if your outcome is only
making money then maybe being a
conventional farmer will be easier but
if you measure your outcome in a in a
different way then you might be in
trouble if you're a conventional farmer
I measure my outcome
by trying to understand how much can I
be of help to other people we are having
woofers and interns and people that are
coming to help from all over the world
and we made a precise choice in terms of
Entrepreneurship in organizing our
system on the farm that is a system that
requires a lot of hand labor and we had
to come up with the opening ourselves to
you know to new people that want to come
and help but at the same time these
people that are coming and help they
coming from all over the world and they
stay with us and they share and we can
you know live together and be happy
together and be you know having the
feeling that we're working jointly on
something that is a common goal no
matter where we are from and no matter
what our life is is to be you know not
everybody is working all the time but we
are definitely sharing knowledge we are
sharing food you know we are learning
from each other and that's a good
outcome you know especially because this
doesn't clash with the fact that I'm
making money I'm not making that much
money but I can stay in business and at
the same time there's more than money
also I want to you know this is a
picture of old ladies back in the old
days harvesting olives and I like
working the way I do not just
because not just because I don't just
want to remember about this but I want
to produce it if possible in a modern
key we are building a community and
that's part of our of of the part of I
like this is the picture of a calendar
that we're putting on sale here in the
United States as a fundraiser to sponsor
scholarships for students to come and
work on the farm we are willing to build
up a community of an ongoing community
of students on the farm with people from
different backgrounds we're shooting
right now to for three people at the
time one out of farming school one out
of culinary school one out of
herbalistic and natural paath because I
believe that knowledge is holistic I
believe that it would be a great
experience for somebody just out of
school to stay six months or one year in
a different country working on something
that is specific and yet being exposed
to somebody that has a similar
background that is you know limiters to
what he or she is doing I I I would love
to do so to to do something like that
but also I'm practical you know and
being practical I acknowledge that the
always so much that I don't know about
the farm you know and that I should know
so I think that the most valuable tool
for my farm will be something that will
always be spending nights on books in
order to know more about it because you
know yeah I know some about it but
there's still a lot more so this is
again one page of the calendar the
concept is that we have chefs for each
page each page is one one picture that
is telling you something about the olive
oil production but also is one Chef's
telling you what to do with it and this
is why I call this a community building
because these are all shed in the United
States that are buying from us that are
willing to support us in something that
is actually supporting American students
to come over to the farm it's a cycle
you know that's the part I like and
that's the part I like because
basically we're all United we're all one
thing you know we're all fractals into a
larger picture most of us don't are able
are not able to see the larger picture
and only focusing on on what they're
doing but I'm sorry that's not the way
to go you know we're all connected you
know and we want
to remind us that men was able to
participate in
the you know both in the miracle of
turning the yellow into green which we
are still able to do we a lot better in
turning the green into into into into
yellow and that's that's something that
we want to be very care careful of but
no matter what this is all connected
okay so this is not an outcome this is a
little plan like this that I took out of
my garden the roots are coming all the
way like this which I take it as a good
sign that my soil is doing well I
mean organic matter is 2.69 now it's
okay hey it was 140 5 years before so
that's good okay I like that I like this
I like this guy to be there this is Farm
crew taking a breath but at the same
time this is more than Farm crew because
it's these guys that are going to hold
on for this line everything goes through
the you know organic matter and the
fertility of soil that is able to retain
water basically you know and at the same
time we don't want to we want to
remember what good ass at Mankind we
were able to do in the past and the bad
this is a picture I took in the arlc in
usbekistan in Central Asia this is the
biggest man-made disaster in terms of
water management it was just
unbelievable to be there and again we
want to remember all that has been going
through in the passing years and every
time I look at those trees and that's
why I call it a challenge to be a farmer
in Italy because every time I look at
those trees I can't but picture the
3,000 years of history that made it
possible for those trees to be there
today and I start wondering what are we
doing today for somebody that will be
here in 3,000 years from now now you
don't want to answer that question
because honestly we're just the
whole thing up so basically I'm just
every time I look at this landscape I'm
just wondering am I doing the right
thing every time I'm desting the water
tunnel are we doing the right thing I
yes I am I'm pretty sure that I'm doing
the right thing in calling over people
from the world all over the world and
share what I'm doing and share what I
have in order to find out what the most
best possible outcome will be how to
measure it uh monuments we can't eat the
all trees we can eat and also his way of
remembering the way mankind has been
able to be respectful to this planet and
this is B the this is in town the golden
ballet everybody's looking for gold the
goal is tomatoes the gold is producing
something that is able to feed us and
again can't but take the water tunnel as
a metaphor for oh I'm going reverse for
you know what good men has done and
hopefully we'll be able to reproduce
this in the future thank
you okay so we have time for some
questions that is a fire alarm but it's
not in this building okay yeah I was
wondering what that was going
okay okay
yeah I take it you do not have to
irrigate
the yes we don't we don't we don't
irrigate and we might do so if climate
change but even so we wouldn't do it in
the summer because in the summer the
tree needs to have at least a solid
month to two months of drought in order
to create the uh antioxidants so
irrigation will will affect the quality
if it's if it's done in the wrong in the
wrong period of time it would yes there
are stories of of farmers that spend
huge amount of money in order to create
irrigation line for the olive trees and
that water is just water so when you
squeeze the oil the water goes down the
drain and actually does bad because the
antioxidant are water soluble more than
they are lipo soluble so all of the
antioxidant will go with the water so
you want to be careful in irrigate olive
trees they need water in the in the the
spring they will need water in the fall
but they will not need water in the in
the in the summer so you can use it once
you plant your trees because you want to
boost the growth in the first years but
once you get into production you want to
be you want to be careful with
that
yeah
uh no for the for the for the most part
our Orchard the a long story short the
the bulk of our trees were planted in
early 50s and they were planted in
combination with Vine with Great Vines
so our trees are very much space spaced
apart so there's a lot because the the
great one was ripped off the ground back
in the 70s for a subsidies that pay
Farmers not to be Farmers anymore or
something like that and so we we have a
lot of space so all of our Gardens are
embedded into into the part of the olive
Groves and some of our fields are as
well but this is very a very common
concept I mean there's a text in the
1600s in Italy that already talks about
intercropping you know trees with with
other type of cropping so I don't I
don't think I don't think there's
anything wrong with it except for the
fact that for example this is
um this doesn't let us do mechanical
harvesting of the trees because we can't
access the tractor you know into the
gardens you know so we have to go with
handmade Harvest which of course
requires a lot of work there are a few
tools and you know that can help with
that but still is a lot of a lot of work
and you need a lot of Labor to do so and
that's basically one of the main problem
with the bulk of the growes today
especially esally in Italy that they
were planted and and and laid out maybe
even only 50 years ago like in this case
which is nothing but they were laid out
and and designed in a moment in which
nobody would think about harvested
harvesting mechanically so we're not
sustainable in on the market because our
cost of production in Italy is  a liter
a liter is a quarter of a gallon if you
go in Spain which is still Europe that
drops to three if you go to Tunisia that
drops to I don't know what because of
cost of Labor and that's why a lot of
people are ripping off ending up ripping
off uh their growth and this is kind of
a you
know a disaster because they're reaping
all of those grow that are more prone to
be ripped off are the one that are
actually strongholds against climate
change Olive Tree is a very peculiar
Tree in fact it can it can grow in a
pile of rocks and you can grow and bear
fruit with less than 400 millimeters of
rain per year so has been used by
mankind as a conquering plant in order
to you know switch from that yellow into
green that was a key factor the ol tree
and now we've gotten to the to the other
to the other end which people are
ripping those plants off only because
they cannot make a living sounds like
to me I mean we call this
progress but honestly I don't know you
know
so I don't know if there are any more
questions or if lunch is calling no yeah
what was your are
and old you planting also no I didn't I
didn't have I didn't PL any any more
trees my again the bulk of my trees are
of a variety is called Canino which is a
local variety that takes the name from
the next town over so it's kind of a
hairloom local variety that was used
forever and it's very Hardy you know and
it resists very it fits very well that
uh environment and and those were the
one that were planted in the early 50s
then when in the 70s they took the vines
off there are two parts of the farm in
which the ground is so shallow that you
wouldn't be able to do anything else and
so they planted more planting there they
you know in in between and those are two
different varieties froo and leino which
are very productive and very common but
both of them are very early in the
season so being early in our climate
means that they're very prone to the
attack of a par side that is
the uh the olive fly so it's kind of
likely that we wouldn't be able to
harvest much on those trees today but I
don't plan to I don't I don't plan to
add more trees right now I don't plan I
don't know if I will ever do in the
future because there are so many
different or Orchard around us that are
kind of neglected because people don't
know how to make a living with it
anymore because the a long story short
is olive trees has always been planted
in small batches in order only to
support the family you know so there are
a number of places around me that have
maybe 10 trees 20 trees 30 that are
never big enough in order to make a
living today they used to represent you
know wealth back in the old days but
nowadays it's just lost so I don't know
if you in the picture where all these
the farm with all the different colors
the colors were kind of getting out of
the farm limits because we're starting
to team in with neighbors you know
because we are lucky to be you know able
to sell our crop and so I better team in
more Farmers or team in more trees
instead of planting more on my on my own
grounds you know I don't I don't think
it will make sense to start new growth
when we have old ones that are dying
yeah have you had success your success
that
uh no not yet my success is not that big
yet okay and um no uh there are a lot of
people that are looking at what I'm
doing with great interest for sure and
um because I'm I'm able
to sell my product ahead of time almost
every year we sell out we sell out with
a price that is almost twice as as much
as the common market price for the same
or equivalent product of course I'm
trying to do my best in order for my
product to stand up of course but you
know it's not said that other people
couldn't do the same you know my um and
we're doing this by cutting the cost of
production in terms of money because
we're using volunteer workers so it's
not that we're not paying them of course
we're paying in a different currency
that's part of how we stay in business
is because we are working in this two
two different currencies one is cash and
one is giving away what we have which is
meat which is good food which is
landscape which is being in Italy which
is our knowledge which is you know
sharing what we have and what we know
which is something that we're very rich
of now has this come to the point where
other Farmers around me are willing to
team in with me just for that not yet
part of it is also a generational
problem you know I'm 40 I just turned 40
a few days ago
and uh I I'm I'm being on on that farm
managing that farm 15 years I'm a new in
a country you know that is kind of
conservative Farmers that have been
there for 700 generation you know and oh
you know this is the way to do it
because my father used to do it and my
grandfather used to do it and what do
you know I don't know okay you keep
going and I keep going my way and then
you get you know again how do you
measure your outcome you know I'm not
unhappy of what I'm doing but I can't
just be forcing other people to do it
because it's a matter of philosophy
basically you know hopefully one day
maybe my business My Success will be so
big that my economic success will
overpower the differences in philosophy
but you know that's not my main
occupation right now my main occupation
is trying to stay in business and and
and and run a farm not just being a
sociologist for now but maybe for the
future I don't know yeah a question
about your water Tel yeah um so I guess
one one of the infrastructure projects
back from the of August was the aqueduct
you had a photo of one of the aqueduct
no say that again you had a photo of one
of the aqueducts right Aqueduct so I
guess the question is um is there any
evidence at least on your farm whether
these water tunnels might have been
feeding some of the aqueducts there uh
there is plenty of evidence not on my
farm but there is plenty of evidence
that the water tunnels that I'm talking
about of at trasan origin are at the
base of the Roman
aqueducts okay it's exactly the same
concept is the same uh technology all of
what we know about the Roman and that we
know of as Roman hydraulic technology is
actually has been invented by the atrans
and it was pockets of uh intelligencia
of the trasan people into the Roman
society that was still managing those
the only invention in term important
invention in terms of hydraulic
technology into the Roman time is the
reverse siphon that came much later so
uh the principle exactly the same is
also this um underground is also this
horizontal structure linear structure
that got bigger and bigger and the only
thing that the Romans actually did is
couple those with the ark with the
building of the Ark the arch and um and
so and the other difference is is
basically a difference in the society so
all the tunnels into the at trasan
Society were feeding small communities
because it was a society that was very
spread out while the Roman power of
course was Central Power that was able
and had the need to let out and and had
build these huge works that of course
went on as long as the cental power was
able to defend and then maintain it and
then of course they collapse after that
but there's absolutely a continuity
between in in in the two in the two
technologies the main difference in
terms of water is that the water tunnels
are um the water the walls are unlined
so the water can seep you know through
the walls and so there is water
exchanges between the inside of the
tunnel and the underground versus an
aqueduct that is only made to transport
water so we'll have the walls lined with
waterproof plaster that will retain
water but it's exactly exactly the same
thing this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu