this is a production of Cornell
University all right thank you very
much I don't think it
works it
yeah all right thank you thank you very
muchan so
yeah digital
a
uh assistant professor of digital
Agronomy so I want to uh to tell you a
little bit more so last week it was like
a very quick lightning talk about few
things that we are doing in in the
program this week I would like to go a a
little bit more in depth in
um what uh what we're trying to achieve
uh uh bringing the the the the people
together uh trying to change things
maybe uh in different ways how we we
want to to accelerate change uh in
agriculture so that we uh we can reach
sustainable a and agroecology faster
than the pace that we are on right now
so uh I'm uh sorry that I want I want to
share something early on with you here
always the same thing here you need to
click on the thing
first yeah I want to share this with you
this is uh I I I uh watched a talk from
rockstrom Joan rockstrom it came out
like three weeks back and in the Ted
Talk he's presenting so it's kind of an
update on the planetary boundaries that
came out like in 2009 but there's a new
report 2023 and he's talking about the
Tipping Point so here what you see is
that see a human pushing the Earth and
potentially Crossing that dipping point
and then the new normal is Hot House H
so this is kind of a scary thing but
then he goes in details and then he show
those those spping points across the
planet and um we can see that
on
uh we can see that for a bunch of those
like six the five first ones we all
we're already in the in the line where
we can see those stepping Point changing
how uh our planet looks like Okay so
this tells us
that I said we need to have something
happening not in 10 years not in 20
years right now we need to see change um
and then sustainable development goals
uh from the UN started in 2015 we are in
2024 the goal is to achieve all that by
2030 clock is taking so um we make a lot
of Innovations and progress in ag
research okay we have different uh
different fields and we are kind of
attacking the problems from all sides
and we are finding
Solutions and we all hope
that it goes like this so we invent a
solution we run with that thing pass it
to the farmers Farmers take that take
that thing and then just run with it and
then changes happening but the reality
is that it's a little bit more complex
once you have invented something when
you once you have put something together
that you've demonstrated with
scientifically that it can have a change
it can make a change uh it's not
necessarily happening at the pace that
we would like okay so this is an
illustration here
of a recent paper based on a remote
sensing they looked at cover crop in the
midwest so uh how much do you think
what's what was the percentage in 2011
of the land in the midwest that had
cover
crops okay spoiler 5.4 and now you look
at this
uh we really want that thing to work
doesn't
work work U again you you look at the
title of the paper rapid increase in
cover crop adoption across the Midwest
what rapid increase looks like is like
this this is real
data
uh I mean we have plenty of scientific
evidence that cover crops are good and
they are compatible with uh with
farming yet adoption is is is tricky
other examples this is in the do region
in France I'm just going to read that
thing so project involving 400 farms and
around 40 40 villages in the doev region
in Western France where scientists are
experimenting with different techniques
to cut pollution even the farmers who
participated in the experiment and saw
the results with their own
did not noticeably change their
practices what does that tell us is that
you had scientists
there demonstrating and experimenting on
Farmers field but farmers were not the
leaders of that thing they were
observing that it going and it did not
stick they did not adopt it as their own
practice they did not integrated in
their practices another long quote from
Dan toi conservation practitioner in
Indiana okay if noil corn is done let
let me turn around if noil corn is done
incorrectly for example if a farmer uses
the wrong planter setup or does not use
starter fertilizer on the planter corn
yields and profits may be
reduced if this happens when a producer
first switches to no till they may be
more likely to go back to previous
methods this case tillage there is
always a learning curve with something
new this makes some producers risk
adverse because because if they do
something different they may miss
important details and run the risk of
reduced yield this is kind of a simple
thing that we can all picture in our
head but this is an important process
going on when Farmers try something to
gather evidence that it works for them
if it doesn't work then now they have
evidence that it doesn't work for them
okay so what I want to get at is that
change is a people's
process and very interesting uh
paper it's it's they are about to
release it but I was able toh to get
access to it because I know I know the
authors from Ruiz and Dumont 2024 what
they did is that they studied 50 Farmar
over six years that were adopting cover
crops okay like the process of adopting
the the practice of cover crops on their
part what they did is so they are social
scientists and what they did is that
they they try to see where they are in
that uh chain of process from inaction
where you don't even have an opinion you
don't really care to integration okay
and integration here it's a little bit
different from uh adoption in their
perspective where if you do something on
your farm is considered adopted like you
can check the box they adopted it but in
their definition it's more like uh like
a tractor if you if your tractor bre
braks you're not like ah I'm not going
to use tractors anymore doesn't work for
me you're going to fix the damn thing
and make it work because it's integrated
in your operations it's part of your of
your farming okay so from inaction to
interaction uh integration
sorry then there are three steps here
from resistance to amb to inflection and
all my life this is where the my scien
scientific work this is where I have
operated I'm studying uh things in the
field research Farm uh even on farms
Gathering evidence WR analyzing the data
preparing scientific publication
extension Publications uh presentations
like that seminars and then I uh show
the evidence that things are working
things are will benefit the farmers
things will will make a better better
life better everything and then the idea
here is to tip the perception from yeah
it doesn't work it's not good to oh yeah
okay yeah seems good let me try it so
it's just like to to to change to go
from negative to
positive but I kind of have stopped
there normally when once I have like I
publish stuff then I move on to the next
thing and then continue working on
things that are not finished and then
working on other stuff and then I'm just
trying to push that information yeah
it's going to work you should try it on
your farm but this is similar to a lot
of scientists where we stop here then at
that point Farmers needs to take that
bat on that we are TR giving it to them
now they need to pick it up when they
are they perceive a positive uh benefits
on on so at this point what they will do
is that they will experiment with that
new uh new approach new technique in my
case it was Precision management input
management but it could really be
anything they want to obtain evidence
that it works for
them we run series of interviews in in
in New York to ask farmers how are they
experimenting say we met with 15 Farmers
two hours each and then we just like
discuss the experimentation process and
you would be surprised that a bunch of
them they would do a side by side
experiment and then I'm asking them I'm
digital AG so I'm like okay what data do
you get how do you analyze your data and
and more than one ins something like
this I see it from the tractor cabin
when I harvest yeah it work or it didn't
work that's the data that they use to
see to to move on for next year the that
will influence the decisions from for
next
year this experimentation process is not
trivial okay I I put it there here
because I wanted to to show that we went
from the to Saint to the corn that we
know there was no experimental design
there was no science involved it was all
on Farm experimentation same thing here
for the three sisters uh way to grow
crops or for the use a fish head to bury
under each crop to to get the the
nutrients no science no uh no experiment
no no experimental design no statistics
or nothing involved and this can have
evolved to towards things that work
things that are very significant like
from theci core I mean this is
something okay so I just wanted to point
point this here that this is an
important process happening in parallel
with scientific research that we are
doing okay so when farmers are
experimenting on their farm with that
new practice that they were convinced
that W it could it could do something
for me help me more more environmentally
friendly or uh improve my Ben my profits
and things like that when they
experiment with it and if they see
something that doesn't
work then the danger is that they are
back to square one because the square
one is resistance I know that is it
doesn't work so now you have all that
work to go back to before they can try
again and in this study they looked at
how long it would take for Farmers to go
from one box to the other and it takes
about two years on average okay so this
is a real setback and thinking that we
need to accelerate progress I mean this
is not
trivial so uh I perceive this
experimentation here as a crucial
process uh for Change and
progress okay so then what we realize is
that everything that we do we develop in
science uh will go through the filter of
unarm experimentation before it creates
a real impact on
agriculture and what we know is that
conventional research benefits from all
the bells of and whistles of Technology
ing data organization data analysis and
all that while unarm experimentation is
a very low Tech process which mean that
it's prone to error because if you don't
have if all you have is to look by the
tractor window you may either do make
the wrong decision or you may not
understand why you made the wrong or the
good decision
okay so the premise of why program is
that digal a can support endogenous
experimentation and this is not just my
program that does that a lot of people
that have develop Precision agriculture
techniques really realize that yeah if
I'm doing this uh if I'm able to gather
all those yield Maps those as applied
maps and all the good stuff that that is
going on in Precision a real maybe we
can use it to experiment and then
there's a bunch of of different groups
across the so you see group groups from
Canada NGO
universities um you see a group in
France here uh and this is really very
short SP partial list but it shows that
like people are are trying to to make
this like a new way of uh of uh
collaborating with Farmers through the
the the data okay so we see a diversity
in the in in approaches from groups that
are more researcher Centric so they
would build a protocol and try to
disseminate it at to as many farms as
possible two groups that are more farmer
Centric uh sorry here okay strict
experimental design versus more open
design so here you have a protocol that
everybody needs to to adopt to be part
of the network while here everybody can
do their own protocol and then you have
here more researchers andrick where you
want to have more um the goal is to do
scientific Publications and here you
have more farmer Centric the goal here
is to have more pragmatic information to
see what works for them on their Farm
okay so I this is cooked up like just
through those uh those points there to
to to uh to illustrate a little bit the
different the the the
distribution uh but what's interesting
is that all those group have common
challenges how to gather and
contextualize the observations how to
analyze the data how to help farmers
learn from their
experiments and
uh now that we are starting to engage
with Farmers those challenge emerge and
then we need to develop the science the
solutions to make this process uh more
fluid and more easy to so that we can
scale in this process basically what we
are doing is that we're changing what we
used to call an adic do okay if you see
you have a farmer you go visit with a
farmer hey I've seen this and in that
field for scientist we see this as okay
this is an interesting observation and
and actually we use observations like
that to create hypothesis but for us
this is an anecdote it's anecdotal we
don't necessarily consider this as
potentially a scientific evid
observation but with that with data
science what we can do is that we can
transform this into something scientific
everybody have heard of the G by e by m
so the idea here is to say okay you saw
this that observation what was the G by
E by m
context uh of this observation and now
this makes that one observation worthy
of a scientific database that we can use
to start learning to see Trends and
patterns that can emerge that we may not
have seen um with the traditional small
plot experiment or by just talking with
farmers at the the coffee shop and
learning from their anecdotes here and
there
okay um globally if farmers in
Innovations were valued at just 05% of
farming production which is4 trillion
dollar that would match formal R&amp;D
investment from the private sector which
is about20 billion so I put it there
just to to show like the scale of if we
are able to transform those observations
into something to Scientific data I mean
all of a sudden we have access to a
wealth of new data to learn uh about
Agronomy and about
agriculture um so here I would it's not
just about data okay so I want to uh to
kind of describe a little bit what is
the the the on Farm experimentation
cycle so here first we uh we need to
engage with Farmers Farmers need to
understand what we're trying to do why
we're doing it and
uh and we need to understand why also
they want to experiment and and to be on
there on to be on the same page with
them so that when we engage we help them
Reach their
goals um and then comes the part where
we acquire the data we clean and
assemble the data organize it we do some
first analysis then we we uh continue
the analysis with some things that are
more in depth and then we discuss with
the farmers and partners to learn uh
together from the the results and then
um we have a process to uh review and
repeat and the idea here is that if we
are able to close that Loop of
experimentation within one year we are
more in line with what Farmers typically
do that they iterate until they have a
working solution as opposed to uh how
scientists experiment where we want to
replicate two three years the same
experimental design the same protocol so
that we can publish from it okay but if
you look at this thing here you have
really different groups going on so here
you will have more agronomist and social
scientists here you will have agronomist
but also data scientists involved and
again here to interpret the results and
to understand the farmers and to to to
help farmers learn from that result
again we have Agronomy and social
science so this makes really makes it a
co-creation process where we recognize
local actors capacity to explore and we
build on the scientist capacity to
quantify and detect patterns okay this
is um at least in digital Agronomy this
is what we are good at to quantify
things and detect Trends and
patterns uh so this is really a good
example of decentralized research and
the idea is to try to be iterative and
flexible so what I wanted to show you
here is this is an a
transdisciplinary approach okay because
you have all three Agronomy data science
and social science working
together Agronomy is there for
consistent interpretation okay so we use
the science uh soil and crop science
chemistry physics biology to have
consistent interpretation we use that
science to to interpret what we are
seeing then we use data science to get
greater certainty so whatever we we
conclude whatever we uh we analyze is
based on actual data and then we have
social science to make this a more
effective process to to to help people
work together
basically so at the middle of this this
is the unarm experimentation process so
that was kind of the that was my intro
on on Farm experimentation to for you to
understand a little bit what is the
principle and what I want to do next is
to show you a quick example of uh how it
could look like in practice okay so what
we I've never done a program like this
when I was at agriculture AG Food Canada
I started to work on a living lab uh
with Farmers to uh the objective was to
reduce the pollution in the S Lake which
is a part of the St Lawrence River and
that was the only thing and then we just
start sitting together and trying to
understand who is doing what scientists
like explaining better what is the
problem far
trying to understand the problem and
maybe linked to some practices but and
then I left and I came here so um that
would have been my first experience here
uh this is my first experience here was
with
Biologicals um so what I did is that I
thought okay let I want to try this idea
the idea of really helping Farmers
experiment but on their term to to
support farmer lead
experimentation so what I did is that I
consulted with extension Specialists and
uh industry uh service providers to
under to to learn like what our Farmers
uh interested in this year what are they
experimenting with and a lot of uh this
came back on Biologicals okay the idea
was that so biological is like a it's a
bacteries or a cocktail of bacteries
that you apply with the corn at seeding
and this thing is able to fix nitrogen
and Supply a part of the nitrogen to the
crop and on that uh the beginning of the
project it was everybody wanted to
experiment with it first because it was
a big um promotion campaign from the
company but also the numbers were kind
of aligning okay they were saying that
they would that would provide 40 units
of nitrogen so that would look like a $5
saving per hectare uh per acre uh for
the for the farmers so they kind of said
okay let me try it basically they were
they went on the Tipping Point they were
con vinced to try it on their
Farm uh so then we consulted with
specialists in soil this is a soil
microbiology uh project so I'm not a
soil microbiologist so I the the process
of unarm experimentation relies on
working with experts so here we
consulted with Dan and Alysia to
understand like okay how is this thing
working so basically the bacteria what
what happen is that you are have um the
bacteria in the soil in natural it's
there naturally okay and then it fixes
nitrogen buing being like in subis with
the
roots and then when it has enough
nitrogen for its uh its organism boom it
stops fixing the nitrogen okay so what
the company did is that okay that that's
a that's a bacteria that is very good to
colonize the corn Roots so let's modify
it to make it better at fixing nitrogen
so they they looked at the The genome
and then they found a part where where
it says okay I had enough nitrogen and
they just remove that part so that's
what I learned from working with the
soil
microbiologist and then with this they
were able to to uh with this then the
process would restart indefinitely and
then just continue fixing nitrogen
Non-Stop and that's the nitrogen that
becomes available available for the for
the the
crop okay so
once talk with the Cooperative Extension
people and service providers to learn
okay what people are experimenting then
I consulted with Specialists to learn a
little bit more about the topic and then
after that we met with Farmers to
understand and with the specialist in uh
nitrogen and corn and soil to just
generate some questions what are the
questions that will be relevant to
understand with this process okay and
the questions that came out are okay
what is the what is the effect on crop
nitrogen status we not just looking at
yield of course we will look at yield
but not just the yield we want to see
does that increase the nitrogen status
of the
crop will the organism be present in the
soil during the season if it's not there
it means it's not doing anything and
Farmers wanted to know is there a link
with some management that I'm doing with
the type of soil with the weather if
it's a drought dry year or a wet year
okay so with all that and learning from
um the soil microbiologist on how to
collect transport and store and process
the samples uh then we just went and
collected a bunch of samples so uh we uh
we identif we met the farmers via the
the CCE and the The
Cooperative Corel Cooperative Extension
and the service provider to have some
address some name some some phone
numbers so we contacted them and then
those Farmers explained to us okay what
is my experimental design where is the
field they met with us in the field
there's a flag there from here to there
you see so so that that that was that
was a little bit of a cumbersome process
to be honest but uh we were able to see
where their experimentations were were
taking place and if you look at this
here it's a little bit all over the
place so you see normal strip trial
alternative strips side by side so this
is very common how Farmers experiment
just side by side like this um adjacent
field so they kind of assume that those
fields are very comparable so they would
they would test this we even saw that
one Edge Rose we know very well about
the edge effect but still some Farmers I
mean he said like yeah I don't care much
about the the side so uh I'm going to
put the control
there we didn't say like okay that then
we don't engage we said okay let's
collect all the that still and when it's
time to analyze it it will become a
confounding factor and then the farmer
will learn from this experience uh
rather than if I would just tell them
like no that doesn't work okay okay so
then we went there and with interns
students we um we collected a bunch of
samples at every location trying to make
it like very efficient trips uh every
time we went out then uh Phil worked on
a on a process to uh to simplify y
gather retrieving all sorts of public
domain information such as uh pre like
the weather data remote sensing imagery
drought index topography and then soil
series okay so just by delineating the
the boundaries of the field then all the
data is aggregated so now we have this
to contextualize those
observations um and then this part was
was tricky we went and consulted with
the farmers to know like what did you do
what did you do in this field all the
the the step uh from planting to harvest
and cover crops and we had all sorts of
things there there and we had to do a
lot of back and forth to um to get that
information as accurate as possible but
it was all on paper and it was a little
bit tricky and then we processed those
samples the soil root
samples uh to detect uh the the presence
and the presence of the bacteria using
the bacteria using
qpcr okay so now we had like a mountain
of data okay from all the context data
all those agronomic sample data all the
data that came from filling out those
fields I'm this is digital Agronomy
right there it's just like a pile of
data we wanted to say okay how do we
present this to the farmer so that they
learn something I mean at that point it
felt more like man we're going to
confuse them more than anything else so
what we thought is like okay let's
transform every TW data into something
that looks more like an infographic and
that can be uh that is more like a
graphic that can be analyz briefly and
simply okay so each data we generated
infographic so I'm not going to go too
much in depth on this um but for each
piece of data we had some something like
that so here I mean it's not so easy but
you have the treatment versus the
control and then we would be able to do
like distribution curve okay like fairly
simple the yield coming from the
treatment the yield coming from the
control are they perfectly overlapping
is there a shift is there difference
okay then here that data here is a
little bit trickier to understand but
this is the nitrogen versus the yield
potential and what it shows is that here
you are in the response part of the
curve so more nitrogen equals more yield
and here you are in the flat part so
more nitrogen doesn't change anything so
what we wanted to Farmers to see like
hey if you're here and you put 40 uh 40
units less more or less it's not going
to change your yield okay so that that
was an important piece of information
then after that trying to see like okay
how can we illustrate the qpcr
results so we draw like really how did
where and how we collected the samples
and then we did an infographic with this
so that they can quickly see is there a
bar or there's nothing there I don't see
any any uh any any data from that then
after that remote sens thing helps us
like see like is there special
variability in the field and then the
weather data showing like uh it's maybe
a little bit easier to see here but them
versus the the rest of the group and
then you can start seeing okay was was
there drought in in during that year was
it a dry year or it was a normal year or
then you can can start seeing it then
another piece of information that we
wanted to add was benchmarking how did
your field so you will find something in
terms of your yield presentence of the
the bacteria and your nitrogen status
but how is this com how when you get
this information how did your management
compare to the the other people in the
network okay we had 23 Farms so we were
able to draw uh box plus like that that
kind of illustrate the entire um group
and with this we can put okay this is
your farm so you can see okay here I had
quite low Growing Degree Days my wheat
pressure was a little bit High I had one
of the highest yield in the in the in
the the group you see so now you quickly
see by benchmarking with others like how
how things are panning for you where
where where you stand okay so now that
we had like okay those infographic we
did not just throw those at them by
themselves we provided a key to uh to
help them interpret the results okay so
that they would would go through that
key flip through the pages and then see
okay this is how I interpret this uh
this result and with this they would be
able to get to a conclusion for each of
their site okay remember that it's a
side by side you don't have
replications uh it's one year okay so
you have really one one thing to look at
and from this you want to to conclude
something of course it's not going to be
a scientific conclusion but what we're
trying to do is to um
stack layers of evidence that kind of
all point in the same direction if you
have 10 things pointing in the same
directions conclusions are stronger if
everything is all over the place
conclusions are weaker okay that that
kind of approach that's what the data
allows you to do so okay so we went
through the the yield first that was the
most important question for them then
nutrition index and then was the the
bacteria in the field or not and for
each of those they would mark
if it was very clear or it was Fuzzy in
their interpretation just to allow them
to yeah this is something decide
something because if if you have to be
perfectly clear it's better to have a
conclusion with a level of certainty
than nothing at all
okay uh and then with this we would we
would generate a conclusion and a level
of
confidence so it looked a little bit the
results were a little bit all over the
place but here what I wanted to show is
that um in general there's a good
agreement between very simple just
looking at yield and adding more data
but what it does here is that when you
see something like hey it didn't work it
didn't work for me if you have uh more
data what it allows you to do is that
you can learn why you are allows you to
to ask question why it maybe didn't work
because if you just have it didn't work
for me then you may just ditch it and
never return again but if you're trying
something new if you understand why it
didn't work now you're kind of willing
to give it another goal maybe the
following year or to kind of pursue uh
the learning
process um okay and then that allows us
to kind of see at the at the at the
network level to understand a little bit
more what's going on and I'm going to go
uh briefly over this here
um uh so Phil uh Ed AI to try to
understand a little bit what's going on
in the data okay so we looked at what
the at the presence of the bacteria KV
and then we just drew like all the
variables try to see what could explain
the presence absence or the the the
level basically and then we saw like
okay it's inversely related with the
other bacteria so there are two bacteria
in that in that cocktail if one bacteria
picks up then the other one kind is kind
of recessed and vice versa so that was
kind of interesting and that would
explain why they put two uh but then
there was a bunch of things that some
make sense organic matters some are
maybe a little bit harder to under to
interpret but then what this
does is that it could be so some of
those it's easy to dismiss yeah it does
like a giving an agronomic diagnosis of
that of that kind of data you can see
yeah no that doesn't make sense and
working with Farmers also they can
quickly see things that make or don't
make sense um but what it does is that
things that we don't have a clear answer
why is this so
impactful uh then it could generate new
hypothesis for research is there
something about the slope something
about the calcium that could change
something in in the the abundance of the
the bacteria in the soil so I mean if we
had like a conversation with specialist
we could dismiss some of those but some
of those things coming up we could could
investigate further so I wanted to touch
on this because this process here is is
a is kind of powerful for problem
finding for generating new hypothesis
instead of generating your research
hypothesis based on uh farmer that
points at something that they s in their
field that's kind of interesting but now
we have a new process that says like hey
this is happening we see that
consistently over the years over the
fields we don't understand why there's
such a strong relation here oh now
that's a new kind of interesting
research project to
start okay um so we wanted to learn from
that first iteration of un Farm
experimentation so yeah we learned that
farmers appreciate this way of
collaborating and were engaged basically
they were doing it either if we were
there or not okay the engagement was
really to exchange the data and then
work together to interpret the results
data change was a mess okay the flow
this is a very slow flow that was that
was not uh that was not easy H and the
conclusions with data are what we see is
that they are more nuanced and they
raise questions so ideally it would be
very clear for Farmers what they learn
from from their experimentation but the
reality is that when you do a side by
side you cannot have the same level of
certainty that when you do
a scientific experimentation
but yet you can learn
something okay so this kind of fueled
the the the the second wave of
development if we are going to do
another cycle of unarm experimentation
let's be more prepared to make it a
little bit more easy because by the time
we started the first the first project
and the time that we had all the results
ready it took two year because it was
such a mess to go through and it was
like a learning learning process the
idea here is that we need to be involved
being able to kind of make it happen
quick so that we can do a full cycle in
one year so let's try to develop tools
that will help us do that one of those
tools to quickly learn and to maybe
allow for a little bit more diversity on
what and how Farmers want to learn is
the experimentation card the experiment
card we're basically asking okay what is
your hypothesis how are you going to
test your hypothesis what are you going
to measure and how are you going to
interpret those measurement
it could be very simple but at least it
kind of puts on paper a little bit of
more
um more motivated or more uh practical
way to to experiment for them it helps
them like crystallize this on paper then
we are working on the development of a
of dashboard and this will allow us to
better capture the data so we want to
build
a a web tool that will allow Farmers to
say like okay I'm dedicated to
experiment in that one plot they would
not do this for their entire Farm but
I'm experimenting in that one plot I
have scientists from Cornell from
different groups coming in helping me to
to extract the information and learn
more from that thing so our hope is that
they will be willing to spend a little
bit time at night to kind of populate
and explain what they did in the form of
a timeline so they would just add every
operation that they did during the
season for that one uh field and then
with this we will have access directly
to all the the the detail information
then we are starting a uh a survey on on
Farm experimentation and digitalization
so we want to learn a little bit more
there's one survey that exists and it
said that 90% of farmers were
experimenting but now we want to see
okay is this does that hold for New York
and then learn a little bit more about
that process like what kind of data they
collect and uh how they interpret it so
uh yes so ktie Ellison and M will be
collaborating in this project so this is
this is great and then we have a new
website coming up Farmers that lab that
where we want to kind of centralize both
the information about what is this
process but also a way to get engaged
into for Farmers to to work with us just
wanted to touch here that the next round
of on Farm experimentation next summer
will be on adjusting nitrogen rates in
corn after cover crops uh so this
project was funded by the New York corn
and so being grower associations and in
collaboration with American Farmland
trust so that uh that's nice because
when we presented the the project I
presented it this way like we want to
help farmers derious their their
experimentation and learn more from it
and the growers association I mean they
they like the idea and they funded it so
that was kind of a good um that was a
positive thing for the program okay so
now I just want to uh to uh finish or or
to to conclude on
how I see that this could become like a
little bit of a like a vision for the
future if we are able to scale this
process okay so we have Farmers here
that are after pragmatic knowledge they
want to find things that work they don't
necessarily understand why the same
thing as when they developed the three
sisters they may not have understood
exactly how the beans were fixing
nitrogen it was just pragmatic it works
for them okay this is this is what
farmers are looking for
then we have academic research where
we're looking for semantic knowledge
something that is general knowledge that
can be uh Universal okay that's what
we're looking
for in this part here we have
observational research so it's all
anecdotes that are transform into
scientific piece of observation that can
be used in the database for analysis and
this way we can uh find Trends and
patterns in the data generated here
while here we are uh developing the
experimental design so that we can run
statistics and uh
quantify and quantify the processes and
explain like cality and better
understand so the idea here would be
that those two would work together both
are very important for the acceleration
and the transition to a sustainable egg
and how it could work is that with this
here we could generate hypothesis as I
was saying okay maybe something
sometimes we see something that is very
strong but we don't understand why so
that becomes an an hypothesis for
research I want to say here also is that
if that if we just spin that wheel
without the connection here maybe we
will find something that works but if we
don't understand it maybe over time like
in 20 years 30 years Boom the thing will
break and then we don't understand why
because we did not have a clear
understanding of the processes behind
that's why the connection is super
important but then here academic
research provid
an understanding so that yeah we can we
can roll with with that pragmatic
knowledge and really continue the
progress and Accel accelerate the
progress and in this way back to my
title that's why I I think farmers will
will lead the transition because when in
this process uh farmers are leading the
the
experimentation the exploration process
okay so people that are making this
possible I mean I had I did not realize
before putting that slide together that
so many people were involved this is
this is awesome uh so grad students Alex
Phil KT and then all the interns uh that
were with us over the years I mean
during the season I mean when we are
going to on all those fields of having a
big team allows us to just like hop from
one one field to the other and be very
efficient and then collaborators to the
program uh and funding here uh with
Cornell AES USDA at kinson C New York
Growers and soybean
Association okay so if you want to learn
more and I'm going to stop on this uh
there's an an important paper that was
kind of explaining the whole all the
principles of onar experimentation and
how it can transform Global agriculture
uh we are putting out every month a
newsletter on the topic of unarm
experimentation via the international
Society of PR act and uh we are also so
putting together a new uh Network called
the Gan the global on Farm
experimentation
network uh so that we can all share
tools knowledge develop the science and
organize it's a little bit like a
society so M and I are kind of leading
this this initiative so thank you very
much for your
attention have five minutes for
questions David is said David first I'm
wondering about the balance in the
driver behind on Farm experimentation so
as an example you know pivot bio is
advertising on country radio stations
every five minutes but you know maybe
Herold can't afford an advertisement
every five minutes for soci health or
you know internationally like jaica was
always pushing effective microorganism
as part of their development mandate but
maybe conventional convention
conventional extensionist didn't have
that option that budget y so if the
driver for on Farm experimentation is
driven by a commercial entity to the
disfavor of research generated how do
you address that this is this is a great
question okay so we went with the pivot
bio
experiment I must say foolishly now
after after the fact my my uh kind of
thinking that was that okay I like the
idea that nitrogen comes from from a
bacteria bacteria rather than coming
from natural gas so that was kind of
okay so this could be a sustainable
thing because I mean we can pick and
choose the experiments that we want to
to to to support so right so that was
kind of okay with the principles behind
the farmers that I have okay so then I
felt like okay this is could be fairly
simple it's kind of you apply
treatment versus control so that will
make for kind of a simple uh learning uh
um learning experience as compared to
maybe working more with cover crops or
no tail where you can have like a some a
lot of diversity between the control and
the treatment so we wanted to go with
something simple but uh you you are
right that we cannot just respond to
like everything that is going on so one
thing so to to
the the solution or maybe the the the
way to to work with this is to uh rather
than taking everything that is coming
our way what however it is is to kind of
be more uh purpose oriented for what we
choose so one thing that I'm thinking to
do is when we do those experiment card
we may have topics start with topics and
topics that are related to actually the
science that we know we know
work that we want to kind of push
but that's that's
important and then David so um two quick
questions um I hope that experiment that
involved the uh the
enros um was thrown out because that you
know I mean I I get your point that you
know that's how the Farms do it but you
got to throw out data that's yeah
because head goes always on theform but
the other question that I have is is is
did
when you say would bu a work like in 24%
of the cases what does that mean that it
worked was did it economically work
because you're charging quite a bit yeah
for uh product actually given an
economic advantage and have you then
made an aggregate analysis if it only
works in one out of four cases and you
pay what was it $20 or something like
that per acre like how does a pencil out
yes yes okay this is a good point I mean
how we determine that it works
is that with increased yield you were in
the response curve of nitrogen and the
organism was present that's what we
could deal with but you're right that we
don't know if it was uh economically
viable uh with I mean we have yet to
kind of dig into the data to uh to to
extract all the information and you're
right that some some fields we could we
could not work with with some
experimental sites so what I showed at
the end was just 16 Fields out of the 23
because some that are just not good
enough and actually 16 is not much to
try to look for Trends and
patterns much better than zero yeah
better than zero but like the idea is to
to find tool so that we can kind of
scale because the the power really comes
when you have
numbers my question is how you get the
confidence that you had there you have
your interpretation tree and each one
you had a little you know how in the
heck I sta
how did youate yeah so we part we start
from the premise that farmers uh they
they are used to look at their yield and
decide
something uh but in this case you have
the data in front of you so we did not
do stats because we cannot really do
stats so what we did is that we uh we
just you just look at the data and you
decide so that's the farmers themselves
deciding if they find that this is
convincing or not because in the end the
conclusion will serve
them I mean this because you see the
idea back to pre Fisher though I mean
this is
1924 something the pile of potatoes and
the other pile of potatoes yes but in
this case we at a certain point want
statistics we know that we're really see
something that's true not just
somebody's opinion yes so in this case
we were looking at
heal pretty sure you're looking at heal
and this is not I want to work with you
on this okay so what I think we can
solve this when you cannot conduct
statistics statistics is that with the
data you can have multiple signals I
kind of touch a little bit on this and
um you will never be able to have like a
95% certainty about your conclusion what
you will be able is to to have something
that will hint you for the for the
subsequent Seasons to to make a decision
to move on to learn something from your
experiment and what I think is that if
you have maybe two three four five
signals and the more independent those
signals are if they all point in the
same direction then that strengthen the
the conclusion if they are in different
direction then it's weakens the conion
so it's a little bit of a paradigm
shift we because we have to work with
the data that that exists
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu