this is a production of Cornell
University okay without any further Ado
I'm here to tell you a couple of things
uh first of all I'm I'm proud to stand
up here and say that what Lori and I are
about to do uh today continues to be a
good indication of how when uh conducted
properly Cooperative Extension in New
York state and the United States is
still alive and well and still a very
important part of the land grant mission
that I hope continues to uh maintain its
important as we as we head through uh
difficult budget time so that's my
political statement for the start of
this thing um my personal statement is
it's always wonderful to have colleagues
like Lori who are uh make for a
wonderful partnership where we know
there's a need we identify the way we
want to approach it we identify the
behaviors we want to change and we go
after it and do it in very classic
Cooperative Extension fashion so that's
the message for for
today you have to wonder what you all do
with yourselves coming out to listen to
a lawn talk on a day like this but we're
glad you're here nevertheless why do you
know Lawns why what is it doing here why
do I care about it I don't understand we
should completely get rid of these
things and the fact is uh Lawns both uh
cover a lot of grass a lot lot of grass
a lot of a lot of land um this is from
mesie of 2007 he did some spectral work
from a NASA satellite um and you see the
land cover it's um I think it's about
333 I'm not even sure exactly the land
coverage but you can see that it tends
to be focused around urban areas it has
enormous economic value it's an 85
billion dollar in Industry uh industry
nationally and Lawns make up 65% of that
economic value so Golf and sports and
sad all the other things uh account for
the other
35% uh nationally in New York state we
did a survey back in 2003 so that's uh
fairly dated now but at that time it was
a $5 billion industry and in New York
about 75% of the economic value came
from people buying stuff for their lawns
not hiring a service but buying things
uh for their lawns equipment uh
fertilizers pesticides seed uh Services
because we don't have a farm gate value
the uh Na s did the the stats they did
it for us in 2003 based on uh the way we
projected PE the amount of money people
spend on lawn so we have a lot of La so
why do we have Lawns why do we need
Lawns and and we need Lawns because we
do this to where we have Lawns when you
have a high percentage of impervious
surface you have enormous impacts on the
way water for example will move through
that system so it it then heightens the
importance of these vegetated green
spaces and I'm arguing a particular part
of it we can see from this slide is
Lawns and so how do we view the lawn as
something that helps us or at least
recognize as the people in the
Chesapeake Bay Area have recognized that
this is a significant land use that may
not serve a purpose out here to have it
doing the things we do with it uh in
urban areas in
Nebraska uh but in areas where we have a
lot of pavement it makes a lot of sense
to have something to medicate the
problems that the pavement cost very
good so so we know Lawns are everywhere
there's a lot of impervious surface we
also know that the climate is changing
dramatically right the climate is
changing anybody that works in growing
something recognizes that this is some
data from 2011 from the from Noah and at
that time they were keeping weather
records for 117 years and two parts of
the United States had their warmest year
on record the march to August 2011
growing season and in the Northeast and
in the the South Central South Midwest
here um had the 108th and 109th so the
in the top 10% of the warmest years ever
so the climate is changing lots of Lawns
how do we get to love a good lawn why
would we embark on a project like this
well let me give you some background
that's my job is to sort of set the
stage for Lori to pick up on a little
bit about our program uh and what we
focused on a programmatic approach to
how we do things High touch Hightech
used to meet a lot 20 years ago when I
started an extension um doesn't mean as
much now but I want to show you we've
come through the ranks on thinking like
that in extension we've had some good
scholarship and of course measuring
impact we've been at this a long time in
Turf this is from the United States Golf
Association green section record from
July of 1921 when Cornell was commended
for starting a short course for parking
grounds
managers lebit toown the
original the original subdivision
Suburban love a good Lawn Place and so
as this happened in the 40s right at the
same time um not well not long after
about 20 20 years later we started to
realize the pressure on the Long Island
groundwaters uh the groundwater that
that the Long Island citizens use uh for
drinking water was under siege from
Agriculture and at the same time we
looked at urban area so historically we
did the Cornell in cooperation with the
Water Resource Institute Dave Balden did
a bunch of surveys of Lawns on Long
Island in the
1970s looking for are Lawns leaky are
things leeching out into the groundwater
and what they found was that if you look
at the data as the lawn ages the organic
matter gets accumulating in there starts
to supply a fair amount of nitrogen
right right in the weeds we're getting
with in the 70s we figured out we knew
that this was happening now to be honest
we're slow learners but now these people
outside of the turf field just published
a paper this this past month on
household management practic an effect
on global warming of Home Urban
Lawns and what they concluded
was as the lawn ages you shouldn't
fertilize it as much because it
increases the global warming Problem by
putting out nitrogen fertilizer that
leaks into the atmosphere nitrogen is
300 times more potent as a greenhouse
gas than carbon so it's interesting to
see how things that started here at
Cornell are now still very currently a
part of the thinking about taking care
of Lawns so we've had a strong research
base for a long time very much focused
on Environmental Quality that has been
the emphasis of our program for a very
long time we also have a a focus with
our collaboration with the New York
State IPM program on a progressive Pest
Management approach that's both
ecologically based and uses IPM and
finally from an extension perspective
our work is always focused on enhanced
decision- making it's one thing to
create information
that that you just let loose at a
website or on a booklet it's another
thing when you take that information and
help people to make decisions to make
make their lives or the environment
better so here's our programmatic
approach that was the history and maybe
our focus our approach to this
particular project fits in like every
other thing that we do what's the issue
what's the audience let's get a resource
going let's work and work that resource
in various venues and now of course you
can add the augmented environments we do
webinars and Google chats and Skype and
everything else that we do we're
connected to Geneva so this uh is the
high touch and of course we're still
learning how to work in those augmented
environments for the high-tech part and
then we check out how we did you know we
put all this energy into doing all this
work did we change Behavior this is I
think a a thing a lot of extension
people don't always get that that just
putting the information out there isn't
isn't a role of extension there's a lot
of dopes that put information out all
over the place they don't help you make
decisions and that's a singular
science-based focus of uh Cooperative
Extension at least from my understanding
of it so an issue closer to Lawns as
environmental assets was when I got here
in 1996 we had just signed the New York
City Watershed agreement I sat on a
Governor's uh panel with particularly
protect ing the resources on the east of
Hudson Urban water the urban Watershed
that's the east of Hudson and primarily
uh phosphorus loading now we Marty
Petrovic and I did a bunch of work over
the years looking at leeching and runoff
of different compounds so we had to
research we put together that research
with colleagues in New England to sort
of get a better handle
on from a large perspective but here
from an extens perspective we developed
an
almanac we looked at lawn care and water
quality in a calendar format so it was
January you opened it you could look see
what should I be doing in January what
are the kinds of things if I want to
have a good lawn and protect water
quality what are the kinds of things you
can do so um we then did a bunch of
training for several years with this
Almanac um that's got to be 18 years old
now and when we went back and surveyed
how effective we were were from the the
money we got from the New York City
Watershed 40% of those we educated this
went out and soil tested for phosphorus
we said to them 90% of the Lawns east of
Hudson don't need supplementary
phosphorus if you test and you got this
number don't put it out there and so we
had enormous impact in the training that
we did and overall the four or 500
people that we trained particularly
through this process Master Gardeners
and otherwise all said we raised their
awareness they had no idea all the ways
taking care of their lawn could impact
water quality now this is translated
further in some of my professional uh
extension work the golf superintendent
and the golf industry came and gave us
$160,000 to develop a best management
practice set of principles that's online
um that was both uh reviewed by our
scientific colleagues for accuracy and
also by uh people in the division of
water and the division of pesticides for
the dec so they looked at what we wrote
here so it's U congruous with their
regulations and we're currently in a
phase two process we're now assessing
superintendent use and changing of
behavior for now that they have this
resource okay on our way to the ebook
which is to me the height of the the the
the star of the show here obviously
climate change is a big issue and I
mentioned it earlier it's one we think
about all the the time because this is
when people take care of their lawns or
their Gardens they can potentially have
an impact uh and their practices may
change we've done some research about
this um this was actually a a a class I
taught a bunch of undergrads and grad
students we got together and asked this
question this was one of the this was
the number one downloaded Turf article
from the turf information file from 19
uh from 2009 so we asked the question
how much carbon are we burning how much
are we sequestering got some good
preliminary data that many many have
published Beyond this we also published
a paper looking at how the changing
environment increases the conducive
environment for a folar pathogen in this
case dollar spot and I published it with
Rd Gano and we actually found looking at
weather records over a 50-year period
how pest pressure from the environment
has changed all these black dots are
where the environment is getting more
conducive to this particular folar
pathogen so we got some foundational
data I mean climate change is the issue
we see how it's impacting disease
pressure we published a research article
on it and we use that forecasting
information in our Weekly Newsletter
that we've uh written about our surveys
from in the Journal of
extension an example of just in time
education
and the forecasting and predicting of
these issues are part and partial to our
Weekly Newsletter and also well
integrated into our forecast website
that's managed through the Northeast
climate Center so again a commercial way
where we've identified how climate
change is altering uh pest pressure how
do we help the managers make better
decisions by regular contact with them
through the shortcut newsletter and
forecasting how their the risk for the
particular problems might be so they
might not use as many pesticides in
taking care of
it the Beth Page state park is another
example of some of the uh
decision-making work that we've done in
this case we started with the New York
State Park policy people who wanted a
ban pesticides across the entire State
Park system and we said maybe you should
treat golf courses differently so I
partnered up with uh Jennifer grant for
the New York State IPM program and
started working with uh the 27 State
golf courses throughout New York State
we've got a resource here developed by
Bob portes when he was a graduate
student and utilized in his time now as
an extension associate funded through
the uh New York state parks
department and we've taught national
seminars we are current you know we
started working at Beth Page now we work
at all 27 state parks um we've had
pretty good superintendent extension
update on from our website hits and our
extension colleagues continue to use
this in their training Pat vidto
uh uses it in her class at the
University of Massachusetts and those
that have done gone through our national
training said that 25 to 40% by using
tools developed through this we're able
to reduce their environmental impact at
their Pest Management program so again
how do we help people make decisions and
how do we determine how they're doing on
the other
end little gloating this is the book I
did a number of years ago this uh is the
top selling what as was the en raay now
was C now it's pal
um this book is still their number one
seller and again it's a tool devised for
helping people decide what to
do
okay just to remind you of the approach
that we
take and the introduction to Lor's uh
effort here our thinking based on all
that I've led to to this point is that
Lawns are a resource in an increasingly
urbanized environment so when you ask
people what a sustainable lawn is
they'll give you a variety of answers
right depending on what perspective they
come to you know what makes a lawn an
environmental asset or what makes a lawn
we can sustain so we sort of word Smith
uh different definitions but optimizes
the functional aspects of the lawn in
harmony with conserving natural
environment under economically F sound
and socially responsible you know all of
us adapt these things for whatever crop
we're working on but our emphasis has
been on the functional aspects of the
law not necess necessarily how it look
how it looks and that's why this isn't
love a great lawn it's love a good lawn
now why do this well the gallipo people
are are when you ask the degree to which
Americans worry about environmental
problems this is from 2008 or N I think
and you can see that how many worry
about these particular environmental
problems uh uh water pollution drinking
water pollution global warming
has about 50% not much at all think
about global warming now this is four
years ago so it may have changed a
little bit but the point I'm building to
is environmental actions in the US
they've there's been little increase in
general in environmental action most
people the biggest thing they do is
recycle across the board the biggest
thing they do is
recycle now the challenge we face in
getting people to look at Lawns as an
environmental asset is very much tied to
the econ economy again a Galla poll
taken all the way into
2011 which one of these statements about
the environment and the economy do you
most agree with protection of the
environment should be given priority
even at the risk of curving curving
economic growth or economic growth
should be given priority even if
environment suffers to some extent and
you can see the Gap from the 85 1985
when they first started asking these
questions in right around the turn of
the century you started to
see well I sort of think the
environment's important but you know I
got to have money right and so it was
you could see the downturn in the
economy right here we now a much bigger
concern for economic stability that
Environmental Quality and you can see
how these things are hovering right
around each other so to get people to
pay attention to environmental issues it
has to make economic sense it's actually
an easy set
once you tell people caring about the
environment inherently could mean you're
going to spend less it tends to balance
those things for people now this was a
tough go even internally the American
Society of Landscape Architects in
cooperation with ladyb Bird Johnson and
the US botanic garden said we want this
sustainable initi sustainable sites
initiative which is essentially lead you
know the building standards for lawns
I'm sorry for for the outside for the
landscape lead for the
landscape and in in right out of the
gate they basically said well you can't
have a sustainable site if you have any
grass because there were no
recommendations for having grass in this
initiative so we uh put a class together
and did some work but what I can tell
you is we're up against quite a battle
both you know this
issue our own peers don't seem to
understand the role that these these
things play and we all know how this
governs a lot of the Landscapes that we
manage but in the end in difficult
Economic Times people tend to reduce
their commitment to Environmental
Quality and I think this is what makes
the cell we're doing with this U new
project even tougher so you have to make
Environmental Quality make economic
sense and that's exactly the approach we
took with this book so what does this
mean for lawn care well my career has
led me to this point where I believe
we've got to anticipate the effect that
climate change is is going to have on
managing the things that we're doing
we've got to position the lawn as a
resource it can't just be a beauty
contest it can't be I got to have a good
lawn because the Joneses down the block
have the good lawn and I want to have
the best lawn and we know from current
uh economic and sort of environmental
awareness surveys a lot of people still
feel like they got to have a good lawn
to keep up with their neighbors that's
not gone away and we must adopt a
progressive approach that balances cost
look and function and that is where we
get this wonderful resource now that
capitalizes on a lot of the things that
I've talked about in the past but now
really utilizes that that technology in
a a really meaningful way and you know
not like it's any great deal people make
iBooks but for us this is Leading Edge
in some of the Cooperative Extension
stuff that we see so without any further
Ado I'm going to transfer just two
minutes past sorry uh to my colleague
Lori spend a few more minutes on a few
more slides and then I'm going to show
you um sections of the of the iBook so
as as Frank um alluded to several
reasons why it was a top priority to to
think about lawn care for him and for me
equally um I was thinking about why
should I care about long care and with
our garden based learning program
certainly thinking about um how people
are environmental stewards is a top
priority so so that was an easy sell for
for me the the several other reasons are
that there are 2.8 million Acres of Home
lawns in New York state alone so what
people do with their lawns really makes
it matters so that was another
compelling region and also in Cornell
Cooperative Extension around the state
we have County offices and our County
offices uh report um they get phone
calls from the the public and they
report that 50% of their calls related
to uh gardening and Lawn Care 50% of
them are lawn care and so in some
counties that's 800 calls a year people
calling up and asking about what to some
some practice that relates to La care so
another compelling reason for me to be
involved and to for me to get the people
I work with the horiculture Educators
and the master Garder volunteers
involved and then um certainly Frank
relayed lots of research and new um
information that's coming out about
lawns and how Lawns are an environmental
asset as well as some new regulations he
didn't touch on some of the new
regulations but there's some new
regulations out there as well so another
reason why we want those Cooperative
Extension Educators and Master Gardener
volunteers to be aware of the best
management practices that are based on
research-based
information and then also Frank was
willing to to partner with me so
certainly I could pick other topics but
if I don't have a research um faculty
member who can help me develop that
resource with their expertise it's hard
to go forward so that's that's critical
the another critical thing that led us
in the direction of trying out an iBook
was that we did get funding from New
York State IPM to to help offset the
cost of developing this book so critical
reasons and so why did we decide that we
would
um try to create an i book and um we
wanted to main be maintain our current
be current and connected to where people
are getting information and this report
is actually from 2012 so I think it's
probably even more um the numbers are
higher now but a Pew Research Center
revealed that 43% 43% of Americans age
16 or older have read an ebook um as as
a source of pleasure or gathering
information so so people are
using ebooks and so maybe extension
could be
there those of you are laughing I know
why um and
um so uh so again Frank already showed
you this and the handout will connect
you to um to um iTunes so I did the
ebook in iTunes and there are many
logistical reasons why I did that the
main being my my knowledge of
programming is limited in iTunes iBook
author makes it somewhat accessible for
somebody with my knowledge to do it
there I will not tell you it was easy
but I couldn't do it uh in a different
format but they made it slightly easy so
in order to get to the iBook which can
only be viewed on a a Mac a smartphone
or I uh or a a Mac laptop that has iBook
on it so it has some l that way or an
iPad um but if you go into iTunes and
you search under long care you get like
this many books and um none of them are
based on backed with research-based
information and I'll tell you how
exciting some of them are um how much
time do you want to spend on lawns this
book on organic lawn care work it's only
250 pages long and then this one 100
lawn care tips um number five says think
about your lawn just before going going
to bed I'm pretty sure most of the
people we're trying to reach who are
taking care of their lawns are not going
to spend the time to shift through some
of these so really Our intention with
our our um iBook ebook is to make it
much more accessible to those who want
to spend a limited amount of time um
carrying thinking about their lawn so
really the average lawn person to really
maximize the number of people who will
actually look at the information and do
the right thing change their
behaviors so yeah you'll see that those
books essentially are PDFs they're PDFs
we can put PDFs up we actually an
extension know how to do that and um so
Craig can edit
um so but this iBook um I'll show you
some clips from it and the intention was
to keep the text limited and um you can
see it's actually only 45 pages long and
and if no one read be Beyond page 12
most people would be doing the right and
did what was in the first 12 Pages
they'd be doing the right thing so
beyond those first 12 pages are just
like bonuses for the people who are
geeking out about their lawns and um and
we do have a section where we ask people
to that actually go to a qual trek
survey and they can give us feedback on
what they they get behaviors they might
have changed by reading the book so we
have that sort of built into the book a
little opportunity for feedback so so
this is sort of the layout of the book
and now
um I'm going to escape this and go try
to quickly go to um iBooks
here so if you download it you then open
up
iBook and it will actually come out
um it'll look a little different when
you first open it this was just the last
page I'm actually going to do it
slightly different so so you see what
happens when you open it
um so when you open it
up you get the really the last page that
you looked
at and then let me see if I
can I might have to keep it down for a
second I just wanted to show you the
table of contents and I'm going to go to
the thumbnails and and then I'm going to
go big
screen so um these this thumbnail is
just just shows you quickly what's in
the
book rough rough thing in the book and
um and it this is the first section here
four steps to success these are the
first actually only 10 pages because
there's two intro pages and um and so
I'm going to actually show you first the
intro movie the simple steps that we
were trying to get across to to uh
introduce people to really the most
important things they need need to do to
care for their lawn and so we have a
number of these videos all of them are
less than uh most of them are about a
minute long some are U the longest one
is three minutes but most of them are
quick and the whole
um the whole book really aims at being
uh an easy short read and friendly um
words not trying not to use any language
that that you know a typical um maybe
even eighth grader wouldn't wouldn't
already have that vocabulary so back to
the four steps this is these are the
four steps in which if they just did
these few things it would be terribly
exciting um and we would have a great
impact on on how Lawns are an
environmental asset and they're Lawn
Care people are environmental
stewards so um I'm going to skip right
to make
adjustments so you can jump around
easily in in the book and down here you
can even flip back to whatever page you
previously were on and again uh make
adjustments we list uh keep the mower
blade sharp mow grass higher mols grass
clippings mow tree leaves in the fall
patch weaker bare spots and I'm going to
skip to the mow grass higher and I'm
going to see if I can I can um actually
I'm going to flip back I'm going to go
to sharpen your mower blade so with all
the videos as with the words in the book
most all the were saying do this um as
opposed to well you could do this or you
could do this um or this uh we
essentially went to these are not
necessarily Avid um gardeners who want
to know all this information and who
delve into and wants to make decisions
these are people who are like I have
this house I have this lawn what the
heck am I supposed to do and we're
saying just do this do this do this and
and just trying to uh address that
audience who who don't want all a whole
bunch of options this no no no what can
I do to do the right thing and so all of
the the videos really focus on on just
do it this
way right and and so as Frank mentioned
all of these videos were were were
filmed and and uh edited by
professionals so we didn't we didn't
make
these we might have um structured how
they would U come out but we didn't make
them so again I'm sort of going to flip
through the first 10 pages uh do less
skip
feeding that oh and I should also say
all of our images um so all of our
images we had to because it was it was
out there in I iTunes uh all of our
images had to have been um our images
but I also must tell you I found great
images on Flickr and if you go to those
that um allow you to use them with
recognition um got great images onl and
flicker I know everybody's looking for
those um and then uh so this is really
page 11 and I would this is also a very
short short video uh but this was that
was the sort of bulk of the content that
we that we want people to focus on and
you can always go back up to either the
thumbnails or the table of contents and
flip through the book some more I'll
just show you Advanced Care just to
highlight um what we have in Advanced
Care and Feeding which is what lots of
people think of fertiliz in as feeding
uh we consider that in the Advanced Care
um section it's not really part of that
F those first 11 pages that really
mostly you want people to use a sharp
mower blade and um if they everyone did
that um the fuel consumption that would
be saved um would be great and I will
show you again um even information about
insect pests and weeds is in the
advanced care I'm going to see if it'll
go to the insect section for
us
maybe oh just a little sluggish so in
the insect section we actually
throughout the book I have um a number
of galleries photo galleries which you
can embed in the book and so you can add
content that
way as well
as this interactive image and um
get will can flick on it and get some
additional
information and again you
can very easy to flip through the book
this
way people can quickly find something
that oh I wanted to know about
that and it and as I said all the way
back I have a place where you can share
feedback and that's where I want to
mention um that uh we haven't really
launched this book because we finished
it up and the lawn care season is a
little under the under the weather right
now so people aren't really thinking
about lawns but we plan to launch it
this spring and we've done a sort of a a
soft launch but we will fully launch it
and hopefully get some good um press and
some sending it out to uh those people
we want to to take a look at it and get
some feedback but even though we haven't
really sent it out to a wide selection
of people I have actually had people
click on the yes that this book was
helpful and and the exciting thing was
that the things that they say they were
going to change so that goes to two
questions and it asks if you're going to
change any behavior and three responses
I got was I'm going to change how I um
fertilize I'm going to remove the high
spots in my lawn so I don't scalp my
lawn and then um I'm going to stay on
keeping my mower blade sharp so already
the indications from those few people
are like okay they're getting it they're
getting the message because maybe we're
keeping it simple enough we're not
giving them too much information very
few people would sit through Frank's 20
brief minutes about long care and you
guys are very polite
and and so so we really Tred to sort of
entertain them as well as try to to
deliver that information and as far as
as next steps
go um I'm this is kind of the the
Bible for lawn care in our cooperative
exension
system I just wanted to go back to
acknowledgements and um and so uh I but
I have the opportunity to take this and
make easy updates you might see that
it's already version 1.1 because I
already found things that I needed to
update so it's easy enough for Frank to
feed me information and then I can make
updates in in the text and those people
who already downloaded the the book can
then um Can will get noticed that that
it's been updated so so that's that's
pretty pretty easy to do and what we can
also do is we have about seven videos in
there if we get get additional resources
we can change some of the the text to
add more videos that we didn't just
didn't have the resources to produce uh
any more than seven so um one of those
might be related to the the under what
circumstances should you be mulching
leaves or what conditions because there
are some municipalities who who thought
that leaf mulching requiring everyone to
mulch their leaves would be wonderful
way to save money
but there are circumstances under which
um they won't mulch well and people
won't like it so that one thing that
we're looking forward to in the future
as well as using this as the core the
core uh portion of the Master Gardener
volunteer training about long carees so
with that we have about five more
minutes maybe take some questions or
comments this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu