this is a production of Cornell
University thank you all for coming
today the title of my talk is
introgressing resistance to hempa mildo
into different genetic backgrounds I
know that some of you work with father
melus and there are 10,000 plant species
that are host to 650 father me so I'm
going to introduce the one that we are
working
with hemp PO mildo is the most prevalent
disease in indoor hemp cultivation and
it is caused by the biotrophic fungi
gisis and brochi it's an ice comis it it
grows on the leaves but you can also
find it growing on stems and
inflorescences and we also don't have
many fungicides that we could use that
are available to us mainly because they
are not on the fungicide lab
and now I want to tell you a story I
want us to go back to 2018
2019 and at that point farmers in New
York started trying to grow hemp outside
but there was not really like a history
of growing hemp here so which were the
cultiv war that are adapted to this
climate to the soil um to the latitude
so what Larry La did was get
a lot of cultivars different genetic
materials and they planted them in New
York in different sites and they
collected a bunch of data growth rate
flowering time and one of those rates
was disease severity to PO M so what I
want you to look at in this graph is
this cultiv over here that is f 58 that
has a zero% disease rating both in
Geneva and in itha and that is great we
are trying to breed plants and we see a
plant that doesn't get bother M so it's
this not resistance what is going on
here so what they did is they grabbed FL
58 they crossed it that is our resistant
parent they cross it with theal parent
that is DJ's CBD did the linkage mapping
and they ended up finding out that there
is a mutation in an MLL Gene and for
those people that have worked with BOS
mlos are a big thing for people that
haven't worked with mlos they stand for
mildo resistant Locus o and a mutation
or loss of function mutation in these
genes confer is durable recessive and
broad spectrum uh resistance durable we
want it because pathogens are mutating
all the time and we don't want it to
break resistant so this is not supposed
to happen with the this type of
resistance and then broad spectrum
because it's not race specific as it
happens with other major R genes but we
also know that it's not great because
there are some biotropic negative
effects in other PL species such as
reduced yield and quality I included a
representation of what this ano proin
would look like it has seven
transmembrane domains has an end termin
that if this is a the plasma membrane it
would be in the extracellular part and
the C terminal would be uh towards the
cytoplasm we also know that there are
many mlo genes in Plants uh genomes and
that they participate in different plant
processes such as reproduction root they
thigmotropism symbiotic fungal
colonization and why we're here today
father M infections so as there are so
many of these genes in plant genomes
they are divided in seven clades Glade
five are the ones that are related to
powder M
infection and you usually need to mutate
all of them to have a resistant
phenotype in the plant
so you're going to be thinking now now
we know what mlos are and there I said
before that FL 58 had a mutation in the
mlo so it turns out that it has an
approximately 6.8 KV insertion between
the exons 10 and 11 and that causes uh
improper mRNA spacing and that results
in a premature stop
colon but you're going to say I'm I'm
only talking about one and I just said
that plants have can have many of them
so how many mls's are in the Cannabis
attiva genome okay for us there is a
study published in
2021 and this is a long graph but I only
want you to look at the two clade five
mlos in the canis sativa
genome uh csmlo1 is the one I was
talking about that is in chromosome one
this uh is where the mutation is
insertion and csm4 that we don't really
know much about it so with the
information that I just gave you I
propose four research questions the
first one is if you are homozygous for
the f508 version of the
csm1 are you always going to be
susceptible what happens in other
backgrounds my second question is are
there other sources of resistance in
other genetic backgrounds and if there
are are they going to interact with this
Gene third question is
um are we going to start seeing negative
OT Tropic effects in other genetic
backgrounds we're not seeing them in F
58 but it doesn't mean that we're not
going to see them if we introgress this
gene into other
backgrounds and my question number four
is are we going to see other Al from the
other clade 5 csmo Gene that are going
to recover a susceptible phenotype in a
homoy CSM
f58 um
plant for the sake of time I'm not going
to talk about all of them I'm only going
to focus on the first one and the
hypothesis is that if you're homoy for
the AL you're going to be resistant to
powder and what am I doing to answer
this question or test this hypothesis so
the first thing that I did was generate
a list with genotypes that have the so
the first one in this list is f 58 we've
been talking about is homoy for that
version and then we had two other uh
genotypes 1910 1067 and yvg they are
both females and high cannabinoid
backgrounds they are both hetus and they
are susceptible to powder
mildo white CVG I have to say it's very
susceptible to hand poow M and it is so
susceptible that that is the genotype
that we use to maintain the single conal
isoline that we
have and
then I said that I wanted to introgress
it into different genetic backgrounds so
I made a list of uh cultur or genotypes
that we had access to that capture
genetic variation so there are different
types of materials that belong to
different Market classes different Sexes
what they have in common is that they
are all susceptible to gomis and brocha
and that they are homos wild type or
almost homos wild type so I have my list
one my list two and what do I do I just
grw some right how am I approaching this
I put the two plants that I want to
cross into one pot then I put a cage on
top of them and on top of the cage I put
a poing
exclusion uh bag and then I take those
plants into our room that has the
irrigation system installed and uh that
room is in flowering inductive
conditions that means like is in short
days and we let them
cross so going back to the list that I
just showed you I've done most of the
crosses at during this winter I had um
52 crosses at the same time not all of
them worked most of them um the ones
that
are female M by female a bit more tricky
but what I'm planning to do is I'm
planning to plant the seeds in the field
this summer and evaluate their
susceptibility to handw M then I'm going
to choose plants to self or to cross
then I'm going to with those seeds I'm
going to plant them in the field next
year evaluate their susceptibility and
then compare the phenotype and the
genotype Bas it just right now in the
CSM one Al but we can add things later
as usually
happens
um and uh that is my plan for for the
summer with this I want to thank the
Larry smartlav my committee members and
the funding support and thank you for
coming and listening to
me that's do you have any questions I
hope I was uh I didn't miss things yeah
how do the female by female Cress work
or don't work yeah so the question was
uh how do the female by female crosses
work so it
is hemp is quite plastic so you can
spray the female plant that you want uh
to start producing male flowers with SCS
silver thyo sulfate and after a couple
applications it's going to start
generating m flowers and those uh male
flowers produce
pollen when it
highly the problem with the high
cannabinoid plants is that they are
highly inbred and they are starting to
show um some problems when it comes to
generating viable pollen so they can
produce a lot of flowers and you're
happy and you think you're going to have
a lot of seeds and then you don't really
have that
many just to make sure that I got it so
the FL 58 it has a loss of function
mutation and that that leads it to have
resistance
yeah that's the hypothesis so uh what
the linkage mapping that was um George
and Ali paper they identified a marker
their most significant marker was close
to the csml gene it's in around
chromosome in chromosome one around
position 21 and that is a closest Gene
that um explains the phenotype that
we're seeing if it's mutated and it's
also being expressed but it is um it is
being transcri transcribed so there is
an M an MR
RNA but if I go
back it will cut the the protein around
here and this part the C terminal binds
to culin and it's supposed to be
important for its function and it does
plus sense calcium um so we think that
yes it is a loss of mutation of function
mutation yeah I'm great presentation I'm
curious when you're going to inoculate
your field trials at like what stage and
are you looking to score for like adult
plant resistance or in
seedings thank you for that
question so in which the question was in
which state uh do I inoculate and the
yeah and when at what stage you gonna
screen for the disease unti and screen
so it does depend if I do it just in the
field I um I just depend on when we can
put the plants in the field and that I
would let them grow a bit and then
inoculate we don't I know that there is
different
susceptibility in um different
developmental stages in other plant
species we don't really know much about
it in hemp that is something I want to
consider yes um and when I did uh
Greenhouse inoculation last month I am
just depending on how much space they
have and uh they grow so fast then that
uh when I inoculated them like three
weeks after I sewed the seeds were like
this and then um right now they are
taller than
me so yes
thank
you awesome hello everyone um my name is
Beal and as Lou said I'm also a member
of the Smart Lab um I'm going to be
talking today about uh fiber hemp so
towards better fiber quality so we're
trying to characterize hemp fiber in
diverse germ plasm and one thing to know
is what hemp fiber even looks like if
you haven't seen hemp plant after it's
been reded so this is the process where
you let um the natural microbes that
exist in the field kind of break down
all the pectins that are holding
everything together and then it becomes
very easy to separate the fibers and
you'll get these two types of fibers so
you get vast fibers these are these long
fibers here they're high in cellulose
they're low in ligin and they have a
very high tensil strength so these vast
fibers are the flum tissue uh and you
also have the inner Woody core of the
hemp plant so that's called The Herd
this is short fibers they're higher in
ligman and they have a lower tensil
strength so this is the xylem of the
plant these fibers have many different
uses um they can be used as bedding for
animals The Herd is very absorbent you
can make textiles out of them so this is
an example of something you could go out
and buy now this is patagonia's um line
of hemp clothing which is very durable
and that's how it's marketed uh you can
also so make paper out of it of course
and people have been using hemp for a
very long time for these sorts of
applications but one of the newer
applications is in Composite Materials
so this is an example of BMW who is
showing off their car door that they
made out of natural fibers including
hemp um and fun fact this is actually
not a very new thing because Henry Ford
back in the early 1940s had a car that
was nicknamed the soybean car where he
used natural fibers that were rumored to
be soy um in a resin to create these
plastic panels on the outside of the car
and the goal was to make the car lighter
because back then they were using steel
so this isn't a entirely New Concept but
there is a renewed interest now in
sustainability and getting away from
petroleum based products and using more
renewable materials so this is an
interest in the automotive and
potentially Aerospace um industry to use
composite materials using hemp
so some of the objectives of this
project are Guided by this um concept
that there are many uses for fibers so
um and also that we we don't exactly
know what um the variability that we
have in hempt to work with to try to
breed for better fiber quality so we
wanted to characterize a diverse set of
fiber varieties um for fiber quality and
also of course fiber yield yield is
always very important and identify the
variation in these traits among the
different varieties so here um you can
see a list of 12 cultivars that we
identified as um you know representing a
a broad range of the type of fiber hemp
that is currently being grown in the US
so we have ital um Italian and French
varieties so these are the European
varieties that have been bred for a very
long time for you know a fiber purposes
um there's a mix of dious and manous
varieties almost all the French
varieties are manous uh and then you
also have these um Asian Chinese
background um varieties so there are is
an increasing interest in the US of
growing these they're very vigorous and
um perhaps they are better suited to
lower
latitudes and um so we're including
these and you'll notice also that we
have this here Ursa Alta so this is a
new variety that is coming out of the
smart program that we're releasing so uh
it's uh will be interesting to see how
this Stacks up to other um varieties or
some of these Chinese varieties could be
considered more land
races so some of the approaches that
we're taking to characterizing these uh
the fiber in these plants is a
histological approach so taking very
thin cross-sections using a microtom and
um looking at the fiber bundles under a
microscope we're also doing cell wall
component analysis so looking at the
different um sugars that are in the cell
walls like cellulose or Manos or um
different components that could be
making up cellulose or hemicellulose or
pectins so we also want to um get a
little bit more uh quantitative and
detailed view that's a bit more High
throughput than doing microscopy uh so
this is the thermog gometric analysis so
this can tell you the different
components that are in the whole M
tissue so you can do whole stem or you
could do just fibers um that will give
you the total amount of cellulose how
cellulose lignan Ash content so um that
is important for knowing you know what
your cellulose yield is in the plant um
we also have fiber strength testing so
that's an important you know
specification if you're making Composite
Materials you want to know how strong it
is you know hemp is you know has been
long time used as a very high tensil
strength material for you know ropes in
the um for ships and stuff but is there
variation in this or is it correlated to
other traits that we can select on we
also of course want yield we want high
fiber yield so we have to go through the
process of decortication so that's after
I said you readed the stems you allow
the microbes to break down pectins and
then you can basically strip off the
fibers using a a decortication
machine so um today I'm mainly going to
talk about this histological analysis
that I did this is a picture that um I
took I don't know if the lights can dim
a little bit in here see it
better yeah so here you can see this is
this is the bass fiber bundle that's
primary flum there and um hemp has a lot
of flm fibers so uh it for this analysis
um in 2022 there were small plot um
small plots were grown of these 12
cultivar by my labmate Luis monserate
and then uh there were four biological
replicates of each cultivar and we
harvested um a one meter Square plot
that those plants were used for will be
used for the uh yield analysis and then
also the thermogravimetric analysis and
at the same time we harvested for
individual plants and collected the
middle internodes and those middle
internodes were used for this
histological analysis and also the cell
wall component analysis so um this
cross-section is 10 microns thick I used
a cryomicrotome so these were embedded
into um uh a material that if you know
you freeze it very quickly you don't
have to go through the process of like
paraffin embedding is much quicker um
and then I imaged three different fiber
bundles uh per replicate and then
Quantified some different fiber fiber
bundle and fiber cell um
Dimensions so I did this U measuring
these dimensions in Fiji uh so so you
can you know draw circles around things
and it measures them when you give it a
scale so some of the the results that
I've gotten so far is that there is
differences in the fiber bundle area
this is an example again of a fiber
bundle and um we see um significant
differences within um the cultivar that
we're testing uh the highest being FIB
79 which is you know papora is actually
being a very good fiber variety that has
very good fiber quality so that's
interesting to see um also uh this is
this Cult of our is a little bit
interesting Han cold you might want to
remember that so that has very low fiber
bundle
area but we don't see any significant
differences in the number of sell per
fiber bundle area although there is a
numerical difference in a trend so
perhaps I just don't have enough power
to see that in this
study we also see differences in fiber
cell cross-section area so uh again H
cold came up small fiber cells so it's
interesting that that Tren holds and
fiber 79 larger fiber cells it had
larger fiber bundles so interesting um
another uh uh thing that is an important
aspect of fibers is of natural fibers is
the paracity so if you're using hemp for
like insulation or something this can
affect how well of an insulator it is
and also is indicative of how um filled
the the fiber cells are so um these
plants were all harvested at uh 50%
flowering which is isn't what a lot of
people use to harvest fireberd as an
indication of when the plant is mature
but hasn't become too lignified yet um
but the paracity is this ratio of the
Lumen that's the empty kind of portion
inside the fiber cell to the total cell
surface area so it basically tells you
how open and empty that cell is um and
then again uh numerically honold
is down lower so it's interesting to see
some of these varieties that have you
know certain Trends towards higher or
lower values within the things that I'm
measuring here we also saw some
differences in cell wall thickness um
which is another um important thing this
may correlate with how strong the fibers
are um I'll tell you a little bit more
later about how we're trying to test the
fiber strength in these um and then I'm
going to move on here and talk a little
bit about the cell wall um analysis this
was done by even Sorenson in the Rose
lab so this is a diagram here showing
you what a cell wall looks like so
there's primary cell walls there's
secondary cell walls one differentiating
thing between them is that primary cells
you can see here have these pectin that
are gluing everything together and then
you have um ligin in the secondary cell
walls and I said earlier that um the
bass fiber is low in lien because the
the main component of the bass fiber
that we're harvesting is the primary
flum not the secondary flum although
it's there so we're we're hopefully
decreasing Ling because for many
applications you don't want a lignified
fiber so in this analysis um we're using
this instrument it's a high performance
andon exchange chromatography with pulse
Amper metric detection it's a very long
name um and um this can measure a number
of different sugars that are components
of the cell wall some of them are very
um Cut and Clear what they are so like
cellulose but then all these other you
know sugars can be components of
multiple things or at least some of them
can be components of multip things so um
I think you can see here that uh xylos
can be a component of hemicellulose or
of pectin so it's you can't always quite
tell that if it's high in one sugar then
it's definitely oh it has more pectin um
but it gives you an
idea so we did see differences in uh
fiber
cellulose uh which is an important thing
because cellulose is one of the more
important things in fiber yield and
hemp and then then we also saw
differences in galactonic acid so
galactonic acid is uh only in pectin in
the an in the um diagram that I showed
you here so it's not one of those that's
like oh it could be hemos it could be
pectin this is more an indicative that
if it's high in galacturonic acid then
it's high in pectin so um that might
have implications for how easy it is to
um break up those tissues and how easy
it is to decorticate after reading so we
might want to select for a lower pecum
we haven't um done the I haven't
evaluated the Doric ability yet so we'll
see if those
correlate we also saw differences in
fiber galactose but galactose can be
found in hemicellulose or pectin so um
that one is a little bit more
ambiguous and also um arabos which again
can be found in hellos and pectins
but interesting again on cold pops up
very low in arabos so
interesting so here's a correlation of
all of these things that I measured just
to see if um they are um cor with each
other and I'm only showing here ones
that were
significantly um correlated so
unfortunately all of the correlations
with cellus were not significant which
is something I'd be interested in
although it did have a positive
correlation with the fiber bundle area
area of 0.5 but I don't think we had
enough power here to um maybe see if
that was
significant um I uh also will want to uh
look at the the strength and see if
that's correlated with like the cell
wall thickness so we have this
instrument called an instron basically
you can like clip a fiber to either one
of these um little clamps and then it
pulls on it until the fiber breaks so
you can see a graph that looks like this
and where each one of those little
triangles are that's where when the
fiber broke basically so um the trouble
is though that it's hard to get a single
fiber with him if you just keep pulling
the fibers you keep splitting them and
to use a machine like this you want to
kind of use a single fiber and also you
need to standardize by the fiber's
diameter and measuring a fiber's
diameter is actually not that easy so
um some of the the takeaways that I um
found with the work that I've done so
far in this project is that we did see
some differences in some of the um fiber
bundle and fiber cell Dimensions um by
cultivar uh we didn't see uh different
so I actually forgot to say that the
results that I was showing with the cell
wall composition those were for um just
the fiber when we looked at the whole
stem level there were no significant
differences but when you peeled off just
the fiber um and ran that analysis then
we saw differences so the isolated
fibers did have compositional
differences so some of the next steps um
I'm want to do the thermogravimetric
analysis um to evaluate the ligo um
cellulosic composition we also need to
decorticate these reded stems to
evaluate the fiber yield um and then we
want to identify more instrumentation
that could be used for fiber analysis so
is the instron the best instrument to
this you know there are some other um
you know uh in down in uh North Carolina
State I think they have a very big uh
fiber and textile college and they have
some like scanners that you can use to
get the the diameter of fibers and some
other
instrumentation uh I also want to
develop some more High through print
methods for characterizing this because
actually doing hystological work is
takes a very long time and there a lot
of materials and a lot of work so is it
possible that we could in the field just
use um like a a 3D printed microtone to
take thicker SL sections and then stain
them with like a non-fluorescent stain
that stains um lignan and cellulose and
just take a picture with a camera to get
a rough idea of the area of the uh fiber
that has been done in some other cops
like switch grass so is that something
we can try and hemp hemp is actually
very hard to cut into into the Sim so I
don't know how that would work even
using a razor blade When I Was preparing
my samples it was very difficult so um
we'll see if that could work in him I
want to say um thank you to everyone in
my lab the Smart Lab and the rose lab
thank you to my special committee uh
Jason Londo Moira shean Joselyn Rose and
then also our funding sources so we're
funded by New York State a um a and
Market the New York State Office of
cannabis management and then also I was
funded this last year on an EA ship so
extension and Outreach through the
Cornell agratech
program um also if you want to learn
more about the work that Cornell is
doing in help you can go to this link
here any
[Music]
questions oh
yes thank you for that it was really
interesting your first slide around uses
how do you work with industry Partners
or material scientist techology just to
kind of Define what good quality fiber
is for specific uses just how you
interact yeah it is difficult we do have
industry partners and um one of the
things I've learned is that some uses uh
the specifications for the fibers is
highly regulated so like in the
automobile and Aerospace industry the
fibers that they can use have to meet
certain
specifications and um they it can be
hard to switch new materials because you
know they they have very strict
specifications and they also really need
uniformity so not just high quality but
they can't have variation in the um the
materials that they're using to create
their composits so it it can be um a
little difficult I even heard from one
industry member they would rather have a
lower fiber quality but consistent and
uniform than high fiber quality but if
it wasn't uniform so can be
tricky yes um in general with fibers
does ttile
strength is it proportional to the
cross-section and and if so could you
use that like could you could you
instead of measuring the cross-section
could you just weigh the fibers and and
get tensile string by weight uh so the
question is um is the weight of the
fibers correlated with the tensil
strength um the
weight I think that the crosssection
could be but it also depends on the
Lumin area
and um the weight I think that would
maybe not work because again as I saying
it's hard to get an individual fiber so
uh I don't have a picture here of what
it looks like when you decorticate
although it kind of let's go
back oh there all of the the fiber
that's um those long fibers that come
out the stem it it kind of basically
looks like that when it's coming out of
the decorticator uh without the Herd on
it so to get an individual fiber and
weigh it and then compare that to
another individual fiber I don't know if
you could really do that although it
might be correlated with
strength thank
you yes was looking the you had chicken
uh vetting down there is that the likely
to be a big market for that because
actually I I know they trying to go with
corn Stover and miscanthus are also
going for those that market and there
seems like there be a lot more of that
line around that
yeah so this is more of like using a
byproduct so we don't for a lot of
applications you don't use the herd or
even if you're growing High canabo hemp
like you don't harvest the stock for
anything usable so is there something
else you can use it for the only problem
with using something like high
cannabinoid hemp for application like
that is that it can smell like hemp so
if for a farmer maybe they don't care as
much but for if you're just a backyard
chicken keeper maybe you don't want your
whole coup to smell like hemp I I in my
personal experience the the fiber uh
varieties and grain varieties don't
smell as strongly of that kind of hempy
turpenoid smell but they still have't
head
smell oh question on Zoom uh let see in
the chat um are you familiar with the
papers of K asua measuring fiber
strength in linam no I am not in fact I
don't actually know oh
linum that Flex okay
uh no I'm not familiar with that exact
paper but I will look it
up yes
yes can imagine
compx
soing expore some
collaboration science Coles to see how
they measure construction material
strength or even the car strength
yeah so here um so uh star was asking
about uh different collaborations we can
have with material scientists about um
the material strengths and how to
measure it and specifications that are
needed for the different applications um
and we definitely are looking at that so
actually the Cornell has the um College
of human ecology here and they do a lot
of work with textile fibers and so um we
have been in contact with them about the
um some of the methods using and then
also with um NC State as I said they
have a very large um fiber uh program
and then also the um USDA AR they are
working on um they just started working
on fiber quality um standards for hemp
so they are they have you know um very
robust standards for cotton but no such
thing exists for hemp of standardizing
what are the what are the things we
measure and how we measure them and um
so that is currently being worked on at
the
USDA if there are no more questions
thank
you this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu