This is a production of Cornell
University. Okay, thank you so much for
such a nice introduction. Um, I'm really
happy to give a talk and talk a little
bit more about both my research and the
phenocite. Uh, and hopefully I get to
convince you all to come and use our
fantastic phenotyping facility more. Uh,
because we do have space and we do have,
you know, availability for for for
phenotyping all of your plants.
So as you probably are aware the world
is experiencing crisises of all kinds
and uh agriculture in in particular
let's focus on the crisis that we can
actually know something about and do
something about. So uh you can see all
kinds of crisis including pollution,
deforestation, erosion, things like
that. I don't really know too much about
soil which is weird for a root biologist
but um yeah uh but what I do know quite
a lot about is water stress. So you've
got and the blue dots are representing
regions that are affected by water
stress. So you've got either too much
water, too little water or the wrong
kind of water. And that's the case in
salt stress. So what we can do about it
as plant biologists with our talents,
our skills, our knowledge, we can
diversify the agriculture. So don't be
fooled by my Photoshop skills. Here is a
desert rose that is native to an island
off the coast of Yemen in Satra, which
is here. Very desert-like environment.
And we can learn about from those
extreme extreme plants, how are they
dealing with those extreme environments
and maybe include that in our species
that we like to eat like tomatoes. Or we
can look at the species that are very
closely related to the species that we
already like to eat uh and look at the
intrapecific variation. So within the
species and that's that's really the
approach that my lab has been taking to
really look at the wild relatives to uh
to common to to crops that we like to
eat um and uh and learn from them
because those species haven't been
pampered in the greenhouse, haven't been
pampered by the breeders. Uh so they
really had to fend for themselves. So
let's learn from that. And so as as Jan
already mentioned, so we're we're
working on a quite a variety of species.
Arabidopsis is still a workhorse in the
lab because it's just an easy plant to
work with and and validate some of our
things. Uh we're also working on the
wild tomato which is a very close
relative to cultivated tomatoes, salan
pimpleium. So that's this guy over here.
We also have been working on peppery
beans. Uh temporary bean is a close
relative to uh common beans. It's a
fasciola species. It's native to
southwest of the US and northern Mexico.
So another very dry environment and it
has been used by native communities uh
for for for centuries right now. Uh
we've got natural diversity panel
established for that that we have we
have sequenced. I'm not really going to
talk too much about that. The other
species um that we're also investigating
is cowpie. So cowpi is native to
subsaharan Africa where it has been you
know a great resource for many
subsistence farmers that don't have
access to irrigation don't have access
to a lot of fertilization and it's
really thriving there and the really
cool thing about comparing those two
species together temporary bean it's
fasiolus aquitifolius if you know any
Latin like not me um you can you can say
like okay so actifolius is really
because the leaf the the the needle like
leaf right Um, so temporary bean, it has
those very, very narrow leaves. Like, no
wonder you're drought tolerant because
you have hardly any leaves. Cowpie, on
the other hand, has leaves as big as my
head. So, it's really interesting that
both of those species have drought
tolerance, but probably the mechanism or
their strategy of dealing with drought
stress is very, very different. And at
the beginning when I was starting a lab,
I'm like, okay, I'm going to screen all
of those species for drought tolerance
and see which genes are common between
them. And now I'm like, I cannot do that
because it's a stupid idea because all
of those different populations are very
different. So cowpi, we're really
screening a population of domesticated
species. Pepper bean, we've got a mix of
domesticated and wild accessions. salon
pimpleum as far as I'm aware except
maybe for joy for an egg nobody has
domesticated pimpinelogum yet uh so
we're really dealing with a variety of
different populations and their nature
so of course we're not going to find the
same genetic signals it's already hard
to find to reproduce giwas between two
different greenh houses so let alone
between the species but in the end I'm
like well it's might be not the best
idea to look for commonalities of
drought stress resistance but diversity
and that's a that's a hot work hot word
in the in the recent recent climate but
diversity of mechanisms and strategies
uh of of dealing with drought stress
might be actually even better because if
I I have my own ways of dealing with
stress before the presentation and maybe
Jim will have a different strategy of
dealing with stress and if we're kind of
exchanging those strategies between each
other maybe we can get even more relaxed
and even more chill because I know that
Jim is a great presenter. Um so um so
similarly with drought stress maybe by
combining different strategies exhibited
by different plants we can actually get
like super drought tolerant plants or
breed plants for different drought
scenarios because droughts in in Ithaca
is very different compared to drought in
Arizona or drought in Australia. Right?
So before I go into more detail, I'm
really going to focus a little bit on
the discovery pipeline that we're using.
So we're really looking at the starting
with the trait identification. So you
have a whole phenotype of a plant and
you can study all kinds of things. The
longer you look at the plant, the more
things that you can measure, you can
think of. The trick is for us is that
that specific trait need to have some
kind of heritability because we are
using forward genetics. If there's no
heritability to it, maybe genetics is
not the best way of studying it. Maybe
metab biochemistry or transcrytoics is
is the best way to do that. But for us,
we're really relying on genetic. Uh so
we're looking at heritability. The other
thing that a lot of geneticists are not
a big fan of is we're looking at how
that trait is how how that trait is
plastic in response to stress. So a lot
of the research that has been done on
that has been already done on genetics
of stress resilience has been done on
you know genes that are like traits that
are not necessarily changing throughout
the environment and there was a very
good reason for that because you want
your corn to be growing very well in the
field in Ithaca as well as it's growing
in the field in Geneva as well as in
Pennsylvania and everywhere else in the
world. So you want something that has
really really high heritability. But
we're missing on the things that the
plants are incredibly plastic. We know
that if you grow plants in different day
length, they start to develop different
number of leaves. The leaf size might
change a little bit. The number of
flatter roots is changing constantly
depending on the water availability. So
we're really interested in like okay
what are the traits that are showing
some plasticity and and that's a part of
like an experience of working with GW
was we really want to have as atomic
value of a trait as possible and that's
why we're working with the fiends. So
fiend to phenotype is the same as gene
to genotype, right? So fi is like a
dissected component of of your
phenotype. And if you think about like
okay well if I study drought stress
tolerance and I just study survival
survival is extremely complex trait
because it depends on how deep are your
root grows how what is your water use
efficiency how big is your shoot toroot
ratio uh what is your growth rate
maintenance all this stuff are you
slowing down as soon as you're like
thinking like okay I've got I'm
experiencing drought I need to stop for
a second and think and adjust and then
keep on growing or am I just like
insensitive to drought and keep on
growing and then I grow myself to death
really. Um so we're trying to dissect
the phenotype into as many molecular
like as many components that are as as
easy as possible to describe with a
number and hopefully by doing that we're
increasing the heritability. So if you
think about like the survival, the
heritability of survival, it's hard to
measure. Um but heritability of growth
in one week after germination, well
that's that's already increasing, right?
And the growth rate is already a
complicated trait and you can divide it
even further, right? So then okay, I
spend a lot of time on that. Now now
that we've got a lot the trait
identified of interest, we're going to
do a population screening. We're doing
phenotyping and forward genetics. And
then only once we are at the level of
gene of interest, we're we're doing a
study. We're validating it using reverse
genetics, we're identifying what is the
molecular context because some of the
genes might not be conserved in all of
the species, but the molecular context
in which they are as they are acting
might be easily translatable across
across different varieties of species
that we like to eat. And also at this
level, we're really going to look at
like what is the relationship between my
trait of interest caused by one by by
that one gene and the overall plant
performance. We're not looking at the
correlations or relationship at the
level of natural diversity panel because
those plants that are different in
number of lateral roots, number of
branches, they are also very different
in their root physiology and morphology
and pollen development and stuff like
that. So if I'm harvesting all of the
diversity that is really related to the
root system architecture, why should I
be ignoring all of the diversity that is
happening in the in the reproductive
development, right? So I should be
cognizant about that and looking at the
relationship between that at the natural
diversity panel might not be the best
idea. If you've got maybe a biparental
population, that's a very different
conversation. All right. So as Jan told
you, I I already started my kind of
research in in stress induced changes in
plant architecture really looking at
arabidopsis because that's a well-
domesticated species in the lab. Um and
really we we're asking like okay so when
I grow my plants in the increasing
concentration of salt stress my plants
are getting smaller but are they growing
different is just smaller like and how
how are we going to tell if it's just
slower and smaller or is it a
difference? So what we have done is we
really dissected the root system
architecture in three components. So
you've got a speed at which your main
route is growing, a speed at which the
lateral roots are popping up, and the
speed at which the lateral roots are
growing. So now we're using the same
functions for all of the three
components. If all of my functions are
decreasing by
50% under stress, it means root system
architecture is not changed. It's just
really slower. But if one of my
functions is decreased by 20% and the
other one is decreased by 80%, it's like
ah okay the stress is really actively
reprogramming my my plant architecture
my root system architecture because the
plant is actively choosing to put more
biomass in their lateral roots compared
to the main root.
So those models were the basis of um the
whole screen of the natural diversity
panel back then that we had in uh in
Arabidopsis. Right now the natural
diversity pan of arabidopsis is extended
uh beyond very eurosentric population.
So we have collected some accessions
from Africa, Saudi Arabia as well and um
and and and uh greater Asia. Uh we have
also developed this uh screen to look
because root system architecture we're
very proud bunch of people because we're
working on the hidden half but it's
still a half of the plant. So um when I
was doing my postoc in in cow mark was
Mark asked me like well what happens to
the roottoshoot ratio under salt stress
and so we developed this little tool
that you can quantify the shoot size and
the root size from your augur plate
images and we realized that okay that
the the rootsto ratio unlike under
drought stress under salt it just gets
disregulated we identify a gene that is
causal for that and that paper just got
published so yay and Mariam a posuck in
my lab really made the the final strides
in that in that work. But today I really
want to focus on uh pimpleium. So
pimpleium is a wild tomato. Here you can
see a plant of pimpleium growing in the
uh high throughput phenotyping facility
in Australia. So we are working with
approximately 220 accession of pimpinary
volume that were that were collected
around the west coast of South America
and some of the Galapagos Islands. Um
they're important source of genetic
variation. Their native range is really
varying because you've got regions that
are called the llamas uh which are those
fog deserts. So there's hardly any rain
and really the only only the fog is
coming in there but then some of those
excessions were collected around the
river beds where you know it's not
exactly like limited in water. Uh so we
thought okay there is a really great
great variety of environments that those
excessions were collected with. uh so we
have already screened them back in cow
in the field uh in for for control and
salt stress and in the plant accelerator
in Australia and that work has also been
published last year. So me being me I'm
like let's have a look at the root
system architecture. How are we doing
that? I just did that before I left
Saudi Arabia. So we're germinating the
plants under control conditions. We
transfer them for until for control and
sold plates and then we scan the plates
every single day. And then what we're
doing is not necessarily high throughput
phenotyping. I like to call it high
dedication phenotyping because there is
until now there was not really a way of
automating it fully. And every single
person that has been working with half
half automated pipelines also can
appreciate how much work half manual
work is because you can still you have
to still like draw all of those roots uh
and make sure that every single time
that they are crossing to manually
correct like which which route is what.
So we have done that together with Haley
Susman who was a technician in my lab we
have screened the entire diversity
panel.
All good. But with Mariam, we really
looked at the diversity panel in
slightly different way and we're like,
okay, are there any plants that are
showing exactly the opposite response to
stress? And we have identified two
lines. So we've got M248 which is uh
pimpleium and we thought well how about
we also look at some of the cultivated
lines. So we looked at the LA511 and as
you can see in here they're showing both
of them are grown on salt stress and
they're showing exactly the opposite
response. So one of
them is really investing in um producing
new lateral roots but those lateral
roots they are not really like very good
at growing. The other one on the other
hand is really very good in investing in
elongating the existing lateral roots
but there are not many new lateral roots
showing up. So we thought okay this is
really cool maybe we can do some
transcrytoics but which time points. So
for that purpose we grew our plants on
this device that is called spyro. It's
entirely well it's 3D printed and it
also has some aluminium profiles. Uh so
we can image we can we can take the
pictures of the plants growing on the
augur plates every hour.
So Mariam or me don't have to sit in the
lab and scan those plates every hour
which is as you can imagine quite
laborious and boring. Anyway, so we
collected all of those images. So now
we've got a time series that is
incredibly dense for both of our lines
under control conditions and salt
stress. So salt stress is red and you
can see that one of our lines is indeed
so in here we're looking at the lateral
root length individual length of latch
roots and you can see that one of them
is really suffering in their lateral
root elongation and the other one is
like salt what salt what's happening the
same happens if you calculate the root
growth rate so it's basically derived
from here and you can see that the root
growth rate again for one of them is
really suffering and for the other one
it's like well no I don't really see
much of a difference only at the later
stage we're starting to see difference.
Then we looked at the popping up of new
lateral roots and you have in the in in
here you also have the time after
transfer to different lines and you can
see in this line that all of the lateral
roots so the line that was really
struggling with the lateral root
elongation you can see that the lateral
roots are popping out throughout. If you
look at the average yeah it is a little
bit delayed but average in that specific
scenario is not super
informative. But if we look at the other
line, you can see that all of the
lateral roots that are indicated by the
red bars are clearly delayed in here. So
this superdetailed time point allowed us
to select time points before before we
we start see visual differences that we
then harvested for the for the RNA sec
experiments. What Mariam also did
because she has a training as a
reproductive biologist, so she's not
afraid of crossing plants. So she
crossed those two
lines and we looked at the root system
architecture of the F1 hybrid and I was
like well you know combining those two
traits it's just too good to be true and
yet those two strategies seem to be
complimentary because we don't see plant
with either more lateral roots or longer
lateral roots we see both of them. So
yes we can significantly improve
although both of those two lines
whenever we look at them in the field on
in the plant accelerator both of them
are growing pretty well we can still
improve on the pretty salt tolerant
accessions by combining their their
their uh their complimentary strategies
which I think it's really really cool so
what we did of course we did all of the
genomide association after um uh after
Mariam crossed the F1 we also grew them
out for F2 and Zangjin Feay helped us
with the B segregant analysis for all of
those BS and Leangu from Andrew's lab
helped us with the RNA sec experiment
and analyzing all of this data. So we
have the genes that are associated
through GWAS we've got the regions of
the chromosomes that are associated with
the book segregant and then we've got
individual gene expressions that are
differing between our lines. So what is
the overlap? So we found couple there
are some of the lines that or some of
the genes that are the
duf677 it's one of the strongest
candidates but the do the duf stands for
basically domain of unknown function so
thank you for calling it anything but we
cannot really like make too much sense
out of that. Two other things that we
found that are described as something is
this uh ethylene responsive
transcription factor to3 and ascorbate
peroxide. So basically vitamin C
peroxidase having something to do with u
reactive oxygen species. Couple of
months ago, uh Ron Mitler was visiting
um Cornell and Mariam went to his talk
and then she started, you know, sending
him messages like, "Hey, Ron, can you
image the roots of our tomatoes because
we think there is something going on
with reactive different reactive oxygen
species reaction." So Ron was like,
"Okay, cool. Send me the seeds." So we
sent him the seeds and um Santos did did
most of the experiments for growing the
seeds and basically here's an example of
how so they are really using a
visualization for the react for the
hydrogen peroxide um in live images. So
what we have seen and in here we've
got accession number one accession
number two in root and in shoot
wait yes okay this is complicated
figures so we've got accession number
one is having much more reactive oxygen
species accumulation quite early on in
the root while the accession number two
doesn't like nothing is happening in the
in the root whatsoever
But this one is having much more
reactions in the chute compared to the
root compared to the sorry other
accession. Right? So we have the ones
that that are if you don't have a
reaction in the root you will have a
reaction in the chute and it's not
necessarily sequential because in the
chute we see the signal building up much
quicker than we see in the root. So
there are the absolutely differences in
the reactive oxygen species accumulation
between those two lines. We're still
cloning the genes and we're hoping to
knock them out in both of the lives to
see what is the effect. Um, but this is
an intermediate result. Um, and then
what we also did is this is another
complicated graph. Uh, we also grew the
plants with ascorbate with and with
H2O2. So what we're seeing in here, so
let's have a look at the sold stress the
red dots and we've got the main root
growth r growth rate average lateral
root growth rate. So how how fast is the
main root growing? How fast are the
lateral roots growing? How f how how
quickly are new lateral roots popping
up? Right? So our c this cultivated one
is we've got okay lateral roots
elongation is suffering more than number
of lateral roots and in here we've got
an opposite pattern right so we've got
lateral roots keep on elongating but the
lateral root number is suffering right
cool so then when we add in here the
green one is we add asbate as soon as we
add ascbate this pattern is not really
changing much because the lateral roots
are still growing great. We get a little
bit more lateral roots popping up, but
in here, haha, we are reversing the
pattern. So, we are rescuing the lateral
roots and still grow faster. And then
whenever we add hydrogen peroxide into
the plates, we're kind of making
everything even worse. And this line,
for whatever reason, it's like, well,
I'm still fine because it's not probably
not related to ascorbate ascorbate
metabolism at all. And we also looked uh
on ion accumulation and we have noticed
that ascorbate addition of the ascorbate
is lowering the potassium to sodium
ratio. So potassium to sodium ratio is
important because typically under salt
stress potassium is out competing the
sodium. No other way around sodium is
out competing potassium. So the higher
that number is the worse the plant is
getting. So getting it lowered by
ascorbate is a great result and is
reflecting kind of the changes what's
what are happening in the root system
architecture. All right. So that's
that's where we at with our like
molecular biology following up finding
the genes. We also started to uh explore
how we can describe the root system
architectures using different metrics.
So when we were spending entire pandemic
looking at the roots and tracing them,
we started to observe like a very
distinct pattern. So you've got roots
that are really growing like a Christmas
tree or roots that are growing like a
telephone pole, a little bit droopier
telephone pole and a broomstick. So all
of the later roots are coming from from
the base. And in here you've got it's
really like a maze root. Like all of the
roots, they are very nicely spaced but
very definite length. we don't have that
diversity of the of the lateral root
length as we see in the in the Christmas
tree, right? So, we're like, well, this
is cool and I see it and I know when I
see it, but when I'm using my metrics of
lateral root number per plant, average
lateral root size, even the branch zone
size, I always have this one comparison
that is not significant. And I I know
that I should have like a number. How do
I describe that? And that's a never-
ending conundrum of anyone that is doing
phenotyping. I see it with my brain. How
do I translate it into a number? So I
was like, "Oh, maybe I can combine all
of those three numbers." Mathematical
modeling. And then Arjent Chandra Seca,
who is a good friend and a
mathematician, he's like, "Well, no, how
about we just calculate the Pareto front
optimality for those root system
architectures and then you've got all
nicely
separated things." Mac, great. Can you
explain what this PTO front optimality
is? I've got a number, but how does the
number work? So, Paretofront optimality
is really designed for um like
evaluating efficiency of infrastructures
in the cities. So, in here we've got a
subway network of my favorite city in
the world, Amsterdam. And you can see
that everyone you've got all of those
neighborhoods that are semi-affordable
to work with. everyone needs to go to
the central station and you've got all
of those hubs. Sometimes they're
crossing over. Okay, we can also think
about like that in a root system
architecture. So you've got the roots,
you've got all of the absorption
happening of nutrients and water.
Although if you talk to people that are
working on modeling of water and
nutrients, we still don't really know
how the root is absorbing water, which
is mind mindboggling for me. Anyways,
but let's assume that we are absorbing
majority of water nutrients in the with
the tips and here we've got big pipes
that are doing majority of the
transport. Okay, so we can think about
it as neighborhoods that need to get to
central
station. So we need to abstract it. So
abstracting the root, we've got a root
system architecture, but we can connect
all of our lateral roots in a very fast
way, in a very cheap way, and in some
intermediate solution. So basically what
partotront optimality is saying you
don't have one optimal solution for your
problem. You've got a front of optimal
solutions and you can see how far from
those optimal solutions you are right
and that gives you a
number. So um however there are couple
of couple of issues with the parto front
optimality. So right now we are assuming
that
conductivity and the cost of a lateral
root is exactly the same as for the main
route. So in here this is a very quick
experiment that I did for for for this
grand that we got is looking at the
number of vessels in the main route
compared to the lateral root and that's
that's the main pipes that are doing the
transport and you can see the blue
things there's huge difference in the
number and the surface of the vessels
that are doing the transport. So that's
already an assumption that is wrong that
we need to correct and also the number
of the the cortex layers and all of the
cells that needs to be not only built
but also maintained as the root system
architecture is growing. So right now
what we're doing is we're doing so Emily
and Trend have been really amazing in
collecting all of the root sections for
the main roots and the latter roots.
Those are the best pictures I could get.
It's very hard to kind of get them get
them really nice. And we're quantifying
basically all of the the vascule, the
surface area of the cortex, the
endodermis, epidermis, and the xylm
bundle sheet cells. And we can see that
between the lateral root and the main
root, there are tremendous differences.
And also there are differences in the
developmental stage as well. So your
bundles are very looking very different
at the root tip compared to the very
mature root. And at some point we also
are starting to have the secondary
growth which is specific to dicots. Uh
so right now together with Arjun and
Guiam Lo from from Belgium we are
integrating all of those physiologically
quite relevant features into our Pareto
front optimality metrics and then using
those adjusted models we're going to
recalculate everything for our entire
diversity panel and then use that to run
the genomide association and hopefully
we're going to learn a little bit more
like which genes are involved in um
optimal small root system architecture
or optimizing the cost or the transport
rate. The other thing that I want to
just briefly mention, so this is there's
a it's a happy news. Uh recently we have
been awarded together with a a bunch of
really amazing collaborators from from
BTI this FF grant. So we've got Sylvia
Restrepo, Jim Jovanoni, Julian Fay from
our tech technology transfer office. Uh
Gagan from um myiogenics and Zangjin
Feay is really like the the the the lead
brain in here. And basically what we're
going to do is we're going to screen the
wide tomato diversity panel for drought
stress tolerance. So Sylvia is going to
do that for for a bio for a for a biotic
stress. I'm really going to talk only
about the the drought because that's
that's what I know. So in here, so we so
far we only have focused on liopers and
pimpleium, but there is so many more
tomatoes. So that's what we want to
really screen like, okay, are there much
more cool diversity strategies for all
of those different things. So as you can
think about like drought is a complex
trait. If we just measure like, well, do
they survive or do they wilt? We're
again throwing a lot of a lot of
complexity into genetics. So how are we
going to dissect it? And dissection is
going through isolation of individual
feeds. So we're going to dissect it into
daily use of water, maintenance of
growth rate, plant health indices, and
photosynthetic efficiency. And that's a
combination of the tools that my lab has
developed as well as phenocite. So I
hope that this is just providing you an
overview of what are the tools that are
available and if you want to use some of
them just let us know and then we can
either borrow you some of our cool toys
because that's the best thing of like
having cool toys is sharing them or uh
we can we can help you with setting up
your experiment for the FIMO site. So
the first toy that was developed
actually by Olga Millinsky who is now a
PhD student in plant path uh but was an
amazing undergraduate student is this
device that's called Osmo. So Osmo is a
little Arduino. Uh it's a computer
that's costing $20 and we put that in a
box with an LED screen and it's
connected to a scale and a little water
pump. This is how it looks in real life.
So, we put all of the mess of the cables
in a box and we connect that to the
laptop. Basically, how it works is you
hardcode all of the reference data for
the weight of your plants onto the
Arduino. And then you have the plants
that are mixed with drought control and
you know that your control plants should
be watered to that specific reference
weight. Your drought should be watered
to let's say 100 grams less. Right? So
you put your plant pot number one and
it's already hardcoded that pot number
one is control. It says oh okay your
reference weight is below the ref like
your measured weight is below the
reference weight. Therefore I need to
activate the pump. Pump activated. Okay
fine. Measure the weight again. Okay.
Now the weight is above the reference
weight. Click this button and then I can
do the pot number two. And so it goes.
And if you connect this little device
into a Windowsbased laptop, h because it
doesn't work on anything else,
unfortunately, but it will also record
all of the weight before and after
watering, which gives you cheap but
dirty evapor transpiration data that you
can get. So this evapor transpiration
here I've got an example of cowpie
plants that we have exposed to control
and drought conditions and this is the
average evapo transpiration rate. uh we
can see that definitely under control
and drought stress we've got a decrease
and we also can see differences between
the individual genotypes in their in
their evapo transpiration. So again this
is a very dirty trait but it's helping
us provide to all of the plants exactly
the same drought stress treatment and
gets us data that is kind of for free.
Then we're going into the maintenance of
the growth rate. So for this
um we've got uh we have built something
that's called the pheno cage. So as long
as you're not working with arabidopsis
turns out that plants have 3D
architecture and you kind of have to
like image them from all sides. So what
we did is we did exactly that. So we're
putting a plant by hand on this little
display rotating ring that we bought off
Amazon and it's meant for displaying
jewelry in the shop. But it's also doing
a great job at displaying plants in the
growth chamber. So this is the picture
how the plant looks like. And again this
is an example of the cowpie because the
technician that is starting the the the
work on the FFIR started this week. Um
so this uh the plant is uh is turning
and we're taking seven consecutive
images and we're doing it every every
three days or so and then afterwards
we're analyzing the images because we've
got a nice white background. we can
quite easily separate the planned bits
from the background bits and have that
as a projected shoot area. So the number
is totally artificial but it can it does
give you the increase in the size of the
plants throughout the time in a
non-destructive way and you can
absolutely differentiate again the
control is blue here the drought is red
you can differentiate between your
control grown plants and drought stress
grown plants based on this data we can
calculate the growth rate throughout the
experiments for each of the genotypes
which we have done in here and again
this is for copy and you can see like
okay so here I've But overall my
population kind of decreased by 50%. But
I can also do it genotype specific and I
can say okay which genotypes are
performing relatively well. So close to
one or some of them are above one which
are suspicious. Um but uh and which of
my genotypes are extremely tolerant and
this whole setup in general is costing
like $200 to build up. So I built it up
before we had a big fancy phenotyping
facility set up and because we needed to
collect some data but uh it's a very
it's a very cost-effective way of
getting the data out of your of your
natural diversity panel and identifying
which genotypes are of high high
interest. Right? Then we're getting to
fancy stuff. So screening for plant
health indices. So we're uh we're able
with phenocytes. So this is this is
using our fancy uh cool uh phenotyping
facility at the BTI. So we're able to
using a
multi-spectral camera. We are able to uh
isolate the NDVI indices as well as
anttosyin and chlorophyll index. So here
you've got the tomato plant growing.
You've got the color images. You can see
the NDVI index, chlorophyll index and uh
anttoscin index. And you can see that
they are changing at the different time
points. And I've got an example of a of
a experiment that we have done with
tomatoes exposed to two different
treatments represented by two different
colors. And you can see that chlorophyll
index, anttoscin index and
NDVI are showing a very different
pattern throughout the time. So again
really it's and some of them are
somewhat related. So the h the
anthocyanin and chlorophyll index are
showing some similarities but not not
always because there is this very early
time point that this guys goes up and
here nothing is really happening. So
you're really able to to look at the
plant as if through different angles and
different strategies isolate those
different strategies more effectively.
Then we've got things that are having to
do with chlorophyll fluorescent and
photosynthesis. So I don't know how
about you but my photosynthesis was
rusty before I started to work with this
machine. So I'm going to explain it to
you. So what is happening? We're able to
only extract the data that is related to
photos system 2. So photo system 2 is
the one that is like absorbing most of
the light. So what's happening? You've
got a lot of electrons going. What we
need to do first is we need to adapt our
plants to dark. So all of those
electrons are like can chilled freak
out. So they chill out for 15 minutes
and then we put the plant under a camera
and then we put a tiny flash and then we
can measure the minimum fluoresence and
then we make then we put them under like
a super saturating flash so we can
measure the maximum fluoresence. So this
is the maximum amount of the light that
the chlorophyll can like shine back at
us. Fine. Maximum minus minimum is FV
which is the variable fluoresence. FV
over FM is quantum yield max. So maximum
yield of your quantum yield of photo
system 2, right? Cool. All right. Then
what we're doing is we're switching the
light back on under the camera. We let
it adapt. We see a kowski effect and
that's basically related to all of those
all of those photons are like either
like shown back or slowly they are being
integrated into the photosynthetic
machinery and that's whenever they are
that's why we're seeing this drop in the
chloro fllororesence. Then again we're
adding this like super saturating
flashing and then we're measuring again
minimum maximum fluoresence and again we
can qu quantify the quantum yield but
it's not maximum quantum yield because
you can see this quantum yield is so
much smaller. So once we've got that we
can calculate non photochemical
quenching based on the differences from
our light adapted chlorophyll
fluorescent and dark adapted and
photochemical quenching based on all of
the other stuff. So there's a lot of
data that we're collecting and we can do
ratios and all of this cool stuff.
Anyways, so long story short is and
again we've got images of color and then
we can superimpose all of those
calculations onto individual pixels in
the plant and we can see like oh but
there is something happening to those
leaves that are really suffering at some
point and how is that looking how is
this suffering looking at at different
traits and again we're seeing very very
different trends. So in here again we've
got experiment of the tomatoes uh over
the time and you can see that the FV
over FM is differing at some point but
then it comes back. So that shows you
really the value of looking at dynamic
systems and looking as close as possible
because otherwise if we would measure
only here and here we would be saying
like FV over FM not changing but because
we're looking through time we can see
like no there's actually things
happening. FQ over FM which is the light
adapted quantum yield it's not really
different whatsoever and we can see that
non-photochemical quenching there is
some variation and there are some points
where this is significant the
differences between our treatment but
the data is a little bit messier here
but again allows us to dissect all of
those those responses into
individual categories and what and for
me I'm not interested in learning more
about NPQ V over FM for me as a root
biologist I use those to to indicate is
my plant okay is my plant doing well. So
this is my fitness rather than waiting
and growing my plants all the way to the
seed and counting the seeds that my
plant is producing because as we as I
told you before natural diversity panel
that thing is complicated but if I do
that at the same moment that I'm looking
at my roots maybe this is this is this
can be a useful data. So before I have
two slides, no three slides left. So
just summarizing the phenocide features
and capabilities, we can image up to one
meter tall plants, which is three foot
for the people that don't like metrics.
Uh we have a capacity of 64 large
plants. So we have grown citrus trees,
we have grown tomatoes, we have grown
beans, we have grown sataria. Sataria is
a tricky one, but we can um we have
grown arabidopsis. And for arabidopsis
we can actually grow 20 plants in one of
the tray which increases our capacity to
1,280 plants. Um so we have RGB imaging
that is masked with chlorophyll
fluoresence which is allowing us to do
automatic calculation of the plant size
and the growth rate. We also have
photosynthetic efficiencies indices and
high precision watering and fertilizing.
So we don't need to come and water those
plants because the machine does it for
us. How cool is that?
So, how do I get to how do you get to
use it? I know how to use it. Uh, so I
left couple of stickers uh next to the
coffee area. So, if you go on the
website, there is a project intake form
available. So, you can download it. You
can fill it up to as much as you as much
as you can. Sometimes you don't really
know what you want, but it gives us a
good starting point for a discussion.
So, once we've got this form filled up
as much as possible, then we've got a
meeting. So it's the the the the person
that is doing the experiment. It's me
and it's Julie Bell from the greenhouse
facilities and BTI just to kind of make
sure that the greenhouse facilities can
provide the conditions that you need for
your experiments that we are not
overpromising you so that we can track
the movement of the microbes in your
plant. We cannot do that. Um but um so
then once once we've got that done,
we've got a project agreement proposed
with the costs. We grow the plants
within the dedicated uh BTI phenotyping
facility and what we provide you with is
your raw data but also some level of
pre-analyzeed data in R. So basically
the same graphs that I showed you in the
previous slides where you've got the
changes throughout the time and also
those p values like when are they
starting to to be significantly
different from each other. We already
have pipelines for that so you don't
have to figure it out. Um and you know
we can we can keep on collaborating like
whether you want to have something else
maybe you want to have like one leaf
analyzed uh per in in your in your in
your experiment rather than the whole
canopy. Uh we can also provide you with
the snapshot data. So if you've got
plants growing preferably in the
greenhouse of BTI because we have had
some insect introduction from the gutmen
recently. So we would like to avoid
that. Um so if you grow the plants
within the facility you can come in and
we can open the machine and just make
one snapshot data individually. Riley
has done that. So if you've got any
questions for her user experience uh
please please come and talk to her or
me. Um and then kind of summing up my
entire talk of today. So some few
take-home messages. So I think studying
stress resilient plants um like wild and
cultivated tomato can can provide new
new strategies for improved uh
performance uh under under very bad
conditions. So you have prioritizing
different components of root system
architecture can be combined to further
improve the tolerance and also there are
new ways we're working on the new ways
of quantifying the roots because we
looked at those at those natural
diversity panels and we have not
observed Christmas tree broomstick and
the telephone polaropsis we only have
started to think about it how are we
going to describe those root system
architectures by working with tomatoes
um I hope that I showed you a couple of
costefficient phenotyping tools that you
can either build yourself or we can help
you build them uh with you uh to
identify uh drought stress responses but
they can be used for identifying any
responses if you're working on pathogens
probably also quite useful or or or
nutrient
availability and hopefully with the
phenocite uh we can provide you with a
little bit more depth in your
environmental response and quantifying
that environmental response.
So this is all that I wanted to mention.
Of course this work wouldn't be possible
without the amazing lab members that I
had plenty of fantastic collaborators
and also I wanted to give a big shout
out to the uh BTI plant growth facility
team. They have been very very great in
helping me deal with the monster that
the phenocite uh is uh is is sometimes
and it's sometimes giving us a lot of
headaches but we're figuring out
together and we're making it we're
making it work. Um and of course the
work on the pimpleum initially started
in caused in the group of this guy Mark
Tester and I was lucky enough that I
could take a lot of it with me. Um, and
thank you for your attention and I'm
happy to hear any questions.
I have a question. I came to I have a
couple of questions. I kept saying we
don't really know how water is taking.
So my question is what do you mean by
that? And the second question is what
role are you looking also at the role of
uh endodies?
Absolutely. Yes. Great question. Yes.
Yes. So yes, I will repeat the question.
So the question is what do I mean by the
fact that we don't know how water is
being taken up and the second is uh what
are are we including endodermis
exodermis in our water calculation. So
um both of the question are pertaining
in the like the cross-sections that
we're collecting of the latch roots and
main roots and uh in including them in
the parto front. So yes, we are
including endodermis exodermis. By the
time that I was making this figures, we
haven't done the stainings yet for the
superization. But yes, we are we know
that the exodermis is forming first,
endo endodermises forming later. So we
are we are including them in the in the
in the tomato. Nobody has ever done
looked at the exodermis and endodermis
formation in the lateral roots, which is
mind-blowing to me that nobody has done
that. But knowing how difficult it is to
get those lat roots cross-sections, I
start understanding why nobody has done
that because those roots are very
finicky. So, we're embedding it in the
in the plastic resin, which is which is
as as you probably know, a bit of a
pain.
Can you stain the whole crosssection?
Can we stain the whole root without a
cross-section? Uh it might
be we could we could potentially but
because we already have the
cross-sections might as well just stay
in those cross-sections. uh the so okay
so I answered your second question first
now let's go back what do I mean by we
don't know how water is being taken up
um well we know roots that's short
answer but if you think about okay so
and I I have been having a lot of
conversations with yam and people in lon
that are developing a lot of like water
transport models so you would think that
they know the question is as is majority
of the water being taken up by the root
tips
or throughout oh sorry throughout the uh
the main the main root. So m majority of
the models are actually developed using
monocots monocots they have um they have
what the the the vascule is changing and
the the conductivity is changing. So
you've got axial conductivity and ra no
radial conductivity and axial
conductivity right so axial conduct no
radial conductivity is decreasing with
the with the age of the root
and axial conductivity is increasing
right so the older roots are kind of
becoming more pipes rather than
absorbent right and that's that's for
monocots and the monocots don't show any
um any change in the root
diameter. Dicodes on the other hand they
we do have secondary growth in the
docodes. So they have and Marco and
Marco is a PhD student of Guiam. Marco
hates me for that because I forced them
to develop those models for tomato and
they're like well in mono inots we've
got secondary growth so your diameter is
not changing. So even though you've got
axial conductivity, no sorry radial,
yes, radio conductivity decreasing
because you've got those endodermal
things, you've got more woody stuff
happening and so forth. Your diameter is
increasing and the increase of that
diameter is sufficient for kind of
counteracting that that effect that
we're seeing in the monocots. So the the
thick roots and D cuts are absorbing
just as much as the thin roots according
to their models. So we're trying to kind
of like see what's happening if we what
can we learn from the model into the
real life and can we just grow plants
with thick
roots and just chop off those main root
merist stems because we apparently don't
need them but I think we still do. So,
so that's that's what I mean by we we
don't really know how the water is being
taken up because we don't know what
features are the most I mean we do need
we do know that features like cortex are
not c number of cortex layers it's not
really playing much of a difference the
number and the size of the exylm vessels
is endodermis exodermis is absolutely
playing the majority of the of the of
the big uh big pictures um but uh but we
don't know how how it's working with the
root diameters increasing because all of
the sudden and things are being like
it's not Yeah. And it's in the way it's
good that they developed all of those
models on monocodes because it's a
simple
system and now we're going we're
upgrading into the D codes.
Um yeah, sure. I had a question about
the two um tomatoes and the cross. Yes.
I was wondering um was there any
differences in associations with um
microisals microisal associations and
the cross? Does that change it? Okay. So
Claire is asking whether there is a
difference between the microisal
association. We have grown those plants
in the sterile conditions on the augur
plate. So we don't know at all with the
microisal associations. They are
performing both equally well when we
grow them in the soil. Uh we don't we
don't incubate any microisal communities
at all. But I assume that they just
emerge. I don't know anything about
microisa. So um I see potentially there
there is definitely potential there but
we haven't studied it yet. So if you
want to have some seeds we can totally
give you
Sam um I was wondering so you have the
differences um in the root architecture.
Can you speak up? I can't hear you. Um
in the hybrid line do you see a
difference in the Ross accumulation? We
have So Sam is asking whether we see
differences in the Ross accumulation in
the F1 hybrid. We have not looked at
that because we had so few seeds of the
F1 and we haven't sent it to to Ron um
because we were like well how about we
establish this protocol because they
haven't done the roots before because
they were like oh roots there's a lot of
out of fllororesence we don't do roots
we only do shoots I'm like roots are
cool so um and we see huge differences
in the stress response between the roots
and the shoots so hopefully hopefully
now we convince them uh but that's
that's a great idea to do that on the on
the F1 I don't No, and we haven't done
RNA sec on the F1 as well, which would
be another way of kind of helping us
figuring out the not the cy the cyst and
the trans of it all, but also like which
of the responses are are dominant from
which genotype? Yeah, great idea. Thank
you.
Yes, John.
So how would you determine that the
change architecture is actually adapted
like a full saw to yes how do you know
that this change it's not a consequence
of stress yes you know damage yeah yeah
yeah okay so Jan is asking whether how
are we going to identify whether change
in the root system architecture is an
adaptive response we don't we don't we
don't know yet so we are we're assuming
that natural variation and we assume
that the maintenance of the growth is
something that is adaptive over the long
term because if you've got roots that
are growing and I think Jose didn't deny
published on that if you've got roots
that are kind of keep on growing
throughout the stress exposure and they
don't stop and think they typically the
meristem activity is decreasing
afterwards. So we don't we are focusing
on the maintain meristm activity and
hopefully that is allowing us to then
say like okay well if you've got after a
week of stress if you still keep on
growing it means that okay you can you
can survive that and we're also going
away we're we're working with the stress
concentrations that are as
physiologically relevant as possible. So
we're working on 75 max 125 millolar
salt stress. So, we're we're trying to
stay away from osmotic shock. Uh because
that's I think that's also not how salt
stress is typically occurring in the
wild. Um but yeah, we don't we don't
know and that's also one of the reasons
that that we want to add the we still a
lot of the stuff that I have presented
is a very descriptive studies. Um so we
are going to identify the genes and once
we add the genes then we can say is it
adaptive is it not
adaptive. But yeah, a very good question
and it's definitely something that we
that we have to keep in mind like the
fact that things are changing or like
stopping growing it's it's not
necessarily a good thing but maintenance
of growth we we are assuming that that's
that's what the plant want
time so let's think thank you so much
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu
edu.