this is a production of Cornell
University um so my background is in
hydrology so this talk is mostly
hydrology with some kind of agronomy and
agriculture thrown in just so you kind
of know what perspective I'm coming from
um in terms of the project I've been
working on this um with a a grad student
Sher Martin who's here and then also Dr
tresa selfa who's at Sunni ESF um she's
a rural sociologist all three of us are
actually uh have at least one cornal
degree
um so I guess it's a good
pedigree so in terms of just some
background on the project um so this is
um funded by USDA um so two years ago
almost they had a um a new program come
out the water for agriculture challenge
um sort of the context of it was 2013
2014 um and clearly a lot of the
motivation was because of the drought
out west uh so when I was sort of
contemplating is there anything to
propose it's can you really come up with
anything as compelling as what's going
on out west so one question that kind of
occurred to me and I think have occurred
to other people is what is the potential
if it's if it's harder to sustain
agricultur out west to shift agriculture
back East right and that seems like a
reasonable question to ask um with the
idea of the intended impact of the water
for agriculture challenge is to ensure
um quantity and availability of Water
Supplies so if you want more water out
west why don't you take your agriculture
somewhere where you actually have
water but then a few other questions
arise with that so one thing so I was
just looking at some papers um this this
is more of a climatology paper um
looking at Water Supply in the west so
this is just someone mapping out uh
Reservoir storage um in the Colorado
River Basin so basically storage in the
um Lake power Lake me so that's the
black line so they're tracking that from
2005 to 20 um or that's the green line
so from 2005 to 2014 but at the same
time what they also did is they also
looked at groundwater and the way it
looked at groundwater is they used um
what's called Gra the grace program from
NASA which is the satellite program and
it looks at small changes in the
gravimetric field um of the earth and
what they can do is they can detect um
at a regional scale changes in
groundwater storage so interesting thing
with this graph is they basically saw
2010 2011 people are concerned that Lake
me might go dry it basically recovers
but what they continue to see is they
see ground rouer levels go down and stay
down so this kind of suggests a few sort
of interesting things really to my
project and also Western
water which is one is that the drought
has probably to some degree impacted
Western Water Production um but to the
other degree it's it's Western
production of Agriculture is to some
degree probably been mitigated by
Reliance on groundwater um so if we sort
of look at 10 20 years out when that
groundwater isn't there will there be a
more obvious need for shifting things
somewhere else the third thing that it
does in terms of some perspective for
thinking about New York is it is it
highlights the fact that even out west
where there's these irrigation districts
and well-known basically is a a definite
need for managing water there's been
gaps in terms of understanding and
management and that big gap has been in
groundwater so people have been drawing
down groundwater basically because
there's no regulations there to manage
it that basic parallels New York um in
the sense of in New York it's sort of
been free rain in terms of nonpotable
water use um in turn and I'll talk about
this in a few minutes until only about
three years ago there were basically no
restrictions in most of New York not in
the sasan River Basin Delaware River
Basin but everywhere else if you were a
non-potable water user so a golf course
a farmer you basically could take as
much water as you wanted never had to
report it and never had to tell anyone
so to some degree New York is sort of in
the place where the West has been with
groundwater is we really don't know very
much right so this is sort of the
motivated the two questions of of this
work is um can we shift agriculture back
East um if we do that and we do we need
water to do that that um have we
basically been using more water for
agriculture than we think in in the East
and in New York um and what do we
actually know about how much water use
there's been right so those are those
are sort of the overriding
questions okay so basically four things
we'll look at sort of four different
parts of the talk um first one is more
antidotal but is there less water than
we think in New York and we'll do a
little case study on Fall Creek um
second one is how much do we actually
know about agricultural water demand in
New York um third is what sources of
water could agriculture make use of
right we're very different than the west
where they have snow pack they have
large reservoirs they've been planning
for irrigation basically since the
beginning of of saddling L West um and
then the fourth one is can we actually
demonstrate a benefit of
irrigation okay so place to start is
just thinking about um sort of a case
study of what do we know about um water
use um in New York so we're going to
look at Fall Creek um one reason it's
nearby um another reason it's a good
size right it's the water shed at least
above the gauge is about 125 square
miles so big enough to actually have
some water to do something with but
small enough to get a grasp on so this
is our map so we're right here well yeah
we literally are right here right um the
gauge so one nice thing about this um
Watershed is it's actually gauged most
gauges in New York are either on New
York City water supply watersheds or big
Rivers so this is actually a relatively
small watered that's gauged um and then
it has some interesting things going on
in terms of water use
so there's the Cornell Water Filtration
plant um did most people know Cornell
has their own Water Filtration plant we
do um then there's several places where
they pull water out for irrigation um
all related to Cornell so in Varna um
they have some irrigation sometimes and
then there's the Homer Thompson
vegetable farm out in Freeville um and
then the other thing that's interesting
too is there's discharge of water um
from dried and Freeville wastewater
treatment plant so that's actually
inflow to the system and for the most
part of that water we could kind of
consider consider it an outof base and
transfer in the sense that it's
basically groundwater from homeowner
Wells um or from deeper groundwater it
might be in the The Basin but it's
basically deep groundwater it's not
surface
water okay so then we can basically say
um can we do sort of some water
accounting for for what we have
available um so as I said it's really
only been in the last few years that
anyone's really bothered to pay too much
attention um to what's what's available
so basy Cornell as far as I know has
really only done a um made an attempt to
sort of compile the records for the last
four years um so going back to about
2011 luckily though we've had some
really dry years in there so 2011 and
2012 um basally approach uh the
historical lows um in this summer um so
the historical low is determined by
going back the USGS gauge goes back to
1925 so basically picking off the the
monthly minimum um all the way back to
1925 so 2011 and 2012 come pretty close
to those monthly minimums right so we
can get a good sense of demand when
you're actually at your minimum in terms
of of moisture
availability okay so let's look at some
of the
demands um so cornal a withdrawals basy
for
irrigation we can see sort of what we
might expect but often this date isn't
available is that when it's drier in
2011 and 2012 you use more water and you
use about four times more water um the
thing to look at here and kind of put
this all together in a minute so
everything is in MGD anyone know what
MGD is some people probably not a lot of
people so it's in million gallons per
day um so that's in water supply that's
a pretty typical measure is to use
million gallons per day okay um okay so
that's around 0.1 million gallons per
day um in terms of Maximum irrigation
demand this is monthly
average this is the coronal Filtration
plant so they use quite a bit more um
they use between 1 and a half and 2
million gallons per day of water and
that's pretty consistent um as we've
been doing this we've been learning some
interesting things about who uses water
and and how they use it so the golf
course actually uses filtered water from
the Water Filtration plant whereas most
other places well irrigation on campus
just uses unfiltered water but we are
sort of surprised to find
that okay so putting these numbers
together um so the one thing to realize
is the withdraw and the the gains to the
system are all um Upstream of the gauge
so the gauge is basically not telling
you what's available um before you take
anything out it's basically telling you
what's available after you take things
out so it sort of is a good it's a
relatively good indication of the lowest
available flow um so if we basically
look at um fil Filtration plant um
subtracting off um cornal irrigation
subtracting water and then dried in
Freeville adding some water um and
comparing that to um 196 4 um this is
the 1964 minimum assuming the gains and
losses are the same as they are now
which we're not quite sure if they are
um this would be September 1964
including these current gains and losses
so we basically it seems like if we look
at historical minimums drought of record
um we would always have some amount of
flow in Fall Creek but 2.7 million
gallons per day isn't much flow does
anyone know probably what it's flowing
at right now Fall Creek
want to put a number out there I like to
do this with my classes I like to ask
people make some guesses it's probably
about um I didn't look at the gauge it's
probably around somewhere around 100 MGD
right now and in the summer when you go
out there and you think it's pretty dry
it's probably around 20 MGD so if you
say 2 MGD we still have water that's not
a lot of water that's like that's
basically a trickle of water um so main
point is right if we look at this we do
still have some water but not a lot
right so we can basically say within the
historical record drawing some water of
the system we're basically getting to a
point where if you take much more water
of the system you have nothing left
right and people haven't really as far
we've talked to um Chris bour who runs
the wastewater treatment plant it's
interesting they have a number for what
their um maximum withdrawal can be but
it's actually based on their plant
capacity it's not based on hydrology
right so no one is really out there
looking to say are there minimums that
we have to meet
um the other thing too is that these are
all based on monthly
averages right so we know within a month
there's going to be variability but then
within a day there's variability um so
if you go and look at the USGS gauge
record um and this is this is
instantaneous flow it's every 15 minutes
you see this cycling like this and we've
actually been trying to figure this out
for a while what this is because it's
this only shows up in the last few years
um and what we realized is Cornell
change the way they operate their plant
so now they turn it off at night for a
few hours but what this does is if your
daily demand is to MGD but you turn it
off for half the time that means your
your demand when it's on is for MGD
right so and if the if say if the
irrigation works the same way if they
only turn on certain times of the day
turn off certain times of the day your
monthly mean you might be meeting what
you have available but you could
certainly be at a point during the day
where you actually dry things out right
um where your instantaneous demands
exceed what you have so it seems pretty
reasonable just based on this sort of
this case study that there definitely
can be places one of them being Fall
Creek in the state where if people
aren't really looking at how we're
withdrawing water um that we could
potentially run out of
water um one thing to note to this and
as we go on a little farther is the way
this operates is it's what we would call
run-of the river system right so out
west or places like that ideally what
you have it's not run-of the river you
have a reservoir some storage to draw
but here we're basically just taking
whatever Waters in the system is what
we're taking out um as we talk about
other potential sources in New York
state for for irrigation and water
demand what we want to look for is
places where it's not run-of the river
where you actually have storage if you
think about New York though we don't
necessarily have a lot of storage we
have some we have the Great Lakes we
have the Finger Lakes but they're not
necessarily at an ideal point to make
use of them but we'll see a little later
on where we might actually have a source
that people don't always think
about okay so kind of part two of this
is to ask the question um besides just
this case study what else do we know
about Irrigation in New York state right
um are there any numbers out there so
there's basically two entities that sort
of make an attempt to put some numbers
together um there's USDA so they have
their agricultural census every five
years and they ask some questions about
irrigation they basically ask about
irrigated acreage and then there's USGS
us Geological Survey um that also every
five years comes out with estimates of
water use on a county basis um so these
numbers official government Publications
they're out there it's by County it
seems like it might be reasonable to
trust it um so let's look at some of
these uh so I think might be a little
small but you can probably kind of see
it from the back um depending how young
you are or old you
are um so first three columns USDA Nas
um National a statistical service data
so that's irrigated Acres um and then
the last colum is USGS demand um in
terms of MGD right so comparing kind of
apples and oranges one is Acres one is
actual demand um just some interesting
interesting things to pick out so
Gennesse County um and I'll I'll show a
map in a second well I'll actually go do
it right now um so if you don't know
your your New York State um geography
and you're wondering where these places
are so basically places with most
irrigation basically from nas Orleans
genese and Wyoming counties those are
sort of the three highest ones stacked
up right there um and then Wayne County
and Niagara County probably sources or
what they're irrigating is a little
different Wayne and Niagara County
probably predominantly Orchards um well
known right that's where most the Apple
production is in the state um and then
Orleans Gennesse and Wyoming Orleans and
Gennesse probably more vegetable
production Wyoming I actually don't
quite know I think it's mostly crops but
that's sort of part of the Gap I don't
don't quite know what that
is um okay so then our other source is
thinking about USGS demand how
consistent is this um the interesting
thing about the USGS demand is it
doesn't exact correlate to the acreage
right the highest one for USGS demand
does correspond to genese County um but
you have other counties with relatively
low acreage um that still have
relatively High USGS demand numbers
right if we go do just some back of the
envelope calculations so I basically
just took MGD converted to cubic meters
per year something a little easier to
think about maybe um and then kind of
look at a few possible irrigation rates
so basically centimeters per year and
look at how how many acres irrigated
would one MGD give you so now we can
kind of do a comparison between acres
and MGD so irrigation rate it seems like
10 centimeters per year is probably the
high end in New York state it' be hard
to believe you have a year that's much
drier you need more than 10 cenm per
year during grow growing season so that
would say um 10 centimeter per year um
irrigation rate could you could irrigate
uh almost 3500 Acres with one MGD right
so that would in gene County if the
numbers are right from USGS 5 5 MGD at
10 cm per year would give you 17,000
Acres um what NASA is reporting is 6,000
Acres seems like a pretty big
inconsistency right and and that's even
going to be true especially when you
look at some of these smaller counties
with less acreage like Erie County 3.36
MGD 390 Acres there's a pretty big
inconsistency there so clearly
something's missing that we don't know
um not surprisingly though USGS does
this for every count in the country and
if you look at the report there's about
five people on the report so however
they do this it's some way where they
really crank through it
so okay but this basically raises more
questions than it answers right it
basically says doesn't tell you anything
about how often is irrigation occurring
if we trust the nas data which I think
is pretty reliable it basically just
tells us it's irrigated it tells us
nothing about actual demand it doesn't
tell us how much water is being used it
doesn't tell us where the water is
coming from um and then there's this
inconsistency pointed
out okay so as I've sort of alluded to
there's more data becoming available and
it basically is coming from um the
nework or the the Great Lakes compact
which was passed or at least discussed
and agreed to be passed back in 2008 um
and a basy agreement between um States
and um provinces in Canada um about how
to manage their water and New York State
as part of that said they would actually
start to try to track water usage
non-potable water usage um so in 2011
people who used over 100,000 gallons per
day of non-potable water use had to
basically start telling the state that
they're using the water it's basically
voluntary in the sense that the state
doesn't know if you don't report so but
what it does is it starts to give us a
data source okay so what this is is this
is um for the most part people reporting
um to DC who's collecting that data um
and this is we we geore referenced at
least the the address associated with
the the user which might not literally
be where it's taken from but we're doing
the best we can um and then this is
overlaid over a crop map of different
types of crops in New York state right
so the yellow is corn the darker green
is soybean um the pink is alala and you
can kind of see the darker red is
usually some cases it's apples and some
cases it's dry beans and things like
that but it starts to give you a pretty
good sense of sort of some distribution
of things in New York state the other
thing we have added in here is and I'll
start to talk about this in a minute is
the Barge Canal Authority also provides
water to people and if you take water
from the Barge Canal you have to get a
permit um so we also have the blue dots
are people with a Barge Canal um permit
to draw water okay so if you put this
out there this is sort of our best
picture to date in terms of sort of
sight specific users of irrigation water
in New York state right and it basically
matches up with what we knew from the
nas data in terms of people are Center
in Orleans County jese County and
there's actually a few more off the
bottom let's see let's go this way um
which get cut off there down in Wyoming
County and for the most part the dots
lie in areas with agriculture which is
good so it seems like it's consistent
with what we're
seeing um so at this point no we still
don't really have any idea of of demand
um what how much water they're using or
where they're taking water
from one thing we do kind of know is
with the dec data at least it does have
it does give information about who the
user is um so we can get some sense um
actually there is a little bit of
withdrawal data I forgot with these CD
data there is um so we have some sense
of demand and then we have some sense of
what they're producing and for the most
part as I guess we might expect it's
fruit and apples and vegetables so
things that would Horticultural products
that would generally be more sensitive
um to water
demand okay so some examples up there
okay so one thing you might notice and I
sort of highlight here is we have a
large concentration along the Barge
Canal right anybody from New York State
have most people walked along the Barge
Canal just to get a sense a few people
okay a lot of people haven't right so
original URI Canal 1825 um basically
went from um just outside of Albany over
to Buffalo at the time Upstate New York
was mostly Forest land and it
effectively opened up um the Western
frontier at the time right just about
every city in New York state in Upstate
New York is basally on on a river or on
the Erie Canal what was the Erie Canal
um in about um 1905 or so um the Erie
Canal was 80 years old they decided to
update it so they built the Barge Canal
in some places it stayed along the same
path but in other places um like in City
of Rochester it went around the outside
of the city of
Rochester um but you basically have this
almost 200y old you know kind of major
engineering feat um sitting out there um
interestingly enough so I'll talk more
about it in a minute um I think it they
have a budget of over $100 million a
year I think their revenue is about
$100,000 per year so if you ever wonder
why your taxes are so high or especially
why it cost so much to drive on the
throughway you can partially thank the
Eerie Canal
so um okay but this is where the Eerie
Canal goes um on that western side of
the state um it's basically totally flat
um and it drains out of Lake Erie and
then here's Orleans County that it cuts
across um and then it eventually hits
the genese river over by Rochester um so
basically the reason all that irrigation
is there is because they're taking
advantage of the Barge Canal of pulling
water of the Barge Canal um and it's
basically it
was um so two things I guess so the
original Eerie Canal was actually
intentionally built up higher um to
avoid flooding when they built the Barge
Canal they built it lower so it actually
intersects the genesy river now um which
is a good thing because it basically
means what this is it's basically a
direct conduit from Lake yie um across
the state and it also can potentially
pull water from the jese river so if you
start to talk about is there a way is
there actually infrastructure in New
York state where we can draw upon stored
water the Barge Canal is it because it's
basically connected to the genesy river
and lake yuie and I don't think most
people really look at it that way but
that's really what it is um so part of
this project is basically thinking about
can we other ways to sort of optimize
the use of that infrastructure
okay um here's a nice view of things
1905 um probably looks more quaint then
than it does now but I don't I don't
think it looks that bad now either this
is
Madina um so this is engineering report
from 1905 um which is interesting so
basically when they modified the Barge
Canal from the Eerie Canal um they
intentionally recognized so you know
when you open the locks and the canal
you basically lose water so you have to
have a you have to have a lot of water
coming in um so what realized was um so
they intentionally made sure they had a
large source of water and here is the
Eerie Canal or the lake Eerie um and
they basically put a number on this so
they say that it has a capacity to
provide at least 1237 cubic feet per
second of water in this portion of the
canal um that's a lot of water um in
terms of MGD that's about equivalent to
about a th000 MGD um so there's a
potential to to carry to convey a lot of
to supply a lot of water there another
question you might ask is okay so if
it's not the Barge Canal um other other
sources of water in the state um there
are some aquifers um a lot of those
correspond to to glacial Valley bottom
aquifers um for the most part they're
not extensively tapped there are some
out there something else to consider um
we're we might go there but not
necessarily but just something else to
put out
there okay so despite the fact we know
there's Irrigation in the Northeast and
in New York I think the the other
question that's out there is is it
scientifically is it defensible is it
necessarily is it necessary right we
know people are doing it so it seems
like it must have some value um but is
there other evidence out there of what
the value actually
is so and I so surprisingly there's
really not that much information right I
mean there's a lot of farmers that kind
of say I think we need to do this and
they they're doing it um but at the same
time if you start to look for actual
scientific studies that show um the need
for it um there's not that there's
really not many out there at all so the
one thing that complicates things I
think as most kind of aromy people know
and especially in the Northeast is you
have lots of different factors
controlling yield um right so I kind of
at the top here I just picked corn just
because it was a nice image I could find
it easily right but at the top I sort of
have different factors that can affect
yield so clearly in the Northeast early
season wetness is a big one how soon can
we actually get in the field and plant
things um once things actually start
growing is it actually warm enough for
the crop um so do we accumulate enough
Growing Degree Days um once things are
growing do we have rain we don't want so
do we flood our field um do things are
things too wet and then finally on once
things are actually getting mature and
there's actually quite a bit of water
demand do we still have enough water
right and this is really the fourth one
is the one we're really asking that's
the one we're trying to control with
irrigation so the difficulty in trying
to understand is how much of our yield
is dependent on on moisture availability
is also trying to to identify these
other controls on your yield right so
you basically have a bunch of factors a
lot of them not related to moisture
availability or at least um a moisture
availability deficit um that you need to
kind of eliminate to to see if how
important that other factor
is okay so this is just showing um kind
of peak demand for corn um about 80 60
to 80 Days in so by July August right
that's when we be most interested in
having
water okay so some interesting studies
from people in Canada um actually so I
guess a group um C and all um they were
looking at Horticultural crops so they
were doing two things they were looking
at temperature um and they were looking
at mean seasonal temperature and then
they were looking at just days over 30
so just sort of short sporadic changes
um so they saw for a few things cabbage
cauliflower um some significance um just
in days over 30 um and then they
actually saw some significance with um
days with rain not with growing season
precipitation but basically short
periods um without without enough rain
um so a little bit of evidence there um
other sources of evidence out there that
irrigation might actually matter and and
sort of um potentially be useful in the
Northeast um so crop insurance data
which is out there um as we can see so
this was for apples um blue one for kind
of this is um indemnities for crop
insurance um certainly for apples
freezing is a much bigger deal than EX
moisture well actually excess moisture
doesn't even show up here right so we do
know they irrigate apples but it appears
and that might be the reason it doesn't
show up is because the irrig it's
already irrigated so people don't need
to um don't include it in terms of crop
loss um corn irrigation does show up so
most years at least lately we've had too
much water but 2012 was a dry year it
did show up as people claiming crop
insurance for lack of
water
okay and then we've also been doing some
of our own analysis using um Nas data so
National a statistical service data um
using county level data um and what
we've just been doing is just starting
with relatively simple things so just
trying to predict um annual yield um and
using Growing Degree Days um using June
precipitation and July precipitation
basically for sufficient water and then
using May precipitation for being too
wet early in the season um so this is
for Livingston County this is down near
kind of Danville kind of Danville and
the kind of the center of the state um
and you can see here not a great model
but the main thing I kind of look at is
do we get the quadrants right in terms
of observed versus predicted
um and the other thing to note is that
here importantly if you if you just try
to model just using gdd and early season
wetness alone it's not significant so
only when you put in precipitation kind
of Summer July June precipitation is it
significant so again some more evidence
suggesting yet yes precipitation or
moisture during the growing season is
important things get complicated though
so this is another County um this is
jness County um and in this one we
actually find the model the best model
is actually just includes gdd and just
includes May um early season moisture
not summertime precipitation so we're
not quite sure right this is where
they're in the process of kind of
deciphering if you move around County to
County um why do things change um one
thing there is a little bit of
irrigation in the county 2% but probably
not enough to make a difference um in
terms of of changing these relationships
here possibility is soils they might
have deeper soils um so even if you have
less rain you have more moisture
availability over time but we don't
quite know um so we're we're basically
trying to kind of decipher these
relationships and kind of get a better
sense of of what's going on um to make
the case that irrigation is actually
potentially useful um right and then
this is only for corn for vegetable
crops and things like that um it might
be a different
story okay so kind of the final part of
this is um when we consider this and
part of this project was sort of
considering historically what's happened
but then also part of this is basically
looking at potential for climate
adaptation with the assumption that
things um likely and will change in the
future um so without at this point we
haven't done our own work but looking at
what other people have done um there was
a paper by McDonald and geritz um about
two years back and they for the entire
United States um looked at moisture
deficit using climate models um and then
they basically on changes in moisture
deficit they used historical
relationships to irrigation given
moisture deficit and projected how
things might change so for New York
State they said there might be an
increase of up to 25,000 hectares in
irrigated acreage or yeah hectares in
irrigated land
so they recognize something kind of a
well-known study um Anderson and all
from about 5 years ago um looking at a
climate assessment in the Northeast um
they also use climate models um looking
at changes this is in soil moisture
seasonal soil summer soil moisture um
and they saw a decline in in summer soil
moisture although not it's a climate
model so you know you can't put that
much if any trust in it but it seems
like um they did see a decline of about
1 cm so not a huge
amount so it seems reasonable to think
that there in the future there be some
additional moisture deficit and that
might kind of that might be equally
important to not only looking
historically has there been a need for
irrigation but basically changing sort
of the equation of can you justify it
more in the
future okay so as you can kind of tell
project is basically ongoing we've been
doing this for about six months and we
basically are going to do it for another
year um but I think we can make a few
conclusions already um and kind of and
then think about where we're going to go
um so first thing is basically given the
Reliance on run-of- the river supplies
in New York State for the most part um
it doesn't seem it does seem like there
is potential for conflict between users
I do know like say for Fall Creek um I
we belong to a CSA which is itha
Organics um they recently started
farming right next to the Tom Homer
Thompson vegetable farm and they have a
plan to irrigate um so there's lots of
small users out there who might be using
water um that don't necessarily fall
under the 100,000 gallon per day
threshold to report right um so for now
those people kind of remain invisible
but um if there's enough of them they
might
matter um let's see they remain
inconsistencies and and what we do know
right in terms of Nas and USGS um it's
there's basically no consistency there's
little consistency between that data
that's being put out there um so clearly
clearly gaps in
reporting um despite not really being
intentional the Barge Canal seems to be
a really interesting piece of
infrastructure it's currently being used
to some degree um evident by the number
of people clustered around it but I
think there's interesting questions to
ask of is there a capacity to put more
people around it and one thing I don't
really get into because I don't have the
information yet is right there's an
expense with irrigation and to irrigate
you basically have to say um is the
economical benefit from what you can um
get an increased revenue does it equate
what you have to put in in terms of
capital right the Barge Canal is
potentially interesting because
everything's nice and flat it's already
right there it might be a pretty cheap
source of irrigation in New York so it
might it might be a pretty economical
way to irrigate
nearby
um based on sort of some analysis of
what data is out there dry periods do
cause measurable declines and yield
despite other factors that cause
measurable declines so it's definitely
we can see it um it's just a matter of
better eeking out you know what is that
as a total percentage of of loss really
um and that's sort of the economic part
and then as I said at the end climate
change will probably make things more
economically feasible it seems pretty
likely things are going to become D um
in the future how much remains to be
seen U so kind of remaining parts of our
project are basically to do an intensive
survey in the next few months um of
farmers to basically get more um focused
information in terms of what sources of
water they using um how much are they
using and what kind of irrigation
equipment are they using um and also
what are they irrigating um and then to
also continue on with with doing more
crop yield modeling to get a better
sense um but in the end I think it
should be sort of an interesting picture
of sort of this to to a degree sort of
untouched um consideration of
non-potable water use in New York state
um and going out in the future it kind
of it might be some sort of some
potential for future investment in
Irrigation in New York if you can kind
of make the case that um there's a place
to to boost production without basically
having too many competing users for the
water so all in there and I'm happy to
take
questions
yeah this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu