this is a production of Cornell
University okay so I think after a long
day now it's U it's time for me I guess
to uh Entertain You for the next hour or
so and um try to keep you awake and and
what I thought what I should do is um uh
share and discuss with you uh our more
recent work on uh microbal Association
with healthy plants and also proposed
functions of these uh
microbes now um since this is very much
a an emerging research field I thought
you know it would be appropriate to give
a brief
introduction and um so personally I
believe that really one of the more
profound discoveries in molecular plant
microb interactions during the last
decade has been the observation that
healthy asymptomatic plants in nature
live in association with a rich
diversity of microorganisms and in
simple terms the sum of the
microorganisms that live in association
that colonize a healthy asymptomatic
plants that's what called the plant
microbal and it's important that really
for Association of healthy plants with
microbes that we see association with
different microbial classes so we see
for example association with bacteria we
have association with protes and we have
also associations with
fungi and
um the microbes that live in association
with above ground plants uh that's often
called the phosphere and uh the microbes
that live in association with below
ground Parts particular the root uh this
is called the risos spere now what I
thought what would be useful to
structure my presentation today what
I'll do is in the first part of my
lecture I will uh tell you what we've
learned about the bacterial um plant
microbot and then during the last maybe
10 15 minutes I'll tell you some uh
recent findings of uh association
between healthy plants and root
Associated fungi I thought this might be
interesting so let's get started with
the bacterial root
microbot um it's I think it's now um
widely accepted that essentially all
flowering plants in nature are densely
colonized by by bacteria healthy
asymptomatic plants and literally
millions of bacteria colonize the leaf
surface and the interior and it's very
similar to The Roots we we find zillions
of bacteria that colonize the root
surface and also the root interior what
is slightly more controversial is the
source of inoculum of these Leaf
Associated bacteria because leaves you
know they thrive in a in a natural open
environment and and and it's very clear
that there are multiple sources for
these Leaf Associated microbes but this
is quite different um from the root from
uh the root microbot it's it's now also
I think widely accepted that um bacteria
that live in unplanted soil that those
bacteria defines the bacterial St in
ulum for the formation of the root
microbot and that has some experimental
advantages that I will explain to you
later during my
presentation so what are proposed
microbot functions for the plant hose
there are a number of them and um these
include nutrient mobilization there's
certainly strong evidence that many uh
root Associated bacteria help plants to
mobilize uh nutrients for plant growth
so plant growth promotion is has been um
repeatedly reported there's evidence for
IND indirect pathogen protection and I
will report on that as well aoic stress
tolerance and increased Fitness so it's
almost too good to believe and one has
to be really skeptical because many of
these claims are anecdotal and
importantly many of these claims are
based on monoassociation so one microb
member plus one host under a laboratory
conditions but the the community context
is frequently missing so one needs to
really um take these claims uh with a
grain of salt so these are our long-term
questions that we would like to address
for our work how can healthy plants
establish intimate associations with
microbial communities how can plants
discriminate between beneficial and
pathogenic microbes I think this not
understood and and and lastly how do
plant Associated microbic communities
promote plant health so this is really
what guides our our research
activities now let's have a closer look
into the root Associated bacteria it's
known actually since more than 100 years
that's Roots growing in natural soil
live an intimate association with a
diverse range of soil born bacteria and
I think there's some evidence now that
um it's really organic compounds that
are actively exuded by Roots into soil
that those serve as chemical cues and
attract soil born bacteria many of these
bacteria then become enriched on the
root surface and some of them also make
it inside the root so they are bacterial
root endophytes now there are two
numbers that I would like you to keep in
mind and the first number is really that
soil so unplanted soil uh is an
incredibly Rich compartment on this
globe for bacteria um and one gram of
soil contains between 10 to the 7 to 10
to the N bacteria so this is very
important so essentially roots are
growing in a bacterial broth this is um
it's it's really a remarkable um
observation the the second um important
number is that about 10 to 20% of um
carbon dioxide atmosph Eric carbon
dioxide that is fixed via the Kelvin
benenson cycle in green leaves is ex is
extruded as organic carbon vir Roots
into soil so there's substantial organic
carbon sequestration by plants into soil
and you ask OS why why do plants invest
so much energy into soil now
conceptually I think um the root is
analogous to the digestive tract of of
of vertebrates and you may ask why um I
think the arguments for this is both
organs the the digestive tract as well
as roots are organs that are dedicated
for nutrient mobilization and nutrient
uptake the the difference is between the
two system this is a closed system this
is an open system and essentially you
can look at a root you know as a
digestive tract where the inside is
turned out and I will come back to that
in a
minute so um then I thought it might be
useful if this works to briefly explain
to you how do we measure these root
Associated bacterial communities and
this in a cartoon explains the
fractionation of the arabidopsis root
Associated bacterial microb AO which is
now more or less a standard protocol so
what we do is we grow our arabidopsis
plants in natural soil but in otherwise
controlled environmental conditions in
the greenhouse we grow them to bolting
stage then we Harvest about three uh 3
cm long segments of arabidopsis roots we
wash the roots and collect the soil
particles that physically adhere to the
root surface and this is then what we
call the risos spere compartment and
subsequent to the washing we apply a
sonication step to deplete remaining
epithetic bacteria from the um root
surface and then we end up with these um
washed and sonicated Roots we homogenize
the roots to release bacteria that
thrive inside roots and this is then
what we call the root compartment and
then in a subsequent step we compare the
bacterial communities in the root
compartment with the bacterial
communities in the isosphere compartment
and as a control the bacterial
communities present in unplanted natural
soil right so it's very simple so how do
you
molecularly characterize these spectal
communities we and essentially most
other groups in microbial ecology use
the bacterial 6 in srna gene uh it's
really the most widely used DNA sequence
for taxonomic assignments of bacteria
it's technically a relatively simple um
experiment you just use various PCR
primer combinations to amplify segments
of this bacterial 6 ands ribosomal RNA
genes and then the PCR amplicons are
subjected to pyro aluminous sequencing
so that's you know it's it's relatively
standard uh what becomes important is
the uh computational or the the
bioinformatic processing of these 6ins
sequences and so for this um we
developed a customized pipeline uh we
use at least 10,000 high quality reads
per sample then in the first step
there's a read alignment and this is
perhaps the most critical step which is
called complete linkage clustering where
all of the um six and srna sequences
that share greater than 97% identity are
used for the definition of a strange
term which is called an operational
taxonomic unit so bacterial otu and to
give you an idea of the taxonomic of the
resolution power of these otus this is
roughly between the bacterial genos and
a bacterial species so it's very
important to keep in mind this
technology fails to discriminate between
different strains of one and the same
species but it can resolve in the best
cases different bacterial species and
then you get two types of information if
you examine a compartment you can Define
the number of different otus and you
also obtain the relative abundance so
you know which one is abundant which one
is a rare one and those two informations
are then used for um multivariate
statistic uh analysis
so why don't we have a look into um our
early work that was published now some
time ago where our goal was to
characterize the structure of the
arabidopsis root microbot and for this
purpose we've grown our plants in
natural soils but under controlled
environmental conditions and then we've
compared um the root Associated uh
bacteria with the bacterial communities
in the risos spere compartment and in
the unplanted soil and this is typically
how we visualize these results it's a
Turner plot and I need to explain to you
how to read uh uh these uh these plots
each dot represents an bacterial otu as
defined by six as sequence tag and the
size uh indicates the relative abundance
so let's say large dots represents
abundant bacteria small dots low
abundance bacteria more important is the
position within this triangle because
the the position of a particular
bacterial otus indicates um the relative
abundance of a bacterium in these three
compartments and so what I've colorcoded
here are those bacteria that become
enriched in arabidopsis Roots relative
to unplanted soil and the rizosphere and
what when we when you do the taxonomic
assignments of these root enriched
bacteria root enriched otus they
essentially Define three bacterial F
they correspond to three bacterial F
which are called actinobacteria Proto
bacteria and back to dat is so
relatively at this High taxonomic rank
you know a relatively simple taxonomic
structure the major take-home message
from independent experiments carried out
um by David bulgarelli and our lab in
Cologne and by Jeff dangles lab by Derek
lunbeck in the US really uh uh using um
soils from from two different continents
in Europe and us uh is that soil type is
the main determinant of root microd
composition how genotype contributes
limited variation so relatively simple
uh take- home message so since that time
when We examined really the structure of
the arabidopsis rot microbal and also of
uh some arabidopsis relatives there were
a number of additional studies now
published these include various crop
plants barley maze uh Grape Wine and so
on and quite recently we've done a meta
study we simply wanted to know how
similar or dissimilar is the root
associated microbot in all of these
different plant species right that span
um about 150 million years of of
evolution and the result is actually
shown in uh this projection where each
of the dot uh represents a sample and
the proximity of the dots represents uh
the taxonomic similarity um of the of
the root microba and what you can see is
that essentially um the taxonomic
structure of the root micro water from
these different plant species is very
similar to each other but when we
compare the taxonomic structure of the
root Associated bacterial microbot with
the gut with the human gut microbot it's
it's there's essentially no overlap so
although as you recall both the
vertebrate gut and the root are if you
like physiologically equivalent organs
but you know it's it's it's very clear
the bacteria that populate our digestive
tract or of any other vertebrae are
totally different so um uh the major
lesson from this is is uh there's a
conserved taxonomic structure of the
bacterial micro root microb at phm rank
Proto bacteria actinobacteria bacteria
datus andic so it's it's a highly
conserved plant
trait now about two years ago we we
weren't entirely satisfied with the type
of work that we were doing and we we
felt you know we were really reaching a
ceiling um essentially what we were
doing is we were we were doing case
control studies or time serious studies
we applied the 16sr gene Community
profiling that I've explained to you
we've applied metag genome sequencing
and then uh we inferred from these
results hypothesis that are based on
statistics on Advanced statistics but if
you really look closely in our
Publications these are correlations
between multiple variables and because
I'm trained as a geneticist I'm somewhat
I'm I'm not satisfied if you end up with
qualitive observation so we felt that
there might be an opportunity on the
long run to develop a new br brch of
plant microbol research and this Branch
might involve really systematic
cultivation of um the bacterial plant
microt so high throughput bacterial
cultivation and then if this were
successful then we could design
synthetic bacterial communities that we
call syncom um and then we could add
them to germfree uh plants and then we
could test the hypothesis you know from
these experiments and make scientific
conclusions that are based on clation so
that was the idea but a potential caveat
is that when we were talking with our
colleagues from uh environmental
microbiology that they told us well
whatever environmental sample you take
if you want to cultivate the bacteria
you can only cultivate barely 1% of them
so if that were true then of course you
could say well is this entire approach
realistic right but there were reasons
why we were skeptical with the claims of
the environmental
microbiologists and um we therefore um
about two or 2 and a half years ago we
started to establish a reference culture
collection of the arabidopsis root
microbot and this work is now impress in
the British weekly so I um uh this
involves uh initially we collect Roots
again from plants grown in natural soil
we wash them we homogenize the roots and
they're very simple we just uh PL the
root homogenates on on Ager plates or um
on 96 microtiter plates with uh liquid
media and as you can see um by these two
methods we've now been able to isolate
more than 5,000 root derived um
bacterial colonies and then we determine
just by sequencing the 6 in s RNA Gene
sequences from all of these 5,800
bacterial colonies and this is why we
call our culture collection sequence
index risal libraries that are stored at
minus 80° and can be used then for
subsequent
experimentation so this is again to
remind you that our root culture
collection these 5,800 bacteria that
they are isolated from arabidopsis
plants growing in Cologne soil and in
parallel with our collaborator Julia
fold at the eth sirich um we've also
isolated Leaf Associated bacteria of
arabidopsis um about 3 and a half
thousand and keep in mind that these
leafes were harvested from arabidopsis
populations growing either um um
surround in turich or in the vicinity of
of tubing so at at a geographic distance
right so then in the next step this is
really the most critical one because
what we needed what we had to do is to
cross reference our culture Independent
Community data this is the six ands
Community profiling with a culture
dependent approaches to really estimate
you know what fraction of the root
microbot can we actually recover as pure
bacterial isolates and that's shown on
this slide where the Inner Circle all of
these small dots they represent
bacterial OT root Associated bacterial
otus from colog grow cologne soil grown
plants that we can resolve by the 6s
Community profiling and in the outer
ring these uh um uh black squares they
indicate hits in our culture collection
from these 5,800 culture collection and
the same is shown here for the leaf
deriv p culture collection so um in
total we've now recovered more than 60%
of the root and the leaf
Associated bacteria um so this is um
clearly not a perfect culture collection
we still have some gaps but it's
certainly way more than the 1% that the
microbial ecologist wanted us to to
believe so um the next question then was
so from from these thousands of
thousands of of root and leaf Associated
bacteria we've we've um um characterized
really and assembled a core collection
that is maximized for philogenetic um uh
diversity and that's shown by these
philogenetic trees in the center of
these um slides and and this represents
the color code is really according to
bacterium phm resolution so you see
actinobacteria bacteria futs and and
Proto bacteria but then what we wanted
to compare these two culture Collections
and we wanted to know how similar or
different this SAR are the bacteria that
associate with healthy roots and leaves
of arabidopsis and that is shown in the
most in the outermost ring by these
green arrowheads or by the the brown
arrowheads because uh this denotes a
strain from our culture collection from
leaves that shares greater than 97%
identical sixs sequences so it's
essentially it's the same species and uh
we were quite surprised to learn that 40
to 50% of the root and leaf D Bal
isolates share greater than 97 so
essentially are same sequences and and
the same bacterial species and we think
this is notable because recall our root
and Lea derived culture collections were
generated from plant material of
populations that are geographically
widely separated 500 kilometers
apart so that's something to keep in
mind uh for later on so then in the next
step we thought um um it would be useful
to determine whole genomes of all of our
root and leaf associ bacteria and we
generated whole genome assemblies and
also annotated U the genomes of 432
microb members and then inferred a whole
genome philogenetic tree which is shown
here which is largely congruent with a
philogenetic tree that is purely based
on the bacterial 6 ands ribosomal R but
this is mainly you know archival but I
think the genome sequences are of course
a very powerful resource and one thing
that we were of course interested in
having access to these whole genome
sequences is to study genomewide
functional diversity between microbot
members of the root and the the the um
um leaf microbot and what we use for
these experiments were really KAG
annotated genes or k annotated Pathways
and then simply compare how similar or
dissimilar are um those genes in in
these different genomes and what is
shown in these projections is each dot
represents a bacterial genomes and I've
colorcoded uh the dots such that the r
red dots uh represent root derived
bacteria and the green dots represent
Leaf derived bacteria and again
proximity is a measure of functional uh
similarity or functional overlap and uh
what we noted is that we can clearly
resolve different clusters functional
clusters functional capabilities of uh
these bacteria in our culture
collections but the functional clust
um they mainly correspond uh to um
bacterial phog to bacterial philogen so
that there's a strong philogenetic
signal but as you will see in most of
these clusters we find both root
Associated and leaf Associated members
so there must be a strong functional
overlap of members from the root and the
leaf microbol and there's actually only
very few clusters where you can see a
separation so at this level we observed
only weak signatures for n Niche
specialization at the whole genome level
and then Ruben gido he decided to take
this analysis one step further and to
look really for differential enrichment
of functions at at um um individual
functional categories and this for
example involves carbohydrate metabolism
membrane transport so these are high
level functions and what is shown here
this is a heat map and uh the relative
proportion of the genes that are
annotated to these high level biological
functions and in the upper part um Ruben
calculated for differential enrichment
between the root and the leaf microb
Auto members and what he noted was there
were two functional categories
carbohydrate metabolism and I think
cobotics biodegradation and Metabolism
where we see a highly significant uh
difference between the root and the leaf
microbol members so at this level we see
um clear evidence for Niche
specialization at individual at least at
two uh individual functional categories
and again you know this might become
important later on so now I would like
to come back and and to this scheme and
I hope I've convinced you that we have a
decent culture collection from the root
and the leaf microbot we have the whole
genomes and we thought now we in the
position that we can use this culture
collection and design synthetic mural
communities add them to germ free plants
and then test uh particular um
hypothesis so this is what we call
microbal reconstitution experiments in
the lab
so for this purpose I need to introduce
to you keline clay which is an inert
Matrix for condation of germ free
arabidopsis plants with defined
bacterial communities it's very simple
you use this sterile keline clay and
then you uh inoculate the keline clay
with defined input syn comps
simultaneously with a sewing of surface
sterilized arabidopsis seeds and then
you you close the container you grow the
plants to together with the microbes in
a closed container it's a magenta box
it's a very simple experimental system
was actually originally developed this
system by um in uh in the lotos yonos
community by y stat in in in Denmark and
then after seven weeks you determine
output syncom of kelen clay without host
roots and then you determine the output
uh syncom in the roots and leaves using
6s Community profiling so I need to
familiarize you how to read these uh
data we typically display them by heat
maps and that's shown here this is an
experiment where we've added a root
derived 188 member syncom so from our
culture collection these are all root
derived bacteria and this is the input
syncom and uh the numbers indicate
biological
replicates so each row indicates a BAL
replicate and each line represents
either a single bacterial strain or
group of bacterial strains and the color
code indic Ates the relative abundance
color code is relative abundance we try
for the for the input Community
inoculate U the bacteria at a 1:1 ratio
so when after 7 weeks if we look at the
root output Community you can see
there's a marked Community shift so this
community shift can either be dependent
on the host but it can also be host
independent and to discriminate between
those two possibilities we also
incubated the input Community for 7
weeks just in unplanted clay in the ABS
of those and you see also a marked
Community shift but if you then compare
the output community in unplanted clay
in Roots then you will note numerous
changes for example the relative
abundance of this bacterium increases
this one barely grows in unplanted clay
but in the presence of the root is
really dramatically enriched this
bacterium which is dominant in the
absence of the host becomes depleted
from root so you see really significant
changes but the surprise came when we
also analyzed leaves from these bacteria
so seven weeks later because we noted
that now many of the root derived
bacteria can also colonize arabidopsis
leap so there's an ectopic localization
and ectopic colonization of these Root
Drive bacteria that was uh somewhat
surprising now the nice thing about this
experimental system it's quite flexible
so um you can grow those arabidopsis
plants for 3 weeks then you can open the
magenta boxes and you can spray them
with a leaf derived bacteria and then
you incubate them co- incubate them for
another week and then do community
profiling after 7
weeks and I think this slide shows the
result again this is a highly Complex
Community 226 members this is the input
communities now we have only Leaf Drive
bacteria this is why the root ones are
negative are black and expectedly and we
were quite pleased about this most of
these Leaf Drive bacteria can abundantly
colonized leaves that's not so
surprising but the surprise again is if
you now look at the roots then you see a
substantial proportional subset of the
leaf derived bacteria can ectopically
also colonize Roots so bacteria from
Roots go up to leaves and bacteria from
leaves go down to roots of course we
have to quantify these results this is
where we use a bit more quantitative um
um analysis of these Community profiles
these are principal component analysis
of break Curtis dissimilarity matrices
in principle um each of these or in a
simple terms each of these dots
represents the community from a single
magenta box with four plants and uh what
I've colorcoded here this is the input
Community where we added The Root Drive
bacteria to the keline clay and these
are the output communities output
communities uh in the absence of the
host this is the root Associated output
community and the leaf Associated output
Community it's very clear that the root
and the leaf output communities are
different and they're also different
from the output communities in the
absence of the host so this is the host
Independent Community shift and this is
the host dependent Community shift and
this was the second experiment that I
explained to you uh where we spray
inoculate the leaf dve bacteria to
leaves and this is the input Community
output community on the leaves and
output Comm ectopic colonization on
Roots so take home message uh from these
experiments root and leaf derived sync
comps colonize cognate host organs but
they're also capable of ectopic leaf and
root colonization that's something that
was rather unexpected so summarize this
part of my presentation we interpret
these data such that the leaf microbot
appears to be a derived form of the roof
microba we think really the major
inoculum source for leaf Associated
bacteria are derived from root
Associated bacteria and from soil uh
bacteria and this is based on an
extensive species intersection between
the leaf and the root micro Waters using
this culture Independent Community
profiling and I think there's also now
support on the basis of whole genome
drafts more than 400 isolates that
revealed this large overlap of genome
encoded functional um capabilities but
also uh significant differences at the
level of individual functional
categories and I think this is now most
strongly supported by our microbol
reconstitution uh experiments showing
that leaf and Root Drive sycom colonize
cognet host organs and are capable of
ectopic leaf and and root colon and I
think this really raises the possibility
that um bacteria from Roots make it up
um to above ground parts and and vice
versa so I think there's an unexpected
dynamic between the leaf and the
microbot and I think some evidence I
don't have time to go into details um
we've also now strong evidence um for
microbot specialization to their
respective
Niche all right so I thought that in the
next um five or 10 minutes i' I'd tell
you a little bit more how we now take
advantage of our culture collections of
the root microbol to test proposed
functions of the microbot and one of the
proposed functions um from an early
timeo was really indirect pathogen
protection so this is now again a bottom
up approach where we use this
reconstitution experiments to to test
this this function and um for this
purpose I need to introduce to you
fusarium oxysporum I'm sure many of you
will be aware of this fungal pathogen of
arabid that severely inhibit arabidopsis
grows so if you grow arabidopsis just
eally on um on Ager plates this is how
it looks like you know for yeah
germ-free plants but if you add fusarium
oxos sporum um the plants really grow
very poorly and um one can actually
visualize growth of this fusarium uh
fungus by lectin staining pharum oxos is
a soil born vascular pathogen these are
the fungal hyi that surround paropsis
roots and the fungus also makes it into
the vasculature and um uh really this
this results in this severe um disease
symptoms and um what we were wondering
is and these are experiments from Yang
Bai and K hiruma what would happen if we
um co- inoculate Our Roots with fusarium
oxysporum spores and individual root
microbol from our culture collection
right and and this shows the difference
so the the presence of this B1 bacterium
plus oxos essentially rescues
arabidopsis grow and we can see also
some rescue in the presence of this
bacterium but this bacterium has no um
antifungal activity and uh this
correlates indeed if you look
microscopically um the the fusarium Hy
in the presence of these bacteria are
highly distorted and in in in in almost
all cases the fungus cannot any longer
enter the the vascular
of of of roots so of course we had to do
this more systematically and young and
and K they tested about 50 of our Riso
bacterial strains and we Quantified um
the protective activity of um these
bacteria against fusarium infection by
measuring shoot fresh weight and so
these are the controls uh this is if you
incubate arop plants with fusarium alone
uh the plants essentially die and if you
grow the maxic this is the this is a
shoot fresh weight and then this is the
shoot fresh weight in these Turner
interactions so the host the bacterium
and the fungus and we see a range of
infection phenotypes we can uh broadly
um Define three categories um one
category is these Riso bacteria where
there's unrestricted fusarium hyy growth
there's intermediate growth and then
these bacteria are really strongly
protect arabidopsis against f
and um if you um uh overlay um on these
results those bacteria that are highly
root and Rich you you will note that in
this class we find almost only bacteria
that are highly root enriched members of
the the microt and they are
taxonomically quite diverse um bacteria
so one of our hypothesis on the basis of
this result was that evolutionary
selection might have favored root microb
auto members with strong protective
activity against soil born pathogenic
funi so um Stefan Haka a postto in the
lab he decided to test this hypothesis
by extending our work from fusarium
oxysporum to another soulborn um really
an economically relevant pathogen vedum
and plos cumarina and another root
infecting um Kum pathogen kot trium
incanum but but he decided you know
rather than using this time consuming
and and really complex experiment with
the fungus the host and the bacterium
just to test binary interaction so just
co- incubate the fungal pathogens and
the individual rise of bacteria from our
culture collection so these are he
tested a total of 90 of them and then he
developed a quantitative readout to
measure fungal growth in these co-
cultures so this is all done in 96
microtiter plates and the results of
these testing the interactions of these
rise of bacteria individual rise of
bacteria with these four different fungi
the results are shown in from triplicate
experiments for each of the four fungi
and they are visualized by a heat map
where the cool blue colors indicate
fungal growth inhibition and the red
colors indicate growth promotion and I
hope you agree with me uh what we could
see is that the individual um uh
philogenetic lineages of the root
microbot that prefer that confer strong
protective activity against all of these
four fungi for example these araa
uh than the pseudomonas here and the
mesor rium and there are other ones the
streptomyces they're very potent against
fum oxysporum but their activity against
plos Karina is is is lousy and So based
on these results and when we compare the
results from these binary uh interaction
screen with these uh tritrophic
interaction uh system you will note that
there's clear overlap between the
results so what we conclude from these
EXP performance is that specific
taxonomic lineages of the bacterial root
micr water exert direct inhibitory
activity you don't necessarily need the
host that that's very important um and
against a wide range of soil born
pathogenic root colonizing fungi so what
we infer from these experiments that
indirect protection against soil born
fungal pathogen is a major physiological
function of the arop bacterial root
microbot so essentially it looks it it
looks you know as as if arabidopsis
really recruits a subset of the soil
bacteria right and and that many of
these root Associated and root enriched
bacteria uh help the plant to protect
itself against attack from these um soil
born fungal
pathogens now you could still criticize
us and you could say well you know this
is um you've just tested one fungus one
bacterium and one host it's still not in
a community context so this is really
now I think going in the right direction
um where we've uh now tested um this is
in the keline clay system if you just
focus on this one uh these are germfree
plants uh this is when we add 30 of our
bacterial Riso bacteria that we've
tested also in the in the binary or the
tritrophic interaction system the plants
still grow happily but this is if we
really incubate the plants with our
deadly mix of of four soil born fungal
pathogens and the plants essentially die
and if you add then the fungal community
and the 30 micro members you see this
rescue so I think this suggests really
that um the protection against the
soulborn pathogen also can be reproduced
under laboratory conditions in a
community
context all right so I think do I still
have yes I think I still have 10 minutes
or so um because I promised that during
the last part of my presentation and
also because Maria is in the uh in the
audience um I mentioned in my
introduction that the root that the
plant microbot does not involve only
bacteria but they are also association
between healthy plants and fungi and
this illustrates the beautiful
biodiversity of fungi root Associated
fungi that we've isolated from
arabidopsis Roots and uh so these are
all um uh fungal endophytes that we've
isolated from surface sterilized
arabidopsis Roots grown in natural soil
now
one difficulty with the uh fungal
endophytes or with the fungal microbot
if you like is that plant Associated
fungi are hyper diverse in natural plant
populations so this is fundamentally
different from the bacterial root microw
water recall you know I mentioned to you
there's a highly reproducible taxonomic
structure consisting of this Proto
bacteria actinobacteria and so on but
for fungi you know this is terrible you
know you you you just isolate too many
um and and that makes it difficult to
discriminate between stochastic
encounters and associations that have
ecophysiological relevance that's really
that's a challenge and one way to
overcome that limitation is that you
sample over successive years and this
illustrates you how we've done it and I
want to discuss with you this is work
that is now in revision um um um yeah
how we do those those experiments so we
isolate ated this fungus which is called
colot trium teli from healthy
asymptomatic plants in natural
arabidopsis populations of the central
plateau of Spain and and you can see
these are four different populations and
uh it's really an endemic fungus uh in
the central plateau of Spain We examined
habitats from Germany and France and we
could not detect this Fung but here you
it's really it's persistent over
consecutive years there was one other
reason why this fungus attracted us uh
and I think the the the Pathologists you
know may know this because um almost all
characterized colit trium fungal species
cause plant diseases you know this is
Tel these are some of its cousins and
they cause diseases on fruits and leaves
and Roots so um so why you know why is
this fungus is it capable to engage in
association with healthy asymptomatic
plants so that was something that we
wanted to understand in Greater detail
and one important clue really came uh
from a closer look at the natural
habitat where you find this fungus so I
I don't know whether any one of you had
ever had the chance to visit the central
plateau of Spain this is really a harsh
environment and the soil um is very low
in nutrients in particular it's it's low
in in in phosphate and so these poor
arabidopsis plants they really have a
hard time to survive in these
arabidopsis
populations so um uh what we thought is
um to better characterize sorry I need
to go back to better characterize this
system that we again apply our
reductionist approach that I explained
to you before with the bacterial
microbot with this um plant fungus
interaction and so we generated uh a
transgenic uh gfp expressing kriel we
inoculated it with the germfree aops
plants this an aops plants expressing a
plma membrane Mar protein and we notice
this if fungus really forms dense extra
rical Hy surrounding arabidopsis Roots
but if you take a cross-section through
a root this is really remarkable you
know the fungus um ramifies within the
root tissue it's um you know these are
all fundal Hy you find them between uh
arbid opsis root cells but also inside
root cells is really extensive
colonization of of of the root and
without causing visible symptoms so in
the lab the plants stay healthy so um
because of this habitat feature and the
low nutrient um conditions we wondered
you know what will happen uh if we grow
arabidopsis under defined nutrient
limiting conditions and we tested
phosphate nitrate and uh this is um the
typical seven know these are four week
old arabidopsis plants grown under low
phosphate conditions 50 micro at this
condition um arabidopsis initiates the
phosphate station response the roots are
stunted and there's red used shoot
biomass and this is what happens when
you add this col to trium toel roots are
elongated and there's an increase in
shoot biomass we can quantify uh the
shoot fresh weight um this is the mock
control this is if you add the tof
fungus so there's a growth promotion
activity this is an important control
heat killed fungus and this is another
important control when we add the cousin
of telde which is the pathogenic incanum
root colonizing incanum fungus and
there's a of course a reduction in in
biomass and importantly under high
phosphate level so sufficient phosphate
level if you add the fungus there's no
increase in SHO biomass but it's not
only that arabidopsis gr that this
fungus promotes arabidopsis growth under
uh low phosphate but it also increases
the fertility so the reproductive
Fitness of the plants and you can
measure that simply by counting the
number of fruits of arabidopsis and
there's it's very clear there's an
increase in the fruit number
so how how does this fungus promote
arabidopsis growth under phosphate
limiting conditions and this is how we
took advantage of the tools that have
been developed by the microa community
and um the way how we conduct these
experiments we grow arabidopsis plants
on um these large Ager plates and inside
the Ager plates we um we place a small
patri dish and in the small petri dish
uh we add the fungal spores and uh we
add p 33 so Auto phosphate radioactively
labeled Auto phosphate and then what
happens is the fungus grows you know
outside of this inner compartment
establishes connectivities with the
roots and then we measure radioactivity
in the chotes after 3 weeks of
co-incubation and the results the kilo
beel you know per gram dry weight in
individual plants is shown in in this
plot and I hope you agree with me that
there is really a remarkable amount of
phosphate that is transferred from the
Fungus via the H via the roots uh to the
Chute and importantly if we now use the
pathogenic cousin of
kriel there's um you know very minor
transfer and what I find even more
remarkable under high phosphate
conditions so phosphate sufficient
amounts then this beneficial fungus teli
cannot transform any longer phosphate to
the shoes so what this tells us is that
the transfer of phosphate is strictly
regulated on phosphate availability in
the medium right so we wondered of
course what is the genetic control of
this and I mentioned before that
arabidopsis and all plants have
developed a complex genetic system uh to
monitor phosphate availability and then
to adjust growth in response to
phosphate station that's the phosphate
station response system and so we
wondered you know whether this growth
promotion that we see in wild typ plants
whether that is dependent on these
genetic components and this shows you
one results this is the phf1 gene that
is actually necessary to release
phosphate Transporters from the ER to
the plasma membrane and if you look into
that mutant you know clearly um the
plant growth promotion is impaired and
what I find more interestingly if you
now measure fungal biomass in this
mutant only under low phosphate
conditions then you see excessive growth
so then this very sophisticated
beneficial interaction is is is
impaired all right so then in the next
step we were interested in examining um
um at the transcriptome level changes
transcriptional reprogramming induced by
the fungus and so for this purpose we've
carried out time resolved RNA seek
experiments and um we noted that in
arabidopsis Roots um there's a large
number of genes that are differentially
regulated these are 16 pair wise
comparisons very complex uh data set but
I want to pay your attention just to
this cluster of genes cluster nine genes
that are specifically
upregulated in the presence of
sufficient amounts of phosphate and in
the presence of the beneficial fungus
but they are not upregulated in the
presence of the fungus and phosphate
deficient conditions and if you look you
know what do these genes encode they are
strongly enriched in genes that are
involved in innate immune responses so
it looks as if arabidopsis activates
defense gene expression um and innate
immune responses to the fungus
specifically only in the presence of
sufficient phosphate but not under
phosphate deficiency and there was one
cluster of genes from these cluster n
genes that attracted it specifically uh
because these are genes that encode for
indol and tryptophane metabolic
processes and there's a particular
reason for this because several years
ago we had shown that this class of
compound s and and and these genes
encode indog glucosinolates a class of
secondary metabolites in arabidopsis
that these confer potent immune
responses to fungal pathogens so we
wondered what would happen if we deplete
arabidopsis plants of the biosynthesis
of these uh secondary metabolites and
you can do that in arabidopsis by uh
using a double mutant of these p450
genes and the result is shown here so
these plants in the absence of the
pathogens they just grow like wild type
plants there there's no effect but then
if you add the beneficial fungus it
kills the host so now in the absence of
these compounds The Beneficial call it a
triom toel fungus becomes a
pathogen so I think what this tells us
is that these secondary metabolites that
have been proposed to have antibiotic
functions again pathogens that they may
have novel functions and they they
clearly are necessary for the
establishment of an interaction with a
beneficial root Associated fungus and I
think that's somewhat um um
thought-provoking so end of data slides
I think I'd like to zoom out and just
like to put this work a little bit into
a broader uh context um uh so I think
what this slide really shows is the
increase of uh word fertilizer
consumption and I showed you that this
beneficial fungus really provides
phosphate um to its host and help the
plant to mobilize phosphate from soil
and it's also clear that phosphate is
just one of the three nutrients um uh
that we use in synthetic fertilizers
next to nitrate and to potassium and
it's it's also clear that these um
synthetic fertilizers help to feed the
world roughly 50% of the plant
productivity is due to the use of
fertilizers and 50% is plant genetics
but you I guess you will also agree with
me that the the excessive use of
fertilizers has detrimental effects on
the environment and and in addition you
know Global Sources for phosphate in
fertilizers are limited and this
certainly fuels interest in isolating
novel biofertilizer microbes from from
the plant
microbot so but leaving apart this
translational aspect I hope I've been
able to convince you that really what
plant microbot research is about it's
about studying interactions between soil
microbial communities and plants
genotype and I think this offers unique
possibility it creates new interfaces
between um uh disciplines of of of
science that are traditionally more
separated you know terrestrial
microbiology plant science geochemistry
and and and soil science so I think this
is really where we operate and where I
would like to yeah to extend our work
over the next 5 10 well let's see how
long but um yeah um okay so um I've come
to the conclusion most important slide
is really to acknowledge a fantastic
underground group I think I've mentioned
most of them in passing um uh I should
perhaps really give credit to the
computational scientist Ruben Garo or
Gary shrinivas and of course to our
collaborator on the leaf microt Daniel
Miller and Julia fold from the eth
surich and a number of f funding
agencies and then we have a number of
other external collaborators Ellis
mccardy Julie for hold I mentioned
before Jeff dangle of course Simona rut
toy and cor
Peterson so um thanks very much for your
[Applause]
attention oo well in the in the
manuscript of course we Shi away from
any
mechanistic um interpretation but
actually if you if you um look into the
literature Frank deso actually uh in the
US has done experiments with gfp tagged
risia um where he had shown inoculated
them to rise roots and he had shown that
these Rovia then over time uh can be
recovered um from above ground Parts
again how they get there whether they
you know are um whether they make it via
the transpiration stream or outside you
know on the root surface on the um root
surface that is entirely unclear here
but I think um the other way um so from
leaves back to Roots um I think this
happens well more or less on a daily
basis because every rain shower you know
will wash off uh Leaf Associated
bacteria then so it's definitely
possible that uh Leaf associate bacteria
makes it into the soil and then Rec
colonizes the root so this is I think
really a yeah a connected system of of
leaf and root Associated bacteria
no no no no actually in this in this um
closed compartment system in the keline
clay We water them initially um and we
make sure um we water them at um um
maximum water retention capacity and
then we have to rewater them once so we
open the magenta boxes under clean bench
and then carefully add sterile water
just to avoid any
perturbation um yeah I think that's but
it's a it's a good
point ah Ellen yes so with your uh
caline clay
uh population shift experim if instead
of using uh
PL extracts
or a plastic FL or
other you see similar shifts in the
population whole we haven't done those
experiments because we always feel that
it is important to do experiments in a
whole organism context um but I think um
somewhat similar experiments have been
done by NOAA here in the US and he used
um he implanted organic carbon sources
into unplanted soil and it's it's very
clear that organic carbon is the most
important rate limiting step for uh
growth of soil born bacteria so in
unplanted soil organic car is always
rate limiting and so I think one of our
hypothesis indeed is that this whole
process of community establishment in is
initiated by organic carbons that are
released um bya root exudation and that
serves you know initiates a substrate
driven Community establishment process
but this is you know hand waving at the
moment but I I think it becomes
experimentally tractable
now yes please that
se is beneficial to the plant but only
if the plant has certain secondary
metabolics can you say more about how
that works with those
metabolites without it they become it
becom um yeah I think these are really
important questions actually it's um I I
showed only a small part of the data um
and maybe
maybe um yes so for example you know
this is it becomes a pathogen if we
deplete all of these Branch Pathways
we've of course also genetically
depleted this Branch pathway the pen two
Mutant and then you specifically impair
the plant growth promotion but the plant
is still doing well so one hypothesis is
that actually these metabolic products
may have yeah even a signaling role in
growth promotion that's one
possibilities um we know when we deplete
um chin production there's no effect
whatsoever so maybe one interpretation
is that these secondary
metabolites um constrain the growth or
limit the growth of the fungus to a
certain extent and then if you uh
deplete them then um the fun there's
excessive growth and that's consistent
with the fact that at least in the sub
79 B2 B3 mutant um you know there's um
uh things six or Sevenfold increased
fungal biomass compared to wild typ
plants so it looks as if the fungal
colonization is uncontrolled in the
absence of of these secondary
metabolites yes yes because what we've
used um we've used a reporter line U for
plasma membrane Mar protein quorin and
so we can clearly see that the high that
grow inside root cells um are surround
it um by a plasma membrane we're quite
confident about that yes and have
you no not yet no not yet yeah we're
testing of course many many more um
mutants in this pathway um yeah no I
think there's much more that can be
tested I
agree well um I haven't done those
experiments first of all um but we've
taken indeed um we've taken
cross-section through different regions
of the root and we see colonization
really from um yeah from almost from the
root tip to um uh highly differentiated
rots including secondary uh growth so I
think there's no we cannot really
pinpoint at the moment uh a particular
um development stage of the root where
this fungus would establish these
associations I think this is actually a
disadvantage of the system you know the
uh it's unlike in microa where you have
these beautifully uh abascal you know
this is really um yeah the fungus is is
ramifying throughout the root cortex and
occasionally even makes it into a into
the central cylinder but that is really
only um on rare occasions but it's
mainly found in the in the root
cortex oh yes ah so this very important
so we thought if this were true it's too
bad I don't have the slide with me so
um we tested arabidopsis relatives and
for example kadam huta which is a
relative of taliana but kadam huta is
naturally lacks the capacity for calaxin
production and um I mentioned before
that if we genetically impair CX in
production arabidopsis we see retained
growth promotion and so in kadam huta
also this fungus colonizes arabidopsis
and promotes growth but when we tested
capsella rubella capsella rubella is one
of the very few brasic Casia that has
lost the capacity for indog
glucosinolate production then capsella
rubella looks like a SI 17 B2 B3 double
mutant so it kills capsella and this is
relevant because in Spain capsella
rubella and arabidopsis talana share the
same habitat so I think one of our
hypothesis is that these secondary
metabolites are actually a Host range
determinant so um yeah at least that's
what the data tell us so far yes yes now
I think this is one of the central
questions you know how to
um what's a minimum complexity
Community what
determines uh the taxonomic structure
this highly reproducible taxonomic
structure of the
community um and and of course now
having access to this culture collection
enables us to test this you're
absolutely right you know if you have 26
Root Drive bacteria the number of
combinations you can test is beyond
possibility so you need to have some
strategic plan um one possibility is you
can deplete particular taxonomic
lineages let's say you take away the
Proto bacteria um another one is you you
can take away the bacteriodes that that
would be one way another possibility is
it's realistic you can test in binary
interactions um interactions between the
bacteria themselves so that is a
possible and this is one route that that
we are pursuing because we believe that
antagonis mytic interactions so bacteria
bacteria interactions are very important
for microbol
establishment but that's these are
ongoing but very important
experiments yeah we do experimental
evolution in the lab now so we use our
culture collection and then we apply a
defined nutrient stress for example low
phosphate and then we incubate them with
the bacteria then we um isolate um the
synthetic community um and then we
reinoculate for a second time and we're
now I think at generation six or
Generation 7 um on the host side and um
the bacterial of course these are
thousands and thousands of bacterial
generations and so this is really I
don't know whether this will work but
that's one idea that you can apply um
experimental Evolution strategies and
you can test whether there's a realtime
Evolution um to yeah support plant
growth but then
that's um yeah that's something for the
future yes that's another I think this
is you know this is why um you know we
tend to say in Cologne you know we are
facing the candy shop problem you know
more or less you can start so many
things now that it's um and if you start
too many things you can feel really bad
so I think one needs to prioritize very
very um carefully um so so so remind me
again that the the the resilience of yes
yes yes yes absolutely so this is
something that we are now um that's a
project that we've started actually in a
collaboration with shenan he not far
from here Michigan um we now um we do
barcoding of our bacterial culture
collection with a tn7 you know you can
you can barcode them and then we can add
because the fundamental question about
resilience of the community is so if you
I I think the the major function of a
community is that it's more than the sum
of the parts so there are emerging
properties that you cannot explain you
know on the basis of the individuals and
I think a a a very popular um uh theory
in in um um ecology is that a community
whatever community of organism um is um
resistant to invasion of um alien
members so um what we do now with our
bar coded Root Drive bacteria that we
add them to a
preformed um root microbot of plants
grown in different soil types and then
we can test their Invasion and
persistence so I think this is one way
uh we know this is a very rare event
that really a bacterium can intrude can
make it you know into a preformed
Community the molecular basis of this I
think that is again it's years of
research ahead
but it's it's certainly something that
is of fundamental importance to
understand
um in it's I think it's in part it's
already you know during establishment of
these bacterial communities that um yeah
these bacteria must be competitive they
must out compete all of their
competitors that are in the in the soil
zillions and zillions of bacteria so
they they must have a very high
competitiveness yes yes oh yeah the
these are again very important questions
so of course now we have um as I tried
to explain um our core culture
Collections and we have the whole genome
sequences one way to infer um functions
of the microbot is you use metagenomic
approaches but a major limitation of
metagenomic approaches is that only 20%
of the sequences could actually be um
annotated now um when we use our whole
genome sequencing is it looks like as if
you know the um the number of genes that
we can annotate on the basis of
metagenome approaches is really
dramatically U increases so I think I
hope that with the whole genome
sequences that our future metag genome
um uh approaches will become more
meaningful uh that's one thing but I
also believe that
um or at least one hypothesis is that
the adaptation or the the the functional
adaptation is not in the core genome but
it's in the accessory or in the Pang
Genome of of these bacterial communities
and this may explain why we have this
highly reproducible taxonomic structure
and irrespective of whether we grow you
know plants you know in the US or in
Europe or in Asia or whatsoever we
always end up with the same taxonomic
structure but um of course looking at
the whole genome level there may be
signals of biogeography and there may be
adaptations to particular environments
that's that's my
hypothesis um yeah and and so again it's
it's it's a long-term question that I
think through um increased availability
of whole genome sequences and hopefully
many many more systematic culture
collections we can address this
systematically let thank Paul again
[Applause]
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu