this is a production of Cornell
University thank you
Jenny thank you I'll try and live up to
that wonderful introduction I feel uh a
little bit over empowered by that um
yeah so I am a microbial ecologist I
actually started out my life as a marine
microbial ecologist and um applying the
rules of how bacteria communicate with
each other and with their environment
how they sense things uh to
understanding how they do that in many
other ecosystems what it is a really
amazing time to be a microbial ecologist
this is the one of the few times in
history where people have actually taken
us really deadly seriously the first
time was probably in the late 19th
century when they found out bacteria
could kill you and now they found out
that bacteria can make people healthy
they're really starting to pay attention
and what's great is that the
Horticultural world is starting to pay
attention as well and the fact that the
bacteria that colonize plants and live
on the outsides of plants and insides of
plants actually may be playing a role in
the health of the plant now obviously
this isn't anything new um in fact if
anything the agricultural world has led
the world of science in utilizing and
understanding how bacteria play a role
in the health of plants you know uh you
can't look at nitrogen fixation any
other way but it's been incredibly
important for us as researchers to
understand how all of the ecological
interactions that go on inside the
ecosystem which is a plant uh how they
play a role in the health and
productivity and development of these or
organisms so something to do with plants
and microbes um I changed my title uh I
I am did found the Earth microbiome
project around 5 years ago this was a an
effort to catalog microbial diversity in
as many environments as we could find um
with my colleagues Rob Knight and Janet
Jansen we we really tried to push this
forward as a as a an opportunity to look
into ecosystems and build out a
repository to help us understand how
many organisms there were uh their
potential functions and how they were
interacting with the world around them
on a global scale so you know uh as was
famous for Chicago we had no small plans
it was a very big undertaking we were
very ambitious at the beginning and then
we started to ramp back our Ambitions as
we found out quite how difficult it was
to get people to share their samples and
share their data um we initially thought
well everybody will want to have the
microbiome sequence of course cuz the
microbiome's awesome and then we quickly
realized that people were not
necessarily as excited about sharing all
of their carbon data and uh you know all
the ancer data that we thought was just
anid data which turned out to be
people's PhD thesises and uh and
Publications uh they weren't quite as
willing to share that upfront as we
thought they would be and and so we
started to scale back our Ambitions but
to date um with over the 400
collaborators we have we processed
around 50,000 samples for um 16s
ribosomal RNA sequencing about half of
those for about for 18s ribor sequencing
and then um a smattering of those for
shotgun metagenomics as we slowly burnt
through our um Financial supplies and
contacts these represent over 50 large
scale biomes a biome being like open
ocean or um prairie soil you know um and
there's around 60 6 billion sequences in
this database um with a little over 27
million bacterial TXS are identified um
and the data analysis is occurring in
the public forum all of this data is
made publicly available immediately
um we haven't actually published any of
the results of this study other people
have been publishing it for us um and as
I was I was talking to Terry on the way
from the airport I was saying well you
know we'd be quite happy if someone
wanted to take all this data and
actually publish it because it's a pain
in the ass to try and analyze it so that
would be that would be fantastic there
is a people coming out have been
utilizing some of this data to try and
understand how many species there might
be on earth and to predict that number
of species and there are exciting
studies coming out that utilizing this
data to understand biogeographic
patterns um pattern associations with
different climactic variables etc etc
but I'm going to talk a little bit about
how we've utilized some of these data
and other studies in order to try and
derive um some kind of large scale
ecological understanding of the
interactions between plants and bacteria
and over soil systems so um one of the
first ones we did as part of the EMP was
work with Rebecca MCU and um and Fiera
on modeling utilizing microbial
Community Systems to model how bacterial
communities varied across um a range of
prairie conditions in the midwest so
collecting samples from tall Relic uh
sorry Relic Tall Grass Prairie sites
meant creeping into uh basically
graveyards in the dead of night and
taking soil cores and into disused
railway lines anywhere that hadn't
really been used um for agricultural
activity since around 1850 um this meant
Civil War graveyards um we we basically
collected samples from those because
they were the least contaminated by
agricultural activity Illinois has lost
about 98 to 99% of its Prairie I mean
you know that's a remarkable uh
degradation of a natural biological
environment and one that you know we we
bitterly complain with other countries
try and uh you know agricultural eyesee
their land in you know in the
destruction of the Amazon rainforest but
look what we did to one of our primary
biological environments nearly
comprehensively destroyed it but we
utiliz this information to look at the
microbial communities um in different
sites around this um this from the
extent of this Prairie system and then
we interpolated and extrapolated Beyond
those points to understand how climactic
variables that exist now correlate with
the position of those microbes um along
with plant variables and then we
hindcast that back to around 1840 to
when the Prairie was complete so the the
extent of the Midwest um gr tall grass
land Prairie system had a distribution
that looked something like that by
mapping our um association between
climactic variables and plant
distribution patterns we were able to
identify the uh predicted relative
abundances of of organisms like the Vero
microbia fym um across that system and
generate some kind of predictive
understanding of the distribution of
that organism now why is that important
well baruka microbia are hard to culture
um the entire film has very few cultured
representatives in our databases um they
flourish where carbon nitrogen ratios
are very high um because they they they
don't necessarily do so well when you
have a lot of nitrogen they're good at
Carbon metabolism and they're good at
activating resources which can be used
by certain types of plants and so when
soils are turned over to Agriculture and
you get an increase in nitrogen you see
these things disappearing very quickly
and we're very interested in trying to
identify ways to restore these Prairie
ecosystems and we you know it's so very
well to go in and you know rip out all
of the existing vegetation and just
plant a load of new seeds and that
that's proven to be very effective in
certain systems but we're also Keen to
say well how can we create stable
ecosystems how can we rebuild carbon
processes and organic matter pools
Within These systems which support the
uh the autonomous preservation of that
environment and to do that we had to
understand those bacteria which were
significantly related to that and more
importantly their functional diversity
and their capability of supporting car
Caron and nitrogen turnover in these
environments right so this may seem a
little bit like oh wow they us time
traveling statistics to predict what
things look like 150 years ago whoopy
dooo but if you yeah it does look like
that but but that's not necessarily the
the be and endle what we're really
trying to do is capture the system and
understand how that system varies
understand what perturbs it what leads
to its stability so that we can try and
recreate it not just in our computers
but in the field and so working with um
other researchers around the Midwest and
on the East Coast we're now trying to
implement some of the work that we've
done here in small plots and actually
build out new systems where we where we
have restored Prairie sites um we've
also been working on this in uh in a
different context um but across
climactic gradient so this is work we're
doing um with my colleagues in National
Chinese Academy of Science is um trying
to understand the differentiation in
forest ecosystems um across a a
climactic gradient along the east coast
of China so um work in collaboration
between our Labs we took samples along
this gradient 110 so samples from both
natural undisturbed forests um across
this this gradient um and then basically
analyze the diversity of ARA bacteria
and fungi um this paper is uh in
submission I'll show you a lot of data
today
uh that's not yet been published so um
you can you can feel free to peer review
critique it as much as you want uh but
I'm I've always been very upfront about
presenting the data that we we are
already working on I think it's
important to get feedback from the
community and also if you can analyze it
faster than we can then go for it that'd
be cool um but um so you know we see a
lot of Kota we see a lot of AF prodia no
big deal we see a lot of ASCO myota um
but we do see amazing biogeographic
variance and we can map and model that
variance to large scale Network patterns
to ID identify strong correlative
interaction space between different
kingdoms of organisms so every dot here
is a bacterial otu every Green Dot is a
eukariotic OU blue is ARA uh red uh
black lines sorry are positive and the
red interactions you can't see many of
those in fact I can't even see them and
I'm looking that close there's some
there are are negative co-associations
and this again just looks like a morass
of of network information but by teasing
apart the topology of these networks we
can actually start to understand how
some climactic variables can lead to
differentiation in coassociation
patterns so all these connections are
strong and significant only those with a
spearmans of greater than 0.7 are
actually identified in this network
structure each size of each node is
proportional to the relative abundance
of the organism and there there's 66,000
associations among 3,000 microbial to
use okay um sorry nearly 4,000 90% of
these interactions are Global and only
10 are region specific so there are
inherent structures within forest
ecosystems across the Eastern seab Board
of China which are globally distributed
no matter what we see in the system
suggesting that there's Niche
specificity within a forest ecosystem
irrespective of the climactic region but
the inherent variance in the system this
10% of these interactions which are
region specific that's what yields
climatic range specificity and that
climatic range specificity is what's
interesting to us because by
understanding the variance between
regions we can start to understand what
makes an ecosystem important in that
environment because those organisms may
be important to the system ecology
um so looking at this if we look at um
how we interpret that Network topology
the connectivity of the network is
greater we get more connections more
significant interactions between
bacteria ARA and and UK carats up in the
um in the northern region compared to
the southern region we get greater
precipitation in the South it's a
semi-tropical environment um and we
believe that this greater precipitation
leads to decreased Niche differentiation
essentially you're getting more moisture
connectivity in the environment moisture
connectivity allows microbes to uh move
out of their individual pockets and
interact more on a global scale
indirectly through um metabolite
transfer and directly through movement
um and so you get an Inc a decrease in
the in the um specific Niche
connectivity between organisms and an
increase in broadscale characterization
of network space so lower precipitation
North induces a strong Niche
differentiation basically organisms
clustering down in their little niches
um diff disassociated from other
organisms which may be a millimeter away
on another organic Mass matter particle
and that that Niche differentiation is a
globally attributable trait um in a
study I'm not going to talk about in
detail actually not going to mention
apart from right now when I am going to
mention it um but the hospital
microbiome project we in this study we
we followed a hospital environment um 10
patient rooms two nursing stations for
365 consecutive days cataloging all of
the patients on three body surfaces and
all the staff and all of the
environments within the hospital um some
50 different surfaces including air and
water and we looked at the bacterial
community structure across all of these
environments and we see that people
share more bacteria between each other
um including patients to staff and staff
to patients and staff to staff when the
environment has more humidity basically
when bacteria have the capability of
surviving outside the body we see a
definitive increase in Sharing what's
interesting and I again I'm telling you
on published data which is currently in
review but um just don't tell any
um we don't see an increase in disease
burden in that population so this
increase in microbial sharing isn't
leading to an increase in horizontal
sorry so Hospital acquired infections
it's just Distributing microbes on a
bigger scale in fact if anything we see
a small depression and we can talk about
what that means until the cows come home
but moisture is very important it allows
for connectivity it allows for increased
activity and movement of organisms
between sites I I am very tangental as
well if I go off on a too weird a track
does someone throw something at me and
I'll I'll try get back on to what I was
talking about before anyway so utilizing
this information we can start to build
out um uh InterContinental and
transcontinental understanding of of
microbial community structure and what
it means in a system so this is the
Tibetan Plateau North America collecting
samples in transects um um and dotted
samples around areas and transects
around the Tibetan Plateau across
climactic regions we can start to
interpolate and build maps of microbial
community structure across these systems
and Link them into climactic variables
in an attempt to try and predict how
these systems respond to climate
changing environmental systems so um
don't if this work but yeah are so this
is the Tibetan Plateau starting in 1900
we're now in 1925 1930 with annual
averages and the shift in microbial
community structure uh or Bea diversity
across the whole system as we move
across um a de sorry a cent of climactic
variance um what we see in this pretty
picture is a is a significant change in
the let me just play it again so you can
see it while I'm talking about it is a
significant change in the community uh
fluctuation in the in the
differentiation of microbial community
structure as parts of the system become
uh destabilized due to increasing
temperatures as parts of the system
become highly productive due to
increasing carbon dioxide and as
agricultural activity takes over in the
uh in the latter part of the 20th
century um yes how do you know what it
was in 1910 cuz I went back there I'm
I'm English I'm a time traveler um have
you not watched Doctor Who uh so it's
it's it's it's hindcasting we actually
have pretty good climactic records back
to 1910 prior to 1910 they don't exist
there were weather stations present in
parts of Tibet back then um and they
were you know first part by the British
and then and then later by um some of
the French and then the Chinese but the
the the systems been reasonably well
monitored and we have good records for
Global Climate variables at degrees of
resolution for pretty much the whole
globe back to a certain level mostly
interpolated from existing data so I
mean it's a model so oh yeah
everything's a model so it agrees with
your model yeah yeah yeah damn right can
you can you prove me wrong um no no I'm
I'm I'm I'm not trying to predict what
happened beforehand I'm trying to
understand if anything what the
relationship is between microbial
Community desability or stability
between years and climactic variables
and because I can even within a 5-year
Grant I can only get 5 years of that
data I have to try and predict outside
the bounds um but you can use this to
make predictions about what's happening
now with you know at a fine scale if you
understand what the long-term trends
might be so again this is just a pretty
picture but underlying it is sort of
fundamental statistical model which can
help us to extrapolate and predict
beyond our measures so in here what's
interesting is the microbial community
structure of present day Tibet is best
predicted why I'm talking to you alone
stand here um best predicted by the the
climactic variables in between 1968 and
1972 so if we look at the which again
it's a bit weird right but if we look at
the climate in 1968 1972 that is the
climate which best correlates with what
we observe in current day Tibet and the
same is actually equally true for um for
North America and if we take that as a a
variable um predictive algorithm it
means that we can predict if nothing
changed on Earth uh for the next 30
years taking today's climate we can
predict what we should see the system
stabilized to in about 30 years time so
on that basis um this is obviously
Tibetan North America this is the
current richness and um in over the next
30 years if we believe that climate has
this relationship between uh time and
microbial community structure we'll see
a significant shift in richness
basically the systems will become in
increase in richness due to
destabilization of community structure
and reduction in abundance of certain
key organisms but whereas um most of
Tibet will show originally homogeneous
predictive capability the um the uh the
North American Coast will show a highly
heterogeneous response variable but
still majority will increase in in
richness and um if you see the similar
ity between what happens in Northern
Canada and what happens in this other
basically semi Arctic Zone they call
napole the third pole on Earth we see a
similar increase in richness due to a
destabilization of of the um of the adic
variables in the soil system obviously
this is highly linked to plants but what
we haven't done at all is used plants in
any of these calculations we would love
to but we don't have a lot of the data
what we do see is um uh variance in the
types of bacteria that we find
um across these different systems and we
can correlate that to plant inputs so in
Tibet we'll see an increase in Alpha
prot bacteria let me qualify that
statement we predict if everything stays
normal and there's no inputs at all that
we'll see a increase in Alpha bacteria
in a decrease in North America okay of
PR bacteria in both of these systems in
these soil systems show a significant
correlation to carbon nitrogen ratio and
therefore we believe that this could be
linked into um um and moisture and could
be linked into a distribution in the
change in below carbon inputs into this
system right so by changing below carbon
inputs based on changing um um uh uh
plant uh biodiversity and plant
structure we'll see a shift in the
microbial community structure again we
we do but at least we've got some kind
of understanding of the potential
implications and we're now trying to use
this to predict occurrences each year in
in these systems but it's very broad
scale we're hoping to get much finer
resolution as we move forward with our
ability to classify the system okay um
to something totally different Mero um I
know I know I was talking I was talking
with the guys working on uh reasing
earlier um you know we we start out in
Mero I I I also love wine um think it's
awesome um and we were very interested
in the connectivity between above ground
tissues in imp plants and what was
happening in the soil and trying to
understand the potential implications
for um strain type variant and microbial
community structure and adic variables
in soil systems so um number one this is
just a a map if the dots are closer
together more similar the black dots
represent otus
ha sorry the black dots represent
bacterial taxa um and the the colored
big dots represent a sample and so what
we've done is basically taken all of the
dots the all the otus and the similarity
and the abundances of those otus starts
to drag together or pull apart um
individual sample types so bulk Z soil
and root Zone call a root Zone it wasn't
risos spere it was just the soil around
the roots um uh all cluster very closely
together because they're very similar
environments and then your root system
so the rise of plane starts to
differentiate significantly from that
and as you move up into grapes and
leaves and and yellow flowers we see a
significant differentiation but you
notice that the otus that are shared in
the soil are also shared down here there
are lots and lots of these lines
connecting these green and yellow plots
down to the the yellow and sorry the
blue and red plots over here and so that
that immediately told us that that the
vast majority of otus of bacterial TXS
that we found up in the above ground
tissues came from down here or were also
found down here uh if they didn't come
down there they came from there by some
other route um below ground you know you
see um a significant differentiation in
the high level functional struct
community structure of the these
communities um the proteo bacteria
dominating those above ground systems
and mostly organisms which are good at
dealing with stressful environments um
if we if we look at the types of um adic
variables which Drive differentiation in
these systems we see um that the adic
are very important particularly carbon
nitrogen ratio um and pH pH was an very
interesting one for us we saw we looked
at different Vineyards throughout a
Vineyard Vineyard region what's a
Vineyard region called like a winery
region whatever I don't know what to
call it but a place where there were
lots of Vineyards and we looked at the
same strain of Mero the same ecotype of
Mero across these different Vineyards
and then cataloged how the uh community
structure changed across those Vineyards
and we see pH is a big variable that's
drives that because different Vineyards
use different types of organic
fertilizer and inorganic fertilizer to
fertilize the soil and while we sort
impacts of carbon and um and and carbon
nitrogen ratios as drivers the pH
induced in the different soils was still
a key driver which is
known um and interestingly there was a
significant um effect due to air
temperatures indicating a driver for the
microbial teral especially on the above
ground surfaces between 2011 and 2012 we
saw a significant differentiation in the
flowers um and in the um in the leaves
between the two um annual time points
suggesting that a change in temperature
could have an impact upon what's
happening to the microbial population um
and including in the soil so these these
the the system variance was being driven
by soil adic and also climactic
variables um changing tack again I'm I'm
switching around because I I have lots
of stories to tell um we this is all
very well and good understanding how
community structure differentiates
across these natural gradients but what
I'm most interested in is why why
certain bacterial organisms are finding
themselves coassociated with this
environment and becoming abundant versus
this en environment what is the
selective pressure driving those
organisms to uh to develop in that space
how do they evolve to adapt to that
environment and the only way to do that
is to start to rebuild the genomes of
those organisms uh from my perspective
and look at the evolutionary drivers and
the trait selection within those
populations um so um we reconstruct
genomes on a large scale from a typical
metagenome we can grab lots of different
bacterial isolates from different Genera
in that system we can grab viral genomes
we can even grab some archal genomes and
we can utilize that information to build
out metabolic models which describe how
those organisms interact with each other
and with their environment um so this is
a great example working in a soil system
um with hydrochloro hexane pollution so
this is a um when you create lindane um
you uh you have a pollutant which you
throw back into the soil and there's
these huge hch dumps in certain
countries around the world uh they're
illegal in a lot of countries but they
create a very toxic environment um and
so by looking at hch degradation in the
microbial Community we can um we look at
organisms we can culture up and genome
sequence and we can map those to
metagenomes we collect from these
environments and utilizing that
information we can predict what the last
common ancestor of the extant population
in the system would have been and
utilizing this information it suggests
that um the ancestor genotype well lacks
um suest that % of the genes in each
subspecies were absent in the ancestor
so these these subspecies we see present
in the system have gained genetic
material due to a selected pressure
driver from from the pollution event um
the ancestor we we predict is unable to
grade hch and it acquires the Lin genes
to allow it to degrade hch from this
transpose on mediated lateral Gene
transfer and we can actually even
isolate a lot of the transposons and
transposon elements in the in the genes
in the genomes of these organisms and
co-associate them and their um nonymous
synonymous ratio with the lindane re
Lind degrading regions um and this helps
us to um predict the functional
capability of that organism and how it
evolved that capability so you know I
know I I understand what you're thinking
I've gone from the entire planet and
I've now zoomed down into one genome but
looking across those scales is really
important and we can also go even
further when we dig down into the abolic
capability of an organism this is
working work we did in Pete MOS um and
looking at thota and thermoplasma um
therm oxidizes these longchain fatty
acids V trophic interaction with
methanogens um and what we've been able
to do by taking the genomes of these
organisms and looking at them across
Redux gradients in the system we can
identify the the the drivers which allow
these organisms to respire so the we got
anerobic respiration with fumerate as a
terminal electron Etc when we when we
look at
thermoplasmata um another organism for
which we had no uh genome relatives in
the system before we see sulfite and
Organo sulphonate uh reduction as the
driver for its capability to respire so
turb electron acceptors are depleted to
very low levels in some of these systems
and yet anerobic respiration is really
dominant still um you know as a key
component and so why are these these Arc
particularly abundant so looking you
know we now fumerate and Organo
sulfonate are important for respiration
of the carbon mineralized in these Pete
lands which gives us an ability at the
molecular level to start to understand
the potential implications of changes in
this environment upon carbon
mineralization right and the
remineralization of components into the
biosphere and driving potential changes
in um in climate systems so taking you
know I've gone from making spirous
comments about what happened in the 19
1840s to driving all the way down into
the potential metabolic interactions of
an organism with its environment and
linking those substrates between the two
is going to become increasingly
important in our ability to derive um uh
appropriate accurate predictive uh
climate models from what we can
understand of um as a system driver in
in the soil environment um I'm was going
to go to a new study sorry I really like
this one this is a brand new one um I I
have no attention span you can
understand that from this um so we
really interested in invading plants
mostly because when we're working in
Long Tall Grass prairies we see this
beautiful relationship between a stable
ecosystem and it's it's very stable but
highly um sorry sorry very permanent but
highly instable community structure when
we perturb that longrass Prairie even in
Iota the system starts to disassemble
okay um increase the nitrogen by a small
margin the system disassembles so we
want wanted to understand well how do
when a plant starts to invade the system
how does it influence that belowground
microbial community and what are the
significant drivers and um what can we
say about the uh the uh the legacy of an
invasion um in in terms of perturbing
our ability to restore that environment
back to what it was before so working we
got this multi-billionaire in in Chicago
who bought up a load of land in Montana
um because um he wanted to be a
biologist when he was a kid but his
daddy said no and he went into the City
and he made a lot of money and now he
gets to play in his sandbox don't you
love those people only in America can I
find that kind of human I love it so we
get to play in his sandbox and so he's
he's basically trying to his Gambit is
restore the ecosystem back to the
original torra Prairie so he bought up
10,000 acres of ranch and set us with
this task so if the initial task is to
try and understand why that system needs
to be restored so here we have three
gradients of cheat grass naw and leafy
spurge um an invasion gradient from high
abundance of the Invader to absence and
so all intensive purposes is his native
Prairie um going up to um an invaded
plot obviously um for for the plants you
do see a very strong gradient between
the plant biodiversity and and the um
and The Invasion plot when when you get
a highly invaded plot um you have sorry
invaded plot you have a highly
differentiated plant biodiversity Bea
diversity pattern uh bacteria show a
similar but not quite as robust Trend
apart from apart from in the um the
leafy spurge or escula I can't remember
that might be leafy spurge or cheat
grass but either way it shows a very
strong gradient the fungi show a much
stronger gradient in response uh their
be diversity pattern shows a much
stronger gradient in response to the
invasion pattern and so we can start to
say that yes Invasion does have an
impact upon the microbial community INF
structure in that system um we can
differentiate that from well maybe this
Invasion area was pre supposed to be
good for those plants because of these
microbial Community structures or or
some kind of adic variable by looking at
this over time so we uh common Garden
experiments we planted up these systems
with invasives one year after planting
um there's no real significant
difference between the microbial
community structure in either um the
native environment in green cheek grass
in red naweed in blue or spurge in
yellow so one year was not enough um in
these systems to derive any kind of
spatial differentiation pattern but
after three years the system starts to
arrange and we're now pushing this on
but we've only just got three years
about um eight weeks ago so um what
we're starting to see now is at least at
least for nap weed and for spurge we're
starting to see significant clustering
of those populations uh the microbial
communities in the blowr systems around
that Invasion system so the system
starts to show consistent shifts in
chemistry and microbic structure I'm not
showing the chemistry here um and we
believe that these modifications to the
soil properties probably driven by
increases in carbon inputs into the soil
due to predatory release of the of the
Invader in its because it's not not its
native habitat anymore reinforc the
dominance of the Invader um making sure
those invasions are difficult to remove
we think unfortunately for our
billionaire playboy that it's very very
hard to remove some of these Invaders n
impossible um once they get to a certain
level I their legacy on that soil system
might be um might be unattainable unless
you go through an incredibly dramatic
ecosystem structural difference soorry
anyway uh finally um fertilization
reduces Bal I just wanted to point this
out we we do a lot of work uh with
groups um in Africa trying to understand
I've never been to Africa to myself I
was saying to uh to Rebecca early but
I'd love to go um but we we are trying
to take some of this data and put it
into a more translational framework so
that people grows especially can start
to utilize it and so trying to
understand how differential land use
strategies such as rotations and
fertilizer combinations can be used to
increase functional capacity so
utilizing um uh numerical models and
statistical models we can start to
understand the potential implications of
differential um uh Land Management
strategies for improving productivity
for some of the 9900 million poor people
who are using um agriculture as their
subsistence mechanism any right on a
completely different note how much
longer have I got I know I got to be
strict about seven minutes seven more
minutes okay um you are currently
sitting in a built ecosystem right every
single one of you is emitting 38 million
bacterial cells into your environment
every hour you're all becoming more
microbiologically similar the people who
are sitting closer to each other are
becoming more microbiologically similar
than the people sitting further away if
you are physically interacting you'd be
increasing that degree of similarity and
this environment is the environment
where we're all growing up okay where we
as a species unless you grew up on a
farm or you grew up in the Amazon
rainforest I don't know there might be
some people in the room that fit that
description the vast majority of us grew
up in a 20th century home or some of
your 21st century home and that has
significantly altered your microbial
interaction compared to what your
ancestors experienced um your ancestors
probably experienced a more agrarian
lifestyle interacting with the cows and
the pigs not playing on their iPads but
actually living outside and working
outside even as young children and that
increased the microbial biodiversity of
their bodies when when your child is
brought back from the from the hospital
and lives in this environment where it's
consistently cleaned and made quite
sterile this architecturally artificial
system is altering their microbial
profile but enough about health um we
started off this whole Gambit on health
but I wanted to talk a little bit about
microbial forensics it's a new track of
mine something I'm very interested in um
we started out by doing a study for the
Sloan foundation on the home microbiome
we found um among other things that
families um we could look at the
bacterial community on say the floors
and the door knobs Etc and we could with
a high degree of accuracy predict which
family belonged to which home based on
the bacteria they left behind in their
home because of those 38 million
microbial cells you're shedding your
microbial cloud a microbial fingerprint
in your home right nice this is um this
is uh each one of these shows a
particular surface focus on the kitchen
counter these are three people a
grown-up child living with their his
parents um and the three dogs um if we
look at the kitchen counter person three
their microbiome is the predominant
influencer of that environment the
predominant source for bacteria found in
that environment um she's the mother of
the family there's no gender bias here
but you can see that um she actually
went away for a little while person one
goes away here and his microbiome
disappears U that's the red one but
person uh person two who is the father
of the home his microbiome suddenly
became dominant in the kitchen when his
wife went away for a couple of days so
there a lot didn't it um the kitchen
floor was dominated by dog bacteria um
we think this is obviously important
because dogs are significantly
contributing as well as the mother's
bacteria having a significant role
because her cloud is depositing bacteria
there um we can also tell when people
are physically interacting it's a young
couple living with a lodger focus on
this PCA diagram over here um we can
tell that the red and blue um samples
are closer together that's a couple who
are not genetically related but who are
living together and sharing more
microbes because of their physical
interaction hopefully not with the
lodger the lodger does indeed show a
significantly differentiated microbiome
compared to the young couple more
similar to the young couple than he is
to anyone else in our study because he's
living in the same space and sharing the
microbial Cloud their noses are not
microbiologically similar because people
don't interact with their
noses um so working with Time Magazine
we applied this technique with the
Department of Justice to set up some
crime scene investigations that was the
unfortunate cover of our uh our issue of
time but Jared Hampton Marcel who's my
my awesome lab manager and and all
around Guru he um if you ever want to
know anything about DNA extraction he's
your man but um he went down to uh
Florida because it's warm in the winter
and worked with the Florida PD on uh and
the their forensic team on setting up a
crime scene crime scene uh we had a
professor's house from local University
uh his wife and their cat living in a
house they went away for like 10 minutes
and two of the students well like an
hour and a half sorry two of the
students broke into the house and um and
ransacked their fridge uh stole their TV
um they were in there for like 35
minutes and then they left okay we went
in with the PD because this burglar had
happened um and um we uh swapped all the
surfaces of the floor sequenced the
microbiome on the floor and on the
surfaces we went then brought the
husband and wife and the cat back in and
sequenced their microbiome from their
skin surfaces subtracted the resident
microbiome from what we found on the
floors and the surfaces so we had a
residual microbial fingerprint and then
we ran that microbial fingerprint
analysis against 8,000 people in our
database of skin microflora um with also
with um uh with uh the two students who
are burgled the house cuz we knew who
they were right we sent them in and we
could identify the students with 99 6%
accuracy based on our 8,000 people the
microbal fingerprint left over is
actually slightly better than using
their genotype um if you just use um you
know standard genotype fingerprinting
and not whole genome sequencing so we
are very excited by that department of
justice is very excited about that and
they've funded us and JCP and a few
other people to expand this into a large
studies to determine the potential of
utilizing this kind of uh microbial
forensics in order to detect crimes in
in the coming century and if you think
about the number of people that are put
in prison on the basis of bite marks or
uh hair fibers or clothing fibers which
are for detecting anything
accurately um this might be a valuable
addition to forensic team's catalog of
tools in order to get the right the
wrong people in jail you know what I
mean but the get the baddies in jail and
get the keep the um goodies out of jail
um um I just want to point this out
finally because I got like two minutes
right maybe a minute um I mapped my
microbial d in our house this is my
family I don't give a about IRB
don't suck it um talking to
Ruth uh and uh I'm even going to go
worse this is my youngest son let them
fire me this is my youngest son he's
microbially interacting with the bedroom
floor he was the only one that really
had a hand interaction with the bedroom
floor why because he's crawling around
on the floor right when he was two years
old we did the study and so you can see
these weird little interactions and map
them when we add dogs into that mix dogs
significantly increase the microbial
distribution patterns of the of the home
they they increase the amount of sharing
between people my colleague Rob Knight
showed that if you have dogs in a home
you're more likely to share more
bacteria than if you don't have dogs and
we mapped out that interaction over six
weeks of daily analysis and you can see
that the dogs do indeed significantly
increase the diversity and diversity of
interactions what my wife made me use
this to rescue a dog from Kentucky his
name is Captain Bo digley he's a proper
Southern Captain apparently um and he
has actually increased the microbial
diversity of our house only by a small
margin and our house is n of one but it
was significant compared to the time
periods before um and so we think this
is important because if you introduce
dogs into a family's home when the child
is under the age of one they have a 133%
reduction in the likelihood of
developing asthma and work from uh
University of California San Francisco
has demonstrated that dog bacteria such
as lactobacillus when gavaged into a
mouse's intestine can significantly
reduce the likelihood of that Mouse
having an asthmatic attack okay so these
intera all suggest that every single one
of you should go out and rescue I repeat
rescue not buy a dog as soon as you
possibly can um and I'm going to end
there because I talk about toilets and
stuff and I got a bit carried away
but um but I would just like to point
out um uh we have a new Journal M
systems I mentioned it anyone that's
interested in microbial systems biology
and um you you want to publish in an
awesome Journal where you get rapid
decisions blah blah blah um then you can
publish in our Journal we have a great
line of senior editors
um from across the board kind of the
research areas um we have over 110
editors and those 110 editors are the
ones that will handle and make decisions
for every manuscript so you'll get fast
rapid decisions and I am on every single
one of those 110 editors to make sure
that the reviewers uh give out reviews
in the time frame which they have agreed
upon so no more waiting around and i'
I've been a senior editor Isme journal
and environmental microbiology and I
understand pain so this is my way of
getting out pain all right
that's it thank
you 21st century when I change my
microbiome when I go through house just
like or or change it afterwards it's not
based on the structure it's based on the
composition so no not easily I mean you
could take V microbiome transplant and
if you waited long enough you replace
your mic intestinal microb with somebody
else's I couldn't like swab myself with
some CIO back
it's possible you could do it for a
short period of time but remember your
skin is not just a surface it's a deep
contextual environment and um if I
sterilize your hand right now with an
alcohol WIP in 3 minutes afterwards i'
be able to detect your unique
microbiomes it bubbles up back from the
surface right so we've done that study
on a number of occasions um they're very
we're very keen to know that because you
know the best thing about it is yeah you
might be a to perturb it but you're not
very unlikely to be able to change your
strain level differentiation and unless
you're wearing hazmat suit you're never
going to be able to stop it from
shedding even if you wear gloves it's
constantly leaving your
body
OC
spres yeah
yeah well okay so um uh to be perfectly
honest um I'm I'm split between this I
don't think it should be done in in
small children's environments repeat the
question oh sorry the the question is
spraying antibiotic cleaning products
onto surfaces what impact could that be
having on people's Health man's got all
that
mood Terry
Terry Terry over here on the walles
matter so um so pretend pretend the
lights oh there um good pretending um so
what we're most interested in is trying
to see if it affects Health okay and we
see no real implications between health
because as I said is if you use these
things and then you and then you
interact with something you're picking
up a microb your microbiome surface is
pretty fast we do know that certain
cleaning products things with trickers
an can have a potential impact and they
might have some hormonal impact although
that's still tenuous I don't have any
conflict of interest with any of the
companies that manufacture these things
but I would say that in infant
developing I think it's dangerous to
sterilize the environment as much as we
do I think we should actually be
increasing their interactions and we
work with armish hutterite families who
you the armish live on personal Family
Farms the kids always interact with the
animals the Hutterites don't only boys
over the age of 14 are allowed on the
farm they're both from the same
ancestral population they both live a
very similar lifestyle apart from that
one removal of a microbial source and
the hites the arish have virtually no
asthma in their population of 35,000
people we look at the Hutterites have
30% Asma in their their population could
be doed something else but a remarkable
coincidence so I would say increasing
the biological diversity in a world
where we can control pathogens through
uh vaccines and and control um measures
with our community and our environment
we should actually be increasing our
microbial diversity through interaction
with the natural world rather than
decreasing it off
my um come out autis also um can you
like extend that concept you can I I I
have an autistic son so I'm slightly
biased in this respect um my uh I
honestly believe that um that there is a
significant link between microbial
dysbiosis in the child's gut especially
early in life and development of the
brain we we have some evidence that
haven't published yet in rats to
demonstrate this and work with from
sarus mazmanian and Paul pson out of
Caltech has demonstrated significant
link between um a Model A Mouse model of
autism and the addition of a probiotic
in order to alleviate that now what is a
mouse model of autism you got ask
yourself that question deep but um you
know the the the m do show some very
interesting neurological behaviors and
physiological disturbances which are
very similar to what we see in autistic
children and the probiotic does tend to
alleviate those conditions so they're
moving forward with the phase two trial
now looking at its introduction into a
human population so I I have hope that
we can rebalance people's systems but I
just want to point out um I'm slightly
biased because my side is perfect just
the way he is and I actually embrace
neurological diversity in our community
in a way that I think a lot of people
are scared to do because the the other
is a little bit too different and they
don't like it um maybe academics this is
the Right audience to talk about that
right but um uh so I I'm actually not
trying to Kure my son and I wouldn't try
and change him for the world but uh I
know there are other people who are
desperately in need of uh an improvement
in their quality of
life yes where is the science out in
modifying uh in any of them um question
what is the where is the science at in
modifying microbiomes um let me move it
out of humans for a second and into
soils because I think that's an
interesting one uh I I do have a
conflict of interest in this And the
fact I have an interest in um gr centia
Matt wallenstein company which produces
a probiotic to increase your bud growth
for those cannabis Growers out there you
want big buds to make you higher then go
with in in that instance we've
demonstrated that in order to actually
um allow those bacteria that we
introduce into the soil of these plants
to have a significant ability to
colonize we have to disrupt the
ecosystem and reduce the stable
associations between the existing
microbes the best way to do that from
our perspective is to add more carbon
different carbon substrates into the
soil system prior and it shakes up the
status quo and then you add your
probiotic and Bing bam boom some of them
start to take over Matt doesn't want to
know that cuz then they're in the soil
and he doesn't have to add more of his
product which would make him poorer so
that's not cool but theoretically the
same is true for human intestines or
buildings or whatever environment you're
interested in um we disrupt the initial
ecosystem and then add and overlayer it
with a new one vehicle microbiome
transplant works exactly like that
ostensibly with a little bit of hand we
yes just a followup up on that so I
think that's it's interesting that you
say that and I think that contradicts
the Cannabis growth well that too but uh
I think that contradicts what one of the
things we were doing with the
hindcasting right so I think I agree
with you that when you have a community
it's sort of sometimes hard to push that
equilibrium to a new state but yet when
you run that H casting you're saying
that these climate variables are just
going to change the community to respond
to that new climate instantly without
the memory of the system well no so it
takes 30 years for it to change right um
so I'm I guess I'm saying with the hind
casting that it takes you know if the
climate is this it's going to take 30
years for that equilibri to reshift
probably due to a change in plant
biodiversity in the above ground system
what I guess I guess what I'm going at
with that that trending is an an ability
to understand the variance in the
parameters of the system like the human
gut is never going to change to an
environment where it looks like open
ocean right um you know it can't it has
to stay within certain bounds and many
soil systems are the same so if I'm
looking at a prairie it has bounds of
influence it's it's very hard go outside
of those bounds we don't necessarily
know what those bounds are but if we
sample through the parameter variance
space we may be able to capture those
bounds and if we can link the parameter
variance based to what the climate does
to the microbiome or even indirectly or
directly we can have at least an ability
to predict the variance in that in in
the microbiome space the structural
space Sorry the structural space off
that microbiome in that system within
the bounds of reality but you're right
in the fact that I can't hcast back 150
years or even even 100 years as in the
napole system one and actually be
accurate but I'm only utilizing that to
demonstrate the opportunity to identify
how similar Trends exist irrespective of
my ability to predict it um if you will
it's trying to identify an underlying
current of uh of of of um uh of
information which predicts a an emerging
property which I don't necessarily yet
understand um and we can do that with
reasonable accuracy I think even if it's
within the bounds of uh predictability
all right I want to thank our speaker
Jack
[Applause]
Gilbert this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu