this is a production of Cornell
University so what I'm going to do today
is uh talk almost exclusively uh about
undergraduate research uh they have
contributed heavily on advancing the
chemistry and pharmacology and natural
products in in my lab so I'm going to
present a montage of the most relevant
projects that have they have undertaken
so I'm going to start a little bit with
uh uh G lipidomics and uh uh referring
uh in uh particular to uh lipids such as
phospholipids fingol lipids neutr lipids
and qu noites and then I'm going to
spend the rest of the time talking about
disease targeted Botanical pharmacology
with emphasis on particular diseases
since that is what really drives uh
plant research in in my lab so let me
start with a little bit about uh cell
chemical biology um and that's by way of
of a very early project that an
undergrad uh undertook in my lab uh his
name was uh or is Matthew Ginsburg he's
an MD degree now and uh so uh so at the
time that we initiated uh this Pro
project and was financed by a hatch
Grant the egg industry in the state of
New York was under heavy Financial
stress and that is because regulation
was changing and now small and medium
large uh egg producers needed to
accommodate uh chicken uh housing
requirements such as larger spaces etc
etc that was putting a lot of stress on
them uh
and so there was a call for uh Grand
proposals on Research as to how expand
the
market uh of eggs and possibly the
development of added value
products so this CAU my interest because
thinking as a chemist I look at the egg
as an a chemical Factory actually so it
when looks at the structure of an egg is
heavily
compartmentalized um the oneir of the
weight of an egg is the egg yolk and the
egg yolk is actually uh choke full of
lipids okay uh and probably you know a
little bit about the stories around
cholesterol in eggs ET ETA which
actually have been debunked already
there's no threat of cholesterol
intoxication from eggs so um so the egg
yolk actually is greatly composed of
what we call overall as Lestin which is
a mixture of phospholipids and you're
all familiar with the structure of
phospholipids a glycerol back uh
backbone phosphor related with a uh head
group that can be choline ethanolamine
Serene of or inositol and
acetated um by various types of fatty
acids so uh egg Lestin actually has an
application in medicine and that is the
pharmaceutical industry utilizes the
lesian to uh
formulate uh drugs that are going to be
actually administered parentally that is
they're going to be administered
intravenously for example all right so
there are drugs that actually cannot be
made uh water soluable and therefore
they need to be formulated uh in these
uh vesicles so EG Lestin has the
capacity to form is seals that can then
uh include uh different types of uh
theraputic
agents the only problem is that well
these my seals have had some kind of
compatibility uh with uh Maman cell
membrane
composition so so the idea then uh was
to look at the possibility of deriving
from eggs from the state of New York uh
that were appropriate in composition for
this application so I felt the need to
put some you know economic data into the
whole Venture uh as a justification and
just recently at the USDA uh has
established that the value of a grade A
large egg is 13
cents now if you look at signal
catalog uh they sell 250 milligrams of
reagent gred a Lestin for $59 right so
one grade a large egg contains two grams
of Lestin Worth
$472 right of course I'm not including
you know production costs obviously but
this is just to ex exaggerate and make
the point all right now in theory if you
calculate you know you can increase the
value of an egg by more than 3,000 times
in egg letin value right so in anyway so
but the question is as I say is this
leson actually suitable for use by the
pharmaceutical
industry well uh I regreted
participation of a uh New York State uh
egg producer um uh cre Farm uh fresh
eggs um uh uh Kurt Creer is actually uh
the main owner of the company is a
family-owned business actually but it's
a it's a mediumsized uh egg producer I
think you have they have like a 250,000
layers so uh and he is actually a Cornel
Alum so he gladly participated providing
eggs uh in addition to providing eggs uh
he provided also proprietary uh diet we
felt very strongly that the the letin
derived from these eggs was going to
depend on the chemical composition of
the diet so he uh provided two types of
chicken feeds that they use in their
farms uh uh non EB and EB and those are
designations that only they know what
they mean right no is proprietary the
diet so and then the corresponding eggs
produced with the different uh diets so
the methodology utilized is actually
extremely simple uh one cracks the egg
separates the yolk and then the yolk is
extracted uh with a mixture of Chlor for
methanol in 2:1 ratio uh evaporated to
rightness and prepared for sampling and
introduction into a mass spectrometer so
at the time in the uh core facility we
had a
square uh LC electr spray anization Mass
spectrometer that one could actually
operate so that was the playground for
us for the next uh three years actually
so uh
is a very robust instrument but very
limited in capacity of data processing
because it's single octopole and um ion
trap but in any event it was very
suitable for uh the analysis of dtin so
lot of Matthew crank a lot of data and
data processing and this is basically
the results that we that we receive mind
you this is uh the average mamalian cell
membrane lipid composition the main
component is phosphat choline PC uh
followed by phospha ethanolamine and
then a little bit of phosph
inositol so we characterize the
composition profile of the feeds uh and
compare with a uh sample of commercial
letin that is utilized in by the uh
pharmaceutical industry as you can see
um the nonb feed has little pie see uh
large amounts of PE and little Pi uh
however the EB feeds have larger amounts
of PC uh comparable amounts of PE and
both um probably the the the E uh the
fee that compares best with the green
bars which are the composition of the
commercial uh pharmaceutical grade uh
Lestin that contains large amounts of PC
is is the one now this is is the profile
of the ler that come from the chickens
that were fed one and the other diet and
as you can see um very uh they very very
different VI the composition of the of
the uh of the diets um uh so the
composition that is closest to the
commercial Lestin is actually uh the
eggs that were laid uh from chickens
that were uh fed the non EB uh uh
chicken feed and it's almost equal to
the to the commercial one uh same
amounts in PE and uh very little uh Pi
so um if we look at the Lestin
composition of the eggs that come from
uh chickens that were fed the non EV uh
diet is very very close to the uh to the
mamalian cell membrane uh composition so
those were the results that we received
and of course we passed on
recommendations uh we felt also that you
know the diets can be optimized to
better adjust than the profile needed
for uh suitable use by the
pharmaceutical industry given the fact
that uh the the diet it's is very
influential in this composition that's
why organic and omega-3 eggs can be
produced you just feed those components
to the to the chicken and voila you get
eggs that have high content of
Omega-3s and just to illustrate that in
addition to the uh quantification of the
phospholipid classes we actually did a
very detailed uh species profile for
each one of the classes and this is one
example so for each one of the fosol
lipids we actually identified each one
of the particular species these numbers
represent the added number of carbons
coming from the two acil groups in the
in the actual phospholipid including its
uh level of ins saturation all right so
um uh this actually led to a very robust
uh research collaboration with the group
of uh Susan Henry that to this day it is
maintained and uh in this particular
case we actually looked at uh uh
lipidomics uh and the lipidome of yeast
cells uh and through the manipulation of
uh different uh growth conditions and
the use of gin delit mutants uh we have
a better understanding now how these uh
metabolic pathways were actually uh
regulated
so uh we were fortunate that a newer
machine and more capable was acquired by
the core facility we now have a triple
uh quadruple machine that can do uh
multiple reaction monitoring that allows
us in combination with uh hplc to
elucidate in one analysis more than 100
uh lipid species in in samples so this
is the lipidome of yeast depending on
the growth stage we normally work with G
uh populations that are in this
particular uh early
uh developmental stage uh and here is
the whole profile of lipids cardol
lippin uh sterols Singo lipids the
phospholipids neutral lipids and the
lyso uh
products uh this uh just an as an
example the most important phospholipid
in yeast is
phosphoinositol um this is the
composition per species of the steady
state uh however uh using now a very in
Innovative U use of the stable isotope
we can actually look at the nov
synthesis of all this species and
therefore by comparison with the
composition of the steady state infer
the level of or degree of remodeling
that these phospholipids actually uh
undergo so so this is this is what we do
in combination with all the uh genetics
behind the uh uh
yeast so I'm going to move now on to
really what I want to uh spend the rest
of the time discussing that is disease
targeted Botanical pharmacology uh these
are the particular diseases that we are
interested in in my lab is it looks very
ambitious but actually uh on a
preliminary stage they're very very
accessible as I will illustrate I will
con actually I will concentrate
primarily only on cancer and the
epigenetics of cancer Alzheimer's
disease and a more recent line of
research that we have which is uh
menopause so a definition of Botanical
Pharmacology can be the accumulated
developing knowledge of the effect and
motivaction of natural products
occurring in plants in the prevention
and treatment of disease and I feel that
by studying and investigating the mode
of action of a natural product we are
very prepared to provide pharmaceutical
industry with lead compounds that can
actually uh result in a uh clinical
clinical
therapy so
um uh I would like to every time that I
talk about a line of research I would
like to introduce you know the the
students that participating in them and
uh as you can see progress in this type
of uh projects is is punctuated and
cumulative and it transcends you know
generations of undergrads as they move
on uh and that knowledge and skill and
methodological capacity is actually
maintain and uh new students are trained
under it so some of the early students
that I had was Douglas Ryan and more
recently Chelsea uh the uh these two
grer students are actually senior grad
students and programs in Pharmacology
Rockefeller and wild Cornell and they're
almost done with their with their PHD
work so to um introduce our interest in
in cancer from the epigenetic standpoint
um I have summarized here you know the
views of uh the mechanisms of cancer now
the classical view is one in which uh
the genome has experienced some kind of
uh change introduced by mutations uh
deletions of genes or Gene
amplifications and this is the classical
View and the one that has been more
investigated and for which there is more
information however there is an evolving
alternative View and that is that
epigenetic mechanisms can actually and
there dysfunctionality can also result
in cancer
so um mechanisms by wi by which um uh uh
gene expression can take place is by
hone modification DNA metalation and
noncoding RNA so these two hone
modification and DNA metalation actually
have been investigated in the cont of
cancer and found out that actually they
contribute to the uh on regulat
proliferation of cancer cells and for
those two there are already Two drugs
that are being used clinically to the
treatment of certain
hematologic uh uh uh cancers so my
interest in particular and in a moment I
will you will see why was actually heat
Stone modification misregulation of heat
Stone modification can lead actually to
to the development of cancer so just to
remind you um he Stone modification can
OCC occur in particular by a mechanism
of acceleration and de acceleration uh
those changes actually are accomplished
by enzymes that we call hone acetylases
or hone acetal
transferases so uh acetated chromatin
leads to gene silencing uh the acet the
acetalation of Chromatin leads to
relaxation and accessibility to to gene
expression so Mis regul
of this U me of this mechanism actually
can result in in cancer and here is
Illustrated so one particular hastone uh
the acetylase that has been identified
in a couple of cancers um has uh is c
one this is a Maman uh hone DEET so it
can DEET hones but it can also the
acetates proteins and Illustrated here
or two proteins that actually uh the the
acation of those two proteins can result
actually in cancer one protein is
p53 that if certain one de acetates
deactivates and therefore it precludes
uh the mechanism by which a cell that
has uh a Le uh uh a DNA that is uh
damaged cannot undergo apotosis or DNA
repair or uh growth uh uh cell uh
development and that results in tumor
suppression so if that certain one the
acet is actually
misregulated it can inactivate or
deactivate p53 or on the other hand um
it can actually activate uh an enogen
like
bcl6 uh that is actually transcriptional
uh repressor that can result in Toren
bcl6 and the acetalation of it has been
implicated in uh a particular type of uh
lymphoma so there is a c one homologue
actually in in yeast and that is Sir 2
so sir 2 is also a heat stone that setat
and actually uh can um silence uh at uh
silence at at the telomeric uh genes at
theic uh region uh uh it's a family of
his deasis C2 is the most important but
it forms complexes with sir three sir
four it's a whole that called the cerin
and the acation uh actually silences uh
chromatin so to to study he Stone the
acceleration in the context of finding
natural products that can actually
prevent their action and and the
treatment of cancer um
we we had a challenge so before I go on
to describe the methodology that we
developed to do that uh let me just say
that these two uh heat Stone desis small
molecules at the time that we were
looking into the possibility of
undertaking this type of project had
actually been
identified so um these two chemicals
actually were uh critical in deciding
what type of natural products we were
going to Target in the possibility that
we could set up some kind of methodology
to measure his on the satat this
particular molecule have been isolated
from a fungal U from a fungal isolate
that was in the repository of the
National Cancer Institute and it's
called split misin and uh it was found
out that it was a hisone acetat of ser2
actually in in yeast the other compound
is called Saha for short it's a
synthetic compound and in 2006 receive
approv approval from the FDA to treat
this particular type of uh cell
lymphoma so with this type of chemistry
in the
background and knowing a little of
natural products one could think of
natural product candidates that could be
put through uh a an assay to look for
histone dietas uh activity so the
question is you know where and what to
look for histone DEET inhib activity
so knowing that uh so using this
structures as templates what came to
mind was actually cumerin so cumerin
have this particular basic skeleton this
is a uh chromone this is a chrom and own
so you can see right right away uh the
similarity between the two structures so
we decided that cumarin because they
bear uh quite close resemblance to spyin
could actually be good candidates for
histon inhib so as we know cumans are
well distributed the rotas asteras and
inoma Pac now the other uh group of
natural products uh that were closely
resembling Saha or actually alky amides
okay so um these type of compounds are
wiely distributed in rotas Piper and Som
asteras and as you can see there is an
overlap between the presence of cins and
alides in the rotasi so grasi became the
first uh Target family you know to
investigate for this type of activity so
the question is how are we're going to
do
this so so um so here uh we actually I
saw the advice of uh the Susan Henry uh
group and decided that well if we're
going to use yeast to investigate hisia
activity then we need to actually
engineer a yeast strain that will have a
reported Gene and the reported Gene that
was decided to use was a EUR three uh
reported Gene introduced in the telomic
region where the cins hison acasis and
yeast actually uh operate so if the uh
chromatin is acetated there is no urri
expression uh if it is acetated then
there will be urri expression so we need
to translate this uh this theoretical uh
concept into into practice so okay so
I'm not going to discuss the conditions
that already required for this
expression and how the reporting is
going to take place uh and I rather uh
described how we accomplish actually
this so the yeast strain that was
actually engineered was uh done with a
plasmid that was actually provided by uh
Thomas pets from University of North
Carolina that contained actually the
whole uh uh right arm of chromosome 5 in
which the Ura 3 gen reported Gene had
been introduced in the theric region so
by homologous recombination we actually
engineer uh a g strain that contain now
the reported Gene in the appropriate
place so uh now what what is it that Ura
3 does well Ur three actually is a uh
decarboxylase in the osil B btic pathway
from or to uh uracil that removes uh the
carboxy uh group from orod 5 phosphate
and yielding uh uh yurine mono mono
phosphate so um
now in this type of methodologies uh one
can actually give uh where the gene is
operational we can give the cells this
particular compound five floro orotic
acid so is is a is ortic acid that has a
Florine in this position and if the cell
processes it it results in the formation
of this suicide inhibitor which is five
floral uh Ur
uracil so depending on whether we allow
for you know ur3 to be expressed or not
we kill or not cells right so now we
have a way to actually uh set a an acid
to do that uh so Illustrated here is if
the cins uh the acetate uh uh the T the
telic region so the cells can actually
uh grow in the presence of 5 foa because
ura3 is actually uh
non-expressed but if the cerin the
acetate and ura3 is actually expressed
then the cells are not going to grow
because they're going to form this
compound which is actually toxic to them
so uh that can be done very easily in uh
liquid media but I have always had a
tendency to simplify things for
expediency and uh what I wanted to uh
develop was a assay on the same basis
but that actually could be used in solid
media so the concept was if we deposit a
heat Stone the cetas in a filter dis and
we introduce it in a Petri dis and
inoculate with this particular construct
will it show cell growth inhibition so
here's the proof of concept nicotinic
acid is a histone inhibitor and you can
see that in the presence of it there is
no cell growth and without it cells grow
so now we have a system rather simple
but at the same time complex because of
the type of reporting that we can
actually now interrogate natural product
chemistry for
hist
inovision so as I said the rotasi became
the first uh Target family to
investigate for natural product
chemistry that could actually uh inhibit
hison acation so at the time it was
almost winter and so we had to recur to
what we had in the greenhouse and we had
actually two species of citrus so we had
this particular rasi citr forella uh
mtis uh conquet and we had actually uh
lemon so we prepare actually extracts of
the leaves of these two rotasi and then
we put them through the assay and the
result was that well the crude chemistry
of an methanol extract of uh this rasi
actually uh the one from uh the lemon
doesn't inhibit the growth of the uh
cell so that means that there is no
hstone the C IND division while the
extract of Kat does so so we pursue then
the chemistry of citings uh mitis uh in
this particular case we were actually
targeting uh and the reason why we
tested methanol extracts is because we
were targeting the U uh the cumerin in
in Citrus so we pursue Sidis and um so
this right away became a big challenge
because we could not reprod produce this
biological activity at
will and every time that we prepared an
extract of uh kumquat and
tested we would either get a positive
result or we would not get a result at
all and this was very
puzzling and after
reviewing data accumulated we notice
that the only extracts that were uh
giving a positive result were aged quote
unquote
extracts and that that aging required at
least one month of sitting on the bench
if we tried freshly prepared extracts
there was no activity at all so this was
actually later confirmed when we started
now to suspect that there was a
difference between the two types of
extracts okay so we applied the
chemistry to that we compare uh
composition hlc composition profiles of
old and age extracts and we found that
actually uh there was a change in
profile in which one compound in the
um that was prominent in the fresh
extract in the one month old extract
actually uh decreased in concentration
while another com uh compound actually
or component actually experienced the
opposite okay so it started with very
low concentrations and after one month
it was actually high this already
suggested to those to us that this
changing composition actually was key to
the biological activity we further uh
tested that hypothesis using mass
spectrometry and we found in effect
there is a compound that in the fresh
extract is very low concentration it has
a molecular weight of 377 and after one
month actually is high right so we went
after that compound we did you know
bioet guide fractionation and that
actually resulted in uh the elucidation
of the active principle that it is only
active after the parent compound has
actually produced it in large amounts uh
we don't know the mechanism by which
this change occurs whether it is
chemical or biochemical nevertheless uh
it was confirmed here is the comparison
of uh the Mass Spectrum of the uh parent
compound and this is the mass spectrum
of the product that is the active one
which is the result of the loss of these
two uh sugar uh Moes so this
compound which is a cumin uh a Fano
cumerin for that matter is actually a
hone theet inhibitor so uh other
students came along and we targeted then
a different uh rageous plant
uh santox Americano in this particular
case Northern Brickly as occurs in the
area we collected it it had been
reported that uh santox Americana
contain five mop five mop a cumin and
this particular alkamide five Alpha
hydroxy Sanol so we wanted to find out
if either one of these two type of
compounds actually were he on the acetal
lasis so extracts actually were prepared
uh test he is the response a strong
response to one partially purified uh
fraction uh that came from uh colon
chromatography and we further pursu this
biological activity and it resulted then
in a fraction that was reach in a family
of compounds which are actually
derivatives of cuspidal which is a uh
fenel propanoid type of compound so we
further uh fractionating using uh silic
gel colon chromatography gradients uh in
separation we found uh fractions that
were active and that by tin
chromatography showed that it was only
one compound they all contain it we
combined and tested and the activity is
right there so the compound that was
identified by m spectrometry is actually
this cuspidal analog gpic acid that's
what we're calling it and it's actually
a uh histone
inhibitor so um we took a different
avenue to fractionation of uh sxin
Americano uh uh extracts and we isolated
also an additional histone theet gamma
Sanu um which it has not it hadn't been
reported actually in santox americanum
and so here's the structure is it is
actually an alide so you know the
choosing of the rasi because they
combine this typ of chemistry that has
been shown by analogy to be HISD paid
out actually so we have now in summary
um a few uh compounds one furan aerin
and one fenel propanoid and actually one
alkamide so all this in the course of
about four
years all right so let me move on now to
to a different uh
disease and this is Alzheimer's um so
Alzheimer's uh is becoming a a big
problem uh not only in North America but
globally as we have an increasing aging
population that it will experience
certain uh incidents of Alzheimer's
disease uh that in combination with the
fact that uh current Therapies in the
treatment of Alzheimer disease are
actually uh not very efficacious uh
clinically so this uh interest in
Alzheimer's actually started out in 2009
uh uh with these two students Scott and
Michael both of them already were
awarded their MD degrees uh and newer
students like Bernell and and Ry um any
event so uh this is the uh
neuropathology of Alzheimer's uh very
early on uh upon postmortem uh studies
it was actually found out that an
Alzheimer's patient brain actually has
experienced considerable shrinkage and
you know neuronal loss mainly occurs in
the Cal cortex in the hippocampal uh
region where the coleric uh Network
resides and the coleric network actually
is responsible for memory and cognition
so as you can see affecting these parts
of the brain results in loss of those
two
functions so um histological
preparations had also shown that
associated with this neuronal law or the
formation of plaques that now we call
them aoid beta ameloid plaques and also
accumulation of protein to protein fals
inside of the cells all right all that
causes Alzheimer's disease So based on
these results and B chemical studies of
uh uh brains of Alzheimer's individuals
it was noted actually that levels of
acetycholine the
neurotransmitter uh in these areas of
the brain was actually very low so the
first hypothesis or model proposed for
the disease was one in which uh
uh the result the Alzheimer's disease
was actually the result of a low
concentration of aetl choline in this
synaptic Cliff between two neurons right
so so acetyl choline is actually made
from acetate and choline by a choline
acetal trans phrase and degraded by an
enzyme that is called acet Colin estras
all right so
um when acet Coline is released into the
synaptic Cliff uh Finds Its way into
receptors which are in the post synaptic
uh neuron one of them uh the muscarinic
acetal Coline receptor is actually a g
protein coupled uh uh receptor and so it
was then
proposed that that signaling Cascade
that resulted from that interaction
actually was affecting the processing of
AP which is the protein that actually uh
is the precursor to the uh beta ameloid
peptide which Aggregates into the
plaques so the coleric hypothesis that
was proposed in
1975 blamed low amounts of aeroline in
the synaptic cleff uh for the production
of the beta ameloid peptide so from this
model it was very clear what the
solution was well then develop a drug
that could actually restore normal
levels of atic Colin in synaptic cliff
and that Target was actually the Colinas
uh the acetal Coline estras the enzyme
that degrades acetal choline so the
first and only generation of actually uh
drugs um what they do is they block the
activity of acetal Colin estras uh
restoring normal levels of acetal
choline in the synaptic cleff and
clinically it was predicted that if that
was the case then Downstream uh the
production of beta ameloid peptide was
going to decrease and the progression of
the disorder was going to slow down
right so this or the drugs that are
current in current use so the col
energic hypothesis was proposed in
1975 uh the first drugs that came uh
into the uh CL into clinical use uh
where arisp and rivastigmine this
compound is completely synthetic this is
actually derived from a natural product
fos sine that occurs in a African uh
legume which is actually very toxic so
the other compound actually or the other
a is Colin esteras inhibitor uh approved
in 2004 is galantamine that actually
occurs in a host of plants I just cited
daff deal because it's very timely right
now to talk about that uh so uh and is
uh it is used as it is found actually in
in these plants there is an alternative
treatment that uh blocks actually the
the receptor of glutamate which it is
thought to contribute to the formation
of the to protein feals in the in the
neurons and this is all that exists uh
in clinical use and their efficacy is
actually extremely poor
right so given the interest that we had
in this um in this uh and I'm going to
start to abbreviate because I'm I'm
running out of time now uh so we started
to uh so we decided to look for aceras
Inhibitors so the question was what type
of plants are we going to look for to uh
to screen for ainer inion so the plants
that we decided to Target were plants
that have been claimed to possess
neurotropic activity and neurot Tropics
are defined you know as agents that can
be or act as uh memory enhancers neuro
enhancers cognitive enhancers Etc and
the anobot are rich in those types of
description
so uh so the question now was how are we
going to measure this well we had
actually a fluorometric asset to do it
but it just was too uh it was not very
practical to to use it uh it is very
good at quantitating uh activity uh and
Gathering uh kinetics uh but not very
quick for targeting a particular
component in in a plant so we opted to
use an alternative which is a uh bio
autographic a say that can be uh
developed in a uh thin layer
chromatogram uh it entails the uh uh
resolving the components of a mixture on
T on TLC applying the enzyme and then a
reagent that generates a background and
contrasts with a discoloration which is
actually an indicator of acetal Colinas
inivision and here's the proof of
concept this is the assay and this uh
whitish uh discoloration here is
actually arisp the drug that is used
clinically so now we had an assay and we
decided then on what plant we were going
to Target so one of the first plants
that we actually targeted was um MAA
lepidum mayai and andian
braiki uh that traditionally is used for
the treatment of male infertility but
that it lists as an benefit actually
Improvement in memory and and brain
function so this is the aay as it looks
so we diagnos that these areas of
discoloration in particular uh were due
to uh alkaloids in in MAA as we got a
positive with dragon DF reagent which is
highly specific for alkaloids and we
went on to isolate those components and
I'm not going to discuss in depth but
these are the types of alkaloids that
are found in in MAA they're very unique
Idol type of alkaloids surprisingly uh
MAA this brassicaceous plant contains
also alkamides and they're all AAL
Colinas Inhibitors so it could be the
foundation for the claim you know that
MAA probably benefits memory and and
function so another plant that we
another neotropic plant that we targeted
also is lemon Bal Bel falis in the lamia
that there's a claim that alleviates uh
m Alzheimer's so is the acin estras
inhibition uh aay these are the spots
that we targeted there are others but we
felt that this was the major component
it's a phenolic compound as it gives
positive with feric chloride and
ultimately we decided that very likely
this compound was rosmarinic acid we run
hlc analysis compared with an authentic
sample of rosar neaz and sure enough
it's there in the in the in the extracts
of the plant and confirmed by mass
spectrometry so um so these are the in
sumary these are the ass called Nas
Inhibitors that uh we have isolated uh
one alkamide and two alkaloids from uh
lepidium Ai and one um fenel propanoid
in meliss officinalis rosmarinic acid
okay so lastly I'm just going to briefly
discuss um menopause and our interest in
menopause and actually is an extension
of uh the Alzheimer's disease interest
that we have so uh participants in this
uh uh project or uh research is Maryanne
kumal Janet and and Heather so we had
interest in actually uh
phytoestrogens um for a number of
reasons uh one of them was very
pragmatic and that is well uh this
particular group of plants have been
utilized for a purported estrogenic
activity these two black cohos and red
clover have been utilized in alternative
treatment of menopause
symptomatology these other two actually
have been used traditionally as
galactoses to increase uh breast meal
production in lactating women so um we
felt that these two types of uh effects
were caused by the presence of
uh estrogen mimics so uh but at the same
time we felt that the there was no
really uh good hold on the estrogenic
chemistry chemistry had been described
but not never uh conclusively
demonstrated that those reported
compounds were the phytoestrogens so in
a revisionist type of approach we
decided okay let's look again at these
plants we have now a uh an interest we
have plants to look at all we needed now
was to um uh to find out how how can we
do this so uh so menopause is um a age
related biological phenomenon results in
the reproductive cap and the loss of the
reproductive capacity of a woman and is
caused by gradual decrease in estrogen
production in the ovaries so
uh as we review the literature and we're
getting ready to investigate uh estrogen
mimic uh activity we realize that
estrogen was actually integral to uh a
number of symptoms associated with
menopause so they're the classical ones
uh and there are the result from that uh
decrease in in estrogen and uh decrease
in uh progesterone but one thing
actually cut our interest cited amongst
the umbrella designation of
psychological symptoms was actually poor
memory and that cut up our interest so
how how is this I mean what is the
relationship between loss of memory or
decline in memory and estrogen well um
there are a number of studies that
actually have conclusively demonstrated
that there is an association between or
correlation between the progression of
menopause and the decline and memory and
cognitive function so this is one of the
more recent ones published in 2013
conducted at the University of uh
Rochester
which a group of middle-aged women in
different stages of menopause will
actually tested physiologically and
psychologically for verbal learing
capacity verbal memory F modal skills
and attention working memory and as you
can see uh These Bars represent the
women the groups of women in the
different stages and as you can
see especially in veral memory there is
a decline associated with uh progression
uh of of menopause and it's true for all
of the other uh functions uh that
actually were measured so here we have
actually a very concrete evidence that
there two are associated so now
mechanistically why is that uh why is
that well looking at the literature we
now uh been able to summarize some of
the brain functions that estrogen
actually uh performs in the brain
so estrogen actually is a regulator of
the enzyme that biosynthesizes
acetylcholine right so the enzyme is uh
choline acetal
transferase so um so this enzyme is
under positive uh regulation of estrogen
so the other function of estrogen is
envisioned as regulating the processing
of AP and via the modulation of the
enzymes that cleave AP and in the
presence of estrogen the amyloidogenic
pathway that leads to the formation of
the ameloid plaques is actually
downregulated and the third property is
actually if you notice a ring of
estrogen is aromatic with a hydroxy
group this compound is antioxidant so it
performs also a neuroprotective function
in the brain now if you remove estrogen
from the brain
all this happens okay the protection as
antioxidant is lost the U regulation of
chat is lost less AET coling is produced
and it actually increases the risk in a
woman to develop Alzheimer's disease and
we know very clearly the statistics
women are at twice the risk of
developing Alzheimer's disease than men
all right so this actually uh led us to
formulate a different approach to the
study of estrogens and um because of uh
the role of estrogen in in menopause and
what we're looking for now is what I
call combinatorial pharmacology imp
plants that is chemistry imp plants that
can act as an antioxidant that can act
as a promoter of AET Coline uh formation
and that can act as an estrogen mimic to
reduce the risk of developing
Alzheimer's disease right so so we have
encounter now uh actually those plants
uh this is how we uh assay for
estrogenic activity we engineered
another again another yeast cell with
this particular plasmid that contains
the human estrogen receptor and a beta
galactosidase report a gene so the
plasmid is introduced in the cell and we
have now an engineer uh yeast uh cell
that upon the stimulus of estrogen or an
estrogen mimic actually triggers the
expression of beta galactosidase that
process ompg to OMP that we can measure
then spectrophotometrically here is the
proof of concept
um such a construct treated with
estrogen uh results in a positive
response all right so uh the first plant
that we actually uh approach for study
is uh fenek a uh Fai um used since
acquity for a number of reasons uh but
is used actually as a galactogogue uh
prominently uh to increase uh lactation
uh in in women so I'm not going to I'm
just going to go to the to the
results and the chemistry that we have
actually isolated and identify
conclusively so uh one estrogenic
component of enog Greek is actually D
genin we isolate it characterize it and
evaluate it is estrogenic activity is in
the chloroform ethanol extract and in
the aous ethanol extract of U uh fenor
Greek actually we isolated uh three
isoflavones which are actually the same
three isoflavones plus present in soy
and we know that these isoflavones I
mean have a
estrogenic uh mimicking capacity so
they're present also in fenugreek and
the presence of this chemistry is
actually resp responsible for the
estrogenic activity we now have defined
a larger group of plants uh to study uh
the uh junior undergrad students that
are working in this project uh have
already established estrogenic activity
antioxidant activity uh and aeres
inhibition activity and they're the
process of isolating the active
principles in this plant all of them in
the uh lamac primarily salvas which are
uh or have been shown to be uh
estrogenic now I'm going to stop there
uh I just want to
acknowledge see I knew that I had too
many slides so this is this is uh this
is a summary of of um chemistry that is
estrogenic and acet Colin estras uh
inhib inhibitory so the isoflavans and
diine the estrogen mimic in in Fen Greek
um uh and and another plant that we have
studied is aan TR spum Ami in the apaz
that contains estrogen mimics uh folic
acids all of them which also show acolin
estras um activity uh I would like just
to acknowledge the rest of the uh
undergrad students that have worked in
my life throughout the years I didn't
get the chance to to talk about their uh
projects in chemical ecology malaria
diabetes and and cancer all of them
already in graduate school thank you for
your
attention this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu