this is a production of Cornell
University awesome uh it's really great
to be presenting back in this room the
last time I gave a seminar here was my
job talk um many many years ago uh so
this is very exciting to be back giving
my 10e seminar um before I jump into the
science I learn to overcome okay before
I jump into the science I really have to
thank uh my amazing lab members both
past and present uh who are just an
incredibly strong and active group of
people um I flipped back through my
photo re all the way to 2018 when we
started and realized that we moved uh
lab spaces three different times so far
hopefully one more time when the
renovations finished um and there was
almost no complaining during that time
um just an incredibly adaptive group
that um continued to science through the
pandemic my first grad student graduated
kind of in the midst of the pandemic and
did um was just incredibly productive in
that challenging time and now as we
enter another challenging time I'm just
really proud of this group for um always
uh looking for ways to push the science
forward so most of my lab's work it
focuses on plant grafting although as
you heard we had some soybean money so
we've done some other stuff too that I
won't talk about today um I'll just
focus on the grafting and grafting is
simply the physical joining of separate
plant parts so that they share an
interconnected vascular system and uh
throughout this talk I'll really
emphasize that last that second part of
the definition the interconnected
vascular system that's really crucial to
our understanding of what makes grafting
work um and grafting is pretty
remarkable it's our way of making real
live Frankenstein's monsters um and it
happens incredibly easily in the plant
kingdom so Grafton actually occurs in
nature these are two examples of kissing
trees that we saw in yosity on a hike
and this is a self defusing uh Tree by
the itha farmers market that you can see
here um and historians think that it was
human observations of these natural
graphs that inspired the first
agricultural applications of grafting
which date back in the literature um to
424 BCE and it was likely co-invented um
in ancient Greece and in Asia at the
same time um so when I say old tools for
maximizing agriculture uh to some extent
these are prehistoric tools and really
uh anciently historic Tools in human
f um there are many many applications of
grafting I'm just going to point out a
few prominent ones uh that we might care
about um so grafting is used uh across
viticulture to protect Vines from
biionic stresses um there's a very
famous um decimation of European
Vineyards um from the fxa outbreak uh
that was um in which The Vineyards were
saved through grafting to Missouri root
stocks wild Missouri root stocks um and
so if you enjoy wine you might
appreciate the um the the benefits of
grafting in this case um grafting is
also used to modify plant architecture
um so here's an example of dwarfing root
stocks that um make apple harvest more
accessible this is also used in pear
harvests um in the reverse Direction in
vegetable Crop Production grafting can
be used to invigorate the Chute system
or Scion and um greatly um improve
yields in tomatoes and curits um
predominantly and that's a a direct
topic of my lab uh grafting is also used
in Horticultural art this is an example
of 40 different varieties grafted onto
One stock
um and probably one of the most recent
Innovations in grafting is that you can
Harvest ketchup and fries from the same
plant um and you can actually buy this
in the UK and it's covered on a a stepen
uh CH bear episode so it's very famous
um so um grafting has wide Horticultural
uses um but in our case uh most of us
probably read about grafting when we're
studying mobile signaling and so it's
also used to demonstrate um the movement
and signaling function of peptides small
rnas um an emerging field is Messenger
rnas that we're doing a lot of work in
um and hormones and so grafting um is
really the gold standard for
demonstrating mobile signaling and that
was uh this area of grafting was really
the extent of my knowledge when I
entered into the field of grafting of a
postc um and then as I learned about its
dominance in agricultural production I
really became fascinated with the the
concept that we could actually use
modern molecular tools to understand
some of the molecular biology that
underlies um beneficial agricultural
grafting and potentially um start to
engineer beneficial graphs for
agricultural systems which I think were
really at the cusp of doing uh just now
seven years almost seven years into
having the lab
um so we do most of our work in tomato
and the broader nightshade family
because it's very easy to Gras I won't
show you this video just so I have
enough time to get through everything um
but look it up it's produced by a
Cornell Alum Dr Molly Edwards who was
also in Mike scan's lab um when I was a
PhD student and she has a whole series
of science IRL videos so it's very easy
to graph tomato it has almost 100% um
success in graph ing um and it heals
quite quickly relative to Woody crop
systems and so this is the chot system
or Scion and the root stock and this is
the joining graft system The graft
Junction um that's formed 10 days
postgrafting um and so we have a very uh
popular technique that we use in the lab
with h confocal Imaging of cleared
tissue where we can actually image into
the that graph Junction and study the
vascular connectivity that occurs
as the two parts of the plant heal
together and so here we're getting into
the vascular system and you can see that
the regenerative processes um that are
occurring give this beautiful uh stitch
together xylem and flum system um and so
we can look at how that is disrupted and
the genes that are involved in placing
that vasculature so the pl plant can
reconnect um partially using this this
anatomical Imaging
another reason to study grafting in
tomatoes is that they are widely grafted
for commercial production so how many
people in the room knew that the
tomatoes that you buy at wigman's or
your favorite grocery store are
grafted yeah because I've been here a
few years but still not
everyone so so um pretty much all um
Tomatoes produced through um controlled
indoor agricultural systems are grafted
to root stocks that both invigorate um
the production of the S as well as
provide abiotic and biotic stress
protect protection and this is um a trip
that I took the very first summer of
starting my lab um to the Netherlands
where I visited a plant
propagation facility where they were
getting ready to graft 100,000 plants to
ship to the Middle East for production
so it's used around the world um in
agricultural production and so hopefully
some of the stuff that we learn can
influence um some of the practices in
positive ways in um in tomato production
um so despite the fact that grafting um
has been used internationally for
Millennia um there are still some core
questions that motivate the exciting
biology that we do in the lab um and so
one um really exciting and challenging
question is how different draft
combinations produce emergent phenotypes
especially phenotypes um that are
beneficial to us um
and then another question is just what
moves across the graph Junction and to
what extent are mobile molecules
functioning as signals and we're really
focusing on mobile messenger rnas here
which I don't have time to talk about
but I'll will point you to some great
resources from my lab during the talk um
and then finally at the most basic level
we don't have a good understanding of
what determines whether or not two
species are going to be compatible with
each other whether or not they can form
interconnected vasculature during
grafting um and by compatible I mean the
ability for two things to coexist
without problems or conflict so the
ability for them to stitch together um
and so we study our questions in this
compatibility framework where um two
things can grasp but maybe they have uh
like no uh appreciable beneficial impact
on each other um on the other end of the
spectrum two things um that are
incompatible have a problem atic
coexistence so they're unable to coexist
um in that Gras um format and then um on
the The Beneficial side Ultra
compatibility is where two things can
graft and that graft produces beneficial
outputs um that we appreciate as humans
so not evolutionarily beneficial but um
uh appreciated by by us um through our
lens and so a lot of the work um that
we've done is on this spectrum of
compatibility and incompatibility
uh because my first student to join the
lab Dr Hannah Thomas was super excited
about these questions so she really
carved out um a lot of work in this
direction that um two p uh least
bo uh PhD candidate and Sam yanders a
PhD student are now carrying
forward um and so graph incompatibility
is not a huge problem for tomato tomato
grafts pretty well to its wild relatives
but it can be a big problem in Woody
crops and it can go under detected for a
long periods of time and this is really
a classic um graph incompatibility
between pear and Quint um where you can
see this um necrotic divide across the
junction and um by detecting that
incompatibility Growers can then um WRA
in an interstock that is mutually
compatible with the root stock and the
scon which is super cool um so you can
actually rescue these incompatibilities
if you can detect them we think that the
information that we learn from tomato is
going to provide useful markers for um
detecting incompatibility in these other
systems because the process of grafting
is very similar across different species
so when you graft um two things together
um there's an initial adhesion um that
is um
a uh that that occurs through the
release of pectin that helps stick the
cells together um
and then a wound response process
promotes the formation of palis uh and
so that's like an undifferentiated wound
responsive tissue that then um starts to
make contact and the callus will start
to form plasmodes model connections and
communicate across the graph um that
callus fills in and through that space
um vascular differentiation and other
tissue tissue differentiation starts to
occur um and then subsequent quent um
phys the resumption of physiological
transport and subsequent um
differentiation leads to a very very
strong um
Junction that is actually stronger than
any other part in the stem because you
now have extra vascular extra
magnification and so this whole process
involves local signaling to actually
place the vascular strands in the right
place to reconnect the two plant parts
and that process is not um under at the
molecular level um the the use of
vascular patterning and differentiation
genes um and all of these processes um
affect the integrity and biophysical
strength of the plant at the end and
you'll see um how that informs some of
the tests we use to look at
compatibility um so to understand
compatibility in our system we grafted
tomato to a bunch of different um night
shade relatives that were readily
available and just looked at whether or
not there were negative impacts on the
plant um in response to grafting and we
found a really pronounced negative
impact on pepper tomato combinations and
so this is self grafted tomato and this
is perer and
pepato and I think this picture really
uh accentuates the the impact of the
negative graft this is tomato on a
Cayenne root stock um graft at the same
time as self-grafted tomato and so often
these plants are physiologically um
impaired which leads to stumped growth
um and and so it's a pretty clear um
incompatibility phenotype but
importantly the plants do live um
otherwise it' be hard to study them and
so we we consider this system uh an
example of delayed incompatibility where
um they're unable to graft but they're
able to survive for long periods of time
and I've actually had a Topper plant
live in my office for over a year so
they can they can live and grow very
very slowly for a very long
time um and so a lot of Hannah's work
looked at what causes this
incompatibility in pep NATO um and
before I dive into it I'll just show you
some of the the detailed information we
have about what happens when tomato is
self-grafted so when we have a
compatible graft forming and this was um
collected in collaboration with uh
nuclear physicist at wasu med school Dr
Yan chant Tha who uh just had a unique
passion for plants and built his pet
imager which is allows the tracking of
radiol labeled nucleid um through 3D
space and time um he built it inside of
a growth chamber so you could do
physiologically relevant experiments in
Plants um and so we used that to track
um a labeled carbon CO2 movement in
grafted plants um that were sealed they
had an airtight seal right above the
junction what you can see is that at 5
days postgrafting um we start seeing the
resumption of carbon transport and so
that indicates that physiological
transport through the flum um happens as
early as five days post grafting in this
setup um and then we used a labeled
nitrogen to Track xylm Transport um
because labeled water has a very short
halflife and um we saw that uh the
plants resume transport as early as six
days post grafting and So within Le than
a week you have a um a heel Junction
that's
transporting um in pep M we didn't have
access to the pet imager although I'm
pretty excited about the new XLE
proposal um I think the synchron will
have similar capacities in a few years
um so we used a uh fluorescent die
called cfda that's flow immobile you can
see the aphids that are contaminating
our plant um are taking it up in their
bellies um one one example of good
contamination I guess
um and when we look at cfda it uh gets
stopped at the junction um and so we
looked closer into the anatomy of these
grafted plants um and we you can see in
self-crafted Plants you have these nice
long spaghetti strings of zylin running
through um and then in pepato we have um
this disorganized vasculature so it's
forming these an asmosis and failing to
connect and communicate across the
junction uh we see a very similar
phenomenon in the reciprocal Direction
This Is Now with arming o staining um
for lignan and um you get this mass of
differentiating vasculature that's
failing to communicate and coordinate
with the other half of the graft um so
we consider these Bridges to Nowhere um
and we actually have a bridge to nowhere
here in IA um how many people know the
plans for the bridge to nowhere in
IA true okay so it's pretty exciting um
it's getting connected to a major trail
system so it will become a bridge to
somewhere very soon um and that's kind
of Our Hope with this work too is one
day we can rescue these
incompatibilities so we're not there yet
um and so basically the plant is forming
Bridges but they're not connecting
across they're not reconnecting the
physiological transport and this has um
major consequences for the biophysical
stability of the stem and so this is a
bend test that Hannah invented um and
basically you bend the plant and if it
breaks at the junction it fails the test
um because that Junction is supposed to
be the strongest point in the stem um
and if it breaks anywhere else it passes
the test and so toer and pepato almost
always break up the stem every once in a
while you get um an exception because
it's biology but almost always break it
the stem um so another thing we looked
at was uh whether we could identify some
genetic regulators um that are
controlling this compatibility and so we
collected RNA data of Pep and toer
graphs and um tomato and pepper self
grafts at 1 three and five days
postgrafting and we worked with Dr
rani's Lab at NC State to build that I
think are like above average pretty Gene
networks they look organized to me at
least um and they were able to identify
um putative major Regulators of graph
formation at the war three and five day
time points as well as mixed time points
and then we and this is for self-grafted
tomato the networks for incompatible
graphs were crazy and really hard to
navigate it was like this huge mess of
uh disregulation I guess um and so what
we did was we mapped on um the loss of
connectivity in the network um to look
for geneses that were important um in
compatible graph formation that are
disrupted in the in compatible graphs
and this is just an example of one gene
that we see that has um altered
connectivity it's GTI 5 um that Dr Greg
Martin's lab happened to have um mutants
for because it inter it's um yeah
interacts with um avrpto one of his
favorite um mutants and so um this is
cool this was implicated uh to function
and grafting that one day postgrafting
which is when those cells should be
adhering to each other um and so uh we
see that the vascular connects the graph
actually forms okay but there's this
fissure that remains at the the wound
site um and we have more work to do to
understand what's going on there but
it's kind of a neat example of the
networks informing some of the biology
um so one thing that surprised us was
that most of the hubs in the self graph
networks and in these incompatible
graphs um are not related to vascular
patterns
but our big um you know most apparent
phenotype in these incomparable graphs
is disorganized vasculature and we think
that that's because um a minority of the
cells in the the harvested tissue are
actually forming new vasculature um so
it's a bulk Arn AEK data set with a lot
of different things happening and so
they're less pronounced in the network
um so we pulled out known vascular
patterning genes um based on a network
from opsis that's really nicely
characterized um and we uh built our own
network from these genes based on what's
uh differentially expressed across our
time points and graph types and um so in
this network there's a lot of hypotheses
to be tested but one was the role of
this transcription Factor called blcks
four um that's involved in Cambo
specification and so uh one indication
that it might be important in this
process is that it gets has somewhat
chaotic expression in uh toer and pep
relative to self-grafted where it has
this gradual elevation in expression um
and we are also able to obtain mutants
for this from Zack litman's lab um which
is very nice this was in 2020 when it
was challenging to to to do um lots of
wet lab work um and so you can see these
walks for mutants um there
relatively normal they're a little bit
centered in growth but generally they
look like a normal tomato they make a
vascular bundles um so they have a nice
stem anatomy and when we graft them they
have high survival rates um and so um
this is self-grafted wild type this is
self-grafted walk 4 100% survival it was
pretty disappointing um but then Hannah
performed the bend test and saw that
100% of them actually break at the jump
and so that's an indication that there's
a loss of um biophysical stability even
though the plants survive and so that's
like um maybe our like uh big PR message
from the lab is that survival doesn't
equal compatibility um we can actually
look at the anatomy of these walk spor
plants Rel such to Wild type that form
vascular connections and um we see that
they are impaired in specifying vascular
connections and Elise is looking more
into the extent to which um this occurs
so um so so it's pretty cool that these
networks helped us find you know one one
regulator in the process of vascular
specification um and if we go back to
the um vascular network from a Rabbid
opsis you can see that there's other
potential genes that are likely involved
in placing the vasculature in the right
place um so that reconnections happen um
so walk Flor is the one that we looked
at um but Upstream of walk FL are these
um small signaling peptides called TS or
cleas um and CLE 41 is one of those
genes that help specify a walk fork in
the process of vascular patterning and
so um we are also able to get a mutant
for that and it looks like it's
disrupted again in the vascular specific
ation um and again Elise is looking into
the extent to which um this occurs and
and whether this um really a luring
signal could be um playing the major
role in placing Bas coach in the right
place so that roots and shoots can can
communicate post
drafting um and so one question that
we've asked ourselves after collecting
all this data and looking at these
mutants is whether we've really
explained graph incompatibility so it do
walks for look like um our pepato Ander
mutants and i' think not really um so in
pepato we have disorganized vascular
proliferation and in walks four we just
fail to specify the vasculature so these
networks are telling us um about genes
that are essential in grafting but maybe
not explaining the phenomenon of
incompatibility uh so Hannah dug deeper
into the role of tissue death in
incompatibility um again this is an 2020
was dark times and um and so she just
looked at um basically the Persistence
of dead tissue at The graft over a long
periods of time using this trien blue
staining where this deep purple color um
means that the cells are dead um and
these lighter Purple colors um are kind
of just noise in the Imaging um and so
she looked at seven 14 and 21 days after
grafting um and what she found she
Quantified it using an imagej pipeline
um and what she found is that there's
similar levels of dead tissue one week
after grafting in self-grafted plants
and incompatible graphs um but over time
the self grafts will clear that dead
tissue and the incompatible graphs um
persist in having dead tissue so of
course you wanted to see what was
happening in terms of gene expression um
in this this uh persistent tissue death
process um so she did RNA at these time
points as well um and this time she
pulled apart the San half of the graph
and stock half of the graph so this top
half is Canan data this bottom half is
stock and she just looked at um
differential expression and saw that the
incompatible graphs um this is align to
the to Tomato genome and this is to the
pepper genome a lot of factors here the
incompatible graphs have a dramatic up
regulation and down regulation of
differentially expressed
genes um and uh there's a lot of go
categories that are enriched across
these time points but there are some
that uh point us towards some really
cool models for what's happening so one
which is just a nice reality check is
that there's a response to water
deprivation it's not making xylm
connections so that that felt right um
it's still unclear how plants live for
this long without making ayl connections
um that's a open physiological mystery
um but in addition there's a lot of um
these geneontology categories related to
the plant immune system um and defense
and so Hannah's big
hypothesis um from this data and she she
did a lot more digging that I won't go
into but her big hypothesis is that the
incompatible combinations of genomes are
causing this activation of the plant
immune system that's leading to cell
death and if you want to hear more about
kind of our um
our approach to digging into the
molecular details and mechanisms that
might be working within this uh this
hypothesis go to Sam Meander seminar
next
month um the student
seminar um so so another question um
that we looked at is whether pepato and
toer are a specific type of
incompatibility or whether there're some
general rules that guide incompatibility
in this branch of the Sol and AC and so
what Hannah did was she did these
reciprocal graphs across um a few
members of the solenoid that were uh
possible to grow in graph together and
we ignored uh NIOSA and envent of
tobacco because there's some like pretty
wild reports of um Nana being able to
graft like across much any flowering
plant family so it's like a super
grafter that's doing something uh
exceptional so we stuck to this branch
of the
solenoid um and it doesn't look like a
ton of plants to draft together but once
you start doing the reciprocal graphs in
replication it's actually a huge
experiment um and again all the graphs
survive so survivorship is not a measure
of compatibility um self grafts form
really nice vascular connections that
string through um The
Junction um intra generic grafts Within
solanums this is tomato and eggplant
form beautiful vascular connections um
and this is work done by Michelle he a
PhD candidate in the lab um and in fact
uh this system is so strong that it's uh
formed the system that she's using to
look at long-distance communication
between
species um but all intergeneric so
across gener graphs fail to communicate
and form these really really ugly um
disorganized
graphs um and so we did a ton of
confocal Imaging to to look at this
process um but we also perform the bend
test and that's a pretty good indicator
of compatibility so pretty much all the
incompatible graphs here um break Almost
100% of the time with the bend test so
you really don't have to do imaging if
you want like a fast measure of this um
this property um and so to wrap up this
part of the talk we have found many ways
to make grafts
fail um and uh also collected some
really great tools to study this in more
depth so we've really expanded the tool
system here um and again uh T plant and
egg is another system for uh studying uh
communication and Michelle has just
awarded the uh the the best three minute
thesis in Cal so you can watch her her
talk on YouTube um or hear her talk uh
in a real seminar for for much more
in-depth uh view of the process um but
we're hoping to use these tools to to
eventually um find ways to reconnect
those bridges so make graphs uh succeed
and that I think will be a tremendous
effort to to overcome incompatibilities
but uh it's going to be
exciting so I want to use the last part
of the talk to talk about um this other
end of the spectrum um where we're
looking at compatibility this neutral
coexistence which is really home plant
and EG they don't really have huge
beneficial impacts on each other um and
Ultra
compatibility um and so this is uh an
area of work that's really kind of brand
new results coming out of the lab um and
this is looking at the ability to
program communication with implants for
alter compatibility from the Viewpoint
of the the farmer um or the human um and
so the goal here is to actually
reprogram the way plants are
communicating to give us more
information about the environmental
context in which plants are growing and
um enhance the um timing and um
quantitative responsive management
practices from our end um and so the the
first kind of example of this
reprogramming that we're looking at um
involves the signaling system called the
uh sep signaling system see terally
encoded peptide say the name says it all
and th this is um a root tissue and
shoot to root signaling system that
allows roots to forage in heterogeneous
nitrogen conditions um and it it's uh
partially responsible for kind of the
classic High nitrogen low nitrogen split
plate response um um that's described in
the literature where Roots will um
branch and grow more extensively in
areas of high
nitrogen and so how this works is that
under low nitrogen Roots will start to
express these uh small peptides called
steps that move from root to shoot um
where they're perceived by a receptor um
called Step R1 um which turns on the
production of a downstream signal called
set Downstream really great naming
scheme here um which moves back down
from the Shoot To The Roots um and
influences um nitrogen foraging
responses including uh U regulation of
nitrogen uptake Transporters as well as
increased root
branching um in in places where there's
High nitrogen and not where there's low
nitrogen and so our idea was that we
could actually plug in to the signaling
system to um learn about when plants are
experiencing below ground nitrogen
stress by seeing the output of this lowr
signal in the shoot um and then actually
reprogram the activation of the
signaling system to turn on in response
to other below ground stresses um and so
this is a huge collaborative project and
these are the main major um posto and
grad students have been leading this
work um across my lab cjan Le's lab um
AB st's lab and Mark Bin's
lab um and so what we've done is we've
created um these reporter plants um that
tell us when step Downstream is turned
on so that's F us when steps have moved
um and turned on the response uh by
turning on a ruby reporter so this is a
pigmentation reporter in tomato plants
under low nitrogen you can see it's um
really nicely expressed in the FL the
flanking Flo region where it's then
going to produce a downstream signal
that moves back from through and we've
also made a fluorescent lines in Abid
opsis to look at a more quantitative
response of this
process um and so this is the exciting
kind of new data coming out of the lab
where the plants actually work um and so
up here is wild type tomato and down
here are these Ru lines um under 13 days
of nitrogen deprivation um and so a grad
student in Abes lab Jacob Belding has
actually Quantified um using a really
simple image processing um pipeline that
he developed the response of these Ruby
lines under low nitrogen um over time
versus wild typ plant and the cool thing
here is that you actually start seeing a
significant response within days of low
nitrogen treatment which is way before
um any grower is going to see that with
the yellowing of leaves and the loss
productivity of their plant so we think
we have this early alarm system to help
people um manage their plants that can
then be adapted to many different below
ground inputs that are hard to manage um
and so we've also built this in a rabid
opsis with fluorescent reporters where
you see the kinetics are quite fast so
within six hours of low nitrogen
treatment we see um this reporter
turning
on um I thought this is quite a rapid
response and now the big question is
when does it actually turn off like so
if you apply nitrogen can you turn the
signal back off and use it throughout
the season
um and so we'll be getting into these uh
Messier questions in real field
environments as well as in the lab um so
we have plants that are actually uh
started already in uh Tucson Arizona and
they're going to go out to Maricopa and
then another set of plants that are
going to be um here in Aurora New York
growing amongst corn fields so this is
really um really cool to see work from
our lab going out into the real world to
be tested well the quote unquote real
world the research environment but still
the field to be tested and then again
the next step is really to see the what
extent can this communication be
reprogrammed to tell us about other
below ground um events that are really
hard to monitor like throughout
inages um okay I think I
have four
minutes so I'll tell you about um I'll
end with actually the first grafting
phenomenon that brought me into grafting
um and this is the phenomenon of
grafting induced Vigor um where when you
graft to a hybrid root stock an inner
specific hybrid root stock you get this
boost in vegetative and reproductive um
output that increases yield and so um
the commercial root stocks are typically
formed through these crosses between
domesticated tomato and a green fruited
tomato called sanum hites um and one of
the most popular commercial root stocks
that we in our research as well is Max
aort Max for short um and so when you
graft to Max support um the domesticated
tomato shoot system has this huge boost
um in its growth and so here's just the
increase in biomass that you get when
you graft a Max support that then
influences an increase in yield and
that's um a large reason for why the
this grafting is used in tomato
production in addition to atic and bi
stress tolerance and so a really cool
thing with this phenomenon is that it's
highly reputable across environments as
so these are greenhouse growth chamber
and multiple field studies showing that
the max support root stock really
increases uh vegetative biomass and
yield across environments which is uh
not common in biology to find something
that repeats across across environments
um so one of the questions um that I
actually started out asking is whether
it's really the hybrid state of the root
system that's increasing the biomass of
the choot um and so what I did is I
compared yield in a um domesticated
tomato grafted to a a
hites um root stock versus a hybrid an
F1 hybrid that I made with this hites
cross to M82 and I compared that to the
influence of Max of for root stocks and
so what I saw is that um it's really the
hybrid state that boo sealed but also my
random hybrid that I made just because
the seeds were available in the lab um
performs uh pretty similarly to one of
the top performing commercial lines and
that's
because I think we're growing these in
field conditions and a lot of root stock
breeding is um targeted to control
agricultural environments um and so uh
the very first grant in the lab um that
we got was a hatch Grant to look at
whether we can um identify other root
stocks that are beneficial for um
outdoor New York State growing
environments and so we made 30 different
um hybrid root stocks with different
habites ecotypes and grew these in high
tunnels in Freeville so this is a very
popular way to um uh grow tomatoes near
here um and pretty much any Farmers
Market tomato that's available earlier
in the season or later in the season is
likely harvested from one of these high
tunnels um and we found that many of our
experimental root stocks marketing green
um perform well to some top commercial
root stocks or sometimes even a little
bit better and so uh this is another
example of us going you know really out
into the real world where we were able
to take our top performing root stocks
test them out at a major um
production site um two hours from here
um so Zade cck uh welcomed us and our
crazy tomatoes and we didn't get a
quantitative measure of whether or not
they lik them
but this is a quote wow they're
significantly taller and healthier than
the non-grafted s in the ttle um and so
Tian is working on a more quantitative
measure of you know what influences
whether or not people use grafting in
their in their farms and so she's
performing um a real uh intensive survey
at these grower Expos which has been
really fun to go to um and so just like
how the hyperides probably has untap
potential for positively influencing um
um production and and the ability for
plants to perform uh nor is looking at
how other wild tomatoes are also
influencing uh the
performance of of tomatoes and so she's
making a ton of other um hybrid crosses
to these different some of these
different not all of these but some of
these different wild species that have
Superior H stress capacity and seeing
whether you can like rapidly adapt uh
tomato to challenging environments
um so that's I think a really cool
Direction work um so to wrap up we
have um a ton of awesome tools for the
spectrum of compatibility to
incompatibility and alra compatibility
and of course more questions than we
started with um and I have to thank the
lab again um for carving out these
questions and leading the work
forward um our collaborators and people
who really generously provided res
sources um I don't typically do this but
because it's a 10e seminar my mentors um
especially Adrien rer the head of my
mentorship committee who's made tons and
tons of time for me um during the last
many years um and then funding uh
without which none of this would happen
so hopefully funding
continues and that's it yeah I'll take
questions uh is there a relation ship
between
um how whether you can recover hybrid F1
hybrids easy easily and
graph compatibility I know like Peli and
htis are at the kind of that tail end
where you don't need to do certain like
embryo rescue and that kind of stuff to
right yeah so um is reproductive
compatibility an indicator for graph
compatibility and no it's not um so
there's a really cool um study where um
a group in Germany actually overcame
reproductive barriers between to um the
kosana species through grasing so they
uh were able to fuse the genomes of the
of the nuclei basically into one new
alop poly pled individual um That Could
set seed uh so like the graph
compatibility is much much broader than
reproductive compatibility is that that
showed us at least it's really cool
how was Max originally selected given
that hyperides seems to be almost as
good is there like oh like other hites I
think that there's a suite of other
traits that are probably highly relevant
to controlled agricultural
environments um including probably
stacking of disease um traits in
addition to its ability to um promote
that grafting induc bigger phenotype
because it is is one of the most
invigorating root stocks that we've
evaluated and we've looked at many so
it's definitely like a Surefire way to
increase um vegetative and reproductive
biomas which can be a problem sometimes
people have to like it takes a lot more
maintenance but keep the plants in
check I was just think that is it a
two IM response
supression process or it's the very
beginning why is it to overcome that
it's the developmental
process yeah that's such a great
question and I think that's right on
Sam's mind is like what which part's
active um in allowing plants to grasp um
and whether it's like an active process
to be able to graph or an active
rejection of incompatible graphs um so
we don't know but but we'll know in a
couple of
years um so I don't really know anything
about plant crafting but in fungi there
like some there can be some
interspecific fusion but like there are
lots of strains of the same species that
don't talk to each other and that has
really helped in finding these like uh
immune response mechanisms and I'm
wondering if there are like in plants if
like there are different isolates of
like tomato that maybe are in the same
species or or separate species but like
don't talk to each other at all or don't
don't pass the v test or whatever that
you could maybe use to help get at some
of that immune response questions yeah
that's a great question we were thinking
about maybe um ingression lines where
you have just chunks of like a really
distant species that could help with
mapping the genetics of it um but tomato
graphs pretty well to like the wild Bel
that we've tested so far so but there
are examples in puber cucurbit um so
cucurbit where there's um yeah more
distinct incompatibilities within a
species we should look at and try
um
adventurous how adaptable do you think
that nitrogen reporter plant could be to
like remote sensing via uavs we're gonna
test it out yeah so there's um a drone
that will like fly the over the Maricopa
fields and Aurora Fields we'll see I'm
like a detailed phenotyper so I'm a
little skeptical but field people aren't
so there any parallels to this to like
parasitic plants yeah
definitely useful tool to explore yeah
so um that's helped us kind of hone in
on some the next set of candidates that
might be interesting in those networks
um so there's these
LBD there's a lot of these Lal boundary
domain genes but um there are ones that
are essential for um post parasite
interactions in tomato that are also
expressed in our data set so um they're
like high level candidates
yeah this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu