this is a production of Cornell
University I wanted to understand how to
deliver resistance in the field I had a
I have a masters in plan Improvement
because I wanted to be able to provide
to the farmers good varieties that were
resistant but I could have not
accomplish that if I didn't understand
PL pathology I needed to understand the
pathogen side so that was my idea get a
mastering plan breing get a PhD implant
pathology bring it together so you can
deliver the best to the forers so that's
how how my uh career started working
with uh in Puerto Rico then uh in
Nebraska and then when I started working
with the USDA um I couldn't pick a a
better system it was working on Crown R
of oats but then I Had To Do genetics on
oats I needed to find resistance and and
as as if some of you have worked on oats
you know how difficult is to work on on
oats it's so witty there was not a lot
of resources so that was a good training
and then from there I went on into
working on stamas of we and uh that's a
story that I'm going to tell you a
little bit about today um I wanted to
start under this premise and this is why
what we do what we do plan protection in
general and the protection of of plants
of plant diseases into pets is essential
for food security and a lot of times we
don't see it that way or the media
doesn't portray that way or the in in
general we have done uh research for so
many years trying to increase
productivity in the 20th century that's
what we focus on how we're going to feed
the world that's how we're going to
produce more but a lot of times we
forget that we're already producing
quite a bit but we're losing a lot to
pathogens and pets uh in the field after
harvest and not only in quantity but
also in quality so if we can try to to
to retain sort of that loss we maybe the
job is not so tough going
forward and we know that feed in the
world is not new news this uh has been
portrayed since the 60s we knew that
there was a large population that we
needed to feed in the future but now
we're facing having to produce more food
than ever before we need to increase our
production by
70% um to be able to feed billion people
by 20150 so that's the challenge right
there so we need to take a
multifaceted from the production side
but also in the protection of our yields
and a lot of times I find that
um sorry about that um when we think
about food security we need to look at
the components we need to look at
first
um we need to look at production it's
availability is what we're looking at
production and also how we storage how
we reserve it we need to look also
into how we can afford it how can we
access that food so that would be
physically like in the market
be able to go to the market but also
having the uh the money to buy the food
be able to afford it so that's uh our
accessibility to it but also it's also
how we utilize it so we're talking about
nutrition but also we're talking about
safety um we know we know about toxins
we know about post Harvest so we need to
talk about um how to utilize it better a
balanced diet so food security requires
different components and we need to take
that into account when we do
research so how we fits in in this big
picture so uh most of you are probably
aware that we eat a lot of wheat the
world eat a lot of wheat but wheat um
provides 20 to 30% of the proteins in
the world and in many parts of the world
it also uh accounts for up to a third of
the calories uh that I consume in a
daily basis so it is extremely important
you know you know for us here in the US
wheat may be a piece of bread it may be
cookies it may be cake but in many parts
of the world it is what you get every
day it is what is the basis of your or
your diet so we need to take that into
the consideration when we talk about
food security it has to be balanced so
weed is not that the only CR that we
need to protect we need to protect our
legumes we need to protect many other uh
sources of of nutrition but we is
essential in that balanced diet
and I don't think I need to to explain
too much but we know about stas we know
what happened in the US we know about
barar eradication that started in the 19
uh
1917 and over Al 8 million of uh bushes
of barberries were eliminated eradicated
from uh the us and it wasn't an easy TK
but it was necessary and this is a
perfect example how and human can change
the situation this was in a very radical
way we changed the entire population of
a pathogen by removing the sexual
reproduction in many parts of the world
of the in the US and but there's still
barbares out there we know that in the
Pacific norways we have a a population
and we are aware and we have seen the
devastation that can cause for example
in in a specific years and a specific
location for example uh on barley we
know that there's still races of the
stem R pathogen coming out of that
sexual population that has affected
barley production recently in the US and
even after the Barbary eradication there
were still epidemic so the the solution
uh was not it was not complete but it
helped a lot because now we're going
from seeing you know dozens of races
every year to see more or less One race
every year in the US that is the
dominant race in the US so that's what
we can do for example ex if we intervene
but that's not possible everywhere in
the world it is a solution that it was
okay to do and it was able to manage the
disease because we didn't control it we
manage it for in a particular location
but it's not an approach that we can
take worldwide
wide so we thought we put it to rest
after the 50s uh we didn't see major
epidemics but then in
1998 uh William gory in Uganda
identified the first few postles of eug
99 the new the new race of the stem Russ
pathogen that uh it was not supposed to
be that these varieties were resistant
had been resistant for a long time so he
knew something wasn't right and after
verification um by with other
Laboratories because there was only a
few Laboratories that can uh do the race
analysis that was necessary to confirm
the villance of this pathogen then it
was confirmed that yes it was a a new
uh race of stbr and it had beIN on not
only sr31 that it was uh instrumental on
the development of varieties for the
world but it was also varent on many
other genes that were deployed around
the the the
world so the news is starting to get out
the thread was there and it got the
attention of the media it got the
attention of cons investors like the
binda Gates Foundation and the UK
department for International Development
and we then was decided to build a
coalition of scientists that could go
forward and manage this threat so in the
meantime I was at the USDA and I working
on oats and uh thanks to the deliv the
durable ristan we project there was an
opportunity for a post position at uh uh
Ida in Idaho to work on stamas and I was
asked if I wanted to be part of the team
so I decided to take the task and to
start to grow up and and and and start
working with a new uh disease and
shortly after I went to Kenya and
started evaluating
materials and uh we look at land races
uh that could Harbor New resistance to
eug
99 and it was during that period of time
that then I was offer the opportunity to
go to North Dakota so after uh one year
of being working on uh on the stas and
starting to collaborate with the
International Community then I had a new
task that it was to develop my own
research program at North Dakota State
University to tackle this same problem
they were concerned about eugi
99 and so they got a position that like
one of those was that you don't see
anymore theand it was work on Rust that
was the Mandate so how can I not take
take the chance and say hey let's see
what we can do and see now with the the
network of people that I have uh not
only in the US but across the world
let's be part of that community and try
to
help so I developed my program then at
ND NSU and you know they needed it
because wheat in nor Dakota is almost A2
billion industry and this is probably
underestimating uh how we affects all
areas not only of Agriculture but the
economy in general of the state
um and based on the his historical uh
evidence they needed to be worried
because yes they didn't have epidemics
of ASAS in the near past because uh we
have been able to manage the different
races and we have been able to put
varieties that have resistance but they
had the environment for the disease
development even the eradication of the
barberries nor Dakota saw 56% yield
losses in in 1935 so they knew that if
this ug99 or any other races that were
as verin um got to the US North Dakota
would be in big trouble so it made a lot
of sense to to develop a program to
tackle this uh problem so from the work
that I started at at the USDA
identifying another races that have
resistance then I was a able to to start
my project in uh North Dakota that it
was to use these two uh land races one
is from Iran the one on the top and it
has really good resistance to in Kenya
and then this other Montenegro land race
that has also good resistance over time
so this was the first project that I
started developing with my first PhD
student in North Dakota and so Jason was
able to map this resistance we
identified that it that the inheritance
was conferred by uh one G so it seems
like a good project for a student let's
map the Gene and try to determine if
this is a new gene or it's an
underutilized so we can start
incorporating and broaden the resistant
base of our
varieties so after a couple of years and
a lot of investment into developing
mapping populations developing new
markets that at that point were not uh
totally accessible because this where
with the snip ships were coming out uh
for we um so we were able then to not
only uh find the chromosomal location of
these genes but also this Gene but also
map it uh do a high density map that
would allow us to identify good genetic
markers that can be used to uh in
progress this resist to utilize it in in
variety
in the meantime uh we were able to more
resources were coming into weat now we
were able to identify uh some potential
genes that can be uh that in the region
and that could be the the actual Gene of
interest uh they are MBS LR uh type um
so at this moment we are still trying to
figure out because uh for those of you
that uh have not worked on a hex
uh C it you know it seems
straightforward yeah we have five G cand
we should be able to go in and identify
this gen and that is not the case with
we because you have so many repetitive
units and you have duplications of the
gene so every time you time to map it in
the B genome then you find it again in
the D genome and you're like okay so
what I'm dealing with so I've been
really a grow a a Growing Experience a
learning experience uh for me and for
myself
student um so when we were worrying
about trying to clone the Jean because
that was the the the golden uh child was
to to try to clone this Gene e99 start
changing so now we were're not dealing
with one or two race we were working now
at this moment with 13 different
variants and our great Gene it was
effective to some of them but not to all
of them so the work wasn't done we
needed to find more resistance so we
start working then with addition looking
for new sources of resistance so we went
to our second choice that was that
montro land race that uh race uh that
land race seemed really really good we
tested again uh 20 races North American
races and the variant that we had
accessible from the East Africa lineage
and it was resistant to all of them so
we said this is the one we will go after
it um and then we start doing the
mapping and what we found is that it was
not normally distributed when we look at
the
population so we was like okay this is
not looking good it's not one gene it's
multiple genes that we're dealing with
now um we saw that uh there was
transgressive segregants and when we
start doing the
mapping we have lots of gen uh or at
least qls in the in this background so
it made it really difficult because some
of these uh
genes for example like sr12 is not
effective against ug99 but our Gene is
right underneath sr12 so or we have a
different ala of sr12 or there's another
Gene in the same region and because we
don't have a genome of the of whe
there's a lot that we don't know what's
happening in that particular region so
that's just to show you an example so we
find multiple
qtls uh in in the chromosomes C and and
d and uh 6D 7D in
3B and it continues so we have around
five different uh QT when we did an
inheritance yes it was not melan it's h
quantitative but it is a great
resistance so I'm not ready to give up
we we see it in the field side by side
with our checks and our line has zero no
disease is mostly immune every year so
what's going on we need to get to the
Bott the bottom of it but uh it it is
challenging but I think that's what we
do science we just want to know why you
know how we got here so it keeps us
interesting um yeah so it is uh in
addition when we look at the different
uh qls they have an additive effect so
we know we cannot just bring one of the
jeans we need to bring multiple uh cils
or jeans uh into this pet if we want to
have that level of persistance so for
those of you that Do genetics and
breeding then you know what the Tas the
Tas is in hand we need to be able to
bring all this genes together and we're
talking about one trade and briers have
to worry about how many um so so it
makes it really interesting and and
challenging but I think it's all worth
it because we know what would happen if
we don't do the
job so another project that I was
involved uh more on the pathogen side
was working on uh looking at the
population
of pinia Trina so not stas we're now
talking about leas and this was kind of
a personal uh a very personal project
because I didn't want to just work on
stem like everybody was working on stem
because it was needed but like I needed
my own little side project so I didn't
give it to my student I wanted to work
on it myself on my spare time so every
time I went to Kenya and Ethiopia I took
samples of the pathogen that I found I
had a permit so I can bring uh C tra to
the states and working with Jim colmer
in the USDA we were able to look at the
diversity of the pathogen and based on
previous uh report from Jim's work we
knew that there was a unique population
of the pinia triina uh pathogen in uh in
Ethiopia something that is never is
never been observed anywhere else in the
world and we didn't know why so what we
start looking at this uh uh isolates the
first thing that we notice is that they
are not virent on the differential set
that we use for classification so now
it's like okay so what do we do now we
put it on the differential set and it
doesn't grow on the differential set so
we can of give it a race number so a
name um so we don't know what is the
Varin complexity of this pathogen but we
know that we see it every year on during
with the tetrao instead of the hexo that
is our bre we this is on on the Pasa and
emwe that are also tets in Ethiopia and
we found similar pockets of populations
in North Africa in in the mediterranian
region but nothing like we saw in
Ethiopia so this is one of the ongoing
projects uh kind of again my side
projects just something to play with
where we can still uh try to figure out
what's going on what is so unique about
Ethiopia we have some hypothesis uh in
Ethiopia there is a lot of
tet wheat that has been there for
hundreds over here so this population
has evolved in isolation from other uh
um we uh we don't see this popular these
tetr being grown as crop in other parts
of the world but in Ethiopia they are up
to 7% of the crop so there is a unique
population
um so we will continue working on it oh
I want to mention just this so in
addition to Trina there's another lethos
pathogen that is have never been given
much importance and this is a pinia
durad duad so again it only grows on
Duro and has been observed in North
Africa in Morocco in uh southern Spain
in Portugal
and it doesn't have the same alternate
host it has an alternate host that is
called anus italica it's and this whe
wheat here next to the wheat so I was in
Morocco visiting one of our
collaborators and we were looking at
leas and we were in the field and I just
see the wheat I'm like What's Happening
here so we know the alternate house for
this other uh Lea that is pres in the
region what is the significance of that
we don't know we don't know if it's part
of the epidemiology of that disease
there we don't know what uh what role it
plays at this uh point but looking back
in the literature there is evidence that
these uh
pyrogen could uh be a bridge for uh
having uh Rec combination between Trina
and Dua there's a potential for it but
also we have a lot of other
uh wild relatives of wheat in the region
that we haven't looked at yet so are
they reservoirs also of of these older
pathogens and that can play a role of
what the Vance that we see in and so
there's a lot of questions out there
that have not been answered yet in terms
of of Russ you know we would think that
by now we have studied Russ so much and
we will have all the answers but it's
not the case and I like it that way I
like that not only for job security but
also because we know there is a lot more
to do you know there is a lot of
challenges and what it tells us that
there's also a lot of potential
Solutions out there that we are not
aware of because the better we
understand the system the better we can
manage
it so um this is the the results they
are preliminary uh results of the work
where we see the ethopian uh isolat so
you can see here the these are the bread
whe the hexaploid whe is they're here
and here and then uh from Kenya you can
see isol it's also from R but then you
look at what is these EES these are the
one that you don't grow on the
differential set these are the on that
are coming from emmer wheat and from
Duram wheat and they're up here on their
own and they are even different than
other Dural isolates that actually grow
on the differential set this are the
what we call the B races that are highly
a virent on the leus genes that are
present on common wheat but they are
very very different so what is the
evolution of
this isolate how is that to be in
Ethiopia why we haven't observed
anywhere else in the world in the world
and what you know is there resistance
there that we have not explored in
Ethiopia not only to these uh races but
who other uh races that not only um
we have use in Durham we but can be
utilized maybe in HEX because the
isolates that grow on Durham don't grow
well on the hexy we the bread we and the
isolates that are virent on the hexy we
are not virent on the D so it's a
beautiful
coevolution uh study that they I think
is worth uh worth investing on um to to
determine if there's resistance that we
have overlooked there new path that we
can
explore so science it was it was a lot
of fun working in North Dakota having my
own research project having my own green
houses and the grad students but there
was a larger call for me um the farmers
were still the main goal getting to the
farmer get it out to the field making
those varieties available so it was
great mapping those gen it was great to
try to clone the gene but if that Gene
stays in a shell it doesn't do any good
you know we can invest all the time and
effort and money in
that research and if it doesn't make it
to the field if it's not useful like how
I'm going to utilize that those genes
that are uh present in that mon agree uh
land race how I bring them together how
that resistance that it's uh effective
only to few races can be combined with
all the resistance that are out there
and then
uh get it to to the field so we can feed
the world so that's how I ended a
Cornell because I knew that I can count
on a great Coalition of scientists the
great community of scientists that was
uh calling to action by Dr Norman
borlock in
2005 and during when he saw the threat
of Eugene 99 he knew what it needed to
happen and he sounded the alarm so it
was great to know that I was not alone
that there was a group of scientists
that could uh use the expertise I have
developed but also that I can
collaborate with and so I took the role
of coming to uh
Cornell and start working on building on
what was built on the durable roster
System project from 2008 on and what the
durable roster System project did was to
use a
multifaceted uh stem Russ specifically
eug 99 where they look at understanding
the pathogen looking at the alternate
host new Gene Discovery and that was key
part of the project but also developing
markers for those genes so we can better
utilize them we also look at the nonhost
resistance to see if there was anything
there that we can utilize again to to
try to manage the disas and of course
breeding because if it we don't do the
breeding aspect again it just stays on a
shelf it stays on on on Journal articles
but it doesn't make it to the the field
and then we needed seat
multiplication capacity building was uh
what I what I think is very unique about
this uh project is that it took into
account not only the scientific
component but the social component how
do we develop a new generation of
scientists that can take the job on for
the next uh decades because when Eugene
99 came up there was only few people in
the world they knew about stem rust that
have seen a stem rust and they knew what
to do so we needed to develop this new
generation of
scientists and then the world has
changed and we know that gender uh in
science was something that needed to be
talked about and needed to be approached
from a very scientific point of view is
like we need to bring together the best
of the best and we need to be very
concerned about leaving people behind
that could bring in lots of great ideas
and should be respected equally so they
took into this multifaceted approach to
really deal with the problem and I think
it was it was really what attracted me
to to this position to know that I I
have access and to to this fantastic
network of
people um so this is the partnership
that it was developed during the durable
rush for 6 week project and as you see
it's a global partnership and that's
what the one of the strength of this
project because you have experts around
the world with different life experien
with different uh backgrounds in
backgrounds in genetics in plan reading
in Plant Pathology social sciences you
have all of it you have Laboratories um
that could take samples Laboratories
that were very rudimentary but they have
the passion to do the work they only
needed the
training so building on that is where uh
the new project the delivery and genetic
gaining wheat comes about it was
launched in uh March that's when I
joined the team and right now my uh
responsibility is to manage the
scientific components of this uh this
project is bringing some uh leadership
and some uh help the the scientists do
what they need to do uh be able to
provide for that community be able to
communicate between the different groups
so we work together we don't have uh
competitive efforts in but we would
utilize the resources the best that we
can and also come up with new ideas how
you know I if I talk to somebody in one
uh laboratory and see that they should
connect to another laboratory I can
bring those collaborations together um
but at the same time having a a
background in Ros pathology kind of
helps um so this is how the project
looks uh we it started in 2008 this is
the first phase of the d r Sy a week
second phase and now is where we are
with the
ggw and these are the main uh objective
of the project that is to modernize
reading programs seit and National
programs in Ethiopia and sou Asia it
also we're looking at surveillance we're
looking looking at how the pathogen
change move can we predict it can we uh
put additional models out there not only
that we can say oh yeah this is a new
race or the race that show up last year
was this race no we don't want to do it
looking backwards we want it to look
forward can we predict where we're going
to see the next epidemic can we
determine what races have the best
chances of movement into a different uh
location that's what we're looking at
and we're going to continue
um the human capacity
building this is the approach that we're
taking similar uh as before um putting
more effort into again the surveillance
uh during the we're using the
phenotyping platform that is where we
use our um field plots in Kenya and
Ethiopia to be able to screen as many
materials from around the world so we
can move forward faster but also we're
using new technologies uh because only
looking at rust we are looking at how
can we deliver a better package can we
so resistance is one trade but we need
to look at yeld we need to look at
quality we need to look at a climate
that is changing so now we have to grow
more wheat and less space under less
resources can we find better drought
tolerant um heat uh tolerant wheat
parities can we make that power package
so that's what we're working with our
teams uh
and National programs around the world
to try to identify not only resistant to
Ras or to sector that's another area
that we're looking at but also looking
at we in
general um so as I mentioned we were
expanding our surveillance uh when the
project started in 2008 there were just
a couple of of Laboratories that uh can
handle race identification and only few
uh groups were sharing data on the races
that they were observing now we have uh
many countries collaborating and
bringing data every year so we can track
the pathogen better and also predict
where we may observe in the next
season we are continue our breeding
efforts and expanding on the efforts
that were developed
before we're going to bring new
technology like the lyic uh selection
Hydro phenotypic so this brings uh using
new technology the best of the best that
uh that is out there um to develop new
new systems to do the work uh better
more efficient to deliver genetic G uh
to increase the rate of genetic gain in
we uh we're again we're going to
continue using our of what we call the
phenotypic platforms are very large uh
field plots in different parts of the
world that are hotpots for a specific
trades or like in the case of Russ it
was Kenya Ethiopia now we're using also
Ethiopia for septoria but also Sim is
looking into uh finding additional
platforms that they can utilize for
Drought for example in Mexico right now
they're using uh changing the planting
time to be able to uh get drought and
heat
uh test for for um for tolerance of beat
and
drought we're going to continue our
advocacy and this is something that get
overlooked so many times the importance
of communicating the science not only to
uh the media the public but policy
makers uh understanding the value of
really getting
uh science based information out there
uh to remove this the information and
the fears that the public and the media
and even other scientists have about um
what what's happening in our part of the
world in case uh
of um technology and in in general
reading aspects and and should we
interfere should we intervene should we
do things differently so advocacy it's
key not only for communicating the
science but also to attract uh
additional funding you know I'm sure you
are all aware how difficult is to find
funding for public goods this day and to
continue that work it requires
communication and and communicating it
effectively we're going to continue our
talent Pipeline with uh doing a training
of young of junior scientists uh this
will be short and long-term trainings
include some week training or sending
somebody to uh for a PhD abroad and also
trying to maintain the knowledge in the
country we don't want uh to deploy the
countries of of their their smarter
smartest people we want them to go back
and have a place in that community in
their in their country so try to
encourage that um gu we will continue
also uh advocating for those rewarding
those uh mentors that Mentor females and
minorities and do a great job of recog
that everybody should have a place that
can science and can contribute to
science we're going to do thata
management you know we're talking about
Big Data we're talking about having
drones taking data out there in the
field how are we going to process the
data you know now before the bottleneck
was like I cannot walk fast enough I
don't have that many hours in the day to
collect my data now we can collect the
data like what do we do once we get the
data in um so we know that there's a a
bottleneck there so we looking better
way to manage the data and also how to
share it we are big on Open Access and
that science needs to be collaborative
that you canot work in isolation um and
and one of the key components of our
project is that every publication that
is the result of our project is going to
be publ ACC and is just thanks to the
support from our
sponsor we're going to do uh a small
part on SE production in in Nepal
because of the need after the earthquake
we know that there is a really big gap
and we can use this it's an opportunity
to learn how to develop a small uh seat
system that could be utilized as an
example for developing other systems in
the
world and we do it from our headquarters
here at Cornell because we know that we
are very well placed to and respected in
the world to to do a great job bringing
uh science sciences and and the public
together there's a lot of trust built in
this uh University from the part of the
public but also from from our investors
so we are very well placed to
collaborate with
others and again the goal is to take it
to the farmer and
makings thank
you question
I hope that I'm back on my
defense I haven't been asked that in a
while U so when we talk about durability
of persistent we all we talk about over
time but also uh overages so D Russ
system is something difficult to Define
because you can only really look at it
when you look backwards like how long it
lasted where was uh established but we
know that there are some key components
that seem to be correlating with
durability so we're talking about not
putting High uh selection pressure on
the pathogen so the pathogen doesn't
evolve as fast so for example using uh
like uh slow rusting G seem to be
associated with uh durability in some
cases not in all thees some cases we
have seen that there's uh some
correlation there um but we know that
some uh genes that have lasted for a
long period of time like the sr31 was
aning progression from a different
species to each so there are some key
components that that we don't understand
clearly yet uh but there's also some
some dangers when we start swapping
jeans you know are we going to make the
system more easier to evolve so the
pathogen now can go into other
other crops that it was not hose in the
past we have not seen that necessarily
with with our rust but we know that
could be a chance there but in terms of
durability we're trying to
find ways to stack more genes so when we
took we look at durability like if we
put three to five gen together and we're
talking about uh that the pathogen needs
to mutate four or five times to be able
to over that resist in that particular
variety so if we reduce the amount of
inoculum because the pathogen kind of
grow on this plant
enough we are reducing the inoculum that
is there the mutation rate uh is there
but the chances of you know one billion
spores versus two billion spores maybe
we we reduce the chance of amutation
that can overcome a particular
resistance so I think the durability has
to be looked from different aspect from
the host side but also what it's doing
on the pathogen side the
population so that kind of answers your
question more
I know we're always excited what's new
in the pipeline so there's a couple of
things on the surveillance aspect so
surveillance is sampling more uh but
also have uh better sources in the
genotypic side of things so can we
identify uh markers that would tell us
is a ug99 or it's not a ug99 rate so now
we have that in place uh that at least
can tell us the group type we are not
been we have not been able to develop
races specific markers yet uh but we can
tell that it belongs in L uh so that is
part that gets incorporated as soon as
samples are collected they are sent to
Minnesota or to Denmark and they can be
uh uh evaluated that way we hope that we
can do more on that and get uh faster
responses so we know what we're dealing
with uh we're also using more uh
technology so the farmer or the
researcher that is in the field can
identify um is the stem rust is leaf
rust is yellow rust can upload it um can
tell you the coordinates and if we see
that it's a Hotpot and we with the
modeling that we have in place can we
say you need to go and spread you know
in the next region because based on our
wind pattern and the weather and the
information that we have in hand you are
next one so that's what we're doing with
surveillance trying to develop a in
system that can be incorporated so it
have different components sort of
connected's question I know there was
always a lot of concern when when it got
into IR it has because Barber is and
actually used as a barber berries are
used as a common traditional
food so is anything been detected
different fance since it's moved that
that's something to be explored yet you
know after the initial
uh confirmation of of us9 in we haven't
seen new races coming out of so it can
be many reasons we U you know our
triangle so um I don't need to explain
that that's normally how we go in the
disease triangle goes this way so we
don't uh so we don't know what that is
but we have not
observed special
like the question one of the first let
let's look at
uh the country situation in Kenya in
Ethiopia and many areas in uh East
Africa wheat is planted all the time
there is one season after another after
another so we know there is a green
bridge so once you're harvesting one the
other one is already uh in the ceiling
stage so the Russ can uh always survive
you always have a hope um eug 99 per se
is just a a combinations of of of
berance and one of the key that it had
was sr31 and we know that sr31 has been
deployed around the world uh in in many
varieties so selection pressure was
there uh we don't know you know the
first evidence of of9 East Africa came
around that time 1998 but then looking
back at records it seems that it was
there before we very very low frequency
so you know with agriculture we have
probably selected for it but the
challenge is that there's always inum
there's always H in the area so we're
seeing all these new variants in the
region because the pathogen can keep
mutating and you have all the
um oh so if the ug99 has been picked up
on Barberry um so there is barberries in
the region in in Kenya and Ethiopia and
one of the Spees can uh is a it's a host
of ofia gram so we know that if it's uh
I don't think has been confirmed that
the particular race is on the barbares
but we know the barbares are in the
region we don't know uh all
the role that the barber may play
because see the high altitude but it's
definitely there in
the would you comment on use of the
sealing test versus the field test
advantages and disadvantages and
problems so one of the this is the
beautiful thing of working with people
that know the systems uh and know
pathology uh I normally work with with
readers so it's a little bit different
so we have to explain a lot but you have
the right questions um the the uh the
ceiling test for the weat stem rust
works really well for most of our old
stages uh jeans so jeans that are
effective at the ceiling so far are
effective at the adult plant stage but
there is jeans that are in the adult
plant stage that are not uh evident at
the ceiling stage so we those we cannot
detect at the ceiling stage because the
plants look susceptible but once you put
it in the field then you have your field
resistance uh in uh so we use both we
use the seing test to detect the All
Stage resistant genes that are normally
rais specific and then we work with the
adult plant genes that are some of those
slow ring that I was talking before that
are tend to be not raises specific they
have a broad uh spectrum of resistance
and so then we look at the uh latency
period and all of that so both of them
uh need to be used in combination but
the cing test is really help for numbers
it allow us to eliminate a lot of
materials uh but definitely some
materials that are susceptible at the
ceiling stage will be resistent at the
other
station questions for many of our
students or
post you're D to know
great and and uh so the question is
about uh the technologies that we're
using like some of the phenotyping and
the genotyping is expected to be spread
across every laboratory or there
specific centers no we have centers that
are uh are doing the the research and uh
we have for example genotype laborator
that are accessible so people can send
their samples in so we support some of
the USDA Laboratories or a laboratory in
Denmark and in Canada that can do the
genotyping for us and we are offering
the opportunity of training for junior
scientists because many countries want
to modernize the agriculture Ethiopia is
one of those countries that is really
looking forward to modernizing the
Agriculture and so they've won molecular
biology experience so we we're offering
the training so if the opportunity is
there for them they're well trained to
do and be our collaborators
in so I want to thank you again
semar Andel say we would like closer
ties with theologist
here marel has offer to have meetings
with anybody interested in getting to
know a little better just simply send
her an email here so thank you
very this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu