this is a production of Cornell
University um so thank you so much for
um inviting me to give this this seminar
today um I know it is a Plant Pathology
seminar and I'm going to talk about
insect resistance uh but there is a
little bit of Plant Pathology later on
in the in the seminar um I'm just for
disclaimer purposes I'm not going to
take any questions or comment on any uh
political implications that impact or
have impacted the research that we're
doing in the potential for continuing
the project or not so I would just put
that out there um let's talk about the
how the technology went from all the
Innovation to how it has been adopted in
Bangladesh and the impact that we've
seen so far what we think is going to
happen in the future with this
technology and the opportunities that
exist so that's what I'm going to focus
on today it's a good
story so this is why we're going to con
to focus on the Partnerships that made
this
uh project possible it has been about 20
years uh SE of investment in
collaboration between
organizations and I'm currently the the
Project Director for the last uh or the
current investment from uh USA um into
BT egpl so why BT egpl why is important
so egpl is the second most important
vegetable in Bangladesh and as you can
see in this picture there is a lot of
diversity um of the eggplants so most of
the eggplants that we consume here are
uh not necessarily part of the diversity
that you see in Bangladeshi uh diet
there is a lot of diversity of around a
100 different varieties types of of uh
eggplants are growing in Bangladesh so
this is important as we continue to talk
about um how our technology has been
delivered and it's grow by um 150,000
resource for Farmers um and this is the
challenge that they face every year um
the egpl uh fruit and Sho border can
reduce yield by about 70% even after uh
intensive use of
insecticides um Bangladeshi Farmers
spray about a hundred times in one
season 100 time insecti size that are
neurotoxin and for those of you that
have never uh grown an eggplant eggplant
is not something that you harvest once
you will hars over month so think about
the implications of that for insecticide
application you are spraying insecticide
without any safety gear any
protection and as you are spraying
you're also going to be harvesting on
the same day or the day
after and it's not necessarily a person
that the person that is going to be uh
using the insecticide will be an adult
or somebody that has been trained it can
be the children in the family it can be
elderly it will be women it will be
young people as range so again think
about that so when we think about why
was this so important why is this
intervention so necessary so it's not
just a scientific curiosity is not
because the technology was just
available because there is a true need
so the cry1 A1C uh Gene from basilo
tenses can render um eggplant resistant
a single Gene can uh provide the
resistance for the fruit and shoe border
that is the major pass of Egan there's
other minor uh passs and uh that impact
the yield but the fruit and Sh B is the
ma it's the the major and the company
Miko had developed BT act plan Mahiko is
a company in India and that many uh here
at Cornell are familiar with um had this
uh C1 Cene uh incorporated into BT into
Ean uh through the what is called the E1
event so it is a transgenic prop um that
was developed uh in the private sector
and through that
collaboration um with Cornell with sarur
gur consultant um in the Bangladesh
agricultural Research Institute as the
recipients of that technology but
broader uh interaction with the
Bangladeshi government Mahiko gave the
technology to Bari licens the technology
free of charge and free of royalty so
that they can produce BT Ean varieties
that are adapted for the Bangladesh
environment so these were varieties that
are already existed in B the Bangladesh
agricultural Research Institute they
have developed it based on their market
knowledge and the knowledge of their
scientists and their communities these
are varieties that were already adapted
to the area and then the gene was then
inserted so this was not varieties that
were coming from somewhere abroad
without being tested so I want to
clarify that because I know that um many
of the um GMO uh crops that we think
about we think about multinational that
introduce use their hybrids or varieties
into a country and hope for the best no
this was not this was very well thought
and planned um and it was highly uh
consulted with the Bangladeshi uh
Research Institute and government so uh
from 2004 to 2009 these varieties were
developed through back Crossing nine
popular varieties in October of 2013
four varieties were
released and here you can see the
minister of agriculture
um MAA Shri U providing the first btpl
seeds to 20 farmers in 2014 so 20
farmers in 2014 received the first seed
so that tell you about the political
willingness that was necessary and was
behind that technology so we have
Innovation we have science and then we
have political will and we have
involvement of the relevant uh
stakeholders in Bangladesh so this kind
of showcase here the institutions that
were involved in this uh collaboration
so not only the Bangladesh agricultural
Research Institute that it would be kind
of like the counterpart of the USDA but
then also a um arm of the organization
that produces seeds because we're going
to hear that then is not only bringing
the technology to the country but then
how do you produce seed to reach the
farmers and also we needed to do our
reach communication so we have the um
farming future Bangladesh that is a
group of uh Young
um journalists and communicators that do
Outreach in the community understand the
culture understand the values of the
culture understand the language can
speak the language reaching out to them
and then we have Cornell we have
different uh the Ministry of Agriculture
and we have Seth Guru that helps broker
that relationship between the private
and the public uh organizations that
then turn out to be this public private
public partnership that has been so
successful so from 2014 when 20 Farmers
received uh the first seats in four
districts now through all this
collaboration through these
organizations in terms of demonstration
plots um involving the extension agents
producing seed making sure that that
seed is pure that has good quality and
coordinating efforts across them now we
have over 65,000 Farmers every year
growing uh BT equan um these varieties
are open pollinated so what that means
it's it's great that farmers can keep
seed of it but it makes it very
challenge to know where the seity is
going so we are making some assumptions
based on seed that has been distributed
but also we know that based on our um
studies that about 15 to 25% Farmers may
be keeping seed for next Seas or passing
on to their neighbors or their fames so
we know that the number may be much
higher because we cannot uh keep track
of all the seed that is in the market
in addition to the formal SE
system so these are the four varieties
that were released and as you can see
this is the diversity I was talking to
you about so they have green eggplant
purple eggplant pink implant um with
striation we know striation elongated
round it's you name it it's it's they
have different varieties that they like
for different dishes for different
purposes now even to the point that even
within a variety they will be looking at
in the market let's say this green um
GRE green variety that is very large
some families will be looking for
smaller fruit because they only have
four people in the family or two people
in the family so they don't have to feed
a family of seven anymore so they want
small fruits so they don't waste food so
all of this is important when you're
talking about a vegetable um one thing I
forgot to mention and that it may be uh
um relevant is that most people think
that when we think about insecticide or
pesticides in general that are these um
commodity crops the ones that consume
the most but a lot a lot of the
pesticides are actually used in
vegetables and fruit because it's
economically you can make a case for it
and so we like our fruits and vegetable
to be damage free um there's also a high
value of these products in the market so
that when the farmer has to do the math
they say well I can if I protect my
yield I really get a revenue even if I
have to app apply the the pesti signs
so these is the numbers that we're
getting after um the adoption of BT Ean
So based on an independent study uh
we're seeing negligible fruit
infestation in btpl compared to 45% in
nonb eggplant we see a 61% saving on
pesticide cost so think about that about
40% of the cost of production is
insecticide and we're seeing a 61%
reduction on insecticide cost use uh
just from one single Gene in this
technology we see a six time increase in
farmac net return we see have 21%
increase in gross revenue and about 20%
higher uh fruit yield um so the fruit
yield here comes in different ways not
only um the variety yield is is better
but every fruit is marketable or has a
potential to be marketable because it
doesn't have the damage from this um
this pth in addition at the market level
once the fruit is in the market every
fruit that is in the market can be
marketable again and then at the kitchen
level the people that are buying the
fruit can consume the entire fruit
because there's no damage so uh if you
don't know what what the Border causes
it it's having a warm inside of the
fruit or having the the larv growing
inside the fruit so the the at the
kitchen level the person will have to
cut away and throw away like you know
when you do with your potatoes when
there's some damage no so think about
that when it's highly damaged and now
you can consume the entire fruit so when
we think about not only yield but food
loss and food waste at the farm level
and the kitchen all of this is reduced
because of this
technology and then we see about 41%
reduction in toxicity um from the
pesticides you use and based on their
own reports um of symptoms this is from
the farmers and and the
household so in the current investment
uh since this technology since 2014 has
been so successful in terms of getting
adoption and getting track in the field
what we wanted to do was to increase
that adoption and the long-term
sustainability because now we know that
technology is accepted it's in those
four varieties the farmers are growing
it so how do we protect this technology
not only for Bangladesh but for the
surrounding region because BT we know
can be overcome um by the passive is not
uh properly
protected so in the um IRB that is the U
insect resistant Ean partnership um
project um the goal is to scale up the
adoption of these four varieties that
carry that c1c Gene we want to develop
the next generation of btan in this case
hybrids and varieties uh but hybrids are
really important because since the
technology was developed and it was
developed for uh resource for farmers
and the idea was that well if if it's
resource for Farmers let's make sure
that it's open po so they can maintain
seed that the culture has changed
significantly farmers are buying hybrids
because they know the return of
investment so they're buying hybrids of
of potato of uh Peppers of tomato of
eggplant itself and you will see the
numbers later so we know the culture has
changed not only in Bangladesh but in in
South Asia in Asia in general in in
Africa too because the farmers are risk
adverse but they will try things once
and if they sue a return on investment
they will do it but at the same time if
they don't see any good return on
investment they they're pretty smart
they will do the math and they will not
buy hybrids if it doesn't make sense to
them but they are buying hybrids so we
know by a fact that there is a market
for
that there's also we need a a reason uh
a way to strengthen the value chain
because the value chain goes from all
the way from the seed development all
the way to the consumption so how do we
make that uh value chain more inclusive
for different um people in the community
different segments and then how do we do
more Outreach and education so people
that are not aware of that technology or
may have some misinformation or or just
really are curious about it can't get
the right information and that includes
not only the public the consumer but the
scientists themselves and the policy
makers that are making the
decisions so we we want to improve the
enabling environment for btan and
biotech in general um in Bangladesh and
also we were involed we are involved in
supporting that commercialization and um
BT plan in the Philippines I'm not going
to talk about the Philippines today
because that's a whole different seminar
uh it will take another hour to go over
it so how do we do this we do this
through ensuring high quality seed
availability and Market of Market prefer
varieties we do have an increasing
adoption of the existing egpl so that it
can reach um Beyond those four initial
District or the eight District that
we're working but we know that again the
Agriculture and the consumer preferences
are changing so there's more
opportunities for ekan in the
country we're doing it also by enhancing
the distribution providing uh effective
technology stewardship again to protect
that technology um and increasing uh the
value for farmers and and consumers
while reducing the environmental impact
of the Agricultural production in
general um Bangladesh is has such an
intense intensive agricultural system so
if you think exp as an example but many
other vegetable crops are having the
same challenges and it that means the
same amount of insecticides or more and
other pesticides that are um going not
only into the fruit and vegetables and
other crops but also to the water the
soil insecticide that are broad spectrum
that are eliminating beneficial uh
insects while the B can be so uh as
specific and allow for the uh beneficial
insects to survive support the rest of
the of the
ecosystem so this is done through a very
uh diverse group of people in my team
and it it is beautiful to have diversity
in terms of perspective knowledge
expertise um age groups so people that
are willing to go to the field and talk
to the farmers or talk can reach to
women um working in agriculture uh
people that can reach to policy makers
so that can have the potential to you
know translate the the basic science to
uh policy makers and to the public um so
we work very closely with all of these
uh group of amazing scientists to make
this possible and this is an
International Community um supporting
the national scientist in in Bangladesh
and this is part of the group of
scientists that we um employed in
Bangladesh in in the IR office that are
reaching out through extension agents
that are reaching out to like the SE
producers that are working with the
scientists uh to make sure that the
technology is Flowing on time to the
right plac is at the right
time so here you can see a little bit of
the um how the adoption has occur and so
I want to point out here so you can see
a an increase uh significant increase of
adoption of eggplant um depending of the
different sources of seed this is what
we used to determine how many people are
are growing
btpl and so you can see here for example
a big dip in 2021 2022 so that was not
this adoption that was access to se the
problem so we know that tell us that we
needed to be more proactive of making
sure that the seed was getting to the
farmers at the right time because the
intensification of agriculture in
Bangladesh only allows you a very uh
small period of time to get these uh
seat to the ground and if you don't
catch it at the right time the weather
may not be conducive or the farmer
thinking you know what I'm not going to
get the yield that I I was expecting
from this crop because it needed to be
planted three weeks ago so if I don't
plant it right now I'm not planting it
so we see that the was seat was not
available that year through
communication it just it just it didn't
happen and as soon as we start uh
putting more seed out there we saw a lot
more Farmers also growing um uh
btan and I way this is taken into
account not the seat that was produced
but the seat was distributed and we take
into account what was returned so these
are actual numbers of seed that was
distributed uh to Farmers and to
dealers um so what do we have right now
so we have these four varieties so we
have three different streams four
varieties that were released in
2014 that's the first um kind of block
that you see here these four varieties
now we have two additional new products
that are in the pipeline and this is
what is called btb gun 10 and 11 and
they are right now being um back Frost
um through again that collaboration with
Maho um and we'll talk a little bit more
about that and then our third uh
pipeline of products is this hybrid
products that are also under
development so I want to take a moment
to kind of explain a little bit about
the interactions between all of the
different organizations so in Bangladesh
these are all of the uh organizations
that are actively involved in the
project so you have body that is the
agricultural Research Institute we have
badc that is that seed arm then we have
what is called Dae that is Al the uh
extension arm and all of them have a
particular uh responsibility in the
value chain some of them are producing
like the nucleus seed or breeder seed
Foundation seed then they do quality
assessment they then do the production
of seed for packaging and to get it to
Growers um and then through the dealer
networks that exist in the country and
then we have the distribution and sell
that happen from that dealer through uh
extension agents through Farmers coming
to the dealers or for um through
informal systems too um and now we're
adding this layer of um another layer of
access to the technology that is through
using nurseries so this was something
that we started developing because we
realized that farmers are also going to
the nurseries like we do here at the in
the spring you start looking at for
those ceilings so you can save some time
in Bangladesh is is really important
because if you have these rains and you
have planted and the rains come in you
may lose your fi but by having seedlings
you're adding some flexibility to your
planting and you can recover in case of
you lost that seed that you planted
early you can buy seedlings and then
being able to to plant them right away
so you're winning you know you're
gaining all of those three or four weeks
instead of having to deal with damping
off in the field so now you can have
your seedling and you have a much better
stand so we look at different ways for
um uh increasing the
accessibility um so there a lot of
farmer uh demonstration plots that
continue to happen because there are
more and more Farmers interested and
we're also learning that there's a lot
of farmers that are still not aware of
that
technology so this is how the seat
packages look um in in the in the corner
you can see we uh we include how the the
field needs to be planted in in
for
btpl to protect the technology what we
do is that we have BT Ean planted as
traditionally in the field and then you
put a border of uh non-bt Ean to protect
um that technology by allowing the
insect to reproduce in those uh nonb so
you're not putting a lot of selection
pressure uh on the pest at this time
because we only occupy about 10% of the
potential uh
eim hectors and in uh acreages in um in
Bangladesh we're not concerned about the
lack of Refuge what we call Refuge that
is that non-bt uh but we know that
adoption increases this will be more
important so we're making sure the
farmers are used to plant it however we
know that the reality is quite different
in the fields farmers are thinking about
every single inch of that Fields like
why would I plant it to something that
it I will lose if I cannot spray it or
you know then we said well you you
cannot just spray it to eliminate
because the goal is that you have that
the the pest going into that and um what
we suggested to them was if you're not
going to plant this isoline that is BT
think about it all the other varieties
that you like to grow of BT of eggplant
that because we only have four varieties
and you said oh you know in your house
you want to plant the pink one too or
the L purple plant it in the corners so
instead of making it plant an isoline
like plant any other eggplant that you
would like to consume and then just put
it there and then you can Harvest that
one for consumption in addition to
protect the technology so that has
worked well but we have seen in every
single country if in even in the US like
farmers are not planting those Refuge as
expected for like uh BT corn and that's
how we ended with um resistant in the
past uh
population um so this is what I was
telling you about these uh nurseries
that we start incorporating so we have
about now like 400 uh nurseries that are
um producing seedlings of eggplant and
this is going really well because the
farm may have a new option we also uh
started um having nurseries that are led
by women so this is empowering women
through Nursery Enterprise model so in
addition to get learning about the E and
xpl they get the chance to learn about
Finance bookkeeping marketing um and it
has been
extremely um rewarding to see how these
women are starting to work together and
so they create their own network they
are they have Facebook pages marketing
their products they're on the side of
road you see the signs and everything
because they're learning about um how to
Market uh Ean and the idea was that
through the value chain what are the
entry points for women and for youth in
Nursery is what a good way to for them
to participate of the benefits of that
technology so here you can see in some
in the pictures some of the women that
are uh working together in having those
nurseries so what we do we provideed
some basic infrastructure and knowledge
and then uh the idea is that from the
initial um season where they sell they
save and continue to buy then SE uh seed
in for the future or improving their
infrastructure and they have done
that um bar is also involved in the
compliance um of testing that the seene
is
um has the protein in that uh the
technology continues to be effective in
the field so they have to monitor the
technology in the field and this is
technology that can be used for other
purposes so they have learned how to use
Eliza and now it's just a a technology
that they use used in the lab every
single day uh so it goes beyond uh
capacity building for the technology
adoption but capacity building in the
biotechnology unit at Bari um and so
they are responsible as the owners of
that technology for all the um
compliance so doing they do the field
compliance and they also do um the what
is called irm so they have to make not
only make sure that the seed has uh the
protein at the right level uh that con
contains uh the BT Gene but also that
the pathogen is not evolving to have
resistant to BT so they collect the
insect and bring it to the lab they feed
in uh the BT and wait for the insect to
die and to determine if there any any
resistant buildup and at this point we
haven't observed anything um that
suggests that there is a buildup of the
uh resistant in the uh past population
again we have a lot of Refuge of non-bt
uh in the field but we are we know that
it's not if if it is when so again
having that capacity in country is
essential for the
future so now we have these other two
varieties that are coming to to Market
in 2026 is what we hope and the idea
again they have two completely different
Market classes so we can add to the
market classes that we can serve but
they have higher yield and one of the
challenges that the previous varieties
have is it can only be planted in the
winter because in the summer season that
is the large uh season for eggplant they
are susceptible to wilt so this is the
difference when you have a director that
of the project that is an entomologist
but versus having a director that is a
PL pathologist so as soon as I realize
I'm like how we didn't do that so now
we're working on bringing Wilt resistant
and uh working with Adam in uh in our
unit we're trying to understand better
the population of the pathogen in the of
the whe pathogen uh on the ground but
because it's a solenia problem so we not
only we will be relevant for for Ean but
for also other solonas so um we hope
that we can bring some level of
tolerance so there is uh already some
evidence of Tolerance of um the wilt in
the body uh breeding programs but we
know we don't have immunity so I'll talk
a little bit more time on what we're
doing in terms of looking at immunity
but the idea is first understand the
pathogen population so we can then
inform our breeding a strategies for the
future and then do we have a proper
protocols in um body so they can test
for this tolerance to uh bacteria
wit um and in addition to the public
sector engagement that we have been
talking about with the private sector
now we're also looking at private to
private sector so the challenges of prod
producing seed the public sector is not
set up to produce seed for a much larger
um population of farmers growing BT
plant uh it's inefficient it's timec
consuming and so the the body can
continue to produce the the breeder seed
and the foundation seat but then um what
we hope is that private sector that is
better set up with the network to reach
out more farmers and produce seene can
come in into into the picture and also
with this uh idea of there is a market
for hybrids so they can serve that
market the open pollinated um varieties
can continue to be produced um and then
the hybrids can fit into a completely
different
market so this is the information that
we have at the moment that about 40% of
the Egan acreage is been grown to
hybrids you know local hybrids developed
by uh National and international
companies that are coming to Bangladesh
so that is a 40% of a market that we
could enter and reduce the use of
pesticide because they already growing
hybrids so what if these hybrids contain
the
BT so through again collaboration
between Cornell sath Guru and the
private sector we have identified
potential partners that can work
together um so they their partners that
have shown interest on entering the
market they're ready to make investment
so there's Indian companies that are
interested to working with Bangladeshi
company to have licensing agreements but
but there is also Bangladeshi company
that say I want my own hybrids with BT
can I work of getting a um just my
hybrids being converted instead of you
sending some of your hybrids that are
here so they're having this conversation
and our job is to Simply provide the
opportunity for them to meet to make
sure that the the the agreement will be
mutually uh beneficial for Bangladesh's
and in the private sector and that the
government is involved in this
conversation so there's no surprises
because here's a huge investment from
the private sector if they don't have a
market why would they invest so how do
we reduce the risk but by having
conversations with the government when
we make sure that there's an environment
that will be uh positive for seeing an
investment in the private sector into it
and they can have the conversation early
on before the Investments are happening
but also that the companies can directly
talk to the government so they can show
that there is an interest so the
government see like oh there is a true
interest from local companies to enter
the market we can hear that the farmers
are interest CM hybrid so those
conversations take a lot of time and
effort so if we can help having those
conversations and bringing like the
facts of the science you know we can
provide an opportunity to uh make sure
that the companies in Bangladesh have
the infrastructure that they need you
know how do we select these companies
that can actually handle having GMOs or
developing their own GMOs they need a l
of of consultancy in terms of their
research the infrastructure they need so
we can provide that kind of knowledge to
them
and again the idea is to bring all these
other types of uh diversity of eggplants
that are popular in the market and so
there are some that are already have
been selected by the companies as the
ones that can fit very well in the
market in Bangladesh so you can see this
station the different sizes different
shape uh to fit in that market one thing
that we learned is that they really want
this shiny coat on the fruit because if
it's matte may look like it's old so
anything that you may have the best
resistance and the best yield and if
it's mad versus shiny it will not go
anywhere uh so again having these
conversations and this is where our you
know so our social scientists and
engaging with the farmer is so essential
so we understand what the protu needs to
look
like so we hope that these uh hybrids um
that already the conversations have
happened between the companies the
licensing agreements that happened could
be available as soon as 2026 and 2027
for testing these variety these hybrids
carry a different uh event a different
Gene because of they have a different
Gene that is not that cry1c that we've
been using they have to go through a
whole process of deregulation while our
varieties that bt1 and 11 that are
coming because they're using the same
gene they can just be uh approv with
agronomic tests so again this will take
more time and we will see if it's um the
government of Bangladesh will be ready
for going through the process so we
again we are having conversations with
them to make sure that there is a policy
environment that would allow for this
investment to be uh
successful um so we have learned a lot
of lessons um but one of the ones that I
wanted to point out in the interest of
time I'm going to focus a little bit
more on is the idea of again we have to
bring weth resistance so I use WT
resistance as an example so because when
you think about technology we're really
focused a lot of times on that
technology that science that but
remember we don't eat technology we eat
a product so if something I have learned
during this process and this is what I'm
so focused on working in this space of
of Science of making sure that the
science reached the farmer field is
because you need to understand what that
product needs to look like what does the
consumer is asking for so you know and
so to me the science Begins the moment
that you publish that paper no that that
that's not the end that's the beginning
it's like now how do I make sure that
that becomes a product and that
conversation needs to happen really
early on how is this science going to
make it to the field what does that
product needs to look at who I have to
have in my team that will support that
we bring that perspective so that I make
sure that that science is successful in
Farmers field and that's something that
we have learned for me it could be in
this case the pathology so we need to
make sure that we bring that those
additional traits in into the picture so
that because right now we are only
producing the BTF and in the winter
season but if we can bring it to the
summer season we have a much larger
impact in our varieties will be much
more adopted by the farmers in the
regions that have Wilt and that's is a
huge area of the area of of production
same thing we need to make sure that
again we have in place that knowledge in
the um biotech Unit A Bari and with
extension agents so they can speak about
that technology and also they are ready
ready for the challenges of the future
for example continue to do this instagr
system management to make sure that the
Refuge is planted around the border so
all of that needed to be um introduced
but it needs to be contined talked about
and developed because uh science move on
into the next uh best job so we need to
constantly be educating the scientists
the policy makers and and the public um
in all of this we also realize that the
body breeding program for sustainability
purpose need to be strengthened so one
thing is to say okay let's produce two
uh more varieties and then when we look
at the entire pipeline they may not be
varieties that can compete well in the
system today because now there's a lot
more private sector investment there's a
lot better varieties out there our body
variey is going to be competitive if
we're talking about hybrids where does
the market is for that open poll intive
variety so all of these conversations
need to happen and um strengthen the the
breeding programs um for the the
technology to be successful in the long
run um we need to pay more attention to
extension
um what else and you know I think the
nursery uh investment have been really
opening an eye of different ways to
looking at the how the technology can be
adopted and what we thought thought
originally was the only way that we see
now we realized that we were missing a
whole new area again has grown
significantly over the last few years so
we see that there's a lot of more
opportunities for btpl to grow like I
mentioned only about 10% of the acreage
of Ean is grown to BT but every time we
talk to Farmers and we introduce them to
that technology and tell them uh what
the technology can do for them they all
want to grow it but the big question I
get is what is not in my preferred
variety is nothing about concerned about
BT is not concerned about what what you
know they they see the results they see
that it works they see that reduction
and insecticide use a lot of them tell
us that they will not eat eggplant
because they know how much insecticide
they use they don't tell me the same
thing about BT um so we have heard so
much we have learned so much during the
process so we know that there's a lot
more opportunities for BT technology but
again BT is it's like I said like it's
that's 0 1982 technology we need to
think about what is going to replace BT
what are the other proteins that we
haven't look at what are the other other
chemicals uh um natural chemicals like
turpins that uh terpenoids that could be
useful to prevent um uh insecticide
insecticide use that we reduce it but
also that will lead to less insecticide
um BT for example resistant in the field
you know in the pathogen the pest uh
getting resistant to
it um so this is some of the other
opportunities we started working with uh
Greg Martin a couple couple years ago on
looking at ptr1 so now we're so excited
that ptr1 can provide resistance to um
to wilt um and so it's like what is the
opportunity here so we started uh
evaluating these uh technology as a
potential use in initially we say oh
maybe the gene is there we can just
tweak it it can be something edited and
maybe easy to introduce that was not the
case but we needed to ask that question
and then uh what we realized is that um
eggplant has
uh all the elements necessaries for ptr1
to to work um but um let me just go back
here um so it has all the elements the
components needed for ptr1 response so
now it's like can we do this can we
introduce ptr1 as a second Gene so it
will be a dual uh purpose uh um
transgenic that not only provide
resistant to um the eggplant fruit and
Sho B but that can provide immunity for
um Wilt but that required that Adam came
into the picture that's how Adam came in
the PA because we need to understand the
population of the of the pathogen and
the effectors to understand if ptr1 was
going to be effective and everything is
sing up that yes so again we have
technology that is here at Cornell and a
bti that we could use and continue this
next like generation of products so like
this we have so many technologies that
can be so useful in developing countries
for the benefit of the people and this
is like the role that I see for uh
Cornell and other Advanced research uh
universities and Institute is the work
that we do has a place in the world and
it can do really really good things um
so what we hope is that over the next uh
years we can continue to bring
technology like this uh to the field
because it's where it belongs it doesn't
belong just in a journal so thank you
for um listening today and with that
I'll take any
questions right that was very
interesting story than you so let's take
some questions here and and online as
well yes can you say a little bit more
about the resistance um to BT and
mechanism of that and that sort of thing
okay but you put me in the spot and I
feel again like I'm a grad student uh so
I'm not
as a non-
entomologist I can tell you that U the
resistant to BT is a recessive um it's
recessive and so what it means is that
for the resistant to uh to evolve it
will take time but if the pest can
continue to reproduce in non BT we are
not putting that selection pressure on
it so the idea is to delay the process
of selection by not putting pressure on
the p so by having this Refuge the
insect can continue to reproduce and
continue to be a minimum in a heteros
cyos if it develops so it doesn't go to
homus because we encounters more
nonresistant individuals in the field so
that's what we're hoping for no and so
it's similar to when we uh release I
will bring it to PL pathology host
resistance so the idea is that you you
stack your resistant genes so that you
put less selection pressure you're
putting selection pressure against
multiple pathways so the idea by putting
two or more uh BT genes we are going to
reduce again the chance of if that
mutation to become
um uh um to be fixed in the populations
to maintain a minimal of heterocyc
hopefully we don't get there uh but then
you have multiple BT genes to uh estack
and so that's the goal that we will
release Stacks or at least varieties
that have different U BT genes to reduce
the selection pressure in in One
Direction do that helps yeah okay
survive
okay
mentioned that there was
lower due to issues with accessing seeds
I was wondering if you could expand upon
the barriers to accessing seeds and how
you guys increased that
access thank you for that question so
the question is about how we reduce you
know in in 2021 there was a reduction of
um let's say adoption but it was really
because accessibility to see so what and
and so the question is what are we doing
uh to to support like the SE production
and get back into where we needed to to
be producing so a lot have to do with
communication so some of the dealers
were saying oh we are not getting a pull
from the market so we decided that with
our limited resources we needed to focus
on other crops and stop producing btx
plant and so we had the conversation
with do you go to the particular
District where this BT is needed but is
because if you look at the entire
country it may be that you don't see the
pool that is necessary because it has
not been introduced across the entire
country it has been selected a
particular District that have the market
class and that also didn't have the
wealth or that can grow it in the winter
so we were you know that communication
wasn't happening there so when they had
to select where to put their resources
for good reasons they went into a
different um crops and now do we have a
much better understanding of what the
farmers need in which locations and we
communicate that early on in the season
so at the end of our season say okay
these were the farmers that were growing
BT ekland this year and so these are the
districts so we need seed for these many
farmers in this area so I got a lot of
having that communication thank
you I have a question I was curious uh
is the the cry one uh Jean carried in
the pollen and and really the follow up
on that is are are some of these Refuge
plants are the seeds from them
containing the uh that event that so it
is cont U so the the question is about
uh if the K1 seen is um is present in
the pollen and if the Refuge that is
around the field will have then we can
um incorporate that Gene into it so
there is a chance that that c1c will go
into that neighboring egpl um I cannot
remember exactly what is the distance
but it's not a long distance where the
pollen is moving and we and we have
checked for that there's studies being
done on that um Farmers uh that grow the
the eggplant in the
borders if they were to save seed again
this would be just a one copy of that
and that particular event um and so we
are very much concerned with that
movement of that polling when we talk
about herbicide resist no and that's
what we being very aware in this case
that if the gene were to move the only
thing we will do will make a resistant
to the the P so Des by not something
that we wanted to happen because they
have that that the the the idea is that
these um varieties of eggplant continue
to be as indigenous as have they always
been the worst cases scaros that will be
resistant to the pest and will survive
better remember is not fully
over no it's like 10% exactly yes it is
it has like a 10% cross pollination yeah
yeah it's like yeah between 10 and 20%
thank you for that Ronnie that was a
really important
point trying to let me stop share so
it's easier for me to see it there we
go oh Greg is here um
what step do you recommend for a
scientist that just discover a new
controller strategy to deploy it as fast
as possible um so that's a great
question thank thanks Michael for that
question so to me it is important that
we understand uh how is this technology
useful and communicate that early on not
only to um you know your your colleagues
collaborators make sure that you have a
pretty uh diverse group of people in in
your network so that you can move that
technology you know work with your
breeders work with your pathologist work
your entomologist with a agronomist make
sure that you understand the system
where you want to deliver this
technology um Talk early on I know that
a lot of times we tend to be a little
bit secretive because we're thinking
that oh somebody can scoop me but if you
don't talk about it you may not you may
be missing an opportunity for
utilization of this technology this is
what is important that we communic early
on but we also need to get a a group of
sponsors for our research that
understand where science fits in the
field and communicate it's our job to
communicate that to them to policy
makers to donors to sponsors about where
do we see this going and it's not like
it's going to happen tomorrow it may be
10 20 years down the pipeline but if we
have a clear understanding of where the
science can go and can communicate that
effectively I think we can go a lot
farther than we have gone before because
a lot of times it starts with you know
um it's not really an AA moment it's
like hm that's funny moment no in the
lab something that doesn't fit so the
moment that something doesn't f you
think you have something really good and
start thinking what are the implications
of this how can it be used um and to me
like a lot of times we don't tend to
think that big picture we get so focused
especially in in grad school we're so
focused on that particular example that
pathway that Gene and that we forget
that it belongs in a much larger
environment I was talking to uh people
that specialize in photosynthesis on MSU
this this week and they were talking
about what is that technologies that
you're thinking about I'm like you guys
work on photosynthesis you're not
working on robiso we're still working on
robiso you know it is the protein that
has been studied so much and we still do
not understand it of all the benefit and
how we can make it more efficient Etc so
like that we have so many systems that
we do not understand because we haven't
asked the big picture how does it fit
with the rest so I think we just need to
do more of that that's a perfect note to
end on with thank you again
you this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu