this is a production of Cornell
University thank you Jason for the intro
um indeed I'm the adviser of uh of
Judith who if you've seen her talk works
on um
meteorology um so to say the environment
that the plants are exposed to this is
also my background I'm actually trained
as a hydrologist work a lot across
disciplines with meteorology but like I
always say we have a special fness for
plants and uh this is sort of how I
ended up working on
photosynthesis uh in a very cool
environment or very hot environment I
should say uh Yellowstone National Park
um so I'll just tell you briefly how as
a hydrologist I ended up studying
photosynthesis um and this all uh came
through lyans and lyans is a very
interesting species right they
symbiosis uh between fungus and an alga
or a cyano bacteria and what is really
cool about lyans is that they can dry
out completely and then as soon as you
hydrate them they they restart
photosynth photosynthesis almost
instantly so um I was actually doing
this uh sabatical a couple of years ago
with a hydrology group and then there
was a group that uh invited me and said
hey would you like to come and have a
look at our work on lyans because they
have this very cool behavior in relation
to water so I ended up studying uh the
water transport in lyans with them and
another thing we did is that we started
looking at oxygen Evolution from
photosynthesis um sort of playing around
and then what we find out found out is
when we uh ex um expose the Lykan to
light then dark then light then dark we
saw this oxygen Evolution uh accelerate
with subsequent light exposures so we
thought you know what what could be
happening there is that of course the um
the alga produces oxygen which is
beneficial for the fungus but then the
fungus respires produces CO2 that is
then beneficial for photosynthesis by
the alga uh so we were able to prove
that that actually was part of the
symbiosis in addition to the known
symbiosis of water exchange and su Sugar
exchange between the fungus and the and
the alga uh so that is and not so
surprising either right because this is
a confocal micro micr croscopy image
that I took while at rgar University
that was hosting me for this for This
research uh and you can see they're
right in each other's space right so it
makes sense that they're exposed to each
other's gas uh emissions so to speak um
so this led us to to be uh yeah to
become curious about this the role of
CO2 uh in photosynthesis because the
group I was visiting Charles dis mucus
Lab at uh at rgar University they had
mostly focused on the light reactions
around photo system too if you're
familiar with photosynthesis so this is
where water is oxidized is split into
oxygen and and hydrogen protons um but
then we said so you know now that we saw
this effect of CO2 on photosynthesis it
is sort of known right that with higher
CO2 there is this fertilization effect
where the gross primary production is
increasing we also know from Green
houses that I'm sure you're much more
familiar with than me is that when they
enrich in CO2 up to about a th000 PPM
this really benefits growth right it
improves the the fruit
quality um and then uh yeah this is
explained by the fact that uh higher CO2
levels uh enhance the saturation level
of the rubisco enzyme that plays an
important role right in carbox so the
CO2 uptake and then conversion to sugars
uh and then but there's also a couple of
other interactions that are not so well
understood so it's not straightforward
as in you know more CO2 more more
primary production um and then just a
bit of background of of of why CO2 is so
important for photosynthesis right so
here is this this is a chloroplast and
then here is rubisco this enzyme that
fixes
CO2 um and then uh yeah through the
celvin cycle so a series of reactions it
fixes CO2 um converts it to a couple of
com intermediate compounds eventually uh
goes out as sugars and then there is
this R rulos bis phosphate that needs to
be Regen generated in order to take up
the next CO2 but now what Risco this
enzyme also does it can react with
oxygen the oxygenation reaction and that
is actually not beneficial for the plant
it costs energy it produces CO2 rather
than fixing CO2 it produces compounds
that the plant needs to get rid of so so
what you want is more carboxilate and
less oxygenation so you can imagine that
by increasing the CO2 level it is just
more likely to pick up a CO2 rather than
oxygen right so that's a bit of the
background and then uh the other thing
that I'll be coming back to is that in
this series of reactions the the Kelvin
cycle needs ATP and
nadph um to to run the celvin cycle in
in these reactions and these are
produced by What's called the light uh
reactions in the thid membrane so they
capture the light energy that can be
used to produce these ATP and nadph so
they're very connected and that'll be
important as as we'll see later
um all right so then so that there's a
benefit right of having higher CO2
levels but on the other hand very high
CO2 can also lead to acidification of
the cell
environment um because CO2 it's a tiny
molecule right so it can easily permeate
through
membranes um it hydrolyzes and then it
forms acids the leis acids that are just
the hydrolyzed CO2 and then the bronet
acid so they actually release prot into
the environment and then what that does
is that it reduces pH gradients and
these pH gradients across the membrane
are needed to produce
ATP so you can imagine that when the
cell environment becomes very acidic it
becomes harder and harder to build up a
gradient across the membrane because
there's already so much acid in the
environment so that makes it much harder
to to produce ATP so there a very high
CO2 level can actually become harmful
plus it can carate proteins so it can
cause further damage so we were
wondering so if we have elevated CO2 how
does photosynthesis adapt right how does
it make sure to benefit take the maximum
benefit from higher CO2 versus yeah
avoid this acidification uh effects and
we wanted to look at extreme CO2
environments most of the research has
been done on sort of mild CO2
enrichments up to the Thousand PPM level
um but we wanted to see what we go
beyond right where is is there somewhere
a threshold where it flipped from being
beneficial to being very harmful so this
is how we started looking for an
environment where we could find this out
in the field because you can imagine
that doing this I mean in the growth
chamber is that very representative for
the real reality doing it in the fields
this is being done they're called the
face experiments faac but they to they
find out it's it's hard right to I mean
you blow extra CO2 into the field but to
get that well distributed and everything
so we want wanted to look for a place
where this is just happening uh
naturally and then uh yeah a sort of a
natural laboratory where this happens
naturally is Yellowstone National Park
you're probably familiar with it right
it's a it's a volcanic area with a lot
of geothermal sources there's geysers
there's hot pots there's uh and and a
lot and some several of those are
emitting very high levels of uh gas
C2 and have been doing so for many
centuries based on the geological uh re
research history that is likely and
based on records from the USGS we know
that at least uh for the last say since
the 1980s or so they have records or
they have recorded these CO2 levels so
we have a very pretty good idea of of
also the history of CO2 emissions uh
around these geothermal
sources um so we went in 2019 and we
went to scope out sites across the
Yellowstone National Park that had be
reported by USGS as having very high CO2
emissions
uh and very high we're talking up to
about 6,000 PPN or even Beyond in some
places um but of course we wanted to
study photosynthesis so we also need
places where we find plants right where
we find life or lyans we also look for
lyans but we didn't find those it's too
harsh an environment for for the lyans
apparently they don't like an acid
environment so but we did find
vegetation around some of these sources
as you can see uh so so that was
successful in in in that sense that we
could really find a couple couple of uh
geothermal sites or CO2 emission sites I
should say with ve vegetation close by
but then um yeah we found these two
sites to be the most uh yeah stable in
CO2 emission extreme CO2 emission this
6,000 PPM elevation more or less um and
then also vegetation growing very close
to the sources so we could be pretty
sure that they are really exposed to
that very high CO2 level
uh they're both um um yeah calcium
deposits calcium carbonate deposits and
that is what uh causes these very high
CO2 levels as the as the gases move
through the soil you can imagine that
that takes up all the CO2 and then emits
it into the atmosphere now the other
thing we needed is sample species that
would grow very close to those sources
but also in a controlled environment as
in you know ambient CO2 400 PPM more or
less so that we could compare between
the two um so for in inance this is
panic grass that you see on the photo
I'll point it here for the for the zoom
uh attendance so Panic grass is is
famous for growing close to these uh
sources in Yellowstone it has adapted to
that environment and it only grows there
so for us that was the first species we
we thought of targeting but it turned
out not to be useful because we had no
control we had no comparison to an
ambient um but then PR vulgaris which is
actually a very common plant that grows
in lots of environments including close
to the uh CO2 sources uh as well as in a
more ambient uh environment so 400 PPM
CO2 so this is a species we could really
compare U between the high and the
ambient CO2
environments another attribute of prella
that was very useful for our work is
that it uh doesn't like to close its
tomata in the in the sense that you know
even when we harvested uh samples from
the field uh took them to the lab for
experim exp their stomata would still be
open uh and this is important if we want
to study gas exchange obviously so had
they closed their stomata there would be
another no-o but so prella was very
helpful in that regard that we could
really study photosynthesis effects even
when we had taken them from the field
into the
lab um so then we so we wanted to study
the effects of CO2 levels on
photosynthesis um so so this is
basically what we wanted the study right
close to this Risco enzyme that fixes
CO2 but to measure this uh directly it's
kind of hard I mean you can measure gas
exchange but then there's a lot of well
first of all it's an indirect
measurement because you measure Co a net
CO2 uptake but where the CO2 goes and
how fast it reaches rubis you don't
really know uh plus it takes a lot of
time and we wanted to look at dark to
light induction of photosynthesis which
is a dynamic that we needed to more high
resolution time resolution measurements
so instead we use a method that's called
chlorophyll variable
foressence um and this is fluoresence
that's emitted from from photosystem to
so from the light reactions that produce
ATP and adph for the celvin cycle as you
can see here sort of in a simplified
scheme of photosynthesis so the way this
works is that uh photo photos system two
um absorbs the light energy and then um
it gets excited and then uh charge
separation happens and the electron can
be transferred to its primary electron
acceptor QA called QA and then from QA
once it's reduced it can then again
transfer the electron to PQ a
plastoquinone that then is converted
into plastic quinol and then from there
on in a series of reactions eventually
nadph nadp plus is reduced to NPH and by
pumping protons across the thid membrane
at the same time we produce a proton
gradient that is used to produce ATP so
that's the connection but now once this
has happen so photosystem 2 has gotten
excited it has transferred its electron
there's only one
acceptor so at that point we say PS2 is
closed it cannot take another electron
right because it's closed it I mean
there the carrier already has one now if
the um the pigment gets excited the it
the energy cannot be transferred through
the electron it gets emitted as
fluorescence so that means that as long
as photochemistry can be done the
electron can be transferred we have no
fluoresence but if it's as soon as the
system is closed we get fluoresence so
we have sort of a probe of the
photosynthesis activity by by measuring
fluoresence and there's also a little
bit of energy that can be released as
heat um but uh yeah I'll go into that
later we have a measurement technique
that that really we can tease out the
variable portion of fluoresence and that
is not so sensitive to the portion that
goes into into heat but that that is an
issue when interpreting this kind of of
observations so that's what we're going
to do we're going to monitor fluoresence
emission from photosystem 2 as a probe
for what is happening in these chain of
reactions that eventually produces the
compounds that run the celvin cycle and
thereby we can say something about
whether or not CO2 is being uh r Bo
taken up to form
tubers um all right so then uh another
thing I need to say in case you people
are uh familiar with the fluoresence
method the that the method that's called
Pam fluorometry I don't know if you're
familiar with this this has been used a
lot in photosynthesis research this
technique is slightly different in that
it uses it's called Fast repetition rate
barometry it uses Ultra short
high-intensity light pulses
um to excite the chlorophyll pigment
photosystem 2 and then measure as you
can see on on the bottom so it measures
the chlorophyll florescence that rises
as you as you you know shoot light on on
on the pigment um and then as the
photochemistry goes down because the
system gets closed right this QA uh gets
reduced we see the the rise in
fluoresence then we flash at a flash
rate of 100 Hertz so we have this Ultra
short pulse we measure of resence we
wait about 10 milliseconds then right at
100 HZ flash rate frequency then we get
a little bit of reopening of the system
right some of the QA gets reoxidized in
that time frame so fluoresence goes down
again we flash again lence goes up but
the variable portion is much smaller now
right because the system is still
partially closed so we continue to flash
and we monitor variable fresen so this
is typically what this looks like for 50
flashes in a row
and this is the variable portion of
fluoresence normalized by the maximum of
the fluoresence at that par particular
flash moment so the the the maximum FM
right
here um and so what we see happening is
that as we continue to flesh it becomes
harder and harder to reoxidize between
flashes so in the end the variable
portion goes almost down to zero meaning
the system's completely closed right we
can't reopen it between flashes anymore
so QA got reduced the PQ pool if you re
uh remember got completely reduced the
system is stuck right at that point it
can't it can't do further
photochemistry um but then we continue
to flash so oh yeah and another thing I
should explain is we we see sort of the
oscillations here at the at the start of
the of the flash train so this is a dark
adapted sample and what these
oscillations represent is the oxygen
Evolution from the water oxidation
complex this happens in four steps and
that is why you see these um
oscillations so that's another
interesting feature of this technique
that you can actually measure that the
oxygen Evolution from photos system
too all right so now we do not one flash
train but we continue to flash in total
we flash 180 trains of 50 flashes each
so the first uh train looks like what I
just showed right so we have we started
with an open signal uh system dark
adapted we start to flash we close the
system and then we wait a half second
again the system partially reopens we
flash again we wait a half second flash
again so we see a series of trains we
see the system reopening closing
reopening closing so we're probing the
reduction of the system by by by
flashing uh by these light
flashes um and then what we hope to see
eventually is that the system will
reopen once the electrons are used to
produce energy adph and adph is going to
be used in the Calin cycle so it gets
reoxidized and that means it can receive
more electrons right So eventually you
should see this shift of the electrons
being moved into the celvin cycle and
then we can again reoxidize between
trains we expect the system to to rise
again all right so let's see if that
happens so this is the the the result
fluorescence variable fluoresence over
180 trains 9,000 flashes in total um so
the the the start of the of the very
first flash is this dark adapted varable
foressence value also called the the
maximum Quantum yeld of PS2 right that's
what people have who have used perometry
you're familiar with then we see the
system closing right it goes all the way
down like we saw but now it's just
squeezed um but then indeed we do see
the system reopening right we see sort
of the overall levels Rising a little
bit but then they fall so the system
starts to open but then closes again and
then eventually after yeah about a
minute we see an overall rise of the
fluorescence levels and this is then the
signal for us uh to to see to observe
the reopening of the system by the
downstream reactions in the Calvin
cycle so this portion in particular we
expect to be very sensitive to CO2 right
because that's the Risco enzyme
activity um yeah then the other thing is
we see this very wide sort of Comb width
right so this is the difference between
the start of the train so we have a half
you wait a half second between the flash
trains so we weop the system partially
and then we fill it again so this is
sort of a measure of how much electrons
come in and are taken out during the
flash
train um yeah so this is the
overall monitoring that we're going to
do with samples from Yellowstone in the
ambient environment as well as the
extreme CO2
environment all right um then yeah so
this sort of summarizes this uh what I
was just saying that what we are
monitoring with this right in particular
this the rise in variable resence which
is for us a signal uh of the of the
Calvin cycle
activity all right and then the
reduction the the comb width that shows
us uh the ratio sort of between the
light reactions that that push the
electrons in and the utilization in dark
reactions that use nadph and therefore
reopen the
system all right now let's see what
happens when we so this is still an
ambient sample right so it's just used
to 400 PPM CO2 but now we're exposing it
to 6,000
PPM as you know the samples we found in
in in Yellowstone so this sample clearly
responds and as we expected especially
this last phase associated with the
uptake of nadph or the utilization in
the Calvin cycle responds very strongly
right we see all the levels Rises Rising
so the system stays much more open the
electrons just flow through much faster
uh and also even between trains we don't
fully close the system anymore right
because the electrons can really be
pumped forward very fast so this is sort
of what we expected uh as a as a very
strong effect of CO2 we also see that
the initial levels uh are rising right
so even very early on electrons are
already being taken out of the system uh
and and can be used down
stream all right so fast strong
acceleration of uh of the uh of the
reactions in the electron transport
chain faster rise uh faster overall
levels all right now we're going to do
the same thing but we're going to look
at plants from Yellowstone National Park
that have grown in this extremely high
CO2 environment so they were always
exposed to 6,000 PPM now the first thing
we see when we just look at the plant
samples is that uh they're not doing
great in the high CO2
environment um that we see strong signs
of chlorosis uh we see the leaf sizes
that are uh small smaller yeah the
overall PR is looks very unhappy um and
now we're going to do the same
experiments looking at the fluorescent
signal from from these plants so first
we take the adapted plant I'm going to
call it adaptive PL so this that has
grown in 6,000 PPM CO2 and we're going
to give it just 400 PPM CO2 and see what
happens and basically what we see is
well sort of the start of the experiment
so we start out with a dark adapted
sample then we start filling reducing QA
we start filling the PQ pool gets
reduced that sort of looks the same
right the signals go down they come up a
little bit but then they close again but
in the this second phase that we
associate with the Calvin cycle
activity we basically see nothing
happening right the signal stays
down so it looks like it's not
activating the Calin cycle it's not able
to take the electrons out of the system
but the system stays closed uh all the
time all right now let's see what
happens if we give it 6,000 PPM CO2
right like what it's used used
to and boom we see more or less the same
response as in the ambient
sample so as soon as we give it plenty
of CO2 it can fully restore the Calin
cycle activity so the overall levels
reached are as you can see this more or
less the same and also we see this much
narrower comb width so also between the
trains right it can really very fast it
is able to reoxidize the system each
time um the only difference slight
difference that we see is that we see a
sort of a downgoing slope here towards
the end of the experiment expent so
there is some kind of Downstream
limitation here that starts to play a
role which we attribute to if you
remember the Kelvin cycle there we also
we not only need to fix CO2 but for that
we use ribulose B phosphate that needs
to be regenerated through the cycle in
order to take up the next CO2 molecule
so we think that is a limitation in that
Downstream step for regenerating rulos B
phosphate because you can accelerate the
carox reaction but you need the rest of
the cycle to follow right so that's what
could be going on
here
um all right now this is a slide that
summarizes the results so far I've been
showing results for for single samples
right so this the box plot summarize
data for uh the replicates so we have
three to six replicates for each of
these groups so we have an adapted group
uh and we have uh a control group
exposed to 400 PPM exposed to 6,000 PPM
just like I was
this the observation I was just showing
and I'm just going to summarize the
results so first when we look at um
phase one right so the start of the
experiment dark adapted sample we look
at what happens the maximum Quantum
yield of P of PS2 we basically see no
significant difference between the box
plots right so meaning that there's no
significant difference between control
and adapted plants CO2 doesn't have an
effect then when we look at the PQ pool
size so the next step right we reduce QA
and then we reduce the PQ pool uh same
thing right so this is where the signal
goes down in the first train that
difference is
also more or less the same no
significant difference between uh the
the
groups then um when we look at what
we've called uh phase two so we saw that
the signal going down again right so
there is an intermediate
Downstream uh bottleneck where what we
think is happening the full chain gets
reduced right so
nadph gets formed and waiting to be
utilized by the Calin cycle so there we
get a sort of intermediate stop or or
slowing down again we see that happening
more or less similarly for all the for
all the
groups no clear CO2 effect no clear
effect between the different sample
groups but then for phase three we
clearly see as we saw in this in if you
remember there was this very wide comb
WID and the levels weren't Rising right
so much lower celvin cycle activity um
for the adapted plant in ambient
CO2 uh but it's restored in in higher
CO2 um the same thing for this the comb
width right so the reoxidation between
the trains um yeah we also here we again
we see a clear effect for the adapted
plants compared to the to the control a
clear CO2 effect to start with um and a
somewhat different between the control
and the Adaptive
plant uh and then the other thing I
mentioned is this Downstream limitation
by rulos B phosphate um we also sort of
see that starting to appear mainly for
the adapted samples and mainly in
exposed to high
CO2 all right so now we see an an
adaptation effect right in associated
with the celvin cycle activity but how
can we explain it right how what exactly
can be behind this this
difference now for that we're going to
look at the yeah more the the the
various steps in the photosynthetic
electron transport chain so the way we
often think about it is sort of as a as
a linear uh response right so we have uh
more light more uh nadph ATP being
produced more CO2 uptake right sort of a
z electrons flow through linearly and
then are products are used by the Calin
Cy but when you do this then the ratio
of ATP over nadph that needs to be 3:2
is is not correct you don't get the
right ratio so we need to produce some
extra uh ATP in order to be able to run
the celvin
cycle so the sort of solution that is
invented uh By Nature to do this is
called cyclic electron flow so electrons
pass through the system um reach a
photos system from photo system 2 to
photos system one and then the electron
is not transferred to reduce nadp plus
to nadph but instead is cycled back
thereby pumping an extra proton that can
then be used to to produce more
ATP so that's that's so it's all about
tuning this the linear versus cyclic uh
reactions uh because if you would only
do cyclic mode obviously you're not
going to have enough
inph so that is that is the trick right
for the plant is to to make sure that
these two systems are tuned correctly
and what we think is going on or and
another thing I should say is that this
has been shown Al in the literature is
that when plants are dark adapted they
start out in cyclic electron flow
mode uh so they start out in this mode
it sort of makes sense that at the start
they the first thing they start to do is
to produce ATP because ATP can be used
for a lot of purposes right in the is
beneficial to do that but then as soon
as the system sort of send is I also
need nadph it then turns on the linear
electron flow right so you get a
transition uh until you get the right
ratio so how we interpret our data is
that because we we see this adapted
plant and we see it's not activating the
Kelvin cycle so it's very likely that it
is in cyclic mode but when it doesn't
get a lot of
CO2 it doesn't see sort of a reason
right to kick on a linear flow because
there is a very low Calin cycle activity
ity it stays in in cyclic mode and that
could explain why we don't see a rise in
fluoresence but then as soon as we give
it 6,000 PPM it does start celvin cycle
activity it starts needing nadph and
then we do see the rise in fluoresence
we see the system opening
up so um yeah to summarize that so what
we've seen for the CO2 adapted plants
prella plants in in Yellowstone when we
expose it to 400 PPM so much lower than
its growth environment we see that the
Calvin cycle basically stays
inactive um and we interpret this as in
this dark to light induction that we're
looking at the the system the electral
transport chain stays in cyclic electron
flow mode so there's very little linear
flow so there's very little nadph
available for the Calin cycle to do
carox and the advantage of that would be
for a plant that grows in a stressful
high CO2 but also highly acidifying
environment is that is always ready to
make a lot of ATP which it can use then
for uh repair and
homeostasis so that could could be an
explanation um but then when we give it
6,000 PPM the Kelvin cycle does get
active to the same level even as as the
control plant so this means that linear
electron flow must be activated now
right as soon as there is a lot of uh
CO2 and then we get the right ratio in
order to be able to run the Calvin cycle
uh now this is sort of confirmed by a
next set of experiments that we did so
we had our three minute experiment 180
trains but we repeated it sort of in a
light fluctuation experiment so we have
three minutes of uh light and then we
have four minutes uh this is just
practical because because we have to
change the system uh four minutes of
dark three minutes of light four minutes
of dark and then also we start out uh
this example I mean we did lots of
combinations but in this example we
start out with ambient exposure 400
PPM uh two sequences then we Elevate CO2
to 6,000 PPM and we do another two
sequences and now if you think if you
look at this with now having in mind
that we start out with cyclic flow so we
start out with a system that closes very
rapidly and then it opens up in the the
upper level is a control plant right so
it opens up meaning it transitions to
more linear electron flow so that it can
do uh celvin so that it can do carox and
this does not happen in the uh adapted
plant now if we wait for a minute in the
dark we sort of get part restoration of
this cyclic electron flow mode but when
you look at the control plant it's able
to start up cyc um Calvin cycle activity
very fast right we we see the minimum
remains much higher so meaning the
system is already active it's it's able
to stay much more open but this doesn't
happen in the in the control plant not
in Ambi which we didn't expect but even
when we give it a lot of
CO2 we see the control plant being able
to stay almost completely open right we
see it hardly going down so the system
doesn't get reduced it can reopen
straight away meaning that directly it
it establishes this balance right
between cyclic and linear electron
flow uh not so for the adapted plant
right if we dark if we give it a dark
exposure for minutes we see the levels
going down it closes again
from the start of the experiment and it
needs time it does open with 6,000 PPN
but it take takes much longer for it to
to activate and we do it again and we
see the same thing what we also see is
this this negative slope starts to
appear right as we continue to expose to
light this Downstream limitation starts
to become more
important um is what it looks like Bas
based on this data so this this sort of
fits the picture right with the two
experiments so then to summarize our
conclusions for the prella plant um yeah
I'll just show them here 400 PPM we saw
inact no activity on the Kelvin cycle uh
what we think is caused by the system
staying in cyclic electron flow mode
6,000 PPM we saw no evidence of effect
on the light reactions right on the PS2
light
reactions uh what we see is a transition
from linear to cyclic oh this should be
the other way around I'm very sorry from
cyclic to linear flow when we go from
dark to light uh is much
slower uh right this it close in between
and only then could it activate um but
then it becomes almost as active as the
more or less as active as the control
plant eventually which also tells us
that there is not really an adaptation
in functional robiso content because
this has been an explanation uh a
possible
explanation uh for adaptation to higher
CO2 you would adjust your robiso content
right because it's yeah it doesn't work
need work as hard and it has a lot more
CO2 available but because it restores to
the same level as the control we think
that is probably not uh what is
happening in our adapted samples here so
that's also interesting to keep in
mind all right that brings me to the end
of my talk I just like to thank a few
people first of all of course professor
Charles Charles mukes from rodar
University the Waxman Institute who
introduced me to
photosynthesis uh and with whom I've
been writing proposals uh to get us to
to Yellowstone for these very
interesting experiments which have been
supported by of course the National Park
Service Who provided the research permit
the Waxman Institute Who provided a seed
Grant to cover some of our travel costs
and the foru Federation in the
Netherlands Who provided some of the
instrumentation we have been using in
the field so with that I thank you for
listening
questions a
couple go ahead how widely um dispersed
is this elevated
CO2 around the high CO2 sources you mean
yeah um scale yeah meter scale meter
scale very very low it is it is yeah
yeah yeah as soon as you're say more
than 10 10 meters away in most cases the
levels are back to also because of the
air mixing you're back to ambient
CO2 yeah which is convenient because
we're sort of we're quite certain that
other than CO2 the plants are exposed to
the same environment same soils
everything else
yeah yeah um so I was wondering you know
sometimes we see that when plants are in
those conditions right they're exposed
to extremely high CO2 maybe not
necessarily adapted but if you were to
have a plant that was you know
synthetically just yeah in a plant that
has a very high CO2 environment there's
trios phosphate utilization limitation
that occurs and you know that could also
limit the rate of poesis like do you
hypothesize that is some Ru and what
you're seeing yeah good point yeah this
is another Downstream limitation that
could explain what we're seeing yeah
yeah yeah that's a good point especially
very high CO2 so we have a high
production of sugars um and if they're
not moving out of the system fast enough
then that also inhibits the reul
phosphate regeneration so yeah okay
yeah yeah um a colleague and I have been
sort of thinking about doing some work
at Yellowstone
also with high
CO2 uh one of the things that we've been
spending some time thinking about is
that these emissions are not just CO2
there are other gases that are in there
um that also can affect the soil
chemistry your adapted plant didn't look
very
healthy and I was wondering whether you
had any concerns about these other
stresses that the plant is under in
interpreting any of your resch yeah
that's a that's a that's a very good
point yeah I should have mentioned that
we selected these sites because they're
almost exclusively emitting CO2 and very
low in sulfuric gases other types of
gases also relatively low in water vapor
some of the sources emit 90% water vapor
and then a tiny bit of CO2 so they were
really selected the travor time deposits
so they really emit mostly CO2 as a gas
and very low in other gas compounds it
could be yeah confusing our signal yeah
did you do the monitoring of the
emissions or did part USGS yeah this is
the
USGS uh yeah we're taking from their
reports
okay
yeah did you uh studied any light
intensity based uh Cycles which could be
different in these two different
environment I here we always use the S
the same uh lights schemes for the
fluoresence measurements yeah so we
haven't played around that's another
thing we could do indeed just play
around with different light intensities
and see what
happens HR data is very clear there is
adapt there is sort of acclamation or
adaptation but I think your data I think
all the conclusions are dependent on the
fluorescence
data uh couple things first when you
compare chlorophos assins at 400 PPM
versus 6,000
DPM in the first case you have
photorespiration and the second in at
6,000 PPM photorespiration probably is
completely inhibited so the total
electron transport measured by
choses so represent you know you have
these two two sinks right mhm one is
carbon dioxide reduction the other is
oxygenation so how do you differentiate
those two that's the first question the
second question is you suggested that
rubisco the amount of rubisco didn't
change but you never measured this no we
did not yeah so I I really don't feel
comfortable with that conclusion because
without directly measuring Risco the
total amount
it I you know be very difficult to make
the conclusion that rco demount didn't
change because cor is the indirect
measur what you measuring is meing the
live reactions so not direct not a
direct measurement of robis Med dark
reactions no that's why that's exactly
why I put functional Risco to start with
because we didn't measure rubisco
content okay uh but functional rubisco
because
if the robiso the functional robiso
content would be very different they
would not the samples would not be
reaching the same variable foressence
levels uh that that we're seeing the end
of the experiments right that that there
would be differences when they're
exposed to the same amount of the same
levels of CO2 so that's why yeah we
pretty confident that this is the case
yeah yeah but there's a way to directly
measure the functional risal portion you
can measure the initial activity that
represents the amount of risk that is
active actively engaged in
photosynthesis and they can measure the
total amount of risk that's the total of
now so that's the ratio is called
activation percentage of activation you
could directly measure the initial
activity of Risco to support this
conclusion I think right that would be
much better yeah that would be very
interesting the thing is of course here
we are in in Yellowstone National Park
with very limited facilities so we build
up sort of an improvised lab to do the
these experiments but it's not easy to
do every kind of measurement that would
be ideal you know to confirm all the
conclusions but we do plan to do is to
go back uh with an instrument that can
also measure uh the oxidation state of
p700 so photosystem one and also to
measure the proton gradients which you
can all all do with Optical measurements
so they're yeah relatively feasible for
for this environment so that would at
least um we yeah with that we could
corroborate some of these conclusions
because I agree it's only one method I
fully agree but yeah so we we hope to
fill some of the holes with these
additional measurements in the
field yeah I'm going talk to you later
more detail about this I kind of agree
it' be really great if we could like
sort of reject the hypothesis that
involved um yeah and understanding the
field limitations there of course um I
have a very naive question about what
the you're measuring with the
floressence is it riscal activity or is
it essentially like I you DP reduction
is that the Regeneration phase that's
being
measured what we measure is is a net uh
rate of uptake of electrons so yes so
it's when the NAD Etc is being so it's
that's in like when it's going from like
3pga to g3p right so it's measuring the
rate of RP regeneration essentially
which is consistent with when you're
seeing like that down shift that's
limiting I just out of my head whether
that is
appr proxy for Risco activity or not but
this could be a yeah maybe yeah maybe
the terminology you're right maybe yeah
correct my terminology if I'm wrong but
what what we really measure is the
utilization of n or the reoxidation of
nadph by the Calin cycle because we see
strong CO2 effect sort of confirms that
it has to do with but I shouldn't call
it Rob Risco activity because that is
not more be measure you're right I mean
the correct term is reoxidation of the
electron transport chain
yeah um how much of the inability of the
adapted plants to use to efficiently use
the ambient levels of CO2 do you think
is related to the chlorosis and the
general like uh lack of health of the
plants that it would just be harder in
general for it to
photosynthesize uh it depends because if
it's in its high CO2 environment it's
always exposed to 6,000 PPM it would be
able to do photosynthesis right so then
that would not be causing the the
chlorosis that we
see um if on the other hand the CO2
levels are
fluctuating because of air
mixing then that would definitely be
part of of the of the stresses right
because then it would be exposed
sometimes to this very nice and high
level but then it goes down it goes up
it goes down so then that would be part
of the
explanation
now I have two questions one is on that
part right there so so um when you when
you take the Adaptive plants and they're
at the lower PPM that's where you see
the cyclop kick in right and you're
generating too much ATP relative to nadp
where does that ATP go if it doesn't
go where does it get shunted if it
doesn't get used uh yeah well this is
something I think a lot of you people
know more about than me but ATP is used
for a lot of processes in uh in living
cells as an energy carrier so how it
gets shuttled out I'm not sure yeah so
because I was thinking maybe that's part
of the the toxicity right if it's
getting shunted into something that is
is hurting the plant then the ATP itself
you mean yeah but did some thing but
then the other thing I wanted to ask you
is about so you have this swath of um
the plant that's getting the high dosage
and then the adjacent sloth is the
control so if you if you take the high
adapt and you I doubt you've done this
but maybe and you put it in a 400 PPM
and just keep it forever does it ever
acclimate back to 400 yeah that's a very
interesting question yeah yeah for that
I mean so it would be hard to do in the
field I I mean we would be need to be
sure to be able to come back every year
and it has a very short season because
we're at more than 2,000 feet 2,000
6,000 feet altitude um but this is
something we're thinking about if we can
bring the plants out of the we it is
included in our permit now that we can
bring plants back from the Fiel and then
we could see if in the greenhouse or in
growth Chambers we expose them to 400
PPM and whether they react that would be
very interesting right to see if it's
elastic yeah and then also just to move
the 400 the 600 until you see a decline
right the the first part of the
hypothesis was that CO2 can be
detrimental at high right and so then to
like model that breakdown basically yeah
yeah that's something we need to find
funding for though because that's going
to be an extended set of experiments but
yeah yeah I'm thinking back about the
plants again are are there plants that
are growing in this high CO2 environment
that that actually look healthy because
because the ones that you did show they
look pretty ragged and uh I'm trying to
imagine the leaves that you would look
at to do these experiments did did they
have did they have healthy leaves any
these plants there are lots smaller but
they yeah some of the leaves do I mean
this in kind of measurement we do we
need a small only a small portion of
to be healthy to do our measurements
okay so because the one I don't think
okay yeah no no that was a pretty crappy
example you're right
yeah just before we go back to the crowd
we have one quick one here yeah you
might want to just say it out loud yeah
there's a question from the zoom
audience did you notice any differences
in stomato conductance at different CO2
concentrations so this is sort of the
nice thing about prella is that it
didn't respond um very strongly in terms
of stomat conductance so so we took
stomat conductance measurements in the
field uh and we brought samples to the
lab we measured in the lab and we didn't
see strong differences I mean stom
conductors there's a lot of variability
to start with right when you me measure
it in the field but that degree of
variability and range didn't change for
samples uh control or adapted and even
when we brought them to the lab the
conductance um got smaller but the stata
did stay open and also to a similar uh
degree more or less right within the
variability range that is inherent
through the
measurements you sort of mentioned this
before but I just want to ask again how
far apart were the exposed plants and
the controlled plants Auto magnet to 10
meters excuse me 10 meters more or less
so that is uh 10 12 yards or yeah 30
feet 30t that's about
30t you think
that's do you think your control plants
are really control plants I mean wind is
blowing this stuff every which direction
okay so if they're only 30 ft apart my
guess is that at some point your control
plants were being exposed to elevated
CO2
also it's rather the other way around I
think because it's a it's a point source
of of of very high CO2 yes uh so plants
growing very close to that point source
do get the 6,000 PPM
where the stuff came up out of where the
within
within a
foot okay they grow directly at the edge
of the of the source yeah and the soil
is not hot so these are not hot sources
they're really CO2 sources okay
yeah yeah is there like so 6,000 is that
the extreme that was identified that's
like consist like consistently around
6,000 around these out sources
this is the level that we measured out
in the field at at about 6,000 PPM okay
there's been some sites where they found
up to 10,000 in the G USGS reports but
those sites had no growth no vegetative
growth around them so right I yeah I was
just wondering like if you were to
measure with I'm not sure if this is
like by your design or not but if you
measured in sites that had low were like
2,000 to 3000 PPM right so like some of
the gas exchange systems can ramp up CO2
like about 3,000 right I mean if it's
like you compromise some of the you know
the extremity I guess of the CO2 level
but at the same time You' be able to
actually like get that CO2 assimilation
and get the direct parameters like you
think that'd be something you'd be
interested in doing in the future well
this is actually what we intended to do
when we went we thought about measuring
along a transact with a over a range of
CO2 concentrations but this turned out
to be hard for exactly for that reason
it's very hard to get something of a
stable CO2 concentration trans transient
in the field with all the other uh
variations so we stuck to very high very
close to the source and then ambient far
away from Enough From the Source that we
had a stable ambient what we did do I
can show you that data in the
lab uh we because Panella is a common
plant right so you can actually just
order it and grow it in the lab and then
we did uh here we did the the range of
CO2 experiments where we we start out
with an ambient signal uh and then here
we expose it to just zero CO2 so you see
this last phase basically you system
staying closed and then we had a couple
of intermediate levels so 1600 3,000 and
6,000
PPM uh so these are lab grown samples
now so there we we yeah we able to
control a lot more things these are so
they're grown in ambient CO2 and we
looked at the CO2
effect just to get an idea of of yeah
what what it looks like what the inter
intermediate levels uh look like okay so
s connected to um question about like
elasticity but um when you saw the
difference between the control and the
adapted samples do you have an idea of
like how much was like how much of the
difference you thought was like due to
like actual like evolutionary adaptation
and how much was due to the like
acclamation of just being raised in this
environment yeah that's a good question
it would be great if we could do all the
genetic analysis but we uh we haven't
done that uh we didn't bring samples
from the field in the the times we we
went uh but so the reacclimation
experiment would be one to do to see if
yeah we can confirm acclamation versus
adaptation probably easier even than the
genetics because I don't know how well
the Gen Genome of prella is known but
that might be very hard Trace back but
this is something that would be very
cool to do to confirm which of the
two let's do one more and then well and
then I also want to say there's the
student lunch in man 413 just on the
hall so St you had your hand up couple
times there let's do that and then close
it out did you notice like Chang of
changes in theill as you approach the
CO2 source as compared to you know more
of the control population you speak up a
little bit I just I just couldn't hear
changes in the density of the pill as
you approach the CO2 short as compared
to the control the density you're
saying
uh that's kind of hard to say there's so
few plants growing very close to these
sources um we're going back this summer
so I I'll keep an eye out and
see if that is something we can get a
good observation of nice
idea all right so let's uh do one more
round of
applause this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu