this is a production of Cornell
University so we we're really fortunate
uh Kyle and I and our students are
fortunate to have a chance to um get a
second look at the floral behavior of we
stingy 2 and 1/ half years ago we had a
chance to study around o clock for 2 and
1/2 days its production of the stinky
volatiles Vis its name and for which
it's justly known so uh during that time
there was a a Blog on Cornell site and
people from all over the world rode in
and asked what are those strings what
are those wires what are you people
doing to our flower and and I we
responded that we were actually
collecting data from it so we thought
we'd take a few um minutes to talk about
what T me all right so when when we
stinky starts when the Spade begins to
open and The Show Goes On we're going to
have a fishing line dangling from the
gers above the plant uh to support this
little battery Opera vacuum pump here's
a 9V battery operated um pump that'll
allow us to collect volatiles from the
flow what's really interesting about
this is that usually we enclose a flower
they're always always smaller than this
in what we call a headspace bag an oven
bag say that you big turkey and that
doesn't have volatiles of its own we let
the volatiles accum accumulate and then
we collect them over a little trap like
a cigarette filter but much smaller and
so uh what we have here is the is the
battery pump that we're going to put a
little filter on and and then hang it
suspend it into the floral chamber where
a lot of the volatiles are be produced
and we're going to take snapshots every
2 hours of how the odors change as the
plant as as the as the infloresence
we're doing this in two different ways
this one is cumulative okay the B the
pump is just going run it's going to
collect volatiles over time this little
syringe here we call it a solid phase
micro extraction fiber or speing it has
a little piece of of essentially fishing
line that also gets exposed in the
chamber of the infloresence and absorbs
the volatiles onto it then we can use
chemical analysis to um to strip those
volatiles off and separate them into
their component Peaks and we'll be
posting those data on the on the Corel
site for everybody to
see then what we're going to do as we're
taking these chemical measurements we're
also going to be taking measurements of
temperature of carbon
dioxide so we've noticed from previous
research and also um two years ago was
last that um there are rhythmic um
thermal blasts and we also want to
measure um possible carbon dioxide um
blast so what we have here is a a
digital temperature go and what we'll be
doing
is sticking it into the tissue at
various um Heights of the spadex um to
test the temperature over time we also
have syringes that will be taking air
samples from inside the J um to
calculate the CO2
concentration um and we have our CO2
analyzer behind us and we'll be
injecting samples into that test that
concentration right and so what reason
for being that we know from the thermal
imagery that these things really heat up
just as they're producing um the the
largest release of volatiles but the the
insects that are attracted to these
flowers um experience all of that at
once the heat inside the chamber the
carbon di side is the planet respiring
like a sprinter um and these uh very
strong information Rich volatiles that
that flies and and beetles that are
attracted to this plant um have a lot of
meaning because um they are simul
the the the cues that needed from a
rotting corpse so we'll be doing that
around the clock as the flower opens and
as people come in and trying to
surreptitiously sneak into the corner
and collect our data and we'll be
posting these data as we as we collect
them this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu