this is a production of Cornell
University good afternoon everyone as
Jenny said my name is Megan Williams and
today I will be discussing our work on
investigating the nitrogen management
and alphalpha variety performance in a
dual use kza alphalpha in our cic system
so let's start out by breaking this
title down into its components to help
us better understand the why and the how
of this study starting with perennial
crops and their
benefits first some stats the
agricultural sector accounts for more
than onethird of all Global greenhouse
gas emissions with around 11% of those
emissions coming from synthetic nitri
fertilizers including its manufacturing
Transportation application and po post
application soil emissions which make
synthetic edine fertilizer account for
around 2% of global annual greenhouse
gas emissions synthetic nitrogen
fertilizers are the main source of
nitrogen in conventional Agriculture and
wheat is one of its top users as one of
the top three crops in the world
covering around one and a half% of the
earth land area perennial grains have
been identified as a potential
sustainable alternative to annual grains
like meat due to their wide ranging
benefits which include soil health
benefits from increased below ground
biomass inputs improved water
infiltration and access carbon
sequestration and lower overall carbon
emissions with their year-to-year
longevity allowing for reduced tillage
and for few tractor passes for
planting here we can see a side by-side
comparison of the root profiles of
annual wheat here on the right and the
perennial grain crop known as
intermediate wheat grass here on the
left these deep roots are what are
largely responsible for the improvements
to soil
Health next let's dive deeper into
intermediate weat grass as a perennial
grain crop also known as perza just a
disclaim kza is technically just the uh
trade name for a specific cultivar of
The Grandin product of intermediate
wheat grass but because cenza is a lot
easier to say than intermediate we grass
and because we did use that specific
cultivar in our work I'll should be
saying cenza for the rest of the
presentation so while initially
cultivated in the US as a forage crop
intermediate weak grass was selected for
development as a perennial grain species
over other peral grasses towards traits
that include High grain yield and size
as well as grain qualities like
nutrition and taste the intermediate
weak grass cultivar known as Minnesota
Clear Water became the first perennial
grain commercially available under the
trade name kza kza grain has been used
to make a wide range of products
including beer flour pasta cereal and
more and I personally can endorse the
fact it's very tasty um however despite
Kenza being selected for development as
a pral grain there are still reasons why
Kenza is not yet a household name
despite successful breeding efforts to
increase its grain size current of grain
is still about onethird the size of
commercial annual wheat has been
estimated that it'll take another 24
breeding Cycles to get KS of grain size
up to par with wheat additionally Kerns
of graani Neals consistently do decline
over time in this graph from latell at
all we see two different populations of
intermediate weed grass both
significantly declining in Grain yield
from year one to year two this grain
yield decline makes Farmers less likely
to want to maintain a Cen stand for
multiple years thus negating some of the
perennial benefits so beyond breeding
for grain yield maintenance over time
research is being carried out to
understand how agronomic management
practices can affect current of grain
yields over time while still maintaining
the sustainability benefits of its
perality findings in the 2018 paper by
Tois at all suggest that intercropping
cenza with the legum forage crop does
have the potential to better maintain
currenza grain yields over time time
when compared to fertilized monoculture
alone so next we're going to talk about
how intercropping sits in our
sustainable perennial
framework intercropping is the practice
of having two or more species of crops
in one field at the same time Studies
have shown that intercropping has a host
of benefits compared to Conventional
monoculture including yield increases
which can lead to a higher land use
efficiency where the same yields can be
produced on less land as well as higher
yield stability over time we can see
these Trends here in this figure from
Lee at all where they intercrop maze
with other grain crops including wheat
fabine soine chickpea and oil seed
across multiple sites and nitrogen rates
they found that grain yields were
consistently higher in inner crop and in
monoculture and that average grain yield
increased over time when compared to
monoculture inner species interactions
lead to effects like lead suppression
increases in nitrogen and carbon in the
top soil beneficial in refuge and
disease and pest suppression all of
these effects and more come together to
create the increases in yield land use
efficiency and stability documented in
intercrops now that we understand the
benefits of perennials kza and
intercropping in general let's look at
why we specifically chose alala to
intercop with our K Alfalfa is a leum
and legum symbiotically associate with
nitrogen fixing resal bacteria in the
soil and by trading carbon resources for
the nitrogen fix by these Rovia they
live in the nodules formed on the lum's
roots like you can see in the picture
here on the right and this nitrogen not
only benefits the legum crop and reduces
their need for synthetic Nitro
fertilization but also can contribute
nitrogen to the soils to be taken up by
other plants in the interring system
nitrogen transfer to soils and crops is
accomplished through root and nodule
tissue decomposition root exitation or
even directly from the legume to nearby
crops through plant Associated micro
mediated
transfer research has shown that legumes
in inner crop with non-legumes do have
the capacity to transfer as much
nitrogen for area as monoculture legumes
and if enough nitrogen can be
transferred from legumes to the other
crop and inner crop to still support
profitable Crop Production then less
synthetic nitrog fertilizer can be
applied overall to the inner crop
reducing both fertilizer cost and
Associated
emissions alala was selected for
intercropping with kza in the system
because it is a widely used profitable
and perennial forage crop Studies have
found that alpha alpha nitrogen
transferred to grasses like krenza
increases overtime with production year
indicating that its use in a perennial
inter croing system can not only confer
previously mentioned intercropping
benefits but also more nitrogen to the
system as each year
passes as alala is widely used there are
many varieties that have been sprad for
specific performance metrics one metric
is fall Dy rating which rates alala fall
regrowth on scale of 1 to 11 with one
having the least fall regrowth and 11
having the greatest fall regrowth fall
dorcy is Loosely correlated with winter
hardiness and fall dorcy ratings between
three and five are well suited for
northern states that experience soil
freezing and so we used ratings of three
to five in our Al varieties selected for
this experiment and here in this picture
we can see some alala and some Kenza in
our Crow together here at New York
so even if intercrop and kza with the
legum is able to help slow grain yield
Decline and reduce n fertilizer costs
Curr of grain still simply is not yet as
high yielding and thus not as profitable
when compared to annual wheat so farmers
interested in growing corenza may need
to tailor their management techniques to
man to maximize profit utilizing a dual
use system is one potential method a
dual use cropping system is one with the
intended purpose of both harvesting
grain and utilizing vegetative growth as
Forge for livestock economic analyses of
dual use systems have shown that can
both improve the profitability of a
cropping system and reduce business risk
additionally dual use systems can
provide a bridge and feed quality and
quantity gaps for livestock at different
times of the season analyses of cenza
systems have specifically shown that the
financial risk of KR of grain production
can be reduced by managing the system
for high forage yield thus providing the
farmer income not only from grain but
from its forage as well further
intercropping Al ala with Kenza would
then not only benefit farmer bottom
lines by increasing yields per area and
reducing notion fertilizer costs but
then also presents the opportunity for
multiple sources of income through the
Dual use cropping system that being said
though ideal current and management
strategies to maximiz profits are still
largely dependent on current grin prices
at Market which are still shifting as
the current of Market
develops so to summarize what we've
learned so far to help reduce
agriculturally Associated greenhouse gas
emissions we can utilize perennials over
annuals and Leverage The Yield benefits
from intercropping to help reduce
emissions and pollution Associated
nitrogen fertilizer production in use we
can utilize legumes and in crop to
provide biologically fixed nitrogen to
the system to help reduce grain yeld
decline in kernza intercropping bling
should be investigated and to help
kernza grain f makeup for small CS of
grand yelds compared to wheat they can
manage their system for dual
use now that we see the why of the
system we can finally get into the how
of our experimental objectives designs
and analyses in my first chapter we
investigated whether in our croping
Kenza without Alpa can reduce the need
for synthetic nitrogen fertilization
while maintaining or improving grain and
forage yields and quality compared to
monoculture we also St to understand how
yields changed over time in this inner
cropping system and different levels of
nitrogen fertilizer as well as how all
of these parameters varied based on
planting locations across the United
States and my second chapter we wanted
to understand how alop variety affects
the performance of this INR system and
compared alop varieties with three
different F
ratings so in order to understand the
effect of environment on the current Z
out the system we replicated this
experiment at four locations across the
United States here at Cornell University
of Wisconsin Madison University of
Minnesota and at the land Institute in
Sal Kansas we had four replicates at
each location and 23 treatments in each
breath treatments included two cropping
schemes in our crops and monoculture our
monoculture plots were seeded at about
11.2 kilograms per hectare and our crop
plots were seated at 5.6 kilos per
hectare of each species in what was
known as a replacement in cropping
design which is where rows are replaced
with the second crop rather than the
second crop being planted in between
rows as we can see here Kansas itself
did have a slightly different planting
scheme due to planting equipment
limitations but those differences were
accounted for in the
analysis data collection included Curr
of grain yield Cur of Forge biomass and
off Apple forage biomass we also
collected weed biomass but did not
include it in the following
analyses we harvested both grain and
forage biomass in a quadrant basis by
hand and here we can see a hand
harvested plot from last summer in New
York we completed summer harvests of
grain and forage once grain reached
maturity and another harvest in the fall
before first Frost in year two locations
of available labor also harvested
biomass before currents of stem
elongation in the spring but spring
Harvest data was not included in the
following analyses after the spring
Harvest plots were mowed and Ura was
applied here we can see a picture of
alala biomass being harvested from a
quadrat in the fall the canas location
did did not have sufficient regrowth for
any fall harvests so we don't have their
data for that and we also don't have any
year 2 data for Minnesota as they had to
replant their experiment in the next
year due to rodent issues um each
replicate had both monoculture and
intercrop plots fertilized at one of
five different nitrogen rates increasing
in increments of 40 kilograms per
hectare from 0 to 160 kilg of nitrogen
FR we used three different alala
varieties Hest 360 with a fall Dy rating
of three Shockwave VR with a fall Dy
rating of four and WL 365 HQ with a fall
dcy rating of five only shock wave was
planted at all five nitrogen rates
because we didn't want to have hundreds
of plots at each location um so Hest and
WL were only planted at zero and 80
kilograms of I per hectare so we have
one big experimental design for both
chapters but use different subsets of
the data for analysis each chapter
of analysis after the Grain and biomass
was harvested Forge biomass was ground
and analyzed using Neo infrared
spectroscopy in our modeling of Forge
quality we use both crud protein values
and relative feed values because they
both indicate the nutritive quality and
usability in livestock the relative feed
value is calculated using parameters
from that NE infrared spectroscopy to
help understand the performance of
forage once fed to livestock we analyze
the forage quality of each species
separately so we also calculated a total
crude protein and total relative feed
value for inner crop plots by adjusting
the forage quality values based on the
proportion of biomass yield made up by
each species and despite breeding
efforts kza still has some threshability
problems meaning that the grain does not
always easily separate in its outer Hall
thus skewing some of the masses that we
got from our grain yield here we can see
some curs of grain still in its Hall and
here is some dehaul um so weuse a
digital imaging and analysis software to
estimate the proportion of dehal grade
in a given subsample which we then used
form adjustments on the total grain
yield for clock we were unable to
complete this Imaging yet for year two
so we used year one adjustments in order
to calculate the year two DEH hold grain
yields so please keep in mind that
technically the year two grain yield
results are preliminary moving
forward Forge harvests from each
quadrant were converted to a kilogram
per hectare yield and then both
mass-based yields and land inclement
ratios were modeled for biomass Harvest
more on land inclement ratios in the
next
slide linear mixed effects regression
models were created for each individual
Harvest because we did expect to see
large differences between both fall and
summer Harvest and year one and year two
results were log transformed to me
assumptions and post talk analyses
included analysis of variant and pawise
comparisons the factors that we included
in the nitrogen rate study were of
course nitrogen environment and cropping
system and factors included in the
variety study where genotype environment
and croing system so as mentioned lent
ratio our intercropping was in a
replacement design meaning that there's
half the seaing rate of each crop in in
crop compared to monoculture to be able
to compare the performance between
monoculture and in crops we can use the
land of clant ratio to visually explain
this if here in yellow we have a
monoculture of Kenza and here in green
we have a monoculture of alala covering
the same area and here we see our alala
cenza inner crab over the same area with
half the total area taken up by each
species we for example may expect to see
six kilos from a hectare of Kenza that
is not an accurate number but easy
numbers for the example um and we may
expect to see four kilos from a hectare
of alphalpha so with half of the seaing
rate in our inner crop we'd expect to
see half those yields in inner crop but
due to the
facilitative effects of intercropping
that lead to overyielding as discussed
earlier we often actually see greater
yields in a given land area like in this
example if we saw three kilos from Alpa
and four kilos from cran using these
expected and actual yields we can
calculate the partial land equivalent
ratio for each species and then sum them
to find the land equivalent ratio so
this example the partial L for corenza
would be the yield in in crop compared
to the yield in mon culture and if we
see a value greater than 0.5 for the
prod L we then see an over yielding
effect in that species the same
calculation can be done for alala
comparing intercrop to monoculture and
if we see a value greater than 0.5 we
see over yielding and we can add these
values together to figure out our land
flent ratio for an entire in our crop
plot and comparing expected or
overyielding to expected and if we see a
value greater than one we see over
yielding in the hole in our prop
plot so with that we can finally get
into some results for the niten rate
study um we'll start with brain yield so
for both years we saw significant
interactions between environment which
is eating the table and nitrogen rate
which is n in the table as well as
environment and cropping system which is
C in the table Our Stars indicate
significant levels from our anovas and
at a P value of 0.5 with more stars
indicating a greater degree of
significance
here we can see M mean grain value mean
grain yield values in kilograms per
hectare at each nitrogen rate at each
site with lines fitted from our linear
mixed effects regressions lines in red
are from year one data and lines in blue
are from your two data with dotted lines
being monoculture krenza and solid lines
being intercop data as we can see in the
graphs NE gen rate only had a
significant effect on Gran yield in New
York in year one and at Wisconsin in
year two for the sites that did not have
a significant difference in Grain yield
between nitrogen rates this indicates
that applying nitrogen does not
meaningfully increase grain yields in
either proing system so a farmer could
reduce or eliminate nitrogen application
while still maintaining great
yields with the environment by cropping
system interaction the effect of
cropping system did vary by sight but we
only see a significant difference in gr
yields between cropping systems in New
York and gear
one no signicant difference in Grain
yields between cropping systems shows
that despite half the seating rate of
corenza in in crop intercrop grain
yields were still comparable to
monoculture grain yields overall the
effects of environment that we do see
here and will see across many of our
response variables may come from a lot
of sources including variability and
temperature precipitation soil nutrient
loads soil types and wheat pressure just
to name a few for example here at New
York we had weed pressure in the form of
white clover which encroached on
monocultural curs of plots as the Clover
filled in the vacant leg Niche this
could have affected the nitrogen load in
the soil although we did still see an
effect of nitr rate in these plots in
New York another factor that may have
affected brain yields was lodging we did
observe lodging at high nutrtion rates
in both intercrop and monoculture and as
we can see here in this picture of
monoculture corenza at 160 kilg hect a
lodging may not only decrease grain
yield but also make the grain Harvest a
lot harder for Farmers through planting
to combine to PL grain
grain our grain partial land infl ratio
results support these claims about the
effect of croing system and nitrogen
rate on grain yield we did not see
significant effect of nitrogen rate on
grain fure l in either year indicating
that any overyielding effects are
independent of nitrogen
application these graphs show the
response of grain fure ler to nitrogen
rate in both years at all Sites the dash
red line is at 0.5 above which indicates
a yield advantage in INR
year one and year two grain partial ler
results showed that grain yields had a
yield advantage in the crop compared to
monoculture across rates and locations
except at New York in year one Kansas in
year two and at 160 kilograms of n per
hectare in year one if competence
intervals are taken into account we do
see some outliers at Kansas which may
have skewed the year one data in favor
of a gr yield advantage in in crop um
but as year 2 gr yields preliminary we
do hesitate to make any strong claims
about the effect of nitrogen rate or
Copic system on grain yields over time
we generally do observe that year two
grain partial L values were higher
across locations and nitrogen rates in
year two than year one which can
indicate that intercropping may help
amarate grain yelds declining over
time next we can look at the forage side
of this dual use system there was a
three-way nitrogen rate environment
proin system interaction in year One
Summer year one fall in year two summer
as well as a significant effect of
environment as well as a nitrogen rate
by cobic System interaction in year two
fall which highlights that total forage
yield reaction to cropping system and
nitrogen rate is very sight specific
which does make sense as for yields can
be highly dependent on site specific and
annually variable factors like
precipitation temperature and nutrient
availability now would also be a good
time to recognize that the alphalpha
stands were not managed in a typical
carb pattern usually alphalpha stands
are harvested multiple times over a
summer growing season which maximizes
forage yields and quality but because
our currs of forage cannot be harvested
in the summer to avoid disrupting brain
development Alfalfa also cannot be
harvested in inner crop so we also
didn't Harvest monoculture alphaalpha
until green yield time as well in this
picture you can see our senior research
associate Julie Hansen holding up some
of this late summer monoculture Al Alpa
you can see it's very stemy it's lost l
of it leaves and therefore it's going to
have a pretty low forage quality um but
because we're most most interested in
comparing inner crop plots to
monoculture parenza just to see how the
prev presence of alphaalpha benefits
overall yield and quality we still
included monoculture alphalpha as a
benchmark that being said here we have
some graphs of our total forage biomass
yields by nitrogen rate cing system and
location we now have three lines
comparing inner crop to monoculture
Kenza and monoculture alala with a
different color and representing
different harvests across the two years
we only saw a significant response of
nitr rate in monoculture perza where
there was a positive correlation between
nitrogen rate and total forage yield
which is expected for a grass that
cannot fix its
own we also saw in New York in year one
in their fall Harvest there was an
inverse relationship between nitrogen
rate and total forage yield in in crop
plots because we do not see a
significant positive response to
nitrogen in intercop plots this inter
this indic Ates that intercropping Kenza
with Al alfha provides the opportunity
to reduce or eliminate nutrtion
fertilizer application and costs will
still maintaining High total forage
yields when compared to monoculture
current Zone additionally we found that
intercrop total forage yield was
significantly higher in monoculture
corenza across Nation rates in the fall
Harvest of both years we did not see
this effect in summer Harvest but some
locations did have higher summer total
forage yields at lower rates than
monoculture corenza a higher total
forage yield in intercrop during fall
harvests but not summer harvests shows
that a system like this may be best for
grain Farmers looking to get higher
yields and qualities from their fall
forages but that still recognize that
their inner crop summer forage yields
may not necessarily be higher than Kenzo
monoculture across cropping systems we
generally saw a decrease between years
one and two summer Harvest total forage
as expected however intercrop total
forage yield was higher High than
monoculture Curr a total Forge yield
from your to Summer Harvest indicating
that the farmers could benefit from a
greater total Forge yield over time with
the inner crop then monoculture
kzone we saw the most dramatic changes
in total board yield over time in Kansas
across all cropping systems in year one
we did observe a much higher total mon
precipitation at Kansas in the late
spring compared to year two so our
hypothesis is that this precipitation
may have increased soil water
availability during either critical grow
growth periods or just throughout the
entire growing season which could Boler
forage yields and actually make the year
one for a yields more of the outlier
than year
two we can look at our ler results again
to understand whether intercropping
convered a total forage yield Advantage
compared to
biculture we only see a significant
response to n rate in year two summer
where there was an inverse relationship
between nitrogen and ler indicating that
Forge yield advantage in an ACR is more
likely at lower nitrogen rates in other
words a higher nitrogen fertilizer
application in monoculture is more
likely to match any yield Advantage
conferred by intercropping than a low
nitrogen rate overall ler results
consistently showed an advantage for
intercropping across nitrogen rates
except at 120 to 160 kilograms of
nitrogen per hectare the year One Summer
and 160 kilograms a year
two we saw the L values were higher in
year two than in year one for both
summer and fall harvest in Wisconsin for
summer harvest in New York and at low
ntion rates in Kansas a greater yield
advantage in in crop in year two is
likely tied with the fact that root and
nodule DEC composition is the main
mechanism for nitrogen transfer from
legumes and these tissues just have had
more time to turn over by gear
two so while Forge biomass yields are
important forage quality is extremely
important when feeding forage to
livestock and therefore can a large
impact on
profitability we saw a significant
three-way interaction in year One Summer
and varying interactions between the
factors for other harvests while our
Nova results tell us that nitrogen rate
had a significant effect on total fruit
protein we in fact see that there was no
significant difference in total cruit
protein between nitrogen rates within a
given cropping system and location
monoculture alphalpha total cre protein
was significantly higher than
monoculture Kenza which is expected When
comparing a leum to a
grass total forage crud protein values
in inner crop plots were higher than
monoculture corenza regardless of
nitrogen rate this indicates that inter
croing corenza with the legum does in
fact confer a forage forage quality
benefit however the inverse relationship
between total CW protein and nitrogen
rate in New York more Harvest that we
can see here was contrary to
expectations that providing more
nitrogen to the system would reduce
nitrogen scarcity in their or increased
total gr protein one hypothesis is that
this may have been due to higher
nitrogen availability leading to a
greater nitrogen allocation to the grain
rather than the forage but as we don't
have grain quality data this hypothesis
cannot yet be tested overall both the
general lack of effect of nitrogen on
the total cruit protein as well as that
decrease in total cruit protein with
increaseing nitrogen indicates that
farmers in croing currents and alphalpha
could again save money while maintaining
forage quality by decreasing their
synthetic nit
applications we also observed that fall
Harvest had higher improv protein than
summer Harvest which was expected with a
shorter regrowth period between summer
and fall Harvest compared to Spring
Harvest and summer Harvest while not
statistically compared we also generally
saw that year 2 crude protein values
were equal to or greater than year one
values which is expected again with
transferring more nitrogen over time as
tissues
decompose all right so for total
relative feed value we only saw a
three-way interaction in year two summer
but nitrogen rate only had a significant
effect on total RFB in in crop plots in
Kansas in year two summer where total
RFB decreased with increasing ntion rate
here we do that additionally at New York
and Wisconsin in year two summer there
was no significant differences in total
RFB across cring systems and nitrogen
rates this with the fact that we did not
see a significant effect of nitrogen
during other harvests indicates that
there is no total RFB advantage to
applying nitrogen to intercropped Cur
alal systems while we saw significant
cropping system effects across harvests
intercrop total RFB was generally
greater than or equal to RFB in
monoculture crza acrost locations and
harvests both Total CP and total RFB
were generally higher in Fall Harvest
and summer Harvest across locations prop
systems and N rates though we did not
yet analyze spring Harvest we would
expect to find similar things with
spring quality higher than summer
quality this higher quality forage in
these marginal Seasons could be more
valuable to Farmers by helping Bridge
any existing heat quality gaps after the
main forage growing
season so to recap our results from the
nitrogen rate study we did not see a
significant effect of nitrogen on grain
total forage yields or total forage
quality in intercop intercropping
significantly increased fall total
forage yields and intercropping
increased forage quality when compared
to monoculture corenza and while not yet
modeled we generally observe that grain
yields did decline over time but
preliminary results indicate that
intercropping may decrease the rate of
grain yield decline over time these
results indicate that a dual use
intercropped Curr alpha alpha system may
be a viable route for maintaining Curr
of grain production for more profitable
Farm uh more profitable systems for
Farmers when compared to monoculture
Kenza by reducing n input needs and at
those lower nuring rates increasing
grain and forage yield over time over a
given area increasing forage quality and
potentially maintaining higher grain
yields Over time however to truly
identify the best system further work
must be done to understand the cost and
benefits of the Curr cenza alphalpha
system based on the cost of nitrogen and
the value of the Grain and forage yields
over time based on the markets most
readily available to
Farmers hopefully you're still with me
we have just a few more slides of
results for the alphalpha variety study
which are luckily pretty
straightforward um so first of all even
though we only fertilized all three of
the varieties at two nitrogen rates we
found that there was no significant
interaction between nitrogen rate and
variety for any of the response
variables so we removed nitrogen as a
factor in all models there were also no
significant genotype by Crossing system
genotype by environment or three-way
interactions for any of our response
variables which indicates that no one
variety is better suited to a single
environment than another nor are any
varieties better suited to inter crop
with than another we did see significant
environment by cropping system
interactions indicating that
intercropping success does vary with
environment which is what we also saw in
the last chapter so we'll start with our
forage and grain yield results I promise
this slide is not as scary as it looks
um we did not include currents and
monoculture yields in total forage
quality or models because there is no
level of variety of alphalpha from cza
monoculture so for cza yields we only
looked at variety performance in in crop
that being said we did see an effect of
variety on alala forage yields and total
forage yields in year one for both
alphaalpha yield and total forage yield
the variety shock wve V led to
significantly higher summer yield than
WL 365 HQ and significantly higher fall
yield than in highest this indicates
that out of three varieties Shockwave v
may be the most profitable choice for
for yelds at least in year one its
performance may have been correlated
with the B dorcy rating but it also may
have had additional attributes not
Quantified in the study that may have
led to higher total forage yields while
there's no significant differences in
alphalpha or total forage yield in year
two additional data in year three May
better eluate the trend in total foral
changes over
time with the environment by crop
actions intercrop total forage yields
were higher than monoculture across
sites and harvests we did not see any
effect of genotype on currents of forage
or grain yields which indicates that no
one variety increases currenty yields in
in crop more than
another we did not see a significant
effect of genotype on total ler across
Harvest indicating that no one variety
leads to a greater forage over yielding
effect in a crop compared to the other
variety
while no variety was statistically
greater than another all the variety's
total L confidence intervals did exceed
one indicating a re yielding effect
except for shock wve VR in year One
Summer which is interesting considering
we did see it had higher total forage
yields like in the nitrogen rate study
we did see a sign significant effect on
environment in total L as we can see
these box plots and we might not see it
in these graphs because they're on
different scales but we did see a total
ler that was greater in Fall than in
summer
harvests so we see similar Trends in
Grain partial ler there were no
significant effects of genotype across
years which indicates that no one
variety leads to a higher grain yield
Advantage andr than another while no
variety was statistically greater than
another confidence intervals indicated
that a grain yield advantage in a croing
is likely for both shock wve BR and Hest
360 in year one but not for WL 365 HQ
variety performance in in crop again
varies with environment and we saw in
year one in New York confidence
intervals actually did not show that
intercropping gave a grin yield
Advantage for any variety which may have
been related to the lodging we've
discussed
previously so for our forage quality
there was no significant effect of
genotype on total CW protein or total
relative feed value which indicates that
no one variety prefers forage quality
advantage in inner crop over another
while the effect was not uniform across
environments there's generally a lower
total crude protein in total relative
feed value in inner crop compared to
monocultural Alpa which is expected with
the lower proportion of lanss inner crop
while we did not include monoculture
crims and Analysis we would expect there
to be lower forage quality than
intercrop as SE in the previous chapter
as and as well we would also expect to
see no effect on currents of forage
quality from genotype
to summarize our findings for the
alphaalpha variety study out of the
three varieties tested we did not find
one to be better suited to the
environments tested and we did not find
one to be best suited to intercop perza
we did find that variety had a
significant effect on Al for yield and
total forage yield in year one with
shockwave BR more consistently providing
a higher yield than the other two
varieties variety did not have a
significant effect on currents of grain
yield or forage yield total forage of
grain over yielding forage quality while
we saw some effect of variety on total
forage yields we cannot definitively say
that this was effect of qu dorcy rating
of Shockwave as this was a rather narrow
study only using three varieties of
three fall dmy ratings which may not
have actually been representative of the
Fall Dy group we also only tested these
varieties across four locations and
there may have been other attributes of
the varieties besides fall Normy rating
that contributed the role in these
results to bring together all of our
findings from this cenza alphaalpha in
propic experiment our results show that
a farmer focused on cenza grain yield
production could potentially benefit
from a dual use corenza alphaalpha in
our cin system with brain yeld
advantages during the summer and a
higher Forge biomass of higher quality
in the fall while increasing profits
through synthetic nitrogen need
reduction we also found that fall dormy
reading may not have an effect on
alphaalpha variety performance in the CR
currs of Beyond year one Forge yields
despite these initially promising
findings we recognize the study was
limited we only have two years of data
only four locations and only three ala
varieties with only three full Dy
ratings there's plenty of work to study
and future studies could continue to do
to overcome these limitations to better
improve our understanding of the Dual
use Curr alphalpha system in the study
we plan to include a third year of
harvest data next year and longer term
studies are generally important for
perennial systems both this study and
future studies could be improved through
more thorough modeling of relevant
parameters including the effect of
pre-existing soil nutrient conditions
and their changes over time how the
system and its management affects brain
quality and how confounding factors like
Leed pressure row spacing and Inter
anual weather variability affects
outcomes breeding of Kenza is ongoing
and will continue to be important as we
pursue larger grain sizes and yields
slower yield toin and optimize currer
for use in inner crop and of course
there's plenty of other management
effects that could be investigated
Beyond n
fertilization different Health Alpha
varieties should be tested for or bred
for inner crop more work on that coming
soon um and overall while findings are
promising economic analyses will be very
important to understand how reducing n
fertilization and intercropping and a je
use system actually affects
profitability in Farmer bottom lines
with that I'd like to thank my committee
members for the guidance and kindness
and my collaborators for their patience
and support I'd like to thank my lab
members for all the laughs in the field
and all the help in the field and of
course my friends and family for their
unwavering love and support it was such
a privilege to work on this project and
I really love my time at Cornell but I'm
also very excited for my next chapter
back in Virginia and with that thank you
all for your time and please feel free
to ask any
questions
about logic did you
environment so we did not analyze that
but we did largely observe it mostly at
New York in year two um other locations
definitely have observed it um and there
is some work saying that lodging rate is
likely associated with higher ntion
rates um but no one has specifically
looked at environment effect that yeah
but we except way very naive question
about these systems I know they're going
to have to be renovated like alala has
to be renovated how long do these go
before typically you repl and you
renovate the whole right so that's one
of the problems with the currens of
forage yield def so in my first graph we
saw that those uh intermediate we grass
successions they declined after one year
typically the literature says that they
yield decline is after two years and for
forage yield decline we typically see
them after around three years for both
kza and Al Alpha so right now we're
looking at Farmers um probably wanting
to renovate after three years but the
more work we can do on the system to
keep yields higher for longer we're
going to have that three perennial that
fit over time so the the typical
alphalpha renovation would then be your
cycle because the turns it with
keep
yes
question think
inter that is the question um a large
part of it is is thought that by keeping
nitrogen rates consistent and higher
over time in the field then we reduce
that limitation and make sure that gra
meals get Stay High um and also it might
just be one of those incing effects that
have not been fully understood yet um it
yeah I think there's still more work
that needs to be done there to truly
understand the effects of that yeah I
think Jake's work found that
y
totally fellow kza kza
homie
yes
question understand you're saying you're
notec but it not
protein but not effects where's all
[Music]
the what part of the system
going that is a great question so the
question is about if we're not seeing a
nitrogen effect where is that nitrogen
going in the system is it running off is
it going to weeds um those both options
so when we're not seeing a nitrogen
effect in inner crop it is essentially
because the legum is helping provide
enough nitrogen that the cenza does not
need to continue to forage for the
excess nitrogen um so we would expect it
to either stay in the system or go to
beads or run off um or potentially if
there are any other changes in um
nutrient balances maybe go into other
organisms within the system
yes no I totally agree so we did some
baseline testing on our soils but it was
not in depth I'm not sure if all Lo Pati
actually tested um and that was mostly
just to make sure that our nitrogen and
our potassium and our potassium and our
sulfur and our what am I you know the
big ones yes phosphorus thank you making
sure that they were all in Balance um
but I think that more in depth like
analysis of nitrogen cycling throughout
the whole system would be really
interesting to understand where
everything is
going yeah good question um so we handh
harvested let me see if I can find a
good example
what we
did um here so you see how I'm basically
grab a bundle you basically cut the gr
heads off the bottom we dry them we
brush them but that's hard mode that is
experimental mode um theoretically we
can use combines one of our locations
Kansas actually did use a combine to
harvest in year two because they had
limited data or limited labor for hand
harvesting so and we do have some
Farmers that are actually growing
parenza on farm and they use a combine
that
yeah thank you very much Megan that was
great lot of work U and a lot of
intriguing data work you do I was
wondering whether you had nitrogen
uptake data and you could calculate from
the tradeoff between adding nitrogen and
the lack of nitrogen uptake or or
somewhat a nitrogen transfer
equivalence from leum to non leum to
answer May question I'll provide some
find points on the mechanisms why
nitrogen doesn't increase Feld because
it's a tradeoff between getting from the
legum and getting fertilizer and
somewhat cleverly use the data to
calculate that transfer rate yeah so we
actually did calculate a parameter that
we called relative field which actually
a lot of things but the way we
calculated it we compared inter crops
plots at zero zero nitrogen rate to
monoculture plots of perza and alala at
the different nitrogen rate levels and
using that proportion then we could
basically estimate how the inner crop
clots with no NES fertilizer compared to
fertilizer effects in other plots um so
we kind of did do some fun data stuff to
approximate that but we didn't really
find any results that were surprising
more exciting or necessarily worth
including in a 45 minutes but I do have
that in my paper if you would like to
see that time but I agree I think a more
thorough understanding of where the
nitrogen is going in system is really
important um I had two considered two
questions one is do you know the the
yield decline that you get in the second
year has anybody looked at nitrogen
immobilization by the microbes are you
sort of feeding the microbes and instead
of feeding the crop when you're adding
that fertilizer and then a follow-up
question to that is how much is the
yield declin been investigated in out
years so if you waited three four five
years to your yield start coming back
because something is changing below
ground and they basically just stay low
uh for your first question um we have
not specifically investigated that yet
in the system seeing whether
mobilization is a large factor in that
decline um and in terms of whether or
not we see uh regression basically um I
have not seen any of that in the
literature it pretty typically is just a
steady downward decline um and there's a
lot of thought on what may be causing
that um some of it is greater amounts of
leaing out and tillering well not
tillering but um basically reallocation
of resources away from brain and towards
bionas yes Jenice
yes good question and the question for
people don't here um was whether or not
we actually checked if the alphalpha had
any nodulation going on so we did use uh
pre-treated seed for the alphalpha so we
hopefully saw some RI Association but we
did not check nodulation rates so we
were just assuming that the Rises were
doing their job down there um and with
the results that we saw at low nitrogen
rates in intercropping we assume that
they were giving some nitrogen um but
with the fact that intercropping itself
even without legums in the system can
still contribute over yielding effects
then it is hard to untangle that so we
did not check nodules but we do assume
that there were at least some doing
their
drop if not
yes acoss
thees n
application yeah so n application was
done in the spring um basically during
regrowth right after spring mowing um so
around April early May time frame and
all the NS applied just as at one point
in the year um and we could potentially
see different effects if we did a split
oblation the year but that's not the
experimental design we went with um in
terms of weed control we largely let
that um left that up to sites so we know
that for example with or Minnesota I
think did some spraying for shepherd's
first um and Kansas Kansas had plent
problems they had aloh bevel they had
spray for different
um yeah so each site only did their
management as they saw fit so like New
York we didn't really do much management
and we certainly saw plenty of clover we
saw um we see a lot of perennial weeds
in the system as people know in
perennial systems you have a shift
towards peral we l Timothy we have
Canadian pistle all that so and even our
reps varied and how weedy it was um but
yes weed management is one of the large
problems in theal system can't just
especially with a system that both has
grasses in it can't you know you have
different modes of action when you're
spray can't necessarily you know just
blanket apply any we
treatments he thanks thanks all for
coming
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu