this is a production of Cornell
University
Oh
so thank you for coming today today I'm
going to do a talk that is a little bit
different than the technical talk I gave
in plant breeding a couple weeks ago if
you're watching on YouTube it's maybe in
one of the channel of videos around this
portion of your screen but here today so
I just want to talk about some things we
doing more than the art side of breeding
and some of the trends and things we are
looking to influence to try to
maybe give us some more opportunities in
what different crops we can breed
and so in plant breeding much of what we
do aligns with some grand challenge
questions feeding a global population
look at sustainability and various
facets climate change addressing
malnutrition throughout the world and
being able to keep up with evolving and
dispersing pests and pathogens that are
coming to challenge their crops and
there's a lot we do to directly address
these but in the process the the topic I
want to integrate today and we'll
explore in a couple different stories
some you're familiar with some might be
new is reducing waste in the breeding
process itself and not necessarily
looking at directly in the waste stuff
there's a lot of the squash that is left
over from our breeding program that ends
up going to the food pantry a lot from
trials we've been distributing the
leftovers from our genomic selection
populations around before Thanksgiving
so there's some direct ways but there's
also just some wasted opportunity in the
breeding process so that's one of the
main things I want to talk today and
really bring it back to the market class
concepts and demands of the marketplace
and to see if we can influence them we
can maybe influence how much progress we
can make
and so the one of the main challenges we
work on and so this pest this is a
striped cucumber beetle is a specialist
herbivore feeding on Kubik crops you've
probably heard from myself or my student
Lauren about how these beetle just are
specialized to feed on cucurbit crops
they will lay their eggs at the base
they sequester some of the bitter
compounds in the plants used for their
own defense and if you have a winter
like we did last year or it looked like
we might have this year remains to be
seen we really didn't have that killing
from the really low temperatures to
really really reduce the butyl
populations and so there were swarms
everywhere and it was one of the most
challenging year for a lot of Kubik
growers that i've heard of and we're
just really thinking about climate
change and how those mild winters are
gonna intensify this problem so from the
reading perspective you know what can we
do and it's important to think about it
from a breeding plant breeding
perspective because as we look at some
of the chemical controls we have and
we've relied on breeding for resistance
to these insect pests and probably many
insect pests has lost a lot of attention
because of the cheapness and efficacy of
a lot of the pesticides we've had that
really do a really good job of
eliminating this pests the challenge and
the increasing scrutiny these pesticides
have is as you can see these insects are
attracted to the flowers there's a lot
of nectar in the flowers pollen protein
and you know that's also where the bees
are feeding and so as we're starting to
scrutinize neonicotinoids and their use
and how them there might be some
interaction with pollinator health
having some alternative and if we can
find one within the plant that would be
an ideal solution
and we initially approach this how many
people have before starting to do some
field assays of beetle damage where you
can see there are some plants and some
plots that are green and thriving and
other plants where it's noticeably well
the plants are rather absent the bee
it'll just devour them to the ground and
as we sorted through this you know we
definitely focused originally on those
extremes and that's why we've shown a
few times before so on the top we have
success PMS straight next summer squash
developed here at Cornell by my predator
and
also very popular in organic systems
it's an organic seed is broadly
available this one on the bottom you see
a golden zucchini and this is a crop
where the beetles really prefer it
they've d foliated it and also in the
process the plants that escape that have
gotten bacterial will and then will die
from that and there's been a lot of
people have looked at from the
recommendations in trying to figure out
so what can a grower plant that's really
going to be able to give them a crop
that will be less vulnerable to these
beetles and they've often looked at
different cultivars that are popular at
the time
we took it one step further and looking
at all the different market classes and
the amount of defoliation damage we saw
there's definitely a trend and you can
order the market classes through
increased damage and further where the
biology really comes into play is it
turns out there is a really nice
demarcation in the middle where of all
these squash you eat pumpkins
jack-o'-lanterns pumpkins acorn squash
zucchini coca Zell there's two different
subspecies two separate domestication
events and there's a clear distinction
in preference based on the best same
subspecies klein so on the top you see
the summer squash that are getting very
little damage a member of the subsidy
fanon and the bottom the zucchini a part
of the people people and so how this
relates to some of the market class
questions is one thing it really comes
down to those two extremes I was showing
genetically they're very different
there's two the beetles they're very
different
to consumers there's still different but
you know to what degree could they
substitute right so here is that yellow
summer squash on the far side is a
golden Cikini you have two yellow summer
squash fruits once you put a less almac
marinade and put them on the grill you
know how different might they be but
still there is driving the marketplace
to have these two different market
classes
and use them differently or at least the
demand to have access to both and indeed
the zucchinis tend to be a little bit
more preferred in the marketplace which
is again a question that comes back to
the sustainability because the yellow
summer squash
they have multiple flowers print per
note are actually much higher yielding
so you have it's kind of the more
sustainable choice okay and further
looking at all of the different market
classes here will you see if her
breeders off and what we do is to try to
be able to continue to make progress and
most rapidly many people do conservative
crosses they you seldom see crosses
across the subspecies and often you'll
see crosses within a market class and so
the amount of gain you can stand to make
is you know quite narrow quite
restricted
but we have started doing many of those
crosses and so here's a population
between those two contrasting squash I
showed and you can see the selection
process here after lauren has gone to
the field and vacuumed up thousands of
beetles to put into these cages and you
can see there's some clear preference
differences as we have these segregating
populations some plants defoliated some
plants still have you know fledgeby's
full intact leaf
and so here so we're doing a cross
between the two and
one question we're going to have is so
at what point are we going to need are
we going to be close enough to a golden
zucchini and in this time they were
doing the breeding - you know what
extent can yellow summer school our
substitute in the marketplace it's
really a market class drive we're doing
here friends so in terms of being able
to have just a good summer squash it's
well there's already exists
the true alternative that we are very
excited to be starting to work on and
it's something where I myself need to be
kind of persuaded down this road to
explore this is an Italian summer squash
this is a trombone Chi know summer
squash they are part of the most shot of
species so rather than being between
those two subspecies its own species
and they they can be used as a winter
squash the butternut squash you might be
enjoying this week in addition they can
be used as a summer squash in our work
to look at some of the climate change
aspects we often have trials in the
southeast because that's a good
predictor of the climate we might have
to come and the growers are working
through many of those challenges now and
one of the key differences that makes
this from an chino more sustainable is
nearest to me on the right you have a
zucchini stem it is hollow and very
susceptible to squash vine borers they
get in that passageway they're very hard
to control once they get in on your left
you have the solid stem of one of these
mo shadow species so just naturally much
more resistant to the vine boards
because they can't really burrow in and
just have a subway system through the
plant
but this was the Trump and Chino is an
heirloom there's a lot of room to
improve and
so this is where we started to get some
of the great input from the team at Blue
Hill and chef Dan barber as we look
through to see so what are the
characteristics we do need to preserve
in these from and Chino squash as we
start to breed with them and then
understanding so how can they best be
displayed in a dish and so you have some
different uses where you find the
Tremonti no they're much more delicious
than a zucchini they have Laver and so
if you've ever thought about where its
flavor in zucchinis well there are some
classes that they do have some great
flavor but also here in a trump and
Chino you get a lot flavor there's a lot
of density to it and this became a very
popular offering there and this model is
something that we have
we're very optimistic for how it work
with the trombone Chino because of the
great success we've had in the past and
so the honey nut squash you know
hopefully no one enjoy now is here in
the bottom corner and it wasn't
something that originally took off
because it looked different than it's on
the marketplace the Trump and Chino is
going to look different than this squash
the growers we talked to that's one of
their major concerns is how are they
actually going to get in the marketplace
it's a crop they know that works for
them but so how do you get that culinary
trend to catch on well the the chef is
the key so Honey Nut is a small squash
it has a built-in ripeness indicator you
can tell when it's fully ripe that will
change from a green to an orange rind
and is much more delicious at least I
will tell you than any other flutter nut
squash you'll have and the key within
that is that it has a cross I was done
many years ago dick Robinson at Geneva
started the process Miley John continued
it but it's a cross between a butternut
squash and the Buttercup squash and that
yielded the honey nut squash which that
talked about some of the technical
aspects before this is an exciting crop
both for how good it is itself and it's
much sweeter much smoother texture then
it was much of that to the Buttercup in
its pedigree but also it has about twice
the beta-carotene
more than three times the lutein again
as much alpha carotene so it's really a
neutral and antioxidant nutrient
powerhouse there and it's also been
serving the basis for further genomic
selection work we've been doing the the
reason it had some challenges getting
into the marketplace and the kind of
what's helping it now is that its
distinctive right and so it's smaller
has the orange rind if you're growing
your garden starting out dark green
so it took a while for that to catch on
it was getting that popularized so then
when it did catch on now we're getting a
privilege it's normally reserved for
apple cultivars where it's sold by name
in the grocery store that had the SKU
code that's specific to it and so all
the work we've done in Vienna crates on
it's really delicious has is
identifiable so consumers can go back to
find it experience and they can know
when it's ripen at its peak is all
coming together and this is something we
can do hopefully for many of the other
they work on the ripeness indicators
that trend were putting into all our
squash it's really hard to tell whether
a butternut squash is ripe or not
otherwise and
also just an example of one of the
trends that we now know we can drive a
couple others where we are
recreating some crops that don't
necessarily fit in the existing molds is
our work with some purple snow peas and
so this is exciting to us for the color
there's a of course in the antioxidant
boost that comes with the anthocyanins
and associated flavonoids but these are
a little different and they're a little
different because they're not a
perfectly straight and so in pee
breeding a lot of effort has gone into
making the pods perfectly straight the
challenge we find when it comes to you
know beyond incorporate them into food
is whether you have a few of those in a
stir fry it works very well it's pretty
they mix in but once you start to add
more than a certain amount they start to
look a little bit like the truckloads of
firewood that might have been dropped
off at your houses so there's just you
have that pile of them and they all just
kind of stack together
these as you can see have a curl to them
they have this wavy nature that actually
is really cool initially because it
gives them loft and so they just have
much more presence appearance on the
plate and as you are starting to work
with them share it it is actually just
something that's more interesting to
work with and present in addition to all
the work we've done on getting the
flavor to be sweet and overcome some of
the stringency of those purple flavors
there's some often some bitterness and
astringency associated with the
accumulation anthocyanins and crops the
other example where we just having fun
and creating new types of in this case
peppers and so just trying to do some
things to really increase the market
appeal you see those little snacking
peppers that you'll see increasingly on
the vegetable trays you have a gathering
it's great to see that they are one the
first one first vegetables to go off the
tray but we can think we can increase
the consumption even more the vitamin C
content in these is also through the
roof and so there's this novelty and
looking at flavor and quality and then
also being able to capture some insect
disease resistance with the Trump in
Chino
there's also work we do on another
pathogen q Corbett downy mildew
this there's a lot of this work I do
with Chris smart and the resistance we
had to downy mildew it wasn't really an
issue for many growers for quite a few
years for a few decades there was some
resistance and been bred into held
really well the challenge we faced is we
started to get some new races some new
strains of the pathogen that we're
starting to overcome the existing
resistance and so you'll have some
telltale symptoms on a cucumber leaf and
then once it occurs an area it rapidly
the fully it's the crop and so on the
bottom left you can see just a little
bit over just ten days of disease
progress for this pathogen so once it
moves in you go from having a productive
crop to nothing very quickly now all the
downy mildew resistant cultivars that
were out on the market you know the
pathogen has overcome their resistance
and toward that we've hard to do some
this isn't working Peter Oh jumbo in
North Carolina and looking at how we can
track the pathogen you know one thing
you can see it's going to retrieve to
the east coast we can watch how it moves
through the year and with some special
emphasis with has been in from the major
area than the Carolinas in Michigan
where a lot of the production happens
and then up in our area in New York it
always often arrives later but this is a
pathogen that's being dispersed it is
probably overwintering in
protected structures around Michigan
where as we try to have this global
continual supply of cucumbers year round
that leads to we're growing cucumbers
year round in the pad the gin is present
year-round and especially as tropical
storms move up the East Coast as those
increase we often get much more and
sooner the dispersal of downy mildew up
the coast and so you know this is a
pathogen that then interacts with some
of our food system issues on a large
scale and the most direct way you would
interact with it is if you were growing
cucumbers in the fall you'll see that
your plants just quickly die in all the
regional local food markets all the
cucumber's are lost at some point in the
fall not just because of you know the
frost of the season is ending up but you
know this passage is moving in and the
fungicides are losing their efficacy as
it continues to rapidly evolve
so we've been excited when we can be
able to have a major change in disease
resistance for this so our two most
resistant varieties on the top so
varieties that are now commercially
available talked about now
compared to some of the other options
growers had as they turn to something
that had improved downy mildew
resistance or was just one of these
heirlooms you know a typical crop they
had been cucumber called bard they had
been growing and
excitingly also and as I showed you that
map of how downy mildew is coming up the
East Coast this is a trial of the
beautiful location our collaborator
Janine Davis has in North Carolina and
you can see in the foreground as downy
mildew starts to move in and take out
our cucumber and melon pots behind it
you can see the this site I was
overjoyed to see as I pulled in is the
arrows show you the green patches so
these are our resist and cucumber
cultivars so it's bred in New York but
it's not as something that works in New
York it's something that is also really
holding up in some of the severe disease
pressures in some of the main cucumber
producing regions in the nation and with
this and one of the the back stories
with it that is exciting is often is
people think about the time line four
introducing a new cultivar so for us
this new downy mildew resistant line 401
it's something that I've showed in some
other talks is a much higher yielding
when downy mildew is there of course
it's still alive but also has some
competitive earliness in the initial
cross we did in 2012 to take what was a
later but robust disease resistant
breeding line this a 264 cross it to
Dasher which is one of the most commonly
grown slicing cucumbers around
that cross in 2012 we were doing
selections in the field in 2013 we can
have the benefit of a couple of
generations a year using the greenhouse
face we had a a selection that we were
really confident about in 2015 was out
in a couple of trials as a really
preliminary stage
the our release just came out last week
and so the publication of its existence
is just coming out and also there's a
seed company that has it licensed did a
see production this summer and so this
is something that we started the process
in 2012 it's going to be available to
growers or the specific focus on the
southeast where they really need it most
next summer and so this is a really
rapid response system where is it really
fully finished can we do more with it
certainly we're going to keep working on
it that's in part why we're giving them
these numbered lines and not names yet
because these are still going to be
works in progress but that doesn't mean
that a grower can't really benefit from
having this tool on their farms now
right and so we've just continued to
release things as soon as we have
something we know is an improvement it's
hard to fast-track that get it out to
the growers
and so and while that is something we're
proud of and seems fast on that scale
there's also something that could be
even faster some of the sources for
downy mildew resistance we're using are
things that are our cultivars that are
well know their cultivars depending on
where you are in the world that was the
seat that was the key to much of our
resistance breeding is taking different
cultivars that had moderate resistance
bringing that together and getting an
even higher level of resistance and
looking through some of these cultivars
you'll see there's some Chinese
cultivars that are in growing in parts
of the world where these pathogens are
endemic there are also Indian cultivars
that are also being grown in parts of
the world with some of these pathogens
are endemic and so these are existing
cultivars that are fit with existing
cuisines around the world and while we
can spend a lot of time adapting these
doing some breeding to be able to kind
of take that resistance and intrigue
resset into some of the market classes
we enjoy there's also the potential for
these to be enjoyed right now and to
help to
diversify to share more broadly this how
well they might do the many have
excellent yield these in high tunnel
open field trials with them and the
flavor is great sometimes the flavor is
different sometimes it needs to be used
differently in the kitchen but these are
still cucumbers that can be grown now
and enjoyed at least while we are at
certain times of season when it's
difficult to grow the other cultivars or
while we are continuing to make it into
to do the breeding process to introduce
the resistance into the market classes
we enjoy
and so that's really looking at some of
those aspects of the breeding process
and where we can interact
another opportunity and that has
increasingly drawn attention so here's a
study by the NRDC is just looking at the
amount of produce that is harvested and
then just never really makes it
into you know well into our diets and
never makes it into our bellies and a
variety of reasons sometimes it is
oversupply and so there's often to make
sure you a grower can meet a contract
they will produce more just to make sure
they can have that supply
much of what's over produced my end up
in a landfill something that doesn't
look like you might be expecting to fit
that market class concept might end up
in a landfill and so as we've been
starting to look at some of the
different ways we can improve this again
we've taken the lead from
our great collaborator chef Dan barber
and this is his salad
collaboration with sweet greens that's
been a big inspiration to us and how we
start to think about
also how we can change some of the
attributes we're breeding for okay and
so this is their their salad where it is
essentially the what you might have left
over on your cutting board after you
make a salad and so it is broccoli stems
carrot peel you see the leaves from some
of the brassicas that actually do make a
fine salad these are they're all edible
parts and this was celebrated in a salad
at sweet greens where it ran for a wild
is really looking at even as we have the
harvested of plant parts that come in
and whether we are not we choose to use
them how can we be able to change our
approaches to be able to use more of
that and so you know there's part of it
that can happen through culinary trends
and how consumers the public approaches
what to do with the produce they bring
home and it can be you know introduced
to them in these ways but also for me as
a plant breeder we start been
increasingly starting to think about so
what about all these other components of
the produce that I'm not selecting for
so I'm always selecting for the best
fruit quality and as I try to get over
the hurdle the trombone chino and how
that was something that wasn't really
fitting with my concept of what I was
going for in a butternut squash we're
going for a straight next small really
sweet then to be introduced to this long
windy squash it and it took a little
while for me to be able to really
realize the potential of doing the
breeding work within how release it into
the food system in a more sustainable
choice so looking at the under
appreciated components in this salad the
part where it's kind of come home to
some of the breeding and selection I've
been doing is I find myself going
through a squash field tasting more
parts of the plant than I ever would
have imagined even a year ago
then barber started to tell me how it
was you know I should be doing this and
how we would be you know and how there's
this potential to breathe for the flavor
of the stems of a squash plant the leaf
petioles and
again this was something where he helped
me really kind of think more broadly
about what we could be selecting for and
for me the what converted me was
sampling the dish so the nearest to me
is a cue carpet people penne pasta where
there is the leaf petioles of the squash
plants that are prepared if you look for
a gluten-free pasta now this is 100%
gluten-free it's just the leaf petioles
but you know there's variation within
squash so some actually don't taste very
good some are okay and some actually do
have good flavor and so as I've gone
through the field and doing oscillations
one of the key places you can really see
this can impact sustainability is
at the end of the season here's a
panorama of a squash field and you can
see on the side nearest me on the right
you see the typical loss that plants are
succumbing to powdery mildew even the
spider breeding efforts at some point
they senescent go down there's also some
other species from other parts of the
world that I have growing on the Left
these are naturally adapted species and
some of the the breeding work we start
to do with them and you can just see
they are still green vibrant growing
this was at my house in October you
could only imagine it a little bit more
milder part of New York they would have
been growing just fine probably up until
maybe well today last night
and so this is a poem you know so the
ground is being used it's being planted
growers can harvest the fruits but you
know at the end of the season or as they
are just having a succession of plants
there's really a lot of food out there
in the field and so as we've gone
through and learned how to be able to do
some of the sampling or kind of realize
that this is a great thing that we can
do
you know it you can only have some some
benefits
and so there's also an emphasis on
Lawrence right so I learned this from a
chef
you know and so this sort of approach in
some of the cultivars we're using it's
something that's not new to the world
and so in many parts of the world you
know this is part of the culture this is
part of the cuisine these plants are
eaten the whole plant in many other
different countries and so for us it's
been a matter of kind of learning those
cultures learning those traditions
appreciating the value they have and how
it contributes to sustainability food
access and those parts of the world and
just kind of really starting to enjoy
and celebrate those opportunities and
for us of course as a plant breeder
there's also as we look into some of
these crops they're growing much warmer
parts of the world still there's an
opportunity to adapt them to more thrive
in our parts of northern North East it
will be very different from where
they're originally grown right but so
this is learning from other cultures
kind of getting some more diversity in
and being able to
appreciate some of the the plants now as
they are as they come from many
different places of the world and
there's definitely some breeding that
can be done but also as value as they
are and so the kind of some of the
themes I try I wanted to focus on today
is
its be able to be have a more efficient
breeding process you know there's an
opportunity cost and waiting until
something is finished and restricting
ourselves to this is exactly how it
needs to look in the marketplace so what
what diversity what potential is there
to have uniqueness and how can it be
used to actually drive consumption and
so increasingly some of the approaches
we use as we look and how to take
something that's working well now and
just get ready access to a grower so on
farm trials as pilot production and so
as we start to do our own farm trial
work there's often an idea that whoa Kay
it'll be available later when it's
commercialized as we can commercialize
some of the cultivars some of the
breeding lines that are actually doing
well now that gives growers immediate
access to it we're not gonna have them
risk their whole farms to it but they
can certainly be able to take a portion
of their land and be able to have
something that might work better and
work into more land for it as we
continue to improve it and that's
because it's before it's finished
cultivars there's often some value
reading for reduced waste learning from
other food cultures on you know what are
the other plants parts of use how are
they consumed what makes them delicious
how can we be able to look at what we're
growing and be able to apply some of the
same and also maybe try some of those
cultivars here to see what we can do to
introduce those and with that as we can
get some culinary trends led by a chef
to look at how we can be able to take
those cultivars or adapted now are
working really well and be able to
hopefully start some culinary transit
can embrace that diversity because those
are things we can eat now that will have
a much greater sustainability
even before the breeding process starts
here and to really embrace the breeding
process that's been going on for the
many years to get it to the state it was
as we experienced it from those other
parts of the world
and so with that I like to thank the
graduate students in my lab I showed
clay work Lauren Brazil ski former
postdoc Brian lucky and a fantastic
group of graduate students and postdocs
in the lab some great technical support
to make everything come together and a
big thanks to chef Dan barber at Blue
Hill that's really led us as we've
learned to explore things explore
vegetables a little bit more bravely
than we were before and lots of great
collaborators that have helped us that
have helped or we've helped with some
there's aspects of I've shown and a
great support from USDA nifA and some
other funders thank you
[Applause]
nope yeah yeah yeah
yeah it's from 2012 to 2017 yeah sure
did I skip one
well no so we're getting two generations
a year there this so the the cucumber we
can get multiple generations a year we
can even squeeze it to three and and
yeah and so that's what really helps us
be able to push it forward quickly
yep
Zack and then Marcus yeah
yeah and I guess maybe I should repeat
the questions and so the question about
if there is hazards in rushing something
to a grower and if there might be some
more durable resistances other progress
so I think the it is in kind of rushing
it to a grower I think the the
considerations are you know they might
be losing production out they might have
given up on a crop completely as we talk
to some growers in the southeast they've
given up on summer squash zucchini
entirely and so in that system being
able to share something that might work
and we won't suggest so plant their
whole farm too that that would be a huge
risk but you know to put in a row and
see how it does and so it is really
those exploratory plots kind of getting
them at a scale an appropriate scale
where they can be introducing them to
their production and also at the same
time then they have enough to test
market and kind of and start to be able
to build their following before they
take something new and novel and
introduced in a large scale so it does
have to be balanced but I think it works
and Marcus
yeah and I think it's in terms of you
know culinary trends you know start so
kale was it you know so that's chef
driven trend you know I think the baby
leaf lettuce you know and how that's a
like similar to the teas and so you know
that's something that provides law so
loft to a salad so as we moved away from
iceberg lettuce to all these baby greens
it's something that's actually much more
sustainable for a grower it gives them
more some opportunity so you know how
many farms do we see now with high
tunnels that are growing greens
year-round and they're not just doing
one market class or type you know they
have multiple different species families
brassicas are being mixed in and so
there's great diversity at least going
in and so you know that's something that
got a lot of its push from the chef
community
yeah any questions in Geneva
yeah
well the
well we have been working with some seed
companies that are can kind of see a
real critical a way to address a need
now and so some of these are are ending
out in more regional seed companies that
do not need to have you know thousands
of pounds of seed but can do it at much
smaller scale and be able to kind of get
it out now so as we have field days
throughout the southeast its attended by
many of the southeast seed companies
many of those are picking up so these
varieties now is it they can see it's
starting to work well in a region in
need and
their seed production can also be kind
of their last proof in the trial
so but yeah so it's otherwise it is yeah
being able to convince someone to take
the plunge and something radically new
that's why we need somewhere the pull
through help sure
anything else from Geneva before I move
to a couple here
yeah
Hey Bruce
yep
yeah sure and and I I didn't focus on on
it here there's a
campaign I did a talk in plant breeding
couple weeks ago they're really focused
on much of that and so that should be up
on YouTube now so again for the people
on the screen at home it'll be hopefully
in the list there but so a lot of the
work we're doing there is so genomic
selection is a really great in promising
tool for us right now and so we've been
doing genomic selection for quality and
winter squash the next step is store
ability because we'll have that the
whole debris the whole crop cycle is one
year to be able to fully evaluate the
storage of those to go from and when we
plant them to when the last ones come
out of storage and so that's going to be
a huge help we will be looking at the
true the games we've been able to make
next summer but so far it's it's very
it's very promising and we're seeing the
games being made and so and again that's
one that kind of fits in as we've had
the intermediates in the genomic
selection process we've been
distributing a lot of butternut squash
from that which are all I think
hopefully being received very well and
so they're already high-quality they are
diverse there's mixtures of fruits sizes
and some qualities and shapes but
there's still very high quality produce
and the other majors with the stripe
kubera beetle starting to look at the
genomic context so what is the reason
for that subspecies difference in in
beetle preference and we've been
focusing on f2 populations by parental
populations because the population
structure for an association study
precludes that we are studying the sub
structure and so we had to mix that up
but so we've done that coupled with
starting to look at RNA seek to see what
and using some of the new 3-prime
quantitative methods to look at you know
the gene response for beetle feeding and
what's going on between those you kurby
tason's and
also just some other volatiles and other
maybe anti feed and metabolites and
the thing that we're very proud of and I
was just accepted this morning the
powdery mildew resistance that was
famously done by Henry Munger here at
Cornell
4q cucurbits so moving the wild species
introgression from the Q curve Itamar an
easy I into Mossad ax and pepo and a key
attribute and much of the brain has been
done here so we're the first to have a
published publicly available marker
that's so far completely Co segregates
with the trait and we were very excited
about how we did that approach because
rather than creating a lot of
populations for ourselves we just took
advantage of the populations that were
already there and so as we had that
resistance gene that Henry Munger did
and shared throughout the world dozens
of breeding companies hundreds of plant
breeders working on that for probably
millions of meiosis and as we've been
able to just genotype what's resulted
from that the one region they share in
common is a 75 KB interval about 75 KB
with a couple really promising candidate
genes and we're now following up so
those are the types of studies we're
doing it's a via another video that kind
of summarizes all those but and this was
really just looking at some of the the
art behind it and some of the other
opportunities to change how we do what
is otherwise
and kind of an established pipeline
thanks Bruce
yeah Rachel
mm-hmm
yeah
this is the zucchini say that that
subspecies yeah
mm-hmm
yeah so yeah so the question here was as
we're crossing these two and we are
trying to go toward being able to put
the non-preference from the summer
squash into the
more consumer preferred market class of
the golden zucchini how are we going to
know when we're close enough
so that will be something that will be
on part up to kind of consumers and as
we're sharing some of the intermediates
with growers if they are being in a
market there are some subtle flavor
differences there are some other
characters who might come along for the
ride we can it will probably in the end
just be a match of the visuals if we
kind of converted it over but and also
you know there are some culinary
differences that we can also
rotate will taste a lot of squash yeah
thanks is a time for remote yeah
yep
yeah and so there's a
conference in 2013 that really helped
get a lot of that going and kind of a
much greater visibility to the potential
there so yeah it's increasingly you'd
see the the chef breeder interaction
going which has been really exciting and
you know it's it's a way to be able to
you know capture the creativity from
both sides and be able to work directly
so there's actually two ends of the
process that are coming together and
Hannah did use the other
okay
you know and I think then the the thing
I'd be arguing is to what extent can we
do to move beyond that of it and so and
just have it so what other is people
think about creating new market classes
is kind of it when is something just
great as it is and Ken Hakeem can
introduce that and that was with the
honey nut squash you know a miniature
butternut squash was not not something
that really fit into the market is small
and looked different in it it tasted
really good but it wasn't until people
really got introduced to it that they
got popularized
[Applause]
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at Cornell edu