this is a production of Cornell
University
thank you thank you so much for the kind
introduction and for was importantly for
having me here on this beautiful campus
I if you ever visit texas a man and you
would like to see fall colors you will
never see that not now not later it's
going to be all the same gray is it
vintage fine it's so pretty here I
wished more when they fly back to that
since I will take a picture from the
plane to throw my wife because she
misses for the fall colors
I
have quite a bit of slides but the
journey to the slides are simple so I
will go through the past and they are
showing a bunch of different phenotypes
and that's the point of my participation
today is to convince you that
there is life beyond just mana gated
just one occasion it's just one of the
acceleration reduced by the plants and
plants produce
hundreds of different and other level
species of silicones and I would like to
leave you with a strong conviction that
other absolutement in plants have a
quotient physiological array of
functions in the worst resort achill
processes and especially in defense
against pathogens and insects and even
interaction with beneficial
microorganisms organisms called
colonizing roots so i would like to show
this picture simply because i'm really
proud that texas A&amp;M decided to build a
new building for plant pathology and
microbiology department is going to be
right here
so this is my lab my lab is
quite large simply because we do a lot
of freedom in the field and i will
explain you how backwards and so these
are all great your students here
kiss her there's another graduate
students and all of the gradient
ok so I collaborated with a lot of
different planetary of people in the
world I was funded by the National
Science Foundation for ten years in a
row and that funding came to collaborate
with Nancy color if you were sick
wisconsin madison to study attention a
fox lakers a in maize and of sleep is
produced by the fungal pathogen produce
legs i
collaborated a lotta skibo Forstner in
at university of göttingen beds until i
went there in 2010 sabbatical leave and
i now am capable of running all the
biochemical analysis that you taught me
how to do while in his lab and now i'm
your dreams that in my life and in fact
we do not I'd not vibrating longer and
input I collaborate is these people but
they do not need the services any longer
to run fight hormone analysis for
volatile organic compounds analysis or
out of all the tools
used by the plans I started
collaboration this group here mr. Becker
Nelson and Jenna Coleman and they are
testing our buildings for assistance to
local Connelly flight which is a big
problem here in the north of the United
States but other problem in taxes at all
that's has its own problem in deserts
for Joe's famous in my thoughts and
contamination
by by the front way that hummus I
collaborated you struck candidly if you
work some trichoderma Venus as you may
know and the role of technical
appearance trigger no more games is it
at the root colonizing n to fight that
induces induce systemic in the above
ground organs and we just got funded by
USDA to study signaling events between
the two organisms and clever it is a
story and to myself it was primarily for
fuel based testing for mycotoxin
contamination and more recently I
collaborate with rezian st. Pearson and
Beth's to study effect of pseudomonas
fluorescens which also gives an end to
fight of beet and corn that can do
systemic resistance and promotes growth
and fortunately we're not had time to
talk about this research
so I will give it a brief for you of
what we want to do in my lab and what
the idea is behind all of these
different projects that we have in the
lab
we primarily work is to gene families
sleep oxygenases and pokes a vital 1808
interfaces and these genes are required
for são paulo just one occasion
biosynthesis but production of other
oxer limits
then I will talk you put focus primarily
on what we have found so far
in terms of the role that absolute mins
play in maize interactions views design
which severely reduces reminiscent and a
specialist claims that produces a fat
ass
and then it will finish up Wiz
showing you the data the suggestion to
the boxes units and oxalate things that
are expressing eludes have a strong
where are the positive or negative role
in the interaction you started erm
appearance and conferring in you
systemic resistance in above-ground
audience that's also a new project so
what are also lateness of
solutions simply stand for oxygenated
lipids that are implants derived from to
polyunsaturated fatty acids we delay it
contains two double bonds 82 with elana
case contains three double bonds to the
tribute speech in safe the resulting
products of this primary oxygenation of
variances is production of a vast array
of oxidants not sure this scheme or
biosynthesis of his machinations and
they are suspected in addition to just
Monica severe suspected was as potent
signaling tivities strong antimicrobial
and insecticidal activities however we
know very little to put small kids are
doing in the plants we know what they do
in animal systems let me show you will
they do in any system
this is an inspiration for my lab so I
show only here there is several reviews
you will never find a review that will
show you what oxa lipids to in mammalian
system simply because they don't even
call them usually obsolete as they call
them by the class of hormones and so one
of these classes of moments is called
prostaglandins there are six other large
groups of hormones play the toxins from
books and so on that are produced by the
melon systems I will only show you an
example for prospect rankings because
this molecules are diverse again in use
a reduced from arachidonic acid which
has 20 carbon chain fatty acids that has
four double bonds they produced a subset
of prostaglandins all of these letters
and numbers indicate a different
molecular species of this prostaglandins
and each of this prospect landings is
produced specifically in specific cells
and
transported to a specific servants
quarters and perceived in other
different cells by a number of different
g-protein coupled receptors so if you
think about this morning case just one
in case it as a single to center in land
both Corey one dose and duration so
prostaglandins different molecular
species of prostaglandins and melon
systems have different g-protein coupled
receptors and different functions that
they convey and if you look at the list
of all the different physiological
processes across the grandest regulate
it's amazing they seem to regulate every
resource for processing the new
mammalian systems
it aspirin is known to all of you
because it's the mode of action of
aspirin or us is to prevent biosynthesis
of this oxalates by binding to cycle
oxygenases and inhibiting activity of
lipoxygenase and the result of that is
down regulation of some of this
absolutely so and i will show you some
of the data showing that when you know
how assembly oxygenated genes in maize
and all of a sudden instead of increased
susceptibility to pathogens they
displays don't increased resistance so
you should think of them as or that
effect as effective of salicylic acid or
aspirin winding to inhibit a dispenser
so sometimes overproduction of this
molecules lead to array of physiological
disorders
so this pathway is so well understood in
mammalian systems sixty percent of the
drugs currently available on the United
States market target asbestos of course
not only sentences but also transport
but also to specific perception in fact
my proposal is calculated because
existing data from this science paper
into sultan monte calculated what is
current number of drugs in regulating
specimen and here is estimated 85 of
fda-approved drugs target dispensaries
in mammalian system so that's how much
you know more than mammals so what do we
know about plants Lance produced a bunch
of this of Sullivan's and they reduce
remember by the oxygen is passing so
what I've oxygenators do is oxidized
fatty acid to different positions 9 or
szczecin and it's very important that
you discern these two types of the gods
it is because only 13 lipoxygenase is
capable of producing eventually just one
just one in case it lineups lipids can
not take part in ox alypium in interest
more negated by sentences they produce
what we call line of some intensity so
that reaction seems to be simple only
for different products that producer
your brother Bob seaman's yet the
problem is the box is the best day and
the complexity comes when you take into
account that this primary results by the
probe straight asses are converted by
seven different sub branches of the vote
Spencer to produce
tons of different of celebrites right
and some of the superiors right I talk
to you a poisoner who knows best of
slipping field in the plants I ask you
one passion so you know how many ox11
spread plants produce collectively
because we measured then in many
different species he is to make it six
hundred and now people this is probably
more 27 hundreds of solutions and every
year there is about four to six reports
of a new clip is being investigated in
plants so the best understood absolutely
implants of course is just more negates
it is produced by that Allen oxide
synthases branch of the pathway and
involves also fight to the innovator in
the cases only few of them not all of
them to make just more negation and
eventual just one against our sewers now
you can measure most districts olivion's
in my lab imagine about 75 different or
two living species and then it's because
we
we purchase this liquid
chromatography-mass spectrometry
instrument we are not capable of
measuring unfortunately all 700 of them
I wish we could but we want to measure
what we can get standards water so my
long term goal of my lab is to design a
function so wats lipids in maize and
whatever those functions are we are
after what they specifically limits are
doing for plant responses to stress
including a buyer expects so and the way
we do it is to generate hospital
insertional mutants in the oil contains
of those living voice synthesis pathway
if those jeans are known and so it means
there are certain lipoxygenase genes are
quite illegal sites in tight jeans there
are eight occupied today United
reductases and there are two
hydroperoxide lasers of course in RB
Dodson these numbers are about half of
that for each of these defendants and so
the way we generate these mutants is by
taking advantage of that so-called tried
to shield the system for corn available
at pioneer because that's where it
worked as opposed up and so pioneer has
paid long time ago couple dozen years
ago did this huge population about
48,000 pleasant each one in fish
yourself that was produced by the
crossing and new at Japan increase
diversity in brake lines so that
resulted in this collage mutagenized
population basically
and what they do it pioneer is you
specific primers and potato specific
primers cleaning pools of this
plant I don't actually know how many
plants are in that pool and they
identify plants or pools and individual
plants and individual families that
containing insertion of the gene in your
insertion your chain of interest so it
takes about two to three weeks Bob feel
is very good at that and it takes my lab
both sample back crosses and about ten
years and to the three generations for
graduate students to produce near such
an opponent's it back for seven states
that are now Apple to Apple comparison
and honestly because of how long does it
take to generate is Newton's he only
published maybe five percent of the
Newton's that we have generated so it's
a great time to be in my life because
mutants are generated you just come in
the lab for graduation and do the
research
ok so my genome contains sixteen
lipoxygenase 'as they can be grouped
grouped roughly into large to large
subgroups this our city lipoxygenase and
those jeans are required for just more
negated by a synthesis or relatable
purpose in this is my personal belief
that all these regions are producing
gops but in different organs I will book
today only both walks 10 and book seven
eight and nine are likely to be involved
in Jade biosynthesis
besides two teen boxes they mention our
encodes a
69 lip oxygen is one of each is very
unique to mana codes call it looks well
and i will show you data for this gene
this gene somehow Oh regulates
biosynthesis of just motivated by this
type of such this is a huge potential
for crossroad between the nine boxes
versus it evolves so this is unusual
lipoxygenase it doesn't even use fatty
as it is a substrate it uses
hydroperoxide of areas which is produced
by another lipoxygenase and what it does
it please or fatty acid into unusual
effect CA chien and c5 and could see
five main if you've not heard of Antonov
so this lot size of one is likely to be
involved specifically in biosynthesis of
this volatile fentanyl so today I will
so we generated mittens for all that
matter what fun or whatever reason we
tried many times to identify putative
insertion in different places in Cold
Spring Harbor in pioneer the premiere
came and we all this fail to identify
insertion of a mutator in lots of energy
so it's only one that for us to go
octave and I will talk today about the
phenotypes and a bunch of the function
of the end block three looks fine and
look stand and look strap alright if you
want to know about any other the
partition is that I can talk to you
personally some of them like looks too
and Vaughn are involved in salt stress
tolerance and drama tolerance looks for
appear to be required for defense
against anthropos sleep like a stalker
but they will not mention well that
looks why Sheree ninety percent identity
to look for as complete opposite
functions resistance against me sex and
in fact when you look out that gene this
plant are more resistant or the children
and
oak stan is involved in in difficult or
biosynthesis okay so somehow insertion
of potato elements results in unstable
are they that gets decree so we rarely
see any
the trans confusing northern part or RNA
signal if insertions happen to be in its
own the genes
so let me tell you what we have found so
far for the function of the car
situation to be an amazing tractions
alien pretty ladies and aspergillus
lives so Astrid Osiris produces
important carcinogen in fact aflatoxin
is number one the most potent carcinogen
produced by naturally by microbes okay
its most potent carcinogen so it's it
causes cancer development in liver it's
a mutagen and it also pinnacles
immunosuppression in handles so if you
said in British Lloyd's produces another
mic the box can hold few Morrison and
she wants
induces or consult as
inhibits a single lipid by synthesis in
fact that's how program cell death is
used by three models invite their
binding to
ceramide synthase and preventing suva
lipid synthesis in accumulation of the
cursor sort of single limits and
so the idea about lipoxygenase is having
a something to do with the regulation of
mica toxin production came from nancy
kelly research where she showed when she
disrupts and of slipping by synthesis
genes in juice they called sifang
co-producing oxygenated
this arc length by nancy SP BOS
lipoxygenase are also producing there is
one leap oxygenases various flavors
produces an other subset of excellence
and this side factors when you know them
out they were shown to either inhibit or
promotes for Genesis depending on what
sports are
regulated sexual or asexual and they are
put and regulates like regulators
mycotoxin biosynthesis so when you shut
down basins the sign factors might be
after study what assistant in
aspergillus nidulans for aflatoxin is
inhibited and if you and they were also
shown to be involved in quorum sensing
danger so if you look at the chemical
structure of plenty right and humble
direct observations you can clearly see
the resemblance okay and that's
suggested that is potentially a lipid
mediated coastal so the absolute is
produced by the fungal species can be
perceived by the plant to modulate a
limited metabolism in the plant and
plant direct box elements may affect the
physical processes of the pharmacy we
have published in Newport rating 2011
schedule is very complex to show their
schemes from baby booties really hairy
on detail so let me tell you what we
found so far towards testing that
hypothesis that absolutely is produced
by the planet may in fact have two
different effects of mitosis or if I
think induced micro toxin synthesis by
the fungus or suppress my clubs and
synthesis so in this particular case
when you know how it looks three what we
had we have seen right away when his
team seed in production growth
see if we found that ninth agency is
produced from Lee Nolin decades linoleic
acid and 90 youjizz were reduced and 98
UT it's an obsidian derivative from
linoleic acid is completely gone in this
luxury for
mutant alright so they are good line of
silicon deficient so what three is not
involved in just more negation directly
cannot be it's my lip oxygenates so when
we tested how the fungi grow on the seat
is very Buddhist we found no difference
whatsoever so fans I don't care in terms
of vegetation pros they don't care about
the presence of locks sweet gene in the
course
but big surprise came when we measured
humans in b1 see all of a sudden the
mutant
when fungus is wrong or Lotus erosion
they produce about 200 a full last
mycotoxin what they suggest that looks
Li is required for induction of my detox
and biosynthesis you do not ignore it
even now how it works but that is a fact
that's what the luxury function is also
without log 3 in the course the
facilities we use a lot less spores
so for that reason we placed on three at
specifically regulating secondary
metabolism and microphones and synthesis
and positively regulating where the
fungus ends for genesis so and it
appears to have no role in vegetative
roads with it fungus only in the
Colonel's so when we tested what it is
in laxmi mutants that may be responsible
for such effect in P monster so we can
ran microarray analysis long time ago is
then ground of study and bigger see that
many other day partition is such as
about six books 9 10 11 and appear 78
you are in go to jail by scientists are
all over expressed in this Locksley see
colonized by she say so you have tested
independently some of the scenes for
user-generated Newtons and we should be
what I saw that book sleep also
overexpressed looks 10 and looks wife
then suggests it looks three SunPower
nine Olympic sprinters by Lopes three
suppress expression both these are the
lipoxygenase and I will tell you about
the phenotypes of dis mutants in this
post of fusarium and aspergillus legs
and later on we'll come back to the same
gene to show you how overexpression of
these two genes in the rules impact
interaction respect to her mentor
ok so when we testicles five minutes
remember looks remittance a colonized
equally well reported on drone and
either wild-type or the mutant if you do
subscribe it's clear that was five
million see it's much more susceptible
to physically see Louise and
probably corresponding to the increased
by a massive loads by mutants we see
also increased number of cornelia
produced but what was shocking to
discover that it had not no effect
whatsoever on few Manas embody synthesis
so that place looks wide as regulated by
regulating vegetative growth and
probably due to confuse educated rules
increase Canady Asians so looks like as
specific effect productive talks like a
specific effect on the vegetative growth
of the promise
logs Daniel came contrast to the log
three movements books 10 meters are
heavily colonized by the fungus and in
this case it's humanism that was
increased the public responds well to
his own growth and comedian Rosen is but
not the strongest
suggestions look Stan has more specific
effect on few months in their synthesis
unlike absolute looks like because the
phenotypes of Fox 5 meters in 10 in
terms of colonization are set so that
places look stand together it looks wide
as controlling vegetative growth books
10 potential against most stronger
effect or inducing
mycotoxin synthesis
so this differently passages we have
just finished a rating just published a
little audible puppeteers will be have
found that looks 12 again another night
like oxygenase monitored specifically
oxygen is no lo dico to contain this
gene has a very specific attack on
on defense against various Hillary's
Wyatt just warning acid regulation so
let me show what the console expelled is
here so it's not as it involved but not
be involved in jail by synthesis so
looks well Milton similar between five
and ten is also heavily colon infection
saying and in this case if they
introduce a lot more of those spores and
few models in view on probably what the
function of books 12 the right
absolutement is to regulate and
vegetative growth so how does looks 12
okay
early papers we were not able to met up
with his house sells you know that so we
had to send his hands to Germans but now
we can do that analysis so we did a lot
greater analysis of syllables produced
right by this mutant and so in addition
to see it looks when minutes are a lot
more susceptible in Mexico toes to
fusarium organization and so when we
measured up syllables we found that
several of the line of slippers purchase
even some szczecin are absolutely 15 she
not statistically significant though but
mine kg is specifically reduced in the
box 12 moon just that this morning maybe
the one involved in resistance in
providing assistance against the
Tsarevich eluates so when we tested this
morning education loosened levels would
be the found that in the world that it
can
see if you're not inoculated by fusarium
just mana casing is increased
dramatically however not in box 12
mutants so somehow it is nine blocks and
potentially 9kg regulates just more
negated biosynthesis
so the question was there so it's really
debated just like that suggesting
control and then three we're say well
since you have republished just j
division Newton see hope your seven
eight double mutants why not test the
role of just folic acid in resistance to
freeze any resource which was a very
valid question except that looks 12
mutants are so susceptible to various
facilities that every time we planted in
the field it doesn't germinate well
because it's homes to representing and
potentially other soil borne pathogens
it's extremely susceptible it took us
one year to quite as this mutant to grow
it in such a way that it doesn't have
any fusarium recolonize plants so but
you are able to do it when we tested a
diffusion mutants as well by the way
they're also i will show you this data
they are not able to survive on this
view conditions due to extreme
susceptibility to beijing so what we
test it is this of your 78
w infants you have to knock out both of
these genes in order to get rid of your
activity that is required from from for
converting sis vga the natural substrate
for j bias it's into just morning is
this father of yours and six of them
don't know what they're doing we do not
know what they produce because they use
Cesar PDA as a substrate and convert it
into some profit yet unidentified
unknown absolutely potential it's with
instances in all five even talk
simplification of the beauty unsaturated
carbonyl so when we tested those mutants
for resistance against you saying it was
really shocking so we infected the plans
before we left work it poach six or
seven you come in the morning at eight
o'clock and they already
macerated two days later they just
completely collapse so that suggests
that just mana case is clearly required
for defense against desire it's Louise
no doubt about that
so guess that potentially people who
work with deserving salut ages and as
the jewel slave still are you we don't
be are not confident what these the
lifestyles of these two passages are so
we still argue whether they are neck
across any white rose or not documented
by toast but we do not know if they hang
but crossover or negative so it's a
chest because the requirement of G of
defense against this pathogen that
fazaia which solaris is likely to be
either an actor probe or please the
chemical and roll
okay Oh beyond seven eight new double
mutants you took my book to generate his
double mutants about two years because
he would plant a large field of
segregating one in 16 population and
none of the plans that he didn't play
for double minutes instead of I mean
talking to me he says we failed so next
year he plans instead of 200 individuals
he plans five solve an event his cleans
them all and none of them are double
defense and then I don't
you cannot fail two years in the room
what happened it says well I don't know
what happened but there is no no double
mutant said well you were supposed to
think well that might mean of course
what that means that this plant there
are Alyssa so they died for some reason
and sure enough you can only guess oh
damn thing off sorry thank you so much
and dumpy off seems appropriate to
so I guess we did identify that the
culprit in this case was pleased him at
least the sperm invest what we saw in
Texas fields will the tiny or
commercials also also have pity and so
it dries really fast if you terminate
the plants in style soil and then
transplant them in the field like this
and I don't even know why he didn't work
because i know they died from fishing
but he want you to see how fast i said
okay various whatever it is he was
excited about it and look how fast they
prompted infection takes all about 10
days to kill hundred percent of these
plants so they explain this acceptable
so what was really surprising when you
started testing for existence against us
produce things and also thoughts because
that's what Texas farmers careful they
don't care what you say believes our
problem is our thoughts and that's when
I lost funding
because Locksley mutant that was
characterized by extremely low level of
contamination perfume arneson are
extremely susceptible to aspergillus lay
beside the colonel acid is raising the
field basalt they produce all this a
much greater level of aflatoxin so few
months in town of a toxin is not
colonization percolating is down there
is no change
flavors just love this
so the desk there is other boxes that
are
test in loxley mutants and Sheree not be
so exact opposite so in contrast of
screen opens looks fine movements were
contaminated by foot dachshund about
fivefold Max and in epigenetic
background that we have tests including
that
check the breeders used for resistance
to also tops so it's really amazing
effect we danced it looks tan and it was
the same so the sick since 2007 weekend
every year retention we still being
published because I don't stand how it
works because I wanted to get the
Matthews but we showed that
long-standing Europeans are there barely
cool about his body produces a whiskey
Colonel can see and think whatever's for
Jules in fact produces very little
aflatoxin so these two genes appear to
be helping the pathogen to colonize
helping the pathogen to reduce megabucks
so in case of hooks while I still do not
cannot pinpoint what exactly it produces
in terms of what of slipping it reduces
however I do know for sure that looks
tan is the sole lipoxygenase in the
National is possible for Greenlee too
volatile voice synthesis when you go to
leave a while type you see a
spike in the emission from this world
because it is the external d3x and all
external acetate all of them go up but
you cannot identify any traces of this
halitosis about 10 Newtons suggestion
box tank is the only gene required for
govt I wonder now where the jail if had
anything to do is making plans
susceptible to schedule slaves and to
contamination is slaves
so let me switch gears and tell you what
we have found for some of these mutants
in terms of the interaction with
beneficial microorganisms
yeah so you can publish a paper before
this vintage I was invited to publish a
paper or long-distance igloo route to
shoot okay it's some projects it died
long time ago in 2007 and program and I
never figured out why Locksley mutants
are more existent in to enter possibly
apply it seldom to live like and they
will show you this data so if you plan
to experience in the field they have
always searched on the same team title
they're much more resistant to solving
leaf blight they are more resistant to
enter closely employed they are more
resistant to enter co-star crowd of Zion
Brazilian stork wrote and what was
really surprising that when we tested
expression of these genes in response to
fungal infection to all the leaves in in
this cases the conductive amigos the
same is true for bubbles and restaurants
this gene is not induced it doesn't want
it doesn't matter how long you imagine
expression of this gene after infection
this gene is not expressed in the play
in the place where it has effect right
the leaves are resistant to this pasture
so you would suspect that at least it
has to be expressed some house lit
during infection it's not it's not a
gene that is expressed in leaves period
where it's expected it's expressed in
news that
pointed to as potential significance of
food expression of these genes or on
what is happening in the above ground
pools in terms of resistance
increase resistance so
the hypothesis then walls o'clock three
militants produce some signal in the
rules that are consorted from the roots
into the lesions in stocks and induced
increased resistance so how to test of
course if you've worked with dye pots
you know what to do in this case okay
three minutes ago well that you would
you will do the crafting experiment
unfortunately for those of you who work
with monocots it's not possible and it's
a huge problem so then we had to come up
with a new massive how to do it is
theft bike experiment so
one time I both work was cutting this
plant because he was done his end when
you look at them or my brother you're so
much silence sad that you can collect
milliliters of it within a single day
and it's oh wow this that would be a
very firm you to know if reason is taken
as different present being silent here
so but how to apply when you make a tiny
incisions once inches away from each
other all these siblings and apply twice
diluted silence and only 10 micro litre
six hours before infection and then in
fact
mystical Grameen ego and what we saw is
was really interesting so when you
collect silencer from wild-type and
apply to implants they are normally
infected for equally protocol normal
vision however when you take the same
plan the same genotype and a half their
vocational valence and collected from
box three militants this plans for much
more resistant to pull the documentation
supporting the eight-year the runes of
luxury produced the Sun signal and you
can collect it and we can bash it and
apply to that while the plants and you
see this event so then also suggested
that potentially
this gene is regulated particular
appearance prognosis wounds so remember
when you get rid of locks three the
plants are more resistant in background
orders but box key is not expressly so
it's expressed in root log 3 is a
negative regulator then a very sorry and
if so then trichoderma may or may not
not have effect on this gene or the
mutant so if you treat it trichoderma a
restricted number means roots of wild at
all those three miracles and of course
in world up what you see rapid or making
uses technical assistance so the lesions
are much smaller however in the normal
actually compared a violent violet here
to convert my juices in business
business invokes limit they ready
resistant doesn't matter how much like
the derma they have on the roots they
already resistant to take a turn so then
because of this was in order protected
or much to have and I oh sorry amusing
activity it must suppress locks free
expression endurance and hope valley
it's easy to propose this hey boss I
remember like now and they weren't doing
my students were doing this experiment I
thought oh my god what if it's not going
to work I will never be able to submit
this paper and I was shocked how
beautiful it work so then and what we
did it we used a delta s amount of
liquid or without this small peptide
it's a sweet pad line when you know
about that gene for sm one these plants
are not able to induce secure smokeout
movements they were not able to reduce
systemic resistance in the leaves when
you overexpress there is worse more so
this SF on seed protein is required for
induced systemic resistance easily so we
use this mutant and prepare it to the
effect of
expectation vs. wild type on expression
for three nodes and what we saw that
while that indeed like I
really hoped it would happen
and what the hypothermic effects roots
books read expression is repressed
however looks we cannot be repressed
when you use this is artificial movers
so that places look sweet as one of the
targets for sm 11 function of sm one
fumble energy and from the protein is
the suppress expression for floats the
stream
then the question was what it is it
looks with makes it so crazy that you
could use this is our signal all the
time so we can test expression of all
all the lipoxygenase from each week a
mutant or some other genes and what we
saw is incredible so if you look at nine
lipoxygenase pressure in the roots
compared to welcome there is 420 full
induction
overexpression of logs for in the log
three minutes
as it looks fibers of Express looks
available to express and bunch of other
look at this HTC sir james or or hope
you are they for example 22 424 424 Alan
oxide cyclist who r e8 for
overexpression interviews so the roots
of look-see overexpressed whole bunch of
this pod of silicon biosynthesis and
ethical investment decisions he
suggested just one occasion nine ox
lipids and actually maybe the reason why
this mutants are more resistant to fully
investigate and that signal is produced
in books units Constitution rather it
then in inducible man so we tested it
doesn't look Stan just because we knew
exactly what is with it is doing in
terms of their chemistry is required for
gob by sentences but also because we
found something really unique about dog
stand
behind
a project to localize sub seldom
variables NP is in Compton cell so we
used on Jenny plants is a help of Dave
Jackson from cosmic carbon and he they
produce Jenny plant that express quietly
type of Stan and they look everywhere
one looks them ears and found that book
stand spawning be found this was founded
for a blessed and they also identify
some other organelles still do not know
where what it is but what was really
surprised intercedes will expand seems
to stream in BOS florin in silent
because if it moves with opposite
directions so extend directly as a
protein secreted in
24 mins I'm so that may look stand a
perfect candidate to be
relevant to long-distance signaling
right so when then we test book ten
Milton's
44 I saw in response to prep adorable
musician so when you in fact and you
have wild that you think you see in this
case is out regular they are normally
susceptible the addition of trichoderma
to the roots makes it more resistant for
the total protection looks 10 Newtons
arbitrate surprising this gops are
believed to be required for defense
against pathogens we did not see in fact
his mutants were more resistant not only
in the leaf looks 10 mutants were
resistant is a strength to get accosted
by two
the so-called Azalea stop we were
resistant to everything we tested but
immediately after you treat box Daniels
mr. could learn this plants become all
of sudden completely susceptible to
attributed to call each other
communication not only they have both
induced systemic resistance eight league
in some interesting phenotype I quality
juice systemic susceptibility because
remember these plans are resistant
result regularly however they are a lot
more susceptible than regular beads
around so that suggestion box 10 is
relevant to eat and we tested all the
mutants in that list and at least before
exactly the same time for a box 12
mutation so look scrawny opens are
normally they there is no change in the
resistance levels but one plant is cole
mize with epidermal they become a lot
more society so here now
funded by used a to identify his own
business signals in theory utilizing to
silent said that we can collect collect
massively
profiling ox Olympians hormones and
other metabolites if you already have
several candidates needs to be tested
and those candidates are whether they
are not just mana cases
it's totally against the grain because
just mana case it is believed to be
required for virus are in tight let's be
she's not in men's when we used a pair
seven eight JD few minutes they are
still capable of responding to check the
door mobilization by increased
resistance in the stem and in the leaf
so J is not the long-distance thing is
some other movement produced by
nine up oxygenases or precursors oj that
are required for induces
so then I would like to invite your
questions
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell edu