this is a production of Cornell
University so thanks for the opportunity
this is not going to be your typical
scientific seminar
um I'm going to cover the basics of
climate change bear with me I'm an
entomologist I'm not a climate scientist
but I've also dedicated an aw out of
time of learning the science of climate
change I'm going to cover the basics
then we're all going out to dinner get
your credit card out because we're going
to have an expensive meal but the point
is what's changing on the menu and then
I'm going to talk about uh what Cornell
is doing both a little bit from the
academic side which you're all part of
but also facilities and operations there
really is a lot going on it was just
launched a report from the senior
leadership sustainability group on a set
of recommendations to get us to carbon
neutrality by 2035 so I'm going to
summarize
that and Tony failed to mention that
this our latest publication we actually
published Together made the front cover
of weed
science it's my picture on front no was
that it no no oh okay well
whatever okay so Tony and provide a
little bio but I'm going to add a few
more things uh here I am milking a cow
in Costa Rica a few years ago it's one
thing you never forget and that's like
riding a bike you never forget how to
milk a cow and the tour guide was just
blown away that I could milk a cow and I
did it rather effectively I also got
really excited about this anerobic
digestor back there and he said we've
never had a tourist who could milk a cow
and got it excited about the
manure uh I grew up on a little farm in
Wisconsin had a pet Crow named Carl
although recently I realized it may have
been Carla but you know when you're 9
years old you don't have that kind of
conversation with your pets spend time
in a Marine Corps Vietnam veteran I tell
this story because it helps with a lot
of different
audiences I'm not just a professor going
to talk to this group I'm part of
it um I've also held leadership roles at
Cornell and when you're in one of those
roles you're supposed to see the big
picture you can't just be an enologist
anymore I'm also a parent climate change
is
personal going affect my
daughters and lastly the homeland
security motto is if you see something
say something I'm here to say something
okay how many
trekkies probably how' they get their
food replicat replicators right so what
happens with they blew both their
engines throughout the what was the guy
the Klingons you know they're
incapacitated they're lost out in space
in trouble they had to be
self-sufficient kind of looks like the
same place our situation we don't have a
whole lot of places to go got to take
care of what we
have and I think it's better to tell the
truth make you a little
uncomfortable so here we go all right
this is the Endeavor first time I saw
this what a remarkable selfie
but that orange band is the
troposphere right here about this part
of the world's maybe five six miles high
that's where the action occurs that's
where 80% of the climate change activity
occurs
it's like a very very thin
blanket solar radiation comes down hits
the surface of the Earth if it's white
snow most of that energy is reflected
back if it comes down and hits a dark
surface it's absorbed that some of that
energy is then irradiated in as I and I
just learned this the other day
listening to Toby alt if you had a
candle in your hand and you feel the
warmth is it the actual air that's
warming
up it's not it's the radiant energy so
it's that same kind of energy reflecting
off the surface of the planet hits
carbon uh greenhouse gases which are
essential to life on the planet and some
of those are reflected back so we're
simply adding more and more greenhouse
gases to that thin little layer that
blanket is getting thicker it is getting
warmer one of the carbon do one of the
greenhouse gases carbon dioxide on the
bottom is year 1,000 to year 2000 you
can see the Industrial Revolution tion
how quickly things have changed when we
started burning fossil fuels fossil fuel
uh we should be at about 270 parts per
million we're now at 404 more or less
40% above normal if we keep going
business as usual will it hit 900 parts
per million that means we'll have 60
days here in this part of the world
above 90 degrees in the summertime very
different nothing new Tindle hand others
had this worked out in the 1800s what a
greenhouse gas is all about one of the
things that's I've had farmers say to me
is when I mentioned this carbon 12 is
actually increasing the atmosphere and
it comes from the burning of ancient
plants or fossil fuels it's another
direct indicator that the burning of
fossil fuels is changing the atmosphere
and I think this is 97 out of 100
scientists agree we are the cause
climate change is happening I think it's
now 99 out of
100 pretty solid evidence another way to
look at this is the atmosphere is a
bathtub we're filling it up with
greenhouse
gases the natural systems which would be
the drain the oceans the plants Etc to
absorb the greenhouse gases in the
atmosphere uh can no longer keep up
we're putting more water in more
greenhouse gases the drain has not
changed the bathtub is filling
up the relationship ship between carbon
dioxide and
temperature going back 400,000 years we
all know where these data come
from Ice cores the ice the bubbles in
ice and if you look at the top you can
see how CO2 fluctuates over the years
from 400,000 years of current time and
so does the temperature very much
aligned CO2 decreases temperature
decreases CO2 increases temperature
increas es and of course here we are in
current times going off the
chart where does it come from
Transportation about a third electricity
production any idea how many cars are
produced per day on the
planet I just
forgot okay I'll make something up I
think it's like 180,000
day here we go how many flights
commercial flights a
day
93,000 these are things we take you know
we enjoy there's my 93 Volvo up there I
still drive that I drive so electricity
industry but agriculture in the US
contributes about 10% of greenhouse
gases worldwide it's more like 18 to 20%
so it's not always fair to Pro Point
one's finger at agriculture as a major
yes it's a contributor but there's a lot
of other sources of these greenhouse
gases so let's just summarize we've
gained about 1 and A2 degrees
globally it's warming twice as fast at
the
poles the idod the dog sled race every
year now they're concerned they'll even
have it and they keep moving further
north 2001 2010 the hottest decade 15
the hottest year this year will surpass
all previous years hotter Summers warmer
Winters nights are warming faster than
days the rate of warming is very fast
we're going to gain as much heat in the
next 100 years as we have since the last
ice age and again you can't turn this
off even if we sto and really behave
today it'll take hundreds if not
thousands of years to sort of
equilibrate and the distinction between
climate and weather weather is what's
happening outside today over shortterm
climate is decades in length so we Face
a challenge a Grand Challenge
the
evidence with a few exceptions when I
did my Ted X talk we looked for great
pictures of glaciers and we had this
beautiful one I thought let me check and
was actually highlighted because it was
one of the few glaciers that's actually
growing we didn't use that picture
Glaciers are melting um worldwide this
is an important source of irrigation
water and chili in a lot of other
countries uh if you haven't been to
Glacier National Park I suggest you get
there soon because the glaciers will be
gone in about 20 years and talking to my
daughters about where they want to go
next year and they want to go to Glacier
Park while the Glaciers are still
there this is summer sea ice the Arctic
this is a actually I looked just today
at where we are with uh retreating sea
ice in the summertime it rapidly freezes
over and is rapidly freezing right now
but this is an image of in September and
you can see it's about 700,000 square
miles less than it should be when you
compare to historical records so here's
an example of where solar radiation
comes in it's absorbed by that deep blue
ocean warms the water melts more ice you
get
it there's actually uh and a concern as
the passage is open here because it will
well one there's a military concern
because of more Russian and Chinese
transport but also invasive species that
exist in buges and ships because the
ships are going to get from point A to
point B much faster there's a likelihood
of more of those kind of invasives being
moved around the
planet oceans are changing 30% more
acidic than they should be the rising
thermal expansion accounts for about a
third of that much more comes from
melting GLA
glaciers obviously I think most
everyone's aware the acidification is
affecting shell forming
organisms how many have hugged a
redwood kind of hard not to
right uh these are these the largest
creatures on Earth living no okay well
they're big they're massive and they're
hard not to
hug so in the Sierra
invasive species and other plants are
moving up the sieras because of warming
conditions so someone asked a question
what about the Redwoods well it turns
out they're just this narrow band of
perfect soil conditions for the Redwoods
so in time they're already under stress
but in time they will be compromised by
warming temperatures even these Grand
creatures so let's talk about
agriculture and food security with all
these changes it's no longer business as
usual there's more variability more risk
the impacts are local local to Global
food production is moving North we've
essentially shifted close to one
planting zone North this obviously has
impact for farmers in Manitoba where
they've expanded grain
production growing seasons are longer
we've gained about 10 days here out west
it's more 19 the Northwest 16
days but that doesn't necessarily mean
additional growing days for Farmers
because of more extreme weather
we're having wet spells in the
spring or in the fall that interferes
with Harvest or
planting some of our farmers are
uh I heard Dave wolf mentioned this a
while back where they're splitting their
planting they get in early while they
have a dry period early spring with a
long season corn and then they'll wait
for the sort of the the wet spell and
then they'll come in with a short
seasoned corn later on so they still get
a
crop and we're having more heavy
precipitation of events especially in
the Northeast were up
71% there was um Libby pumpkin which
grows 90% of their excuse me grows
almost all their pumpkins within 90
miles of their processing facility in
Illinois in 2012 they had a very wet
spring in
2014 a very wet fall uh which meant
planting or harvesting of pumpkins was
compromised I think in 2012 they had
about half the crop the nor wood and
they produce almost all the pumpkin f
pie filling in the US this is
serious we're talking about pumpkin pie
filling but it's an example of
diversification spread out your risk
don't plant all your pumpkins close to
the
plant and this is a quote from a farmer
uh we've done some videos of farmers
interviewing them their perceptions of
climate change and just happen to go to
this this Farm right after a heavy
downpour and he had lost $80,000 worth
of Al Alpa seed he had just planted it
but with the Heavy Rain everything was
washed away as a farmer you can weather
the storm but you can't weather
continuous
storms panan in 2014 they had 5 Ines of
rain and 4 hours ice slip Down The Long
Island had 18 in in 24 hours there more
of these U events are
occurring and this is where I really get
into the climate change for job security
dir sake they're more insects excuse me
the likelihood of with longer Seasons
more Generations uh new inv bases coming
in the bottom the corn near worm down
here what is a pest primarily of sweet
corn historically when I started that
Cornell it was a late season
corn late season pest now it's here year
round presumably because now it can
overwinter last week there was a forum
in Washington DC on uh climate and Pest
and I heard Lou zisa a weed scientist
talk about some of his work and it was
just
amazing he found a he had a call from
someone in the ARs lab and say we got
this old seed that's like 60 years old
should we throw it away and he said ah
yeah sure then he went wait a
minute that seed those plants grew under
much lower CO2 levels than what we have
today and he did some comparisons there
clearly the the weeds have evolved but
he summarized his talk like this
preliminary suggests that weeds May
impose greater limitations on Crop
Production than earlier assumed the
worst weeds often wild relatives of crop
may be able to better adapt to increase
CO2 and temperature associate with
future
changes at the same time adaptation
among wild weedy lines may serve as a
means to enhance adaptation of
cultivated lines Especial Especially
serial lines to increase production as
CO2 increases so we're going to both be
fighting weeds but also learning from
them and there were several other
stories at this form on crop
diseases and even insects were there
just some of these subtle but kind
of uh scary changes that are
occurring this is an interesting
prediction looking forward the gray band
is
historical high and low average
temperature by Year from roughly 1850 50
to current times and here's projections
the red line would be business as usual
worst case scenario and what it shows is
by
2050 the
coldest Year we will experience will be
above any high temperature we've ever
pre previous 150 years we're moving
the temperature
band and here here we go watch carefully
this is average temperatures from the
1800s to 2100 this is going to show uh
increasing temperatures over the next
years now we're not supposed to go by 2°
C that will happen at roughly
2028 and by the end of the century we're
past 5 degre
steep want to see that again
I have to one
2:00
no one
11 all right we'll go through this one
more
time
okay that's looking forward in
temperature let's look forward in
precipitation patterns just find New
York on the map and you'll see it's
darker blue and thatched that means
we'll have generally increase in overall
precipitation annual precipitation in
the winter and the
spring fall so so summer is a little
drier but then look at the
Southwest it's going to get drier and
drier and
drier does that mean that we here in the
Northeast have an opportunity to
actually diversify and expand
agriculture because we will have water
in the coming
years now if anybody body follows Toby
Alor there's two papers one in 2015 and
one in
2016 this is the risk of a mega drought
a mega drought is 35 years in length or
greater the two the arrows point to
megga droughts were U civilizations
collap in in the southwest back in 1150
and about 1300 because of long-term
droughts but the odds of us having a
mega drought went from the first page to
80% to 99% in the
southwest that has an extraordinary
impact on agriculture in California
agriculture in Mexico and U just
communities there and cities as
well and you know if you can make a
dollar on something why not there's a
beer called Global warmer it's actually
a very good beer it's seasonal I have no
idea why it's seasonal CU I can't always
get it but the little on the back it
said extended Refrigeration at retail
magnifies beers carbon footprint please
enjoy as soon as
possible comes in a four pack okay let's
go out to dinner so growing food is
changing Supply chains are changing
price volatility is increasing and I had
the opportunity three four years ago to
actually meet with the president of
craft food at that time she's a Cornel
Alum and I brought up climate change and
she paused and
said price volatility is is costing us
about $3 billion a year we're a big
company but that's a lot of money so
this is a business issue as
well we got to start with the right
ingredients for a good
meal agava grown in Northern Mexico and
it's been subject to the drought it's a
10-year crop it's under severe pressure
we're messing with
tequila cor trees around the
Mediterranean with higher temperatures
the bark is changing and they make like
a billion corks a year it's a big deal
but if you drink really good stuff that
where the cork is important because
there's a breathability issue uh that's
changing so your product will be
different and they're
considering synthetic corks Etc but the
cork trees are changing which is having
an impact on this these kind of
beverages um olives some are grown in
California
but the point there is California is
starting to lose its Winter Chill which
is essential for fruit in many nut crops
and in the longer term UCF did a report
and I think they're going they said
they're going to lose about 40% of their
Winter Chill by the middle of the
century that's going to affect plums
peaches pears apricots grapes you name
it in the longer term that's a kind of a
ominous change or subtle change in the
background that a lot of people don't
fully appreciate
if you're producing uh whiskey in
Kentucky the angel is getting a bigger
share there's evaporation through the
oak barrels the oak oak barrels are
stored essentially out of doors
in there the term they're buildings but
they're open to the outside so as
temperatures increase there's more
evaporation and more loss of alcohol
through the Oak and it's actually enough
that they're getting a little worried
and they call let the Angels share well
at least the angels are happy
okay salad uh avocado production in
California will be off about 40% in 30
years because of increasing temperatures
it's hard to grow organic tomatoes in
this part of the world now because of
these early heavy downpours and the risk
of Lake light so they have to be grown
under
plastic if you're going to grow lettuce
in Selena Valley in the future you'll
probably need to switch to more uh heat
tolerant varieties uh wine is affected
because grapes are very sensitive to
temperatures changes so that's going to
affect California grapes and maybe be an
advantage for us grain production
worldwide is off a little because of
more extreme in
weather lobsters off the coast of Maine
they've moved North 50 mies the oceans
off the coast of main are warming eight
times faster than most any other place
on the planet it's also affected the
shrimp industry which is pretty much
crashed if there were saffron in this
rice most saffron has grown in Iran but
about 10 to 15% is from Kashmir and
India because of changes in
precipitation patterns and temperatures
they're going out of business and it's
affecting thousands of farmers in that
part of the
world and I I don't even want to talk
about this one but yes
coffee it happened to be in Costa Rica
as I mentioned a few years ago and walk
through some coffee plantations and you
know it's getting warmer and warmer so
they simply move up the side of the
mountains a little further but obviously
they're going to run out of space
uh cof there's a coffee bore spreading
worldwide in part related to climate
change that's also impacting industry uh
vanilla grown on the coast of Madagascar
is moving Inland because of more storms
increased Transportation cost of cocoa
probably move from Western Africa to
Central and South America so the point
is if you go to next time you go to
restaurant just look at the all that's
available to us and changes occurring
but what
if you're in a country poor where
agriculture is rainfed and you really
have limited resources so this we Face a
food security challenge globally it's a
national security challenge it's a moral
challenge there are arguments that the
war in Syria started because of a
long-term drought started driven by
climate
change and actually a few years ago
there was a conference on
campus Chris Barrett L it this was not
the one that really big one last year
but about four or five years ago was
actually funded by the
CIA they do that um and they publish
they're in the background but I was part
of that sort of background dialogue
which was kind of
interesting so I was had the honor
privilege of being in Vietnam in March
and here's a country the makon 17
million people living 5 ft above sea
level they're already affected by
saltwater intrusion and some other
complications but it's a land and a
people on water which is just remarkable
to watch but you can also Envision what
would happen what will happen with sea
level rise and they have also 2,000
miles of
Coastline it's a beautiful country if
anybody gets a chance to go there just
remarkable and wonderful people and just
for the record we're actually planning
to take students here in January and one
of the internationalizing Cornell
curriculum programs to spend two weeks
in the
makon food secur is in the News Press
picks this up sharp swings in ingredient
prices we're aware of so on so there's
this concern in the food
industry and another example of uh a
potential conflict with Rising Waters in
Bangladesh and changing temperatures in
India movement of people
in multiple countries with nuclear
weapons and it's a moral issue I'm sure
you've heard the pope came out in
support of getting her act together
there have been religious summus the Dal
Lama har Desman 22
Etc all right we take a breath we get
pretty depressed overwhelmed by all of
this so I guess we could move we could
ignore deny we're too busy it's actually
in part not in our DNA we're not
responsive to threats that are far in
the future or somewhere else we're more
of the immediate we respond to immediate
threats and generally life is good and
we're busy leave me
alone so a call to
action and if it's a short book written
by Mary Piper it's called The Green Boat
and She lays out and it's her personal
story on how she as one person person
made a change related to climate change
it was actually related to
energy become aware listen to the
science accept
it this was the O shoot moment or
otherwise and
enact and I love this quote from Zorba
the Greek To Live is to roll up your
sleeves and embrace trouble and I think
we've got something to put our arms
around right here at
Cornell so I'm going to talk about some
of the things going on here at Cornell
both on the sort of the academic side
but also the operations facility
side I think you're all aware this is a
land grant but in particular we have
Incredible strength in climate change
and agriculture we have
much uh capacity beyond that but we have
particular strength at the Nexus of
climate change and
Agriculture and I made a list of some of
the things going on and there's many
more um strength and PL breeding soil
Health nutrient
Management Hot cows give less milk I
sometimes show a picture of some
research out of UC Davis and it shows a
picture of a dairy cow on a platform and
there's a shower the cow is getting a
shower and the the idea was a cow comes
in gets the shower cools off and leaves
trouble is the cows didn't leave they
just stayed there so they had to put a
little kicking device to get cows to
move on we have exceptional talent in
communication and climate change water
management IPM Etc we have the Northeast
climate center it's a collaborative
environment it's the right place to take
on this
challenge we have the Atkinson
Center Innovative research they have a
climate Forum making connections through
topical
lunches some new initiatives the US
climate change hubs created in
2014 there's actually a sub subhub on
campus at the ar ar facility um but
their their agenda is to bring all
parties together land grants extension
stakeholders non or NGS Etc and
coordinate their efforts there's also
the relatively new Cornel Institute for
climate smart Solutions which focuses
primarily on agriculture right now the
climate smart farming
program this is an example of what
happening the climate smart Farm
extension team this is the first in the
country where six of our Educators
actually have part of the responsibility
is to work on climate change they're
distributed around the state they have
different responsibilities most are with
regional
teams and the other thing being
developed by The Institute are tools
there's a growing degree day tool we
don't do it these are the faculty and
programmers Etc we help facilitate this
there's a freeze risk tool and somewhat
relevant to this drought for this last
year there's also an irrigation
scheduler that looks out 30 days and
gives probability about uh plant stress
given different scenarios and you can
put in soil type you can put in crop
type you can put in location and it'll
give it for your particular this kind of
prediction for your particular Farm or
location so Cornell walking the walk I'm
not sure sure how many follow this but
we are now committed to carbon
neutrality by
2035 that's a really big deal it's a
really big
challenge we have a climate action plan
that's been around for several years
that has something like 60
recommendations to help us get to a
lower carbon
footprint uh two years ago there was an
acceleration working groups and how do
we speed that all up I Cod shared that
more recently there's a senior
leadership campus committee that just
released their report a couple weeks ago
on how to get us to carbon neutrality as
mentioned early on there's also the
president sustainable campus committee
they have responsibility
for implementation of a lot of these
recommendations and as an institution
we're a living laboratory faculty and
staff can work on these issues together
and it's a big
place 21,000 students 1,600 faculty
8,000 staff 600 buildings 2,000 acres of
land 25,000 light
switches
annual here's this summarizes the
greenhouse gas emissions this is
basically 2008 to 2014 in 2010 we went
from coal L heat and power plant runal
gas so this shows the combustion
emissions obviously dropped in 2010 when
we got off coal
we have to buy electricity but we're
buying less after 2010 because now we
produce a lot of
it commuting is a big deal lot a travel
Believe It or Not sports teams do a lot
of
travel air travel and then some of this
is offset a little bit by Forest
sequestration and the fact that
uh we're also selling on occasion
electricity
and um this shows the net emissions
essentially a 30% decrease over that
time span and at the same time an energy
conservation initiative helped the
campus actually grew by about
20% Mike why does it appear that it has
gone back
up unusually cold winter in
2014 thank you okay I'm going to bear
with me what
time 10 minutes okay all right I'll just
summarize rather quickly what has been
done I think you're familiar with Lake
Source cooling this has reduced energy
use to cool the campus by
86% combined heat and power plant if
anybody ever had a chance to tour that
it's essentially two
747 jet
engines running on natural
gas they're producing electricity and
the heat the exhaust creates steam it's
all captured instead of
wasted solar power if you fly in and out
of Etha airport I'm sure you've seen the
solar array out there there's now one at
Geneva I think the blackout project the
wind project is has the green light I'm
not absolutely sure but Cornell is one
of the few if not the only universities
in the world or the US that has a
hydroelectric plant produces all of 1%
of our
electricity it used to produce all of it
lead
buildings anybody know what's wrong with
the the gates building right there you
see those
spins they're directly
connected by metal to the inside so
there's a transfer of heat out or called
in and out and you know this is one of
the things that changing with the new
codes don't bear with me don't let Deans
and architect put up buildings you need
an energy person there as well
because they got to look pretty and you
know Etc uh energy conservation if you
play tennis they put new lights out
there saving a lot of money about
$20,000 per year in energy cost and
there's a about 50 buildings on campus
have the stash board so I went this
morning and I checked on Bradfield
probably not the best building to do
this and how much energy was used but so
far this week starting Monday at 12:00
a.m. to roughly a few minutes ago uh
40,000 kwatt hours of electricity for
Bradfield um $3,600 in cost and 36,600
lb of CO2 to operate that building for
the entire year it cost about $300,000 a
year you can this is pretty easy pretty
handy you can go in and type in any
building it gives kind of immediate
feedback on energy use in a building not
only electricity but also chilled water
and uh
heat um this is a we reflec the energy
conservation these are new buildings
that were built over the year the dark
line is Square footed Square uh gross
square feet you can see the quite an
increase from the year 2000 to
2016 this is steam sails
flat electrical sails
flat chilled water flat despite a very
large increase in our number of
buildings and square footage just
reflects the effort that the facilities
and sustainability office put into this
so the carbon neutrality by 2035
typically these are driven by financial
reasons this is a quadruple bottom line
does a solution help Cornell fulfill its
academic Mission and purpose does it
meet the needs of the people on campus
and the communities will it enhance
overall prosperity for the campus in our
region does it support a sustainable
Planet it also
includes natural gas and the leakage
issue solutions for tomorrow the big one
is Earth sort Heat digging down about 2
mies to tap the warmth and uh Deep Rock
and using that to in part heat the
campus there's heat pumps nuclear was
actually considered or we can just buy
our way out of this through
offsets that's looking in the longer
term this is a depiction
of also called Deep Rock geothermal
going down 10 to 30,000 ft this is not a
trivial investment very expensive and it
be initially
experimental more short term what do we
do build more high performance buildings
concern energy uh switch over as much as
possible to electrical vehicle increase
our capacity there's this thing called
think big live green which is
um really all of us participating in
doing what we can in our offices and
labor Laboratories there's also a campus
climate huh not campus campus literacy
it's climate campus literacy
I personally don't think anybody should
graduate from this institution without
being fully aware of climate change
means to their
life it's a living laboratory and
uh this climate literacy is the why
we're doing
it and there's two working groups that
are going to be formed one focused on
climate literacy how do we incorporate
more of that into experiences for
students and our staff and faculty and
also a group coming together and how do
we really change Behavior behavior and
when I say group these are the faculty
working with staff The Faculty have the
expertise and I have a personal issue
with
windows open when it's 100°
outside this one's pretty close to
home this is Kennedy one day I walked up
to Kennedy and Robert's Hall and there
were 13 windows open and the AC's
running hello Newman I'm in the gym my
hair is getting messed up because the
air conditioner is blowing so
hard the door's wide
open some of the stuff the simple
Behavior changes could really make a
difference I would just love to have a
group of students having the opportunity
to wander on campus and just start sort
of grading occupants these are really
simple things but in fact they're
they're game changers um is it possible
for the faculty to work with staff to
make these kind of changes this is Cal's
green that happened in
2011 energy conservation in several
buildings the winner was Barton lab in
Geneva but in one year we saved about2
200,000 $23,000 in energy cost 2 million
pounds of
CO2 those are the simple things as the
experiment station which I was director
of we adopted a culture
sustainability where people were
empowered to find better ways of doing
things there was actually a sustainable
action team one of the things they did
on their own was to reduce the
greenhouse footprint by 25,000 ft saving
a college $300 to $400,000 a year they
also designed a better growth chamber
that uses 85% less
energy
so it's a Grand
Challenge we can tackle this if we have
the will and look what we've
accomplished as a species
art disease gone to the Moon we have
these things called iPhones technology
agriculture engineering
we can do remarkable things but we have
to decide we really want to do
it so I challenge all of us get informed
stay inform accept the truth making it
personal
helps leading is also a good thing and
raise your
voices and it's personal two alums from
Cornell 06 and Tim when they look back
what are they going to say why didn't
they take action
thank
you um could you go back to the slide
that was on the solutions for the future
I just didn't it all
I did um what what are the current
thoughts about which one of these
solutions would be best the big one is
for S heat if
um yes very expensive to install Etc but
it's essentially the energy the heat
from the earth is free and it's just
just circulating and G know capturing
that heat clusion bringing it up and
it's hot water wouldn't be steamed but
that hot water then is of the turbans
have starting with cold water and
heating that up they already got hot
water to go in um they would also
potentially change the entire meeting
system on campus from Steam to H water
which would be another investment but
that if it works it can be replicated is
a real game changer and that's longer
term Mike great talk um thanks for great
bringing up Brad all I think most people
don't realize how terrible that building
is the worst building with the highest
um energy cost on campus because of the
any he or air conditioning that comes in
goes directly out and so finally they
it's going to be handled but the comment
I wanted to make is is related to the
buildings in General on campus Because
the problem is that when buildings get
upgraded or new buildings get
constructed there is this apparent need
to have Platinum lead and to have these
beautiful buildings but at the cost of
the older buildings that that never get
a turn to to be upgraded so you get this
it's nice to have all the these
buildings um but if you spend $120
million on one building that means that
other buildings like Brash and
Emerson you know stay the same and and
is a pretty awful working environment as
well and that's a
problem St nucular in countries like
Germany
me what's your stance on nuclear energy
and countries like Germany moving away
from given the threat of climate change
I am an advocate for nuclear energy
however there's also these new Breer
reactors which are smaller and produce
distributed energy production which we
be much better Direction and I'm
thinking that's where James Hanson wrote
his book scoring my grandchildren and
that's essentially his the his story is
we need reinvest
in newer technology and the breedo
reactors use existing nuclear waste as a
s of fuel breeder is that what you
said so the Deep Rock Energy mention has
that been you said it was a little
experimental have other larger
institions done it work great an Iceland
an Iceland you don't have to go very
cute yeah and I think there are some
experimental and so part of the
experiment here is they're not sure how
deep they have to
go if I understood one of the graphics
that you showed for uh climate
predictions it shows that this part of
the country is predicted to have more
precipitation uh on the other hand the
temperature is also increasing so that
will drive more rapid evaporation
what's the net effect are we going to
have more likelihood of drout events or
less um
globally we going to be a 30 fold
increase in Ry events I understand it
not that much here but it's just more
extremes um but yes more precipitation
higher temperatures and increasing
frequency of drops but then there's also
these increasing incidents of heavy
downard yeah more Extreme More
VAR my background is atomic spectroscopy
and some p and um I think talk was
really good I think we need really need
to focus on adaptation and I think
sometimes people can get distracted by
the
CO2 effect because the new calculation
show doesn't take much CO2 to raise the
temperature
and those say that the new calculations
coming out doing at you doing
spectroscopy analysis so I think in even
keeping the um carbon neutrality is very
important but it could be as low as this
effect could be seen is as low as 50
parts per million carbon dioxide so that
means it's that makes it really scary
because it's not going to take much just
any more increase in solar radiation and
our temperatures are going to keep going
up so I just might don't get too
distracted by this CO2 okay and don't so
we can focus on adaptation
y i I gave a talk yesterday I give one
tonight give one tomorrow too and
there's another side of this because you
also see we're also seeing more and more
solar and contributing more to Electric
production I I want to There's Hope here
yeah ter that comes up and actually
mention presal called Clean Coal can you
highlight that what that is it
I'm sorry I'm
being right that's the idea is it's
lower
sulfur yeah some of the other
contaminants but not NE
CO2 um I think if I understood you
correctly you said that the contribution
of Agriculture to greenhouse gas
emissions in the US is lower than the
world yeah we're about 10% globally it's
18 to 20
is that because the differences in
agriculture or is that because in other
places they
like Transportation
lower I think in far is agriculture
because of rice production is anybody
help me out on that well agriculture is
a large part of the GDP for a lot of
those countries we have also a lot of
energy use in Industries that's probably
a prim for Reas it's just relative right
it is so much actual change in the
agriculture it's more that
right yeah another problem with those
statistics is there's a lot of embodied
energy and embodied greenhouse gas
emissions in what we import so actually
our footprint is much larger than it
appears if you just analiz the emissions
country by
country it is disproportionate though
10% of our
GDP agriculture is not 10% of our GDP is
much less it's like 3% or 4% dis still a
disproportionate impact on
agriculture so thank you for the
presentation I thought it felt really
nice to know like we can all do these
small parts to decrease our own energy
usage
but if it is if we do our small part
that it is such an insignificant part of
still and that we're all operating in
this very high energy environment we
justify it because we are working in
things like better climate change
farming and and we're all working
towards some greater goal but what is
quel University doing as an institution
to
systematically change this high
energy
output well I tried to share as much as
I could what Cornell is doing referring
on the operation side
um do a lot more
but ad of like the university as
a you know you're talking to the person
at C but who else is Cornell talking to
there is some major
players I'm going to slee around this
wait I'm
sorry I just happened to look at some
upper Administration positions across
the country proos
being climate change is not included in
those
job I me find that Prett sad um I
think we have trustees that don't
believe in
clim I I wonder like when you think
about okay that the Southwest is going
to you know get Dr an AG culture is
going to be moved um to another
centralized somewhere else I guess I
fear that we will just repeat the same
issues with centralized agriculture I
mean maybe we'll have new energy sources
and things like that but we'll still
have this great demand to move stuff
around uh for fertilizer for you know
all that stuff like so it feels like to
me is or I guess I question are there um
as many efforts going towards some kind
of I know that it's happening at a
Grassroots level um to see decentralize
some of Agriculture but I do have this
spere that will just move it somewhere
else and still have the distribution
question Transportation cost and all
that sort yeah yeah and you know energy
need
yeah Harold knows the answer
that um let's hope not uh I mean I just
we're the process of trying to put
together a USDA proposal right now that
looks at the Northeast
and preparing for climate change and it
has transportation components that has
the whole food chain involved we trying
to get them all in the room kind of
layout scenarios of what it's going to
look like in the future and how do we
work
together that's my answer it's very
complicated enormous amounts of money a
lot of food growing maybe in the wrong
places and then you think of global
shocks
um you know what what if California
agriculture does collapse there in 2060
what does that mean globally where's the
say newk going to get it food there
actually I would contract contacted a
while back by someone in y York City
trying to find a group of a Consulting
Group that would come in and help them
understand where the food come from
because of
PL the that's kind of the driver if you
get Metropolitan are asking those
questions then we can make some change
one thing I
say seems to me like some some work well
work to would just be in the on the
consumer level about this idea of eating
locally and not eating everything every
season you know
that's one more like we have a
greenhouse and hoop house operation so
we're trying to do it centrally we have
a corn burn stove and a p stove so we
cance and we're selling out of all of
our Tomatoes you know so local
production because you can make it fresh
you can have it taste good so it still
tastes all of its flavor and of all its
nutrients and if it's done Lo it is a
way to adapt to the climate change and
it does work well and Market it as lower
carbon footprint and selling all
out all right let's thank
M again this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu