this is a production of Cornell
University over the last 20 years or so
I've been obviously doing a lot of work
on Photo receptors and the phototropins
and I got kind of sidetracked and uh
that's what I'm going to talk about
today because we discovered that there
were some interesting things going on in
guard cells that for us at least were
quite unexpected perhaps not to others
and so um we'll just
continue um we're going to be talking
about stomal
function but I thought I'd give a little
bit of early history um for example of
way back in uh 1836 uh Charles doony at
Cambridge
University did a very interesting
experiment and I'll show you his
experimental setup in just just a minute
but he showed that blue light was much
better than red light in inducing plants
to lose water and to my knowledge this
is the first actual observation of a
specific effect of blue light on guards
on stomal function although obviously he
didn't know anything about that at the
time
um then in
1898 um Francis Darwin invented a little
device called a parameter and first
demonstrated that light increased the
rate at which you could pull air through
a leaf again uh indicative of some
change in the physical properties of the
leaf that allowed
more gas movement
across um it was long
assumed however despite this experiment
by Dominy showing blue light to be so
effective it was assumed that stomal
opening was strictly responding to
photosynthesis and after all we have
chloroplast in guard cells so why not
and it was only
much much much later that agava showed
that blue light alone doesn't have much
of an effect in increasing transpiration
but against a red light background the
effect is spectacular and you got a huge
increase in transpiration and then uh
Zyer and field refined the measurements
and demonstrated that it was highly
specific for blue light and as we know
now it's a response mediated by the the
phototropins well here was uh daan's
very ingenious experiment
he used various colored glass and he
used also some uh solutions that were
colored and simply measured he would put
concentrated sulfuric acid which is of
course hydroscopic takes up water and
he'd weigh it and then he would put it
under a Bel jar and uh turn the light on
and when he turned when he turned blue
light on he got a much bigger increase
in the weight of the sulfuric acid over
time than if he turned the red light on
incidentally he also also noticed
something else and that was that red
light was far more effective than than
blue in inducing what he described as
the secretion of green matter into the
leaves which of course was that he was
seeing for the first time the
development of of chlorophyll
transformation of prot chloride to
chlorophyllide and then all of the
phytochrome responses that follow that
to get mature chloroplasts so this was
just a nice piece of work that got
totally
lost um so this is again the first
report of a blue light response guard
cell function then here is dorwin
Francis Dorn's
parameter um you take a leaf and then
you seal a little suction cup there and
hook just hook it up to a
uh Durette like this and then you
measure the rate at which the liquid
drops and of course if you turn the
light on then uh the stom open the guard
cells separate and the rate at which it
drops increases and then you turn the
light off and it goes back down again a
a very elegant very simple demonstration
again which has been pretty much
lost
um more recently uh we identified
phototropins and uh one of them f one
eventually derell it all with the first
to identified the second phototropin and
then can it all in uh shimazaki lab in
Japan demonstrated that both fot one and
fot 2 mediate light activated snow metal
opening so now we've come to the point
where we can actually identify the photo
receptors involved in the light response
first described by Charles
doony well um in the last three decades
or so we've learned a tremendous amount
of about Stow metal development um a
number of different people working on
this and uh the genes that are
responsible the transcription factors
involved we've also another totally
unrelated in many ways we've learned a
tremendous about the ion pumps and
channels that are involved in sowal
opening and
closing uh we' learned now about the
specific role of abic acid and closing
but there's not a whole lot of work uh
that's been done on the role a possible
role of the cytoskeleton in stomal
function but particularly not
microtubules there been there are some
very nice studies from Young so Le in
Korea on on actin changes with stomal
opening and closing and other papers
since then but not
particularly so let me let me now
digress slightly because we got
interested in stom in uh quite
indirectly um things happen to
phototropin when you turn the light on
and of course one of the first things to
happen is that you get extensive
phosphorilation um second thing we now
know that you get can get binding of a
1433 protein to a particular seran in
fot 2 highly specific um we know that
you can get mon idation um here uh
probably other places too according to
Lum and this is all work that was done
by a longterm post. s in the lab um so
here's phototropin structure you have uh
a serin 3 and in kinas a classic Ser
three serin 3 and inise and then you
have two domains of about 100 amino
acids which B A flaven which is the
chromophor and both phototropins have
this
structure um when you turn the light on
saturation these are all the different
uh amino acids that are
phosphorilated um the ones in blue were
discovered by the Japanese group the
ones in Black were discovered by John
group and the ones in red were ones each
time you do this you pick up different
ones we've just done another um Mass
Spec experiment and we picked up three
more that haven't been reported so I
think the number of phosphor relations
that occurs with light saturation
probably is not yet completely
identified okay well one of the things
that Don Chung did was yeast to hybrid
and he found that f 2 was associating
with the A1 subunit of uh PP of a
protein phosphatase pp2a and both um by
East to Harbor and by pull down so then
the question is well um is that
phosphotase going to play a role in uh
actually could show that it was the love
domain that was apparently where the
binding was occurring and not the kise
domain um so we hypothesized the blue
light would induce
phosphorilation and with a wild type
enzyme um then you could inactivate and
so that this was a way to deactivate the
system after after
photoactivation however we hypothesized
that if you had an impaired phosphotase
then you should actually at steady state
increase the amount of the active um
phosphorated
phot2 and it was clear that phosphor was
required for for normal function and if
that's the case then we might expect uh
first phototropism might be more
sensitive um and stomal aperature at
steady state might be in fact wider and
so when we looked at phototropism sure
enough if we got got rid of fot two I'm
sorry got rid of phot one so that we
were just looking at f 2
behavior um in the absence of the in the
impaired activity of the phosphatase not
only did we get a more rapid phototropic
response but we actually got more
curvature um more curvature over time
so the um that indicated we then looked
at guard cells here they are um closed I
won't show you the um quantitation but
here's what it looks like when they're
normally open but in the absence of in
the absence of functioning phosphatase
with the mutant phospatase note that the
guard cells are far wider open than they
are in the wild type so in both cases it
appears that the phosphatase is
downregulating the functional
molecule well it was interesting the
interaction between photot with
phototropin 2 affects phototropism in
storm aperature but no other pH to
mediated response that we tested uh they
were all absolutely the same with or
without that mutation in the phosphotase
and furthermore pp2a this same mutant
had no impact whatsoever when what we
looked at was phototropin one function
instead of phototropin 2
function well so our second brush with
guard cells that was our first our
second brush with guard cells had to do
with another of dong Chung's discoveries
from yeast to hybrid and that is that uh
there's a 14 three the Lambda isopor
interacts with photoactive phototropin 2
at a particular Serene at that uh seran
747 and again uh yeast to hybrid and
pull down uh um verifi that there was a
real
interaction and here you can see in this
case that the interaction is now
Downstream it's with the kyes domain
instead of with the uh the Upstream l
domains and here we found that snow
metal opening was in fact severely
impaired couple of experiments here it's
impaired except that when we can
complement put that put
the
um 14 wild type 1433 molecule back in
and we can restore nor normal stomal
function and in this case it was even
more highly specific in that this is the
only phenomenon the only phototropin
mediated phenomenon that we could find
that was impaired in the 1433 mutant
highly specific to just that one um
phosphorilation and
Association
um well in 2007 Bill eisinger joined the
lab he was a longtime uh professor at
Santa claro University where he didn't
it's an undergraduate institution and I
was lucky enough that he wanted to
continue doing research so he joined the
lab and he was interested in guard cells
and guard cells were affected by
photoactivating phototropin so uh our
interests were pretty much in common so
also I had a colleague Dave arhart who
had plenty of AR rabid officers that
were carrying gfp tubulin so we decided
it would be fun to look at the behavior
of the microtubules in guard cells as
they closed or opened and thanks to Dave
we have very very good confocal
microscopy so this was the initiation of
this
project and as you as I mentioned
there's this very large literature on
osmotic regulation of stom lature people
like Mike blat Sally asman Jordan Scher
and a number of others but only a
limited amount of information about the
possible role of the SOS skeleton
so as you know uh schemes like this have
been developing
and I find them understandable barely a
bit
confusing so here's what bill first saw
uh these are guard cells now expressing
gfp tubulin and you see that the tubulin
is in hoops around the perimeter of the
guard cells and now this is with a guard
cell wide open if we treat with abs
which induces closure um a couple of
things happen first you see there are
lots and lots of these microtubules and
it turns out the brighter ones are
probably bundles I'll come back to that
in a minute but over time the number of
those bundles that you can actually
resolve decreases gradually here's 30
minutes 40 minutes and also there's been
a loss in total florescence and this is
interesting because the monomer of the
of tubulin is just as fluorescent gfp as
is the polymer so there's a net loss of
tubulin and a rather significant loss of
tubulin over
time and then if you uh correlate stomal
aperture with the storm metal aperture
with the number of these things that you
can count um you see that there's a
pretty good relationship there pretty
clean relationship and uh when they
close the number of of aperture the
aperture closes and the time course for
the loss in uh structures that you can
resolve or goes down
simultaneously and then you can take
take these plants when they're closed
put put them from the light to the dark
they close the number of elements that
you can count goes down put them back in
the light they open and simultaneously
up on the number of those bundles that
you can see
so why the decline well maybe less
growing ends of the microtubules that's
one thing could happen maybe you have
the same number of growing ends but
they're growing more slowly this could
account for some of the loss you could
have more rapid degradation at the minus
ends or some combination of those
processes so let's take a look at the
growing ends and let's hope that this
works
um so we're going to be able to look at
the growing Ends by looking at a
different label and this is n binding
one gfp this is an a protein that's
found at the growing ends of
microtubules and let's
hope
oops Yeah so you see now this this is
just watching in time lapse and these
are the growing ends of those
microtubules and having this you can do
two things first in the first place you
can count the number of them and seconds
you can measure the rate at which
they're
moving and uh so we did that and this
would tell us maybe more
specifically they moving away from the
pardon are they all moving away from the
they're well they're moving in a
circular fashion it's difficult to tell
whether they're going under or over we
think that there are some going in both
directions but um that haven't really
studied that in any great detail but
here if we now look at the number of as
the as the guard cells close following a
uh ABA treatment Deuces closing very
nicely but it doesn't change the number
of comets these little comets that you
see flying around so the number of
growing ends doesn't change um just
showing the pavement cells along with
the guard cells um
and then if we look at the velocity um
closed versus open there's no difference
either they're going just as fast and
there are just as many of them so we're
left with the conclusion that they're
actually um undergoing differential
degradation at their minus
ends okay so the question of the
question then
becomes
well um do microt tubules play a major
role in noow Middle opening and closing
they're appearing when they open they're
disappearing when when they close um so
do they play a function roll or is this
just simply something passive that
happens as a consequence of opening and
closing and there are ways of testing
that um we can there are two drugs
aralin that we can use or I think kosine
does that too but arisol and
destabilizes microtubules and taxo
stabilizes them so we can try these
drugs and see what effect they have on
opening and
closing and in this experiment um we're
starting with them initially in the dark
we're putting putting the leaves into
the light and either visha or rabid
opsis you can see that the guard cells
open um on the other hand if we have
treated with a risin uh
the these structures don't reform as you
can see this this is just sort of messy
inside the cell and they don't open on
the other hand if we treat with taxol
they do open uh and they open relatively
normally uh if we now do the reverse
experiment going from light to dark
normally they would close in the dark
with a risin of course they do close and
you get the this same sort of mess but
in taxil they're stuck open so we
conclude therefore
that the microtuble changes that we
observe on stom opening and closing
these changes are required for normal
stomal
function one of the uh one of the
questions you might ask as well we've
transformed these plants and put
different stuff into the guard cells
than was there naturally so just maybe
uh We've interfered with um interfered
with transpiration so this is just a
classic o um water loss experiment uh
done with colleagues in the ecological
physiology group at carnegi and no
matter wild typ or any of these
transformance they're all behaving
perfectly normally so we don't need to
worry about
that well then Bill decided to try to
get a little more quantitative some of
the early pictures look like that you
could then draw a line and scan across
and get a little profile of
fluorescence um here's from the lower
cell and here from the top cell and then
you could do some exper some experiments
such as this where when you went into
ABA with open guard cells you notice
that the high peaks gradually decline in
fact they're virtually all gone after
whatever that is um 40 minutes whereas
in the pavement cells there's no
particular
change he then got more sophisticated or
I should say the equipment got more
sophisticated and now we have a better
uh better image and now you can take
this and rotate it um so that you're now
looking at the ends of the
microtubules of and the fluoresence from
the gfp and then you can uh draw a line
here and do a scan and You' got
something that looks like this and if
you sort of squinted this you could
convince yourself that there are some
Peaks that are down in here some Peaks
that are around in here and some Peaks
that are here so maybe this isn't going
to be a uniform series from from small
to large maybe they'll be uh uh discrete
steps now but for this particular one uh
you don't see that very well but every
once in a while we've got something that
looked like this and uh where the one
clearly was having a single a series of
increments and we interpret this as an
increase in in bundling as the uh the
total number doesn't decline all that
much when they close going down to here
going down to here um but the number of
high peaks drops down and it drops down
stepwise so we we uh interpret that as a
decrease in bundling we're going from
Singles here to doubles to triples to
quadruples and so forth and this
accounts for the difference in the
brightness of the fluorescence that you
see in those various
structures well
now Vin as I mentioned doesn't lose its
fluoresence as the monomer so what are
the possibilities it could be that loss
of fluoresence is like is likely
proteolysis if that's the case then if
we treat with something that'll inhibit
proteolysis just maybe we can block the
uh block stomal closing and inhibit the
fluorescence loss
likewise cop cop one is an E3 logas and
the cop one m
c one is involved in all kinds of things
going on in Plants but it was known that
uh c one mutation prevented stomal
closing so it might also prevent the
fluoresence loss um so here are a couple
of experiments that we could
do
um so we're
um first thing is if we inhibit
proteolysis with mg132 you can see that
uh the I don't have my glasses on but I
assume that that's uh yeah that's the
snow metal aperture uh they do indeed
they do not
close and if you uh look at fluorescence
the mg132 also very much impairs the
fluorescence laws that's essentially
reflects photo bleaching that occurs
under any
circumstances and again you can see that
in DMSO uh we go into AB a we lose the
structures whereas if we have mg 132
present um these guard cells don't
change particularly in the appearance of
the
microtubules
um okay um it turns out that uh a lot
more than just prote is involved in
closing because you can inhibit
transcription or translation um here's
another proteas inhibitor besides
mg132 and and again if you inhibit
transcription or translation you prevent
the closing reaction and they remain
open in ABA uh 40 after a 40 minute
treatment so there's a lot going on that
at least I hadn't we hadn't
expected and the other thing is what
about cop one well cop one uh as I
mentioned doesn't close incidentally if
you look at uh c one guard cells notice
that they're more nearly circular than
uh the um wild type y cells um and note
that in cop
one ABA you can Hammer them you can't
get them to close so they they are
essentially stuck open and uh not only
are they stuck open but the microtubules
are not uh Changed by the ABA treatment
so I guess that's consistent with what
we've seen
before yeah this shows the that's the
stom
aperature unchanged in C one and there
is the uh this is the fluoresence in cop
one with the controls here no different
that's just the bleaching whereas in the
uh in
the wild type cbone protein you see the
fluorescence loss again plus ABA over
the same time
course
well if we disrupt um c 1 six guard cell
microtubules of the rising can can we
get them to close and so we tried that
experiment and sure enough if we treat
them with arisal and they do indeed
close
um and now this is I've now qu dist
worked by rogin Canna who joined the lab
about 3 years ago on on fulltime and
then a part-time basis and is still
working with us on it and you notice
that if you treat now with ar Risin um
the cop one guard cells not not only do
they lose their microtubules but they
also close but now of course that could
be simply uh we may just maybe we just
killed the cells and with the inhibitor
so what happens if we try to wash it
out oh here's just a uh quantitation the
one to look at
is this one darker light with ar risal
in uh in cop
one uh they
close
there
um
so again did we just kill the cells or
in fact uh
can we recover them so if we do a wash
out um the the microtubules structures
reappear and they open back up again so
we haven't just killed the cells and
again it's it's fairly good evidence
that these microt tual changes are
indeed essential for opening and closing
of guard
cells okay now the question then becomes
does the cop one mut in any way affect
electrophysiology of the guard cells
because after all they do have to get
driven by osmotic changes
uh potassium has to move in for opening
uh has uh and all these other things
have to go on and for this we started a
collaboration with Julian scher's Lab at
UCSD and Jan jnan Lee uh was a postto
there who did these
experiments and here is the
thing I showed you at the very start and
there are two two important channels
that are worth mentioning there's this
potassium Channel which is essential for
opening and then there's a slow anion
Channel whoops yeah there's a slow an
Channel which is right here which is
required for closing um actually this is
a very much oversimplified diagram I
have another more recent one but it's AB
for me it was just absolutely
overwhelming so I chose chose the simple
one so required for closing required for
opening so let's take a look at the
behavior of those two channels and so
here's what happened when uh he looked
uh Jan looked at the potassium
Channel um cat
one in Wild type this is the behavior
that you get uh it's the usual uh
experiment voltage Uh current
plot and you notice that in C one it's
absolutely normal there's no impact
whatsoever on in C one on the potassium
Channel but to our surprise when we look
then at the slack one the slow anion
Channel um it was completely dead uh in
cop 1 in fact Its Behavior in the cop 1
mutant was about the same as what you'd
expect in a black one mutant um it was
essentially nonfunction
well that raises the question what's the
interaction between slap one and all
these microt tual studies in cop one and
what is the in fact what is the role of
these changes in in stomal
function um structural do they provide
some sort of structural contribution it
seems unlikely they're not all that
strong uh to be able to have a role in
changing the shape of the
cell um maybe they're transporting
vessicles to and from the plasma
membrane remember that these cells are
expanding out like in in our experience
in in C one for example where there
seems to be no closure the pair of guard
cells is formed something it's almost
circular but a circular pore whereas in
Wild type the arrangement is a bit more
elliptical and the POR is smaller
so it's as if there's a balance between
opening processes and closing processes
that gives you some sort of interim uh
intermediate state of opening and when
in the presence of cop 1 we kill the
closing process then we're only sealing
the consequence of the opening processes
and they are at their they're at their
most distended and in fact they're in a
in almost circular confirmation as a
result um
so um when you expand these cells we can
argue about this later on we're chatting
about the shape and so forth uh it looks
it appears that there's a an increase in
the outer surface the size the area of
the guard cells and this means that one
of two things either if you're going to
increase the surface
area at all either you have to make it
thinner or you have to add material and
so it could it be that the role of these
microtubules is to transport vesicles
containing proteins and more membrane
material for fusion with the plasma
membrane uh transport two on opening and
remove uh on
closing well one of the ways to look at
that then would be to look at what are
is the relationship between these
changes and slack one if we could get a
slack one uh fluorescent label we could
follow it so we started to do that and
these are the our most recent
experiments uh this is slack one
gfp and uh it's in the cop One Cop one
mutant so that these guys are wide open
and uh you can see here that the slack
one as you would expect of a channel is
pretty much localized to the to the
periphery of the cells
um and uh not much in the interior also
if you now look at and again these are
very preliminary pictures you see that
the arrangement um in the first place
it's near the Meridian of the cells uh
and it's more there than it is on the
upper and lower surfaces the surface
towards the air and the surface towards
the interior of the leaf but also it's
showing some kind of structure
um the question is when they're open
like this does that structure coincide
in any way with the microtubules um
because that would at least be a lead
that things that the microtubules could
be involved in moving stuff around well
what does it look like when they're
closed um what it looks like if we now
this is in the cop one for mutant but if
we now treat it with ar risal and to
close it remember we could close it then
we could treat it with washing out and
get it opened again um I think that's
shown in the next SL slide does the
distribution change with snowmetal
opening and closing and we're using C
one as our test system and you can see
the change is really rather dramatic
when they're
open the um slack one gfp is mostly
peripheral at the plasma membrane
whereas when they're closed it now is
very much internalized internalized in
what appear to be vesicles of some sort
the nature of which at the moment uh we
simply uh don't know um as I said this
these are all very recent well so what
the the next step now and one which
we're just starting is to get plants
that are expressing both a fluorescent
slack one and a fluorescent um
fluorescent tubulin but since what we
had was in both cases gfp that wasn't
going to work so we've had to work now
with different uh labels we finally have
just gotten some plants that are
expressing M ter tubulin which is a red
fluorescer and uh slack 1 gfp which is
the green
fuesser
and here's um here's last week's picture
uh this is the m cherry tubulin and the
slack one these are almost closed and
the picture here of course is just sort
of a mess but it's the very first
picture demonstrating that we do in fact
have the have double labeled uh um
fluorescent labeled um plants and we're
going to be able to take a look and do
time course studies and watch and see
whether indeed the microtubules are
involved in moving moving vesicles
around containing slack one and who
knows what else that's our operating our
working hypothesis at this point and uh
with that I'll have to
say there's clearly a lot more to do so
I'm looking forward to a lot of neat
pictures in the next six months um so
with that uh our I mentioned tongun who
did that earlier work looking at post
translational modification of
phototropin on photo exitation bill
eisinger who did the initial work on uh
the initial work on micr tubules and
then rajish all of this more recent
stuff our collaboration with Julian
schroer with thanks special thanks to
junin for making the um
electrophysiological
measurements and we're halfway up the
mountain but we still have 600 meters to
get to there from here and that's a
different mountain by the way um and we
have a lot more to do and people are
going to be busy I hope we're going to
be busy for a good longer and support
came from both carnegi and from the
National Science
Foundation and thank you very much for
your
[Applause]
attention
esac um fluoresence or channel in the
aninal plasma membrane only and not it's
it's largely in the an yeah we have have
other pictures of that alone and there's
a sort of a band band of it around uh
the
antiel
it subid yeah I'm I'm guessing we're
guessing that it's in fact in contact
with it's where it's in contact with the
surrounding epidermal cells and those
comets may be
bringing yeah the Comets could be could
be bringing stuff up that to deliver I
think we're in a position that with not
with my skills but with with David aarts
and Rines we might be able to to probe
that and find out whether that's really
what's going on yeah yeah the question
is whether the the hypothesized vesicles
that are going back and forth could have
some impact on the physical properties
of the cell wall i
i in you know just my gut feeling is
no I don't mean to reject it out of hand
but I think it's unlikely because the
the microtubules start out as being uh
as the guard cells develop of course
they're the microtubes are what
determine where the microfibrils are
and that this function that we're
hypothesizing is is a later one and it's
a
function for a mature cell you do know
that
calcium
can the elastic modul
and it's a reversible process there are
ways of testing that now there are ways
of testing the elastic module of a cell
wo and I've seen papers on that but uh
so it's something we thought about but
haven't haven't done it would be very
interesting to test just that notion I
think the techniques are out there
whether we have the skill to use them
properly or not per much to be seen got
to get NSF money for that
have you looked at the effect of blue
light on the microtubules in
theone because I think David SE blue
light affecting micr stability in cells
hyper that's right he gets he gets a A
really elegant reorientation of the of
the microtubules in the hypoc which is
clearly related to the change in the
growth pattern um well we what we see
specifically is that in Blue Light the
microtubules increase in uh number and
very much increase in bundling uh and
that's that's a blue light response not
other other photo receptors will
modulate that response but without
without the phototropins um you don't
get any light sensitivity at all for
stomal
opening see the takes about 40 minutes
so there's plenty of time for a lot else
to happen and I've may have said
something misleading when I said
the cop one is involved in the
degradation of the microtubules because
it could be involved in the degradation
of something else that then
plays you know it could be much more
complicated than
that no purely cor correlation and that
is that the fluorescence decline
parallels the uh parallels the time
course for closing and and rather
closely but I mean these are happening
in on a time scale of of many many
minutes so the time resolution simply
isn't good enough to say more than the
at this point it looks as if they're
closely
correlated better time resolution might
show that that's not necessarily the
case but that's a good
question and it caught me up because I
tend to be much too confident when I
talk about copon and proteolysis and
microtubules does not have to be uh
that the primary event could be
indirect ask one question so have you
shown polination of the of the
microtubules and and what what triggers
the polination what's the signal
transction pathway that triggers the
polynation I don't know about that for
uh for the microtubules I know that
there are these uquid Nation studies in
uh a phototropin itself but no I can't I
can't address that that's a prerequisite
for degradation by the prod yeah yeah
but we haven't looked at we simply
haven't looked at
that trival but the Peaks you had with
sort of half length and mic yeah what
were the width of those
Peaks well well what's what's the length
of the Guard cell uh I maybe 200 mic 200
microns so they could be those they
could be 100 the uh width of the cell a
micron or so but know they vary a
lot the bundles are going to be bigger
than that the singles in our earlier
experiments the resolution wasn't good
enough to see singles and that's why we
thought we were actually uh losing the
number of a large number of the
structures we're actually only losing a
small number but it just we going from
multiples to the singles thank you very
much for a
[Applause]
wonderful this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu