this is a production of Cornell
University and welcome to this uh
Symposium and honor Peter Davy's
contributions to Cornel over the last 46
years my name is Fred Beringer uh back
in the last Millennium I was a student
with Peter I was here from 85 to 90 and
I'm delighted to be here today to help
them see this event um first thing I'd
like do is introduce uh the chairman of
the section of plant biology Dr K have a
few words to thank
you okay uh I guess my job was to talk a
little about Peter and not to talk too
long about Peter and I made a few notes
to myself to make sure I covered every
aspect of of my interactions with Peter
I knew about Peter before I knew Peter I
missed him by a couple of years at Yale
but I knew of his eminence in the area
of plant physiology so I was delighted
to meet him here when I got to Cornell
Peter was then the chair of or soon to
be the chair of the plant biology
section u sounds the same but it's
different it was a smaller unit I did
then knew Peter as a member of The
Faculty of plant biology and ultimately
I got to know Peter as a of course as a
colleague and a friend I got to know
that he had a remarkable wife Linda who
was in intellectual force in her own
right I got to know that Peter was a
heck of a dad but twoo extremely
remarkable and accomplished children uh
and
uh their their
accomplishments exceed those that anyone
could have rationally hoped for in
life I'm still in a that most of my
colleagues it seems put pressure on my
kids I guess uh I know Peter as a a very
interesting teacher he has courage he
takes uh he was a good and Effective
Teacher in PL physiology for years but
toward the end of his uh plant
physiology teaching career he introduced
a course where he covered major events
in biology and the pop based on the
popular press and on things that were
happening at the
time I um I sat in on the course I to
reintroduce the course I was very
impressed by the courage Peter exhibited
in covering issues that are highly
controversial at times I was quite
impressed by the guests and the guest
lecturers we had in the course including
one of my favorite old Yale professors
who it turns out as a good friend of
Peter dick gold so uh that was a nice
thing about knowing Peter I also knew
Peter in the role as a wonderful host
and a fine colleague I like very much I
think today we'll see that I'm not the
only one that shares that very positive
view of Peter and his contribution with
Cornell and I'm happy to turn it over to
the
program thank you we're going to hear a
lot of nice things being said about
Peter today um I want to thank everybody
for coming today and um it's great that
you're all here to to honor Peter um I
see quite a few familiar faces but some
don't recognize um so I I think it's
um it's fair to say that uh all of you
have U benefited from from Peter in some
way or another in your career and uh
he's helped us learn and
grow different ways but if it was just
that I don't think we have this uh this
seminar here today because it wasn't
just how Peter helped us with our our
careers and learning profession it was
it was the way he did it and the simple
word for it it was just it was a lot of
fun to work with Peter um Peter brought
a lot of energy and positive uh thoughts
to all the work that I did with him um
he was
uh he made it fun to work he he uh was
open to new ideas and supported trying
new things
he
um gave everything did everything with a
healthy dose of humor and I think his
Hospitality to the people who have come
through his lab over the years is is
well know so um and the last thing is I
know that he kept the best interest in
mind of all the people he worked with
over the years so um those are my
Impressions that I think he'd share
those as well so um it's great that
you're all here as a way of showing some
gratitude to Peter for what he's done
for our careers and also um be thankful
thankful for the way he's be learning
and collaborating on science working in
the lab and fun thing to do so thank you
very much
Peter and um I'm going to read a little
bio about Peter so hang on there
apparently Peter uh got a
very um I got an early Head Start in
plant biology when he um took a class in
high school uh PL class high school and
U his textbook at that time was by erns
and Daniels who were two carel
professors so they didn't snow small no
circumstance K endel after all these
years and it was at that point that he
learned about gibberellin which become a
lifelong
passion Peter uh has been a member was a
member of The Faculty of Cornell for 46
and A2 years and a full Professor for 33
of those years he retired this January
with the title professor of plant
physiology and international professor
of plant
biology Peter holds degrees from the
University of reading in England
Bachelor of Science honors and
agriculture botany in
1962 and a PhD in agricultural boty with
an emphasis on herbicide physiology in
1966 in between that time he ordered
Masters of Science in plant physiology
at the University of Davis m got that
degree in
1964 prior coming to Cornell Peter
postto with ar gon y University for
three
years Peters published over 100 papers
on plan hormones and several books and
book Chapters at Cornell he taught plant
physiology his entire career reaching
thousands of students who went on in
sciences and
agriculture he also taught plant growth
and development with Dominic k for many
years more recently Peter started a
popular course entitled issues and
social biology covering the societal
implic implications and advances in
biology and even more recently joined
the GMO debate science and Society
course on GMO props the regulation
societal implications and we're doing
that Ron hering and dve and Sarah Eva
who will be speaking
today Peter has had a long history of
service till Corell he was the chair of
plant biology from 1992 to
96 the director of Graduate Studies for
field of botney from 80 to
83 director of undergraduate studies and
plant Sciences major from 2004 to
2009 and chair of college of
agricultural and Life Sciences faculty
Senate 2001
2004 he held the position of Jefferson
Science fellow
at the United States Department of State
from 2011 to 2014 serving as a science
adviser in the area of agricultural
biotechnology and has been involved in
Cornell's mission of international
agriculture this Symposium today
reflects Peter's long-term interest and
contributions in the field of plant
hormones is more recent advocation for
biotech Pro advocacy we're delighted to
have Jim Reed and Sarah Davidson OFA and
Ronnie Harin all close collaborators of
Peters over the years to help honor
Peter's
career so with that I'd like to
introduce our first Speaker who is
Professor Jim
Reed Jim is a plant geneticist has
identified genes that regulate plant
pron synthesis
reception he's shown how gibberellin
grassin steroids oxin and ethylene
regulate plant development from the
molecular to the whole plant
level he's currently working on the role
of plant hormones role of plant hormones
play and
symbiosis Jim is isi highly cited
researcher and former dean of science
engineering and Technology at the
University of
Tasmania he's a fellow of the Australian
Academy of techn technological sciences
and
Engineering Jim spent two sabatical here
I was fortunate to be a student here
during one of those and can attest to
how much fun it is to work with Jim but
more importantly Peter and Jim have
collaborated over the years and have
made significant contributions to the
field with plant
mons so Jim thank you very much for
making a truck here from Tasmania all
the way to Upstate New York the floor is
yours and the title of Jim's talk is
hormones and plant development
thanks very much Fred it's absolutely
great to be here and thanks very much
for the invitation and the organization
Sarah and Fred G um put on the show over
the next couple of
days when I was asked to come I was
asked to talk to a titled something like
this which was to talk and give an
upto-date version overview of where
plant hormones are at and then thinking
about it I thought that field is just
huge these days it's just enormous
there's no way to give a contemporary
overview of that whole area so I thought
that I would actually focus a little
instead of trying to cover the whole
area on areas and questions that Peter
had asked back in his early career and
tried to show you how over the last 30
40 years those questions have been asked
so I apologize if some of the d a few
years old some of it will be quite up to
date but um I think it's important to
actually address the questions that
Peter posed back in the' 70s and see
where they come today we not being able
to be
answered who has been engaged with
hormones for a very long period of time
he this is a conference
1967 so he's been working for 950 years
on plant hormones that's Peter DAV is
there and probably about mid 20s early
20s so he's been working in this area
for a very long period of time and
I would like to Define three areas of
research which I think he's made a a
critical contribution to over that very
long
career there are areas that I think are
close to his heart he's worked
extensively in these areas and he's
really been at the Forefront of the
field when some of the discoveries were
made the first one is a perhaps an odd
one for somebody to prod up he's been a
champion of hormone physiology and I'd
say that because he influenced me in the
early days to be interested in for
physiology and I think he's done that
through being the author and editor of
key texts over a very long period of
time to enthuse people to actually get
involved with the field and at times
there's been a real need for that the
second area that I'll talk and probably
talk more about in terms of length are
the growth promoting hormones orans and
gerin the things he worked on and
particularly their control of the
elongation sh ation plants and he did
early work where he identified Au and
transport patterns and gerell metabolism
and some of the Jon intermediates with
bioses in a number of key
species sorry I probably should have
said but the first area is highlighted
perhaps by this paper horal regulation P
plants with Arles in back um in science
in 1969 so this perhaps shows that he
was interested in this overview because
this was a a large review in science at
that time second one is highlighted by
this early review in the panical review
about the current modes of action of
orgm and the third area I talk about and
Pet's made a major contribution is the
genetic control of development the use
of gen to understand development and in
his particular case it was about AG in
essence and that was before people
started to work on arox and have all the
model species that we have today so it
may again appear why are we saying this
you assume that's the way people do
research no not that in the 70s and the
key paper there is this PO periodic
control of in essence the genetic line
ofes which he did with Jer Marx who was
at Geneva perhaps Mentor as a geneticist
plant geneticist and Bill Pro one of his
PhD students and I think in each of
these areas think has made a major
contribution I'd like to show you how
over the next little while
my first involvement with Peter came as
I said through that first area and that
was this text which came out in 1970
with art gon presumably based upon that
review in science and this came out in
my final year as an undergraduate
student and so I was introduced to the
area through this text and we used it
for a number of years in our third year
course in our
teaching more recently he's produced
this these texts on plant hormones the
titles changed a little bit over the
years there been various additions of
them between 1987 and
2010 and this is really the major
graduate level text in my opinion in the
field over the last 20 or 30 years there
are chapters by the experts in the field
have been invited to write this text
Peter put it together you can see his
interesting J because the molecule is on
the front cover of pH and he in genetics
because here are some drawings in this
case of various P mutants that syes and
in the
same when Peter started his work that
science paper had these five plastical
group of hormones were n and since that
time the complexity has expanded and his
texts have expanded along with that the
chapters on new hormon groups like
steroids that became defined as a
hormone group in 1996 the L groups St
lactones in 2008 there are a bunch of
other hormones that have also been
identified over those years
polyam yes or no some of the defense
hormones chlorogen been identified we
know that's ft protein other signaling
proteins like CLE peptides have been
identified these control roou
shoot information flows during processes
like
modulation and there are still hormones
to be identified there a carak like
hormone carak is a substance you find in
Smoke and bufes which has affects plant
development but it's fairly clear that
there are signaling Pathways within um
the plant and there's probably a natural
hormone that's great to so the field is
grown and there is still more to
go why do we need a champion of plant
hormones why do we need somebody to
stand up and publish the texts write the
Books edit the books it's hard work and
perhaps doesn't get you the high
citations that you may get out of some
of the papers in a high-profile journal
and my view is because of some work that
happened during the 1980s largely led by
Anthony who questioned whether planned
hormones really did
exist he was suggesting that hormone
sensitivity was the key controller of PL
development and in the more popularist
issues of new scientists here in
1984 you see that that there really was
a question do plant plants really have
hormones and what I'd like to show you
over the next little while is indeed
they do and show you that the evidence
that was put forward against them and
there were seven reasons given by ders
against the role of
plan some of the key ones I just shown
here in Black they are the FAA to
correlate hormone levels with
development FAA to show localized sites
of
production and the effects of the
environment on hormone levels were simp
be trivial if in fact hormones really do
system play a key role in plant
development then we must be able to find
evidence that shows those statements are
not correct and what I would like to
show you is that in working with Peter
over the last 30 years we will see
evidence that contradicts each of those
statements I won't go back to these
statements so it might be wise just to
remember them but I hope that I can
convince you these criticisms that were
there in the 1980s have been overcome
and Peter played a key role in champing
the role plan through the T that he
edited to move to the second um section
of the tour the growth a Jons and
El and this is where I've worked with
and collaborated with him um during some
wonderful sabatical that we've had and
my family have had at Cornell and that
he has had while he worked in our lab
back in
Tasmania we used a range of techniques
over the years the early years it was
great physiology PL physiology and the
forward genetics approach as the
analytical techniques became better we
use GCM lcms techniques and of course
the last 20 years the molecular ology
but I hope again I can show you that we
need all of these range of techniques if
we're really going to understand plant
development from the molecular level
right through the whole plant
level why work on shooting elongation
why look at it as a process that we want
to understand and I hope this graph
gives you some idea why we thought it
was an interesting area of working if
you look at yield in serial crops are
just wheat crops over the period of
about 1963 to about 2000 there's a very
dramatic increase in yield and this
increase in yield is obviously
contributable to improved agronomic
processes and arra of other things at
that level farming practices but the key
thing was that the Breeders produced
dwarf varieties new dwarf varieties that
had substantially improved
yield they they used the genes but they
didn't know what they did and it was
important to understand how we're modif
our crop plant at the molecular level
and understanding um therefore being
able to potentially use those same
processes in other
crops why are the DW varieties so
important well lodging is a major
agricultural problem lodging is when you
get the crop heavy crop of seeds on top
and heads and it falls over due to wind
rain whatever and the dwarf
varieties especially with good
fertilizer application lodged to a much
lesser extent than po varieties and of
course the putting less carbon into the
stems there's they a partition a great
proportion of carbon so you've all heard
of the Green Revolution and that's the
one of the key elements behind
it we wanted to understand what the
jeans's controlling height actually
did so back in the early 80s um I
started to collect a whole range of
dwarfing mutants and I was using P of
the
model and I could classify them into a
range of groups so there were ones that
were
short responded very well to the
application ofic
acid and I speculated that they were G
deficient
mutant there were some that were
elongated
like that responded very well to gors
speculated they were G over producing
plants there were ones that were the L
elongated didn't respond to the
inhibitor classifi those as G
constitutive LA and C have subsequently
been shown to control what are known as
the Dela proteins the production of Del
proteins which are in the signal
transduction pathway
from the V efficient
mutant short war they don't respond well
to GA they respond very well to
application steroids they have a
discrete phenotype you their lead color
Le shape stem structure is different
from the ones and these are all G
subsequently being shown to control
steps
Andoid
biosynthesis there are ones that control
the receptor
steroids and we have other mutants that
have a short bushy phenotype and are
involved with orm metabolism or orm
dection in various ways
so we we could guess at what the mutants
did but we needed to prove
it so if I take that first group The J
bios synthesis mutants here's the wild
type this is mle's dwarf mutant has been
used in as in crop the P crop for at
least 500 years and there are a bunch of
other ones that control other steps J bi
synthesis we wanted to understand
initially what controlled this
difference between men
dwar dant and this wild
type apologize for this slide this was a
first computer generated slide I ever
had made just a copy of it obviously I
hope my taste has improved a little
since the color those days but in the
literature at that time the explanation
for how mle's Gene was working was that
it could affect J levels could affect J
and
sensitivity it could be affecting a
levels another growth M hormone
it could be affecting the level of a
growth inhibitor and because of the big
difference you get during de ulation of
the plants it could be affecting po
receptor function and particularly p p
function so these were the Alternatives
that were in the literature in about
1982 at that stage we knew the J B
pathway went fromy phosphate through
onine Caro acid g12 and then out um
through the G20 that was established
Peter worked on that and identified some
of the mediat in that work but we didn't
know anything more about it now I want
to talk about this little bit at the end
we added to this
pathway and show that in fact this these
are the steps that are controlled by
mle's Le and then I'll talk a little bit
about
this so the first question was were the
JS involved took the dwarf mutant apply
ga1 to it get very rapid elongation so
ga1 strongly promotes elongation but the
precursor molecule the molecule that was
at the end of the N path that stage G20
would not cause this
elongation bias which is all we had at
that stage suggested that that the menal
mutant lacked a G1 might Peak that was
present in the wild type fact so that
was the
hypothesis and then we started to be
able to to
measure the levels of the hormones
using C13
labeled internal standards and indeed we
found that wild type had about 30 nog
Grand press weight of G1 and about a
tenth of that in the m so that suggested
to us that instead of the bio pathway
coming through here G20 and being
deactivated by two Hydrox to G29 that
there it was also possible for three of
Hydrox relation this position on the
molecule which was n to activate the
molecule and then can be subsequently
deactivated by 2 Hydrox so the
hypothesis was that mle's Gene was
blocking M was blocking this
skin so we tried to apply radio Lael G20
for the plants and then looked at what
was produced and the mutant G20 is
produced just to
G29 whereas in the wild type ga20 not
only went to G29 but it also G1 and G8
were also ched so suggested we had the
the right step the question was what was
the mutant doing this mutant could be
just a regulatory Gene could be in the
structural gene so we had to try and
identify the gene product of that lus
and now we might do this and we probably
give a student a month or so to get the
job done back then wasn't quite so
simple took us many many
years
so Dian Lester who was a postto in the
lab at the time Peter was with us on
sabatical Peter was on his paper back um
he was with us in 9697 and this his work
that D headed up the theer was working
with us at that stage we isolated the
three o days gen by scen and then show
that the mutation in that Gene Co
segregated with M Clean so here's the
parents tall has one band dwarf has a on
mutation in it which causes two bands
pl2 and 1 K Band and then in the
segregating F3 proy and pleas that takes
about five six years to generate we um
could show that all the dwarf types
Offspring had the two bands whereas the
tall ones either had three bands hetus
or just a s band that were
H so it suggested we actually found the
right
Gene the final proof of course is
showing that that what that Gene can do
and here's um that Gene the wild Gene
was expressed in me coli with G20 and
indeed the wild typ Gene G20 to G1 but
in mle's mutant there was some activity
only about a tenth of the activity you
found wild so M Le gen is a leaky three
oxid gen and we had other mutants that
in that were completely null for example
le2 so that's we added this step to the
pathway but nobody knew much about the
regulation of the
deactivation and I'd like to talk a
little bit about the es engine
here here it is here's wild type
seedlings they elongate very
rapidly and we identified the
appropriate
Gene and we beg ga1 in this case
metabolize the G8 the wild time but in
the mutant the
G1 had no activity at
all the this is for the um the genes
expressed in E
coli and reason
I'm talking about that this afternoon is
that was the first Gene known to affect
G deactivation known to control the
level of the bioactive molecule by
regulating its degradation rather than
its biosyn so it was an important step
at that time now of course we get takeen
for granted we just assume those
steps the question really then began we
took this slend mut
and crossed it to one of these jell
deficient mutants this one it's a very
severe mutant
na what phy would get this one over
producer and this one has a block on the
bi synesis when we produced
the F2 um seed and looked and selected
the double mutant it was elongated just
like the time and the question was how
could that be if this has a blockage and
biosynthesis how how this be the
hypothesis we came up with was that the
na mutation is s specific in its action
does not block G synthis of maturing
seeds and therefore these double mutant
seeds contain plenty of a
ga20 when they are mature and on the
germination that ga20 is metabolized to
ga1 because the foundation if that's the
case we should get a a quite strange
phenotype we grow on these lands Bel
long we did that this is what you get
the dou grows on it's very elongated
early on but then the effect from the G
carried over the seat wears
off and you get this very short to Old n
spe towards the
a at that time we assumed that each of
these steps was controlled by one G we
didn't know anything about Gene families
controlling steps in hormone
B and when we looked at the na like
genes and PS we found here's the normal
na Gene it's expressed in the stem but
it's not expressed in the developing
seeds and there's a second DNA like Gene
that is not expressed in the stem but
it's expressed heavily in the developing
seeds that explains why the seeds could
produce G but the stem couldn't and in
the reason I put it in today is because
the NAC is to produce G and it confirmed
the suggestion I made in that first
edition of that book that I Peters
published on plant hormones
that genes controlling plant hormone
bies can have precise tissue and AOG
geneic
specificity we now know that we take it
for granted most of the biosynthetic
pathways that control plant hormones are
multi have Gene families controlling
individual steps and they quite often
had quite specific um sites of action or
points in which they operate in the life
cyle it's why a small number of plant
hormones can control complex plan
development quite
precisely this piece of evidence was
important in
M
identification the other hormone hormone
P has been intered in right through the
early 70s was Oren and IA indic acid is
the major Oren in both
plants and the question was if I'm
saying G1 controls elongation and Peter
would have said in the early 70s that a
was involved in elongation how do they
interact and what I want to describe is
a little bit of work by a colleague of
mine worked in the lad H for many years
John Ross and he came up with a
hypothesis how at least one they one of
the
way his hypothesis was that a was being
produced the leaves where it was loaded
onto the basic pedal transport stream
for aen and flows down the stem and but
in the elongating in node Oren
controls the level of G1 by increasing
the conversion of G20 to G1 and blocking
the activation of G1 either from G1 to
G8 or PR from G20 to
G25 and he tried to test that hypothesis
to see I'll try to just describe it into
this experiment um we need to look at he
had three treatments an intact
plant plants where you
decapitated just below the Apex plants
be decapitated and then reapply or and
in L and past to the cut Stu and he
measured the IIA level in those tissues
and if you decapitated the the pl the or
level dramatically reduced and you put
or back on in that on the paste as you
would expect the level of GA was
elevated as a
tri the question was was there a a
subsequent change also in the level of
ga1 if you look at this panel you find
almost exactly the same pattern as you
find here supporting John's view that
the change in a levels seen in these
treatments are affecting J G1 levels in
sh
or how's that occurring well if you look
at the two genes I described earlier the
L and sln gen the G3 oxid and the G2
oxid gen
intact plant in L wild typ it's highly
expressed you decapitated it's down
regulated P walks them back it's uppr
regulated and the reverse happens for
the deactivation Gene it's low in the
intact plant elevated in the decapitated
plants and then goes back down when
you apply or B to cut stum cut stump of
the um and as you can see G1 endogenous
level follows that pattern
so the point from that is that the two
growth hormones that been a lot of work
have been done treating them separately
they interact and one is operating
through the other in that particular
instance the Oren is affecting
J another question that was posed by
tavas and posed by Peter over a long
period of time was interest in how light
controls elongation during de de
which hormones are involved in the mid
1990s it considered to be the steroids
were opposed to be the ones that are
involved but it could be the jome could
be the AL I'll try to show you some
results and show you that it is in fact
the jome that are the primary of this
early change duration and if so how is
the plant deceiving the environment what
photo receptor is involved I'll try to
answer that question you remember travas
suggested that the environment didn't or
wasn't the pick for grack I try to show
you that
St I got interest in that work when I
was here on study League back in 1989
with Fred um and in Peters at that time
you had some wonderful trans jues that
could measure the change in PL plant
growth at very fine intervals and so you
could actually measure the change in
growth over those first 2 to 4 hours
after exposure of red light so the dark
plant walking on here and in red light
continuous red
light growth rate is reduced to about a
quarter of that in
the so we want to know how that happened
so I looked at again the same couple of
genes the deactivation Gene here in the
dark it's low and it's elevated within
half an hour transfer of light and then
stays up for a couple of hours and then
drops back to normal after about 4 hours
and the reverse happens for the menal
gene the synthesis Gene it's high in the
dark half there's two dark controls here
just to make sure the safe light is
weren't causing a
problemin half an hour drops down
exposure to light and then gradually
builds back up to normal after about 4
hour so there's a very rapid
transcriptional change over those first
couple first half hour
does that CH does that Ty mean there's a
change in G or in the hormone levels and
indeed here you are the hormone level
after 4 hours in red light and the wild
type plant here it's dropped to about 1
of what it was
in and if we look at a h v mutant a 5
mutant the difference is the same but
you a fire a
m the difference has been removed
there's no signific difference in that
the environment is affecting
elongation by being perceived by
photocom a and then that changes the
level of the ga1 of hormone which then
results in change in impation so p is
the PO receptor involved and the reg
regulation of Light by light is
occurring
transcription and just to show you if
you're interested in V DRS here's the
cell the
manot cell here's the nucleus stain for
those same cells and we're looking here
Pome Pi
a been labed in mon body and in the dark
in round dispersed through the cytoplasm
not
nucleus after a half an hour of red
light it has formed into Speckles and be
transported into nucleus and subsequent
sh of that's
part of the pathway for action and then
the f is
degraded and it's nearly gone by 42
hours so the pattern of change in what's
happening to P is completely consistent
with those other
results now I'm going I'm talking
probably too long but I was going to
take these this this group of slides out
yesterday until Peter told me that he
still wasn't absolutely convinced about
our ultimas
so he didn't necessarily believe all the
all the evidence that
people so back in 2009 one of the
students in the lab um had this diagram
and there were at least five ways in
which Orson was proposed to be bi
synthesized IND 3ic acid from either
indol or tryp and the predominant
pathway in the literature at that time
was through triamine Andy Trine that was
the prop
and that was based upon the fact that
the yaka
jeans arabis have been shown or
suggested control the conversion of
tryptamine to an hyox
triamine and that came from work by Z in
2001 in science where they published
that this is where the yaka were
operating and there was a paper in MA by
declair all in
2010 also suggesting and providing
evidence that this was the Maj part well
we tried to have a bit of a a book at
this and see whether it was the
same and this is one of our Brad
students na
ti and he applied triamine and he could
not find a getting metabolized to I now
Nathan was a good synthetic chemist as
well as being a plant physiologist so he
said he set out to actually make in
hydroxy synthesiz it and didn't looked
at its mass and when you this is theic
in a hydroxy and be checked by
NR and when you look at it major and it
fragments to
144 when you look at say clear our paper
is
the fragment M main ir and then it
fragments give these are clearly not the
same compa so the suggestion that we
were getting was not only couldn't we
find it being metabolized me metabolized
to this compound
piece the Spectre on which this hypothy
was based appear to be
incorrect and some excellent work by a
couple of major groups elect biology
groups in the following year actually
moved the yak jees from here over to
this point controlling the conversion
indo3 gas to I with the Copan
I IA pathway being proposed as a
dominant
pathway and now it's s to be that
AR we wanted to again therefore check
whether this occurred in PE our model
and John Ross again working in the lab
um collected genes to control this step
the first step of this Pathway to
I and he obtained mutant in them and I
just want to show you that indeed this
is in developing seeds and here in the
green is the wild type and here is the
mutant in
purple and as you can see indeed
mutation in that a gene in that um Step
has a major effect on Oren
bios there's a complication because in
PCS the major or is in fact a for plated
compound not just the simple I but the
same thing is happening for a p at the
same
time so it indeed appears that the IP
pathway is the predominant pathway for
or biosythesis not only in some of the
models like arsis but it certainly
appears to be the case in Le such
as well enough about the growth motive
hormones the other area I'd like to talk
about is the use of genetics to study PL
development and this is just a slide
just grab some information from the
literature over Web of Knowledge and
looked at the number of papers that were
talking about plant mutant by decade and
how they were controlling plant
development and you know back to the 50s
and 60s it was a very very small number
it was a rare techn people didn't use
it and it built during the
1970s has rapidly expanded um
you know since until these days of
course we take it as a matter of fact
that it's a the technique of
choice Peter and myself I started
working back in the' 70s when it was a
relatively rare technique and I'd just
like to show you and this piece of
information may only be of interest to
Peter but Peter and I I Dre my PhD I
worked on flowering control flowering
and Peter um worked on
genes controlling a in the end it turned
out that the genes were exactly the same
je the genes that control the photo
response whether it beesing or flowering
are these genes HR
and here's a wild type plant very
similar to the wild wild relative it
branches it has no Rel Essence and it
plows very
L you mutate HR it becomes a the
branching is reduced the essence occurs
at an earlier no you can't see it here
and it flowers as a quanti day plant
this is almost a qual day and if you you
take s the plant becomes early flowering
day neutral and it will only put on a
couple of PODS before its
nence and so these were the jeans that
pza and a whole lot of people in this
lab have worked on for many many years
and we' all tried to work out what they
would do and it's only really quite
recently
um that we have actually been able to
find evidence out this is done by jimer
one of my former gr students who
worksart and we were looking he was
looking and tried to isolate um the HR
Gene and see what it did and when
he uh looked at the expression of plot
jeans
Gene when he looked at the rhythms you
got the rhythms in the wild type one
transfer to constant life the Rhythm
will keep going in constant life but in
the HR
mutant it is ding out almost
immediately when you do the same thing
and you transfer not to constant light
but constant dark the rhym in both types
contined so HR is needed to maintain the
Rhythm under constant life
when he found that Gene isolated he
found it was an or of an
Arab Gene called early flowering free
and you can prove that he proved that
here we got Columbia arabidopsis elf3
the3 mutant in arabidopsis here he's
transformed those elf3 mutants with HR
p and as you can see the wild time HR
compliments the mutant and they look
just like colb wild type if you trans
form the three mutant with an HR mutant
then they maintain this clearly
demonstrating that he had the right gen
so one of Pet's gen that was there to
control phot peric response is in fact
um
3G it's actually quite important because
if you look at um PL genes of peas going
from Wild relatives through the land
races in Afghanistan through to those
that are in Mediterranean and Northern
Europe originally you find that this
only a single mutation that has occurred
in
HR right across that range and that HR
mut that single hype containing the HR
mutation has become widespread is the
key that has allowed P to be adapted to
Spring sign in high latitudes so it is
actually an important Gene and it's been
fundamentally used
in the other Gene I'll go through even
more briefly that's the day neutral Gene
SN Wild Table with SN and again what you
find here is the cing rhythms have been
modified by mutation mutation in purple
and the Rhythm has been Advanced by
about 6 hours
in and when you go through the normal
when you go through the process and
isolate the gene you find SN is the
ortholog of the arabis pl Gene LS so
those two genes that were controlling
and Peter worked on right through the
70s and 80s about % actually control
genes fundamental to the cadan
RH is that right Peter
convinced yeah I'll you I'll talk you up
[Music]
good the other thing that now I'm
getting a bit more up to date with some
of the more recent work um I've been
doing in the lab my interest in the last
few years have moved to using the
hormone genes that we isolated and
identified back through the 70s ' 80s
and '90s to looking at how they affect
and using them to see how other hormonal
processes are regulated in
um for example the N I talked about the
the roots of the N quite clearly the
roots are smaller and Shor we expected
that but the nodulation is dramatic it's
almost eliminated and showing that g are
absolutely essential for some of the
early stages in
modulation we also look at other my
horiz other soses in plant groups for
example Bas horiz here instead of being
depressed as it was in that last slide
in the na mutant the number of muscules
to P significantly elevated that can be
reduced or returned to normal by
application so the gibons play a key
role in regulating both nodulation and
the muscular micro Rizal development and
they're operating in different
directions so we presume they are not
operating in the common pathway the
controls
both um I haven't got time to go into
any more details
St most recently isolated group of
hormones this is work done by L my so if
you take a mutant CCV just a mutant
Pathway to the they Branch down the
Bas show they contain no
me look the fungal
structures substantially reduced aular
micro Rizal development in the that's
been known for a long that's not new to
us but certainly what is is are also
affecting modulation we're working on
how the spaid are affecting the
communication between the root and the
um the Rises here and how that then
results from different levels of
modulation so that's work we're
currently
doing another M we just isolated
recently P it's been know in other
species but some time is line to ethine
in
sensitive and as you can see here is the
wild type here's the I2 nodules all over
it's almost
super which is a discreete phenotype so
it affects
that that that been determined by other
people in things like medicard before
but what we were interested in is how
that effect of ethine interacted with
things like um other some other hormone
gen for example LK is a steroid
deficient un because of blocking steroid
so you get a significant decline in
nodulation when you get rid of or reduce
thein steroids but when you recombine it
with the Ion 2 unit is the
double the implication is that you get
an elevation of nodulation back to what
you see in i2u words I2 is static cave
and when we look at that and try to work
out
why it's because this plant um this
plant the LK
VI has elevated levels which would
normally be um retarding modulation and
when you introduce an eth sensitive M
then the difference between the and
wild so my current work is concentrating
really on how the root interacts with
the rise
spere and how the hormones that we've
looked at for a whole lot of other
processes in the choot how they interact
to
control that symbos development within
the plant group the power and this is
important for nut nutritional Gathering
by the plant since the mizal development
leads to increased phosphoros uptake and
the modulation leads to increased
nitrogen uptake so we're trying to piece
together inside the bral plant hormones
regulate these processes so that they
are effective for the plant and but
don't become parasi don't become get to
the point where too much carbon is being
lost to the
m that's probably at least 5 minut so
this is a photograph taken in our lb
back our building h when Peter was with
us back in 1996 97 um and some of the
key people who have done the experiments
that I've been going through there Dian
leester did the one of the molecular
work with the El M John Ross did a lot
of the or work I've been talking about
Jim is there did the work um on the snhr
the fling jeans the clock jeans um I
think that's probably the Ian Mur is
there who was my mentor he was the
person who collected together some of
the mutants that I worked on the smhr
mutant that I worked on way back in my
PhD so he was you know my mentor in
getting into the use of jeans and how
they
also he well you want to go into the
story he
didatics up in Geneva and with Corell he
met Peter at that time and in fact Peter
ended up being I believe my PhD examiner
which I of course wasn't allowed to know
at that time they have done conviction
but subsequently obviously found out
many many years later so it's a long
engag and of course there's been a huge
number of collaborators um at Utz in our
lab Utz as well as people all around the
world but particularly in this audience
obviously beat up the top and PR but I
had some absolutely great times out in
Ken State uh doing some work in um down
cosos lab while I was here over that
period of time so it's been a it's been
a great
um I've enjoyed the career and the work
with Peter and it's been at the heart of
a lot of those studies over those last
20 or 30 years and I thank him very much
for his contributions he's made to he's
been me over that time I should
acknowledge the sponsors um clearly our
university has supported me over a long
period of time and the Australian
research Council um has been like said
has been providing funding to allow us
to do this many many years so thank you
very much for listening thank
you thank you very much Jim for the
worldwind tour through the history of
plant hormones toxins jellin bring us up
to stre with some the latest
developments of rhms those are all
topics that have been GE to comp for
many years so that was a really great
talk very
fation um we're going to take a break in
a few minutes but anybody has any
questions you have to entertain I got a
comment or
comments well I never believed the trip
story anyway sounds like
Stewart we we're coming we're coming
back to the
pathway that was proposed in the
1940s so you got all I say go and grab a
text from 20 8 2009 2010 and see what
they were talking about um it yeah
you're absolutely right there had been
evidence and people supporting each of
those Pathways and that each kind of had
their turn in the sun I think the
difference is we've now isolated the
genes in some of those Pathways we've
been able to put those mut put mutations
in those genes and place them in the
pathway and actually not only follow a
change in the phenic development of the
organism but actually monitor the
hormone levels and show their change and
um while we did that in the 80s um for G
and the '90s for steroids it really has
only been in the last 8 or 10 years that
we've been able to do that in the same
way for all so even though it was the
first hormone identified and we we
really should have known how it was
biosynthesized years ago it's really
only in the last few years it's become
an hour I'm just going to do a quick
introduction uh first person really show
the pathway of Orin in Roots which is
now Central and he also did orx in
biosynthesis in Roots my first
undergraded student Eric Mitchell you
stand up
Eric who's now come
back Eric Eric is an
MD pathologist but uh we nearly got him
to go into plant Sciences but medicine
called
well I I actually did I I was another
student and I collaborated and we
decided that if I went into medicine and
got the money we can start our own
land but then I get married
and I probably not qualified to ask
questions about plant
biology when I left a while ago grabing
o
key model organism so I'm interested to
hear how much work you've done with P to
elate these
mechanisms some of that workis as well
okay genetic
genetics um there was a period of at
least a decade where the field was
dominated by the molecular advantages of
arabidopsis and there's no doubt for
example when we pulled out that G3 oxid
Gene I talk about M gene the there had
been we would not have been able pull
that Gene out unless somebody had
identified previously in our that there
was in fact a gene that controled free
oxidation um and so we were able to to
pull it out so um a lot of with Jim
Will's work um the recent work there on
the flowering as I said they were had
already been been identified as CL gen
and arabidopsis we now have a we have a
sequence for metac cargo he he got the
SE P sequences out of met of cargo and
then bought the sequences out of P we
had the mutants um we didn't know what
the J structure was but he was able to
prove it by actually going back and
finding mutations in the homo Arab so
Arab opsis in terms of being able to
allow us to advance this molecular front
was fundamental for at least 10 15 years
we're getting to the stage now we've got
enough other genome sequences that we
can start to um work from those species
in their own right and if you might ask
why do I work on
symbiosis what don't Arab what doesn't
Arab dois do it doesn't form symbiosis
so the obvious reason if you want to
stay working on your favorite model is
to actually look at developmental
processes that are important in
agriculture important um developmental
process but things that do not happen in
AR I guess you'd have to say that's why
we're now working in that area of my
it's an area that um you have to have
theuts and you have to be working in a
species that um has the symbos and leg
units have the advantage they have both
modulation and
mizon therefore they are a really good
model to doing some of the basic um
moleular work so that's why we that's
why we where we are at one well some of
us are very attached to PE I've work
with P soes it's good to see that
they're robust to be used in
research any other questions
thoughts
comments okay we have about 25 minutes
or so to have some refreshment and uh
each other so let's take a break and
we'll get
back it's my pleasure now to introduce
Sarah Davidson
IA Sarah came to Cornell after
completing the ba in biology from RE
college and I went on to receive her PhD
here Coral
2009 for a dissertation she conducted
he an interdisciplinary studyed plant
electrobiology with science
communication and focused on the
controversy of genetically
engineered involing countries focusing
primarily on
Thailand she says Lord by the great
weather here today
Cales plenty of water and an unbeatable
intellectual environment who can argue
with that she remain in
remain Cor University after completing
her
PhD and she helped lead Global project
at that time um to protect the world's
Fe from be St
West Sarah now serves as a director for
the Corell Alliance for science which is
a Global Communications effort that
promotes evidence-based decision making
and
agriculture she teaches courses on
agriculture biotechnology at The
Graduate and undergraduate level in
Sarah serves as a senior associate
director International programs in the
College of Agriculture life sciences and
holds an adjunct appointment in the
section of plant reading genetics and
integrated School Plant
Sciences Sarah was also instrumental in
launching the Cs initiative aware
advancing women and agriculture through
research and
education throughout a time here in Cor
s's interacted with
Peter first time was as a grad student
Peter's plant growth regulator's
graduate level module in the fall of
2001 she's gone on to work with Peter in
international programs as well has
contributed to lectures for Peter's
social issues and biology
class and she's also been on the faculty
team along with Peter Ron hering that
has explored the
GMO Sarah with your common interest
interest in collaboration with Peter on
his activities written to act byot Tech
policy public understanding it's big to
add here
today and your talk to as you can see
global aspects of PL biote technology
thank you
br it's an honor to be here and to be
asked to celebrate um fin retirement in
this capacity and this is an area that
Peter and I share a real interest in um
Peter has been a great mentor and source
of support for me as Fred mentioned uh
for many years and in many different
capacities both as a graduate student um
he was always that faculty member who
made sure all the graduate students had
a place to go for Thanksgiving um
invited us over to his home Etc and that
means a lot to our students and it's
been an honor to teach with Peter in
more recent years and of
course of course
the remote doesn't work
right okay and of course he was also one
of our um real supporters as a fellow
graduate student involved T La Ashley M
and I uh delayed and procrastinating
procrastinated writing our PhD Theses
and launched a roller
derby Peter was one of our founding fans
always a great um color of support it is
a little bit overwhelming and maybe
humbling to speak on this particular
issue because Peter is probably one of
the most
um well one of the best people in the
world to address this very topic Global
aspects of biology so I'm I'm a little
um humbled but I will la in here so I
think um many of you can appreciate the
genetically engineer crops are being
grown around the world 12% of the crop
land globally is zwn with genetically
engineered crops there's about 10 crops
that have been commercialized and are
out there eight of them are GR in the US
the US is the largest producer of
genetically engineered crops um we we
produce the most Brazil follows that
Argentina India which Ron will probably
talk a bit about today and then
Canada you can see in this graph that
many of you may be familiar with um
there's about 180 million hectares stwn
toic engineer crops today in about 28
different countries and about 5 years
ago the number of Hector grown in
developing countries exceeded developed
countries and of those 18 million
Farmers growing engineered crops the
majority are farmers in developing
countries however um despite this
widespread um relative success of CH
engineer CRS there really aren't very
many genetically engineered crops out
there in terms of diversity so soybean
comprises 50% of that heage um maze is
30% add in cotton and you're at
95% and uh if you add canola that
comprises 99% of the
[Music]
totals that are planted today and so
what this suggests to me is that there's
a real lost opportunity to um use these
tools of plant science and plant
breeding to improve some of the
important crops that are out there in
security crops and really highly
nutritious
crops in a similar vein too few traits
have actually been deployed so uh over
half of the jally engineered crops that
have
cultivated
are haveing to tra herbicide tolerance
Round Up ready as we s commonly hear it
um and the um other uh dominant trait is
herbicide tolerance and if you combine
those two things together you have
covered about close to 100% of the props
that so again two uh little diversity of
CRS that have been able to benefit from
these tools and too few traits um that
are actually look some Farmers I think
yeah what is the reason for the
dip uh developed resistance is probably
overall the um the the uh number of
hectors of genetically engineered crops
di this year for the first time from
2014 to
2015 and um there of course uh Earth
crops have we heard a lot
about taking overt field for
[Music]
example
sou away
to Sarah can I
jump now that we've had the wine you can
jump in all you want and and and and if
you and if we had more wine we can start
to debate whether or not plant hormones
exist that diagram or this graph is
herbicide tolerance only insect
resistance only and more and more now
are combining the two that is stack
trades that means both together so
you'll see stack trades things by to
jump up as the other two go down that's
because they're growing combination much
more oh more there were price changes
over time so a lot of cornland went to
wheat so there's every year Farmers that
and we don't have any genetically
modified
wheat so I think um most people in our
society today know um the reasons um why
we don't have more genetically
engineered crops out there in the hands
of farmers um there's been a lot of
controversy around this technology and
unlike the field of plant hormones not
much has changed uh over the last decade
or two in terms of conversations around
act biot technology and this is despite
that nearly every highly reputable
scientific organization in the world has
um endorsed the safety of genetically
engineered crops um over and over again
for s years not the least of which is
the recent study by the National Academy
of study of Sciences that came out a
couple of weeks ago that again
emphasized that there's no substantiated
evidence of a difference in risks to
human health between conventionally DED
props and genetically engineered props
and they did not find in this study any
conclusive cause and effect evidence of
environmental problems from
props even the Girl Scouts have taken a
strong stand for science on this issue
when they were Meed um a year and a half
or so ago to remove genetically
engineered ingredients from their
cookies that they're so famous for they
took a stand and cited worldwide
scientific support to safety of
currently commercialized ingredients
derived from genetically agricultural
props and they went on to say that in
the future GMOs may actually offer a way
to help feed our ever increasing
population Hill girls um there have been
a few studies published that have
suggested that there are risks to
genetically engineered CRS and I think
the most famous of which is the serini
study um but that study was retracted um
after it was published in 2012 it got
some it got some play it um had Major
Impact on some policy in in in various
countries around the world and then was
later retracted but it wasn't retracted
before as I say it had some some pretty
serious implications um not the least
which was the effect it had on policy
making in Kenya where there was a b put
into place on import of genetically
engineered um props and genetically
engineered food and despite the fact
that the serini paper has um been
retracted
in there's a long list of ways in which
it was flawed um this B remains in place
it's also had impact in countries like
Uganda where um groups like a that have
been campaigning against the um uh the
use of genetically engineered crops um
have cited this study and I will and and
and they even go further um so I'm going
to play this action a is an
international charity raising tens of
millions of pounds a year to alleviate
poverty and end
Hunger in Uganda as a bill was being
debated to allow GM crops action a ug
Ganda ran this radio act for a week in
2013 did you know that genetically
modified organisms are organisms made in
the laboratory by Crossing genes from
different species such products cause
health risks such as cancer infertility
Etc single study Ling G with cancer in
rats was discredited by the European
Food Safety Authority a different study
suggesting a link to infertility withraw
so this gentleman in the red sweater is
the former director of Green Peace UK
the course Green Piece is an
organization that's campaigned against
jally engine CRS for a number of
years this message is brought you by
action a Uganda protecting our health
environment and Farmers right to
seed
well that is really shocking to be
scare muming about health risks
particularly
cancer with no scientific justification
for me that is
totally so I I share that example of a
way in which the serini paper has had
impact on um policy and decision making
in Uganda but I also share it because I
think it's really encouraging that
people like the former director of
Greenpeace are actually starting to come
around um and nuan their position on G
crops and I think I think we're at a t
point and we may we may be experiencing
um a turning of the ties if you will um
around around the conversation around G
crops globally I'm also encouraged by
people like this woman in this
Photograph Matia Chad from Bangladesh
she's the minister agriculture there and
she has stood very firm um in in her in
her support of uh genetically engineered
props and ensuring that farmers in
Bangladesh one of the world's most
vulnerable countries um have access to
this technology so she pushed for the
approval of BT bringel in
2013 and that uh material was made
available to Farmers a small group of
farmers of about 20 farmers and you can
see see that ceremony here and this
gentle in Monsour SAR car was one of the
first farmers one that first 20 um who
received the seed for genetically
engineer uh BT brel so the eggplant as
we call it here so in 2014 he planted a
small quar hectare plot of this ET
bringel and was rewarded shortly
thereafter with a prop that he could
then Market as CTI side free BT of
course
um is um the that reduces insecticide
use in in these in these
contexts so when growing conventional
eggplant he had to spray his crop twice
a week um sometimes as much as twice a
day under heavy um
infestations and now he doesn't have to
do that and so he sees this both um as
an economic benefit as well as an
environmental benefit he and his wife
and his daughter E eggplant two to three
times per week and the money that they
earn from eggplant um helps him to
support his family and importantly send
his girls to school his neighbor's
eggplant at this time I'm sure he has
better seed now but at this time um when
the seed was originally released um he
was still growing conventional eggplant
in this roock was little bit p and not
fit for sale or for eating so the stakes
here are are pretty high I plan the
South Asia's first uh genetically
engineered food crop it was developed by
public sector scientists and really
intended for resource cor Farmers like
monster
SAR and his story I think is really
remarkable because it's a case where one
single a Innovation and strong political
will uh on the part of NAA chav um have
really offered him the chance to greatly
improve his livelihood and the lives of
his daughters and that could ultimately
break their poverty
cycle his story however should not be so
exceptional and the case of BT br that
we all like to talk about and celebrate
should not be so exceptional there are a
lot of products um in the pipeline in
late stages of development that have
been developed not by the Monsanto of
the world but by public sector
institutions in the US and around the
world um that that that that that are
quite promising so products like
biofortified bananas being developed um
in
Uganda products like these nutrient-rich
Tomatoes being developed by a public
sector institution in the UK plant dried
fish oils being Abed in camelina another
project happening in the public sector
in the UK Lake light resistant
potatoes cold cows so these are cows
that have been genetically changed to
not grow horns which eliminates the
inhume process of dehorning so this
addresses a real animal welfare issue
insect resistant cow this is a a major
food security crop in countries of West
Africa and biofortified or virus res in
casava to name just a few examples um so
it's it's my hope that while we in in
this country sit around um the luxury of
debating whether or not we want to label
our Foods as containing GM or non GM
this technology doesn't bypass Farmers
like Jima uh this pav farmer in Uganda
who in
2016 still struggles to cultivate a crop
that is technically under domestication
it could use um Improvement
tools it's my hope that in four years or
5 years I can be telling jima's success
story um in which she's had the option
to choose whether or not she wants to
grow genetically engineered products and
whether she thinks it's technology is
something that will benefit her family
and that that choice isn't made by
organizations uh like action a and that
are based to wellfed countries like the
UK I think it's also really important um
and particularly in the context of
Cornell that we ensure that scientists
around the world have access to the
tools that they need to innovate to meet
the great challenges that we face today
um we we've seen what's happened with GM
and there's new tools coming along and
we need to make sure that we don't uh
lose access to those tools as well so we
need to make sure the public sector
scientists can use these tools to
innovate scientists like Ellison Ben
enman from UC Davis who's been
responsible for the the old C work that
I mentioned scientists like Chuck mayard
and Bill Powell up the road at sunf and
they've taken a gene from wheat and
moved it into Chestnut to protect
Chestnut from the devastating BL that
has for the last 100 years or so
decimated nearly every American chestnut
tree on the planet so they're using this
technique to hopefully reintroduce a
near extinct species into the forest of
the eastern US scientists like Tony
Shelton one of our own entomologists
here at Cornell who's using genetically
engineered insects to reduce past
populations for cavage growers in New
York state without the need for
excessive
insecticides again real environmental
benefit scientists like Andrew kagundu
from the national agricultural research
program in Uganda and he's taken a gene
from sweet pepper to protect his
country's starchy banana staple b m
banana from bacterial will
disease so it's scientists and Farmers
like these who I've I've talked about in
in the first few minutes of my talk that
have really inspired us to build the
Cornell Alliance for science um the
initiative that frig mentioned that
we're leading there and our mission
really is to promote access to
scientific innovation access to choose
to use these Innovations as a means of
enhancing food security improving
environmental sustainability and really
improving lives globally
and we think biotechnology is an
important part of that so in our first
year we're relatively new organization
just 2 years old founded in 2014 and in
our first year we really um focused our
efforts around this Central pillar of
access to Innovation um but following
the success of cop 21 we um are now
launching a new uh Global dialogue
around the climate change and Central to
this dialogue is is um helping explore
how this technology or new um Precision
breing Technologies that are coming
online might help us mitigate and adapt
to climate change so we we Face a steep
climate challenge that of um improving
um improving the environment uh reducing
poverty and increasing food security uh
while ensuring that the global
temperature does not increase by more
than 1.5 to 2
and that's impossible if we don't make
major strides in agricultural
Innovation so we are out there in the
world our Communications team um talking
to to Farmers to scientists to Consumers
to policy makers about how they think
this technology is playing a role in
helping them deal with climate change
and there's some really interesting
stories out there stories of adaptation
like the BT bringel that I talked about
um water efficient maze for Africa is
another great case but there's also
stories of mitigation so projects that
are looking at developing nitrogen use
efficient props or nothing reducing
rice the other piece of this um climate
for change initiative that we're leading
is to continue to use our training
programs to develop champions for Change
and we have um two different training
approaches with the alliance for science
one is a 12we program that happens here
for now many of you probably met our our
two our Ina World cohort when they came
last year these are champions from all
kinds of different walks of life
different countries 10 countries who
were represented last year who all feel
passionate about um this issue of
ensuring choice and and access to to
improve modern act Technologies and they
want to ensure that they can bring that
house to their own home countries so who
are these people um a few examples this
is re Reverend father no El par he was
one of our fellows that came here to
Cornell last fall he's a priest of the
Roman Catholic church and he came to
this issue of of
biotechnology um when he asked himself
the question how can I expect people to
come to church on Sunday and praise and
worship God when they're hungry admired
in
poverty this is clui Mas Masa from
Uganda he's a sorghum breeder and he was
also one of our fellows last year and he
asserts that every other field every
professional field is taking advantage
of scientific advancements and there
should be no exception in plant breeding
so why is it that the tools plant
breeders have or plant scientists have
are are being so politicized to the
point where they aren't able to use them
to serve um as Farmers or jie Kamya
she's um the daughter of a farmer from
Hawaii one of the first farmers to adopt
the genetically engineered virus
resistance papaya that was developed
here at Cornell and growing up she saw
firsthand how does technology could
positively impact small Family Farms
like hers and she wants to ensure that
other small Family Farms are around the
world and also benefit from this
technology so that's a sense of who our
fellows are I was going to show a short
film about them I'm not sure if I have
time
um
[Music]
yeah and the the your job in this film
is not only to enjoy it but to try to
find Peter davies's Cameo
[Music]
appearance money my name
is I'm father Al par my name is James
FY from the
my name is Li I am Jason Merkley my name
is a my name
[Music]
is when I was a student in college uh I
became an activist fighting a
dictatorship I was with flight farmers
and laborers and they were so poor so I
kept on thinking how could I help these
people it's um really very painful when
you see families that cannot afford to
feed themselves at least three
times it's ironic that farmers the very
people who tilt the soil to produce food
are the same people who experience
hunger we're not just talking about
American consumers here that have plenty
to eat we're talking about people in
food insecure regions who have nothing
to eat but a small handful of rice every
day my story is De my story she's one of
those small older casaba Farmers casaba
a major food security C is under Threat
by two major viruses this is very
devastating all the treat all the had
virus in his heartbreaking for him he
said I was so scared Jo I was so scared
that we l everything traditional ways of
farming in my
country are just not enough to be able
to Fe the many and I think the science
and technology that is happening our
midst could be a solution to that indeed
biot technology can be of help to
solving some of these problems and
therefore if this technology is adopted
by the I think it can help them BR and
it's my from conviction that is a
fundamental right Farmers to have access
to various farming options it seems very
cruel to deny that technology those
people who are in such desperate need
access to biotechnology is really a
social justice
issue being a part of the first batch of
cohorts of the Corell Alliance for
science is truly a very rewarding
experience for me this is a
completely unique problem as they say
here in America a there was really a
science to communication and I knew that
I needed to learn that so when I found
out about this program and that
opportunity to learn more about how to
communicate science I couldn't do
anything but jump at the opportunity and
there was a completely new approach how
what
theying I got interested in this program
because it was an Avenue for me to
improve on my communication skills in
the area of Agriculture bi technology my
participation in this is hopefully to
empower need to speak up and get others
to speak up in support of this
interacting with experts agronomists
scientists forers policy makers
journalists commitment and
dedication can actually help someone to
get father and proove a point and
there's such a rich exchange of
knowledge and wisdom and the friendship
we're becoming like um brothers and
sisters because I strongly believe that
science can be a key in solving hunger
malci and poverty I can do it alone I
cannot succeed on my own all by myself
this why I realize the need to unite the
need to engage in the need to empower a
network of
Partners right now I really feel
empowered right now I am more confident
in engaging the public in scientific
undertakings isn't Fascination and
Discovery wonderful this is one of the
best experiences that I will ever had in
my entire
life so um that was the 2015 cohort they
went home in November and we've just
selected and invited the 2016 cohort
will come here in August they're coming
from there's 10 coming from countries
across Latin America um three um fellows
from China and about team fellows coming
from different countries in subsaharan
Africa so I hope that those of you who
are on campus will come out and and meet
them when when they arrive so since
returning home fellows like Modesta who
you saw in the video have gone home and
they've recruited five to six um
additional Champions who share her
mission of ensuring the Nigerian Farmers
have access to biotechnology access to
choose this she's recruited them in into
her um her her initiative um these six
Champions then attended our short course
in Tanzania that we held in March and
then they went home and and recruited
two three four more people and so you
can see how very quickly someone like
Modesta becomes a very catalytic um
Champion for change through this um
program so as the alliance for science
here at Cornell we're really trying to
engage um individuals and organizations
who share our mission and want to extend
and lend their voice to um to our our
Global um Collective
and so I encourage any of you who share
who share this Mission and passion that
that Peter and I do um to to join our
alliance we have now engaged people
through our efforts in over half of the
world's countries um and I and I think
we're really building something um
that's important in ensuring that
science and evidence guide decision-
making
globally that said the reality still is
that too few products have come out of
the public sector and we're still
dealing with that situation that only
four cops have been using those tools
and of course we like to talk about
Dennis and and the papaya that was
developed Cornell that's the only case
where something has come out of the US
land gr system and I hope that that that
will change um because that's I think
this is really something that's
consistent with our land gr Mission and
I think as scientists it's really
important to step up and can take a
stand for Science and not get run over
by people who are making a living um
spreading fear about biotechnology so we
need to invest in the research we need
to invest in capacity building both in
terms of scientists as well as
communicators we need to engage with our
communities and hopefully we can
ultimately improve the policy
environments um that will inspire a
change in the conversation around I
technology and ultimately more of this
technology can be in the hands of
farmers so my appeal to you scientists
in the room is to really you know look
up from the bench and and realize that
we need to do things differently so we
sort of lost it on on GM and there's all
of these really exciting
transformational uh Technologies coming
down the pipeline or that are here and
and we need to make sure that those
don't get demonized in the same way that
GM has and I think this is where we can
all get inspiration from Peter because
he's done a remarkable job in the last
few years of doing just this both on
campus through his courses it's been
said a few times today how much impact
he's had in in wrestling with and the
the tough issues with students here on
campus through the social issues in
Biology class and also the GMO debate
but also through his Jefferson
fellowship and through his volunteer
work after the Jefferson Fellowship he's
really circled the globe from lvia to
botsuana to India helping people
understand this technology so that they
can make their own informed
science-based choices about whether it's
good for their country or not so I take
inspiration from Peter I encourage you
to join the alliance and then I wouldn't
be doing my job if I didn't promote our
new moo massive open online course that
Ron and I have been um developing in
connection with Patrice from ma of
Technologies who's here and Becca
Harrison who's here um in the third grow
also members of the Muk team so this is
a massive open online course that uh
we've been develop developing over
several months that'll launch September
13th and anybody anywhere in the world
can take this Cornel course an internet
connection and access to a computer um
so I'm going to play our trailer and
this is going to be the perfect
[Music]
segue early in the 21st century citizens
of planet Earth were distressed and
anxious the problem what to think of the
GMO the science the politics the
Clashing of values scary stories and
Grand promises compete contention swells
what are the benefits what are the risks
how is a responsible Global citizen to
think about all
this the GMO Muk team has come together
from different backgrounds bringing
different
skills a
scientist David a behavioral economist
Ron a political
scientist Shar an Information
Specialist and Becca a social
scientist they may not always see eye to
eye but together they pledge to guide
Learners on the ultimate Voyage of
Discovery what is the GMO and why does
it matter embark on this Voyage of
Discovery and share your views with
others from around the planet learn how
science works the limits of science risk
human behavior and how you can defeat
the confusion in your own life sign up
now and let the Cornell GMO moo team
help you activate your own information
[Music]
superpowers the premiere
right but enrollment is open so with
that I will
to thank
you thank you very much sir that was
that was
awesome say
America yeah just quick introduction for
Ron we'll move on um Ron Herring is
Professor of government International an
international professor of Agriculture
and World development your corn
University the field research in South
Asia and Central
I seted farmer interests class politics
and government policy his first book was
land to the to to the to the political
economy of aarian reform in South Asia
that was published by the University of
press which was on
responses PE movements for social
justice
development curiosity about GMOs was
ignited by the intense controversy
around BT cotton in India farmer welfare
sustainability
the crop play by crisis the lowest
yields in the world This research
stirred to edit the special issue the
Journal of development studies which is
called transgenics and the poor
biotechnology development studies
published a book for
by this interest continued in his work
was continued as editor of the Oxford
hurg food politics and Society in 2015
and Harper the annual review the
resource economics conception of
political economy and Fire Technology
Ron is now working on his book
manuscript entitled suicide seeds and
silver
blls with Peter's interest in public in
the policy and public
perception it's very fitting that you're
speaking today and thank you very much
for contributing to the
S can we do a hand off for a little
T
um well it's a it's a real honor and
privilege to be here uh I didn't I
wasn't told to would be molecules but
otherwise I'm okay um you know Peter and
Sarah as well as shantu shant who
sitting right here have helped me as a
social scientist understand what is one
of the more bizarre political phenomena
in the world and that's the GMO debate
that it's really very interesting that
there should be a debate about
biotechnology and everybody asked are
you Pro or anti and students have
decided to drop the course in part
because all the profs are pro GMO it's a
very bizarre thing you think like
there's a course on like uh I don't know
computer technology or cell phone
technology or something and people say
are you for it or get it it's a very
bizarre position but Sarah and Peter and
people like shantu off Cornell campus
have helped me as a social scientist
understand this now my position on this
is kind of the obverse of
s Sarah is a very hopeful person and I
cheer on her hopefulness and indeed uh
contribute periodically to being uh part
of a hopeful campaign um for Farmer
Choice informed choice and defeating Mis
information that is contrary to public
good all for all of those good goals I
periodically write such things um in
that regard on the other hand I don't
think the picture is quite as rosy and
I'm going to give the flip on right uh
what Sarah told you about the advantages
and the possibilities and the science
communication runs counter to a lot of
what we know about science communication
and risk so I'm going to talk more about
the flip side there's benefit side to
biotechnology there's also a course of
risk and that discourse is politically
powerful so I'm doing plant politics and
I hadn't thought about plant politics
much till as asked to uh to be part of
this um so here's Michael pollen who
really thinks plants have politics
Michael po must to tell us that all
these plants have convinced human beings
to give them special privileges Politics
as who gets what and how so all of these
plants have qualities like sweetness
Beauty intoxication that have caused
human beings to to protect them and
invest in them and improve them uh and
of course he periodically backs off from
that CU he knows a little bit of Science
and so he backs off and says well
actually plants don't have much
Consciousness but this is the the burden
of a botney of desire and then Michael
Colin's great question of the battle
between the trees and the grasses the
dominance of the earth is human beings
that of course have intervened on the
side of the grasses uh to defeat the
trees and that that is kind of the
nature of the development of nature on
the planet now plant politics though you
know my a palici side human beings do
plant politics and there have always
been kind of demon plants this is this
is there are dozens of such things I
didn't know you injected THC but but uh
this is the um weed with fots in hell
and there have always been kind of a
classification of plants politics of
categorization of plants as uh
unacceptable or acceptable and of course
the British Empire I did this because
Peter of course uh British Empire um
profited enormously by using opium as uh
and its progeny for control of much of
Asia um so but here I want to point out
we're talking about the effects of
plants so both marijuana and opium have
definable effects that you may approve
of or disapprove of but uh we have a new
set of plant Poli
this is the new set the J GMOs it's an
apocalyptic version oh by the way I'm
Sarah talked about the alliance for
science I'm actually wearing thei for
Science and uh I'm wearing a jacket
because Peter every time I se him
lecture wees wears a jacket I thought i'
don't be dressed can't wear a tie this
so anyway um so this is the the new
plant controversy and what's important
is that unlike opium or marijuana the
entire category of GMOs what is a GMO
anyway the entire category turns on how
the plant got the traits that it had
it's not the products of the plant or
the safety of the plant per se it's the
process that produced it and two of the
most important elements here of course
are the hubris they're playing God uh
and they're shoving it down your throat
it's just a dimension of power so that's
the kind of opposition this is a
Biblical response genic in Third Edition
by the way um now there's the darker
side which is an attack on science this
is biotech genocide Monsanto
collaborators there's a list of Monsanto
collaborators who are targeted for death
and the Nazi Legacy of science
justification for murder um and this is
a health Ranger in natural news right so
that dichotomy of the natural and the
unnatural and the health Ranger who
watches out for dangerous things like
plate is part the discourse now um this
is this is of course the the other kind
of critique that GMOs in the third world
cause Farmers to commit suicide this is
a very very powerful discourse and it it
won't go away it turns out that um it's
it's simply changing its form and
changing its shape but this discourse of
farmer disaster will not going okay so
here's our University course and we we
took this question on and it's evolved
over time but uh you see the the
different departments that have have
sponsored this course and we try to take
on the GMO debate to talk about science
in society and how science is accepted
in society what are the cost and
benefits of technological change so
that's the core of the
course now uh the props diverge in this
course but the students fail to notice
this is not surprising Peter Davies says
um people just don't understand the
science this is his his shtick with the
state department right you guys have got
to understand the science and he has
huge amounts of science behind him it
says there's really nothing to worry
about no problem here right Ron Herring
says it's not about the science it's
about politics and that the whole debate
has more an Nation remember the uh the
notion of of truthiness remember coar to
coar whe there truthiness rather than
facticity so it's not about facts it's
not about evidence is about truthiness
now this is this is a much stronger
claim to make right now do you realize
what's happening to the Republican party
in this
country right has anyone ever stopped to
ask um whether or not Mexican
immigration in the United States is
increasing or decreasing it's decreasing
dramatically right has anyone ever asked
this guy well anyway I w't go on about
it but the fact is that the facticity
has completely disappeared from the
majority of Republican primary voters
believe Barack Obama is not an American
Citi 70% believe Muslims should be
banned from this country so there's
there's an incredible amount
of truthiness substitute me for
facticity where so the first plant
causes whole politics is why did rdna
crops become framed as a separate
category law trade social movements
consumer Behavior international
relations where other applications of
the same technology were normalized
Pharmaceuticals vaccines Industrial
Products evaluated by product not by
process right so what I want to claim
here is the GMO was a brilliant
political invention it loaded one
concept with all of the risk and
disutilities that you could imagine and
Sarah mentioned some of them there's
sort of cancer and there's there's
sterility and and all all the incredible
numberers of things that GMO has caused
autism so I'm spectum down um but
excludes all of the clearly definable
benefits such as higher Farm deals or uh
in recant fical um improve products so
science and plan
politics what do we know about politics
um science across the board is
inherently
L the think about global warming classic
science commits itself to tentative
conclusions it won't give you a bumper
sticker the certainty of kind of bumper
sticker epistemology is restricted to
the non-scientific Community uh
scientists expensive and scientists are
not this interested right uh scientists
disagree the inevitability of fringe
science we saw sarin's work it's been
tremendous if you ask how many citations
are there to sarin's article about rats
with tumors compared to Peter work on PL
home hormones I'll tell you a secret
serini wins hands down by huge
quantities so scientists disagree in the
inevitability of fringe science makes it
possible for people to say well not all
scientists think global warming is
happening not all scientists think it's
human induced um and then finally um is
policy makes impossible knowledge hands
to disprove negatives no scientist will
tell you there cannot be a Black Swan no
scientist is going to tell you no one
will ever discover an allergen in some
trans Gene that was produced that was
put into a crop the fields that cannot
happen simply because the nature of the
epistemology and science so you're
disadvantaged politically you know uh
the the environment Minister of India
and turning down BT bringel said I want
absolute certainty that nothing could go
wrong with this plant and of course you
can never have absolute certainty in any
scientific process then finally
institutions are not trusted um Nina
feder off probably many of you know n
federov said in her presidential address
the tri a that I am scared to death of
the anti-science movements all around
the world and it's it's true okay so um
so this is this is the kind of worry
about science is sort of using people as
guinea pigs right that what we know is
based on a knowledge that is not
complete every scientist being honest
admit it's not complete it's tenative
tomorrow a new study could show that we
were wrong about something so this this
cute kid is he's not a scientific
experience stop do those now here this
gets back to the serini
sty people are also convinced that there
are thumbs on the scales right that
professional journals are edited by
people who are part of networks which is
true part of networks I made it in two
journals we're part of networks in which
we know who to send papers to to get the
response we want right so peer review
doesn't necessarily tell us very much
sarin's work on rap tumors which is
total rubbish total rubbish was
peerreview a peerreview journal not a
high status Journal but a peerreview
journal so this this goes uh this is in
from the Harald in Edinburgh a couple
years
ago study suggesting genetic modified
food kill of rats has been suppressed by
lobing and Multinational biotech
corporations environmental campaigners
claim so there's a thumb on the scale
that that science is produced by the
very corporations that benefit from the
bad science that they produce that's a
widely shared uh view of how science
Works uh so let's just think about this
Division I made between green biotech
which is food and red biotech which is
medicine
Pharmaceuticals and vaccines things of
that sort so look about the the risk
utility balance virtually all of
Technology change and Technology
politics revolves around some balance
between risk and utility think about
flying an airplane or surgery or any of
those things do we know the risk try to
figure the risk you know the utilities
and try to figure the disutilities and
then you make a decision so the risk in
red biotech is balanced by high utility
uh doctor prescribes a drug you may die
if you don't take it the comparative
safety of these drugs is vetted by
authoritative knowledge certified
experts that work through certified
organizations State science right so we
have state science either trust the FDA
or you don't but there's a state
scientific process that vets certain
kinds of of uh safety there are
voluntary acceptance of risk being
benefits unlike biotechnology in which
what's growing in fields whatever
effects it has you don't sign on
voluntarily to be part of that you don't
sign on voluntarily to consume the food
that's produced if it's not labeled so
there's a kind of
involuntary subjection to risk which we
all know by scientific studies shows
that people will enhance their
assessment of risk if they believe that
they haven't signed on to the risk they
voluntarily subjected themselves to the
risk unlike drugs or surgery or air
traffic right and so green politics bi
Tech GMOs produc a very different
politics but it's quite variable now
Sarah presented this this uh map after
telling me we should never use this map
again because everybody's bored with it
but this is the map so the world sort of
divided between GMO and non GMO
countries Sarah gave you a nice overview
of how few crops there are how few
traits there are but one thing she
didn't say well maybe she didn't say but
uh one thing that that people often Miss
is how little of this is direct food
props right mostly mostly these CRS are
either for fiber or feed so you have
this remarkable thing where the in the
EU um all of the farm animals that are
used for uh for consumption all those
animals are fed GMOs but somehow going
through the gut of a pig removes the
Stigmata of the being a Cho right even
even the euro is made BT cotton fber so
in the EU there's a kind of an odd kind
of transmogrification in the world of
growing food crops that are that are
transgenic or genetically modified in
some way and the world of safety and
nonrisk and somehow animals stand
between human beings and the crops that
way but very little of this of this
graph uh is food crops for direct
consumption gringle Bangladesh being a
dramatic example of an an exception to
that rule since bringel are eaten in in
Bengal two or three times a day often so
it's a major vegetable crop India is the
second largest produc world these are
major vegetable crops and uh but mostly
biote crops do not go into that kind of
circuit so this is sort of when Sarah
gave the example from the US Academy of
Science um this is a European study um
and I think in a way it's it's good
because nobody trusts the Americans
globally nobody trusts Americans because
they well Monsanto does the studies
Monsanto has his finger on the
scale so um this is a conclusion from
the EU studies for a huge Set uh of
studies they funded themselves
metaanalysis there's just no difference
in Risk profiles between transgenic
plants or genetic engineer plants and
any other kind of plants but what's
important about that is that tells us
going back to our earlier thing on
Plants the entire GMO debate is a
political debate the entire
classification is political there is no
difference here except that created by
political entrepreneurs there's no
evidence of any difference except that
created by what so it's not about the
science it's about risk politics okay
now um think about the benefit side of
that we said there's kind of an equation
technology policy there a risk there's
benefit there's a regulator that weighs
the risk and benefits and decides
whether we can go forward or not you at
nuclear power very complicated risk
benefit calculations they got global
warming they got Fukushima very
complicated calculations in the risk
benefit so in the benefit side of this
equation the benefits to Farmers have
been quite obvious and country where
biotech crops have been made available
they've been adopted pretty
rapidly in fact the dotion curve in
India for things like BT cotton is just
sort of 45 angle astonishingly rapid
adoption down like 98% of BT C in India
um so farmers they have a risk benit
calculist too but all adoption of
cultivars involves risk for Farmers if
you can't if you don't adopt a new
cultivar you're taking a risk as well so
farmers are continually at risk but the
GM crops important to American farmers
are much less important to European
Farmers so you get this difference in
the US and and Europe because European
Farmers don't really eat certainly not
Beach cotton they don't grow on soy the
the corn rootworm doesn't show up very
much far north of Mich so Spain and
Portugal are heavy users of B corn but
not much of Northern Europe so they have
a different kind of utility calculus and
they're protected by
government policy that provides them
with pretty substantial livelihood uh
independent market and banning GMOs of
course reduces competition from American
uh products so there's a there's a
different kind of benefit Matrix for
European Farmers compared to Americans
um and the final the final point I want
to make here about farmer adoption is
that farmers on every continent have
taken very high risk to grow illegal
crops that are biotech whenever the
prices are too high sometimes the case
or access is restricted so virtually all
over the world you'll find instances of
farmers taking up the technology there's
an underground defusion Network for
biotech seeds even when they're not
approved by government so the benefit
side of this equation is pretty simple
for Farmers producers and of course
firms uh most firms have made money on
these products um not all firms they
sometimes go out of business but but
firms and Farmers have some
benefits um the risk how do you
calculate risk this is the hard part
benefits are easy to measure and they're
very clear to a farmer um the risk side
of this equation is
completely politically determined and
that's because of what we call NY and
uncertainty when you can't measure risk
or you don't find any evidence of
specific hazard there's no specific
hazard you can't measure the risk
precisely then you're in the world of
uncertainty and that uncertainty means
that that you have to construct some
kind of risk calculus even though you
have no Hazard as I mentioned with the
uh euu studies there is no Hazard
demonstra so any kind of risk you have
with regard to GMOs is entirely
anticipatory and hypothetical
okay now most paration explanation
variant and outcomes this classical
political economy right you wake the
beneficiaries how many farmers are they
do they have organizations do they have
access to the Ministries do they have
some political CL then you look at the
opponents do they have large numbers do
they have resources have they mobilize a
lot of people do they have media access
and then they they interact some kind of
vector some comes out a regulator which
we'll just call for now a government
this is critical because part of the
variance around the world is explained
by the character of this regulat that is
the political structure of the
evaluation of science so in the EU you
have multiple veto points and multiple
veto players public opinion about GMOs
is about the same in the US as it is in
Europe in both countries people are very
suspicious percentage of people saying
it's unnatural it may be dangerous it's
roughly similar everybody asked the
questions different ways so it's hard to
compare public opinion surveys but
there's not a huge amount of difference
across the EU and the United States the
difference is that very small numbers in
Europe can make a big difference we have
multi-party governments in which the
greens often have Ministry of
environment or have at least a clout
with the ministry of environment and
those Coalition governments can be
blocked by the action of very small
numbers of players so there's a there's
a this regulator who who is in charge of
agree between the beneficiaries and the
opponents what kind of risk a society
should take now empirically around the
world uh ministries of Agriculture have
supported biotechnology Sarah gave you
an example minister of Agriculture inesh
supported BT
brel the Indian BT brenal from which
they the same trans gen it's actually
the same genetic event the cry AC that
came out of India donated to Bangladesh
that very same Eugene was not approved
in India and it was still put on
moratorium in 2010 it's still on
moratorium in 200 16 now and why is that
because in India the minister of
Agriculture did not have say the Prime
Minister did not have say the entire
decision was made by the minister of
environment ministries of environment
all over the world are much more risk
averse for reasonable reasons but also
because their political constituency is
environmental groups the political
constituency of Agriculture ministers is
Farmers and Farmers expect progress so
they have a different kind of system
between those places where the Ministry
of Agriculture dominates and those
places where the ministry of environment
dominates so India doesn't have BT
bringel uh and Bangladesh does now since
Sarah brought this up I do have to
mention the hazards you know we say risk
is Hazard times incidents or Hazard time
exposure the hazards in India are very
well documented they're very well
documented the spraying of bringel
presents hazards to both the consumers
and to the people who are doing the
spring we have evidence it's very clear
that the current system of producing
bringel is quite hazardous I I talked to
some farmers in Maharashtra 2 years ago
and I was asking about BT bringel and
they said yeah we spray two or three
times a week and I look kind of
horrified I said but not up to 5 days
before Harvest right because all of the
these these bottles of poison saying do
not spray within 5 days of harvest and
they said oh yes up to the hour of
harvest if we have to the worms are
there and uh I look horrified again and
and they they saw they saw my reaction
they said oh but we wouldn't feed this
to our families this just goes to the
market so uh but there's a genuine
Hazard involved in the current use of uh
current ways of growing r
that would be alleviated to a large
extent by growing BT brid but that's but
the regulator was of course risk averse
rather
than so I've kind of already said this
uh and the reason that science has a
hard time is rum spells unknown unknowns
Black Swan phenomenon right and in human
behavior we have tons of loss dominates
game right so if you're healthy you're
walk in the supermarket you do not want
to do anything thing that might cause
some small no matter how small the the
risk you don't want to take a risk if
you don't have to and so you get very
powerful risk politics uh I guess the
most impressive way to and science has
no no answer to this right so there you
there is no answer to uncertainty if you
don't know you don't know I want to give
one example of this in the in the
vaccine debate you know
that most people that can read would
know that um all of the official signs
says there's no risk of autism from a
vaccine but suppose there's a shadow of
a doubt suppos there a tiny tiny chance
that the studies aren't adequate or they
haven't done enough studies or they'll
change the studies next month you you
have absolutely no risk in not
vaccinating your children so long as her
immunity is maintained in your area
right so if her immunity is maintained
even though you're free writing on
everybody else's vaccinations there's no
risk to you but the fact that her
immunity is being lost in many areas and
vaccination rates are declining this
indicates that this risk discourse is
very very powerful even though it's a
tiny tiny tiny tiny risk one other
example is interesting one of our former
students um did a study of raw milk
consumption that there 13 more states
allowing raw milk consumption now than
there were like 10 years ago and I was I
was kind of stunned by this I we were
getting more rather than less health
conscious right uh CDC has these big
block capitals do not treat raw milk um
90% of the of the the illnesses from
drinking milk come from raw milk so I I
asked this student who comes from a
dairy farm in in California you I just
asked her about her farm and her feeling
about raw milk this stud said this is
terrible this is really horrible all
these people drinking raw milk I said
have you ever drunk any raw milk said
well of course we all drink raw milk on
my farm but it's my cow
right so she trusts the raw milk on her
Farm just like the farmers gr brel that
I talked to they're not going to use
poison on the brils if they eat they're
going to use poison on the bringel for
the market okay so I mentioned cell
phones early on right it's a classic
case there's no debate about safety of
cell phones actually from the time cell
phones came out there has been a certain
amount of debate this is from science
May 27th as last week or two weeks ago
um tumors in rats from cell phone
radiation that's non ionizing radiation
so you think how can there be tumors
well no one's quite sure but the
critical question here is and as usual
it comes with a caveat that studies of
rodents can mean little for humans so
rational person says I don't care how
many rats you've killed with a transed
crop in how many studies it may not
apply very well to humans and in fact
the rat is not a very good model for
human physiology so we had this problem
of of cell phones all adopted everybody
adopts cell phones why is it because
utility is so high that even as the risk
goes up people's risk utility balance
stays on the side of utility you don't
see any campaigns against cell phones
there are no demands to label cell
phones although Scandinavia they do
label the the output radiation but
basically uh We've accepted the risk
utility
Matrix for cell phones and we don't for
GMO food okay so what divides
politics there's no single Dimension
this is unusual somebody studies
International politics uh they're not
variations of a North South pattern
developed underdeveloped Rich poor or
Democratic authoritarian they cross all
of those lines there is no Dimension to
This Global Rift unlike all the rest of
international politics
so I want to talk a little bit about
risk politics in food so we've said
there are a number of claims about GMOs
and the risk and find their benefits
talk a little bit about food because we
know from prior to GMOs that pervasive
anxiety about food drives politics this
is a longstanding issue and it comes up
every year CDC at one point said 5,000
people a year die of of uh food safety
in fraction the United States they've
reduced that to 3,000 these are
epidemiological estim nobody knows how
good they are we know lots of people die
from problems with food safety in the
United States um there's a distrust of
Institutions and of course in the EU
this was especially TR man cow disease
and several other catastrophes where
State science got it wrong okay and then
there's this capacious political opening
for risk entrepreneurs if you have high
anxiety and it's almost impossible to
convince people of safety then you have
a capacious political opening the risk
entrepreneurs here's one so what do we
do we rely on epistemic Brokers this is
one of my favorites this is food bab
people know food
bab yeah okay so food bab it's time to
break free from the toxins in your food
now food bab she looks very friendly for
somebody who's taking toxins out of your
food um but this is what I call an
epistemic broker people all over the
world are in networks looking for cues
about who do you trust nobody out there
reads cell nature or science right so
what they're looking for is epistemic
Brokers that they can get cues from that
crystallize the information they need
and so here's EP broker one the
food here's Science
Guy we going to trust right
so here's a science guy this kind of
dingy ill lit room talking
to small crowds with some kind of cheesy
PowerPoint you know and he's got he's
got a rat here looks like it's got It's
a Ser rat you
know store so that this guy and look at
this right he represents the Department
of State goes around the world trying to
convince people and this looks kind of
like a a gray bureaucratic are they
really on the side of food safety I
don't think so right so um so this this
is the broker number two and they're
many like days um and here look this is
love the food B way so who are you going
to trust in this kind of competition you
social media networks who are you going
to follow you going to follow Peter the
food bab well food bab does very well
okay um so does she this is V Shea now
her Advantage is not being as attractive
as the food babe her Advantage is that
she claims to be a scientist which is
not true she is has the advantage of
indigeny the authority that comes from
indigen
Indian female woman right there amid
some kind of grain problem so this is
this is a different kind of epistemic
broker but you'd be
astonished how powerful she is she gets
$50,000 a lecture in the United States
astonishing what am I being paid
today I'll have another
chip this is one of Peter's favorites
she's the one that tells us then finally
we said it institutions there is
empirically evidence that the the
perception of mass publics compared to
perception of scientists is diverging a
bit more than it had before so if you
ask scientists about global warming and
GMOs the Divergence has increased and
the public is less scientific than it
used to be relative to the scientific
community so the FDA uh the power
Monsanto dominates the FDA so in fact we
can't trust anything the FDA says right
and of course there the these incredibly
powerful campaigns sweet kid and and
he's he's being killed along with the
bees and he's he's in a bee protest GMOs
killing all it's such a sweet picture
you don't see his face and maybe start
okay uh so let me Su up the
wrist there are very few general laws
because there's great volatility of time
and place and population if somebody had
told me two years ago or even 6 months
ago that Donald Trump would be heading a
major American political party I mean
seriously seriously how can that happen
so politics is inherently
unpredictable okay um but celebrity
predictably drives a lot of politics
think the food babe has his treat she
she has absolutely no background in
Science Biology food anything but she
has this kind of presence she celebrity
yes why is Parris Hilton important well
she's a celebrity why is she a celebrity
because she's a celebrity and that's the
Donald Trump phomen okay so this
volatility of time and place means we
have no general laws it's hard to come
up with a covering law that makes any
sense for politics but we do know that
loss dominates gain and secondly there's
pervasive anxiety about food as creates
political openings history matters
compare nuclear power if you're doing
the RIS risk benefit analysis pre and
post
Fukushima very different kind of
analysis or think about the malthusian
anxiety no countries in the world oppose
the Green Revolution right Green
Revolution plants to resolve world
hunger were sold on the grounds that we
had a volusian crisis people were going
to die in Starvation and we got public
science involved a tremendous increase
in productivity of our major food crops
in fact 8,000
High yielding varieties were introduced
if you count all of them all over the
world huge numbers of improvements in
Plants uh and that malthusian anxiety
the benefit of doing that overcame there
was no risk discour why was there no
risk discour there were no transnational
organizations right the transnational
advocacy organizations did not exist at
this time there was no green piece
there's no friends of the earth none of
those people were in the political game
they are now dominating the political
game in many places and finally I don't
know what happened to my brain here but
I forgot the last point which is that
structure matters so who these groups
can approach where they have a chance to
have influence where the veto points are
where the choke points are varies from
country to country but transnational
advocacy networks have been tremendously
effective at blocking biotechnology all
over the
world for example so this is this is a
green piece uh we're not Lab Rats and
every single sign is the same they're
all middle class people they're all in
cities and they had a tremendous impact
on what 9 years of field test lab test
scientific consensus about the BT gr
will be good for farmers and good for
health and environment it was blocked
right so we have to think about this the
power now GRE piece has been essentially
delegitimized in India it's been
thrown out of the country in an
important sense and Cornell was blamed
for this I'm particularly blamed for
that GRE okay so how how might things
change I don't want to end on a
pessimistic Note One
Way what here's our problem for how
things might change rist therapies are
as difficult to stand out as garlic
mustard everybody here P garlic
mustard I mean it doesn't go away every
time you break off a St plant it's just
H like it's like Asian foil so okay so
um it's not going to happen these risk
narratives will not go away the
Terminator Gene HX is still floating
around India and it was used in a high
Court decision in the Philippines it's
not there even after we knew that
farmers were underground taking this
technology and pocket free new varieties
of e c even after that and even F A sha
she was complaining about the failure of
the government to stop all these Farmers
from creating new hybrids at BT cotton
dozens of new hybrids of DT cotton while
talking about the Terminator gen right
so how do you cre new varities plant
that kill itself anyway so uh how I
think to you're not going to wipe out
these narratives these narratives are
very very durable so one quick story um
there's a book by Heath and Heath called
made to stick about how ideas are stuck
in people's minds and they have an
example at the last chapter they said
how do you unstick the stuck idea and
they actually we have very few examples
Sarah is working on the other side of
this Sarah may be unsticking things but
on the other side of this he said the
only example they could come up with was
Ray Croc who ran McDonald's I think
that's the right name he ran McDonald's
and he was accused of having worms in
his hamburgers how can he have such
cheap hamburgers well he puts worms in
his hamburgers Ray Croc does on TV and
he says now here we have hamburger it's
39 cents a pound here we have worms
night crawlers a bought from the local
bait shop 29 pound I can't afford
to and they said that's an example of
coming unstuck the mean is businessmen
are out there to make money Ray Croc
would not be grinding up nightcrawlers
to put into his hamburgers so this must
be so he kind of McDonald's went from
there success to success anyway so this
is this is just a a kind of a counter I
I firmly believe uh in Sarah's narra but
how might things change so so and this
is this is my other example the autism
business this is unbelievable by the way
this was also promoted by someone like
the food Bay Jenny McCarthy who was a a
playmate of the year or something like
that but this was also supported by
celebrities mer jelen's disease the the
House of Representatives voted to give a
million dollars to CDC to investigate a
disease it's a it's a invention by a
psychotic 17th century Spanish physician
and their website from margel deceased
CDC said this is a the web hoax we don't
want to deal with it and the Congress
said we've got to spend a million
dollars investigating margel disease so
there's a report marel disase says we
can't find any evidence from marel
disease we're sorry we just wasted a
million dollars so that the power of
these kinds of narratives uh should not
be underestimated and of course if you
think about suppose you have this kind
of
narrative taking apart every piece of
that you know Monet doesn't really own
our government and is it really poison
our food really just taking that apart
requires a kind of activity which is so
much more demanding than this bumper
right okay so maybe increased utility
for consumers so fill in your favorite
bot G desire here let's say got you know
sugar without calories or something like
that um or gamechanging non planned
applications of Biotech and here I I
think the combination of of climate
change which Sarah mentioned and also
nonplant applications biotech may turn
this corner and the zika virus is kind
of my favorite in the 80s egypti carries
five four really really deadly um
diseases yellow fever chicken cumia uh
Dy and now the zika uh if you could wipe
that little mosquito out you know no
great loss to the human rights it's
invasive anyway um you might have a game
Cher for increasing a massive Global
benefit uh at the risk of getting rid of
a pest thank
you very much and justly switch from
Sarah to Ron I wanted to open up the
floor for any questions or comments
thanks for those great talks these are
uh the person many of you share this
it's a very plexing problem frustra to
all of us it's great to see people so
passion trying to do something about it
so kudos to you
guys
really so any any comments
questions Randy yeah um I'm not I'm
neither Pro nor con GE
but um I noticed that Sarah's um slides
were labeled for the liance for Science
and Ron's t-shirt was labeled I assume
because you're proud of the alliance for
Science and and my feeling is to argue
against
labeling just show just to
me neither Pro nor
con just indicates a lack of pride
[Music]
GMO
Foods labeling Foods yeah
so your argument you're against labeling
so no I'm I'm actually for labeling
because it would show I'm proud of this
yeah yeah yeah no I think that's a
really strong argument for labeling um I
think it's the best start for labeling
actually that you know this if this
isn't something that we think should be
demonized then label it and and and it
it can be a good thing like pasturized
milk so yeah I I don't actually have a
position on labeling I think um I
struggle a little bit with it because
why would we label something as if it's
as if it's dangerous when there's no
scientific basis that it's dangerous but
on the other hand I think that the best
thing we can do is label it and people
get over it and and maybe they'll sele
itate like we do with P Mo or slightly
change your labels so now you say
instead of saying contains GMO which is
kind of like got worms or something of
this you say contains high quality GMO
ingredients right emphasizing that this
is an improvement that save the envir
yeah producing pesticide application and
if you look at like Arctic Apple for
example I mean there're and and I think
um Theo also like they're really
promoting and branding their product as
something special
um and and it's GM and it's special and
and they're branding it as such I
support labeling for different reason
because I think it it's going to it's
going to create a tremendous wave of
inquiry and and questioning because
every state government every
municipality everybody around the
country be huge numers of lawsuits the
USDA has officially said you can't call
things GMO free because we don't
recognize the concept of GMO right I
mean we have substantial equivalents so
I think if you allow people to start
labeling things GMO it's like the
question of natural unnatural people are
labeling things natural what does that
mean so I think actually labeling is
fine um because the the negative Fallout
if you refuse to label things is what
are you hiding that's right that's
that's my absolutely so I don't see I
don't see any downside I see no downside
to labeling but within that it's a
matter of whether it's mandatory or
optional labeling because if you're
making it mandatory labeling of process
that's only the only process we're
requiring people to label why aren't we
saying you know this was from radiation
breeding so it's singling out it'll be
the only process that is forced to be
labeled as opposed to Sarah's example is
optional Laing well we still AR to be
proud of it and then put that on their
label that it's GE but do we want the
federal government to say that this is
the only process we're going to
label we do label other things by how
they're made like the the
sweat shop free texes fair
trade it's no it's a marketing thing it
is
very but the whole labeling fit is about
whether mandate Mand
optional so pride pride comes in op or
Artic say hey you should buy this John
did you ever manage to succeed in deated
coffee that's what well yeah this is one
of the one of the problems about doing
it um
outside of a big company which are
always demonized is that it's a big
project we started working with coffee
and you have to have a transformation
system um and if you develop your own
you have to spend millions of dollars
getting it all all through regulatory
apparatus so you want to buy it from
someone else well coffee doesn't work on
a lot of them that's the first problem
and then just everything is is you know
raising enough money it's a different um
marketing strategy so you go to Monsanto
and say hey you want to partner with us
and they go well how we going to make
money on this cuz the trees grow forever
you know and and so there's all these
kind of things it's really hard for
small companies to do this um but one
one of the comments I wanted to make is
is uh and it came from this study that
Florida State put out a while back from
I forgot what the department was it was
like the egg economics guys um
looking to do a survey to figure out
well how should we label things one of
the things in in it turned out that
people don't understand anything one of
the things they asked about was um uh
something like 33% of the people that
they surveyed thought that vegetables
did not contain DNA and one of the other
questions 80% of the people answered
that every plant product that has DNA in
it should be labeled 80% no I mean
I I I don't know I don't even know where
to go with them where were these in
science
class but you know so I don't know what
labeling does and just one other quick
comment I started doing working with
genetically modified organ really early
on like in the mid 70s and we saw the
same thing in everything back then I
remember this guy named Jeremy Jeremy
Ripken I don't know whatever happened to
him but he was against everything and I
think when products came out in the the
pharmaceutical industry after and this
went into the '90s
and you know everybody's aged parent was
taking something that you know that's
pretty good you know so I think that
risk thing is is is maybe goes to that
and other things like they came out with
with um uh uh like some of the proteins
factors for like clotting that were were
you know completely GMO made and a whole
a whole generation of Hemophilia were
wiped out by AIDS because they were
taking stuff from plasma and you know it
wasn't and so I think maybe you need
something like that to turn it
around I we thought maybe our coffee
would if we could then then 2008 came up
and you couldn't raise a dime anywhere
so that was
like but it's yeah it's a really
difficult thing for for you it's amazing
that the papaya thing got through that
that they could do that on such a shoe
string
amazing that was before Jeremy
ruin no it was after way after way after
he was he was the 70s it as a concept I
mean it was before the you know the
controversy when the papaya got through
before GMO was a household name and
before Green Peace yeah it was pretty
early on but it was there was still a
lot of controversy because I I've spent
20 years at University of Hawaii where
the breeder that worked on the project
Richard mansart worked and that was a
it's still there there is still within
the last it's worse than ever within the
last 6 months or so I was just talking
to someone whose father grows papayas or
brother grows papayas on the big island
that that were the transgenic ones
someone came in and chopped all his
plants down one week one long weekend
yeah sitation in Hawaii is in terms of
yeah it's it's a hot bed of of growing
GMOs cuz sna monsan Pine everybody has
has Laboratories there and winter seed
production there and it's also a hot bed
of anti-gmo sentiment
so I don't
[Music]
know guess we're still left with a lot
of
questions
to any other thoughts or
comments we can spend a long time
talking about this topic may you can
talk about it some refreshments Ron I
was I am I am now officially owed with
the power to propose that we all go get
something to drink and then we'll do a
toast to Peter
who's the man of the
hour this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu