this is a production of Cornell
University uh good morning and I would
like to first start by thanking aloy for
the invitation so and the opportunity to
talk to you about the work I do in the
lab today I'm going to focus on one of
the lines of Investigation we have in
the lab which is in natural products and
I'm really glad to say that because of
that meeting with the ly um when I
joined Cornell years ago um I couldn't
fight anymore and said okay we'll work
on natural products because I thought I
was going to stop working natural
products I I did some work on natural
products at my PhD and I'm and post do
and I'm going to mention it today but I
thought okay I'm that's going to be it
I'm going to move on to better and newer
things and then I back to natural
products and and I think I'm very happy
that I Revisited uh that
area so so um just a brief outline of
what I'm going to discuss today so I'm
going to tell you about what are cancer
stem cells specifically what is leukemia
what are leukemia stem cells and um the
way I see what are the challenges on
eliminating leukemia stem cells um the
compounds uh that we're using to Target
lemia stem cells the strategies we're
using to deliver these compounds and uh
in animals at this point and all other
other natural
products so I would like to begin with
describing what cancer stem cells are
and to me the best analogy to think
about is plants um since we're talking
about plants plants is the best analogy
well not just plants
weeds and uh I guess you hear in Etha
are more familiar with this view Us in
New York we never see this so I like to
dream that that's what I would like to
see um so we typically see weeds in our
Gardens and they're annoying we want our
grass to be really green so what we
think is the best way to eliminate that
we is come with the um with the w Walker
is not the wood wer with the lawn mower
and um the wood is gone however we all
know if that that's not going to solve
the problem if we don't get rid of that
root that we is going to come back and
be there again so cancer stem cells are
pretty much the same thing are the root
of the disease is the root of the cancer
and we need to eliminate that cancer we
need to eliminate that
root so I specifically focus on leukemia
and in general leukemia is considered a
rare disease when it's compared to bre
prostate cancer or breast cancer it
affects around 300,000 people in the US
uh it is estimated that around 54,000
people will be diagnosed with leukemia
uh this
year and it's expected that around
24,000 people will die of this
disease so what Le what is where
leukemia comes from uh I would like to
than um what I like to think I would
like to First describe the hematopoetic
system so we can discuss leukemia and
and the blood system is highly
regenerative and to me it's highly it's
very fascinating because if you think
about how many cells were using every
single day and I put this Li just as an
example because every time I look at
this lie I go wow it doesn't matter how
many times I see it but these numbers
are real just as an example 2.4 million
new arthrit are made per second per
second as we're speaking we're just
making tons and tons and tons and tons
and probably exercise we making even
more so um neutr fils as is a most
abundant white blood cell and 5 billion
neutr fils are produced every hour of
the day and if you notice also the
lifespan of these cells is very short so
to keep this highly uh regenerative
system you need a very powerful cell
that can maintain this every day and
this powerful cell is what we known as a
PL poent stem cell the pl poent stem
cell is a cell that can give rise to
both the lymphoid a lymphoid progenitor
and myoid
progenitor these cells has a very high
capacity of self renew and can give rise
to these progenitors that are more
committed to give rise to mature blood
cells and as they differentiate into the
hierarchy the ability to sell prew
decreases so you can imagine this this
has to be tightly regulated so what
happens with this regulation is um uh
mutated or something goes wrong you stop
making mature blood cells and what
happens is immature blood cells
accumulate in the blood and and then
this is what we called um or known about
leukemia so leukemia is an accumulation
of immature blood cells and these are
known as leukemic blasts they could be
of the myoid system or the lymphoid um
hierarchy so then it will be myoid
leukemias or lymo leukemias my
laboratory specifically focuses on myoid
leukemias
so what what is the origin of leukemia
it has been hypothesized that either a
hematopoetic stem cell or a hematopoetic
progenitor will have one two or more
oncogenic events that will give rise to
a leukemia stem cell this leukemia stem
cell also has a capacity to self-renew
and give rise to progenitors this in
this case leukemic progenitors which in
turn will give rise to the leukemic
blast but what I want you to think is
not what leukemia comes from what I want
you to think is how heterogeneous
leukemia is so in a single patient
you're going to have leukemia blast
leukemic progenitors and leukemic stem
cells and the problem becomes then when
you look at the outcomes of patients
with AML or acute myen of leukemia which
is what I would like you to focus on
because this is a big problem and that's
the reason we work in
AML so in the in the past 40 years years
you can see that the outcomes of AML are
really poor and they have not changed at
all uh you can see
1973 and
2002 2008 the Cs are pretty much on top
of each
other H in patients over 55 years old so
and the reason is not because uh the
therapy doesn't work is the reason is
because standard of care works in the
sense that most patients with AML when
they go to standard induction they will
go into remission so around 85% of
patients that get get
chemotherapy will achieve complete
remission the problem is that most of
these patients are going to relapse very
rapidly and then die of disease so
that's what the outcomes are always poor
and that's what the therapy has not
changed because there is nothing so far
that is better than that
85% and the reason we like to think is
because this again this heterogenity on
the cells what happens is the patient
comes with AML and then under go current
standard of care and we know that
there's disease left behind and we like
to call that minimal residual disease
and it's minimal residual disease
because we know it's there and in many
cases is very hard to detect unless we
can track a mutation and other um
features of that particular leukemia but
most of the cases this still a black box
but we know there's disease left behind
why because the patient relaxes we would
like to think that the reason that the
patient relaxes is because there are
leukemia stem cells Left Behind which
again has have the capacity to self
renew and give rise to disease so um my
focus has been to try to find and
identify differences between a leukemia
stem cell and a normal hematopoetic stem
cell in order to be able to eliminate
leukemia stem cells with without harming
normal hematop stem cells so stem cells
can be identified by imop phenotype and
I'm here putting the Min phenotype I
knew when I started doing this research
many many years ago which they were
pretty much identical they were Define a
c34 positive c38 negative HDR
negative so what is the clinical
implications so yes you tell me all
these very nice hypothesis but is that
actually clinical evidence that suggest
that this population is important and
the answer is yes there is many papers
that have shown that patients that have
higher proportions of c34 positive cd8
NE c38 negative U cells in the bone
marrow or in the peripheral blood it
always correlates with poor outcomes so
patients do wors if they have high
proportions of this population of
cells
so why would the high St of frequency
correlate with po
outcomes um I'm going to show you the
experiments we did to to demonstrate
that lemia stem cells were resistant to
chemotherapy but before um describing
those experiments I want to briefly
describe the acid just in case people
are not familiar with it uh which what
we do is take B glucemia cells we treat
them with cabin or whatever drug of
choice we we want and we stain the cells
with an nexting and 7 a so cell that is
alive and intact U you'll have phospher
a phospho lipid in the inner lifelet of
the membrane of the cell and the nucleus
uh and the DNA in the nucleus will be
unaccessible because the cell is intact
as the cell starts undergoing apoptosis
what it's going to happen is the phospha
theal sering is going to flip to the
outside lifet of the cell and then an
exing can bind to that phosphat serin
and stay in that cell as the cell
continues the process of cell death then
the nucleus becomes available because
the cell becomes very permeable and then
7 ad which is a a DNA die will stay the
nucleus and the cell will know that the
cell is dead so we Mark these cells
which are an next negative 780 negative
as live
cells so what we observe when we take
total bulk AML and treat with cabin
which is the drug that is used for
standard of care we see that this drug
work we see more than 50% of the cells
are actually dying or dead so the
conclusion is yes this this drug is
actually working uh
however what happens is if we focus on
leukemia stem cell population the fin is
34 positive 38 negative population you
see these cells are intact most of the
cells are not touched with this
chemotherapy and therefore are
surviving so why are they're
surviving when we look at cells that are
more mature Define as 34 positive 38
positive and label them with a a
proliferation marker known as Ki 67 you
can see that there cells that are
proliferating and in in contrast when
you look at the leukemia stem cells 34
positive 38 negative cells most of them
are quiescent they are not proliferating
and if you think about the chemotherapy
when it was designed it was designed
under the basis that cancer cell grow
very
rapidly and that the best way to
eliminate this cancer was to block their
ability to their ability to proliferate
so these cells do not proliferate
therefore they cannot be eliminated by
standard of care that targets
proliferating
cells so that's nice however when we
compare the the quiessence of leukemia
stem cell that's a feature that is
shared with hematopoetic stem cells so
both of them are quiescent so we cannot
just pick a drug that will kill
quiescent cells because they will have
normal hematopoetic cells and as an
example I'm showing you cabin which is
the standard of care which is the worst
of all things does a pretty bad job of
killing lukemia stem cells and does a
decent job and harming normal
hematopoetic stem cells so it cannot
discriminate between these two
populations and there for is not a good
drug to kemia stem
cells so this was how everything started
um over 10 years
ago um and now we know more Market that
can distinguish a leukemia stem cell
from a normal hematopoetic stem cell and
they are all labeled in green are the
markers that are found in this in
positive in either cell and in red are
are labeled the markers that are absent
in either cell so you can see there are
a good number of markers that can
distinguish a leukemia stem cell from a
normal hematopoetic stem cell and the
list will keep growing and
growing however I have to tell you the
disclaimer which is these will change in
Patient to Patient to Patient to Patient
because we are all different and
Leukemia stem cells are also different
between patients so the best way to
define a leukemia stem cell will be by
function so what we do in the lab is
perform functional assay which means it
evaluates the ability of a leukemia stem
cell or a or a progenitor cell
to give rise to
progeny so one of these assays is the
colon forming assay the colon forming
aay what it does it measures the ability
of a progenitor stem cell to give rise
to progeny in the case of hematopoetic
cells what we see will be normal
colonies and in the case of the leukemic
cell we'll see leukemic
colonies and the gold standard assay is
what we know as the cenot transplant aay
which will measure stem Cel activity in
the case of um hematopoetic cells if we
inject them in an immuno deficient mice
we will see normal hematopoesis normal
human hematopoesis in the mouth and in
the case of leukemia what we will see is
Leukemia in this mouth but the best way
to prove that is indeed a cell that has
the ability to self-renew you have to do
serial transplantation so then you
should be able to propagate the disease
again and again and again and again and
again forever and ever if you have a
stem
cell so um these are the assays that we
use in the
lab so based on that uh then the next
thing is can we find molecular features
that can identify a lemia stem cell from
a normal hematopoetic stem cell and take
advantage of that feature to fill the
cell so we found that feature and that
feature is NF capab NF capab is a
transcription factor that is involved
in growth and survival responses in
tumors and the way it works is in a
normal cell NF capab will be find
inactive in the cytoplasm of the cell
and it can maintain be it can be
maintained inactive by its inhibitor
called IA B Alpha Upon A stimuli that
could be many different types of stimula
like um infection for example in the
case of normal cells uh NF Capa IAB B
Alpha will get phosphorilated and then
degraded by the
proteosome leing an Capa free to go to
the nucleus and start the transcription
of genes involving survival
proliferation and
inflammation so that's what NF capab
does so what we found was that in
leukemic stem cells NF capab was
constitutively activated in the nucleus
shown here by a uh DNA binding acid and
in contrast normal hematopoetic cells
did not have NF capab constitut the
active when we found this first uh we
were not surprised that NF capab was
constitutively active in in AML because
it already had been reported to be
critical for the survival and
proliferation of tumors many other
tumors but what actually surprised me
was when we look at the very primitive
quiescent stem cells NF capab was also
constitutively active so these cells are
quiescent are resting but yet they have
this transcription Factor constitutively
on so that led us to think and
hypothesize uh can we use this unique
characteristic to eliminate leukemia
stem cells can we target NF capab to
selectively eliminate leukemia stem
cells without harming normal hoptic stem
cells so to do this we turn to
plants and we use this compound called
perano which is derived from a a plant
known as fever
Fu and it's called fever Fu because it
has been used for many years to decrease
fevers as its name uh says and but it
has other uh medicinal uses such as um
relieve migraines endotoxic shock and
stomach eggs arthritis asthma skin
rashes tumors insect repellent and so
forth and so on there are many uses
which fever F has been listed for in
ethnobotany chemically is a c
and it was well known to be a potent
inhibitor of
NCA by now with all the research we've
done and other groups we know that uh
parite also depletes stle and has many
other targets but at the time it was
listed as a very poent NF cap inhibitor
so we tried
it what we found is when we use n pareno
in leukemia stem cells shown in here we
saw that most of the the the leukemia
cells from different AML patients each
line represents an AML patient sample
these leukemia stem cells were
eliminated with a concentration of five
micro of
pareno in contrast when we look at
normal hematopoetic stem cells you can
see these cells at five microl
concentration were not affected by this
compound so this demonstrated that
peroly can very effectively eliminate
leukemia stem cells not harming uh
normal hematop stem cells but this is
just based by phenotype we also
corroborated this uh
using sorry the functional assays that I
mentioned to you which first we did The
Colony forming assays and you can see
that treatment with pareno decreased
very significantly the ability of uh
leukemia cells to give rise to colonies
but did not affect the ability of a
normal hematopoetic stem cells to give
rise to normal red blood cell colonies
and a white blood cell colonies
and more importantly when we treated the
cells with parthenolide and then
transplanted them into imuno deficient
mice to assess the function of these
cells we found that treatment with
paroli eliminated the ability of these
leukemia stem cells to give rise to
leukemia but it not affected the ability
of normal hematopoetic stem cells to
give rise to normal hematopoesis so this
demonstrated that indeed pareno was a
very poent inhibitor of um
of leukemia stem cell
function we needed to corroborate that
the reason that perite work was because
our hypothesis we wanted to corroborate
that we're indeed inhibiting NF
capab so the way we I'm going to show it
to you is using inun floresent which in
a leukemia stem cell n capab will be
active in the nucleus and in this case
will be staying with yellow so you'll
see it in the nucleus and we expect that
if we inhibit paral life an capu go back
to the cytoplasm where it belongs so
what we found is indeed the treatment
with perano inhibited effectively n
capab in these leukemia cells and the
other feature that paroli did was a very
potent induction of reactive oxygen
species in this case measured with a
transcription Factor known as Nrf2 Nrf2
in a control cell will be found in the
cytoplasm but if it if this R signal
gets activated it will go to the nucleus
and and then will activate transcription
and indeed perol resulted in activation
of Nrf2 demonstrated that it's inducing
reactive oxy
species so everything is very nice and
beautiful and we found something that
can kill leukemia St cell but of course
paroly cannot be used in humans as it is
why
because it has very poor solubility and
bioavailability
uh in animal studies when parol was used
at 40 milligram per kilogram which is
the maximum amount you can solubilize
this
compound um very low amount was detected
in the plasma of this mice which was 200
nanom so if you remember I told you we
need at least five micro to kill
leukemia so this amount will not be
useful to treat animals or
people so for those reason we started
collaborating with Dr Peter krooks
to make medicinal analog to
paralite and uh what we found was the
map which is a soluble analog of paroli
and I just point out here the timeline
so it it takes a long time to go through
all this process to make a medicinal
analog and take it to phase one clinical
trials so the map is right now in
clinical trials and we're expecting to
see what happened with this compound um
to see if it actually would kill human
stem cells in
patients but I since since I'm in Etha I
would like to talk about the studies we
did in dogs um because I um I think this
is very interesting and very cool and
and I think you guys will appreciate it
more um than other people so we use
canine leukemias and I have to point out
that this is not a leukemia stem cell
model uh these were advanced containing
cd34 positive
leukemias and at the time that we
started this collaboration which we
sorry was a collaboration that was
established um by chance so what
happened is we published the paper with
paranoide we received a phone call of
AET and said hey would can we use your
compounding dogs dogs have AML and they
di very rapidly of AML there's nothing
for them can we try it so we thought
that would be cool but we don't know
anything about dog leukemias we don't
even know if an if capab would be active
in dog leukemias so the very first thing
we did is tested ffab was constitutively
active in leukemias of dogs and the
answer was yes so we did checked and
then the second thing well would
paranoide work in this dog leukemia in
vitro and the answer was yes we also
tested normal bone marrow from dogs
healthy dogs and we found that par pite
was not harmful to normal hematopoesis
of dogs so with that in hand we said
okay let's do it let's try it and we
tested in three dogs so the end is very
small but I thought the results would
really big and change how we saw perite
for clinical
trials so we three dogs with Advanced
c34 positive
leukemias we treated them with the m
different doses different schedules
because that dose and schedule was
dependent on
the the the I guess the dog the size of
the dog and how far the the bed Clinic
was and and
also we we knew um we knew all the
pharmacology of uh the map in dogs
because that was a study that was done
to take the the drug to clinical trials
so we knew that a dose of 100 Mig per
kilogram was the maximum tolerated dose
for the dog so in even in that sense we
were lucky we had that
information so so we took different time
forms we collected peripheral blot we
check the white L cell counts we look at
c34 because was the only marker that we
knew and there are very few markers
available for closy ometry to look at
dog
cells and then we also look at our
biological markers of course NF capab
and in this case to measure reactive
oxygen species or stress we use gamma H2
and mainly because it cross reactors
with
dog so uh what we
saw is first we saw an increase this is
an example of one of the dogs we saw a
very marked increase on white blood cell
counts after the treatment with the m 50
Mig per
kilogram what we saw too was a decrease
in the expression of cd34 positive in
these leukemia cells so this data was
suggesting to us that the leukemia cells
were
differentiating potentially into normal
white blood cells before they they they
die and what we observed was indeed the
MP was causing differentiation of
leukemic cells in
Vio and of course it was inhibiting NF
cap in
Vio so um these pieces of evidence
confirmed that indeed parol in cap but
the surprise to us was was that in Vio
in dock dmap was inducing
differentiation rather than just
immediate s dead as we saw in
vitro this was a major change for how we
Dr the clinical trial because then we we
thought you know maybe it's a good idea
to First decrease the white L cell C of
the patient because you don't want to
have um tumor liis syndrome in people we
did observe tumor license syndrome in
one of the dogs so this was a very lucky
I think for us to be able to feed these
animals and be able what happens when
you have uh a spontaneous lemia where
you have dog leukemia in dog micro
environment which we don't see of course
in the Cog grabs that that's the part
we're missing when we treat xenographs
because you have human cells in Mouse
micro environment which is not the same
as you see
people but you might want to want you
might wonder what happened with the
leukemia stem cells this was a shot we
took in the dark because we don't even
know if the animal if we could do
xenographs of dogs so we said well let's
just try it the wor that can happen is
that nothing happens so what we did is
took cells from day Zero of treatment of
this dog and then day 12 after treatment
of the dog we we transplanted the cells
equal cell number of leukemia cells in
the mouse at Day Zero and in the mouse
at from day
12 and we measured the ability of these
cells to give rise to leukemia in this
mice and what we found was a significant
decrease in the ability of these
leukemia cells to give rise to leukemia
in the mouse what we did next is do
seral transplantation like I told you
the stem cell will be able to
recapitulate disease forever and ever
and ever and what we observe is when we
serially transplanted these cells again
equal cell numbers for dog cells for
this mice we saw a significant decrease
that the significant decrease was even
stronger when uh the cells were serly
transplanted this data strongly
suggested that paroly was indeed
targeting leukemia stem cells uh in
these
animals so um so that that was great and
now we're just waiting to see what
happens with the clinical trials with
people and uh and is still undergoing
but we expect to see similar
observations and the end points that
we're going to take are going to be very
similar to what we did in the
dogs but this always very nice but we're
still trying to think if there is better
ways to take these compounds that are
not soluble that have very poor
pharmacological properties if there is a
way to take them faster to the clinic
and closer to where leukemia stem cells
reside so leukemia stem cells live in
the bone marrow and they like to hide on
top of being chemor resistant and quent
they also like to
hide they like to hide in the industrial
region of the micro of the of the B Maro
where they're also further protected
from chemotherapeutic
drugs so what we thought is why we don't
take uh paranoide as a proof of
principle and use nanop particles to
take parol to the bone
marrow so we took parol uh we U this was
in collaboration with hien he is in
Houston uh we took this the parol we put
it in mles this Mel are covered with
silicone
particles and then these particles are
covered with e selecting tho the E
selecting
theep will guide this nanop particle all
the way to region of the bone marrow as
it will like find is
selecting and then very slowly they
deliver the drug in that area where
leukemia stem cells
reside so before telling you about um
what happened I want to compare and
contrast how we use the nanop particles
with how we use the soluable compound I
tell you about the
DMT so in mice they have life of D mapts
only 30 minutes and the those that we
thought we had to use to achieve the
five microl concentration is 100 mgram
per kilogram so we need to give it three
times a day oral Gage every single day
and just so you get an idea each syringe
represents a dose so I was a post dog
when I was doing this I cannot I can
tell you that was not fun for me or for
the mice nobody was having fun
um but um the worst part and I'm not
going to show it here is in another
paper we already publish the dmap in
mice by itself cannot eliminate tumor
burden you need to combine it with
another drug and we think is because
probably the mice produce more
gluathione and then prevent the activity
of the drug to get to the lemic cells so
if you combine with an anti with with uh
EMP inh with empor Inhibitors you can
potentiate activity of the map in Bol to
kill leukemia in mice I also show you it
works in Ducks without any other stuff
so I think again the biology of each
species is going to be very
important but what was very cool about
the nanop particles is because they are
very slow release we can deliver them
once every two weeks uh via tail pan and
also we loaded as much as we can load of
pereno into that cell which will
represent approximately assuming that
all the perite made it in the animal
will be 2.5 millgram per kilogram uh per
Mouse so you can see it's a huge
difference in
dosing so what we found is that in the
nanop particle paroli was very potent at
eliminating total tumor burden when
compared with the mys uh with peroli or
with the empty nanop
particles we also found that was very
potently inhibiting NF Capa B in
the and the thing that I found really
interesting is when we measure
parthenolide either in the plasma or in
the bones of this mice 1 hour after
bolo's treatment with these nanop
particles we found that there was
nothing in the plasma and everything was
in the bones just in one hour after
injecting these nanop particles
suggesting that this nanopar particles
were very effective at bringing perol
life to the
bones we also did the serial
transplantation to demonstrate that we
actually still killing leukemia stem
cells and we saw these are two PDX
meaning two primary AML samples injected
into the mice we show that the in serial
transplantation will decrease the
ability of leukemia stem cells to give
rise to
disease so uh because all of these part
because of the Great it of paroli
because we find it from natural products
we thought that it would be very
important to start a collaboration with
people that know about plants that know
about chemical um the chemical
structures they know about spin lactones
so we started a collaboration with the
New York Botanical
Gardens with Cornell here with uh Dr
Eloy Rodriguez and with the uh
University of Arkansas and this
collaboration consists in finding plants
that are related
to ffu to find better squint lactones
that will have similar activity to perol
light uh that we can take to the clinic
hopefully in a rapid Manner and
understand better what are the critical
activities of this type of
compounds so I hope to we can have more
updates uh soon but this project is
advancing
ridly so just to switch years after we
talked all about um cquin lacton and and
paranoide I would like to briefly
mention the work of cranberries and the
reason I want to talk about cranberries
is because this work started from a PhD
student that came from um this school
well now she's supposed to talk in New
York but she did her PhD here at Cornell
her name is Lori uh
vrom and she loves cranberries it's her
passion everything she does leaves and
things is cranberries and uh because uh
Dr rodri is uh it's true she Rings
everything with cranberries I'm not
exaggerating um so
um and we're all learning to love
cranberries too so uh she she came to my
lab because Dr Rodriguez mentioned her
uh my name and she wanted to test her
extracts in cancers so I agreed to be
her mentor and uh she had cranberries I
had leukemic cells and we said let's try
it it's a a perfect
combination and uh cranberries as you
all know they are well known because
they are used for urinary tract
infections and also can stimulate immune
system so what we did first is try total
cranberry extract in different uh
leukemia cell lines and this is just an
example of all the leukemia cell lines
we tested and you can see that the
cranberry extracts are very potent and
at causing cell death in leukemia cells
there is a threshold like a lower
concentration that you can see some
cells are more sensitive than other
leukemic cells around here but the
higher you go in the concentration it
seems to work on a leukemia
cells uh we also pu well Lori also
purified the active one of the active
compounds of The Cranberries known as
apacks which are formed from different
multim multimar is not purifi it's not a
purif compound is a mixture of dimer
drers teters and
pentamers and we have also found that
individual um components are not
sufficient to kill the leukemia cells so
this mixture we use at lower
concentrations in primary samples and
did the colony assays and you can see
that uh at 62.5 micrograms per
milliliter we can see that leukemia
progenitor cell activity is decreased
and normal activity of H biotic cells is
not
affected uh we have also done the U the
stem cell we discuss and we see
selectivity against leukemia stem cells
not normal hematop stem
cells and because um we wanted to see if
she can because she really really wanted
to try it in Vio so I said well let's
try it so we set up some cographs we
transplanted primary patient samples in
the mouse we established the cograph the
cograph the animal had leukemia
uh she treated either with PBS sarin or
apx at 25 Mig per kilogram 2 a week
three uh for three weeks and what we
found is that apacks were really uh
poent at eliminating a two more celling
rment almost at the same level as RSC so
this is the standard of care 60 migs per
kilogram which is very toxic to the mice
as in contrast 25 Mig per kilogram which
it was not toxic uh to the animals so
this suggest that these uh cranberry
extracts could be
used uh in um in Vivo to Kure leukemia
and hopefully leukemia stem cells the
secondary transplants are under way so
hopefully we can also show what kills
leukemia stem
cells so just to summarize uh what we
discuss today is that compounds derived
from medicinal plants uh such as perol
and granberry extracts can be used to
Target leukemia stem
cells also that nanop particles
represent that strategy to deliver
compounds uh with put pharmacological
properties into mice um and potentially
also to humans and that other natural
products are currently being studied to
Target leukemia stem cells in general
what we're doing in the lab is trying to
get uh AML samples uh characterize them
well from Patient to Patient do hro put
assays to evaluate the ability of
compounds to kill uh leukemia stem cells
using functional assays and also develop
uh biomarkers so we can uh match a drug
with a
patient and also from the bedside to the
bench when we start the clinical trials
we like to save samples characterize
them well Bank One marrow peripheral
blood plasma so we can do biological
assays to determine if we're targeting
leukemia stem cells in the patients and
also test the biomarkers to make sure
that the drug is doing what it's
supposed to
do and just finally I need to thank the
people that have been working so hard on
these
project first I want to thank my
collaborators and the clinical side
especially Dr G Robos uh who is the
director of the leukemia program at
Corell uh Dr Michael bik is our
collaborator at the New York Botanical
Gardens and he's been getting us a lot
of plants
uh Michael Becker at the University of
Rochester he he provides us uh also
leukemia leukemia cells Peter Crooks and
Cesar Compadre work on the modification
of compounds and the purification of um
the compounds from
Plants uh this is my lab in the summer
it looks busy in the summer we get a lot
of people students high schoolers and
undergrad but it's a lot of fun and
these are the team so this
Lori uh Sabrina and Bernardo were the
pack Grand team meaning they work with
ap packs and cranberries and they named
themselves pack Grand and they held
their logo which was a little Pac-Mans
ship like Pac-Mans ship cranberry eating
Lans
themselves so and then is H Gabby Rachel
she's actually student here from from
corala uh B is from
Ecuador Mar
and uh yes let me see one person and
Gabby but she's not in this picture they
are from the weeds team they couldn't
come up with a better name but that
means that they focus on the plants like
FF and all other um medicinal plants
we're getting from uh the newor
Botanical Gardens and this is the
funding that of course without funding I
would be doing nothing uh but just
thinking about it um and thank you to
you for your
attention have you got any uh like gene
expression or anything with the cells to
see if anything besides NF Cap B is
affected with the with parol we did so
and we found many other parol like
compounds using the Gen expression
signature of
Leukemia and uh the strongest signature
is inhibition of NF
cap and activation of reactive oxygen
species uh We've also done modifications
of paranoide with biotin so we can pull
down its targets so when we did that we
found that paranoide has other targets
that are involving metabolism and that
was reported by my previous Mentor CH
Jordan and other people have also found
that can also affect epigenetic
Machinery so in general uh per light
will bind to any protein that will have
a preyin or any th group that is
available um so it is not just an NK
inhibitor we use it because of that
feature but it causes many more
things yes what is the mechanism for the
nanop particles to move the the paral wi
into the right place
where so it is it is label on the
surface of the nanoparticle with an E
selecting thomer so it's a very tiny
peptide that can buy etin so etin is
expressed in the endothelium and is
found in very high amounts in
endothelium of the bone marrow so that's
how it it's guided there so it's really
cool but it's very expensive so we're
trying to find other ways to take them
right there
so the DPT studies um in the K9 model
then induces diff differentiation so in
in AML then of course I mean
differentiation induction therapy has
been remarkably ineffective so those are
really exciting results and I was
wondering if you've tried or if anyone
has tried to look at you know how the
DPT works in the K9 model it doesn't
presume work in in in the human
primaries yet uh no I mean that would be
very nice but at the time you know all
everything happened so fast like really
so fast that uh the amount of cells we
had it was not a lot but I mean thinking
back yes we even discussed this at some
point with with Greg it would be nice if
we had cells left over to see what
happened to those cells what is the
signature in the dog cells but first of
all we had no experience with dogs we
don't know anything about dogs we were
just working with the with these three
animals so I think uh just I was talking
to Christie yesterday I think it's a
great opportunity to work and uh with
dogs and try to understand more about
the biology of these compounds in a
system where um hopefully we'll be more
similar to humans hopefully maybe um a
discloser than mice and xenographs um
is it an ahr
liend I don't
know I don't
know might be interesting to know if it
can potentiate say retinoic
acid yeah and the thing is because we
saw this effect in dogs not in mice so
even in the mice when we combine with
the enter inhibitor and we saw very uh a
significant Synergy in the mice in the
gra we never saw differentiation of
cells in the mice so so the system
probably is also important to consider
and we've never went back to those
studies uh in
dogs yes so you mentioned that um
different patients have a different
subset of um phenotypic Market does that
change with um treatment with pereno or
is that kind of stable have you looked
at that so that's a very good question
for any chemotherapy so we really don't
know and part of the efforts to try to
evaluate minimal residual disease in
involes flowetry because if you think
about tracking a population we need to
know how this population behaves and we
cannot assume that the markers are not
going to change my personal point of
view I like to see uh the phenotypic
markers as your dress as your coat you
decide to wear something today maybe
because your gen expression told you to
but it doesn't mean that after you get
exposed to some very aggressive
chemotherapy and you want to hide from
this therapy maybe your dress also going
to change uh so that's something we want
to understand and we have very strong
efforts following and understanding
minimal perit of disease after any
chemotherapy because probably is going
to be different from Patient to Patient
and from therapy to therapy but if we
can tell what is
normal then would be a way to track
those
cells my com on LA on in a review that I
did quite a while back uh there were
almost almost 2,000 of them know quite
diverse in primarily in the aster
sunflower family and with one of them
they just gave a Nobel Prize
fortiv malaria the point being that
these lactones are
we really don't understand how they go
about it but there are certain bar force
on the molecule that make that we can
attach to proteins but uh we're still
very far from really understanding
mechanistic uh action on this compound
so they're right they're open to an
incredible kind of diversity and I and I
like what you've done because this is
what we have to do with I think say for
any kind of any natural product that we
trying to push and and utilize it that
you know as a as a pharmaceutical you
need really good rigorous uh essays
which unfortunately we don't do with a
lot of natural products and I think that
part the negative feelings toward
natural products as
potential yeah so that's I mean that's
the goal of the big collaboration with
uh all this multidisciplinary team which
we said together because uh also I mean
I didn't mention it but when I was a
post dog I tried many different cquin
tropin lactones just because we said oh
let's try uh anything that we saw that
looked like parite and all of the
activities were very different and when
we were screening the the the medicinal
analoges they all behave differently so
the idea is to try to find the most
potent cquin lacton that are still
selective and try to understand where
the selectivity comes from because
probably the targets are not going to be
the same and maybe we will be able to
tell okay she has to be NF capab and
what else what is the right combination
of the S pons uh Cesar my collaborator
you know Cesar he likes to see it as a
Melody he says it's like playing the
piano you have to hit the right keys in
order to produce music and so we want to
find what that music is for S when
lacton and
Leukemia yes that's very in the phic
markers in untreated disease reflect
multiple paths for development
of differences individual I think we
don't know yet and I think the more we
know we are doing sequencing and trying
to match
sequencing to to each individual patient
we might be able to understand a little
bit more and also I mean I didn't want
to mention it to don't make not to make
everything so more complic ated because
you are all going to get out very
depressed after all of this information
is that there is a lot of heterogeneity
even with within the heterogen I told
you in the tumor there is still clonal
heterogen meaning within the same
patient you're going to have several
clones with different
mutations so when I think about
targeting leukemia lukemia stem cells
we're playing the game wack wack them
all you hit one and the other one one
comes out of you and we just try to find
a huge Hammer to get them all down so um
so this is this is a problem and
probably it's also that heterogenity
that you have in the genotype that will
be reflected in the phenotype and
because all of this is evolving so
rapidly maybe we'll very soon have
enough information to match the theer S
oface signature with that some genetic
signature and will help us distinguish
them one from the
yes is there any possibility that when
you do the serial transplants that
because everything is so rapidly
evolving that um like like a leukemia
cell that's not a stem cell can gain
more stem cell like properties and kind
of like be a Founder for the disease
even though it wasn't originally a
leukemia stem cell where it was coming
from or is that not something that
really happens so this is a hypothesis
that people have thought but not only in
the mouth also in people so that's what
when I told you about the origin of
leukemia is that's a hypothesis we don't
know what is the directionality of the
cells which so the definition of a
leukemia stem cell does not mean it's a
cell that came from a normal Stem Cell
It's a cell that Acquire The ability to
behave like a stem cell so could have
been a more mature could have been a
blast
but the right combination of genetic
modifications or epigenetic modification
give them the capacity to self renew and
give rise to progeny so yes the more and
actually there's studies that have shown
the more aggressive the tumor becomes
even impatient so if you take a patient
a diagnosis and separate c34 positive
c38 negative cells you can see the
hierarchy as I described to you Works
beautifully the stem cells are the stem
cells and then you have the pl etc etc
if you take sample from a relapse
patient the same patient at relapse and
take the different c34 positive 38
negative and then other cells every cell
will behave like a stem cell so the
hierarchy is not maintained in that case
meaning that chemotherapy must have
changed something in the process so
that's why we think we to really catch
and kill the cells from the beginning or
when they are asent before they come
back once they come back they're a
different
monster I think we'll stop the question
andless somebody has a real
important so again thank you very much
one again thank
you this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu