this is a production of Cornell
University say hello good morning good
afternoon good evening depending on
where you are for those of you who don't
know me my name is Luc V I'm organizing
this fourth edition of our hemp webinar
Series this year we have decided to
focus on H grain we have eight amazing
amazing speakers who who have uh kindly
agreed to give talks on various topics
we are kicking it off with a Morgan
tweet from IMT hemp and a member of the
hemp feed Coalition who is here with us
today since this is our first webinar of
this year I'd like to briefly explain
how it will work we're going to start at
1M EST allow participants to join and
once attendance stabilizes I'll
introduce the speaker the presentation
would last approximately 45 minutes and
we are going to follow it by a 15
minutes Q&amp;A H session then we'll wrap up
by thanking the speaker and uh for their
time and insights so please submit your
questions for the speaker using the Q&amp;A
button and use the chat for any other uh
communication the webinars will be
recorded and uploaded to our school of
Integrative PL science YouTube channel
sips YouTube channel so if you have to
leave early or you want to watch it
again you can just go to YouTube and
you'll find the talks from this year and
the talks from the past editions of the
webinar and without further Ado I'll
have the honor of introducing Morgan H
today's speaker Morgan tweet Morgan is a
founding partner of indd hemp uh Montana
based hemp food food and fiber company
located in Fort uh Benton she is the
chief executive author and has helped
design construct commission and operate
one of the largest hemp processing
campuses in the US with their oil seed
and fiber facilities Morgan graduated
from the University of Missouri with a
bachelor's in chemical engineer and then
worked for Archer Daniels Midland in
Decor Illinois launching her career in
Agriculture and food
processing Morgan and her father Ken
Elliot founded IND HP with the mission
to create new unrewarding opportunities
for Rural agriculture communities and
companies that see the great opportunity
in Camp grain and fiber they believe in
the goodness of hemp and its ability to
not only bring another R venue Source uh
to the farm but also believe in its
power as a strong rotation crop
combating persistent weeds and and
helping build soy health so Morgan it's
all yours thank you well um very honored
to be here today I know we're on a um a
a short clock so I'll jump right into it
but um really appreciate the opportunity
um to be invited to participate in the
webinar and excited for the series ahead
hopefully um I set the stage for some
other great speakers that I saw listed
there um I think there'll be some really
good content and this will just be bit
of a scratch of the surface that they
can follow up with with more detail so
um um Corel asked um that I sort of go
into a little bit of in hemp um as a
business and our capability is what we
do um and then we're going to focus on
grain production and sort of end with um
food and feed opportunities I am the
executive director of the hemp Coalition
as well um so personal passion and and a
lot of work that's good work that's been
done by the people there
also um first off a little bit about IND
hemp so we are a certified BC Corp uh
organization this is our town of forb
it's located about 45 minutes um
Northeast of Great Falls if you know
Montana we're North Central um we're in
a really productive agricultural region
a lot of grain is um grown around here
the major rotation crops that we're
working with are winter wheat spring
wheat pulses um some forage production
as well and um we've just been really
thankful and blessed to be in this
community that's really embraced us um
there's about 1500 people we right along
the Missouri River here so very historic
and um beautiful town if you are big fan
of Le and Clark I encourage you to come
out and visit we've got rich history
there and it's just a great Community to
to be in so um I highlight that we're
certified bcorp um because it really
articulates um well our business and our
values you know we sort of um
communicate success with our people our
planet and our profit and so we want to
focus on those things in that order and
um I think that's really boed well for
us and in the success that we've had we
were established in 2018 um my dad's
been doing hemp those since about 2013
he's got the first license in Montana um
all the way back to the 2014 farm bill
and has been working it and then um I
left my career with ADM and as crazy of
an adventure as it started it sort of
really took effect um after the farm
bill passed in December of 2018 we
started in Grain Manufacturing and then
um quickly evolved into fiber as well so
just a few photos of you know our people
and the work we're doing in our
facilities um they mean a lot to us
that's what encourages and inspires me
every day and um just hope to do a good
job for
them um our mission and our vision I'm
not going to read it um it's entirety
you can definitely come on to our
website but I think it does a great job
of um articulating what we see and what
what we want to do the things I like to
highlight is that you know we really
want to create value in the supply chain
it's a very clear need that we have as
an industry is continuing to focus on
the right steps in the process and we
want to do it with integrity and really
focus on those things so like I said
focusing on the relationship with the
farmer um making sure that they're not
getting the last cut but they're you
know their needs and um their
integration is is considered at the
Forefront and then obviously um really
championing the opportunity to work
pioneers of um different ENT
entrepreneurial businesses that see hemp
as a real um opportunity to create
lasting change whether it's as a
material or a food or feed
ingredient um it really starts on the
farm we're going to do go into quite a
bit of agronomy stuff I know that you
guys have some other sessions to be even
more focused on that but you know back
to our mission this is why it started
for us we wanted to create value in
rural Montana and we wanted to see a new
rotation crap that could bring Revenue
to our friends and family um that were
just having a hard time with the price
of wheat every year so it's been really
fun to see um starting with grain and
then working with fiber genetics as well
they're two very different production
models we're going to focus on grain
today uh but we've learned a lot in the
six plus years that we've been doing
production and um really understand the
value and importance of focusing on the
farm
first this is our footprint um it needs
to be updated a little bit but generally
speaks to sort of where we're at on the
presence um Montana is definitely an a
state and a lot of value U manufacturing
has also brought our economy up and so
what you see here um in the stars are
our facility in Fort bton which is where
all of our manufacturing is done and
then our main corporate office and then
we have an office in Belgrade as well
which is serves as a warehouse and then
a lot of our sales and finance team is
located there also then you can see all
of our partner Farms um this has been
updated for a few years so there's more
than that but as you can see we're
pretty um diverse Montana is a really
big State we have to cover a lot of
territory we've actually done some
production in in Canada as well we've
done some seed production also in the
midwest um Kansas Texas Indiana um so
we've we've sort of have a good pulse on
generally what genetics works and what
regions but been hyperfocused on trying
to optimize yields and efficiencies in
our region as
well um we really focus on that grower
um relationship we've to date had about
30 ,000 Acres that we've managed um we
don't personally grow but we work with
um farmers and contract with them and
that's the production model that you see
with most Commodities but it's worked
well for us um focusing on Family Farms
we'd like to stay within 400 mile radius
closer is better um you know 100 miles
would be awesome but the reality is is
we have to you know go where the acres
are and um being geographically diverse
also helps us mitigate some risk so we
do have a full-time anonomous on staff
we do also usually have a a um seasonal
intern that will help as well so we're
there from you know everything from seed
selection to um when they're when
they're planting and doing seed counts
and um stand counts throughout the
season helping them with their nutrition
program um so it's a very Hands-On uh
relationship and so we get feedback from
them throughout the year as well um
everything from you know seed and and
fiber storage um to transportation and
Material Handling needs we are the ly of
x59 which is a variety based out of
Canada it's worked really well for us
and then we're also the owner of IH
Williams which is a high yielding fiber
variety um it's also known as SS beta um
in a lot of University trials so maybe
you have heard of both of those
varieties and we've seen success in our
region and both um and then have
continued to keep an eye on and trial a
lot of other varieties as well our goal
is always to provide the best variety um
for our Farmers to maximize their yields
and um meeting the quality specs that we
need as a processor as
well so really the buckets of products
that we make um sort of fall either into
hemp food hemp feed or hemp fiber we're
not going to talk a whole lot about hemp
fiber but we do have a decortication
facility and so those products that
we're going to be selling is um Bast
fiber cleaned and sized herd and then
some co-products and so um the general
number I think that's nice to articulate
to folks is between our facilities we
can manage somewhere between 20 and
30,000 acres of hemp really depends on
um you know what that that production
mix looks like in terms of dual purpose
or single purpose production um but I
say that just sort of in the grand
scheme of things um you know we're one
of the largest processors in the United
States and 10 to 30,000 acres is not
even a drop in the bucket for most
Commodities and so it's definitely an
industry that has a lot of room to grow
and a lot of room for other processors
to get um on boarded I know generally
hemp Farmers or excuse me farmers are
definitely interested in hemp they're
looking for a new cash crop or something
at least competitive and then they're
also looking for something that um adds
value to their rotation to their soils
so we'll dig into that a little bit more
as
well um this is a quick look of our
facilities again I'm not going to go
into too much detail on our production
um just we can definitely cover
questions but um was asked to sort of do
some other things but both of these
locations are in Fort Bon they're about
you know not even half mile away from
one another um on the left is our fiber
facility you can see the raw straw bales
that are outside um we usually try to
keep about a month's worth of inventory
on hand um and then on the right is our
oil seeds facility so we have seed
cleaning and then um seed processing and
two separate buildings with some on-site
storage as well we do have the the um
you know rest or the uh menu of
certifications that we're really proud
of we work hard for we had our um annual
organic audit yesterday that was went
over really well we've just been um
blessed with a great quality team and a
production team that continue to you
know hold us up to these high standards
and we are confident with what we
communicate to customers um for both of
our
businesses um some Brands just because
we've continued to um Garner more value
in the supply chain and so going further
down um the value chain has helped us to
continue to to get that value the
products that we sell mostly fiber
related are elocks and hemp Tana um we
start with bedding products but then
we're uh have the opportunity to also
highlight our supplement and feed
products with um oil seeds so those are
two animal care products one's more
targeted to you know a smaller animal
versus is you know a farm and ranch
style um animal then we have our Montana
gold which is represented both in sort
of lawn and garden and then we've also
been successful in converting into
textile and been working with um some
smaller Brands to launch our monana gold
into some um finished apparel products
and then our IH oil seed products most
of our feed or excuse me our food is
being sold in bulk um we don't have
currently a retail facing brand um but
continue to support other brands both
domestically and
internationally current applications
that you sort of see us in um a lot of
this is fiber just since it's a more
diverse um sectors that it can sort of
play in but we see non-wovens as compos
and composits as a big opportunity for
us absorption textiles soil amendments
human and animal nutrition um so this
was a picture taken at agon the mall
we're partners with the national hemp
Association they did a great setup um in
DC and and it was nice to Showcase some
of our products um along with some other
well-known hint processors in the
US um so we'll jump into grain
production um so sort of the agenda
basic cultivation knowledge what we've
learned what we need to continue
investigating some Harvest and grain
handling and then product development
and
challenges so there's a lot of
information on this slide um this is
sort of the basic management practices
it is you know um kind of where we start
with a lot of our Growers um I'll make
sure that these slides are available to
share so you guys don't feel like you
have to you know frantically write notes
um some of the things I think are
important to highlight you know it can
be used either in conventional tillage
or no till most of the production in our
area is no till um and so we've seen
that be really successful the probably
highest risk um like most crops but uh
planting is where we can really either
make or break the season so it's
important to get the right depth um and
space spacing you know timing it
definitely is more flexible than I would
say some other crops you can go as early
as late April to early June um we've
seen pros and cons to both sort of um
looking at the production of what you
need if if you're trying to mitigate
weed pressure that's your number one
concerned maybe planting earlier to try
to get um the the uh crop established
earlier if you're trying to chase
moisture maybe you know looking at the
forecast a little bit more um it is
fairly Frost resistant I would say you
know trying to Target that 50° soil
temperature though is probably the the
best time to look at planning um
planning density is definitely a big
thing to sort of um work with your
whoever you're working with production
wise because that is what we see the
play the biggest role definitely
depending on if you're growing for fiber
or grain purposes for seed production I
would say targeting 200 to 300 plants
per 300,000 plants per acre
um is a good place to start it'll depend
um on your variety the seed size and
hemp crass varieties is very different
some are nice round plump seeds that um
you know their bushel weight's going to
be different than some of these really
smaller seeds so I think working with
your processor who's going to be
purchasing the commodity is probably the
most important thing to understand that
and then working with the um whoever
owns the variety to give that sort of
insight into your um pounds per acre
planted um on the right I sort of
outlined our growth cycles of what we
see um you definitely have uh most of
the varieties are dous so you have male
and female plants coming up um this sort
of outlines when you'll see the males
start showing those reproductive organs
first um when you'll start to see pollen
drop and then when those um seeds start
to really fill out I think one of the
challenging things that we see every
year and it's sort of the the um wrist
that fer take is around Harvest um a lot
of variables come into play because it
is an indeterminant plant meaning it'll
just continue to put on seeds until um
you know something kills the the plant
you'll see nice mature large seeds at
the bottom of the seed head and then
you'll see small immature green seeds at
the top that really have no value and so
um that's sort of a thing that farmers
have to evaluate when they're looking at
maximizing yield is when to cut um um so
a lot of things I think every year our
Growers get more confident in their
decisions um obviously Mother Nature has
a pretty big role to play for us um
moisture is what we're chasing most of
the time if we're on Dryland Acres we
have had a lot of success on irrigated
Acres um but just for reference in our
region you know we're working with 10 to
12 inches of annual prip out in like
Pennsylvania and New York you guys are
probably somewhere between like 35 and
50 Ines
so big difference in moisture needs um I
think everyone thinks hemp can do all
things with limited resources and it is
always surprising what it is resilient
to but just like most things green it
wants water and it wants
nutrition um here are some biofactors
and sort of what we've learned um hemp
definitely allows for very biodiverse
soils it's bringing new organisms in um
it's helping promote that activity so
we've seen some value there on the soil
side um you do see to comp see some
competition with weeds early on and so
there are a few chemistries that have
been successful I sort of outlin them on
the side there this is for our region so
I can't speak to what everyone will um
have access to or see success with but I
did think it was important to throw this
on here we're big fans of regenerative
um agricultural practices we promote
that a lot um we also do organic
production so you know we take a a full
holistic approach um we think hemp is an
awesome crop to revitalize agriculture
in general and because of its ability to
be more resilient its lack of or its
reduced needs and um inputs then what it
does at the soil level we think that
there's a lot of things that can be used
in a um transition program for those
farmers who are looking to either go
organic or go um um regenerative but the
reality is is like like conventional
practices are still very much needed for
a lot of folks and so we try to just fit
all applications and um all
operations so um for weeds if you can
get the crop out of the ground and well
established we see a lot of competition
happen throughout um throughout the year
and hemp usually WIS out there with its
canopy closure some pests to be aware of
there definitely some aphids
grasshoppers caterpillars spider mites
you know I know there's probably more in
other regions um
but generally because of some of those
tpin and cannaboids we think um that
there's some natural repellents that are
there for us the most devastating pest
is caterpillars or excuse me sorry most
devastating pest is
Grasshoppers and that's more due to um
hemp is the last thing that guys Harvest
around here and so um grasshoppers are
going to be looking for moisture and so
as the wheat is cut and all their pulse
crops are cut you know they sort of go
to the last green thing out there which
almost always ends up being hemp um so
we've definitely had our years 2020
through 2022 are pretty rough um still
don't have a great solution for that but
um generally speaking that's about all
the pest pressure we see um definitely
see the pollinators like it especially
when those males are out it's amazing
you can walk through the fields and just
see all the bees there so we know that's
a great thing um for your ecosystems as
well and then some diseases to be aware
of um variety dependent um we see some
of those Tarpin also playing a role I
think um and then and definitely the um
structure of the seed head so some of
those grain varieties have tighter seed
heads that hold on to moisture a little
bit more don't allow for that seed to
breathe and so sometimes we can have
some mildew or mold um we don't have
that a lot in our region but we
definitely know of it um in other places
as
well um I think some of the things to
learn to sort of highlight um it
definitely is region specific and I mean
that's
not not a shocker there we see that for
every other um commodity or crop we're
growing but it is important to highlight
that you know hemp is behind obviously
by several decades and when you look at
the germ plasms available and um the
breeding programs that have been
successful him just has a a long way
ahead of it um I think there's some
fantastic companies out there doing
great work um making Headway both in
hybrid opportunities and such um but we
really need to see that increase um both
in just the varieties that are available
to increase yield but region specific um
varieties as well I think understanding
you know what are the important traits
you're looking for whether it's maturity
to due to like Harvest timing um or
plant height um seed head architecture
those are all things to keep in in mind
when choosing variety um and then it
also is really important to talk about
what your planning to do for Harvest um
because that'll play a role in what you
want those traits mostly plant height I
think is is is really the big thing to
um determine there but these are all
things to to
consider um I was asked to share sort of
what varieties we've grown so I've
thrown up these I'm sure I'm missing a
couple um but we try to do a good job of
having a um commercial scale plot trials
out every year so the last year and this
year we've had about 120 Acres um that
we divvy up between you know 10 and 20
acre plots um it's great to work with
universities to get those you know those
TR those plot trials that are you know a
half acre or less um but really rubber
meets the road when you start seeing
these commercial size um trials and
seeing how these varieties perform under
the same conditions same soil type
things like that so um happy to you know
give some insight for our area on these
varieties if people are looking for that
um we always try to have an open book
open door policy and try to be as
collaborative as possible
um grain Harvest storage and handling is
really really important um I'd say if
not more important than that planting
risk um you can have a beautiful crop
and really excited about your season and
it you can ruin it in one day and just a
couple hours if you don't handle it well
um so first off you're going to be you
know cutting it either with like a
draper header or um you know just a a
classic combine um you could SWA it as
well um and then come back with combine
header Harvest it I think the biggest
thing to focus on there are your
settings and your combine um to to clean
the seed we definitely know that it is
you know um High foreign material um
because of that indeterminate nature
you're going to be harvesting really
great dry beautiful seeds but you're
also going to be bringing in a lot of
trash with um both the the bra and the
leaves and then all those immature seeds
as well which hold on to moisture
moisture is not your friend in this case
um because that's you know where we see
mold and other issues so um we talked to
our Farmers about using augers um it is
a fragile seed so similar to peas or
other things you know you can use an
augur you just need to go slow um since
seeds will crack and then that's a
quality concern you know because of its
high oil content it's going to want to
go rant it pretty quick um bin storage
is really important to have set up ahead
of harvest too making sure you have air
ation um we are fortunate enough here in
our region that most of the time we
don't need heaters our relative humidity
is manageable I do know in other areas
though if you don't have you know
relative humidity in your in your favor
um need to make sure that you have a
heater on there to keep that moisture
out um being careful to keep those
temperatures down you know just has that
low flash point so um I definitely think
we can give some insight there as well
good rule of thumb is making sure that
if you're harvesting above 10% moisture
you need to get your Grain on air within
four hours that's sort of a
non-negotiable um so making sure you
have that plan some guys will don't have
that access or are challenged with with
things and so they'll actually choose to
harvest either swath it and let it dry
in the field or harvest it at much drier
conditions um those risk is you have
shatter and other um you know bird
pressure things like that you can lose
some yield if you wait for that but
fundamentally if you don't have a way to
dry your grain you sort of don't have an
option you have to cut it at low
moistures um and then turning over your
bed and making sure you're keeping it on
it for spoilage is really
important um this is a raw food and so
we need to be careful and cognizant of
your your truck and trailer um we do
truck affidavits with our Growers so
making sure they get into The Hoppers
and make sure everything's cleaned up
like I said hem shoes are the last thing
Harvest and so we're following something
else whether it's wheat or peas or
something else um hemp typically is
allergen free and so it's important for
us to try to keep that at the farm level
you know our biggest risk is wheat um it
is also considered generally gluten-free
so making sure we get all those wheat
kernels out it's really
important um just want to like when I
talked about hemp as an opportunity for
more sustainable agricultural practices
I think it sort of
um this is like the Four Points I like
to highlight generally we see overall
lower inputs everything from herbicides
and pesticides even to you know water
usage um a lot of people are really
excited about hemp when we look at you
know some of these aquafers drying up
and other things hemp definitely has a
role to play and I think that the more
we get a handle on what its means are
and what our production expectations are
um and then the economy economies that
survive um for those those costing
models is really important also we
definitely know hemp is great carbon uh
great at sequestering Carbon you know
it's very fast growing and we know that
there's a lot of biomass on the field
especially when we're growing for fiber
we've been working with um a group to to
be able to articulate our carbon
sequestration numbers and then we also
articulate that in our um our lcas with
our products so we think there's a role
to play in um the fight against climate
as
well definitely hemp improves some
biodiversity we're bringing in you know
a new soil structure with uh or excuse
me a new root structure that definitely
helps with the soil we see other
pollinators and other things coming and
really helping build up a resilient
ecosystem for the soil I think everyone
in the last decade in agriculture has
realized how important it is to focus on
soil Health um everything from adopting
no till practices or minimal till
practices to you know how we can
increase biologics in the in the soil
it's really important and I think hemp's
a great crop to help complement those um
practices and then generally it's a
minimal waste product um what's awesome
is even when you're growing for grain
you know you can really model that that
dual crop um scenario where we can
Harvest for both the Grain and Seed head
but also for that residual fiber and
bring value and we're finding more and
more valuable homes um for these
co-products and so that's exciting to
see for an industry that only has you
know half a decade under its belt here
in the US um to continue to see value
opportunities for these
byproducts um so real talk about food um
and feed so we did a market survey last
year to sort of get a feel and help um
point us in our direction of where we
want to go with food um and I thought
this was really encouraging so this was
one of the slides I took from you know
how currently consumers are looking at
hemp and um it's nice to see that you
know we're almost at the 50th percentile
for for consumers that are already using
these ingredients in their diet um and
so more room to grow but you know it's a
lack of perception that you know
everyone still thinks that we're an
intoxicating product um clearly about
50% of people are eating it in some form
or fashion so I think where we've made
progress in the last
decade um I did take this slide from um
Sam Garing is the um marketing officer
with till and Manitoba Harvest so going
to give him appropriate credit but I
thought it was a really good slide to
Showcase you know from a food
perspective where we're seeing hemp sort
of grow um they have a wonderful brand
that they've really grown and invested
in um you know it's been legal in Canada
about two decades more than it is here
and so they've got a little bit of a
head start start on us and they've done
a great job of um incorporating hemp
food um into you know store shelves and
then the consumer
basis nutritionally sort of what we have
and you know a little bit of beyond the
basics but what we're generally speaking
of um from the macronutrients is you
know 20 to 30% carbohydrates 10 to 15%
of that being in soluble fiber somewhere
between 25 and 35% oil and 20 to 25%
protein we have seen this you know
fluctuate a little bit from
varieties um but this is some good
standards um it is a really unique
complete protein meaning it has all
those nine essential amino acids but
it's also you know encouraging as the
The increased bioavailability so what we
can digest this protein composition also
is is pretty unique so that slide on or
excuse me that graph on the right there
is showing those amino acids and it's
it's comparing it to um other proteins
that we probably complement in the food
space so P protein soy protein faab Bean
protein um I think albumin and Edison
are probably the most exciting ones that
we see pretty unique for hemp and I
think food formulators are continuing to
focus on those things um to highlight
that you know the consumer basis is
obviously growing in its consumer
awareness of the value of protein in its
diets and so we're sort of poised to be
able to take advantage of that and think
hemp has a role to play um it's also
still a good source of those plant-based
polyunsaturated fats we talk about
hemp's um unique Omega Omega fatty acid
profile that 6 to3 ratio a really ideal
for absorption and metab Metabolism we
see that value proposition also showing
up in feed applications we talked about
the allergens um which is is always good
to have an ingredient that we don't have
to worry about that and there's also
meaningful mineral micronutrient and
anti-nutrient properties as hemp as
well um I sort of highlighted you know
where I think a potential you know my
background working with ADM I saw a lot
of um growth in um protein isolates and
protein concentrates and so I think as
we talk about the value proposition hemp
has with protein you know we can't can't
miss um talking about isolates and
concentrates as well um it definitely is
a challenge and you there's been some
great processors that have been working
on this they've listed a few here I know
that others are working on it um but
it's conceptually just trying to isolate
those proteins or concentrate up those
proteins to put it in a form that can be
used more as an ingredient versus you
know a finished product so you know I
don't think anyone fully appreciates how
much soy protein is in you know the the
US consumer's diet most most to be
because we don't see it in the or we
don't always look at it in the
ingredient list but it's in a lot of
things so um there's a huge Market base
there for us um we do know that we
complement P protein and in in the amino
acid profiles and so can we create an
ingredient and put it in a you know for
a functional form that um allows us to
get on the back of more labels so some
examples of success you might have heard
Elmhurst has done like teram me they've
done creamers and sour cream
Alternatives nepra has done some meat
and egg replacement um plantet based
food has done some ice cream and other
milk Replacements so I think there's a
lot of great companies that are trying
to break into that consumer space and
we're all excited and and um supportive
of that because we generally all are
want the same thing we want more people
consuming hemp
food um so talk about feed real
quick um we didn't go into a lot of the
processing but hopefully most people
generally know the the B basic
processing for grain um you know you get
clean seed in you can either run it
through a press for mechanical
extraction and you get hemp seed oil and
hemp cake or meal as a byproduct or you
run it through a hauling systems to you
know retrieve that um healthy hemp part
and then your H PS are your co-products
and in both scenarios those co-products
right now don't have a lot of
applications in human food and so it's
really important for us to be looking at
alternative valuable markets that's not
uncommon right most crops and
commodities have this same problem where
not everything can go into the food
market and so having the access to the
Feed Market is really important for
growth of any
commodity um what does the feed
consumption generally look like um so
this is you know sort of what is the
animal feed diet sort of consisting of
right now I struggled soybean meal and
canola meal because that's where I think
we can compete um and so it's not
insignificant um we're definitely not
chasing corn and so I like to remind
people like we're not here to compete
against corn and soy you know this isn't
us trying to take the big bad boys out
but um how can we complement the
existing feed chain and sort of found
find other value propositions um we
don't have a huge market in terms of
process capabilities we don't have the
infrastructure to really compete on
those volumes anyways um but we need to
start working towards
that this is just sort of a snapshot of
you know how how many tons of product
we're talking so back to my comment of
you know we're really not in a space as
an industry right now to to service any
of these um uh markets right now today
by ourselves anyways so we want to
position ourselves as a complimentary
ingredient um you know whether it's from
a nutritional perspective or a pricing
perspective um but making sure that you
know people are very aware and demanding
for higher quality protein sources him
can check that box um there's an
increased awareness of fatty acid
profiles and what it does for gut health
and um you know the just the animal
overall health so hemp can check that
box too and then we have renewable
resources you know wool and hair is one
that's talked about here for um some
other things but hemp with what we can
do with with the fiber the residual
fiber um also helps offset some of those
um impacts as
well so the hempy Coalition is a mission
driven company it's 501c3 sorry not
company but organization a lot of great
members on there um want to highlight
the great work that they did um we
achieved the first uh successful
application for an AFCO ingredient
definition for those who are not aware
um the FDA has two arms a food human
food arm and then a um an animal feed
arm they've been working with um State
Regulators in AFCO and there's more
restrictions on animal feed than there
are human food mostly because um you
know this is people's livelihood their
their livestock how they they make a
living and also animals don't really
have a choice what they eat a lot of
times you know um species will eat the
same thing every day all day for their
whole life and so there needs to be a
lot of scrutiny and thought put into
those their nutrition to make sure we're
putting them in the best position
possible to be successful um so that's
why it was pretty lengthy process took
us about three and a half years close to
$300,000 um we will be listed as an
official ingredient in the next op um
there's one more vote in August but
we've passed the last five we've got one
more to go there are states that are
recognizing the tentative ingredient
definition right now um it did require
us that we completed two different large
scale feed studies we had to establish
and defend a method for cannaboid
analysis and then we had to recommend
contaminant levels for canabo as well
but huge milestone for the industry um I
did want to highlight the um langing hen
study because one is the only ingredient
improved but also just the great things
that we see um from hemp and why laying
hens are a Target species for us so
here's sort of a breakdown of hemp seed
cake versus other feed ingredients you
can sort of see the highlights from an
amino acid
level um this is the fatty acid profile
so we talk about that Omega 6 to3 ratio
which is so important um for metabolism
and for inflammation responses so you
can see you know very competitive
there and then the awesome thing is that
that same correlation we saw in the eggs
and so you can see those numbers going
down as the percent of hemp seed cake
concentrate was in introduced into the
laying H you see that Omega ratio going
down so on the bottom there um is sort
of talking about dietary Health um I
took these slides from um Dr Raj Cula
he's one of our hfc board members he was
the chief scientist on this study and so
um give him all the credit for the work
that they did there with your feeds
happy to share more but it's just it's
encouraging to see that that um value
proposition that we see in the
ingredient translated into the egg as
well and then another surprising um
benefit we also see was an increase in
ltin content which um you know we should
care about ltin is a a critical compound
that we um see playing a role with Eye
Health and so if we can also bring that
value proposition to the eggs and I
think consumers will be excited about
that
um so generally um this is sort of like
the Matrix of why we think hemp has hemp
seed meal has such a great potential as
a feed ingredient you we looked at the
nutrient profile and the
anti-nutritional factors we had to
assess safety um it's palatability we
had a check for Health and Welfare um
you know making sure that there wasn't
any concerns there sourcing processing
availability and economics are all
things we're working on right as an
industry because we're still pretty
small um we don't necessarily have the
economies of scale to compete um and may
not have the availability that some of
these you know um production hen houses
are looking for um but those are all
things that I think just we continue to
chip away at as the industry grows and
it was a huge ability for us to get that
AFCO approval right we really couldn't
start opening these doors until that
happened so that happened in August of
2024 again some states recognize it some
haven't so we really even have sort of
just have a foot in the door right now
um I think once that vote happens this
coming August you know that will be wide
open for folks
so um want to highlight becoming an hfc
member you know hfc's goal is to get
more applications submitted this is how
we open up more um markets domestically
so you sort of the breakdown of
membership um we do have a great uh
value proposition in Our member zone we
sort of correlate and combine all of the
research studies that are out there we
provide an executive summary um quick
access on our member zone um online so
if you want to research you want to say
hey I want to look at you know what
research is out there for um hemp Pauls
with swine you know we'll pull that
together for you and have an executive
summary and then access to um any
Publications that might be out there so
it's always a work in progress
fundamentally you know all of our
funding goes to supporting research um
we've written grants we've been um you
know included on on other feed
opportunities you guys are going to hear
from a couple folks later in other
webinars about studies that are going on
and and then we have to prepare the
applications which you know takes time
and um is taken sometimes even takes a
consultant to do some um safety studies
for us and so all that takes time and
energy and money but it's so critical
for the growth of the industry I I
really can't highlight that enough um
just to be able to have those markets
available to us so please let me know if
you're interested we'd love to have you
in participating as hfc
member so I think I gave us 15 minutes
um for questions I never know what
people want to hear um but you guys can
obviously reach out to me and then happy
to take questions now as well
so all right got a
few
um one question is what has been your
Farmers experience with noil um we've
done really well with noil up here
obviously having the right um the right
equipment is really imperative so a lot
of our guys out here you know have
different types of H drills or other
drills um that work with it that seed to
soil contact is really important
sometimes we'll have um uneven emergence
in the in the furrow if that isn't
managed well if you have too much um
residual from the L crop or things like
that but generally speaking um we
definitely have success with no till no
till um
operations hope that answered that um
recommendations for how to deal with
bird pressure it's a great question um
generally speaking I think people say
when the birds are there it's time to
harvest there's you know a few Creative
Solutions that some Farmers have come up
with with like scarecrows and like fire
cannons and stuff um I don't know if I
would say there's a silver bullet out
there him um definitely attracts birds
so for any of you know Avid bird Hunters
I always say it's a great crop to put in
um you'll see doves in there pheasants
things like that um it's more
challenging in regions that are
surrounded by you know um shrubs or
trees you know I've been to New Zealand
and some other places you know the UK
you guys have more um sort of paddocks
that are surrounded by these these trees
that are full of of birds we're
fortunate here you know we're just the
you know big old M Montana Sky we don't
have that we'll have you know thousands
of Acres at a time without any sort of
interruption and so bird pressure is a
little bit different so unfortunately I
don't have an answer but generally if
you can get in and harvest um that's the
best way to to get the birds
out um so the leftover plant material
after we harvest the seed head the
question is what does indm do with that
um most of the
time we do let it R you know rting is a
really important um aspect you know
that's a whole another conversation for
fiber but generally we want to see that
plant start to
break did I get cut
off okay am I
back
yes all right uh I guess I'll just keep
going but um so back to the leftover
yeah we do um we will purchase that
residual Straw from Growers and then run
it through our cortication facility it's
almost strictly straw material so that's
that bass fiber and heard we don't have
any um Leaf material left it's all um
usually by then it's it's dried up and
broken down in the field and so it's
just it's strictly that um that stock
material a great question um we'd love
to to partner with more researchers um
the key is just starting the
relationship with um FDA CBM and AFCO
early on and so for like our ruminant
application we're going through a
pre-submission process
where we basically um pull together all
existing published research review it
with them and then identify any gaps in
the research so for example um with the
with the laying hin study there was
definitely research that was published
outside of the United States um there
was good research talking about you know
palatability and nutritional
opportunities but none of the studies
had really dove into the potential
cannaboid transference into the eggs and
that was fda's main concern and so we
had to work with um a private research
group with the the we the Winger feed
company and um tailored that feed study
to answer that question specifically so
I think that anything is great and we
get to start but working with hfc early
on um and and sort of mapping out what
uh you know research objectives haven't
been addressed yet is the best place to
start and then hopefully we can design a
protocol to meet those things for an
application
um question about developing single
variety for both seed and fiber I don't
quite know what the question is but
there definitely are varieties out there
that um you know tout that they're both
a a true dual crop which I don't I don't
necessarily disagree with but what we
tell our Farmers is if you're growing
first seed um that is your primary
harvested material it it is it takes the
most care and um attention your fiber
residual is your byproduct and when you
just look at the economics of it it's a
no-brainer you're going to get 90% of
your Revenue off of the seed harvested
not the fiber um and so a true dual crop
model you know it's yes it can be done
and varieties are doing it but I we
always tell them to focus first on the
seed that's the higher value crop that's
what needs more attention to detail um
and making sure it fits your operation
um we definitely collaborate with
academic researchers and universities
we're always open um you know off the
cuff we're part of the um far
consortiums that's Cornell University of
Kentucky andc State um we do work with
Montana State here and then a handful of
others I'm always super excited to hear
what people are going on it's I
definitely don't have a pulse on
everything and so if you guys want to
work with us or you know from Agronomy
to food and feed um we would love to
participate and know more about what's
going on
um question about Stinger listed on work
what not to follow um I will try to pull
up
my herbicides list real quick so I can
make sure I'm telling you the right
thing
um so Stinger is a burndown that's used
for broadleaf here in our region and so
um we know that it works we just know
that it's not labeled for hemp to follow
um SP charge is another one that is on
the other side is we know um is a is a
really um effective herbicide for a lot
of broad leaves but there is carryover
issues and so we like we're really um we
follow the label very similar to Canola
and some other you know broad leafes out
here in oil seeds will follow their
recommendations for um plant back
periods and stuff like
that and I am not our agronomist so if
you want to talk to our agronomist I
will put you in contact with him um he
definitely knows far more about what
chemistries we we use and don't use and
those sort of
things um anticipate approval for live
stock uh we definitely are still I would
say 18 to 24 months out for getting
approval we're trying to do some more
creative applications to see if we can
group more uh species together so this
ruminant application will be large and
small ruminants we're waiting on some
key data be to be analyzed from a lamb
study that c State University did a few
years ago um but that's sort of the the
last step for information before we
finish that
application um question about if we're
developing construction materials for
hemp in the future we definitely um you
know support right now um one of the
larger material construction companies
um in the US that are doing a badend
instulation replacement that's where a
lot of our bass fiber is going to
applications like that I definitely see
a opportunity um and hope we're active
in ASM and other things that are looking
at hemp creete and you know the
materials that are used there um I'm
naturally a little more just measured in
my optimism as far as timing you know
construction is is challenging there's
so many uh regulations and approvals
that you need and um you need to
obviously prove its efficacy uh we don't
want to put people in houses that aren't
made to to last and withstand um so I
think it's a great place for us to focus
and continue to SP research dollars and
there's some great companies that we
partner with and it could be a real game
Cher for hemp as a um as a material
so all right I think I covered all the
questions in the Q&amp;A I hope oh um other
than diesel tractors which parts of the
business presses use most energy um
definit so we've done an LCA of our our
Cradle to gate so essentially looking at
our carbon footprint as an organization
and um the biggest uh footprint is
definitely on the Agronomy side um in
terms of fertilizer usage and like you
said uh fuel for any of the equipment
but that's inherent to like all
agricultural production we definitely
can find and like continue to optimize
those things um finding partners that
are closer by to reduce those Footprints
um but we're aware of that but like
fertilizer is a great example you know
we don't have a lot of control over that
but finding the varieties that can work
reduce fertilizer needs you know that
has an overall impact in our carbon
footprint when it comes to the facility
um it is energy intensive in terms of
what our electrical usages you know air
handling is probably our biggest um our
biggest Motors and electrical use users
um we do have you know it is a
mechanical process to separate the bast
and herd um from one another grain is
not as bad um I would say the air
handling equipment associated with
cleaning the seeds probably where we see
the biggest need and then um probably
our mechanical um presses after that
so um what about using Industrial Hemp
for cleaning the soil and
air um so I don't can't speak to it in
any detail generally though we you know
because we know hemp is so good at
sequestering Carbon um and it's it's
plant cycle that you know we know
photosynthesis does some great things
and because of how quickly it can grow
and just vigorous of a plant it is I
definitely think it's it's doing
something there so I don't want to speak
out of turn but I think anything you
know anything that we can plant and see
and and then reutilize for other
opportunities is awesome as
well um ongoing research in New York or
the US related to Rehabilitation
Rehabilitation of brownfields um great
question my dad actually got us into
hemp um he's a uh geologist in envir
Mentalist background did a lot of work
on Brownfield sites and so he got
interested in him because of its ability
to fight or remediate the soil we have
been engaged with some studies we did
work with Idaho University um looking at
lead uptake um with plants we definitely
see that hemp does does some great
things it's interesting to see where
those heavy metals um even hydrocarbons
and radionucleotides sort of end up in
the plant it does do a good job of
protecting ing you know its DNA from um
from the seed so a lot of those um
compounds you don't find them in the
seed themselves but you'll find residual
in the stock material I know
Pennsylvania um is really interested
they've been looking at hemp to you know
work with some um recovered you know
coal mines or or other things where we
have soil issues so um we're working
with an oil company there's a an oil
field uh excuse me an old abandoned oil
refinery in Northeast Montana that we've
been working on for
almost a decade and trying to work with
them and incorporating hemp as part of
our uh Rehabilitation and Remediation
plan so another awesome thing about hemp
that we hope to see grow in the
future I think that's it hopefully I
covered it all um and you guys have my
email if I missed anything but feel free
to reach out really appreciate the
opportunity to speak on here and
hopefully I did an okay
job yes thank you Morgan it was amazing
talk and thank you for answering all of
our questions too I feel like we learned
a lot today we have recorded the webinar
and we will be uploading it to our
school of Integrative plant science
YouTube channel so if you want to watch
it again if you missed some part please
go over there and we will upload it in
the coming
days for our next webinar which is going
to be on February 12 we are going to
have Nicole guer and she's going to talk
about plant pathogens in him so also
thank you everyone for connecting today
and we will see you um on February
12th goodbye have a nice rest of your
day this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu