this is a production of Cornell
University
so I'm here today to talk about
mushrooms and International Development
I was able to travel to two unique
locations in the world Bangladesh and
Rwanda
Bangladesh was not all about mushrooms I
did go following love I went to go visit
my girlfriend Amanda while she was
collecting her data for her PhD
thanks Amanda
but it was also for adventure you know
there's a lot of lessons that you can't
learn in the classroom and you can't
find in the library and so I was really
excited for these sort of experiential
learning opportunities
um and then uh
you know I'm interested to get into
International Development
um
and I asked Dr Peter Hobbs who some of
you may know I asked him how I could
become involved in international
agriculture development he said Brian
you just got to do it you just got to go
there and get experience and do it and
so
I went and uh that's that this is also
sort of an opportunity for my own
Shameless self-promotion
um I'm gonna hopefully graduate this may
so I'll be looking for a job anybody
knows a good good opportunity I'd be
happy to entertain that
um so let's start by combating
stereotypes about mushrooms mushrooms
are the fruiting body in the kingdom
fungi fungi their own unique Kingdom
there are a number of
um players The Good the Bad and
according to George hudler no no uglies
right
um
and there's a number of uses number of
ways different mushrooms and fungi can
contribute to society in terms of human
health and ecological Health
um
so yeah and then you know one stereotype
we encounter a lot here in the
university is the um psychedelic
mushrooms so if you guys need to get it
out of your system maybe make a joke to
your neighbor really quick and then we
can move on from this stereotype
so
I uh first became interested in
mushrooms and reading this book mycelium
running by Paul stamets
Paul stamets is a he's a rock star
Mycologist
um really very
um persuasive and sort of convincing all
the benefits that mushrooms can provide
to society
um some of the benefits including
include the remediation of Agriculture
runoff on the top you see a number of
mushroom species I know it's kind of
small trust me they're there and then a
number of potentially disease-causing
organisms that are often the result of
um wildlife and and in rain water runoff
and so these mushrooms were incorporated
into riparian buffers have the ability
to kill
a number of these pathogens some of
which are beginning to develop
antibiotic resistance
they've also certain mushrooms are also
capable of remediating chemical chemical
contaminants as a result of industrial
activities
what's really neat about these mushrooms
is that they have the ability to
metabolize these chemical contaminants
rather than just absorb and translocate
as is common with
more traditional bioremediation
strategies plant-based bioremediation
strategies and so you see things in here
like
organophosphates pesticides try not
toluene that's TNT so this is you know a
remarkable way to use a living organism
to sort of fix the damage we as humans
have done to the environment
mushrooms can also be used as pesticides
the most expensive Mushroom in the world
is a member of the cordyceps genus which
is pictured here it affects caterpillars
in the Himalayan plateau in Central Asia
and like I said this is the most
expensive mushroom
in the world there's also certain
cordyceps species that will infect ants
or grasshoppers can really help to
reduce
economic reduced populations to below an
economic threshold
mushrooms are also very beneficial in
human health they have a great ability
to bridge the gap between foods and
medicines there are a number of
different disease and disease
pathologies that they've been associated
with affecting I've got citations for
all of these if you'd like to talk more
about this later
but really they're you know there needs
to be more research done into the
applied aspects of mycology
it's a great way to sort of bridge
explore the interaction between both
human and environmental health
so on to the journey Bangladesh was um
first became a country in 1971 before
that it was known as East Pakistan after
the 1947 British partition
but due to a number of factors not the
least of which was Geographic separation
Bangladesh
fought for their independence and gained
that in 1971.
there continue to be a number of
political issues in Bangladesh that have
sort of affected its its coming of age
as a country but in addition to the
political turmoil Bangladesh is also the
site of the highest concentrations of
naturally occurring arsenic in the world
it infects the soil and groundwater and
has been described by some as a public
health emergency close to 50 percent of
Bangladesh's population is at risk of
exposure
and traditional strategies rely on the
filtration from water
which is significantly inhibited by
access to financial resources in terms
of getting this technology out to the
people who really need it
so in in doing my research for my
Master's Degree I came across this paper
mitigation of arsenic mediated stress in
rats and while it is a big jump from
rats to humans this is very promising
and it's the light bulbs went off in my
head and I wanted to explore this more
how can mushrooms help Bangladesh
um so I traveled to Bangladesh with two
main questions
um what is the current state of mushroom
activities in Bangladesh from an
extension standpoint and then our
specialty mushrooms an appropriate
strategy and preventing
um arsenic toxicity
and so for the first question
um
I knew a little bit of information going
there Amanda had traveled to Bangladesh
and uh in the year prior
and wanted me to come visit her the next
time she would be traveling to
Bangladesh so I said hey find something
with mushrooms and I'll be there and so
she was able to come up with the
national mushroom development and
Extension Center
um which engages in research activities
to promote a national collection of
useful mushrooms human resource and
agriculture development training
researching quality parameters of
products and production tools to enhance
branding and verification expanding
consumer awareness in addition to
increasing consumer interest in order to
develop trade relationships for an
export driven development
um
so that's that's what she found and I
was there to explore it um I know in
their mission this is their mission
statement that I just read to you and
they describe export driven development
um
just out of curiosity does anybody have
any opinion on the goal of export-driven
development versus regional development
in terms of a novel crops such as
mushrooms it could be for anything
special to you know high value
Horticulture products
I don't know if anybody has an opinion
on on that I don't want to be the only
one talking here so
well
right you can can you I mean the goal of
export is it exploitation
and provide shootings for the goal of an
export-driven development opportunity
are you exploiting environment and
people or can you really help people
with an export driven
goal it's been used
anybody else
that's sort of what I think but I don't
want to
you know I know some people believe in
that export-driven development
strategies are the way the way to go
um
so yeah I'd be happy to talk with
anybody after that after the talk
um so uh the national mushroom
development and Extension Center
currently There are 16 sub-centers
located throughout the Republic of
Bangladesh the center is in Savar the
the main Center or the facility was
started in 1979 and experienced a
significant lag phase until 2003 when
they began to Gear Up production systems
thanks to uh grants from the Asian
development Bank
in 2009 the Japanese Development Bank
ex gave another Grant to the Extension
Center
promoting their current capacity of the
16 sub-centers
and making it a part of the national
extension system in Bangladesh
um one thing I should mention is that um
literally literally translated the word
mushroom and Bangla is frog umbrella so
that may give you sort of a hint on on
how people will accept mushrooms as a
food product
um so after arriving in Dhaka we
traveled to the southern district of
Milwaukee
um and I hired a translator and spent
the time roaming the countryside
pursuing my own interest we found that
several former mushroom Farmers no
current mushroom farmers who told us
that when when they were selling
mushrooms
they would sell for about 200 taka per
kilogram fresh and 2000 Taco per
kilogram dry taka is the currency of
Bangladesh it's roughly 80 taka to a
dollar
um
so this is a pretty high value product
and and maybe not within the purchasing
capacity of many rural households
um
they mentioned that obstacles to the
expansion of their Enterprise
included lack of acceptance of mushrooms
as a food product a lack of profitable
Market outlets and unreliability or poor
quality of Spawn that was being sold to
them by the either the national
Extension Center or private Enterprises
but there was promise that they
recognized they began to cultivate
mushrooms because they recognized the
unique properties mushrooms contain as a
food item one of the gentlemen we spoke
to began cultivating mushrooms because
his father was sick and he wanted to
grow mushrooms because he thought the
mushrooms would help his father get
better
um and so you see this in the more
educated individuals that they can
recognize and understand the benefit
um that that mushrooms can have in the
human body
um
following our visit in newarkly and
there were a couple other experiences in
this region
um
Excuse me while I was in newaukee we
traveled to Camilla which is another
city in Bangladesh and visited this
Camilla substation here they were
currently producing mushrooms they sold
for 130 taka per kilogram fresh and 1500
Taco per kilogram dry
um and they explained to me a little bit
about the um training that Growers must
go through to be a part of this
extension system it's a three-day
training program
farmer Farmers or people are paid 600
taka to attend the training
and then they're given 25 free spawn
bags to begin their own Enterprise
so you really you know there's really a
big um push to get these Farmers to
attend the meetings a great incentive
600 taka that's
um you know some of the rural day
laborers we talked with their daily
wages
um
range from 200 taka to 500 taka per day
and so this is you know potentially
three days worth of wage by coming to
this training session whether they learn
to grow mushrooms or not you know they
were there and they got paid
um
we were
um oh so once the the farmers go through
the training
um maybe a week or two afterwards the
extension agents will visit their farms
and provide troubleshooting advice if
they aren't able to sell their mushrooms
then they will the Extension Center will
buy the mushrooms from them usually in
the dried form at whatever the
prevailing market rate is
during this time we were also able to
visit the Finney substation then he's
another city in Bangladesh
and we um
on the way to this station we came
across a doctor
um
I don't know he was he'd been in the
pharmacy trade for roughly 25 years I
don't think he he hadn't been to formal
medical school but
anyways he was referred to as a doctor
within the village
um and he prescribed Pharmaceuticals and
he used a pharmaceutical in his practice
one drug that was a mushroom derived
product for Myanmar in 2005 during the
caretaker government he wasn't able to
access this medicine and decided then
that he would grow his own mushrooms now
mind you this doctor was a former
mushroom grower again he cited limited
market development as his main obstacle
in developing this Enterprise
is the name of the sub Center in Finney
that means coconut Garden they had a
number of coconut trees it was uh they
were evaluating for different different
um
parameters and so we got to eat a lot of
coconuts during this visit it was it was
fun
um
and we talked to the director of the sub
Center who described a failure again a
failure of acceptance as a food item
lack of markets failure to create a
systemic production system and poor
retention of growers in the training
program
and so we see this this big National
um program but it's having trouble
getting off the ground and we'll talk
about some of the strategies in the next
but the next visit
um but one of the the positive impacts
of mushroom production is that it can be
done in sort of a local Village level
the number of Muslim communities women
are confined to The Cloister or the
group of houses that surround their own
household they aren't permitted to
travel to markets
or leave this tight Village area and so
mushrooms you don't have to go out to
the farms you don't have to go to the
field to cultivate mushrooms you can do
it in your backyard or next to your
house and so there have been a couple of
papers
that suggest Mushroom Enterprise may be
a method of gender sensitive development
a way to empower women in Bangladesh
we met with one woman this picture is I
took that picture that's not from the
paper
um
we met with this woman who she was
engaged in mushroom production
but said that
um she didn't know if it was a
profitable Enterprise because her
husband took care of all the financial
matters so
I guess I posed the question is this
really a gender sensitive opportunity or
do they need to tweak it a little
um
so
following
um
uh after a number of different
experiences later on in the fall I was
able to visit the center in Savar and
met with the direct the national
director of the mushroom development
program Dr Nira Chandra shakhar
um
in Savage the primary stage of
development they're trying to establish
processing and production technology
and they maintain a very close
relationship with India China and Japan
this is the source of all their
germplasm for the mushrooms so these are
all exotic species that are being
imported into Bangladesh maybe if they
were able to isolate
locally growing species that may be more
culturally adapted
environmentally adapted they may have
more success in their production systems
maybe the shape of the oyster mushroom
was throwing off consumers if they've
found something more recognizable to
them
they may want to eat it more but I think
there's really a big Obstacle of
perception with mushrooms in Bangladesh
as a whole
um
foreign
there are a number of advertising
programs on the radio and television
trying to promote the benefits of
mushroom as a food source and
people some of the people I talked to
suggested that this was making a
difference there's a few papers out
saying it's making a difference in
promoting mushroom consumption in
Bangladesh but I I'm still skeptical
that that they are um
actually making an impact
um
so just to conclude that section A
little bit uh Bangladesh Harbor is a
very robust extension system for
promoting mushroom development but it's
a very top-down oriented program coming
from International entities to um
to the local level
um
well so I mean mushrooms can be produced
in a variety of scales and methods I
mean you can produce it on the household
level
but you know here in the United States
they're all produced on a big huge
industrial scale
um you know I'm not really sure why they
chose mushrooms as a development
opportunity and why it's received so
much funding
um it I mean it very much seemed like
they were trying to force mushrooms on
the population
so
um
yeah but then here in the Chittagong
Hill track region and I'll talk about
this region a little bit more this is a
um an area a very high indigenous a very
high concentration of indigenous
ethnicities that are probably more
closely related to the Burmese Myanmar
folks than than the actual people that
make up the population of Bangladesh and
they love mushrooms you can find them in
the market you can find them you know
people are very eager and readily
consume mushrooms so
moving forward maybe the Extension
Center should concentrate their efforts
in in this region I know there's some
tension between
um
you know the the banglas and and the
indigenous ethnicities in several areas
but I was actually had the opportunity
to work there working with a Spanish NGO
and I'll get to that in a little bit
um so while I was in Noah we were able
to travel around and um you know I
wanted to develop the agriculture
context I wanted to learn how farmers
were how they formed what they used
while we were in newarkly this is Dr
Chandra charkar at the insavar a few
pictures of mushrooms that they were
growing there
is the pink oyster
it's pink but it doesn't really taste
very good so
I don't know these are Rishi mushrooms
being grown near Finney this was one of
the most prolific growers in the area he
had 2 000 of these spawn bags that you
can see
um
and this is
it's a
rice Patty straw so they take the
Harvest the rice and then the stubbles
left in the field and they will harvest
that there's also
some of the rice crops they'll grow are
just for the vegetative matter and not
for the rice
simply use that too
but you know one of the great things
about oyster mushroom is you can grow it
on
just about anything you stand kind of
tests you can grow it on toilet paper
rolls you can grow it on coffee grounds
and grow it on crude oil
it's really a very uh
very interesting mushroom
um this is in the uh
the the
uh if any office
um
and so we see that education was
um a big factor in adoption of mushroom
growing technology so we could say that
um
mushrooms make you more educated yeah
maybe
probably not
um but that education can promote the
adoption of mushroom growing and
consumption and so
you know I think we can suggest that
um an education program in Bangladesh
sort of as a whole for but one of the
complementary goals would that would be
that people would eat more mushrooms and
so
education
um so like I said I was able to spend
some time in Noah talking with Farmers
learning
um how they farmed
um
in the markets Market vendors were
generally very knowledgeable about
product Origins they can tell you what
town it was from what country it was
from if it was imported or domestic
um
and one problem is the post-harvest
storage and handling of high value
perishable Horticulture Commodities
um
formally used is widespread in the value
chain do you guys know formalin it's
used to preserve cadavers
highly toxic highly carcinogenic but
it's used to keep the produce from
rotting
from the from the when they buy it in
the local market and transport it to the
Urban Market
so we talk about rural urban Connections
in terms of urban food security
um
but in providing that food to the urban
populations there may be greater risks
there's also reports of people using
calcium carbide and
etaphon for fruit ripening both of which
are not permitted for edible crops
and so there's there is our public
health risks in turn in the Horticulture
value chain in Bangladesh that very
seriously need to be addressed
and people understand these risks and
and do not want to eat formally
contaminated food it's unfortunate that
it's mostly only the upper classes that
are able to avoid this risk because
grocery stores have branded their
products as formalin free and full
charge of Premium
um
in Milwaukee we encountered a number of
non-governmental groups engaged in
agriculture and extension development
um
you see up top this is a focus group
organized by the nookily rural
development society
and this Society performs duties similar
to an extension agent
um
except they focus on smallholder Farms
they provide seeds facilitate micro
Credit Opportunity organize Farmers into
groups they provide tractors and a range
for a cooperation within regions
and disseminate information and
Technology
um
when we talked in this focus group The
Farmers you know you ask farmers what
their problems are and you better have
your tape recorder on because they
Farmers love to talk about how their
their lives could be better
they mentioned very few storage options
for perishable Goods that can't be sold
at the market
Winter is the most productive season for
them and but yet they're limited by
access to Water Resources it is winter
is the dry season in Bangladesh
and they like I said were you know you
think with this flooded all these
flooded rice paddies that water wouldn't
be an issue but in the dry season it can
become a very serious issue
some other complaints were lack of
Transportation infrastructure limited
educational opportunities for their
children problems with soil salinity and
lack of access to Capital
uh down here in the bottom left we were
talking with a gentleman who led an IPM
Club this is a group of farmers who try
to disseminate sustainable Technologies
for Pest Management things like
pheromone traps were very popular within
this group
um
and the leader this is a translated
quote he said that waiting on government
extension service providers is a dark
hope so they've really sort of given up
on the government service providers and
providing extension services to their
agriculture communities
um
and so this was mind you this was all in
noakoli in the southern district and so
upon hearing this I said well hey why
don't we go talk to the extension
officers so we met with uh
an upazilla agriculture officer
upazil is just one of their
districts sub-district do you know the
the hierarchy
can you rattle it off maybe some
somebody else knows
said
hello
yeah so it's just how they arranged uh
okay
um so we met with the upazella
agriculture officer
whose primary duties this is
self-reported primary duties include a
thank you
include fertilizer distribution
reporting on agriculture activities and
monitoring the block officers
and so why is a government agent
involved in fertilizer distribution
they can probably well anyways but this
agent was not from the region he wasn't
from Noah he was from another part of
the country he doesn't know the region
very well
um
you know some of his main problems he
advises Farmers on Pest Management
strategies but many farmers will come in
with what they think are Pest management
issues really turn out to be soil
nutrient deficiencies but there's really
a lack of soil testing facilities in
Bangladesh
you know most of the farmers will
receive get their advice from the local
shopkeeper
and the shopkeeper his first question is
isn't what is your problem you know what
have you done
the first question is how much money do
you have and so the shopkeeper will sell
the farmers a product based on not on
their problems but how much money they
have and so if they've got a lot of
money he'll sell them an expensive
chemical or product
if they're if it doesn't have a lot of
money then he won't
these are a list of the pesticides that
Farmers said they were using in Noah I
want to highlight one right here lindane
has been banned in everywhere every part
of the world except for India and
Bangladesh
um
in addition to killing insects it also
kills people and so it's been
discontinued for sale in the United
States we found one farmer that was
using it
some of the other problems is many of
the Farmers can't read and so you have
these highly technical pesticide labels
and they aren't able to
understand the directions and how to
apply these pesticides certainly there's
no PPE personal protective equipment
but you know they're very readily
available there's
um you know probably three chemical and
Seed shops to every small I mean every
every locality
um
after talking with the um uh the
upazilla agriculture officer we went and
found the plant Protection Officer
um who described his he said his duties
were organizing farmer training he also
grants the pesticide shop licenses
um he says farmer training are organized
into small medium and large farm groups
about 70 percent of the farmers in
Milwaukee fall in this small group a
small farm group 25 in the medium and
five percent in the large
landless farmers sharecroppers are
grouped into the large farmer Group
which I don't know if that makes sense
or not
um egg subsidies in Bangladesh are
distributed by the ministry of AG uh
fertilizer and there's four basic
subsidies fertilizer and pesticide are
the entirety of the monies directed to
the Bangladesh chemical industry
Association Diesel and Equipment
subsidies are direct deposited into
Farmers bank accounts by the ministry of
AG so a farmer needs to have a bank
account to be eligible for this money
there's subsidies to seed and seedling
producers which is directed to the
Bangladesh agriculture development
commission and then there's price
setting subsidies for rice and pulse
products did I miss anything that's it
great
um
so following
we did get to visit ashwagandh
um I'm saying that right right Amanda
great
um so and here we found a almost a
success of the extension workers
um
I talked with the district assistant
District supervisor of the extension
um
activities in this for this area
you know we talked with a number of
different farmers who none of them
complained everybody knew their block
officer they talked with the extension
agent I think
you know with the dis the district
officer said was that
this region is more industrial oriented
than agriculturally oriented and so I
think when we say in newarkali is just
there's too many farmers I don't want to
say that right there's the the extension
officers are overwhelmed and here
there's an appropriate number of
extension officers to Farmers and so
they can develop a more personal
relationship
um
let's see some pictures this guy was in
the CNG with us CNG is like a natural
gas like a three-wheeled cart that you
can take between Villages there's a man
going around selling these snakes
um
he said that if he got bit he had the
vaccine so that he wouldn't get poisoned
I don't know it was really interesting
to see him he brings them out sort of
smacks them around
puffs up his hood one poem we visited
had a pet deer I don't know our deer
common in Bangladesh
is this like an endemic thing in the
Milwaukee region you can see it's I
don't know if you can see it's wearing a
collar so
this is clearly somebody's pet
yeah
just that doesn't really have anything
to do with anything just wanted to show
you the pictures
um so the Chittagong Hill tracks uh
during my time in Bangladesh I was able
to get a consulting position with a
Spanish NGO
working in this region my specific I was
an agriculture technical expert working
on rainwater harvesting techniques for
dry season agriculture
it was part of their project to
strengthening
socio-economic rights of indigenous
women in the region
um
when I took this position on
um I I don't know didn't know a lot
about rainwater harvesting I think
people had thought that they would have
rain you know the rain barrels
from the harvesting runoff from
buildings and things like that
um a number of the buildings in this
area were thatched roof not Stu tin
roofs that Harbor a number of microbial
contaminants
um so and at this point I really became
aware of Cornell not just as a brand and
you know a recognizable name but there's
actually professors here that are here
to provide help when you need it
um Dr Norman upoff and Dr Peter Hobbs
and a number of the staff here provided
some incredible resources
that helped me in this position and so
essentially what we were doing the the
um uh we were working in the Llama Ali
kadam area it's characterized like I
said by high populations of indigenous
groups household income is dependent on
agriculture the traditional system of
cultivation is called Doom or jume it's
a shifting cultivation otherwise known
as slash and burn
um
some of the villages due to increasing
land pressure
these Villages would traditionally have
a 30 to 50 year rotation now because of
increased land pressure
they're shortened to three to five so
the soil and the ecology doesn't have a
chance to recover this soil organic
matter and soil nutrient capacity and so
there you've got serious problems with
erosion
um
and loss of of
livelihoods almost because they fall
into this cycle of poverty where
traditional cultivation practices result
in reduced soil fertility decreasing
Vigor of crops in their resulting
progeny all of these Villages save their
seeds
further contributing to lower
productivity and resulting in reduced
wages and food insecurity
um
and so my goal was to encourage more
perennial systems this is a companion
planting guide
that we gave to the so I was working
with a local implementing agency turanga
I think is what they were called and
they had their own agriculture officers
so I was helping to train the
agriculture officers who would then
disseminate this information to the
local villages
and in determining projects to implement
can you guys see that
um
and determining projects to implement we
were able to go around and interview The
Villages you know I tried to engage in
the participatory approach to determine
who needed what what their needs were
and work together we introduced a number
of solutions that came from this
publication if you can see that
implementing integrated natural resource
management projects under the natural
National rural employment guarantee act
the National Royal rural employment
guarantee Act is an act in India
that basically provides a 100 days of
paid labor to rural rural people
and so there were a number of strategies
for rainwater harvesting and soil water
retention that came from this
publication that took place in in
eastern India very close right on the
Bangladesh border so appropriate
technologies that have been developed in
a similar region and then we introduced
these to the localities and they were
able to decide what they wanted to do
there were some cost sharing
arrangements with the implementing
organization and the locality
so it wasn't just sort of a donation
here we'll put in you know a pond for
you for nothing it was the the villagers
were engaged in in the problem and the
solution and oftentimes paid to pay for
their labor to work so a number of the
strategies were based on the slope of
the land we encountered all of these
different slopes within the villages
some people
a few of the more isolated Villages were
living exclusively on this eight percent
and greater slope area
but then like I said a number of
different slopes and each strategy
depends on the slope
um for its appropriate strategies to try
and just hold the soil hold the ground
hold the water in in Syria in serious
moisture events and here's pictures from
the region this is my my friend Nico
this is a pond we dug
or helped to dig with with one of the
local groups
you can see this is maybe two or three
days after we dug the pond and it's
already I got more than a meter of water
in the bottom of it this is a gully plug
this is the same Village
um
which so when when the rain falls you
get these channels being cut out of the
hill and these Gully plugs are put in
place to slow the ground slow the the
water so that it reduces erosion
eventually you'll get like um the soil
will build up behind the Gully plug and
you'll have a flat space to cultivate
your crops it's full of this Rich
organic topsoil
um that has fallen from the rest of the
hill and so you know these are some of
the strategies we worked with
um and again like I said you know
mushrooms were commonly consumed in this
area but I didn't really see the
presence there are I think two of the
extension centers in this area to travel
by foreigners is difficult it's
regulated you have to get a special pass
to enter the Chittagong Hill tracks and
you are are not supposed to be working
when you're there this was all volunteer
so I wasn't working per se
but it's it's a there's a lot of turmoil
in this region
that I don't really want to get into
right now
um
so just sort of reflecting on uh my
experience in Bangladesh it was it was I
mean it was a great country I had a
wonderful time I had a lot of great
experiences but I think
um in terms of the mushrooms you know it
was very top-down oriented approach
um so in in Rwanda I worked for a usaid
Hort crisp trellis fund that sounds like
a lot
um
it's a critical crisp is critical
research support program and the trellis
fund engages graduate students provides
funds for them to travel for two weeks
to 13 14 different countries I mean you
only get to travel to one country and
work with one NGO in that country I was
paired with sustaining Rwanda Youth
Organization
and they had identified mushroom
cultivation as a mechanism they were
hoping to improve
household food security and provide
rural Enterprise for one Village that
they work with and near bhutari the
Southern and the southern region
um and so
when I arrived in Rwanda I spent the
first week traveling to a number of
different
um
mushroom people engaged in the mushroom
industry mushrooms are very popular in
Rwanda it's considered a high value food
item that's associated with significant
cultural events
Sunday Sundays everybody goes to church
it's a family day so they eat mushrooms
for Easter or other religious holidays
baptisms they'll eat mushrooms and so
you know it was once very expensive but
now it's about half the price of meat in
the market and it's it's quite readily
available
so this is a group we met with that had
their own mushroom lab
everybody cultivates oyster mushroom
because it's the easiest to grow
this group
was started from what's called a seed
fund from the UN development program to
start their own Enterprise they they do
grow some mushrooms but mostly their
tests with education
and they work with a couple of groups
throughout the country to uh that are
more technically oriented but this group
was very education oriented
Kigali Farms is a
probably our most helpful partner in in
Rwanda
they're trying to uh like it says bring
affordable high impact crops to Rwanda
um the I think is the CEO of Kigali
Farms was a former CFO of omagang
Brewery just down the road in
Cooperstown so he asked me to bring him
a bottle of the Abbey Ale that we shared
when we met up
um but they're trying to uh provide this
was really neat because they were trying
to they're promoting mushroom
cultivation in rural areas and then
buying a mushroom and providing a
Marketplace here they have solar dryers
um to extend the shelf life of the
mushrooms so they can impact and access
more markets
band producers was probably the biggest
mushroom producer mushroom distributor
they're a wholesaler in Rwanda
they they had a retail outlet and
probably the biggest Market in Kigali
the capital city although we did hear
rumors that they weren't actually paying
their Growers that they were just taking
the mushrooms and writing an IOU
um and near bhutari there's the rabona
agriculture experiment station this is a
partnership with the Chinese government
and a demonstration of Chinese
agriculture technology this is the media
sterilizer they were using to sterilize
their bags they used an elephant grass
media is what they call it it's really
tall you can see it in the background
here you know it grows 11 12 feet tall
these are the spawn bags that they were
cultivating this is so this is a um
uh subsidized you know these bags are
way below the market price for other
other you know Kigali Farms produces
spawn bags and they sell them for 400
Rwandan francs for a bag
the rabona experiment station sells them
for 300 Rwandan francs per bag and they
probably don't even you know they don't
have to sell them for that they could
give them away and they do especially
when it's a program targeted for Rural
Enterprise development
um after we visited all the Farms so if
you see here one thing I learned in
visiting these Farms was just sort of
how they grow mushrooms in Rwanda
um because
mushrooms require a high moisture
capacity high moisture content it's very
difficult to control to create a
controlled atmosphere and so they'll put
the mushrooms bags into the soil and so
they can regulate soil moisture much
better than they can regulate
atmospheric moisture
and so I offered a training I spent
about an hour talking what is a mushroom
providing marketing advice and
production technical production advice
and then we built a pilot plot behind
this community church so that women
could see how to grow mushrooms we gave
them maybe 50 bags to cultivate as a
community
um
the training was targeted at a women's
cooperative and Rwanda is a very sort of
Cooperative country they
the women are they're identified as as
having
um
malnourished children they're invited to
attend a maternal and child feeding
class it's a 10 week class and after
completing the class they are invited to
join the cooperative and when you become
a Cooperative in Rwanda you're given a
savings account and formally recognized
by the Rwandan government you're giving
like a certificate and so
you know they have a savings account for
which they could promote micro credit
activities
um and it was targeted by the the
sustaining Rwanda Youth Organization for
a number of uh rural Enterprise
activities
um and so following the training we uh
we bought some mushrooms and brought
them to this training and the women we
all cooked them together and then shared
lunch after following the training they
make a really nice Curry mushroom curry
with peanut flour
onions and tomatoes
some other rural Enterprise that we
witnessed in in Rwanda this is a wooden
cup it's intricately carved very nice
this is all sorghum that's being malted
they do a lot of home brewing and beer
production in in the rural areas of
Rwanda
um I didn't try any I don't know if I
regret that or not
um and so just sort of Reflections on
the Rwanda experience
um Market access in our specific project
was limited by household consumption
so I don't know if that's a bad thing or
not it's sort of affects the
sustainability of the project because
they aren't able to generate income but
they're also getting a nutritious food
source in their household so you know it
goes goes back and forth
um
the sustaining Rwanda Youth Organization
the director and some of their
volunteers you know I was with a
different volunteer every day which was
nice but they weren't able to develop
the technical capacity that they needed
to encourage this Enterprise in Rwanda
there were some serious issues with
termites so I was able to suggest
biocontrol options I don't know if they
were able to get a hold of those buyer
control options or not
and so it's really difficult to
determine what impact my time in Rwanda
made that the people in Rwanda it was a
profound experience for me but I don't
know
what impact I had in the locality
comparing the two Rwanda
was a little bit easier to work I feel
like the you know there are some
very serious ethnic issues in Rwanda but
the government has made laws saying that
you cannot differentiate between the
ethnicities in public media and so
you know the Rwanda experience in their
history is tragic and I think they're
really looking forward to look behind
that
um and really work together at being one
Rwanda
um
so I don't I don't know but the legacy
of mushroom consumption in Rwanda was
was very important dispute is a high
value product with a considerable demand
looking to the future
I think more work on monitoring and
evaluating Mushroom Enterprise
especially in Rwanda is important
um
there's a lot of information right now
about biochar
whether it works or not people have
different views but in planting the
mushrooms in the soil like we saw in
Rwanda you really are increasing the
soil organic matter and could
potentially pave the way for more
perennial cropping systems
such as tree fruits and agroforestry
related systems
and then you know what is the role in
the government other agencies I wrote
inhibiting up there because you know is
in subsidizing their spawn bags is the
Rwanda extension service are they
inhibiting appropriate Market
development
and then how do you introduce Innovation
to a rural community without having them
be dependent on your
um on you giving input you know the
women they after they ate all the
mushrooms they said okay can we have
some more spawn bags now they said well
we don't have any money so I think the
project sort of ended at that
um
you know how do you how do you introduce
a new idea without
the people becoming dependent on your
inputs
um so that's all I've got today thank
you for coming out
um
does anybody have any questions
in terms of
sort of seemed like limited success of
mushroom cultivation in terms of their
every Target holds
um there's like a castle Enterprise kind
of
100 but um do you think that there's
opportunities
you know you started talking about maybe
like in terms of remediation there for
soil fertility or for the
pricing containing water or I mean is
there is there any additional a better
Niche for mushroom cultivation than
trying to sell people who don't want to
buy it yeah
um
probably
you know I you look at
um
in terms of Agriculture inputs you know
there's pretty heavy Transportation
costs that are associated with Organic
inputs
um
there's a lot of ammonium nitrate
available
in Bangladesh
and so as you know to sort of
differentiate like the
um
you know agriculture mushrooms excuse me
you know for agriculture inputs I think
it'd be difficult
you know and then you know I don't know
how do you incorporate into sort of a
market-based system to get it out to the
people
um I mean they're definitely
could be opportunity I just don't know
what it would be
would it be better as a
serving in need
like let's say you know other
development programs that introduce
different crops
there's like a paired
cooking kind of component
with small scale
their development kind of programs
do you think that that sort of approach
would work
um
right
um so
vegetable consumption in in Bangladesh
was not very common you know around the
time of their independence
my understanding is that once
um
people started working going to Saudi
Arabia and other countries to seek
employment they said you know they
started bringing back the tradition of
vegetable consumption
um
and so you know in that way it's more of
the organic sort of ground up
adoption of these habits I don't know if
there would be a
um education program that could
combat the Obstacle of perceptions of
mushrooms and Bangladesh
is that what you were asking
anybody else were they doing anything
with uh
yeah Bangladesh is a very densely
populated country and so space is a
as a constraint so that's why we were
only seeing substrate
cultivation plus you know a lot of the
yeah a lot of the wood is used for fuel
for cooking fires and so there's not
really that abundance of forest
resources that we see here
I mean in Bangladesh everything's got a
use
it seems like and so
you know to be able to
identify as substrate an appropriate
substrate I think it's difficult
with her
okay thank you very much so nice
communication
you know the Bangladesh government is
going to be surprised to the mushroom
calculation
excuse me
and the substation okay also
the narica Bagan is in Penny yeah
wall Center in the
in the shower why you are not
oh I did go to
um
like cold storage
well so the I mean that was one of the
to answer your second question first
um you know
farmers were selling their mushrooms
within in their Village
um you know there were significant
obstacles of transportation and when you
know in these sort of village units
they're able to educate the their the
other villagers about the benefits of
mushroom
um
and so I think in that way they're able
to develop these Market mechanisms they
they still were not sufficient to you
know that I talked to more former
mushroom Farmers than current mushroom
Farmers so you know something
something's not working in that end and
then we did visit Savar I spent a day in
Savar talking with the national director
of the program
um
but yeah I mean so I did visit some more
yeah thank you
well help your skies help yourself the
cookies and coffee thanks for coming out
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu