this is a production of Cornell
University thanks NE for the
introduction thank you everyone for
coming today um I'm Angela and I'm going
to be sharing some research plans and
some preliminary results for my PhD work
here which is focusing on nanoscale
characterization of carbon mineral
interfaces particularly in intact soil
microaggregates
so to start on the very broad scale uh
these are just some values of carbon
stocks and various uh parts of the
global carbon budget and soil as we know
is a fairly large stock of carbon um
especially compared to vegetation it's
commonly stated to be about three times
the content of carbon in the atmosphere
so this really uh relatively large stock
is important for the overall CL carbon
budget and whether carbon and soil is
increased or decreased or stay stays
consistent is a really important factor
for overall carbon
balance so this is just a global soil
organic carbon distribution um and from
here on I'll be focusing on organic
carbon uh showing in Northern permafrost
really high carbon concentrations in
blue but I also like to focus on some
more uh hotpots of high high carbon
content uh in this case I'd like to talk
mostly about volcanic soils in areas
like the Indonesia Mexico and
particularly Hawaii um so now zooming
into the island of
Hawaii the carbon content in volcanic
soils which are part of the andisol soil
order have a relatively high carbon
content compared to a lot of the other
soil orders and also Based on
radiocarbon data a lot of the carbon is
very old meaning that it's fairly stable
and soil and has been there for a long
time but this actually depends a bit on
the age of the soil so if you imagine
brand new lava deposits just being a few
hundred years old ranging to soils that
have been um weathering for 4 million
years somewhere in the middle there's a
peak in the amount of carbon content and
also carbon age and this uh is a concept
that has been linked um particularly
with mineral properties of that Medium
age
soil and this is particularly apparent
in deeper Horizons uh so this is a map
of um carbon organic carbon content at a
depth of about 60 to 100 cm with of red
showing higher contents and relative to
for instance the contiguous United
States you can see that deep soil
horizons in Hawaii and other volcanic
soils um have much higher carbon
contents and again this is linked with
particularly uh mineral properties in
this system and this is a really good
example of the overall relationship
between carbon stabilization and
minerals um and this is apparent in many
different ecosystems with varying
degrees of importance dependent on that
minerology so this is a process that I
like to think about um as ranging from
the ecosystem scale all the way down to
the scale of a few microns a few
nanometers at the actual interface of
carbon and minerals in soil so again in
the example of the volcanic soils you
have an ecosystem property minerology um
and in these medium AG soils they are
dominated by what we call short range
ordered or semicrystalline mineral Minal
so I'll refer to those kind of as both
SRO or semicryst minerals for the rest
of the talk and then moving down to the
Nano scale there are properties at the
actual surface of these minerals such as
pH dependent charge and high surface
area that are related to their carbon
storage
properties so I'm just going to give a a
brief overview of some of the proposed
mechanisms of carbon stabilization by
minerals but an important concept is
that the actual mechanism involved is
very specific to the mineral uh the type
of carbon present and also the
environmental factors that are at work
in that particular system so just one
example is a mechanism of Li exchange um
or an ion exchange for stabilization of
uh soil organic carbon by the
semicrystalline or short range ordered
minerals that I mentioned earlier in
volcanic soils alphane and Amite being
two examples of that kind of mineral in
addition to Li exchange and an exchange
just a few other General interaction
mechanisms hydrophobic
interactions hydrogen bonding cation
bridging general effects of
entropy and then a little bit uh Less
Direct than actual surface stabilization
uh you can also have more indirect
effects of physical protection by
mineral facilitated aggregate formation
or stabilization in pores so these are
all just very general uh proposed
mechanisms of carbon stabilization by
minerals one of the uh more interesting
models of surface interactions is uh the
zonal model proposed by clubber where
you have amphophilic molecules which
basically have a polar end and a
non-polar end um creating this kind of
bylayer model where you have the the
polar end interacting with Sur surface
and then the long sort of non-polar
Tails interacting in a hydrophobic Zone
and then lots of potential interactions
with the aquous solution on the um
kinetic
zone so there are are many different uh
proposed
mechanisms but why do does that really
make a difference if we know it's
stabilized you know why do we need to
know how and I think that it's really
important Because the actual mechanism
involved May respond differently to
changing environmental variables uh
increased temperature increased moisture
um in particular an example would be a
Cove valent or an actual chemical bond
in inner spher complex formation for
instance May respond differently to to
warmer temperatures than say a weak
hydrophobic Association so knowing what
kind of mechanism is involved could be
really important for prediction of uh
future soil carbon stabilization in
modeling for
instance currently all of these
mechanisms that I've mentioned are have
mostly been determined indirectly by
absorption isotherm experiments for
example and currently they lack direct
observation and characterization in real
soils or in
situ but what we do have so far for
analysis of car carbon mineral
interfaces in soil has shown
unsurprisingly a very heterogeneous
distribution of carbon um on the scale
of an Aggregate and all the way down to
the scale of an actual mineral particle
so this image um shows carbon in yellow
and this is Nan Nano secondary ion mass
spectrometry and you can see that the
carbon is really distributed in in
discret patches and not distributed
evenly over the surface of the mineral
and
this patchy distribution um has also
been observed all the way down to a
single mineral surface so this presents
uh a pretty substantial methodological
challenge for observation um in terms of
both the spatial heterogeneity and also
chemical
variability so to get a little bit more
into the methodological challenges
namely spatial resolution is a huge
limitation so some current techniques uh
such as Nexa which is
near Edge x-ray absorption fine
structure which is a synchrotron based
technique has about a 25 to 50 nanometer
spatial resolution which is just tooo
big unbelievably seems so small uh to to
en Encompass the kind of variability
that we see in
soil also some other methodological
challenges are uh the use of a
stabilizing material to actually make
thin sections which is of often carbon
based so then it's really hard to see
carbon when you use a carbon stabilizing
resin uh also for instance in this study
mineral particles were kind of shaken up
and then distributed on a Surface so you
don't maintain the spatial distribution
in an actual Aggregate and then also in
general um high energy analysis using an
electron beam or x-rays can create
sample damage so these are all things
that have to be considered for direct
observation so one method uh this is now
what I will be focusing on for the rest
of the talk is a combination of scanning
transmission electron microscopy or stem
and electron energy loss spectroscopy
lots of acronyms eels so just really uh
briefly eels involves um the Electron
Beam from the microscope going into a
very thin cross-section sample and then
some of those electrons will just pass
right through and some of them will
interact with the material and then
scatter and so some of the scattering is
inelastic which means that it loses
energy and so you can measure that
energy loss with a spectrometer hence
getting electron energy loss
spectroscopy and that's just basically
how that works um and then when you get
an energy loss Spectrum you have some
distinctive Peaks for certain elements
so this is for carbon which is in
diamond and graphite
um but then you have a distinctive uh
Peak position and shape or the fine
structure which tells you something
about what that carbon is bonded to so
if it's bonded to oxygen it's a double
bond to another carbon uh
nitrogen you can get an idea of what
functional groups are there and what
their coordination might be this is a an
image of um stem eels of a um Amazonian
Dark Earth that has biochar particles
but this particular image shows an
alumino silicate clay in red and then
iron oxide on the surface and you can
determine using eels that it's um
oxidized iron or iron 3 based on the
intensity signals which I'll be talking
about later so eels is a really good
tool for both very high resolution uh
ideally for a
um a homogeneous material the resolution
can be up to0 two nanometers about two
angstroms which is unbelievably high for
natural soils probably not that good but
that's kind of the idea um and then also
be able to get information about the the
chemical composition of the sample so
that's a really useful
combination so now I'd like to give an
overview of the main chapters or
sections of my PhD research uh so to
start I'm going to be compiling um a
library of sorts of eel Spectra for
a number of different soil minerals um
and then also common model carbon in
soil and then building on that uh
collect eels data for simplified
mixtures of carbon and minerals and that
will be designed based on specific
hypothesized interactions that have
interesting spatial uh information in a
in this case a simplified system where
the environmental variables can be
controlled so Redux potential or pH that
somehow may be affecting the interaction
mechanism and then sort of the end goal
or the epitome of all of this is
applying the technique to real soils uh
in thin sections um while importantly
maintaining spatial distribution in the
sample eliminating the use of
stabilizing materials or carbon resins
that would allow us to not be able to
analyze carbon and then also uh
minimizing sample damage
so I'm kind of pursuing each of these
three things uh all at once uh so I'll
show you a few aspects of each of them
uh and then the next steps for each as
well so to start uh some of the
standards that I've chosen uh are listed
here and they represent a range of
elements I specifically am also
analyzing volcanic soil M minerals um
alifan and ulite for instance um as well
as some other elements calcium and
phosphorus minerals and then similarly
for carbon uh there are many different
kinds of carbon present in soil as we
know and so I've selected a list that
cover a broad range of functional group
types and also some that are specific to
Black carbon um or biochar because I'm
in Johannes leman's
lab so I just like to show you a couple
of reference uh Spectra that I've
collected so far these are for hematite
and gerti both iron minerals hematite is
an iron oxide and gerti and iron oxy
hydroxide so each of these particles is
ground very fine and then um deposited
this this Lacy background is a is carbon
that you just deposit the materials on
and then you end up with some areas on
the edges that are are thin enough uh
for eels so the whole particle is going
to be way too thick but you can get some
kind of regions on the
edges and before I start showing a bunch
of Spectra that are not going to mean a
whole lot um I just wanted to give a
quick overview of some of the
terminology so when you're talking about
nexas or eels um you're talking about K
L M and N edges and these basically
correspond to the simplified bore model
of an atom uh the energy levels that you
can also see in your gen cam electron
configuration sort of representation so
you have your core electrons uh closer
to the um the nucleus that are uh your K
and L edges and those will require more
energy to be excited or to uh to move to
the next energy level and then out in
the outer edges you have the M and N uh
which are more of your veence electrons
uh so those require much lower
energy this is a just a simplified
schematic of an eel Spectrum so right at
zero you have a huge Peak called a zero
loss Peak which tells you uh how many
electrons just pass straight through
your sample and you want to know that
because you want to know that it's thin
enough to be able to use this technique
so that's a really important thing to uh
collect for all all of your Spectra and
then you have this kind of indistinct
bump in the low loss region and so
that's indicating all of the those m&amp;n
edges in your veilance elction
and there's a lot of overlap between
different elements in that region so
it's kind of hard to get really
uh uh qualitative information from that
uh but you can kind of confirm that okay
well I see the iron M Edge so that means
iron is definitely present here but when
you start to move out into the higher
energy regions um where you might be
looking at your carbon iron oxygen edges
the elements of Interest that's where
you start to get um an apparent Peak for
the core loss and then all of this fine
structure that tells you something about
uh The Binding environment of that
element so here is a um a spectrum for
hematite and gerti for iron so this is
the iron L Edge now and on initial kind
of observation they look fairly similar
uh
however even very small shifts can be
meaningful in terms of uh Discerning
between different kinds of iron so if
there's you know a little bit of a
difference in the shape of this little
shoulder there could be a shoulder here
that could vary by different kinds of
minerals like this very subtle shift in
in Peak position may be meaningful and
currently there isn't a whole lot of
information in the literature about
these fine distinctions between iron
minerals and soil so this could add a
really uh could add some really good
information to that this spectrum uh so
hematite has been image before with eels
so this is a a spectrum in the
literature so it's quite
similar and also which has been pretty
well established is that the ratio of L3
and L2 these two peaks is um a function
of the sample oxidized to reduce iron
content so that's really convenient and
that's how we can use eels to kind of
discern iron 3 and iron 2 so there's a
pretty uh pretty consistent Rel
relationship between the the ratio of
those Peaks so you could have hematite
which is theoretically 100% oxidized
iron and then something like fite which
is theoretically 0% oxidized iron and be
able to kind of map in this spectrum um
a wide variety of different redo States
in Iron which is really a useful
tool for oxygen you can see that the
Spectrum starts to Look a Lot Messier um
which really takes away a lot of the
conclusions you can draw from it but
there is a pretty um apparent difference
between the ratio of A and B in this
spectrum and it turns out that that is
related to the uh degree of oxidation
and this is also a very consistent
predictable Trend so you can use that to
determine the iron oxygen ratio which is
another really useful
tool and finally for hematite and gerti
this is the veence region the really low
loss so starting
just above zero um up to about 60 and so
there isn't a whole lot of really great
information here you have carbon coming
from the grid that we prepared the
samples on but you do have an iron M
edge here so that's really good for as
like an independent confirmation that
iron is present and we might be able to
get some information from that as
well so just quickly uh two other uh
minerals that we've analyzed so far are
Gibs site and hydroxy appetite so
looking at aluminum calcium and
phosphorus aluminum is really hard to
get um EOS Spectrum for because it is in
the low loss range and as I mentioned
there's a lot of overlap there uh so
that's a challenge um which is a little
unfortunate because aluminum of course
is very common in soil and a very
important part of of mineral
interactions and just quickly this is a
list of the remaining elements or the
remaining um minerals that I have to
analyze as I mentioned some volcanic
minerals alifan and aite some kind of
normal crystallin uh Clays and then also
iron oxides that represent that range of
um Iron
oxidation and we have started working on
some carbon standards an issue with that
is uh they're much less resistant to
damage from the Electron Beam than iron
minerals and also um typically when you
have any sample that goes into the
microscope you have to clean it with a
plas an oxygen plasma before it goes in
so that it doesn't contaminate with just
things floating around in the microscope
but of course these are carbon compounds
and cleaning them with plasma would kind
of just burn them away which would be
kind of useless so we don't have a good
way to clean them and so this ends up
posing a huge problem with carbon
contamination so in order to get around
that we're working on uh doing eels at
very low temperature called cryo eels
which helps eliminate carbon
contamination and then also using
alternative sample cleaning uh one
example is critical point
drying so next I'm just going to give a
quick overview of um my proposed work um
in these simplified mixtures this isn't
something that I've started yet so I'd
be glad to hear any input you might have
in in this or suggestions and so
basically these are going to be uh
simplified systems in a kind of a
classic absorption isotherm type
approach um based on some specific
hypothesized interactions and Then
followed by analysis of the particles
themselves with eels to see if we can
kind of really unequivocally um
determine what is going on at that
interface so this is just one example of
one of my proposed combinations so this
would be using a a polar carbon shown
here just generically as a RC and a
non-polar carbon with a generic carbon
chain uh and
Amite another again one of the volcanic
minerals so one hypothesis is that the
polar carbon will be involved in Cove
valent bonding but only at the edges or
the the ends of the emite tube or at
broken SES on the surface and that the
non non-polar carbon may not interact at
all or it could uh be involved in some
kind of secondary association with the
polar carbon so just to give you an idea
of the spatial distribution that we
might see you could see just polar
carbon at the ends and nonpolar carbon
not associated at all we could see it
everywhere or just in broken sites and
non-polar not associated or non-polar
could go to the ends or it could cover
the whole thing so there are lots of
different uh possibilities here um but
what is great about this technique is
that we'll be able to see you know a
difference between this carbon and this
carbon and be able to assign where it is
spatially in this system which is really
useful and then next uh one of the
proposed incubations or absorption
experiments would involve a sequence of
reducing conditions and oxidizing
conditions reducing oxidizing reducing
oxidizing to try to um encourage iron
co-precipitation with carbon so there
has been some a recent work about
spatial differences between carbon
that's just absorb to the surface of
oxidized iron versus carbon that's just
physically intercalated in the structure
of a um a co-precipitate between iron
and carbon so this is just something
that has a really interesting spatial
characteristic which is really the
benefit of the technique that I'm using
so it's important to select things that
have some kind of interesting spatial
information so finally I'm going to show
you some preliminary results from actual
analysis of real soils which is kind of
the ultimate goal of this work as I
mentioned earlier the main challenges
here are preventing damage to the sample
um eliminating that carbon resin
maintaining the spatial distribution
within an Aggregate and then also being
able to analyze both carbon and the
mineral chemistry and so similarly to
the cryo eels I mentioned for analyzing
the carbon standards we're going to be
us using cryo FIB or focused ion beam
Milling to prepare the samples and
hopefully this will um account for a few
of the methodological considerations and
Then followed by that we'll be using
cryo eel so everything is Frozen from
beginning to end um in water which is a
more natural uh Matrix than carbon resin
and as you might have guessed my initial
soil samples will be from volcanic soils
um from a model ecosystem with mineral
control on carbon
turnover so just a quick overview uh the
soils that I'm using right now are
collected from Hawaii by uh
collaborators Katie Grant who's here and
Lou Derry and Earth and atmospheric
sciences uh this particular sample um is
characterized as a wiia silt Loom and
it's about uh in the middle range of
soil age around 350,000 years old and so
it's characterized by those uh short
range ordered or semic crystallin
minerals that I mentioned
earlier so these are some uh scanning
electron microscope images just of
intact Aggregates just to give you an
idea what they look like and how
variable they are um so you can see that
you know you have some that are kind of
uh lumpy and some that are kind of
smooth some that are stretched out so
even in the aggregate shape there's a
lot of
variability these were collected from
deeper soils and also from A system that
has relatively high iron and carbon
content and they are well drained so
they're probably dominated by oxidized
iron I selected uh Aggregates in the
range of about 53 to 150 Micron diameter
so microaggregates and this is
for ease of analysis it's just a better
size to use and also these
microaggregates may have um really
stable uh mineral
interactions so this is a little cartoon
of
how we start to section the Aggregates
uh so first they're hydrated uh slowly
with a um a humidifier and then just
dropped in a little bead of water flash
frozen in liquid nitrogen and then cut
into sections using a cryo Ultram
microtome or a diamond blade just a
little and then it ends up on a copper
Grid in a thin section that still has
ice around it and it stays
Frozen so then uh if you can visualize
this is now that grid looking from above
so each of these little blobs are
sections of carbon so you can see
they're kind of variable um but if you
were to look at them from the side they
are actually relatively uh flat on both
sides amazingly it's a really
interesting technique and they kind of
cover a range of shapes um some of them
kind of break apart on natural uh
breaking points some of them look like
pork chops I think some of them look
like tacos but then you have to find the
one that just looks just right and
that's the one you go
with so then after you have your perfect
sections that you want to try to look at
you then uh in the FIB uh which is the
focused ion beam you have a beam of
gallium ions that come down at an
angle and kind of cut out a wedge out of
the out of the sample so you end up with
a really thin area at the bottom and
then just sort of the normal sample
thickness at the top and you can see
that in each of these images here we
have um our our wedges with only the
very edge of the sample probably thin
enough for eels so it's getting down to
a really small area for analysis and so
you kind of have to get a little bit
lucky that you catch a really
interesting feature in that tiny
area but we fortunately did last week um
and hopefully more to come um so this is
just some some very preliminary results
for uh some of our initial Imaging so
this is just one of those sections and
then one of a tiny area of one of these
sections then blown up much bigger um
and then this tiny area blown up bigger
here and then finally a um Elemental map
of that region so this is a electron
dispersive x-ray so it's a very coarse
Scale map but you can see that uh we
have carbon which is exciting and you
can see this area here is relatively uh
homogeneous carbon which is nice it's
not mixed up with a lot of other
elements and then we have a particle of
that of mostly aluminum it also has
oxygen no silicon so it's probably an
aluminum
oxide however this is a little bit of a
problem we also have gallium where could
that have come from of course the uh the
gallium ion beam right so uh gallium
likes to uh deposit itself on the sample
sometimes uh so this is just something
we need to be aware of um and make sure
that it's not changing our signals too
substantially you'll notice though that
it's really concentrated in the aluminum
area and hardly any signal at all in the
carbon which is nice because then we can
be able to analyze the carbon without
worrying about gallium um but this is
something we need to consider for future
analyses so now going even smaller we
have this area of carbon and aluminum
blown up to a STM image or stem image so
this is your carbon here and then um
each of the areas of different contrast
are
higher um higher atomic weight elements
so they show up differently and then
even more uh magnification we then have
carbon and we can start to see this
interface with um a mineral that we have
putatively determin as
aluminum and then even one more image
this is the highest resolution I have we
have carbon and then this kind of fuzzy
but still kind of distinct interface so
just something to to note here uh This
scalebar Is 50 nanometers um so when I
mentioned nexs that the resolution is 25
to 50
nanometers just imagine that half of
this or the whole thing is just one
whole pixel so this is a much better
spatial resolution already even at just
this scale than we could get with NEX
apps which is a really exciting thing
also exciting uh we collected a a carbon
kedge eel Spectrum from this area to my
knowledge the first in real soil without
a carbon resin so it's kind of an
exciting day um it's not a particularly
distinctive Spectrum but there are a few
things that even just with very
preliminary uh analysis we can start to
see so there's no Peak at
285 which is characteristic of aromatic
carbon um and very consistent across all
types of carbon for nexafs which is
mostly related to eel's data um we do
have these two kind of indistinct prep
Peaks at about 287 and 289 um EV and
they could really be a whole bunch of
different things um could be shift of
aromatic carbon with an oxygen or a
nitrogen um or could be aliphatic carbon
289 could be uh carboxilic acids or
amines or alcohols so you can see the
value of determining the carbon
reference library and being in analyzing
real soils because we can really start
to link these Peaks and their
characteristics with known functional
groups we also have
a uh a line scan uh which basically
takes points along a line that
you uh draw on the image uh so we can
start to kind of get a range across a a
gradient so first in the adjacent carbon
region this is the Spectrum I just
showed and then starting to get closer
to the edge you can see that the
Spectrum starts to get a lot Messier um
lots of variability here and that's
because it starts to get thicker as you
get closer to the mineral so as we
continue to prepare more samples we
really want to try to maximize the the
thinness of the of the sample um it's
just going to continue to be something
to work on but you can already see that
there are some differences um
potentially in the relationship of those
first two preps just out at this Outer
Edge and then at a point closer to the
interface uh there's there are quite a
few new new small Peaks um lots of
variability uh this is going to take a
lot of analysis to get what might be
meaningful out of the spectrum and then
of course the more uh the less signal to
noise ratio we can get the better it
will be at being able to pull out
features of these Spectra and then
finally one more on the other side um
and you can see that the the first
prepak is almost gone so the meaning of
this is going to take a lot of analysis
but it's kind of an exciting development
to see that there are
differences across this uh mineral
carbon
region so just to wrap up um the next
things that I'm going to be working on
continued sample preparation
uh for the thin sections continued
analysis and then working on linking
carbon compound chemistry and the
interface and then just in general uh
continuing to analyze standards the
simplified mixture experiments um and
then lots and lots and lots of data
analysis forever and ever to get
meaningful information from this from
this data so I just like to acknowledge
my funding which is from the cross scale
bio geochemistry and climate igit and
then also also we've been working with
the Cornell Center for materials
research which is uh a really really
essential piece of this we would
definitely not be able to do it without
our collaborators in physics David
Mueller who works with eels and Lena
fitting kudus who does uh fib and then
their grad students have collected a lot
of this data with me and have been
really really helpful um also my thesis
committee U my adviser Johannes Leman
who's not here today unfortunately um
and then also we've gotten lots of
support support from my lab and the
support staff at the
ccmr so there are tons and tons of
really interesting resources which
obviously you can't read but if you ever
want to talk to about where any I got
any of this information from I'd be glad
to discuss it further and finally uh
thank you so much for your attention do
you have any
questions this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu you