this is a production of Cornell
University let's talk about genomes so
uh frany said she when I met her just a
little while ago she said she likes to
work with things she can see and so you
know who wants to work with DNA which
you can't see so um the problem of
seeing the DNA is really important for
understanding how the genome works and
so we're talk going to talk about data
visualization so uh before I start I'd
like to just some of you may have missed
it but in the beginning of September
there was a major scientific Advance 30
Publications were published
simultaneously in science nature and
other journals uh which is the fruit
coming out of the encode project and the
latest phase of the encode project and
so this was a paradigm shifting uh
outcome and it it it says something
about the genome which I'd really like
to communicate to you the leader of this
this vast Consortium of scientists uh
something like several I think over a
hundred scientists who were part of the
Consortium over aund million doar spent
on this it's basically phase three of
the Genome Project you know once you
have a genome you have to figure out
what it's doing and so they've been
trying to understand what what the
genome does this is what the leader of
program said he said the genome is a
jungle of information is multi-layered
and multi-dimensional and that higher
genomes are mostly functional a major
major paradigm shift in terms of
understanding of the genome and so uh
the bottom line is that not only does we
usually think of the genetic code you
know the code that goes from DNA to RNA
to protein well that only accounts for 1
to 2% of the genome there are many other
codes many many codes in the genome many
languages and they overlap and if you
ask a computer scientist if they could
write overlapping code they would just
you know their eyes would go crossed so
this is uh this is a amazing reality but
it it it suggests that understanding The
genome will be the challenge for the uh
people who raised their hand who were
born before uh 1980 this is that
generation's challenge to figure out
what in the world is going on inside the
genome and what they've discovered so
far most people acknowledge is just the
tip of the iceberg so how do you try to
even approach all this uh new data I
just like to tell you about what data
visualization is it's an area of science
it's uh here's the bottom line the best
pattern recognition software in the
universe is our brain and so uh you can
program a computer to look for a pattern
but it'll only look for the pattern you
asked it to look for whereas our brain
everything we look our brain
automatically recognizes patterns and so
that's um that's something that is
unique to the human brain they still
haven't developed a computer that can
recognize a face for
example so data visualization is the is
the um involves the process of making
data Visual and when it's visual then
our brain can take over and easily
recognize patterns and that's the origin
of this program called Skittle and so if
you look some of you have seen uh
genomic data and it's just endless A's
T's C's and G's you will find that your
brain can't really you know when you
look at a few million of those your
brain doesn't see any pattern if you do
something as simple as adding color to
the scheme you can start to see patterns
and so um Skittle the first first
dimension of Skittle is simple
colorization of
nucleotides so
um I've
suggested now for the people in Geneva
I'm just going to take a minute and show
them some live uh running of the program
and I'd be happy to share it with you
when I'm back up in Geneva uh maybe next
week but uh bear with me just for a
moment and I'm going to escape this and
close
this and I'm going to pull up Skittle
program whoops that's not the one I
wanted there it is okay so this is a and
maybe maybe the people in Geneva can see
this but this is display of
40,000 approximately 40,000
pixels and each pixel represents a
nucleotide so the this is chromosome 10
of corn and the first pixel is green
meaning it's a guanine okay so you're
looking at
40,000 letters but because it's
colorized you can start to see patterns
and so uh over here the way Skittle
works is there's basic settings at the
top you can determine the width WID of
this you can determine zoom in and zoom
out you can do uh determine go Zoom to
any starting point you want there's ways
of bringing in new data like from a
genome browser and there there are basic
functions that will be can be tied to
your mouth and then over here there are
different
displays so right now we're looking at a
simple nucleotide display so this is raw
data this is the data uh it's just the
the data as a genome as a fastop file
colorized
so
the let me just show
you what's the gray the gray are
unsequenced
gaps so let's just see what we can do
here um one of the things we can do is
we can change a d diameter you can
perhaps see that I'm making it
narrower and if I close if I change it
enough you see a new pattern so
basically these are tandem
repeats and if I said I love you I love
you I love you I love you that's a
tandem repeat and if you have a a line
break after the U every time all the
letters of I love you I love you will
line up and you'll get these columns
straight up and down columns right so
that's what you're seeing here is a
tandem repeat and this is a large tandem
repeat and it's throughout the the corn
genome it's especially abundant in the
centr region and it's uh but it's
throughout the genome it may represent 5
or 10% of the genome so it's a major
element and if I told you talked about
TM repeats without a visualization you
wouldn't immediately get it when you see
a picture of it it's really obvious
isn't
it okay so
um that just I'm going to jump back to
the PowerPoint for the sake of the
people at Geneva but um but perhaps that
is helpful to
you
okay
so people at Geneva I'd be happy just
ask me and I'll show you how Skittle
Works later um okay this is a picture of
the cor genome and I like it because it
shows a couple things that are very
significant one is uh it shows the
um the very different nucleotide
percentages there are areas that are GC
rich and there are areas that are at
Rich and sometimes you have areas that
are cusing rich they're mostly red and
and so you have
um it's not you might picture it as a
uniform blend but actually there's these
huge variations this these areas that
are GC rich are where the genes are so
these are genic regions and if you look
really carefully you'll see a tanm
repeat here and a tanm repeat at the
beginning of the end of this Gene so
let's just look at that a little more
carefully um this is a similar tandem
this is a similar genic region and uh
you can see there's a couple of things
one one is it's GC Rich another thing is
that if you look really carefully in
here you'll see a
texture which is called a which which we
call the threer pattern but that
reflects codon preference in other words
you can recognize protein coding regions
okay I'm sorry I haven't explained what
this new display is this is the repeat
map so if you have a light colored pixel
here that means that a string this long
has repeated once if you have a series
of pixels here that means you can see it
correlates with this repeat here where
these are lining up so this is a very
very sensitive map of repeating units
within the genome and it's it's much
more sensitive than any other uh genome
tool for detecting repetition within the
genome and what you see here very
carefully if you look really carefully
is there's a pattern of dark dark light
dark dark light and uh that pattern is
throughout the Genome of all organisms
and it it represents the nature of the
protein coding uh the Cod on
preferences and what's significant here
is that there's a tandm repeat at the
beginning and the end of the genic
region and so that means that those tanm
repeats this is something you find
throughout the cor genome it is in
thousands and thousands of places in the
quino it means normally people have
always thought that tanm repeats are
junk DNA they're just Pro mistakes that
happen during DNA replication but what
we find is that these are strategically
at the beginning and the end of these
genic regions so they're not junk
they're they're precisely where they're
supposed to be and they always match
they come in pairs they kind of
represent the beginning and the end of
the Exxon the Quin protein quoting
region the other interesting thing is um
it's a little bit off scale here but we
we can look at where the annotated exons
recognized exons are and most of the
things we see with Skittle have never
been described before in other words
they've been invisible to the normal
Gene searches and so we're seeing uh
functional
units within the genome that weren't
visible using other Technologies for
analyzing
genomes so this is an example of a
similar similar genic region it's very
ATR you recognize it right away right
it's very distinct here you can see the
the texture that I spoke of can you see
that texture in the back that's that's
very distinctive of protein coding
regions and then you can see here this
is called an xon track this is these
lines are just marking where there's a
protein coding Exxon and what you see is
uh in this case this Exxon has been
identified by previous researchers as a
a functional Gene genic unit but 99% of
these structures that we see have not
been identified previously as exons so
we have a new way of of identifying
exons in any genome which is very
sensitive and very
exciting uh just it's more of the same
you can see a genic region That's What I
Call bracketed by tandem repeats and the
tanm repeats again are these are these
repeating
units so that's uh that's really
exciting here's a closer look at the T
this texture and you can actually see
that the the the greenish yellow the
guanines are lining up because this is a
very non-random this is the Exxon okay
we know this is the Exxon we can see
that it has the exonic signature and we
can actually see the In The Raw data we
can actually see that uh the the third
nucleotide tends to always be a g is
this a linear sequence on itself yeah
I'm sorry I should have expressed that
it's like a book so you go to the end of
the line and go back to the beginning so
it's rastered so
um
another question yes
genome okay
so this display link this 88,000
nucleotides are present in this picture
right here out of three
billion so um so you'd have thousands
and thousands and thousands and
thousands of pages like this oh my good
so you can I've spent uh just looking at
one chromosome you can spend hours and
just get a a few uh highlights of that
chromosome so there's a huge huge amount
of data um this is again what we one of
the things we can do is we can if we see
a tandem repeat here we know there's a
tandm rep here because here's the repeat
map so now we have a new display if we
click on the first nucleotide of that
line what happens is it will take that
line and search the whole genome for
that sequence and color wherever the you
find it so this is basically just
showing that yes this genic region is
flanked by tandem repeats at both sides
and the fact that it's the same color
means it's the same
sequence so you can search um this is a
similar one A different flanking
sequence and U now we're going to jump
to Grape so that's just a the reason I
used corn to begin with is this the only
plant genome I know of where I have the
Exxon track data where people have
actually figured out where the protein
coating regions are but uh let's just
consider another horticulturally
important crop and that is uh the grape
genome and here again you can see very
distinct tandem repeat now you see there
are variations within the tandem repeat
and the question could be asked is that
noise like mutations or is that actually
information these patterns uh often
remind me of again ancient history when
we had Punch Cards for computer analysis
so uh and you can see how the repeat map
very very uh easily detects this and
also the how the repeat map is telling
us that right here there is an
on so visualization data visualization
is a powerful tool when you're exploring
the
unknown this is uh just more tandem
repeats uh some of them are you know
very uh conserved some of them are
broken up is that by Design or by
mutation I don't know does the
automatically generate patterns that you
see on the left because you know the
frame was wider orar you wouldn't good
good point so um this the repeat map
finds these repeats instantly and
regardless of your frame width you have
to find you have to bring this red line
in you see the red line might have been
here I brought it over to the over the
white first white line and that tells me
number one it tells me that um this is a
66 base pair repeat the 66 base pairs
from here to here and then I can set the
width and then everything lines up and I
can see what's going on
so uh we do have a function which I I
didn't while we were live I didn't hit
the alignment cylinder display but
basically it takes the tanm repeat and
turns it into a coil and then adjusts
the coil width till all the tanm repeats
are visible we actually believe that
tanm repeats coil in the nucleus and so
they form like solenoid like structures
and that that's what these repeats are
all
about so this is a just a striking uh
compon component of if you zoom out so
you're looking at a whole grape
chromosome what you see is this 66 base
pair repeat is massively throughout the
center of this chromosome like just
um um millions of nucleotides are are
just coding for this repeat
so okay this is the same repeat actually
showing the the solenoid display and so
you can see we believe that this is not
in nature it can't raster that rastering
you know this is a nice 2D display but
this is meant to be a 3D display we can
make that spin and we can uh we believe
this is the actual structure in biology
it this keeps coiling because it DNA it
turns out wants to align with its own
similar sequence and so the logical
thing for a repeat is to form a
coil so this is uh again Eng grape
showing uh but we don't have it there's
no published exons to my knowledge for
grape but we would predict there's an
Exon here almost certainly an Exxon here
and and possibly xon here the blue line
is a strength indicator and when it goes
to purple that means Bingo you've
definitely got an
Exxon so just more ex evidence of
exons
um a little more of the same so I'm just
going to keep moving because you know I
could show you zillions of pictures I
mentioned that there are thousands and
th these are just a few snapshots of the
genome but the Tomato genome is a Sim
another horticulturally important crop
where they've completed the genome and
assembled it and what you see here again
is um there's some strange uh repeats
here which are fuzzy they're IL defined
uh we have the threer pattern which is
very strong indication that there's
protein coating here and then and then
these other ones are possible
exons since exons only represent 1 to 2%
of the genome it's critical to be able
to identify where they
are more potential
exons um and showing some of the larger
tandem repeats that would be you know
these really big wavy repeats that I
show you there's a name for that it's
called Alpha satellite DNA and uh and so
all plants and animals when you see the
wavy pattern you know you're looking at
Alpha satellite DNA the all ha organisms
show this wavy
pattern and oh I know I want to go back
for a second um you see that there's a
region here that's got more red and
green and versus the other Bluer areas
so this is a GCR region so it's a
potentially a gene and again you'll see
it's bracketed by a tanm repeats so the
same pattern we saw in corn is showing
up in tomato and to my knowledge this
pattern has never been seen before and
until I've seen it in the last few
months as I've been looking at plant
genomes more so this is this is the idea
of data visualization is it will show
you patterns that the computer wouldn't
have spotted what we see is these things
come in pairs and they tend to bracket
protein coating region what are they
doing we don't know but it gives us
reason to want to do research on that
um a lot of things are actually
repeated uh
uh so there's a lot of repetition in the
genome so that's uh more of these
bracketed areas you see this is a this
is an
important um clue as to what's going on
in the genome
and none of these have been annotated so
it's all you know it's really showing us
things about the genome we wouldn't have
known without it then the rice genome
this is really a pretty picture it's a
picture of the uh the centromeric Alpha
DNA Alpha DNA of rice and I'll just show
it quickly because rice like corn the
monocots are really have really
different genomes they have a you just
notice the color is different there's
much more red and green greenish yellow
and much less blue so when you're in the
dcot everything's bluish and
everything's orangish when you go here
we've zoomed in so you can see a little
more specifically the patterns that are
occurring within the the deviations
within the tandem repeat and there's
some interesting things that are going
on here that would be worthy of
exploration and you can see here in
Greater detail it goes a a dark column a
dark column a light column a dark column
a dark column a light column so you can
see more clearly uh what's what what
that threer display is what it's telling
us it's telling us every third
nucleotide is similar to the three to
the one that was three nucleotides
before it and and that so basically the
lighter the pixel the more the
similarity averaged over the whole
string so another thing that uh is a
major feature of genomes that we're
seeing is the every other pattern and
this is basically black and blue
alternating uh sprinkled with uh with
greens and reds and so we have no idea
what that is but it's out plant and
animal genomes so I don't doubt for a
minute that it's doing
something um this is just more evidence
of exons in rice this pattern is very
strong and you can also see the GC rich
and you can even see the alignment
things are lining up here partially
because the because of this pattern it's
very very strong it means it constrains
most of the nucleotides in the genome a
lot of us you know we've been taught
that most nucleotides are just drifting
and they don't matter uh most
nucleotides in genome have a function
and therefore um need an
explanation more more axons just really
rice is really
really strong
signal um okay so that's that's
the kind of a quick overview of what
plant genomes look like when they're
visualized with Skittle Skittle is a a
um program that's in development in fact
some of these features the feature that
measures the the where the exons are the
strength of that signal uh was just is
just two days old Josiah emailed me the
latest revision uh so it's all still
being improved but what what we believe
we have here is a universal genome
browser now some of you know what a
genome browser is but basically if you
looking at you know let's say three
billion letters and you're trying to
figure out what it all codes for you
can't just look at at the letters and so
they've made genome browsers that help
you spot where the genes are help you
analyze where the junk or the repeat is
and other types of um you know
understanding of how the genome is
operating we feel that Skittle is the
foundation for developing all those all
those browsers are one-dimensional
they're
strings and so this is a two-dimensional
display two-dimensional analysis and be
and uh it lets us we believe it's the
next generation of genome browser and
that this we when we get Skittle fully
developed we can uh annotate and
recognize every feature within the
genome in a way that's fundamentally
better than genome browsers today so
we're excited about that um and it's uh
already I think bearing fruit in terms
of giving us new insight into plant
genomes and other genomes but uh I
wanted to add just briefly um some work
that my colleague Josiah Seaman did on
his own so Josiah Seaman you know a
computer scientist I have to I digress
for a second
um so I was um I was never interested in
computer science not even a little bit
and um and so I looked that as a
necessary evil I mentioned that you know
I was the last one in our department to
switch from the typewriter to to a
computer for word processing and then
when email came along I absolutely did
not want to be bothered email I was
absolutely the last person in our
department to finally connect to the
email so it's really funny to me that in
the last 10 years I've uh played a role
in developing what I think are the two
most exciting bioinformatics programs
available and of course the reason is I
had the good sense to partner up with
some really brilliant computer
scientists because I'm still practically
computer illiterate but um but Josiah
Josiah is one of those people and um
he developed all the programming that
went into this and
uh it turns out that you can look at any
patterns with Skittle like you can look
open up any text file you can open up
Moby Dick and see what the pattern is
you can also open up computer code so
the way he found out he could open up
computer code was when you start Skittle
it asks you what file you want to open
and he forgot that he had already opened
Skittles so he used Skittle open the
skittle executable code does that make
sense and he immediately saw some really
surprising patterns so it turns out that
Skittle can be used for analyzing um
execu code and that's machine language
so it's something no computer no
computer scientist almost no computer
scientist can read machine language so
this is the first time we actually get
to look at computer code uh I don't have
the uh that would make a really
interesting talk but I just want to give
you some highlights from what he said
saw um this is Moby
Dick so there's no no pattern no
nucleotide bi this is the repeat map
there's no significant amount of repeats
that'd be pretty boring wouldn't it to
have two the same chapter twice in a row
um so the genome for decades has been
called The Book of Life but we assert
strongly that the actual genome has no
uh physical similarity to a book and a
book is passive but a computer program
is active and runs it's alive so here's
what
uh we this is a zoomed out version of a
one one of these is executable code
zoomed out so you look at the whole code
uh maybe 60,000 bytes of code and the
other one is a zoomed out so you can see
most of a
chromosome which one is code and which
one is ex uh which one is you know they
both have these uh these these major
shifts in color
change uh so in DNA we would call the in
chromosomes we'd say these are isocor
where you have a change in the use of
where the the use of the nucleotides
changes in a fundamental way well it
turns out that computer code does the
same thing but we actually know what
causes these shifts in in color see we
know how computer code works but we
don't know how genomes work and the fact
that we're seeing similarities means we
could use one to understand the other
when you have a change here they're
going like from Pearl to
Fortran it's computer it's when you
change languages you change your letter
use profile
right these These are clearly language
changes and these are in gen genome are
most likely changes to one of the many
you know there are many languages in DNA
yes sir in the genome
thec
computer code what's the the computer
code is uh z0 is a01 we need two bits to
get the four color scheme the book uh
the book was I think actually we had 26
colors
yeah but they were Shades that your eye
couldn't
distinguish so uh so in terms of these
changes in letter use uh computer code
and and he looked at other executable
code other than his own program we both
up lots of and it's it's pretty
Universal pattern um then he looked at
um again we're zooming out so we're
looking at a whole chromosome this is um
what's called the repeat map but on a
higher scale so here we have for example
a long stretch of red which means that a
short repeat um less than 20 base pairs
long is repeating and it's repeating for
thousands and maybe tens of thousands of
letters here just this huge repeat and
so you can map where all these repeats
are in a chromosome and you see they
tend to be all at near the beginning
well it turns out that the uh computer
code is also filled with
repeats and for example here would be
another stretch of red that also is a 10
to 20 uh character repeat and and you'll
see that which which one is if I asked
you if I hadn't already given it away
you wouldn't know which one was a
computer code and which one was the
genome would you and so if we look
closer at these repeats which of these
repeats is plant repeat and which one is
from computer
code this is plant this a computer so
um the the the tandem repeats in
computer code are incredibly similar to
what we see in Plants amazingly similar
so here's the interesting thing is for
decades people have seen
we have known that there are these tanm
repeats and they said obviously repeats
are junk well are the repeats in
computer code junk are there is there a
single bit in a computer code that's not
functional so it's strongly suggest
these tanm re beats aren't here that
this isn't a coincidence it reflects
functionality and that the the we
actually know what these repeats are for
these are data
files like phone directory would be a
data file the first this would be like
some Universal thing like telephone
number and then people have different
numbers so data files uh in computer
code give you this perhaps these are
data
files so these another element of plant
genome is that U they're called what are
dispersed repeats you know you can have
repeats where they're head to toe or you
can have the same repeating element all
throughout the genome and so these these
would be called um these would be plant
this would be like a transposable
element and these would be words that
are common within the computer language
so you can actually you know write in
any sequence you want and it'll look
through through the uh script and find
wherever it occurs so you can find out
how abundant certain words are so word
structure use or transposable elements
are very similar within code and within
genomes so the bottom line is uh what
he's seen is that genomes and executable
code have amazing similarities they both
use linear strings of code they both use
multiple languages they both use
parallel processing which means you know
you can have lots of genes being reading
at the same time like each like lots of
processors in your computer uh they both
have uh strong character bias where the
the total color shift occurs they both
use extensive use of recurrent tandem
repeats they both use commonly dispersed
repeats or words they both use large
scale localization of the repeats at
near the end ends of the program and
they both have passive and active
information a book just sits there you
can read it or not a program runs and
it's self-changing self-modifying so uh
all of this is consistent with a trend
within genetics more and more
genomicists are saying the genome is
executable code and that's really a
better understanding than the idea that
it's an instruction manual and so it's
just really um exciting to see uh that
Skittle strongly supports that and it
goes from a simile or an analogy to
actually a um something we can measure
where we can actually measure the the
features that are in common so I just
like to conclude
uh I believe there are deep hidden
there's deep hidden Beauty in the genome
and so I've gazed at these colorful
pictures for um hundreds of hours and uh
it's really cool The genome has many
levels of structure we've only detected
a small fraction of it the nucleotide
bias is very strong uh which is
interesting
because uh blue blue black areas want to
mutate to red green and red green areas
want to mutate to blue black so it's
very hard to imagine how to create or
sustain those biases um tan repeats it's
clear because they bracket the genes can
carry information they are not
necessarily junk tan repeats can we can
we show can lo would logically form into
large coils which might have function we
see ubiquitous tumer and threer patterns
which threer seems to reflect codon bias
protein cating bias and then there are
many levels of order still waiting to be
found and higher genomes are most like
computer code that's that's uh the
bottom line of what we've been learning
the last few years using Skittle that's
a good place to
stop well the one connection I
would suggest is that uh there's
communication at every level you know
know from the molecules to the cells to
the tissues to communication between
organisms and then of course there's the
brain function which is all kinds of
levels of communication there so
information is at the at the heart of
21st century biology it's all really
about information science and
um and everything is integrated at a
level that blows our mind and so uh it's
very hard to conceive of how that
integration ation could have ever Arisen
and so it's just a really interesting
question that I think more and more
people are going to be asking is biology
is much more fantastic than we ever
imagined and uh so it's just a real it
makes it exciting to be a biologist in
the 21st century right so um basically
for data visualization you have to be
creative in in presenting the data in
new ways to the human brain the human
brain works by methods we have no idea
but um when we do see a pattern like I'm
seeing this pattern where I have a what
looks like a large coding region that
has not previously been identified as a
Exxon and I see it's bracketed by tandem
repeats and I realize that's a highly
ordered structure and uh what Josiah
points out is he says uh Skittle is for
discovering the pattern but then you
have to write special computer code to
analyze the pattern so now we can go
back and ask the computer to find every
instance on that chromosome where that
pattern happens that's that's the next
step for that
research
yeah what's the plan for Skittle and
it's under development it becomes fin
it's it's available free of charge you
can download it anytime it's really easy
to you know it's a really easy to
understand how to use it but it will
continue it's being updated almost
weekly so and actually Josiah's just
introduced a feature so if you're online
and you're using Skittle and he updates
it there a little thing will come up on
Skittle that says update now and you'll
get the latest version so he realizes
that it's going to be under rapid and
continuous Improvement so so they don't
have there's nothing like Skittle no one
has a program like Skittle um I wish
they would take notice of Skittle but
they haven't uh I think as we uh
actually this corn pattern that I
described when we show that we use
Skittle to discover that which I which
is I think a major feature of the Corn
genome uh then people will say oh I
guess maybe I should look into this
Skittle
business because it is a powerful tool
to just see what's going on and also for
teaching if you were teaching genome to
students and you just show them A's T's
C's and G's you you they it doesn't snc
in but with Skittle actually you can
start to see oh I see what's going on
here there's I start to see the
different types of organization within
the genome so I think uh it's both a
research tool and a a great teaching
tool the Bott yes we we basically upload
uh any fasta file and uh it it basically
the first thing it does is just colorize
the letters that's really simple but as
soon as that happens you start to see
patterns then it allows us to change the
width or zoom in and out and it allows
us to put up the repeat map or the
cylinder display or several other
display options so but the raw data is
that colorful screen and you're actually
looking at the genome when you look at
that just like you are see looking at a
fast file but it's a lot more
interesting than a fast
file so your repeat
file the data so so the repeat map takes
the first line whatever whatever the
width is it reads the first line and
then Compares that to the this to the
one nucleotide over the line that
represents the next nucleotide over and
then it Compares that first line with
every other possible alignment on in the
view and then for every alignment it it
gives a score for the similarity and
decides how bright the pixel should be
for that spot so it's uh it performs a
massive uh calculation each time you
move the screen to recognize all the
possible similarities between the first
string and all the other parts of that
display the WID thing seems to me that
the WID
detn is you optimize the WID to come up
with so the dis the display pattern the
the the map which is black and the gray
the gray scale uh that actually doesn't
change as you change width it is it is
just measuring the repeats so you'll see
those repeats uh regardless of the
display and then the cylinder display uh
finds the best alignment but the regular
display you have to manually uh adjust
the width to get those nice uh visual
patterns of the U tandem repeats so
there's possibly even a pattern
wi like you at different you may find
commonality so there's a the 66 myrr
that I found in tomato was also in
corn yeah there's there's uh and and
when you find a repeat you'll find that
it's a family of repeats throughout that
chromosome and all the chromosomes of
that species very few repeats are novel
they're they're they're like words
they're doing something and
and they and they're found in many
different places in the
genome so basically um as as we discover
these new layers of information we would
like to have it like you know how
oldfashioned overhead transparencies you
could put several on top and they you
could see how they all line up we'd like
to have Skittle have transparent Pages
some you you could adjust the
transparency so we can see where the
exons are we can see where the
transcriptional factor binding sites are
we can see where the histone binding
sites are we can see where the fold
folding uh motifs are because there's
layer upon layer of information and the
only way is to have layered a layered
display so that's the
next uh that's in the
works thank you very much
thanks this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu