this is a production of Cornell
University our way I'm Lucia viel and
I'm organizing the hemp annual webinar
this year I'm a third year PhD candidate
in the Larry smart La at Bernal
University where I'm working with father
melus in hemp I'm particularly
interested in disase resistance so I'm
uh especially excited about your talk ni
our speaker today um long awaited and uh
we're really happy that you accepted our
invitation the participants if you
register for this talk you know I'm
talking about Nicole over here Dr Nicole
go here I'm sorry if I'm
butchering um is a professor and
extension specialist at the University
of Kentucky where program focuses on
disease management of specialty crops
including fruits vegetables and hemp in
her extensional role she develops
educational and Outreach crop um
programs to help Growers manage disease
through identification understanding of
path systems and integration of
management strategies her research
program focuses on a range of hemp
diseases including cerium headlight as
well as sand establishment and seedborn
transm
she is co-editor of the uaps compedium
of cannabis
diseases her resources can be found in
uh the University of Kentucky the
pathology extension uh part of the web
page and Facebook in Twitter in on
YouTube so there's many options to
follow her just choose your social media
flavor before I uh hand over the stage
to her I want to remind the everyone to
use the chat for saying hi and greetings
and other
Communications but please submit the
questions for Nicole using the Q&amp;A
button the talk will last approximately
40 45 minutes followed by uh 15 minute
Q&amp;A session and we'll then wrap up and
thank Ni Call for her time and insights
all the webinars are recorded and will
be uploaded to our school of Integrative
plan science sips IPS uh YouTube channel
and um you can check already the one
from uh last week so with that Nicole
it's all yours hello thank you so much
um hello everyone uh it's great to be
here um today we're talking about uh
plant diseases as as Lucia said but I'm
GNA focus on grain hemp today um anybody
who knows me has heard any of my talks
you never know what I'm going to talk
about usually it's disease in general
but today we're going to focus on grain
hemp and again I am from the University
of Kentucky most of my work happens in
Kentucky so this is more of a Kentucky
perspective if you are not from Kentucky
or in a nearby State you should be
communicating with your extension
Educators or extension specialists in
your state to assure that we've got the
same diseases and we've got the same
management
recommendations climates are different
planting times are different and even
disease distribution is different so
again I'm
Midwest um uh located but most of this
should apply to everyone here okay we
cannot start a disease talk of grain
hemp without talking about diseases in
general um Cannabis sativa is him
Cannabis sativa is marijuana Cannabis
sativa is the plant that we're talking
about today so the common diseases of
hemp or grain hemp are the generally the
same ones that we see in all Cannabis
sativa um so we see a range of diseases
from damping off root rots and Crown
rots right so our root rots can range
from those damping off sealing diseases
to something larger Crown rots from
Southern blight which I know is all the
way in the northeastern us and even into
Canada vascular wilts we all know
fusarium Wilt is probably the most
talked about of the vascular wilts in
hemp and in cannabis but we don't see
that many we see surprisingly fewer than
uh the literature would uh make us think
um here in Kentucky we have not U
fusarium oxysporum but we have found
other species of fusaria causing a
vascular Wilt which is unusual but again
not a lot of vascular Wilt in the grand
scheme of
things Leaf spots and blights so a leaf
spot is what you see on the screen a
spot whereas a leaf blight is kind of
that quick death where you see that
whole Leaf die and it dies really
quickly we see lots of leaf spots and
blights and uh human nature that's just
what we tend to zero in on so we talk a
lot about Leaf spots and leaf blights we
um in fact a little bit of a side note
uh we did some research here at the
University of Kentucky looking at um
various U cultivars of hemp and
different Leaf spotting diseases and we
found that regardless of how severe
those leaf spot diseases get we did not
see an effect on biomass yield or canabo
yield so um of course that was a
two-year study in Kentucky so maybe
there's a lot more to talk about or not
so uh but I'm not talking about Leaf
spots today per se all right so mildew
and molds we all know powdery mildew and
Downey mildew and betrus gry mold um
those are more like pollinizers of a
leaf we don't call those Leaf spots per
se but they are Leaf diseases they're
everywhere they can infect um cannaboid
grain or Fiber
cannabis grain diseases and now I'm
talking specifically so when we go
beyond that flower if we have a
pollinated flour we have grain that stay
on the plant longer and so grain
diseases that is what I'm talking about
today and then of course um and in
particular I'm going to talk about
fusarium headlight today not as much the
betrus we just don't have that much
betrus grey mold here in Kentucky it's
too hot um I know that in Geneva and in
the northern climates you'll see more of
that but when I'm talking grain diseases
I'll be talking primarily about fusarium
headlight and uh storage molds because
anything that moves from the field into
storage moves from the field to storage
so sometimes it matters and there are
cases where it
does but my assignment today is to talk
about common diseases of grain hemp so
in this whole list of diseases that I
love to talk about everyone we're going
to focus on damping off and we're going
to talk about those flowering grain
diseases mostly one of them because
those are the big those are the big um
limiting factors for grain hemp so grain
hemp is planted differently we don't uh
we don't transplant into the greenhouse
we go into the field we grow it fast we
get it out fast uh we plant it very
closely so it's more of an agronomic
type crop so we're Limited in the number
of diseases we're going to talk about
today not that any of those others won't
matter but these are the big red flags
for me here in
Kentucky and these are major concerns
for our Growers so these are the ones if
I was invited to a grower talk these are
the ones that I would be talking
about so let's start with damping off
what the heck is damping off that is
well pre-emergent disease or
post-emergent that can affect seeds or
seedlings so that's what we mean by
damping off
pre-emergent damping off is when a seed
fails to germinate fails to emerge or
fails to develop so pre-emergent before
that seed emerges per se um we've also
got so it'll die after germination or
right before
germination um pathogens can affect any
part of the seed or seedling right so
post emergent damping off is after that
seed emerges that could be that ceiling
stage or less there's a lot of gray area
between what's pre-emergent what's
post-emergent right don't overthink it
uh we are talking specifically about an
early infection of a seed or seedling by
a soilborne pathogen that's generally
the definition so um here we've got a
seed a seed that's just germinating
trying to germinate and disease coming
in and in the center we have um we have
a pathogen that has infected that uh
seedling and then the seedling collapses
and all the way on the right well now
we're questioning whether that's a
Seedling at all so it's a young plant
it's been infected it's been affected
and if you want to call that a sealing
disease that's okay and we're not going
to get caught up in the minutia point is
we have early season disease very early
season
disease uh generally these plant
pathogens like wet environments and
that's a lot of times what we're doing
in the greenhouse if we're producing
transplants or if we plant early in the
season in the field to try to get a jump
start our soils are usually cooler so
that's usually when we see these damping
off
diseases so let's start with probably
the most common of the um of the damping
off diseases and that's pythium root rot
pythium Crown rot pythium damping off or
if you're like me you can just say
pythium because it's all of the above
there are sever veral pythium species
that cause damping off or seedling
diseases if you will um and I I'm not
going to go into them depending on what
the field is what the previous crop is
the pythium aadum we usually see in the
greenhouse it's more of a hot weather
pythium but I can find it in soils here
in Kentucky and then uh pythium or
globas sporangium irregular and uh
globas sporangium which used to be
called py ultimum um those are very
common they affect a wide range of
different crops um from soybeans to
vegetable
crops generally okay so so let's back up
pythium is a water mold so it's not a
true fungus it is a water mold or an O
and that means they like water they need
water to complete their life cycle and
more water than just dampness so they
need more water and so when we talk
about water moldes that that really isfe
something okay so the image on the left
you'll see like a dip in this field
ultimately in this field in particular
now this is a transplant field this is
not a grain field but ultimately what
happened is right in the center of that
field in that low area where water stood
we had a um an outbreak of pythium root
rot on those plants and they did not
make it to maturity so low-lying areas
usually more water and if there is um a
pythium or a water mold present it will
be really happy with the situation and
so it can infect more easily complete
its life cycle more easily and then
spread okay so the image on the right
that is a closeup of roots this this was
a container but this is closeup of roots
that are infected with aium species so
notice that we've got some nice white
roots with root hairs those are not
infected yet and then those brownish
Gray roots that have lost heridity
they're probably slimy you could
probably Slough off that cortex that
would be indicative of an infected root
so if you're examining a seed or a
Seedling that color change is usually
really distinct you'll dig not pull and
you'll rinse gently and you'll be able
to see if roots are turgid and nice and
white and color or if they have kind of
lesions or dark spots on them or if um
you know sometimes we'll have a crown
rot that might fool us if the roots look
good and the rest of the plant doesn't
we're looking somewhere else but if
there's a root rot you'll be able to see
it I'll tell you something else about
pythium if anybody wants some nerdy
pathology uh pythium likes to nibble it
Roots I told you it rots off kind of it
decays that um that cortex so these
images here they both you'll see the
cortex has sloughed off and you'll see
the steel sticking out so on the left
hand image all the way way at the Top If
you can see my cursor you'll see the
cortex has sloughed off right about here
and everything Beyond it that's just the
steel sticking out so that's usually
indicative of pythium root rot um and
then the image on the right that's
pretty much the same thing and these are
being held upside down so yes I realize
these roots are pointing the wrong way
so
um that's how we hold them right that's
the way our brain works so when I hold
them to photograph that's what it looks
like but you'll see this rat tail
uh root tip right here and there's some
others in these images and that rat tail
root means the steel is sticking out and
the cortex has slept off almost always
epiom so if you want to do some self-
diagnosis you need a hand lens or a
magnifying glass and um hopefully not a
rotted
root all right our next damping off
pathogen is Fus Arium salani this is not
fusarium oxysporum that causes fusarium
Wilt this is another fusarium um this is
a true fungus this is not a water bold
and uh fusarium also have wide host
ranges they like it wet and warm but
they don't like water at the same rate
that our water molds do okay this is a
true fungus it likes
moisture fusarium salani can cause
damping off it could also cause crown
and root rots and often the fusarium
infection will be as a result of some
wound um I've shown this image in in
before so this so we're not talking
damping off exactly right now this image
is after the fact but this grower had a
plastic hter system the plastic was so
thick and they slit the plastic instead
of burning holes so the plastic rubbed
against the the crown so here is a hemp
stem upside down here I go again upside
down and you'll see this lesion here
you'll see that pink right there that's
usually indicative of a fusarium so
you'll see that wound fusarium got in
and you'll see the discoloration working
its way up and working its way down so
this is a crown rot if you will because
it happened at the crown there's also
some root rot going on I didn't show The
Roots here but if you so before I pull
this plant up if you look in the field
that plant is dying and that's because
that Burling canker on that Crown has
affected the the uptake of watering
nutrients to the top of the plant so
that's what's happening there so anytime
a whole plant is going down you're
looking for the common denominator and
in this case it was the
crown again fusarium salani causes the
damping off if it's in your Fields if
it's built up in your Fields over the
years um and we do have some of that
actually on our Research Forum then you
will see damping off at plant
and you could also see it affecting
later in the
season almost always associated with
wounds that could be insect wounds that
could be mechanical wounds that can be
stress okay and then our third and final
um damping off pathogen is Ry octonia
salani we call this one ryok r hi- i zoc
ryok that's our shortcut that's the way
we talk about this one uh this is also a
soil born disease with a very wide Host
range rise octonia salani can cause
damping off it can also cause a crown
and root rot and um pretty nerdy for a
plant pathologist is this one can cause
a web light or an aerial blight let me
say that rise octonia salani also has a
very wide Host range so if it's in the
field if it's built up in numbers if
it's wet uh and warm at the beginning of
the Season except excessively wet not as
wet as an O as a water mold but still
wet um it can start it can come in as a
damping off and if it's a rainy hot
summer this one loves to move its way up
into the
canopy the image on the left that is a
crown rot so you'll see that Mycelia
that fungal white body that that is on
that crown and the bottom part of that
picture on the left that is like a
crosssection so that is a cut into that
crown and you will see again you see
that uh White Mycelia that white fungal
body there on the right that is web
light and that is when that fungus that
soilborne fungus moves from the soil it
moves up into the canopy this happens
again when it's hot and rainy in the
summertime and when that canopy is so
dense and there's no air circulation so
that's when you'll see that web light so
that Mycelia that white fungal body
moves its way up into the canopy and
it's we leaving its way it's almost
stitching it looks like thread it's
stitching those leaves together and it
looks a lot like a spiderweb but it's
stitched those leaves together so R RIS
octonia Salon can cause damping off and
it can lead to additional um um later
seasoned diseases and again very wide
Host range so if it's built up in the
field with other crops it will be there
when you come in with your grain hemp or
if you rotate out of hemp and you rotate
into another host plant you have not
broken that disease cycle okay so when
we talk about these host ranges it
matters because as we rotate that's
where we're going to see um some some
management
options okay now I'm switching to
disease number two I told you I'm only
talking about two diseases today and
this is a fusarium head and budlight so
this is when we get to the flowering and
the grain stage
this has been a big one for us this has
been a big one throughout oh Midwest and
um east of the Mississippi River we're
seeing more and more of it as we're
growing more hemp um we are on our 10th
year of of hemp here in Kentucky we
started growing it in 2014 on that 2014
form bill so we are we have completed 10
years of field research and since 2017
or 2018 we have seen more and more
fusarium headlight and we're especially
seeing it in Grain hm so just kind of
heads up
there fusarium headlight is best known
for um as a disease in cereal crops so
fusarium headlight or wheat scab uh we
know it in wheat in cereal grains and in
corn most importantly fusarium headlight
or budlight if you don't have grain
right we call it headlight if it's got
grain head budlight if it's a floral
floral cultiv or a non-pollinated
cultivar it's the same disease um but
the fuser the pathogens that cause
fusarium produce mot toxins that can be
detrimental or or or dangerous for
humans and for animals so some very
common ones are Dawn and T2 those are
two fusarium mot toxins that are
regulated in serial grains we're not to
that point in hemp um they should be
regulated we are working on that with
our research program but these mot
toxins again in we're working on test
kits but that is another reason why
fusarium headlight is um is a problem
for
us so in Kentucky and in neighboring
states we have surveyed um um hemp and
we have determined that fusarium garum
fusarium aium fusarium sporo troides and
the fusarium inornatum equiset uh
species complex are the most common
causal agents of fusarium headlight
fusarium garum is the one that everyone
knows that's the one we talk so much
about and um uh garum and spor troides
are what we call the um the Trine
producers so that's where those
dangerous mot toxins are going to come
in fusarium headlight though also causes
a blight of the heads so uh the image on
the right we will see where the disease
is there closest to the stem where that
there that uh bud or that head is dense
and there's limited air
circulation and here's some closer looks
um there's that picture again on the
right it's blown up a little bit more so
infection will begin near the stem like
I said here I'll get my cursor here so
uh it will begin near the stem and where
it is dense where there's limited air
circulation probably a lot higher
humidity there and that's where that's
where the disease will start to
develop um in wheat fusarium headlight
is known to infect through the male
flower parts uh during anthesis that's
not happening here uh what we have found
that um infection will occur pretty much
any time but we have a lot more disease
a lot higher amounts of fungal DNA
during the reproductive phases of this
disease
um so so there's no indication that male
flowers are uh driving that infection as
a matter of fact we have tested male
flowers and they can be equally um
equally susceptible but that is not that
is not affecting us here as we talk
about grain and female flowers um ferium
headlight looks a lot like damage from
some of your budworms like corn earworm
so you have to be really careful if
you're looking at that you have to take
a closer look make sure you're not
seeing that frass or those Bud worms but
this picture on the left um that looks a
lot like budworm damage to me so you've
got to actually spread out um that
flower or that head and you have to look
inside and looking for that white
Mycelia that colonization and what
you'll see as a progression of symptoms
of that blighting uh whereas if it was a
bud worm you would see chew marks and
you would see where where there's that
girdling happen happening as a result of
those chew
marks okay so here here are some
additional pictures and um I kind of
want to drive this home a little bit um
that here on the right you'll see that
infection you'll see that Melia that
fungal that white fungal stringy body
you'll see that happening here and then
of course there's that spread spreading
inside that head and as it moves up
everything above it pretty much D so
you'll start to see that that blighting
occur at a larger scale the image on the
left that entire head blighted
out um so the Rainier it is the more of
this Mycelia you'll see if it's dry
you'll have disease spread inside the
plants and you won't see as much of that
Mycelia um if you do see that fuzzy
Mycelia colonizing it could be confused
with petritis gray mold as a matter of
fact here in Kentucky we're not seeing
gry mold we're not finding Bettis in the
field and so when we see this fuzzy
colonization it's almost always fusarium
headlight so be careful of that one if
you're in a Northern climate where it's
cool especially as fall kind of comes
around and it starts uh we start seeing
those cool nights you could very well
have um you could very well have betrus
but in Kentucky and definitely further
south than us we're not seeing betrus
because it's just too hot
okay so um the amount of Biselia will
vary um by the species of fusarium
that's infected okay so we see incor
meetti gets really fuzzy kind of like on
the left whereas usually the garum has a
lot less of the Mycelia so again don't
let that fool you use a Diagnostic lab
um you are a commercial grower you've
got to know what you have so that that
really depends again
by depending on the weather will really
affect the the amount of colonization
and the spread of
disease fusarium headblade causes as you
see direct losses right so we have the
blighting of those of those grain with
the blighting of that head we'll see
early shattering so there's a direct
loss by fusarium headlight and then that
indirect loss which can be that that
those mot toxins so we have kind of a
double whammy
there all right so I I want to mention
Bud architecture or FL or head
architecture here really quickly we are
seeing and this is a little bit
anecdotal but we are seeing a lot more
headlight in those heavy dense buds as
opposed to the kind of spindly ones
where we have more air circulation this
is an doal we're seeing this in general
a lot of our colleagues around the US
are saying the same thing we have not
tested that theory yet uh we plan
to uh undoubtedly there is genetic
resistance in there not complete
resistance that we know of but there are
definitely cultivars that are more
susceptible than others and then you add
that bud architecture where we don't
have um good air circulation especially
as those buds get dense and they stay
really um wet and and humid inside those
buds so we can have we can have an
either or going on um I am inclined to
say that we have both so that is work
that we need to
do okay I want to mention um this is
this is one of our research field plots
from um last year or two years ago we
were looking for time of infection so
let's back up a little bit and I said
that in wheat that infection occurs
around in thesis that's when that male
flower blooms on that male flower part
is exposed on the wheat head that here
in Kentucky happens in
may we haven't even planted our hemp yet
in May so the question was how do we
have so much fusarium headlight during
the reproductive phase which is usually
August in hemp when um anthesis and
infection on wheat happens in May and
wheat is out of the field in June so
what how do we understand that and so we
were looking for time of infection when
did help become infected so to do that
we planted this field um this is this is
only part of the field but we planted
every two weeks starting in April so we
planted every two weeks we used three
cultivars an early a mid and a late
season cultivar and that basically gave
us uh different growth stages at every
planting date what we were aiming for is
to compare uh time of planting calendar
time of year and then plant growth stage
and that that was what we were aiming to
to uh
uncover in general so our results were
basically that Laten infection occurred
as early as May so Laten infection is
that dormant stage it's that time
between infection and symptom
development so plants were becoming
infected very early they were becoming
infected during the vegetative
stages but not showing symptoms so
infection was there um once in this
particular experiment so oh you do see a
wheat cover crop there that's how we en
ensured that we would get disease okay
so high inoculum load in these fields we
did this on purpose so this was a Drill
Seed on a wheat cover crop so this wheat
did not go to seed this was a wheat
cover crop which adds another layer
right another question because if this
wheat never went to flour if this was a
cover crop it never went to flower then
it shouldn't have been infected either
right okay so I
digress so we had latent infections
early not a lot but but enough but our
highest amount of of infection and then
symptom development started occurring
during
reproduction so plants were highly
susceptible during that reproductive
stage even though they were even though
they were not that that uh anther there
like like the the wheat
scenario okay um the month didn't really
matter and the days after planting did
not really matter it was that plant
growth stage it was that reproductive
stage where plants were highly
susceptible and we got pretty quickly we
got infection so we we identified uh we
um Quantified the amount of DNA in that
plant before symptoms developed and then
um anytime there was rain we had spikes
so we have some weather data lay uh
layered into that too so weather spiked
it but infection was occurring lower
levels during the reproductive
stages as early as may but it was August
during those reproductive stages mostly
those reproductive stages where we had
severe
disease I know that's a lot right so
I've just kind of thrown a lot at you
just to think about and this is where we
are with this
research okay so
um the next thing we asked is where it
came from right I showed you the wheat
and if you see the these the center
picture and the one on the left that is
another wheat cover crop that did not go
to Sea all right so we so we planted
hemp we drill seated hemp into this
wheek cover
crop and we were looking for um we were
looking
for sporulation events right when were
the spores released we know that
fusarium can infect grassy hosts we
definitely know it's a major disease in
um in Gman Nicholas crops right so wheat
and
cereals there can be very high inoculum
loads if have a full wheat crop but we
weren't doing
that so so is is fusarium in this case
fusarium garum overwintering what's
happening and so how is it surviving is
it surviving on the previous crop um is
there debris and did our um wheat cover
crop have um ferium headlight there were
no symptoms by the way so um our
experiments here is we use um a wheat as
a cover crop so we had three Fields with
wheat as a cover crop we had three
Fields with like a mustard cover crop
and then we had three fields that were
tilled so like your traditional um
tilled field cultivated
field we had a severe drought again here
in Kentucky in 2024 so it was very hot
it got up into the upper 90s which is
unusual for us um but we still had and
you see there are sport traps on the
photo on the right and the photo on the
left you'll see some sport traps going
on there and from those sport traps we
had a very high inoculum load or Spore
Spore detection especially in our wheat
cover crop again we didn't have grain we
didn't have that time of enthesis and
infection and we did not have disease on
our wheat cover crop we had a higher
Spore load in that
wheat we um so so we had less less
disease in the mustard and the tilled
treatments
um so so what is so what is our so what
is our conclusion here right so we had
we did not have wheat in thesis we did
have wheat it was um it was tilt it
sorry it was um terminated in
May and then it we didn't plant until
June and then uh drought in July and by
August it was hot and dry but we had
lots of spores and in turn we had lots
of um DNA present in in those plants we
did not have a lot of disease but we had
that DNA
there all right
so what does all this mean what does all
this matter um seeds can get infected so
besides our direct our direct loss right
shattering blighted seeds seeds can get
infected and our hip seeds being
infected can mean a lot of
things um
and we we have we have have to tease
those apart right so if we plant higher
populations in the
field whatever we have left can still
become infected light can be really
severe we can have direct losses or uh
seeds can be contaminated and so these
images here show contaminated seeds uh
those seeds are not viable if we're
using them for if using that grain for
seed and more importantly is we're
moving into the space of hemp grain as
an animal feed and even is human human
food right we we eat H Hearts we eat um
we we do eat that grain so what about
myotoxins are we not talking about mot
toxins do we have mot toxins um and so
the previous field so we we have several
studies where um Henry Smith was looking
at mot toxins and he's definitely
finding Dawn and T2 levels above those
thresholds for human and animal feed so
those toxins are there we're not
regulated them and we're not managing
disease very well
right all right so then what we're
storing this stuff right it's coming out
of our field and we're storing it this
is this is floral hemp this is canabo
hemp but all in all we're storing H so
the diseases that are in the field the
toxins that are in the field are moving
from the field into storage and we do
have fusarium headlight or fusarium
budlight on
canabo Helm we have it in Grain Helm so
it's there so once we get into storage
depending on the level of humidity we
can keep we can have um disease
spreading we can have the fungus
colonizing more and then we can have um
increases in the amount of MOT toxins
especially if that humidity is high
during storage the photo all the way on
the right and the photo all the way on
the left those are tobacco barns here in
Kentucky so they're hanging uh hemp just
like hang tobacco and the image in the
center that is a greenhouse grower who
is using some old racks but either way
all of these scenarios have high
humidity what we do know is that in
wheat um that fusarium griin arum will
continue to colonize and grow on wheat H
as low as 22% relative humidity 22 to
25% relative humidity we still have that
active fungus in stored grain we also
know that wheat has to be dried to 12%
or lower in order to stop MotoX
production are we doing that in him are
we doing that with our hemp grain are we
doing that with our cannabinoid hemp
that's a question and I don't think we
are so that that could be another
recommendation right is to hurry up and
dry that grain down before those mot
toxins can continue to
multiply here are some examples of how
we see hemp um stor post Harvest if you
will so um the buds stored and in terms
of floral hemp we have some ground
biomass that is inevitably making its
way into um to hemp feed um again I told
you that we eat hemp grain right there
is some chocolate that I bought so that
is that those are hemp hearts in that
chocolate so we're eating hemp grain
we're feeding it to our animals um new
here in Kentucky and even in the ecoin
industry up to 30% um 30% um hemp feed
and then laying hens right so we need to
treat this grain like we treat other
grains we need to manage disease like an
agronomic crop that it is we need to
manage disease and we need to manage
this grain just like we do our our grain
um our our our agronomic grains or
serial
grains I know that uh breeding efforts
are under way um in fact at Cornell
there's a breeding program so we have
breeding programs that um several
scientists are looking at breeding hemp
so we need to make sure that we're
breeding against ferium headlight SE uh
we're breeding for sorry ferium
headlight resistance so it's a very
important disease we need to look
further at that we also need fungicides
we need seed treatments for damping off
and um we need to be able to manage
diseases across the board in particular
again the damping off and the Arium
headlight okay so with that um I'll
close up um there are a lot of resources
available for a lot of other diseases um
our put our UK dep depart H sorry
Department of Plant Pathology uh web
page here um so you can go to that web
page and then hit extension and
resources on social media um my handle
is at KY plant disease on pretty much
any of your social media platforms and
at Nicole go on YouTube we have 10 years
worth of research piled up here I work
on a lot of specialty crop so you'll see
a lot of specialty crop resources here
um also I want to plug that very last uh
that very last URL so I am part of a
working group that I work with scientist
at um at Cornell as well uh Dr Chris
Smart in particular and we are
developing um a resource a a national
resource a curated database for our
Growers so uh lots of research out there
not just at Kentucky but in other states
so uh with that Lucia we will take
questions
hello so we've asked people to ask their
questions using the Q&amp;A Buton can you um
see them or would you like me to read
them um let's do both I pulled them up
but let's make sure that um maybe you
can read them so I don't see skip
anybody okay so the first question says
or comment says hello Nicole thank you
for teaching US general question on this
topic is fiber hemp comparable to grain
hemp in its pathogen
susceptibility good question so we don't
really look at um well we our fiber hemp
is harvested before grain develops we
definitely have damping off diseases so
it gets all the same diseases but fiber
hemp goes in out of the the uh field so
fast so really um D the damping off
diseases those seed and seedling
diseases would probably be those to
worry about but fiber hemp is not
resistant it's just really not uh in the
field when we um when we're having these
problems or we're not counting it
right
excellent the next one says thanks
Nicole do you normally re recommend the
Growers till to uh manage
disease oh so usually till no till is a
um is a farmer practice and Farmers have
adopted that for other crops so we
really are not making those
recommendations what we have seen though
is that cover crops like mustards or
clovers might or definitely going to be
that better option if we're talking
about um an oculum buildup fusarium
headlight so we have um we have one
year's data on that but the amount of
fusarium headlight um in the wheat cover
crop versus the mustard and the Tilt are
very different so I'm not saying no
cover crops but it uh we definitely have
um a correlation between wheat as a
cover crop and the amount of fusarium
headlight in the
field super
interesting the next question is about
pythium it attacks the root cortex and
leaves behind the root Steel
root Center tissue yeah so it's it's
it's decaying that cortex so the cortex
kind of rots off as sloughs off and that
steel just kind of stays stays there um
I it is um affecting that steel to a
point but it's that soft cortex that
sloughs off so that's kind of more of
our indication I'm not saying that the
steel is not affected but the cortex is
definitely affected first and it's it's
it's really prominent once you see it
you'll you'll get it so play around with
it this year I hope you don't have
pythium but if you do you'll see
it and if the plant stem and leaves are
affected example by ronia but the plant
still flowers and produces grain is that
grain still fit for
consumption okay so generally yes so
generally um a crown rot will stay at
the bottom now if you have a web light
coming up we usually see that more uh in
cannabinoid cultivars not as much in
Grain cultivars um so rise octonia can
affect grain but it's unlik it'll get
that high generally rise octonia is at
the base of the plant but when it gets
hot and dry and that Crown is infected
um and and that girdling occurs you
usually see a
collapse so Joselyn is curious about the
balance between disease management and
regenerative
practices that's a tough one right
that's a really tough one because we do
want cover crops we do want these no
till systems but we have to understand
the limitations now of course if we're
rotating our Fields if we're if we're
using cover crops that are not uh
cereals we can definitely get around
that so I again I'm not saying don't use
cover crops but anytime we have a
disease epidemic we have to start
questioning all of our other practices
but crop rotations are really important
and to rotate with non-host hopefully
we're really bringing that uh that
inoculum level down but to find other
cover crops I would love to look at a
wider range of cover crops because we've
kind of we were quite surprised that a
wheat cover crop that never went to
grain or flour had that high of an
inoculum
load and Joselyn you'll be seeing
Henry's uh talk um probably at APS or
something so you'll be able to see those
numbers so it's it's quite
shocking choose your cover crops wisely
then um
next question is it common that
headlight can be acquired via
pollination I have noticed that when I
do control breeding the pollinated heads
sometimes mold while where the
surrounding flowers aren't noticibly
affected can pollin be combined with the
control bacteria to prevent the
mold okay wow that's a loaded um I don't
think fusarium headlight moves by by
pollinators I can double back on that I
can check on that I don't know the
answer I don't think so or it's not it's
not a it's I don't know about it um so I
can double check on that um and then uh
can pollen be combined with the um
control bacteria to prevent mold okay so
we are looking at Biologicals to see if
there are some of our biological agents
that are effective against ferium
headlight um right now we have not had
efficacy on any of them now are we
spraying at the right times are we us
using those products correctly we have
research in the pipeline that we want to
look at for that um but right now we
don't know of any of we we haven't seen
any of the commercial biological
products including the basilis products
that are effective against fusarium
headlight during flowering and grain
development um more work to be done on
that but right now the answer is
no okay the next common question is what
passes me is that mold affects also the
flower and valve area at the top of the
plant apparently the Turpin ET
metabolites from the triom are that are
there are not able to prevent every kind
of fungus or
microbes uh what's your take on that wow
okay that's outside of my area um but
but there there has been talk that um
propenes and and even some of the um
cannabinoids or anti
fungal um hemp and cannabis as we see it
is is an agronomic crop it's a
Horticultural crop and it is susceptible
to lots of different diseases um so I I
do not see where um yeah I don't know
the answer to specifically your question
but we see lots of disease across the
board how do you manage the diseases in
Camp since there are few if any
fungicides registered for you on it's a
tough one right so that's what we're
waiting for so we have a we have a
program called ir4 where we're working
to get some of these fungicides labeled
so hopefully some are in the pipeline I
don't know of any I don't think there's
any that are going to Target um husum
but we definitely have one right now in
trials that hopefully we'll get some
labeling in the next couple of years for
pythium um so and and there are some
also in the pipeline for other fungal
diseases so um it's hard to manage
disease when we have a very new crop we
have limited research uh 10 years is not
a long time um so we're getting there
we're getting there slowly um hopefully
we'll have more products on the market
in the next couple of years but right
now we're triing everything that we can
we're trying to get honest answers so
any University Research unbiased we have
nothing to sell so check with your
universities check for any University
Research that you can get your hands on
it will tell you what's working what's
not and all of that gradient in between
um so yes we're we're working towards it
we're getting there but not as fast as
uh we all want it to
go have you seen more incidents of
ferian ferium on mishas than female
individuals due to sessing male flowers
in the grain pad oh that is a really
good question uh no we have not um
generally the male flowers have died off
we have detected latent infection in
male flowers but in general once that
once that head starts to develop it's um
you know plant is securely in its
reproductive that female head is
securely in its reproductive phase it's
highly susceptible and then of course
when you have that very dense head or
Bud where you don't have a lot of air
circulation you've got that high
moisture again I talked about
architecture so I don't see a
correlation per se
um but again male flowers are kind of
gone at that
point how do you distinguish between
ferium and vrtis infection in the
flowers if you have a hand lens um so
any kind of magnification lens you can
usually see pretty well um butrus will
look like a little tree so it'll have a
stock and it'll have some little um
structures on top and it's more of a
gray um so once you train your eye you
can sort of see it uh we use a
microscope so we take it back we use a
microscope um but fusarium is generally
white and gray mold is typically gray um
don't just don't just look far back you
at least have to have a hand lens but um
you're commercial grower definitely use
a Diagnostic lab you've got to be
sure we like looking at things under the
microscop we love looking at things
under microscopes and with hand lenses
and they're always in our pockets and
our bags and our cars so yes we want to
teach you to do it too um but they're
like they're like less than $10 if you
get them online so you can uh sometimes
get like a 40x mine are usually a 20x
but you can get them usually 40x or so
and again under $10 so you should have
lots um
everywhere okay I
agree so the next question is related to
a previous one I'll read it just in case
you want to add something do you think
that many es grain Dual Purpose cultivar
may be more susceptible to headlights
than the ises cultivar because of the
early sessing ve
flowers we have not seen that
correlation we haven't looked really
closely but we haven't seen that
correlation um so I don't think so um
but I'm I'm not
absolute how to H how to recognize
reproductive stage male flowers are
flowering or female flowers or time of
both or something
else I'm not sure I understand the
question um it might be uh for cannabis
when uh do you say that it started
flowering uh for males versus
females so when we're talking so when
when I talk about reproductive stages
I'm talking about that density um so you
know again we're talking about grain
hemp um we're talking about that heavier
denser bud not those early initials
where you'll start seeing those U you
know questioning is this a male or a
female flower I'm talking about later
than that I'm talking about when you've
got that that dense Bud um again when
you're in in that field and you start
getting that um that condensed growth
that's what I'm talking about um and and
we have again we've we've done that
latent infection study we've kind of
looked at a lot of different stages um
that early reproductive mid and later
reproductive but
um this is more this is more of a of a
much later um stage and we I we're
working on the data right now for that
lat infection study we're about to
submit it for publication so I'll I'll
now you're making me question I'm going
to look at that and see if there's
anything that we know about those very
early reproductive stages versus the
later what are the best cover crops
grasses or leguminous options in
Kentucky to break the cycle of pathogens
like
ferian um anything that's not a a grass
right um so if fusarium headlight
infects grasses
or um graminicolous hosts or cereals
those are the ones you don't want so um
I know that legumes can become infected
but it's not really likely we haven't
looked at that um I would would just say
breaking that cycle from a um a seral
based cover crop and again I'm basing
this on the research that we have done
we have not we've not done a widespread
cover crop trial um you know we we did
that one with just the the three right
the mustard the till and the wheat so
there are a lot of other things we can
ask we haven't gotten there yet and I
don't even know across the cereals you
know is is barley a better U cover crop
than I don't know the answer to that but
right now we're just saying that it it
appears that your cereals are definitely
contributing to an oculum load even if
they're used as cover crops and not let
flour such an interesting question right
right and you know hemp is not um a
monocot so how this is playing along
that's a big question too right so it's
not like we're plant you know we are
breaking the cycle we're planting um a
dcot followed you know after that
monocot uh wheat cover crop and um this
is what we get yeah and still still get
it
right um this one is suggested to H
water content in soil is there a
suggested soil moisture range that can
be maintained in a green pouse to avoid
ferium or any of these
diseases so your soil moisture content
is going to drive plant health so um um
and fusarium is fusarium is not a soil
born disease right so it is it is in
debris but then it moves up into the
canopy so soil moisture should not
correlate to the amount of fusarium
headlight um yes there's moisture but
that's more of a humidity thing um but I
don't think you can reduce your soil
moisture enough to um adequately reduce
um canopy canopy uh
humidity thank you yes we have lots of
questions I see that they keep
coming um the next one is about uh the
recording yes we are recording and we
are going to upload it in this coming
days to our uh School of Integrative
science YouTube channel I've uh I've
added the link to the chat so you can
find it uh in the chat
part the next question is what kind of
SE treatment can we do to reduce dumping
off
pressure so in other crops we have seed
treatments in uh hemp we do not have a
seed treatment um we are going to be I
have a student that is looking at some
of some sea treatments with some of our
Biologicals um I'm not sure where that's
going to take us so maybe if there is a
seed treatment or at least a an at
planting drench um we're looking at some
of those I'm hoping that we can get a
seed
treatment product in in our ir4 um
rotation that's the um that's the
labeling uh program that I was talking
about but we are definitely looking
we've just finished two years of looking
at products that are effective against
pythium and the water molds so hopefully
maybe we can have a label for drenching
in green houses and Fields um so again I
hope in the next couple of
years but definitely greenhouse and um
and field was our Target because we know
that pythium is affecting lots of
different kinds of cannabis production
not just grain
heill and we have a perfect follow-up
question what are your recommended
treatments for fil infection in hemp if
you want to mention
the that's for later for the publication
yes give me this year to finish that up
um I am working on uh several projects
in fact Dr smart and I have some that
are kind of going on as well so
hopefully by next winter we'll be able
to have some solid recommendations for
everybody um I I don't wanna I don't
want to make any recommendations right
now so Biologicals are hard I will say
that Biologicals are often alive
sometimes they induce resistance but a
lot of times they are alive and we don't
know how to use them um you know how
long do they persist on Plants what
happens if it's hot what if it doesn't
rain what if it rains too much so to
learn how to use Biologicals is a whole
another layer of questions because those
of us who are trained with conventional
fungicides we put them on and they work
whereas Biologicals have have a
different Dynamic and we have we have a
lot to learn
there so terrific talk thanks for all
the great info this is a message is
Green Camp as sticky as cannaboid types
just wondering how that might affect
airf flow and humidity the sticky but
not as
sticky um but there's still some of our
grain cultivars can have those those
heavy U grain heads but remember we're
planting them closer we have a different
architecture we have a very high
population rate these are very straight
up plants very condensed um I don't know
if I had any images in my um in my
PowerPoint but um yeah planted very
close together there's no air
circulation in those fields like a lot
of we're not even planting them on rows
we're um we're broadcast planting or
we're planting you know those rows are
very close so no air circulation going
on by the time reproductive phas is
hit wow that's that's really
tight um have you found some cover crops
are better than others for seed
establishment we don't know the answer
to that um I I don't know we we haven't
really looked at cover crops right so
usually it's the agronomist who look at
cover crops so you know we we just have
our one year of data with the wheat and
uh and mustard so this is kind of new
for us and of course with any great
experiment comes a thousand new
questions so we have as many questions
as you do um we're going to repeat that
experiment with the mustards wheat and
till but I don't know what our future
looks like in terms of different cover
crops um I can think of a lot of great
ones but I don't know where our
priorities are going to stand
no it's it's a mix of disciplines right
but it really is come together and you
know there there's so few of us working
on hemp and you know funding sources are
difficult and time and so we have to
prioritize and we want to do everything
yesterday and it just doesn't quite fall
that way like we wish it would yes we
[Laughter]
wish is 50 Fahrenheit and wet good
temperature for dumping off we recommend
warmer soil temperatures for planting
but some are advocating for early spring
planting in the field some of your
pathogens like like like cool
temperatures right I talked about
pythium um pythium some of your pythium
can infect really really early in that
cool wet soil others um like rise
octonia like it when it's hot and wet so
I I kind of lump them all together today
just for time sake but but definitely um
the slower a plant establishes the
longer it is in that seed and seedling
phase so the longer exposure you have to
any pathogen so any of those cool season
pathogens that are there whatever those
may be so um it could be even some
opportunistic pathogens if that if that
seed or seedling is just kind of
lingering there with that very slow
spring so it's really about getting that
plant off to a good start and getting
that plant into into a um vegetative
stage as soon as possible you're better
off I don't know didn't really answer
your question but there are definitely
some pathogens that can affect at 50
degrees warmer is always better for the
plant it is good to know I'll keep that
in mind too I missed the first part of
the webinar did you discuss petritis and
it's control I did not discuss Bettis
today um we talk about Bettis and other
pram programs I know the Cornell group
has discussed petritis in some of their
programs I did not do that today um I
went from kind of from damping off to
fusarium headlight uh because those are
grain focused uh we don't have a lot of
betrus here in Kentucky we see betrus in
the greenhouse especially early season
and late season um but we don't really
see betrus in the field um my only
comment was that a lot of times if
Growers tell me they have betras and a
follow up it's often fusarium when
they're seeing that colonization so
depending on where you are talk to your
extension Educators talk to your
Diagnostic lab and find out because they
can look
similar no it's great that you don't
have at tritis there no one will
complain we have other
things and we don't have any any plant
viruses either so uh lots of the other
things so we trade them
out um what kind of rotation schemes are
there and what is the ation
L guessing associated with the feels in
which you grain hemp I'm I'm assuming
that's the question um so we have not
looked directly at rotation so um so
depending on what your disease pressure
is is going to dictate what your
rotational partners are what type of
plants are you willing to grow right are
you going to grow sugar beads or are you
going to grow sugar cane or you're going
to grow right cereal or tomatoes so
rotation is dependent on the Farm's um
on the Farm's production type um and
usually we always say it standard a
three-year rotation cycle will break a
disease cycle most of the time but again
you're not breaking a cycle if you plant
another susceptible host behind it and
that's what I was talking about when I
talked about ferium headlight in cereals
and in HP but but every disease is going
to have its own Dynamic so what are the
major disease concerns on your form what
are you willing to rotate do you have
enough land to rotate for three years
and if you have something really severe
right like us Arian Wilt your your
rotation might be longer than three
years so three years is kind of our
standard rule of thumb
rotation um so again talk to your local
extension educator explain what your
form does and and uh and make those
decisions on what your rotation partners
are but using your Diagnostic lab will
confirm what you have if you don't know
what you have it's a shot in the dark so
you always want to know what you have
you want that confirmed and then you've
got information you're armed with
information to move forward and make
some real decisions that make a
difference keep the diseases in mind
what's that yes in terms of diseases now
your insects and your pests that's a
whole different story then we layer on
Weeds fertility so I am disease
[Laughter]
only um in regards to pum species would
you agree that the oospores are capable
of traveling through the air making
prevention a
must wow
um pythium and your soil born pathogens
move through soil and plant material so
if you're talking about movement of of
any soil born pathogen pythium included
um you were thinking about the way you
move soil and soil particles because
they're hitchhiking in your soil they're
on the bottom of your shoes they're on
your tractor tires they're on the wheels
to your cart they're on your dirty
implements right they're on the bottom
of your muddy jees so that's where
you're moving your soil born pathogens
right airborn pathogens right so you can
talk about rusts they get up into the um
into air currents and they move long
distances fusarium can move long
distances but your soilborne pathogens
are moving through soil and water so
that is surface drainage a lot of times
they're hitchhiking in soil particles or
we're bringing them in if you're a if
you're a canabo grower we're bringing
them in and out with
plugs we have a lot of we have a lot of
pythium in our Fields you know the
question was about pythium we have so
much pythium in our Fields um I I think
we have in our field that we sample that
I was talking about earlier I think we
have four or five of the species in our
field that we that we sampled out so
they're there and in an agronomic field
we have just been you know we're monoc
culturing right so we have a lot of them
and they've built up um so if we worried
about movement think about you the
farmer or or humans that's how we're
moving our soil born
pathogens difficult to get read of them
right yes yes and they are they are the
most challenging absolutely the most
challenging that's why we talk about
them so much um because we're all
stumped you're stumped we're stumped so
that's why we we talk about them so much
because it is really difficult and we
have to break that disease
cycle is filium are common disas in come
in the Kentucky Region no we don't have
much verticillium at all like I've never
seen verticillium in lettuce or
vegetables so um rarely do we see
verticillium in anything but Red Buds
and Woody plants so I've never seen it
in
h you have three more questions okay
it's are you okay with time yes yes
let's keep
going so the next question is uh what
can be done to eliminate lesson ferium
before
storage um disease management in the
field but what does that mean if we
don't have our fungicide Arsenal right
so um
if if there's a way we can use cultural
practices is there if there's a way we
can start breaking or lessening disease
Cycles thinking about um you know again
our whe cover crop and then once we get
um hemp in
storage we're talking about grain we
need to dry it down really quickly if
we're talking about flowers we're not
drying it down definitely not to
12% so I guess it it depends on what
you're talking about but if it's grain
we need to dry it quickly um faster we
dry it but whatever we bring in that's
what we've got so you just want to dry
it down so it doesn't increase after
store after you get into
storage what type of diseases do you
normally see in indoor growing
facilities how can it be corrected once
it is spotted during the drying
process okay I'm looking at that as two
questions in indoor growing facilities
we usually see pythium root rots we us
usually see Bettis we see powdery
milde um and if you introduce anything
in we can have some other soil born
pathogens that are moved in with
contaminated media Etc but those are
usually the big ones um if you spot
diseases during the drying process how
can it be corrected it can't um our
plant pathogens need humidity they need
free water to complete their life cycle
so if we can dry down um we're we're
slowing or stopping um fungal you we
just talking about fungi um stopping
that fungal growth okay so drying it
down but again it depends what the crop
is because grain hemp is very different
than fiber hemp very different than
cannaboid hemp so what does dry mean um
it can be very different things between
the Grain and the and the cannaboid so
um drying it down but there's no there's
no fungicide or there's no um there's no
treatment into stuff and the last
question that we have is are there feral
cannabis populations growing around
Kentucky dad oh that's a good question
so I don't think so so we have gone I
have gone on searches um and I have
followed leads and I have not found it U
we are working with a couple of um
breeders and um some feral hemp programs
and I have not found it um so there
should be um Kentucky was a hemp seed
growing state for World War during World
War II U but we do not um I do not know
of any feral po populations and if
somebody finds one or has a lead I'm
happy to go go chase it for you but um I
have come up short in the past when when
um going out to collect for a
collaborator
oh well if they are I hope you find them
at some
point yes yes it would be great if we
did um so I'm always happy to go uh to
follow a lead if you were a breeder I
don't know who whoever the question came
from if you're a breeder I'm happy to go
searching yeah I think it came from an
academic setting okay awesome yes yes
but you're not the only one uh chasing
that
but well that was the last question
thank you Nicole for your you're very
welcome so good to see everybody or not
see everyone right to answer questions
and uh I wish everybody the best of luck
this growing season and I hope you do
not have ferium headlight or damping off
disease in your
Fields thank you yes okay and follow
Nicole in her social media
platforms yes and we will put we'll put
some of those handles and links in the
description when the video gets posted
yes okay okay have a nice rest of uh
your week good bye
bye this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu