this is a production of Cornell
University
they're so
yeah my title today is a time for barley
to go naked after 10,000 years and if
there was a subtitle to this
presentation it would be the conclusion
of another man after a life with barley
and that is because I have spent the
last thirty years my professional life
working on barley and there is a book a
real book out there this is not
Photoshop called one man's life with
barley and it is a much better book than
anything I could write and it's by Harry
Harlan and he was one of the pioneering
plant explorers and traveled the world
and was responsible for I think a lot of
the vision that we have for conservation
of plant genetics resources and so if
you have a chance to get a copy of one
man's life with barley I'd encourage you
to go there let me do sect the title a
little bit here it wasn't intended to be
at all you know sort of the kind of
thing to bring people out after lunch
but first let's just do barley and in
what's barley for those of you not
familiar with it it is hordeum vulgare
subspecies vulgare you will see it often
referred to as just hordeum vulgare but
technically we should use the subspecies
because it is completely inter fertile
with its wild ancestor which is
subspecies spot Nahum it's a diploid has
a large genome size has that sort of
average number of genes and it is a
hermaphrodite and so this is kind of
all-important in the breeding and
genetics and so forth of this organism
because it's highly tolerant of
inbreeding and as a consequence we see
primarily pure line varieties throughout
the world there have been kind of on and
off attempts at hybrid production in
barley and those really haven't caught
on until recently Syngenta's been
marketing some hybrid feed Barley's in
europe with some considerable success
there is still public and private plant
breeding in the Americas and so my
colleague Mark Sorrels and students on
his project are still barley breeders
and wheat breeders and so forth at
universities we have had a much greater
presence of the private sector in
cereals breeding in the last several
years here in the Americas in the rest
of the world really then it's a private
venture and so barley and wheat have
long since gone down the road that we've
seen in the US with corn and soybeans
and other crops
so let me get to the naked part of the
title here and the naked in this case
refers to the adherence of the lemma in
Pylea to the Kari OPS's to the seed and
so if they adhere then you have what is
called a covered barley and if they
don't adhere they're not adhering you
have what we'll call a naked barley and
I'm gonna use this naked nomenclature
after Takeda at all here who are the
ones who cloned this gene and then
reported in 2008 because by saying naked
and covered you just get around this
real messy kind of grammatical semantic
thing because if you want to say that a
barley doesn't have a halt is it
hull-less with a - is it Hollis with
just two L's and it's just and it's
complicated and further complicated by
the fact that if that's Hollis then what
is the alternative and its hold which
can be misconstrued to sound as though
it has had its whole removed so it's
just easier to say covered and naked I
think so hence the terms
the gene abbreviation is nude for new
demand the covered form right here where
we have the adhering lemma and palea is
dominance and it is indeed the wild and
ancestral condition and when Takeda and
his group cloned this they identified
this as an ethylene response factor it's
a transcription factor and the mechanism
by which it works is that there is or is
not the formation of a lipid layer
between the lemma and palea in the
pericarp and if the lipid forms then the
lemon peleas sticks and if the layer
doesn't form then it thrush is clean so
for you folks who are familiar with
wheat and other grains that thrush clean
this is like no surprise it's sort of
like well why not
we thought all grains were that way
barley is rather unique in being a major
cereal crop of the fourth most important
in the world that actually has a tightly
adhering halt and so we'll kind of see
some of the reasons why that has
transpired
so now to the ten thousand year part of
the title here so barley originated as
din so many of our other crops and
domesticated animals in the Fertile
Crescent and then you saw a
dispersal of barley from that ancestral
site
and there's a couple of key traits that
are part of that domestication syndrome
and the naked covered phenotype is is
one of them so certainly shattering or
the brittle rei'kas is
characteristic of the subspecies font
name and that's that condition have a
picture of it in the next slide here
that just facilitates seed dispersal and
so you definitely want the non
shattering non brittle rei'kas in bulk
are the domesticated sort spot name is a
two row for those of you not familiar
with Barley's two row means you have a
single row of kernels on either side of
the spike and so that's a fertile
florida at every rekha snowed and if
you're a six row then you have three so
the ancestral form is two and the post
domestication form is six the spot name
the ancestral sort has an adhering halt
I said that was a wild type that
dominant allele and there are adhering
and non adhering halls within volgar and
in terms of growth habit something we
really won't get into today but that is
very near and dear to my heart then you
have just winter annuals in the hordeum
spontaneity have winter facultative and
spring annual types present in the
derive so that of course gives us this
kind of apparent situation and we all
know that appearances can be deceiving
that'll be my only political illusion
today but one of them is it seems that
we have much greater diversity over here
in volgar than we do in the spot name
but in fact of course it's quite the
reverse because we had a number of
evolutionary bottlenecks along the way
where we've lost allelic diversity in
vulgare and so that is a very active
averse area of research is to go back
and start to try to bring in our mind
some of those alleles that may have been
lost in the domestication process this
is a
picture of the brittle reyes and if
you've ever never encountered this
you've probably encountered brittle
rei'kas in other wild grassy weed
species and you walk through those
fields in the summer and half the field
winds up in your socks and so it's an
excellent seed dispersal mechanism and
of course just the thing we don't want
in agriculture because we want those
seeds to hang on into their seeds to
remain on the head as long as possible
what's kind of interesting about the BTR
genes there's two of them is that both
of them are loss of functions there's
deletions and that leads to a loss of
function of the abscission layer there
vrs one which is the two row 6 row is
also a loss of function situation also
due in this case to multiple different
deletions inside the same gene nud the
whole advance is also a loss of function
in this case the whole gene is gone just
takeda and all revealed that in all the
exceptions that they looked at the gene
has just disappeared 17 KB of it plus
some flanking sequence they have then
generated some new mutants and then kept
up with other ways of generating the
same phenotype growth habits again not
the topic of today's seminar but loss of
function deletions and flowering time
there are also loss of function deletion
so it's just this kind of long list of
these domestication traits being loss of
function and that kind of gives us
something to think about if you think
about some of the simplest applications
of genome editing how many other things
are there out there that you might want
to go into and then just generate loss
of function mutants with and come up
with target phenotypes
so or some paper that just came out
recently here in Nature Genetics
by masher at all and they report on
doing a lot of nice genomics on some
paleo
botanical remains of barley at Masada in
Israel and it they you know there's a
lot to see about this barley including
the fact that it looks very much like
Barley's we might see today in
fluorescence might be just a tad shorter
but one thing about it it was still
covered in so 4,000 years post
domestication in that end of the world
there was still covered barley now
Takeda it all argued that there was
probably a monophyletic
origin of the naked tree and that that
domestication event happened about 8,000
years ago so they're not sure exactly
where this happened but we've got a
couple of hints as to where that may
have been and we'll come to that in just
a second here
so you have this domestication moment
you have the Middle East and then you
have this just explosive dissemination
of Agriculture and animal husbandry
across Europe and Asia and that's
proceeding at a rate of maybe about a
mile per year and so that may seem kind
of slow if you can walk 20 miles in a
day but you know when you think about
actually then planting harvesting a crop
and then convincing your neighbor to
plant and harvest that crop then mile
progressions every year are actually
pretty impressive so quickly barley
moves out across the landscape and
this migration and specialization then
leads to things that come back to the
halt and so I've kind of told this
little history here of barley and then
I'm coming into this sort of migration
thing to tell you a little bit about
Europe and a little bit about Asia and
then some alternate uses of barley and
holes in those two environments so in
Europe you had a
an ever-increasing focus on barley for
its use in the manufacture of beer not
to say there weren't uses also for human
food and animal feeding and so forth but
principally for beer and principally the
forms that were used were barley with
holes and those tended to be spring
growth habits and they tended to be two
rows so in this little cartoon here you
see a
representation of the Reinheitsgebot and
this is the German purity law this is
barley here this is hops this is water
and that's yeast course they didn't know
about yeast at that time that was sort
of added later but the argument was and
not the argument the law was and is that
the beer could only contain those three
and four elements and it did not contain
adjuncts so this is an angry wheat and
angry maize and an angry rice up here
who cannot participate in the beer as
they are want to do in American Standard
lagers so when I first learned about
this as a as a barley breeder I thought
wow that is just you know another
example of people really knowing good
beer and so there's this German brewing
tradition and you'd think wow they had
this law that just sort of embodied
their their knowledge about beer and in
fact it turns out that it was probably
this law was there for a number of other
reasons one is it protected drinkers
from high prices it banned the use of
wheat in beer so that more bread could
be made and so the fact of the matter
was the the beer drinkers were using up
the available wheat and that wasn't
leaving enough food for the rest of
society and so they said well hey make
the beer out of the coarser grain and
then leave the wheat out there for
nutrition now if you're half of i'ts an
enthusiast or something you'll know that
there was still a tradition of brewing
with wheat in Germany but the other
piece there was that unscrupulous ruiers
were adding toxic and even
hallucinogenic ingredients as
preservatives or flavorings in their
beers and so you know that's a whole
frontier that will continuously be
explored I think as we see an increase
in craft brewing and leaked legalized
cannabis
and so those two elements will probably
be coming together and we may be
promulgating a new Reinheitsgebot here
too
that sort of thing from happening again
so meanwhile a very different sort of
scenario has unfolded in in Asia and
particularly in Central and East Asia
their barley assumes a role in food and
so it's particularly its role in food
was most notable in the Himalayan
plateau and so this gentleman's a
tibetan buddhist monk and he's preparing
to eat some some pup which is in this
case prepared from a toasted barley
flour and that's mixed with yak butter
and green tea and so it's a very
nutritious
material that can be very easily
prepared there are very high elevations
not a tremendous amount of
infrastructure required to prepare this
food and so a recent paper in science by
chen at all actually argues that
barley in fact allowed for the
settlement of the himalayan plateau that
you simply could not have moved into
those higher elevations had it not been
for this very early maturing cereal and
also in their case a cereal that was
naked so that it could be immediately
consumed so you may ask well you know
why can't she just eat barley so you you
could but that's lemma those dilemma and
paleo that hall consists of cellulose
hemicellulose and lignin and it's not
palatable it is insoluble dietary fiber
and wears a lot of us need fiber in our
diets we generally don't need insoluble
dietary fiber and so it's just much
easier to not have it there anybody eat
barley today yeah today I mean white
bean in every day John okay so we'll
talk about that later but okay anybody
barley this wheat oh my god that's why
we come out from the west to the east
and we proselytize our crops yeah okay
so was it a pearl barley perhaps that
you have if anybody so pearl what is
pearl barley pearl barley is barley that
has been mechanically abraded to remove
the hull and so if you have a naked
barley you don't have to pearl it but if
purling this grinding process in that
grinding process removes dilemma and
palea and it also removes a little bit
of testa a little bit of pericarp a
little bit of alley around and that's
enough to make your barley no longer be
considered a whole grain
legally so whether or not you're losing
you know phytonutrients that's a whole
other topic of discussion here but
legally you cannot call that a whole
grain so not the tibetans were worried
about whole grain or not but they
selected for naked and incidentally
populations where there is high
consumption of barley have the lowest
incidence of colorectal cancers of any
societies so soluble dietary fiber is a
good thing also has a number of other
positive effects that we'll come to in
just a little bit this is just a quick
walk through of a Japanese grocery store
showing a whole sample of barley
products that you know readily
accessible now as you got into China and
Japan and Korea barley was an important
part of the culinary nutrition culture
but of course rice was was preeminent
there and so barley has kind of to my
understanding a subsidiary role and
sometimes a very sort of a negative
perception role in those areas where it
is viewed as the famine food so it was
what you ate only when you didn't have
rice and so that's been kind of a
psychological barrier that people have
been having to work for
so that kind of brings us to what's
barley used for and you know what's
implied so what do we have here
malt in the making so the process of
melting barley is a process of
controlled germination and this is the
result of
the end of the first phase and into the
second phase and so you've gone through
what's called the Steep where the barley
is alternatively soaked and then exposed
to air and then it's allowed to
germinate and these are the little
reutlitz that are emerging and the
incipient chute is actually forming in
under the whole but you can't see it in
this case because it is a barley that
that has a hole and once that
germination process is accomplished then
the barley is killed and
depending on the temperature and
duration of that killing process you
come out with a range of malts which
then go into our beers and so you have
everything from pale malts all the way
to roasted malts at the other extreme
the so you might ask the question well
why barley why don't we do this anything
else and the answer is you can do it to
anything else and there are now Moulton
companies that are moulting other grains
besides barley notable is one in
Colorado called Grouse malting and their
monstrous twill ax is an expert in
molting things like chia and buckwheat
and other grains then for celiacs who
would like to have molted grains going
into a beer but why malted barley for
beer so malted barley is is like a
perfect little nutrition capsule for
yeast and in the process of fermentation
what we're after is ethanol and so we're
harnessing the yeast to give its give us
its excretion so that we can have
ethanol and flavor and if you wanted to
design the perfect little nutrient
capsule for yeast it's going to be that
malted barley kernel so that's why of
all the cereals that are out there
barley provides the optimum balance of
starch sugars proteins and that can
carry on the fermentation process and
allow yeast to do for us what we want it
to do
so what about barley foods so
barley foods today account for a
negligible portion of the total barley
that's produced in the United States and
consumed certainly less than 10%
however the FDA says that if you
incorporate barley at a specified amount
into your diet you will reduce your risk
of heart disease you'll reduce your risk
of type 2 diabetes and you will achieve
satiety
achieving satiety alone is something
that could be a goal for many of us
right just to sort of be cool and happy
with wherever you are so just eat your
barley and that's where it will take you
so what accounts for this this these
wonderful properties it's it is a
soluble dietary fiber fraction called
beta glucan and beta glucan is found in
cell walls throughout the barley
endosperm beta glucans found in
appreciable quantities only in oatmeal
otherwise and in oats and in oatmeal
marks orals isn't here so I can really
knock oats but in oats it's only found
in the outer layer of the endosperm and
that's why oats make that horrible gluey
icky thing when you cook them because
the beta glucan is just sort of right
out there you cook barley flakes and
you'll have actual integrity of each
flake but you'll still have the same
level of beta glucan so as soon as the
FDA comes out with this RDA and there
was research prior to that then of
course what do we do is plant breeders
well if a little bit is good a lot would
be better right so all of a sudden every
breeding program is out there going well
let's breed for high beta glucan and so
they've been in fact very successful in
doing so your average barley a moulting
barley will contain about four to five
percent grain beta glucan
that's beta glucan and the malting
barley is broken down by beta glucan ace
endogenous beta glucan aces during the
malting process and in fact brewers want
low levels of beta glucan in their beer
otherwise it becomes viscous and causes
processing problems so on the food on
the other hand you say Wow beta glucan I
want this in my food and so breeders
have been very successful even over the
last 10 years in developing high beta
glucan Barley's and they now have them
up to say 15%
if you were to eat one bowl of barley
flakes made from a barley that's four
percent beta glucan that will satisfy
your RDA these are barley breads made
with 40 percent barley flour barley has
gluten in the sense that it will Alicia
eight elicits a negative response in a
celiac but it does not have gluten in
for a baker in the sense that its dough
does not have strength and elasticity so
you you're about your maximum blend is
going to be about 40 percent barley
going into a wheat blend but if you have
two slices of bread made with a barley
that's about four to five percent beta
glucan you will meet your RDA a sandwich
so what happens if you eat 15% beta
glucan
gastrointestinal distress of epic
room-clearing proportions
so
what then why do I do this so plant
breeders be careful once you start going
down this road of selecting four more
there are sometimes unanticipated
pleiotropic effects right so the so
what's that has led to is kind of a
schism in barley breeding if you will
where if you have a whole-grain model
you just can get by with four to five
percent beta glucan you don't need that
high stuff if however you're on a model
where you want to extract or fraction
ate the beta glucan and put that onto a
Twinkie or a cheeto and call it health
food then you want to go for the high
stuff so there's sort of two different
markets out there
so feed
80% of the barley used in the world
today is used to feed animals mostly
ruminant animals but I don't didn't have
a nice picture of cow so I picture of
these pigs and these pigs in fact are in
a barley field you see in the distance
there that is a barley field and this
farmer just unleashes them into barley
fields and then moves the electric fence
a couple hundred feet every day and the
pigs are happier than if they were in
clover you know the expression like a
pig in clover so they're very happy
they're just eating this this green
barley as they go along and that's the
residue of the barley straw below but
most of the barley in the world today is
fed to animals and
about 80% and in the u.s. until about
maybe 20 years ago and we'll see the
graph of this and talk about that in a
sec that was also the case here now
we've had a complete flip so that almost
all the barley grown in the United
States is used for melting and brewing a
little bit for food and a very little
bit for feed but the feed markets are
essential in my opinion because if you
don't have a feed market you have no
safety net for your grain
barley is has excellent feeding
properties and a lot of research
you know has it confirms that and
sort of brings us to this point here so
we'll talk about that research in a
moment once we've talked about how we
got to this so what do you think this is
US barley acreage millions of acres
so if you follow this graph back to 1986
which is when I started my job it's even
more obviously linear so it's a
cause-and-effect relationship the longer
pat breeds barley in Oregon the more the
barley acres in America go down
once it's established god bless the
tenure system right
now so there's a number of reasons why
this has happened and
before we go into you know sort of this
slope of despondency here let's talk
about this little plateau of
encouragement over here and what that's
due to so
little plateau of encouragement is due
to places like New York State amongst
others where barley acreage is actually
increasing and why is it increasing its
increasing because of the craft brewing
craft distilling and craft melting
industries and then in addition here
you've legislated and that is further
driven barley acres and so the craft
industry is what is driving this the
slight increase but it's really going to
be a tapering
phenomena because there's only so much
barley that those industries can absorb
for example if you're running a craft
moulting enterprise 10-ton batch is a
pretty respectable batch size a lot of
them are smaller than that to run a
10-ton batch system requires about 500
acres of barley high yielding barley so
it doesn't take a whole lot to meet
those needs and so you have the Sunoco
facility opening up here in New York
State that's going to have I think six
10 tonne errs chomping on barley and so
that's going to lead to an increase in
acres but in terms of overall impact
it's still a couple of thousand acre
we'll probably feed that machine
so what caused that decline so there's a
there's a whole there's a number of
factors that contributed to that decline
but they are all feeding into this sort
of story where we're headed here and
anybody in here ever played pit
what was your favorite commodity just
say barley okay it's a supposed to be
the Chicago Board of Trade game and so
you're pretending that you're down in
the pit and you're calling out
commodities and you've got pork belly
pork belly and you got barley barley
barley barley barley is one of the cards
but barley is no longer traded on the
Chicago hoard and so that sort of shows
where it's at
look at where barley is going here the
largest importer of barley if you had
any assailed by Saudi Arabia
followed by China so China is a definite
beer market there Australia and Canada
dominate that market Saudi Arabia is
primarily a traditional livestock use
area and a lot of racing camels are
barley not a particularly stable market
the racing camel in an era of declining
revenues in some of these countries but
what are we seeing we're seeing a
situation where barley is actually
priced after corn it's a function of
corn prices and so typically barley is
priced at 80% of the price of corn corn
prices now are incredibly depressed if
you know to follow commodities markets
their feed prices are incredibly low at
the moment if barley is 80 percent of
something incredibly low which is true
in conventional feed barley production
you lose money from the get-go so
that's a reason people don't want to
have feed barley out there why is there
wire feed barley prices so low when the
research confirms that probably the
feeding value of barley can be the same
or superior to corn in some feeding
applications a couple of things have
happened which are so much bigger than
anything that we can address is plant
breeders are scientists that we just
have to mention them and move on so one
of them are federal farm programs we
have a program of very indirect price
supports in in the US and one of them is
called revenue assurance where you can
essentially ensure your crop if you have
the right crop to a value that you know
will allow you to generate a stable
income you can't do that for barley
secondly you have a situation where
you've had changes in the confined
animal feeding
industry so now you have enormous
operations for consolidated dairies and
feed Lots and even in Oregon these folks
find it cheaper to bring in Midwestern
corn and unit trains than to buy barley
from the farm next door so that that
leads to a situation where you then have
no market for feed even if you do have a
place to actually be selling it and then
you have sort of you know kind of the
final clincher in this which is you have
incredibly successful plant breeders in
the Midwest breeding corn and soybeans
and corn and soybeans along with global
warming have moved increasingly
northward and westward and occupied what
were barley acres in Minnesota and North
Dakota
that corn and soybeans happens to be GMO
which is neither you know here nor there
I think in terms of that effect on
barley but it does play into the story
that we're going to come to in a sec out
in our neck of the woods we don't have a
whole lot of GMO corn our soybeans at
this point but we do have herbicide
resistant wheat we have imidazole and
resistant wheat generated as a mutation
not as a GMO but the consequence of that
is that herbicide is applied to ground
where formerly barley was a rotation
crop that herbicide persists for 12
months and the barley can't follow in
the rotation so between all of those
factors then we've seen barley acres
plummet and you know what do you do well
since I've worked on barley for 30 years
I don't want to see it disappear I don't
want to see it just become a relic crop
but I do think in addition to just
wanting things to persist because
they're cool that there are reasons that
barley can be advantageous for farmers
it's early maturing two weeks earlier
than wheat uses about 80 20 percent less
nitrogen than wheat but has all the same
standard green infrastructure processors
it's absolutely essential for molting
for food processors the same
infrastructure you use for milling
grinding
cracking for the feed industry rations
and delivery can be the same consumers
gives you a range of beverages
heart-healthy foods in some new sensory
attributes in your diet so I think
there's a lot of good reasons to have
barley out there in our lives
but it's it's hard to convince people
sometimes that that's necessary and so
what I've got now is to shift gears a
little bit and I've kind of told you
this barley story and use you as a bit
of a focus group because we're having a
planning grant session at the end of
this month and it's funded by the NIF o
REI so that's the organic research
branch of nipa and a planning grant is
where you kind of get people together to
say do we really want to write a full
grant proposal on this thing and
the proposal is about the release
testing and development of public sector
multi-use naked barley varieties so
that's where I come back to this topic
here this is barley here winter barley
growing next to a GMO corn and on a
per-unit efficiency basis this thing is
going to produce a whole lot more than
this one over here but in this
particular case this is not a comparison
because that is a GMO corn which this
particular panel will not allow so the
question is then okay we come into the
organic panel what could we do that
would capitalize on the kinds of
research that they might be interested
in funding and why
so the first thing is is that we're
looking at market simplification here so
if you have a naked barley in theory it
could be used for all three uses okay
you could vault with it you could eat it
and you could use it as feed so a farmer
currently if they raise malt barley has
barley with a halt can they sell it as
food if they have excess protein no
you'd have to grind the whole off can
they sell it for feed no they're going
to be at a loss if you're selling if
you're growing a naked barley can you
get a mold stirrer brewer to use it and
the answer is no because they're not
familiar with moulting and brewing with
Naked Barley's can you get a feeder to
use it you're going to have to go
uncover someone so in the convince
large-scale commodity markets there is
not room to pursue this multi-use good
idea hence the idea of saying ok the
organic sector may be receptive to a
newer idea and thus that could be a
platform where we could seek to get some
acceptance some adoption and then let it
diffuse out from there some attributes
will be that it has to be naked first
and foremost it has to have modest grain
beta-glucan you can't have 15% erse
because the Brewers won't use it it's
got to have normal starch there's waxy
and high amylose starch types we want to
avoid those you're gonna have to have
yield and adaptation in your target
environments and you're going to want to
have some entry interesting sensory
attributes that you know big people want
to eat this stuff you can kind of follow
a maximum that's been around there for a
long time which that a good malt barley
is a good feed and a good feed barley if
you don't believe that these are ice
cream sandwiches made out of barley
cookies with a barley malt ice cream
sensory attributes fiber
flavor calories okay so what are we
saying here that in this situation we
are looking for the elimination of the
hall after 10,000 years it's time to
just go naked and then say okay let's
focus on this particular aspect of
barley so why go you know organic
anybody in here done on farm organic
research
organic breeding scale plots can be some
challenges right particularly weed
control
amongst other things and certainly in
our environment our University farm has
a very limited certified organic acreage
they can't put in really representative
rotations to properly encourage
fertility and weed control and so as a
consequence you get into this kind of
weird input replacement and endless weed
Patrol so this was an organic increased
block of a new naked barley of ours it's
called buck okay buck naked barley
tough there's some additional work there
we with the organic route again because
the idea was hey there'd be perhaps
receptiveness to this concept we also
struck out with the conventional panels
we had some really elegant genomic
selection models for human food we
created resource I'll mention in a
second here but as I told the graduate
students earlier today never remain
bitter about reviews but just memorize
them and repeat them because someday
that person is going to be in the room
and then they'll understand the mortal
wound that they inflicted on a fellow
scientist so we got a review from one of
these genomic selection proposals and
this individual says you know hey I can
hardly imagine barley as being the
poster child for good nutrition
so it's like get some fiber dude you
know anyway so what can we do to make
this happen so the first and fundamental
thing you may go well wait a second
barley has had a hole on it for 10,000
years because of the brewing tradition
in that hole is absolutely critical so
this is barley moulting with a hole on
it because of a process called loitering
and loitering is after you have taken
your malt and you have boiled it and
added your bittering hops then that
liquid called the wort is then passed
through the grain bed and the process
known as sparging and moved off to the
fermenter that grain that spent malt at
the bottom of that tank then is a
natural filtration system par excellence
and that's why holes have persisted
until today so you ask the question how
can we get past that and it is with a
technology called mash filtration
membranes and pressure use a whole lot
less water and a whole lot less energy
so many breweries in Europe are Team
Asheville tur breweries they went that
way simply to reduce energy and water
usage in the US Alaskan amber you may be
familiar with as a mash filter quit
brewery and we've got three or so craft
breweries in the US including one that
just built a new brewery in Bend Oregon
Krux fermentation project that is all
mash filter based so we do have ways now
that you can move a naked barley malt so
this is naked barley malting down here
directly into a mash filtration system
those of you that are barley people one
of the key parameters that we work on
for moulting is something called malt
extract both extract numbers of a good
barley with a whole are typically around
eighty to eighty three percent in a
naked barley that malt extract can be at
88 or 89 percent what does that mean
that means more beer per unit of malt
put into the brewery so the Brewers can
be very attracted by that what else is a
whole bringing to beer
astringency
microorganisms things that you may not
particularly want in some styles of beer
so I think that we have some advantages
there for the brewer
what about four foods so this was at a
recent event in in Portland called the
plant variety showcase it's a thing
called the culinary breeding Network and
so this is a local Baker who's prepared
a series of breads from different barley
varieties because the point of this was
to showcase the foods made from a range
of barley varieties and pepper varieties
and squash varieties and so forth and so
yes you can do it you can make delicious
breads of all sorts and styles with
different types of barley up to about
that 40% inclusion rate and that could
be exactly the same barley that went to
your malt house could go into those lows
and better yet the malt that you made
out of that naked barley can also feed
back into your baking system and that
brings in a whole other palette of
flavors aromas and sensories
finally the organic feed sector at least
by the advertisements we see they all
have a much better time at their lives
than some people and some other sorts of
operations and so optimistically yes we
can see whole grain barley is moving
into various animal feeding regimes
because that that safety net is
absolutely essential as the third leg on
a stool if you will for marketing
barley crop
so now we come to the plant breeding
part of this you know I'll finally here
in the last you know seven minutes or
whatever that we have and so you know
after thirty years of writing grant
proposals to brewing companies and NSF
panels and other people about different
aspects of our crop finally this is like
the first time I get to write one it's
just sort of carte blanche and you go
like all the way back to those just like
sort of fundamental things about what
you do with the breeding program and one
of them is you know what are your target
environments who are your target users
out there what are the target traits are
gonna work on what kind of germ plasm
are you gonna use how are you gonna
advance that germ plasm what is the
basis of your selection and what kind of
varieties are you gonna release I'm just
gonna kind of walk you through these
real quickly and then open it up for
some opportunities for discussion and
perspective here so the target
environments that we have are the
Pacific Northwest the Upper Midwest and
the Northeast that would be New York
here with mark Sorrels and this is our
colleague Kevin Smith in Minnesota
why these regions well we had plant
breeders who are interested in this we
have processors who are perhaps early
adopters of some technologies we have
consumers who are interested in a
variety of foods and then the
anticipation is that we would see a
subsequent diffusion out into other
geographic areas and into the
conventional sector as well
our target audiences here's one that we
can have cannot neglect I don't think
and this is a very good friend of the
families and we had our one of our food
barley composites growing in her garden
and so she invites her friends over and
we have this sort of little harvest
party these people had never grown a
cereal they had never processed a cereal
they had never prepared a cereal that
was two hours old and so we harvested
this barley took over our threshing
machine harvested that prepared it and
had a barley tabbouleh made from
something they harvested hours before we
hit 10 people out there who went and
told 10 other people who told 10 other
people about how barley was something
you could grow at home and it was really
cool and it was good for you and so
there's an important piece there but of
equal and greater importance are their
children and so moving barley into
schools in through various science and
education pieces and so we call this
sort of the learners they're gonna have
very small acreage things we have
artists and these are the folks down at
your farmers markets who may have in the
tens of acres craft maybe the hundreds
of acres and then the industrial sort of
regional folks maybe a thousand acres
you know levels and so there's different
audiences we're going to be targeting
here and I think we need different kinds
of germ plasm for those people and
there's going to be different sorts of
traits that we target everything has to
be homozygous recessive I think we just
have to have naked varley's molting and
brewing quality is something that
already exists we have the American malt
barley Association it has guidelines we
need some allowance for higher malt
extract they're not going to complain
about that but maybe just a little bit
higher beta glucan maybe a 200 instead
of a you know under a hundred where they
are now not talking scary levels of beta
glucan in beer food quality is really
very simple as long as you don't bring
in novel starch types or high beta
glucan our life as barley breeders could
almost be as simple as that of corn
breeders we just breed for yield we just
want more of this good naked stuff
growing per egg per unit acre now of
course you've got all the additional
challenges of what's going to make yield
under an organic system but it's yield
that you're after in feed quality I
think it's yield ultimately once you get
greater market penetration then you'll
start to see I think some feed back into
the breeding programs that says we need
that flavor attribute we need this kind
of kernel hardness we need something
else but we don't have those signals now
growth habit I'd like to see facultative
in spring Barley's because of climate
change but winners are okay two rows are
preferred but six rows are okay colors a
whole pallet is okay if you're breeding
for conventional markets right now
you'll recognize that this is not the
way that you can breed for large
commodity producers they'll tell you
what color what's specific level of a
hundred and one traits and so you're
much more confined and defined in your
breeding scheme the germplasm basis
we've got some ongoing naked barley
programs and we have something called
the naked barley doubled haploid
composite we've got a germ plasm release
on this that we're writing up right now
so it'll come out but the seed is
available if anybody would like to get
this it's 900 double haploids derived
from about 35 process amongst 28 parents
40 different grandparents that we source
from 14 different breeding programs and
selections we created this resource in
anticipation of doing this genomic
selection program grant didn't get
funded we're in a hurry had to harvest
we said the hell with it drove the
combine perpendicular to all the plots
took us an hour so we just mixed
everything together and so they're all
in there and we've send this
synthesis cools public breeding programs
private breeding programs mark Sorel's
your colleague here has started a naked
barley program based on the naked barley
blood composite it's got Springs witters
facultative two rows six rows whites
blacks Browns etc so there's a whole
range of material in there some very
interesting things to do with schools in
terms of natural selection versus
implemented selection
germ plasm and advance we've got this
all the double haploids that are in this
composite we still have them we have the
original and remnant seat so we have all
900 of those my breeding program is a
hundred percent double haploid based so
we're producing new double haploids from
cycles with naked malt Marley's that
have come out of a Canadian program and
will pursue a collaborative development
and testing of those but segregating
generations will be available to those
who would want them at some point the
basis of selection for that composite
you can simply go real easy Bob Allard
published this beautiful paper in the
late 70s about evolutionary plant
breeding and he showed that just by
planting the same mixture year after
year for his 30 years at UC Davis he had
the same rate of gain as his colleague
Charley Schuyler who was running a
pedigree breeding program and Charley
was a pretty good breeder so natural
selection bulk breeding is not to be
denied but there's directed phenotypic
selection genotypic selection there's a
lot of enthusiasm I would say this is
probably a focus of genomic selection
internationally and so there are
thoughts that we might implement
something to some extent in a program
like this and who's the plant breeder
professional or participatory this is a
participatory program we have going on
with two folks in Eastern Oregon this is
Seth and his dad Brad and they're
working with us to develop a variety in
their case of double haploid barley that
will specifically feed into their estate
molding system so finally let's come to
germ plasm release what sorts of
varieties will we be releasing here so
you know I lay it all out here I'm an
open source person I get really
concerned about tight control over
germplasm resources and so I support at
least the concept of the open seed
source initiative and we have the
variety full pint which then we released
underneath the auspices of that
organization we've been using germ plasm
releases we have a particularly stuffy
tech transfer office in my University
you could quote me saying that I've
called them worse sometimes but when
they won't let you release something as
a variety you can release it as a germ
plasm through the journal of plant
registrations that gets the material out
into the public domain and people can
access it the problem being that you
can't sell classes of certified seed
finally we've made some headway and
except here varieties I had the weirdest
thing this whole trip has been weird I'd
lost I couldn't get here yesterday so I
had this time frame thing in my travel
and then the spell check quit working in
my PowerPoint and I haven't found a way
to renew that but anyways we've got
public varieties with no PvP so that
gives you an option there the revenue
thing is an interesting one because our
office will argue as many that hey we
need to mine our breeding programs they
need to become self-sustaining if we're
going to have public sector breeding it
needs to pay for itself if we use the
current seed royalties we have a
thousand acres is something that
optimistically we would have in one of
those target growing regions that would
generate you about two thousand dollars
a year the university would take 1/3 of
that if you took your thousand acres and
convinced your growers that they
self-assess on the amount of grain
produced then you'd start seeing some
serious money or even some percentage
thereof so I think that if you want to
see this kind of breeding generator
revenue you're going to have to look for
some other funding model other than what
we currently have so with all that
Marley world is where we try to keep in
touch with the world please have a look
at us thanks to the many people who have
worked on the barley crew past and
present and brought to you by these
various funding agencies who have all
given us funding over the years without
restriction and all of our germ plasm
and data are in the public domain
if it is not in t3 it's only because we
just haven't gotten around to posting it
yet
thank you very much
[Applause]
for this
opportunity for disease susceptibility
in their sense
yeah
so the question was is there dis disease
issues by going to
so we are not a concern
so that is not something
so I don't want to say no
we have not seen in this usage
you do have to take extra care in
threshing and processing that green
condition breaks and you could ask the
question why the white was the Masada
barley returning opinion
they're expecting and they probably made
some dinner but they were also
indicated some advantages in rulership
modern support persistence
you get a mesh focus set up can that be
used with covered party or is basically
you know traditional setup works at
every
dependability say yes efficient was mesh
filtration they were being used widely
today in fact all with cover partners so
what it does is instead of making a kind
of course of course but if
you're also getting more out of a
textured and
instead of having that fine powder
feminine 10% and cellulose which isn't
getting anything it could be a hundred
or start
other question is
now Bali has three layers 72
is
usually sometimes people but you know
the question related to the structure
structure before they see the element
layers have an effect not be responsible
for the fact that it is the paper so I
would hazard a that's a good position
starting because it's not just the sheer
lovin that inside eternity to find
important is that higher included these
higher than amazed by her health
attendants perhaps but it's the balance
of course across plus
so do know that gene expression the
algorithm with signals from the interior
information accounts for one enzyme
activity
I can answer the question
it's very different to select dirty with
resistance like
some pliers another possibly exactly yes
oh yes and Skeet Ulrich who is the
reader in Washington State's now retired
started educational program to target
the same teens
the successful Cafferty is clearing at
work on and they are the processing
signals
so the question is that plus or minus in
the systems
the best solution also in Australia now
nice
in the northwest application they would
be Sonique
completion without the use of herbicides
particularly
Australia they needed an additional
website in order to do some people
unfortunately I guess that s where the
science is one which means rather than
all resistant so it's not
sustainable
alternative
so right now the challenge we've had so
practice time we convince a current
grower of barley cover garment focused
on first thing negative this is for the
market and so in fact the first phase of
this proposed project and putting
together would be to produce large semi
commercial nuts
so that those artisan and industrial
users can access and not be a party to
the commercial bolts the whistle gears
commercial foods and get those coming to
the marketplace it's not that
unfortunately I don't think it's just
the music system that's working
production
in western is not a penalty so the top
yielder and our breeding program
the last two years has been indeed and
so he was feeding the mr. Bartlett's
Wiggles and the halt accounts for about
ten percent
so how do you ever have a naked party
take anybody mystical and then how do
you make a I turned it into a naked yes
so naked part is how do you get naked
Marley so you're simply saying is
contain fat rasa in
everyone accelerate that process the
teens on other parts of seven days so
it's not some super chromatic region
there's no that I know like my other
jeans around it really carefully it's a
pretty quick conversion program
we've done some of those kinds of
projects and that's how we got the new
gene into
CRISPR probably not going to be
permitted by
since they need it's not just this kind
of real simple plug-and-play system in
this department but his team under the
pretty decent candidate because you
could completely find induced mutants
have been identified as specifically do
lead to a loss of function where the
scenes so we've got to be able to
you've got a collaborative experiment
ongoing just assuming it
related to this question so that when
you makin a tea party you oughta try to
above them that you said that didn't
good-looking that granny D is that
cursive letter time even the desert
entity divers currently they have so a
problem so in this unit but the
composite that I mentioned that then
forty parents
te or so those who are India parties
source from different Greek programs
around so Eastwood fingers crossed then
we have diversity and other positions in
the genome recording to include them all
we are kind of monophyletic in there's
probably a single origin that that
original mutation that led to the
deletion routine so there could be
things right in the vicinity
and so that's where a couple of quick
speeds are in a basket or at 70 Jill
another turn pleasant to see what the
parties were hiding random useful
discriminatory mechanisms
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at Cornell edu