this is a production of Cornell
University thank you very much for the
intro and for the welcome I'm happy to
be here um and partly because I've been
kind of a sap about uh being back on
campus after quite a few years and um
yeah it's it's beautiful to be here um
so you know originally I came to study
uh mechanical and aerospace engineering
and I was hoping to study under Carl
Sean but uh that didn't work out uh
exactly and then um but I did get to
work with Steve Squire and space
Sciences on some of the early Mars Mars
Rover development work there and uh so
uh then so coming from that you know
Aerospace robotics angle ended up
working on all these tools it had to do
with soils and rocks uh like the
grinding tool on the Mars rover spirit
and opportunity I got to help design and
build that and and operate it uh when it
was on Mars uh it actually one of them
still working on Mars now um and that
was all because of the Cornell
connections here and um and then after a
while I thought uh so I was at a private
company where we built that for the the
Rover missions uh called honeybee
robotics in New York City then after a
while I thought it'd be nice to maybe
take a break from all that uh rocks and
dirt uh basically you know and I figured
I'd go to Carnegie melon to do robotics
robotic vehicle development work and uh
my adviser told me you know once I was
there you know about this it's exciting
Mars you know like a lunar rover project
to De develop a new lunar rover and then
he told me what the task was it was to
to support drilling down into the soils
um so uh I started to wonder if this was
a thread in my career that I was kind of
inescapable uh and
then uh later ended up um here now at
this near Earth autonomy which is a
spin-off company from Carnegie melon uh
from the field robotic Center and um now
you know my major project at the moment
is this agriculture project and so we
end up with a lot of this data where
we're making these aerial observations
on on the crops and and of the soils so
the the thread continues and um I'm
embracing it I think I it's great to be
in the field I think um the other more
uh the more important threat I think is
that uh I've enjoyed getting to work on
systems that are collecting data for
some scientists to make progress um in
their areas so um the this Terra program
uh is has been a great project for us in
our company to get deeper into the the
support of Agriculture um uh from an
aerial sensing kind of
angle um so I think just to give you bit
more of a just a picture of uh what
we're doing this teror program is you
know it's led by Steve C he's the pi on
our project at Clemson um we are the
team providing the aerial data
collection and some of the analysis from
there there's also a team at um at
Carnegie melon doing ground Vehicles so
that robotic uh Vehicles driving through
the crops uh collecting data up close to
the crops um so combining these these
data collection platforms uh uh outputs
and um learning more about ways to
accelerate the breeding process so this
is one of the fields there these um
these exquisitely planted fields in
South Carolina outside of Clemson uh
seeing hundreds of of varieties of
energy sorghum in this one two acre
field and so we're you know while at
this point I think one of the ground
Vehicles was driving uh making
observations um on the ground while
we're flying over
um and I hope the two screens doesn't
make anyone uh MO
sick um even one screen might be enough
um so you can see a lot of variation in
the in the fields you know this is
definitely not a typical farm right when
you're looking at breeding plots um they
there are a lot of different uh traits
in these different varieties um this is
early this is a first year out of three
for this project um so we're we're
starting to we're looking at some of the
uh early refinements of the breeding and
um and refinements of the the data
collection
techniques um so they have two fields in
South Carolina one's in uh is right
outside of Clemson and the other is in
in Florence uh so it's more this you can
see this like reddish clay soil um and
uh the Florence side is more coastal
plains very Sandy um so it's nice to be
working the two different conditions um
so down for a landing so just for a
little bit of background on on the
company I'm at now it's we're about 40
people it's about four years old uh
we're a spin-off from carnegy melon
field robotics Center uh you can think
of us as kind of this uh the convergence
of the standard Aviation where you know
just basically uh flying it's it's good
technology of course but it's fairly
simple navigation usually flying
waypoints straight straight flight
fairly straightforward um converging
that with more of all the kind of
intelligence that you're seeing more and
more on driverless cars uh the Fiel
robotic Center is actually a place that
that uh put out a lot of the people who
are at now at at Uber and at Google
developing these drivers's cars that
came out of this the DARPA Grand
challenges um for for these vehicles so
um so our group is a lot of researchers
that came from from that area and uh so
we're converging into this this kind of
this near thought autonomy so basically
the the company began where it's more
focused on the navigation helping
aircraft fly on their own down near the
ground where it's
difficult uh so we work in in the field
a lot you know we work on a lot of
different you know sizes of helicopters
um this is kind of a cool shot flying up
over Pittsburgh um one of the seeing one
of the rivers and downtown um this is
actually an autonomous flight with a
fulls scale helicopter there in the
upper left uh and you know fly in a lot
of different conditions even out we're
flying out over Lake Erie lately uh
helping a helicopter land onto a onto a
barge uh to show that we could operate
from ships so yeah we work with full
scale helicopters um and also kind of
getting into the more and more where I'm
focusing on the mapping and inspection
kind of work is is in these uh the
smaller kind of the 50 lbs and less kind
of the um the that kind of category of
aircraft with their um you know like
these quadcopters and hexacopters that
kind of stuff now they're the technolog
is really improving they're easier to
use and now their the FAA is allowed
them to be used commercially um uh more
and more so it's all it's all working
together to become actually available
and so that's kind of the where we're
working in uh for our agricultur work so
far so as a company we're working a lot
in navigation uh and mapping and
inspection those kind of the three kind
of categories
um I think we have kind of in our in our
genes as a company um this you know
history in agriculture there was a
fairly big project USDA funded uh years
ago where some of the founders were uh
were working on um with specialty crops
uh this is all ground vehicle based um
but making observations in the field
with specialty crops and uh with
nurseries and and Landscape industry
um and so that's actually the
connections I think with with Marcel uh
to
Steve um and so now our current work is
um we're focused on this accelerated
plant breeding uh using the aerial
reconnaissance essentially to help the
breeding process and also uh trying to
spin that off into more of farm
management uh helping Growers um and so
you could see you could imagine we're
we're kind of working with the kind of
early adopters at this point kind of
breeding groups that are that are fairly
high-tech um think of them you know who
function that way uh and also some of
the maybe uh larger Growers that would
be open to adopting this kind of stuff
early mostly we working with with energy
sorghum uh but we're also looking some
at Maze and uh and
grapes um so this boost is our our team
it's our project under the Terra program
there there are six different Terra
projects um and so it's it's the
department of Energy's u arpa e it's
like it's there their DARPA for energy
applications uh and so I think it's a
fantastic program um the goal for Tera
as a whole is um to support you know to
basically accelerate uh to this breeding
process to get this really good
potential of of energy sorghum as a
sustainable biofuel Source um and also
along the way develop new techniques for
for breeding for Accelerated breeding
for and and looking at high throughput
phenotyping in the field as the as the
main kind of method for that so we're
looking into you're basically trying to
support this development of predictive
algorithms you know you get data early
in a growing season and predict the the
the you know Harvest kind of results U
be able to assess a variety really early
um and then just get get more these
detailed measurements of the the plant
physiology and uh then focusing a lot on
the data analytics and connecting the
the the genotypes to phenotypes that
kind of mapping
um so I don't know if this this might
give you motion sickness too potentially
but it's we're trying you can imagine
that we're this first theme we're
essentially developing these pH
phenotyping hardware systems getting
them into the field so that they can
collect data um both on the ground and
in the air uh taking these results and
putting them in through an analysis
pipeline including machine learning
techniques uh and then uh doing this
phenotype to genotype mapping um and
feeding that all back into the field so
that we you know we have three growing
Seasons to work so this cycle uh goes uh
throughout the
project um so just thinking about our
activity in the field for this program
we've got um these ground Vehicles by
that carneg melon are making um they're
driving through the roads uh getting uh
doing able to do this close proximity
kind of sensing you know you're you're
right up against the plants they're
doing stereo vision lar other sensor
types um then they're also doing things
that are contact sensing which I think
is pretty novel um where they're
actually interacting physically with the
plant um you know measuring uh one thing
they're focusing on right now is a
penetrometer testing on the strength of
the stocks so it actually has a gripper
that visually you know automatically
finds a stock grabs it and does a
penetrometer test um and as it goes
through the rows and then um there's
also a sensing Network for environmental
uh characteristics on the ground and
then we the we're the team that's doing
that the aerial sensing um so yeah we're
we've got this uh this aircraft flying
overhead you know 40 to 60 ft kind of
above the ground um doing mapping of the
whole field um with a custom sensor
package so that's that's the bulk of our
work is developing this custom sensor
package we don't develop the aircraft we
don't develop sensors we we choose
aircraft for the for the purpose and we
choose the sensors for the purpose and
integrate uh and then work with that
data make sure the data can be fused
well it's registered well spatially it's
calibrated well in terms of
energetics uh and bring that data
together and make it make it useful so
this is a picture of our um our first
sensor package for this project um it
ended up kind of looking like a micro
satellite or something this is about six
or seven pounds you you could hold it in
your hands like this um and it it rides
on board the aircraft and is completely
self-contained black box like you
essentially like a very tricked out
GoPro you know you hit start it records
from all of its six
sensors and then uh also simultaneously
um it uh is estimating its position and
and orientation in the world as it goes
so that way we're not just taking it's
not just flying over with a camera and
then stitching together imagery later
that's fairly straightforward um it's
actually uh it estimates the where the
sensor package is and how it's how it's
pointing so that you can uh pull
together uh really explicitly mapped uh
so every pixel you know exactly where it
hits on the ground um and so you can
make this very accurate uh very accurate
Maps um thre dimensionally in some
cases so
um these are the aircraft we're working
with uh this is a a 35 lb uh electric
autonomous helicopter on the left um and
then this is a similar weight um there's
a hexacopter that we're using now um so
we're kind of showing both you know
they're different categories in terms of
cost and uh complexity um and also
performance in some ways the helicopter
can get a lot more coverage over larger
Fields faster flying more wind
conditions um but the hexacopter is
really easy to use uh uh um and so you
know we're I think most of the time
we'll be operating from that but
um so we we Tred to start kind of from
you know first principles in a way on
deciding what was going to be in that
sensor package um
so we ended up uh going through that
that process ended up with these uh four
sensing modes um so one for to try to
get at the shape of the crops uh kind
geometric properties we're experimenting
with Lar so it's you know it's laser
scanner there that that disc kind of
Puck shaped h in the front um so it's
scanning across the ground with with uh
infrared laser points and building up a
3D Cloud um and then to get at kind of
color properties and and also geometric
properties uh we're using visible
Imaging just standard RGB Imaging uh to
to look at temperature related
properties and uh some stress uh plant
stress using the thermal infrared so
that's just monochromatic long wave
infrared and then uh to be a little more
ambitious uh we also added in
hyperspectral camera so um you know with
typical camera you think of color it's
three three bands right red green blue
the you could think of them as three
separate layers um if you really look at
the sensor on a color camera it's
actually red green blue and then another
green it's a pattern of four for every
thing if you think of as one pixel uh
and so so you know you're getting those
three uh separate bands for hypers
spectral we're using a camera that has
100 spectral bands and they're all
they're not overlapping at all they're
all separate uh very narrow bands uh
they're and it's cutting across the kind
of uh red end visible and up into the
near infrared through pretty far into
the near infrared so um there's going to
be I think there we're taking a lot of
inspiration from the remote sensing
approaches uh from you know satellite uh
where they they have all these um
interesting indices where they'll
they'll say this spectral band ratioed
with this spectral band uh ends up
correlating really well with this kind
of plant property and so uh and so there
we're thinking that through this whole
combination hypers Spectrum particular I
think we're going to get to explore and
look for these properties these
predictive things these uh correlations
to plant properties and um and be able
to I think we'll learn quite a bit and
then also get to do a second generation
in the second year year of this payload
where of the sensor Suite where it'll be
more refined and uh and a bit a bit
cheaper too uh so be closer to being
commercialized so here's a shot of us um
it's in the field this is the sandier
site there um uh in South Carolina uh
and there's the sensor package Riding
Down Below on one of the multi-rotor
copter so it's pretty straightforward it
takes just a couple people to operate in
the field takes off and um and collects
data all along lands we uh here's a shot
of us
um I think it was last month
[Music]
I would lower the volume but I don't
know
how I
tried um so you can see it's just it
takes off uh it's really simple to
operate this thing even though it's it's
a pretty serious aircraft in a way I
mean it's still you you have to be very
careful we're following all the fa
regulations we have registered Pilots
like the guy who's actually piloting
this he manually made it takeoff and
then flipped it into autonomous mode for
it to do its kind of simple lawn kind of
pattern over the crops U but he he used
to fly Apache helicopters for a long
time in um South Korea
so that's him there Spencer so he's kind
of unfaced by this stuff
luckily um
[Music]
so yeah the the flying portions is easy
you know it's just just as long as you
follow all the right procedures and keep
everything legal and safe it's all very
straightforward stuff it's not novel
technology there it's off the shelf um
but so it all the all our focus is in
the uh in making the sensor Suite
correct and uh making the data
worthwhile so here's just um series of
frames just of what this so it's all
straight down looking cameras um this is
just some of the visible data from you
know from the RGB
camera um and then just an example of
what some of that looks like once you uh
start to build these orthographic maps
from from the imagery to get a sense of
uh kind of resolutions we're getting
this was flying a little on the high
side about 60 ft above ground level um I
was showing Steve some of the the Weeds
on this shot um and then just you know
better sense zooming in so you're
getting many pixels across a leaf you
know that kind of a spatial resolution
uh seeing color variation seeing texture
in the Pentacles of these uh these sorum
plants U most of the time we're flying
over energy sorum so the Pentacles
aren't there uh but um in some cases we
are you're also seeing uh you we will be
able to be pulling out information about
the leaf geometries we're also seeing
some lodging here as an example I think
that's something we could probably pull
out um a
automatically
um and so then uh another data product
is this the lar data so this is this
point Cloud that we get this isn't
cleaned up or anything it's just
basically what it sees as it's flying um
and so it's just a a real 3D model it's
like flying around in a in a strange
video game afterwards right you just um
it's you can actually take measurements
between points um you can so you're
essentially able to just after the fact
go through and measure uh geometric
properties um so uh so later you get
this this 3D model that you can you know
spin around um map in different ways uh
process in different ways and get the 3D
information so those are some Vans
vehicles and Tents uh here in that big
open
aisle and so you're seeing a lot of the
color variation is it's it's a color
scale is applied just to visualize the
differences in Heights so it's it's like
a heat map for uh for height so you're
seeing all the you know a lot of these
plots you clearly are different
varieties um and so you're seeing fair
amount of variation in the in the height
by
plot um that's actually uh one of the
the pherotype that we're focusing on
these last couple weeks is is cleaning
up a uh a way to produce um a good
measurement of plant height uh averaged
out by plot um so this data kind of
lends itself to that to be able to know
what your kind of characteristic height
is for each plot and the amount of
variation in height in that plot um and
getting more and more appreciation for
how it sounds easy but isn't easy you
know just the idea of I I heard the
story of Steve covich told us the story
of a group with um there were I think
maybe six um pretty uh respected you
know faculty members on this one program
NSF program and uh multiple of them were
in the National Academy of Sciences and
it took them months to argue out how to
measure the height of the plant and um
now I understand that a little bit
better uh the idea of you know if it has
a panicle or not does that influence
your height measurement is the leaf is a
leaf pointing up or down does that mean
the plant is a different height um is it
is the wind blowing things
uh you know what's your me what's your
standard method how a person would do it
versus what can you actually do from
from the air
so um this is I think we're you know
getting more and more appreciation for
uh for some of these things with the
sensitivities um so here's just a just
another shot of the the light R Point
Cloud these are the the Vans there in
the in the top for scale
um so as we fly we're registering the
data using GPS and inertial sensing um
within the payload it's completely
separate it just is along for the ride
on the aircraft it's not Interactive
with the uh the aircraft controls U
we're also experimenting with um uh
Targets on the ground to help uh tighten
up the spatial registration even more on
the calibration there's um you know we
work to some extent with what the
manufacturers give us as far as man the
calibration of cameras but then um we're
also doing our own quite a bit in some
ways we're redoing and improving things
that the manufacturers do uh especially
for the energetics um on like the
hyperspectral camera uh we're doing
things where we
give different light source inputs um
put and then so doing lab calibration
then also field calibration laying out
tarps in the field um taking off and
Landing from a a calibration Target more
or less uh and then we're experimenting
some with the um uh with shadowing too
the intent there is just to make sure
that the data has is closely tied to the
real physics of the plant There's real
plant properties and aren't influenced
by Too Much by the changes in in in
lighting conditions which can be pretty
significant it would be like you know
like if you with photography right if
you're messing around with uh different
white balances you can imagine it being
very different and that's just trying to
make things look appropriate if you're
trying to make physical deductions then
uh it's even more
important so um with our our analytics
kind of support uh We've we've got these
kind foundational things um ways of
modeling what the ground shape is and
segmenting into plots and annotating
things um producing these raw data
products like just you know just the
standard things that are collected right
off the camera um and then these reduced
products these you know image Maps uh 3D
models uh and then these more of derived
data products is where we're starting to
put more focus into now things where
it's like like phenotypes you know plant
traits Trends in these plant traits um
and then uh we'll be supporting the the
rest of the team uh at Clemson where
Steve covich's team is and um the Dan
forth Center where where they'll both be
doing uh a lot of the the effort of
making correlations between um the
phenotypes and and genotypes and feeding
that into the breeding
process
um so I think
I yeah I describe those fairly well I
think just to get a sense of some of the
other um phenotypes we're going after
things like show you know observing
being able to map out when when
emergence happens where um across the
field uh measuring the plant height per
plot uh and then um that how that
changes over time whether or not there's
a
panicle uh so the uh and things like
canopy closure Leaf area index um
lodging you know if the plants have
fallen over just other geometric types
of things uh other stress like water
stress or nitrogen stress or Leaf
necrosis um and uh anything we can learn
about you know the photosynthetic
activity I think from our hyperspectral
uh camera we hope to be able to pick
that up pretty well um and other
hyperspectral indices that could maybe
have novel correlations that will'll
find in this
project um so in the end I think you
know once these become more refined um
you know the hope is that we're giving
advice to breeders um uh feeding into
their their analysis chains um and
advice for for Growers too um you know
how to how to better manage their their
fields um and so that they're they're
not just given you know like say on
earlier this week we had our people were
in the field in South Carolina they came
back with 1.3 terabytes and they only
flew I think six times and so you know a
grower doesn't want that you know that
might a lot of us you know just be kind
of Blown Away by that it's just not
useful um I think Steve and I were
talking you know they're busy already
you know they're not looking for a a
boring hobby on top of their job so um
we're we're trying to refine this
software process so that they're given
something that's more like actionable
intelligence to use U ter from that
World um so it's just basically what do
I do give me advice
um and so the rpu program Tera is really
consciously pushing us to think about
commercialization um we've kind of
identified a lot of different potential
ways that that things could go we could
transition this technology to Market um
in the end um you know we're collecting
a huge amount of just of data in the
field I think that could be valuable
just the straight data um the anal
analysis algorithms uh could potentially
be licensable um the the vehicles and
the sensing packages uh and then also
you can imagine the whole integrated
phenotyping system of ground and Air and
Analysis um and then I think we could
very well make significant progress um
on actual you know new more refined
varieties of energy sorum throughout
this
project so I think uh looking ahead a
bit um we're hoping to you know extend
the work uh onto other Target crops you
know a lot of our sensor approaches and
Analysis approaches aren't um you know
completely specialized to energy sorum
you know they could easily be applied to
other other crop types um or you know
even other other areas um uh uh Beyond
specific crops um like surveying for um
you know disease in in natural uh you
know in trees um that's something that
has been coming up in in Pennsylvania
area lately in discussions um so we're
hoping we're trying to line up more
field trials with uh kind of large farms
and um smaller Innovative Farms we've
got people in the area you know like
Pittsburgh is such a you know robotics
kind of uh Mecca that you know we get
lucky that there's you know a farmer in
the outside of town who's just supports
our work so we get to operate there a
lot work with his on his crops um and so
it's a nice example of that we're going
to be doing some breeding trials um in
Australia and trying to find a way to
stay active during the the winter here
uh so that we'll be
there in uh outside of Melbourne um this
winter so um I think some good
potentials there and then uh so this is
a three-year program uh with terara uh
and so we're hoping to continue that too
there's some potential there once some
if some uh funding matching happens uh
so that could continue the work make it
more refined uh maybe taking some
different different directions
so um yeah I think it'd be be great to
have if anybody had any questions uh be
happy to answer
those thank you very much Paul for
offering uh any questions I have a
question uh I noticed on the uh the fly
flyover that you showed us it was a
overcast day does it matter do you
prefer overcast versus sunny or um
better yeah I overcast is nice actually
it's uh ends up with much more diffused
light less shadowing um yeah it's kind
of like I guess like doing photography
it's counterintuitive um maybe um but
yeah yeah um we don't really we're
trying to just get the the processes
right so that we can deal with either
conditions you know with u but but
shadowing is is hard to work with you
know uh the idea if you want to see down
into the into the crops not just the top
layer um then it gets tricky it can it
can muddy things for sure um just you
know but dynamic range issues you know
that like a very well lit um leaves in
portions of the plant in some part of
the scene and then very low Lighting on
other portions it's hard to get useful
data across the whole range
yeah you do the you get a sense of the
instrument package you're fing over do
you are you able to focus on particular
quite small parts get data from those
for example exclud soil for example
right yeah so as far as the data
collection goes we are just covering the
entire field and um and we do it from
two different directions so we'll we'll
cover it say like east to west and then
go back again north to south um and so
you get um a fair amount of you get very
complete coverage and then you get a
fair amount of uh kind of penetrating
observations like down through
especially you know early in midseason
uh down to the soils and lower portions
of the plants um and then yeah with the
analysis um I think separating out soils
from from plant material is is a fairly
I think pretty straightforward uh thing
that we'll be we'll be doing soon um and
then I it's it's hard to say how far
we'll get to go with breaking out uh
automat in an automated automated sort
of way um different portions of the
plant but um My Hope Is that we could at
least pick out panicle and leaves
separate of the rest of the scene
your thermal
iming
temperature so how would you do that one
instrument way do you use right uh yeah
so that's a um it's a it's fairly low
resolution you know it's an imager from
Fleer uh company called Fleer it's so
it's um it's about 640 uh pixels across
um and it's so that's just because of
the State ofthe art you know with color
Imaging you can we have a 12 megapixel
camera on board bo uh but this was a you
know 1 megapixel camera just cuz that's
kind of the top of what's available
right now um and luckily a lot of the
thermal thermal properties in the field
are are fairly coarse spatially speaking
they're fairly coarse things so um I
think it it's still useful um and so I
think early on it might you know say
early in the season it might be a little
bit muddy where you know pixels are uh
overlapping a lot with you know some
it'll be half landing on a leaf and half
on soil but um later on once the canopy
starts to close I think it'll be
um pretty clean uh sensing of of canopy
kind of thermal emission
guess primary yeah primary yeah I think
we might get to see some in the
hyperspectral too um but I we're hoping
to see the stress mostly in the thermal
yeah
we are planning for about once every
four weeks um we we're also on the hook
to show that we could operate more than
one time a day you know B do full
coverage of of a fairly large field like
a five hectare field uh twice per day so
that's that's more of a demonstrate to
arpa that we can do that kind of
coverage but the the the real field you
know trips will be there once
essentially once per month um it's it's
a bit of I think at some point the you
know it would just be so close together
that there wouldn't be much value um but
uh so that's you know it was kind of
roughly chosen um that we should be able
to see quite a bit of change uh in in
four weeks um and but you know I think
later in the maybe the third season
we're hoping to just uh keep the system
keep keep the the aircraft down there at
the field and it could be operated more
frequently than that so yeah we could
experiment some to see if there's more
utility and more frequent trips
yeah do you
have right yeah completely and we I
think I'm hoping to talk more about some
soil potential it' be nice to hear hear
some advice for me on that I think it's
um you know especially when it's large
large areas to to survey it's you know
the aerial approach is seems really good
for that um and um yeah so I think
there's there's a good potential there
and then um yeah we've had some first
conversations with some people about
some of the pests uh Pest Management and
um so yeah I think it could be I think a
lot of ways I would see we' maybe be
observing I think some of we've seen on
the ground you know actually the ground
vehicle from is actually seeing aphids
in the images you know actually picking
out things able to recognize them um but
uh from us from the aerial point of view
we probably see more of the the effect
on the plant which so be slightly
indirect but still I think uh
valuable what
aspects uh we haven't actually been um
considering it in depth yet I think it's
I think there's a lot there's good
potential for it but um you know we
there this you know I think just if to
see changes you know seeing motion of
soil you know if there's um the the 3D
data is so good you know from our lar
that I think if you're able to see um
any redistributions of soil I think that
could be really good for picking that
out over time um we've done stuff where
you could see small changes in a scene
just you know from one flight to the
next that kind of thing um but then also
with the you know picking out things
like color and thermal and um
hyperspectral you might be able to see
other processes that are going on in the
soils so
yeah it'd be nice to hear advice on that
yeah
yeah that's that's a good question we
yeah you're right we've been focusing on
just this one you know all these
different varieties of of sorghum and um
it's more our Focus has been more about
yeah the kind of basic traits uh but um
yeah I think actually Steve and I were
talking this morning a little bit about
trying to differentiate you know crops
from weeds and so I think uh we were
talking about different methods for that
I think um from this you know high
resolution Vis uh camera you know you
know just visible data um we could get
at some of the geometric properties you
know say some Char some characteristics
they're pretty reliable like the shape
of the leaf um or the way the leaves are
are uh are branching um that sort of
thing could be a pretty reliable way to
to differentiate between plant types and
then also I think the spectral
signatures could be potential on that so
where um you know just something a
pretty a good correlation say you know
something in you know has some kind of
spectral signature in the infrared maybe
in the near infrared that um say corn to
sorghum is very different so um yeah
it's something we haven't done but it I
bet these these types of sensors could
could maybe do it
though
thanks kind of following up on question
about timing I you might
consider for your stress and
measurements you might have to think
about doing more
yeah yeah yeah you of day you want
optim differ yeah that's
nice yeah I think um so I guess yeah
saying once that's it's good advice I
think we've been going going to the site
once per month but like say this week
for instance we had um we had some
flights uh kind of late afternoon on one
day and then kind of uh earlier morning
I guess it was more midday the next day
so uh temperatures and lighting
conditions were different um but still
you know the the state of the crops was
essentially the same so um yeah that's
that's probably yeah you're right that's
something that would be probably good
practice Yeah thinking about
commercialization for for Growers that
use
this how would you imagine that would be
licensing the software and having
someone come in with the hardware or
selling the hardware how do you envision
that working in the fure
and maybe you have any idea what would
you think the ball park amount would
cost somebody to do right later on all
right sure yeah well we're actually
we're trying to work on kind of three
different you know business models
really um you know the from our
company's point of view um you the I
think licensing the software uh is
probably the you know the the quickest
and easiest way uh to Market um but um
you know selling an integrated Hardware
package you know where it's the whole
thing basically the aircraft and the
payload or or selling just the the
sensor payload um those are very viable
too um you know
the most of the I think it's really hard
to
get to get much revenue from or to get
much profit I guess from just selling
Hardware packages really um but uh it's
use selling it more as a service I think
could be actually better in a lot of
ways because a lot of uh the end users
don't really necessarily want to get
into operating these things or dealing
with owning them maintaining them and
all that but they they like the data so
um just for them to hire a service to
come in and collect the data and give
them the data is probably a really nice
model um I think in that case we
probably our company wouldn't we would
be the technology developers and owners
of the intellectual property but another
service providing firm would probably do
that um so that that's those are
probably the licensing and the servicing
probably the two models that are um
probably the most likely to work out
well and then um as far as costs you
know we you know on the aircraft side of
things it's you know that that
helicopter we're working with is
something like you know $660,000
uh then the the smaller one the the not
really smaller but the the hexacopter
one is uh is more uh you know it's more
of a standard product now it's more you
know commercially available um broadly
from the DJI uh that one's about
$155,000 if you get for all the all the
hardware needed so that's a lot more
attainable uh for people and then uh
especially you know Growers um and then
the sensor package we're looking to get
that down from uh you know like a a very
ambitious you know the one you know
we're working with now is something like
75k for just the hardware right not the
labor to build it or get it running but
then second generation we're going to
bring that down um probably you know
more like 40, 000 in hardware and then a
commercialized version of that um down
uh even further maybe uh hopefully more
like
25 so um or maybe even lower you know
with numbers you know at with
manufacturing scale that could could go
even
lower
so well uh Paul has uh told me that that
he does maybe have a few slots open on
his afternoon schedule so
some of you would like to have a a
longer conversation with him uh you
could come up and maybe schedule that
with him have time available yeah that'
be great any any advice or questions
that'd be great and we really appreciate
your coming thank you once
[Applause]
again this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu