this is a production of Cornell
University today thanks everyone I
really appreciate the invitation to talk
with you today what I'd like to focus on
is mitigating Wildlife damage and
cropping systems and I'll talk about
some basic principles of wildlife damage
management whether you're dealing with
birds or mammals uh I also want to go
through results of a survey uh we did a
few years ago to give you a sense of the
magnitude of the impacts that deer and
other wildlife caus in New York State uh
so we'll dive right into it I think
Dennis slate summarized integrated
Wildlife damage management pretty
clearly at a conference several years
ago and it comes down to a very simple
process you can kill them you can scare
them you can put up a barrier or you can
spray a chemical that may or may not
work and that's integrated Wildlife
damage management now we can all go home
so but it's really you don't have a lot
of options when you're dealing with most
of these Critters and they can cause
significant economic impacts there are
some keys I've seen over the years in
multiple species multiple cropping
system uh that tend to lead to success
in an integrated Wildlife Management
program first most important is timing
knowing when and where the damage is
going to occur and making sure you get
up your control strategies whatever you
choose to use out in a timely fashion
before the damage gets too severe once
Wildlife develop a feeding habit it's
really difficult to break that but if
you can sort of know that hey my
blueberries are starting to get uh
turnning color the sugar contents going
up I better get my netting on now before
those birds start feeding uh you can
have more success diversity is important
you got to know what different tools and
techniques are out there and sometime
combining tools work sometimes it
doesn't I'll share some data with you
about that persistence is really
important this is not something you do
once and walk away from to be successful
most of the uh tools and techniques we
have require continues often daily
attention in some cases to moving things
around filling gas generators to make
sure you've got electrical power uh to
electrical powered unit or making sure
your batteries are up on your solar
powered units and then monitoring you
got to know what's working when and
where and as what I'm paying for
wildlife control benefiting me is it
worth it a lot of times particularly
some bird data I'll show you uh later on
it probably doesn't pay for what most of
the Growers are doing for bird control
except in certain uh conditions where
you've got low crop
yields most Wildlife leaves sign to the
Presidents off often easy to identify
who the culprit is like for example you
can see the deer tracks up where in the
corners or deer damaged uh apple trees
or Nursery crops are really easy to
identify uh because deer have lower and
sizeer an upper hard pallet they don't
have upper and lower sizing like rodents
so they don't leave a clean bite when
they bite on something they leave this
ragged torn Edge so it's usually pretty
easy to identify deer damage versus
rodent
damage I mentioned the survey uh deer
damage to agriculture in New York state
I uh partnered with Tommy Brown and Dan
Decker folks with the experiment station
Farm Bureau a few years ago and we
wanted to estimate deer damage by crop
type in region we wanted to look at how
Growers were using uh DEC deer damage
permits that are available to help them
alleviate crop damage and we wanted to
compare what the magnitude of deer
damage is versus other Wildlife damage
that they're seeing on their Farms
across the state so we used the database
uh Farms maintained by EG markets uh New
York egg statistics service and
developed and implemented a male
questionnaire uh to
3,99 Farms across New York State uh we
targeted 500 per agricultural region we
ended up with 909 because there weren't
500 Farms on Long Island there were only
uh so we hit all the farms on Long
Island our sample pool was
2,497 Farms across the state and uh to
meet our criteria a farm had to have at
least $1,000 in reported sales and we
included all Farms that were not
exclusively like Bees and Honey
aquaculture in other words you had to
have a a field crop growing of some type
that Wildlife like deer could
potentially
damage we got a fantastic response rate
uh compared to most male surveys
nowadays with about a 50% response rate
we got 1927 questionaires return so we
think we've got really uh good data at
least old data what the impacts were uh
we also followed up with a phone call to
100 uh nonrespondents to look at uh did
their damage differ at all from those
50% of people who returned the surveys
and we found that by far the
non-respondents had less damage and
smaller acreages of farm so uh based on
a formula we down uh uh adjusted the raw
damage reports by
31.5% that account for the uh
non-respondent bias in the survey data
so again these are probably relatively
good statistics given the sample size
that we've
got probably familiar with all the New
York State egg regions in New York state
I'm going to show you a few tables and
so data are broken down by agricultural
region and you'll see there's some
patterns that
emerg terms of total number of farms and
sales again from that pool of
25,500 farms roughly 60% of the Farms
reported values in sales between 10 and
250,000 uh no big surprise there what
was interesting uh you look at the
proportion of farms that reported more
than
$250,000 in sales the highest percentage
by far was on Long Island with one in
five Farms reporting more than 250,000
in sales and the lowest percentage was
in the Southern Tier with only 8% of
farmers reporting more than 250,000
sales and the big farming regions are
Western New York uh Southern Tian
Central New York again no big surprise
there we looked at total estimated
damage uh by deer that was reported by
The Growers ended up being almost $59
million a year Statewide so we're
talking about a fairly substantial
economic impact to the the farm industry
in New York state by far uh in terms of
acreage and reported damage uh 23% of
that total was uh in Grain crops or 13.6
million in losses if you look combine Al
alfha and other hay crops you've got
another 24% another $4.5 million in
losses so if you take grain and hay crop
you're looking about half the total
damage in the state come from those
three crops so it's again a significant
economic impact for those farmers and
then you can even get down to the
specialty crops things like grapes and
berries are still you know1 to2 million
a year in losses from
Wildlife we look at it regionally break
down the statistics by Far Western New
York has the highest uh amount of damage
with over 20 million and then lower
Hudson Valley uh Southeastern New York
has the second highest percent loss with
a little over 145 million and again
those are our primary agricultural
regions in the state with some of the
better quality soils lot lots of farms
lots of uh cropping systems
there trying to relate that back to Deer
density it's a you got to take this a
little bit with a grain of salt but
generally in Western New York where the
highest damage is you see the highest
deer take uh a lot of these uh Wildlife
Management units are averaging nine to
16 deer taken per uh square mile in the
wildlife management unit so you got very
high deer densities here that overlap
with high crop densities and valuable
crops doesn't hold quite as true in
lower Hudson Valley a little bit lower
Harvest rate but the issue in the lower
Hudson Valley is you've got a lot of
suburban development even though there's
a pile of deer there and there's fair
amount of damage occurring a lot of
those deer aren't accessible to Hunters
because of suburban sprawl and Suburban
development so average deer take per
square mile lower but that doesn't mean
there's necessarily fewer deer there and
then not surprising the lowest deer
densities in the state or in the adarac
Eco region and so you tend to see more
lower levels of deer damage in Northern
New York because you're generally there
you're just you know maybe averaging uh
less than 10 deer per square mile in
some areas up
there we asked Growers on the survey uh
what species were what are the top three
species on your farm that are
responsible for wildlife damage and how
much is it costing you and 83% of The
Growers across the state listed deer in
their top three species and we
attributed almost half of the total
Wildlife damage damage that occurs
Statewide caused by deer so hence we put
a lot of focus on deer and deer
management in our program 30% of Growers
listed turkeys about 15% of the damage
was related to turkeys 21% listed geese
20 groundhog 15% raccoon so this sort of
The Hit List these are the species that
are responsible for most of the damage
in agricultural situation at list of
turkeys and geese specifically I'll talk
a bit more about birds in general in
sort of the second half of the
presentation so what does Department of
Environmental Conservation do they've
got responsibility and Authority for
deer management across New York State
unfortunately most of the laws and
regulations are written for managing
deer at broadscale landscape scale at
the state level or the wildlife
management unit that's Deer tags go tags
are issued based on an estimated number
of deer in a specific Wildlife
Management unit when it gets down to
farm level impact there's really only
two things that land owners have
available the deer management assistance
program and deer damage permits and
those are designed to be land owner run
programs and I'll talk a bit more about
each of those but uh by far and way most
of the effort in the state is at this
level which really may not help Growers
that are down at the individual property
level we ask Growers well do you allow
hunting on your farm and what type of
hunting do you allow and not no big
surprise 83% of Growers across state do
allow deer hunting on their Farm but uh
2/3 to 3/4 only allow family friends and
neighbors that they know that's been
very consistent in many state surveys
that people don't like strangers on
their property they want somebody that
they know and they trust if they're
hunting deer and that may not those
folks may not take enough deer to have
any real impact on crop damage only 30%
of farmers allow strangers to hunt uh
for the 177% of Growers that don't
provide any hunting access they cite a
problem with liability and past Hunter
Behavior most Farms don't restrict sex
of take of the deer taken and that's a
issue I think we've got for Education if
you're going to have impact on crop
damage if you're going to reduce deer
density you really got to harvest a lot
of female deer that's the growth
potential of the herd if you don't take
female deer and you just shoot buck that
herd's going to continue to grow because
the the do's are the ones that are
producing The Fawns every year only
about 9% of Growers require that some do
be taken on their farm and um opposite
that 6% of Growers only allow bucks
taken they don't want you to shoot do
which doesn't do a thing to help with
crop
damage we ask Growers are you aware of
the deer management assistance program
DEC has and have you ever used those
type of permits the way the deer
management assistance program works is a
farm land owners uh fill out an
application with DEC usually in
September and then DEC gives the land
owner additional dough tags antlerless
Deer tags for use by hunters on their
Farm during the regular open hunting
season so what they're doing is
encouraging Hunters to come on the farm
take more female deer hopefully reduce
population growth and hopefully
consequently deer damage only 31% of
Growers who one responded to our survey
were even aware that this program
existed and uh but of those that applied
for permits uh on average they got 7 and
a half permits per farm and killed 5.6
deer farm so again those folks that get
the permits do pretty well at filling
them and uh you'll see that Growers feel
that these do help some alleviating
damage the other type of permits what's
called a deer damage permits Growers
were more familiar with deer damage
permits 2third a day had heard of them
but only 12% applied for them uh deer
damage permits allow for a grower to
kill deer usually ant sometimes bucks
outside of the normal hunting season so
let's say you're a straw bra grower and
you've got deer coming in in June that's
just hammering your crop and you're
afraid you're not going to get your crop
out of the field you can apply to DEC
for a deer damage permit and shoot those
deer during June if you want to or any
any time of the year outside the normal
hunting season also with a damage permit
you can shoot at night you can use
lights you can use bait to attract here
to a safe shooting area you can do all
sorts of things that you can't do with
hunting that you can get written into a
deer damage permit we have been using
those the last three years here on
campus to try to alleviate some of our
problems uh 15 what is there
restrictions on allow
to uh you've got to be a licensed
Hunter passed a hunter certification
course and you have to be at least 21
years old those are the only two things
uh that you have to actually be a farmer
you don't have to be a farmer in fact
sometimes farmers will get the permit
you fill out a form of who your
designated agents are when you apply for
the permit and you can have non-farmers
hunters friends who are licensed and
meet the requirement come in and
actually do the removal on your farm you
don't have to be the land owner when the
application submitted you list your
agents that are going to do the shooting
most Farmers don't have time to do it a
lot don't do it themselves they use
their designated
agents on average again about eight and
a half DPS were obtained per applicant
in seven deer work kill so again most
people are filling these permits if they
apply for them and they feel they do
some good
so just sort of the summarize the survey
part of this uh deer damaged agriculture
in New York state is really important
it's a high economic impact particularly
in Western and Southeastern New York uh
grain and Nursery crops were the two
highest but if you had hay in there
you've got substantial Forge crop losses
most Growers allow hunting but uh most
Growers don't put any restriction on the
sex of deer and I think you know we're
talking with with Farm audiences and we
talk about deer damage we got to
encourage those those farm land owners
to to take more female deer uh The
Growers who used either the dmap or the
DDP program
79% of those growers in the survey said
they thought they were at least somewhat
successful in trying to reduce their
agriculture problem will they solve a
problem no they're not going to solve a
problem but it might uh get you through
a cropping season for example if you got
something like strawberry with a fair
very narrow Harvest window uh intensive
use of a deer damage permit for a week
or might get you through that Harvest
period where you can get your crop out
of the
field what do I recommend to Growers if
you've got perennial crops and you're in
a high deer damage area things like uh
tree fruits uh Nursery crops uh 8ot High
fencing is the only thing we know really
works well expensive six bucks a linear
foot installed on average so you can
spend thousands of dollars on a deer
proof fence but we know that works if
it's done properly electric fences do
work in some situations I like to go
with a baited electric fence on a single
strand of poly tape or polywire get a
good high voltage deer charger something
that's going to put 7 to 10,000 line
volts out over the the line you can
either use the peanut aluminum foil tab
of peanut butter as a c attractant or I
prefer using claw strips with a deer
repellant some type of odor in addition
to the electric enhances the
effectiveness of the electric fence the
way the peanut butter works is a deer
smells that peanut butter when it
approaches the fence and it touches the
fence for the first time with its nose
or tongue and gets 7,000 bolts through
its nose that's a pretty good negative
conditioner they don't fool the fence
again after that happen usually and the
same thing with the repellent they start
to associate that repellent smell with
the electric fence and so sometimes oh
yeah I can smell that I'm not even going
near that thing uh but again the
limitation on electric fences is that
they have acreage size limits they tend
to work pretty well for small Fields
small blocks under about 5 Acres inside
uh sometimes 5 to 10 acres are pretty
good but usually above 10 acres inside
deer will figure out that oh yeah I can
jump over that thing and if there's
something good to eat inside they'll
learn that behavior and the electric
fences will fail
eventually I'll talk about a bit about
bird management some general bird
management principle I was part of a
collaborative project with Katherine
Lindell from Michigan State University
in my grad student Heidi Hendrick we had
a USDA Nea specialy crop research initia
Project funding to look at multi-state
impacts of birds on fruit crops uh in
several States our partners again we're
Cornell and Michigan State we sort of
led the program and did uh the a lot of
the field work we have partner uh
universities in the Pacific Northwest in
their fruit growing region out there
with Oregon state Washington State and
Trinity Western and uh folks from the
USDA National Wildlife Research Center
in Colorado Fort Collins were involved
in some of the survey design and uh uh
discussions on on techniques to
use lots of different types of bird
deterrents out there everything from the
old scarecrow to the aluminum pie plate
you might see in somebody's backyard the
Raptor model scare ey balloons myar tape
all these things may or may not do any
good really depends on on your cropping
system but yet Growers depend a lot on
these type of devices to try to reduce
bird damage to
crops basically just sort of a general
rule of thumb my experience with the the
Haw and Al model that they tend not to
work at all I mean they just a given
that the birds really figure out pretty
quickly that these things are plastic
and they're no real
danger uh small areas we've seen some
success with bird distress collar
devices uh on small areas on certain
crops uh you'll see some of the data
I'll show you in a few minutes they're
not particularly encouraging but we uh
occasionally they work the myar flagging
in the upper right it's just a highly
reflective flagging that's tended to
work pretty well on some field crop
situations particularly with migrating
geese not so much with resident geese
they've sort of figured that out netting
some people consider a permanent fix I
have my question the way netting is done
how well that really works shooting can
be used in limited areas very sight
specific whether you can or can't and
the same thing goes for tra trapping say
starlings around a dairy farm where
they're causing contamination of food
and stuff sometime uh limited trapping
effort can do some
good our project objectives are looking
at things that influence an effective
bird damage management strategy and so
we had one uh group in the Pacific
Northwest and at the National Wildlife
Research Center that was looking at
economics to try to quantify cost of
bird damage producers consumers and how
it affects Regional economies we're
still sort of in the data analysis and
writing stages on that part we had
another group of social scientists that
was looking at consumer habits and
marketing again those data are still
being analyzed we hope to get a paper
out here on that fairly soon and then we
had a group of us looking at the
biological side of things uh landscape
and Edge effects bird species and
behavior and uh effectivess of different
management strategies and the last two
of the things that were farthest Along
on I want to share some data with you
today
we ask Growers as part of the uh survey
in all those uh states in the New York
Michigan and the Pacific Northwest what
works and what does it in your opinion
and you can see very clearly most
Growers feel that the only thing that
really works is netting the claim
netting is very to moderately effective
about 80% of the time everything else
along this access has Effectiveness
rates of 50% or below most Growers have
tried these things over several years
they really realiz well sometimes they
work sometimes they don't uh but they
continue to use them so again we wanted
to get some really hard data on how well
these different devices work for scaring
Birds we had uh field research sites in
New York 96 uh unique Farms where we
collected data in Central and Western
New York we did bird damage assessments
looking at percent damage of missing
fruit we looked at edges versus interior
blocks some Growers claim all all the
damag is on the edges well is that true
we took a look at that we did intensive
bird surveys to look at what species
were present what's their foraging
behavior and then we had 52 additional
farms in Michigan that did the exact
same protocol so we could combine data
from New York and Michigan on the same
crops same year same time and do
comparison to how things well things
worked in two different
states in terms of damage assessment we
broke each block or field up in the five
strata North southeast west edges and
then an interior stratum we select Ed
for trees or bushes in terms of
blueberry 12 randomly selected trees or
bushes per stratum one randomly selected
Branch per tree and then count it all
intact missing or damaged fruit uh and
we looked at sweet cherries honey Cris
apples
um uh blueberries and P Noir wine grapes
so we did four uh focal crops on grapes
because they're on trellises our setup
was a little different we had a ran
random height and a random position
along the vine we pick a a random height
and and position and then we pick the
cluster closest to wherever that random
height position fell out and we count
all the fruit on that cluster again
damage missing
intact additional data we took for each
Farm it's location or there are presence
of telephone wires nearby a lot of
Growers say well it's those darn wires
the birds get up there perch and then
they go down and they steal my crop we
wanted to look through telephone wires
have an impact other bird management
techniques surrounding land cover uh
some uh folks say is you know it's that
da Farm next door attracts all the
starlings and now they're over here
eating my blueberries well is that true
uh so we've got good data on the land
cover characteristics around that still
being analyzed and look at number of
plants each strata height and any
special additional data or notes we
wanted to take while we're in the field
terms of observations we use
standardized Point counts two observers
15 few minutes in the block counting all
the different bird species that they saw
we did it both on the interior of the
block and the exterior of the block we
did forging observations uh we did
started with stationary where positioned
The Observer where they could see on the
edge and in the block and just watch for
an hour what what birds do you see pick
a focal bird follow as long as you can
record all the fruit it touches eats
consumes and then we did uh moving
observations where sometimes it's
difficult to see what's going on in a
block particularly with tall cherry
trees and so we had Observer just walk
slowly find a focal bird followed as
long as he could uh when that Bird's
gone find the next bird follow it as
long as you could to get focal
observations on who what they're
actually eating and
damaging we look at the Sweet Cherry
data uh what really jumps out at you is
the percent fruit loss in both sweet
cherries and blueberries was highest in
2012 you guys remember what happened in
what's that
NOP what else could affect
it frost yeah late spring Frost 90% of
the Cherry crop Sweet Cherry crop in New
York was lost in Spring 2012 a late
spring Frost and a big chunk of the
blueberry crop was lost so one of the
general principles is if you've got L
fruit on there because it's a bad year
for whatever reason drought late freeze
then those of the years you got to pay
attention to bird damage because when
you've got a low crop load the percent
fruit loss goes way up and we saw that
in 2012 in more normal cropping years
didn't see a whole lot very little
damage in apples even though apple G
were seeing the birds are eating our
fruit the birds are eating our fruit
when we go out there and measure it we
don't see a whole lot in fact uh we did
we only did three orchards in 2014 and
saw Zero damage we didn't see an ample
damage by a bird wine grapes tend tend
to be the most consistent you know we're
seeing about uh 3 to 4% loss per year in
Pino Noir wine grapes blueberries again
in sweet cherries you get good and bad
years again depends on the crop
load we looked at again the position uh
to see what Growers are saying is true
the edges get more damage in interior
and we definitely don't see that Trend
in any of the crops that looks like
inside and outside get damage pretty
much the same the only pattern that we
saw was interesting was we saw more
damage on the north and south end of
blocks and wine grapes so why would that
happen what's going on in wine grapes
that would increase bird damage on the
North and South
ends what's that orientation absolutely
it's the orientation of the trellises
most of The Vineyards are oriented north
south parallel to the finger legs
because they're on S slope that means
the open end of the roads are on the
north south side that's where you get
your most intense bird damage because
it's easier for them to get in the road
from the north and south end but besides
that we saw no pattern based on position
in the
orchard we looked at distress collar and
hot kites uh as an Effy uh WRA Refugee
these are very commonly used by Growers
throughout New York and Michigan uh they
think they do some good so we want to
see do they really do any good at all
what can we measure so we uh group uh uh
Farm into four clusters of four so in
that cluster of four you'd have a a
block say a sweet cherry block with a
distress collar a sweet cherry block
with a Haw heite a sweet cherry block
with both devices in the field and then
a control block and uh our criteria is
all those Farms had to be within 30
miles so in the same population of birds
because the birds are very mobile we
selected Farms based on the previous
year's damage so we tried to pick farms
to had about the same percent off and
similar block
sizes we set up the devices two to 3
weeks before Harvest and we position
them at least four rows into the block
and if we had both deterrents on a on a
block we set them up on opposite sides
from each other and so then we actually
collected data to see how well these
things worked we move also moved them
once a week some people say moving a
device adds an element a surprise and
increases Effectiveness so we switch
positions of devices once weekly
and what we found was uh these things
didn't make a bit of difference it was
unfortunate and in fact the damage was
highest where we Ed both devices so
again Growers think these things work
but they are wasting a lot of time and
money if you look at the control block
except for this one uh unusual uh New
York Farm actually the controls suffered
slightly less damage than the treated
blocks and uh there was no significant
difference uh when we did the stats test
across there it just made no difference
whatsoever putting these things up in in
uh sweet
cherries we also came across the idea of
using air dancers and you might have
seen these at the used car lots these
sort of silky things that are air
powered and wave around and we thought
that oh these things got motion they're
big maybe they'll scare birds better
than some of these other devices uh so
we set up sight pairs again with the
same criteria and we had uh one farm
with a dancer one farm with out a dancer
within 30 Mi based on the previous
year's damage and block size again two
to 3 weeks before Harvest and we move
the dancers every two to three days uh
around the field so you can see sort of
the pattering every couple days it be in
a new spot we had to either these are
electric powered fans you have to run
them by either electric cord which we
didn't have any many cases or a gas
generator which means that the grower
had to go out there every day and refill
the gas generator because the generators
had run about eight or nine hours and
then they'd run out of gas
uh but they Growers are willing to do
that we looked at Sweet Cherry damage
and what we saw with the dancers and
sweet cherries a slight benefit not
significantly different slightly less
damage you still see lots of farm the
farm uh variability and uh again that's
very typical with bird damage that's why
you got to do a lot of farm if you do
one or two Farms you're not going to
learn anything you got to be doing five
10 Farm to get some sense of what works
and what doesn't blueberries again uh
slight difference uh uh with the dancers
had about 6% fruit loss uh on the dancer
plots a little over 8% controls we look
at berri's loss per day that was
marginally significant at 0.005 so again
slightly fewer loss but at those type of
differences it doesn't justify the cost
of running the things or putting it out
in the field and blueberries where we
did see a difference was wine grapes and
uh what we saw was a about half the
level of damage where we had daners and
wine grapes and it was significant at
the 0.01 level so these things appeared
to work relatively well in wine grapes
during the first two years still a lot
of farm to farm variability and it
doesn't work everywhere here you can see
on this Farm in Michigan the the dancer
plot actually had higher damage than the
control why said we don't know but again
you just see tons of variability in New
York we had more consistent results with
the air dancing and I think a lot of
that has to do with field size our
blocks uh where we were running this our
grape Vineyards are tended to be smaller
on average than they were in Michigan
our blueberry Fields also in New York
tend to be much smaller on average than
the typical Michigan Blueberry field so
where you have smaller blocks smaller
sites uh these devices are more likely
to benefit you in
work we uh did a a comparison between
dancers and control
and uh in 2014 and used two dances per
side you can see how highly
significantly different except for far a
everything was highly significantly
different so these devices really did
work on the wine grapes and The Growers
have talked about it we had one grower
had a naming contest for his device out
by his Vineyard and his customers named
him Mr penino and so that's what he
called his device he thought it was a
big deal a little bit of marketing with
it we looked at other variables related
to bird damage and again the the
telephone wires kept coming up but we
couldn't see anything significant in
cherries or grapes and when we looked at
blueberries actually the blueberry
fields that were closest to the
telephone wires had less damage and the
reason we think is that those tended to
be much larger Fields so the damage was
more dispersed and so there was get no
strong relationship and again when we
looked at netting in paired plots where
we had dancers and no dancers and both
areas were netting there was uh no
significant difference and so what we're
seeing is birds are getting through this
netting with this larger mes size uh
we've seen that on Long Island for years
the birds are using the netting for a
perch and then they poke their heads
through and damage the grapes through
the netting so Growers are using a lot
of netting spending a lot of money on it
but we didn't see it significantly
really reduce the bird
damage so who are the culprits uh these
are the common bird species we see in in
fruit orchards in New York and Michigan
and one of the take-home messages I want
to leave with you just because you see a
bird there doesn't mean that's the bird
that's causing the damage and we've got
data to back that up now we look at
sweet cherries in
2014 the most frequent sighting by far
in terms of number of birds were
American Robins and European starlings
were number two we looked at Birds
taking and eating fruit American Robins
were number one and number of fruits
consumed American Robins were number one
that lines up pretty well well but when
we look at time spent eating fruit
European starlings even though they're
the second most frequent bird they don't
eat a lot of fruit and it was cedar
waxwings were number two in terms of
eating fruit and feeding on spent time
foraging on fruit but yet we see very
few zedar wax wings in The Vineyards but
they do a lot of damage so again Growers
may be missing the culprit in these
cases uh because they smaller less
visible
Birds we saw similar patterns in
blueberries again the most frequent bird
we saw on blueberry were American Robins
followed by Baltimore oror but when we
look at time spent eating fruit American
Robins ate very few fruits either time
or fruits consumed they were almost dead
last even though they were the most
common bird seen it was the Baltimore
orils and the Cedar Wax Wings again that
spent most of the time consuming the
fruit so I see this with Growers a lot
particularly with turkeys too they say
all the turkeys are damaging my my
Vineyards well we really didn't see
turkeys taking grapes just just because
they wander through and they're big and
visible the grower thinks that's what's
causing the problem and it may not
be what we found is that in our field
trials in New York and Michigan that the
Haw Kites and discust callers and even
the combination to really didn't do
anything and past studies had pretty
misre exols too we did find though that
the dancers showed some optimistic uh
results in grapes and in fact we had a
couple of our operating grap Growers
that wanted to buy the air dancers from
us after the end of the trial they were
they liked them so much uh they do take
intensive management you got to either
have electric power or you got to be out
there like I said moving them around
filling that gas generator every day to
keep the the wind sock up and running
Nets didn't significantly reduce bird
damage that we saw in the dancer site
Pairs and uh we actually saw slightly
lower bird damage uh with blueberries
related to the telephone wires but again
all the sites of wires tend to be larger
blocks I think they just had less damage
in general not nothing really related to
the
wires so I just go back to integrated
Wildlife Management when you're working
on farms or working with a farm owners
it's really important to assess
everything that's going on what are the
species causing damage which crops are
affected uh how many acres what time
what's the housing density what are your
neighbors like a lot of these sound
devices neighbors don't like them and uh
so again if your Farm's more rural you
might have more options available to you
and then you've got to go through you
know what can I afford and I would argue
that in most years for at least fruit
crops in New York doesn't pay to do any
of this stuff except for maybe air
dancers and wine grapes but if you get
that bad crop year where you've had a
late freeze or you've had a drought and
the yield is low you really need to do
something that's the area you want to do
your bird management because it's going
to have an impact on a percentage of
fruit that you might
save let's see it's important to
reassess too if things don't work why
what can I do differently are there
something else I haven't tried what
other options are available to me a lot
of these things The Growers put them in
the field and they walk away from them
and they just assume they're working but
if you don't assess you don't know and
very few Growers go to the trouble of
actually looking at fruit damage and and
actual
loss just want to share website with you
uh while life control. info there's
results of all sorts of extension
Publications for different species if
you're interested in that and also uh
we'll eventually get uh more data from
our research projects and links to
papers and stuff up as uh we get more of
it written up uh but I appreciate
everybody's attention and be glad to
answer questions folks might
have thanks a lot lot lot of good
information um you know your early maap
showing kind of where most of the
economic damage as you point out that
matches up with where the Farms are but
from a farmer's perspective you know I'm
just curious if you looked at the data
in terms of damage per Farm or per field
you know what I'm saying yeah we haven't
really looked at it all at all on a
damage for field basis or the way
Growers react to it obviously you know
if you getting a relatively small fields
that are high value and you a lot of
your income coming and if you've got
wild life damage could be more
economically painful that's for sure uh
but we really haven't looked at into
that in any detail at all we looked at
the sort of the broad Trends broad
statistics um really interesting that
the Dan meod Work
Well certain that really
yeah that's a really good question and
we did try to collect bird species
information for the grave but when we
did our foraging observations both of
stationary and mobile we found so few
Birds foraging there we we saw Birds but
we actually saw more fly overs than
anything else birds that really never uh
fed and so we had zero in terms of
foraging observation in grapes uh so
again the damage was relatively low
compared to the other clout and that may
be another reason why uh the air dancers
tended to to work better
there this kind not right on the
agricultural ends but I see managing
kened East up there and I know that's a
real challenge for a lot of communities
and fancy industrial complexes and
everything else they seem to be hanging
out more and more and more what's the
like the elevator sound bite on the
future of managing and whether they're
going to just become more and more
common year round or what you the what
we call the resident or the local
breeding Goose block uh it's plateaued
now but it plateaued at a really high
level I it's or tens of thousands of
birds what we want above what we want in
New York state currently uh if you go
back a couple of decades there were more
what we call the migratory geese the
ones we all grew up with that breed in
Canada winter in the Chesapeake North
Carolina uh but about a decade and a
half ago that flip-flopped and so now
they're actually more resident birds in
the Eastern flowy local breeding birds
than migrants and they cause all sorts
of problems and they are short distance
migrants they do migrate but only when
they have to so they're the ones that
breed locally they're here pretty much
year round as well they need two things
they need open water which they have on
cuga Lake year round and they need grass
so the only thing that's going to drive
them out of here is if we e enough deep
persistent snow that they can't for then
they force to go south until that snow
melts so they're here most of the year
we've got a pilot Goose project in
Stewart park right now where we we've
been using uh uh the uh town of Ithaca
Goose committee wanted to use only
non-lethal devices and I said told them
right off they don't expect a whole lot
from nonleaf Hit uh we were able to at
least move birds out of Stuart Park
using uh uh firecrackers and radio
control cars we got them out of the park
and uh but they didn't go far they went
to the inlet and cast Park which we
expected what's that it terrify all the
it didn't terrify the park users we
tried to do it at times a day for very
early in the morning very late in the
evening not during the middle of day
when there are a lot of Park users and
so we're be putting together a report
for the uh city of itha here soon on the
goose efforts they really need to start
earlier in the year what we learned we
banded 425 geese and collared 200 adults
in Stewart Park this summer so if you
see a goose waning around Stewart park
with a big yellow collar that's one we
put on and what we learned was that most
the geese that caused the problem in
Stewart Park in June and July are not
local uh breeding birds we only found
about 10 to 12 pairs that actually had
goling a total of about 60 goling that
were produced in and around the park the
rest of them are what we call local mol
mol migrants there's so much water and
grass around Stuart Park it's a perfect
molting area when they mol they drop
their flight feathers for five weeks and
they cannot fly so birds come in and
they look for places like Stuart Park
where they can fly in drop those flight
feather just sort of hang out feed
defecate everywhere create all sorts of
Havoc for five or six weeks weeks till
they regrow their flight feathers in
Late July they're on off again somewhere
else uh but we've got to live with the
mess during that the midsummer when the
parks got the highest use what the town
and the city need to do is move those
birds out before the Mt they didn't do
it and so that's one of the
recommendations going to be before they
drop their flight feathers that's when
you need to do the Intensive hazing and
non-lethal stuff to try to get those
birds out of there get them to Mt
somewhere else and then instead of
having 450 geese in Stuart Park and late
June hopefully we can get it down to
maybe 40 or
50 any other questions PA I was going to
ask a quick question about wild boar I
know for a time we did have them in New
York it looks like they're no longer
here but can you say something about
them because they can do a lot of damage
yeah we're fortunate that uh DEC EG
markets and USDA wildlife services saw
the the wild boore issues starting to
emerge and we did have some localized
breeding population in New York there
was of on courland on DOA county line
one in tyoga County uh one up in Clinton
County in Northeast New York and one on
the Sullivan Delaware County border and
uh uh USDA wildlife services staff got a
contract to come in and do eradication
and uh USDA and DEC staff really did a
good job uh essentially we've eradicated
breeding wild boards from New York they
still get escapes every now and then and
there's new legislation that's passed
that uh Farmers can't keep Wild boore on
their Farm I think it was as of last
summer if I remember right and so
hopefully that will eliminate chances of
seeing wild boes in New York in the
future uh Pennsylvania right across our
border still has wild boards and
shooting preserves and they escape that
was the source of the tyoga County
population so we're still going to have
to deal with that
occasionally any last question you
mentioned a lot about what Farmers to
prot are there any um State programs for
example to
I
know yeah yeah we actually done research
on campus with deer fertility control
and sterilization and we found after
about six seven years of effort the best
we could do with sterilization even
combining it with our campus deer
hunting program was to stabilize the
herd couldn't reduce it and so that's
when we went to our deer damage permit
and started actually removing animals at
night over bait and we were able to cut
the herd in about half in two years on a
damage permit and other plac have seen
that we did a just finishing up an
experiment in the village of cuga
heights this the fourth year the first
two years they couldn't get approval for
shooting uh so they hired in White
Buffalo a contractor and uh we work with
white buffalo and using Cornell
veterinarians we sterilized 99% of the
female deer in the village of cuga
heights the first two years and what we
found was that having that high
proportion sterilize for two years the
population dropped up by 30% there
wasn't enough immigration uh to replace
that lack of fonds and then the village
got approval for a deer damage permit a
kill permit they contracted with the
white buffalo to come back in the last
two years uh White Buffalo's actually
done deer removal with uh crossbows at
night that was approved by Village
Police and so with the two years of
removal now they've dropped at another
40% so they have 70% reduction in deer
in the village of cuga heights right now
with that integrated program question is
will they sustain it it's a deer doing
deer managements like mowing the lawn
guess what it comes back you got to do
it all the time you can't wait a year if
you if you just you know give them a two
three year break guess what they I'll
reproduce you they'll be right back
there and you lose all the all the gains
that you
made all right well let's
thank this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu