this is a production of Cornell
University thanks Neil it's a real
pleasure to be here and I like to thank
Neil for being such a great host uh and
it's good to see him again and it's good
to see him thriving here um and it's a
pleasure to be here I've
uh it's it doesn't seem like spring here
it's 82° today in
Sacramento that's a little too warm for
us but uh it's a pleasure to be here
nonetheless and it's and it's also this
symos of thing uh lee Lang and and
Terren put it
together uh it's it's uh nicknamed the
old fart Symposium because it's supposed
to be bunch a bunch of us tree crop
physiologists who who are in the process
retiring in the in the somewhat either
already retired or in the in the
relatively near future
retiring and uh I did get my degree in
in in at Davis but it was in the botney
department and my PhD was in beach and
dune plant ecology so I I I never did
have a formal course in pomology or
horiculture in life but now I'm the
primary uh pomology instructor at Davis
so life is full of
fun uh and I've really enjoyed my career
uh in in tree fruit physiology I look at
I look at
pomology as basically applied
environmental
physiology uh with trees and I'm uh
today I'm going to talk about work that
we've done
uh with uh
rootstock physiology work
primarily uh I spent a lot of my time
doing crop modeling tree crop modeling
and a whole bunch of other sort of
things I'll talk about that uh on on
Wednesday U of this week at the Geneva
meeting so I thought I'd do something a
little different here
today
um and about 30 years ago now um Scott
Johnson and myself
uh teamed up with a USDA scientist who
had been collecting potentially dwarfing
root stocks for
peach Scott Johnson actually was a
graduate from Cornell he's one of uh
alen lao's early PhD students and he's
the extension specialist at Kerney at
the Kerney egg Center which is in the in
the Central Valley of California he and
I have done a lot of work together and
uh we we uh started looking at at these
root stocks and and and our our typical
for these are all going to talk about
Peach exclusively today uh our standard
Peach root stock in California is nagard
it's a very vigorous root stock selected
for uh root not nematode resistance and
and vigor our Growers are interested in
having a much are having some size
reduction and less pruning costs and so
on so we we began looking at some of
these selections uh
from that program we started out with
122 different accessions of
genotypes and we narrowed and we we got
about 82 of those to root from hardwood
cuting and from that we narrowed it down
to to 10 that looked reasonably good and
then we finally ended up with these two
controller N9 and what are called
controller 9 and controller 5 here and
this Hawa is an old root stock from
South
Dakota but they all had some dwarfing so
this is the the uh trunk
circumferences and you can see there
some dwarfing after 12 years um and this
is the standard open vase tree these are
perpendicular V or V shaped tree they
also and consistently with two different
tops two different
signs so the the trees aren't
tremendously smaller but this is nagard
uh or
uh uh loell Peach on nagard and this is
the one on controller 9 this is
controller 5 the size of the trees isn't
that much smaller but the openness of
the trees is much greater and we have
much less response to pruning when we
prune these two as opposed to this as
you can see here this is some of the
from the early again two different uh
two different tops and two different
Training
Systems uh and
consistently this is the the dry mass of
the of the dormant prunings well
actually some are in dorant prunings put
together and you can see the difference
in pruning weight is quite sign
significant uh subsequent to that early
study uh Fred Bliss came to Davis and
started looking at additional crosses
and the herob blood by okan okan cross
was uh was really really through a lot
of variation in in uh size controlling
potential and so we've released uh four
more root stocks in addition to the ini
initial two the initial two are
controller nine and controller five
controller
five trees actually almost too
small and it produces small fruit so we
don't want we don't want dwarf fruit
when we have a dwarf tree but these
others are all producing
uh reason I mean yeah reasonably Siz
fruit compared to trees on
nagard and so
uh we so we yeah released all of these
six and these numbers basically
represent something relative to the size
of nagard so this should be about 95% so
just slightly reducing 90 95% 80% 70%
60% more or less and 50% of trees on
nagard
so while we did all that sort of
evaluation sorts of work as a
physiologist I got more and more
interested in and the dwarfing
mechanism and so I'm going to talk
mainly about that and so way back in
1939 looking at moling 9 and some of the
mauling root stocks beak pain and and
Thompson beak Bain they were both at at
East
Ming uh they an analyze the anatomy uh
of the SYM and and Flo and so on in in
uh dwarfing apple root stocks and they
they showed that the cross-sectional
area the xylm cross-sectional area of
the various Apper root stocks composed
of fibers prum and vessel rays and the
percent of fibers and vessels were
proportional to the Vigor of the root
stocks imparted to the
San and the more uh dwarfing root stocks
had smaller vessels than vigorous root
stocks
uh and
but well then they concluded that at
least a partial explanation of the
mechanism of root St effect may be
obtained from a study of internal
structure of the fruit trees they were
very cautious about assigning any causal
relationship
between
uh xylm vessel characteristics the root
stock versus a s to the dwarfing and the
reason for that is some summarized in
this
review which is in an annual review of
plant physiology by by Rogers and Beak
Bane and and so at that in that review
they said that there were basically
three potential mechanisms to explain s
root stock interactions one was
nutrient uh May differ greatly in the
capacity for absorbing storing and
utilizing
nutrients one was in transport focused
on the flo transport but acknowledged
differences in sizing and sizes and
numbers of vessels are sufficient to Su
suggest that the capacity of this island
for water transport would be higher and
vigorous than in dwarf plants but this
may not be a limiting factor based on
The View that the number of vessels in
the stems is normally greatly in excess
of that required to transport water so
as you know we have lots and lots of
xylm area in trees and so they basically
said well it doesn't make sense that
that this can actually be a limiting
factor because in general we think that
there's excess xylm
capacity and then the one related to to
to uh growth regulating substance
substances which basically has been sort
of the principle uh mechanism that's
been B bandied around for the rest for
the
last 60
years so
uh I had a graduate student
um in the '90s late '90s
who basically described uh some of these
early root stocks that we're looking at
and what the growth characteristics were
we had uh and
basically uh the new the peach root
stocks Li are affected or limited shoot
length growth that is uh and that was
basically the inner node lengths but not
the number of
nodes and trunk girth was was decreased
in the number as we saw already in the
previous slide or slides ago and the
number of and length of of water sprouts
the epicormic
shoots uh tended to be less with the
with the sight controlling root
stocks and there was a hint that the
trees on dwarfing root stocks had no
lower uh uh more more negative midday
stem water
potentials So based on that work uh that
early the descriptive
work um and on a study that I a previous
student of mine
did uh we showed that shoot extension
growth is is a linear function of the
temperature and late and the rate of
change of of stem's water potential in
in peaches now this is a little bit
counterintuitive because uh before you
look look at that
so what time of
day is a shoot growth the
greatest shoot extension growth what
type of day is shoot extension growth
the greatest in a fruit
tree early in the morning early in the
morning why because the uh D because the
water potential is water potential is
the highest yep okay anybody else want
to guess
why yeah you got sugar accumulation yeah
all right so it turns out that contrary
to the water water hypothesis
afternoon is the is the period of most
rapid stem extension growth so this is
this is the the extension growth right
here and you see that it its
peak is is about
6:00 1,800 hours most people because
they're so fixated on water relations
immediately talk think about the mid the
the dawn water potential being a driver
but in fact temperature temperature is
is one of the most significant factors
ever driving growth and availability of
carbohydrates Le Lang is focused on
carbohydrates so that's involved there
but anyway we could we we could uh
basically model this stem extension
growth rate as a function a linear
function of of
um the recovery the recovery of water
Potential from the midday
low the rate of recovery of water
Potential from the midday low plus the
temperature uh and so we got a fairly
good regression of that well so under
really realizing that or understanding
that I went back and we thought okay
let's take a look at these root stocks
in the
field so we did this experiment with
nagard hawaa and uh K1 14643 which is
controller five
now um and and this a range there's a
range of uh size reduction and sure
enough that we did this uh we did these
dial patterns of of extension growth
rate uh relative extension growth rate
and
and stem mid and stem water potential
over the day and sure enough the the
most size controlling had the most
negative minimum water potential and so
forth and and as the spring warmed up
that those differences especially with
the with the uh controller 5 or the K
14643 was much negative more negative
and and this was as the spring kept
going but but then as as he end up in
June the differences became a little bit
less but so when we put that all
together we we came up with this sort of
integrated daily stem uh fluctuation in
in megap pascals per hour and uh the the
K1
14643 was was the most affected or uh
had the lowest integrated uh water
potential fluctuation and then the
highwa in between and thenard here so it
uh convinced us that yes indeed the
water relations thing is something going
on with water relations and this is this
is the water sprout length or epicormic
shoot
length uh in those same trees that we
were looking at this other and this is
accumulated integrated stem
fluctuation and we uh we again a very
good
relationship the length of water sprouts
which grow sort of in terminant through
the whole season and this and this
uh and and water and and and stem water
potential so then I um so we were now
fairly convinced that water potential
had something to do with
it then I had another student Luis
salari uh and we decided okay in order
to nail us down we should we should
manipulate water
potential so what we did was uh or what
he I should say you know professors
faculty always say we but it's really
the student that does all the
work
uh nevertheless I'll continue to say we
uh anyway what he what we did what he
did was he wrapped the the Chute to stop
the
transpiration and then put this this
sort of
um insulating this like a space blanket
material over the top and so that the
shoots didn't heat up and and he either
he either covered zero 30% or 60% of the
canopy with this with this
material
uh in the evening
before a warm summer day and the idea
here it was to see whether we could
manipulate water potential and get get a
range of water potentials and still see
this change in in in uh stem extension
growth rate
so basically by doing and on he did that
on the three root stocks so nagard hawaa
and k146 are controller
five and you see immediately that the
this is the uh stem water
potential and always uh the the more
dwarf remot stock had a lower water
potential but we could indeed raise that
water potential by covering 30 or
60% of the
canopy uh and so that we had basically
overlapping water potentials uh between
the nagard and the and the uh High waa
in
14643 and we did that we this is the
relative stem extension growth rate and
then we get a corresponding overlap in
stem extension growth rate so there's a
direct
correlation on the three root stocks
three different root stocks directly
related to water
potential so
uh and this this shows the
relationship more clearly as a graph
with all with all the points on
it differing amounts of cover of
coverage and so forth all put together
so they're there're appears to be a
direct
relationship of that so then and then uh
when that experiment was done with a
small
trees he uh we we used a um
a uh hydraulic pressure uh machine to
measure to measure specific hydraulic
inductance of of the plant of the of the
Chute the root and uh or the Chute part
and the root part and then put them
together the whole tree so basically
what you do is you cut the tree off you
measure the hydraulic conductance of the
upper part and then you turn the thing
around and put it on the root and force
the water backwards through there uh
there's a little bit
of concern about forcing whether forcing
water backward through the root is the
right thing to do but nevertheless you
still get you still get these
differences so assuming that the
differen would be relative you see that
when there's no
difference uh
between uh the treatments with a s so
all of these had the same n uh the same
s on top same Peach s on top I forgot EX
exactly what it was but they're all the
same but they're just on different root
stocks uh but the root stock
consistently
had um nagard the root of nagard had a a
higher specific hydraulic least specific
hydraulic
conductance uh and so the the difference
was in the root stock not in the
Canan uh and then this
student uh that wasn't quite enough for
him so we did this additional experiment
where we put the the plants in these
these Chambers we grew the plants in the
chambers for a number of years he had a
whole slew of other ones that he did
some other experiments but the these
Chambers you're able to we're able to uh
seal them up and and apply uh pressure
air pressure to the bottom while they're
while they're uh growing and we moved
them to a growth chamber and did this
work and um this kind of work has been
done before with other plants it's sort
of it sort of documents that yes water
potential actually works and and the
system as we think of it actually works
you apply pressure to the to root stock
or to the roots and you you can indeed
as you apply pressure the leaf water
potential of the of of the S uh changes
proportionally so you apply pressure and
the root and the root stock water I mean
the S water potential increases it
maintain the difference between the the
two root stocks so in this case we just
had two the nagard versus the controller
5 or K1
14643 and and so the the more negative
one is the is the controller five or the
dwarfing root stock and the other one is
is the vigorous root
stock so the so the relative extension
uh and and this is the corresponding
relative extension growth rate of these
root stocks I mean of the chotes so
again we can manipulate the water
potential and we by doing so we
manipulate the shoot extension growth
rate so sort of nails it in terms of yes
indeed um the rate of growth or the rate
of steming extension growth on the roof
stock is directly related to water water
relations and and he also measured then
the the uh the hydraulic
conductance again Lea specific hydraulic
conductance of these two and and again
the Canan not really well in this case
slightly different but not a whole lot
different but the but the root stock is
where most of the difference was between
here and
here
uh so then I had this this visiting
scientist from Italy came and
um and he said you know you've done all
this stuff I read all your papers and it
would be interesting to look at the ZM
Anatomy I said well certainly it can't
be that
easy this whole thing can't be that
simple uh but uh he went went ahead and
he he measured uh The xylm Vessel
characteristics and and then calculated
axial hydraulic conductance of the size
of the size controlling root stocks and
in this case he did nagard and the
controller 9 and controller
five uh and sure enough he got
differences in in the these are classes
of um root uh root size
categories and uh in in the
in and and this is so this is now the
choots of of each one of these so these
are these are actually these were taking
from our from our foundation Plant
Services block where we have that's used
for distribution of of of um grafting
wood or rooting wood and so these are
actual shoots of the root stock here
these are the trunks of the root stock
and these are the roots of the root
stocks and so we saw these consistent
differences again in all these parts of
of having uh a greater number of of
large siiz vessels in the more uh more
vigorous root stocks and and a greater
proportion of smaller side vessel in the
in the more uh dwarfing root
stocks and uh if you put all this
together and calculate weed weighted
mean vessel diameters you see that uh
that
consistently well fairly consistently at
least uh the the nagard regardless of
whether you looked at the shoots the
trunks or the roots had the largest mean
weighted mean vessel
diameters and the the next one had the
intermediate and the most size
controlling had had the next most or
next smallest vessels
so it did seem to be directly related to
vessel diameter and and it is seem it
does seem to be uh as simple as just the
anatomy of the of the root
stock and then when you calculate the C
he used this these
data uh in vessel diameter weighted mean
vessel diameters and so on to calculate
the the theoretical xylm conductance
based on the
uh pyol law which is basically the
the the conductance or the resistance
conductance through a vessel or a a pipe
is is a function of the of the radius to
the fourth
power and and and sure enough no matter
what you looked at
nagard had the highest uh conduct
calculated theoretical conductance and
the others fell in
line so we're fairly fairly certain that
um that we had a story here but then we
we also wanted to know whether uh how
much influenced
because there is the notion that the the
root stock will influ influence the
anatomy of the scian or vice
versa and so we did we had a tree where
we uh well no wait this is
uh yeah so this is the S the a s on on
each of the root stocks versus the root
stock and so this is uh and
U and so you see the S was
basically identical across when when
when grafted on the three root stocks
but the root stock maintain their
differences just like we saw
before and um and this is the the the
calculated hydraulic conductance of
those again showing that that indeed the
Canan more or less stayed the same and
it was all in the root
stock and then we happened to have some
trees that where we where we would put
where he had put uh controller n as an
inter
stem and we had Oh Henry which is a
vigorous San and nagard was a vigorous
root
stock and uh we looked
at the theoretical hydraulic we looked
at the The xylm Vessel characteristics
again in this combination with a with a
vigorous root stock down in the
bottom uh an inter stem here and a
vigorous s on top
and we looked at the uh theoretical
hydraulic calculated well we looked at
the he looked at the vessel sizes and
all that and calculated a weighted mean
vessel diameter and all that and then
calculated theoretical hydraulic
inductance and sure enough it came out
that that basically the the the most
dwarfing root stock when used in an in
stem had no effect in either direction
on the on the vessel diameter vessel
anatomy of of of the root stock of the
the
others
um then we had this series you notice
remember I I talked about uh we had we
had four additional root stocks that we'
released so he looked at the anatomy The
Vessel characteristics of those four and
again
um we saw that that the uh the prim
AR the tri the primary uh effect was on
the was was on the
roots and that it was in line with the
with the with the U the dwarfing
characteristics there was also in this
case I looked at the trunks as well let
me see here so then we had a I had a uh
just last year I had a a geneticist
breeder a peach breeder who was
interested in Peach root stocks come
from
Brazil and he said well if that's the
case we should be able to figure out we
if we're going to breed root stocks in
the future it'd be really
interesting if we could use this as a
selection tool but it but it's going to
have to be simpler than than what tomasi
did because tomasi you looked at he did
a lot of calculations very laborious and
so on so what this so what cloudy
Brookner did was he he looked for some
very simple characteristics that you
could look at doing cross-section of of
shoots of these of these uh different
root stocks and he came up with with
the the the number of vessels around the
largest vessel over the number of
vessels of nagard so uh so basically he
he developed a simple selection criteria
by which he felt as as a plant breeder
he would he would uh and then he tested
whether he would be able to sort them
out or not depending on if he had a 10%
or a 15% or a 20% sort of variance in in
the selection criteria and he decided
that yes he could certainly he could
certainly sort out the more size
controlling root Stocks by having a
quick a simple a simple assay like this
so
um so he's hopeful that he could
actually use this sort of information in
his in his root stock breeding
program so now we're going back to the
beak Bane uh question and how can zylin
vessel diameter and theoretical
hydraulic inductance of the outer rings
of the xylm which is what we measured be
limiting when there appears to be an
excess of xylm
capacity in other words why weren't
Rogers and Beak Bane
correct
uh so I've been troubled by this for for
actually quite a few
years and we did an uh tomasi came back
we did this short
experiment a couple years
ago and the experiment the experiment
was basically we did girdling so in
California for our Peach production
especially early maturing Peach
production it's actually quite common
that that we will the grower will girdle
the trees
which basically means you take a qu inch
ring of bark out uh in the spring 6
weeks before Harvest six weeks before
your anticipated Harvest you take that
that ring of of bark off there down to
the cambium and then and then
um that artificially holds the
carbohydrates in the upper part of the
tree makes the fruit larger and it makes
it about three three or four or five
days earlier and the tree doesn't die I
mean contrary
to all the stuff about girdling the tree
doesn't die the the if you only do that
a quter inch the it grows callous across
the girdle and by by the time of harvest
the girdle's mended again the tree looks
a little sick but but it recovers and
you can do this year after year after
year so we did that and we did two two
times of
girdling an early girdle and a late
girdle and our hypothesis was that well
in most girdling people assume that it's
only the transport of sugars that's
affected not the transport of
water okay but we were we reasoned well
we're not so sure so this has been a
conundrum in the girdling literature for
years why Chute growth is actually
usually shorter on girdle
trees uh while fruit growth is
larger because
uh the fruit growth is larger because
more carbohydrates held up in the tree
but why wouldn't that excess
carbohydrate in the tree stimulate shoot
growth so this is a
problem uh that's been banging around in
literature for a while so we did this
experiment and then we looked at midday
stem water potentials after girdling so
here's the early girdle the midday stem
water potential of the of the early
girdle uh dropped significantly compared
to the control
the controls the the the triangles here
and then the late
girdle it it dropped also relative to
control but but both of them both of
them uh sort of caught up again so
what's the interpretation here our
interpretation is
that that the
girdling not only
affected uh flum flow it affected xylm
flow because when you girdle you're also
hitting the cambium so you're hitting
the
cambium that's going to stop the
development of new of new flum I mean
new xylm for that period so new xylm uh
growth uh
stops and so until it until it rebounds
you see this
effect and and there's also recently in
the last two or three four years
there's mounting evidence that water
transport trees in ring por Asylum with
ring por Asylum relies per primarily on
the most recently formed ring of xylm
maybe two rings of xylm and in fact
uh oh this is the this is the number of
water sprouts for tree uh it also
affected the number of water sprouts per
tree and and so
on um
but uh there are there is something
published in the in the literature way
back in 1890 that said that
robinia if you girdled
robinia uh some at a particular time of
the year the tree would
die if you did this light girdle whereas
if if you did it in the spring but if
you did it in the in the fall there was
no
effect so this is sort of consistent
with that and and and and people that
are doing the hydraulic conductance me
uh with the with the probes they're also
finding that if you put the probe too
deep you don't you can't measure the
hydraulic conductance nearly as well as
if you if you keep it in the outer
layers of xylm so there's increasing uh
recognition that it is the hour later Z
that's important so this goes back to
the root stock thing because if
transport of the water transport in the
plant is
primarily uh uh
uh dependent on the last year or the
current new growing uh xylm as well as
maybe the last year's Island that's
going to have an influence on having
smaller vessels in the root stock will
have an influence on the water potential
of those plants and so I think we have a
story so
basically the most recent ring is that
current years XY well obviously there's
some movement in the previous year xylm
but the the efficiency of the current
year xylm is thought to be much as it's
developing is supposed to be thought to
be much higher than the previous year
xylm and I think this varies by species
probably um but anyway so a summary of
of the way we think about this now is
that of how the root stocks of peach
root stocks work is that the DI the
diameter of the water conducting vessels
of the dwarf and root stock are small
smaller this causes the hydraulic
conductance of the root stock in the
water conducting tissue to be lower this
causes the water availability or water
potential in the stems and leaves to be
slightly
less this causes the elongation of stems
to be slightly less and overall Vigor of
the tree is decreased over time and this
is particularly true of the water sprout
parts of the the epicormic shoots uh
this decreases the amount of pruning
needed the decreased pruning reduces the
number of water
sprouts uh that are produced in the
following year because if water sprouts
are produced in response to pruning
pretty much
only uh and this decreases the need for
pruning even more so you have a cumula
effect of less
pruning and this decreases the internal
canopy shading and thus increases shoot
quality and flower Bud development we I
don't show you data on that but
typically the bloom on the on the size
controlling root stocks is much heavier
than the Bloom on the doring on the
vigorous root
stocks
um yeah so uh question is can we
simulate this so I've done a lot of work
with what we call the L Peach model it's
a lyen l stands for lynen Meer it's a
particular modeling language and I'll
just show you uh uh a movie of the
simulation of of of the growth of two
peach trees one on one on a on a
vigorous root stock and one in which the
hydraulic conductance of the root stock
only is reduced by 50% and so if we can
get this to
run um out of this and then we'll click
on the
video Let's see see if see if it'll I
might have to go out and yeah go out
let's get this
one okay let
me um music with it too yeah there
is okay so what we have here are three
identical
trees uh the first uh two years have
already been simulated so uh the the
initial year in the nursery and the
first year then then in the nursery
after they they grown in nursery for a
year they grow they grow a main stem
that's that's in the way we grow the
trees in California that main stem is
then hacked off at knee high
about and then you then you allow uh uh
shoots to grow out of that and then in
the sub in the summer I mean the winter
of the subsequent year so after the
trees are really two years old one year
in the
orchard uh we have we have three types
of pruning here so it's exactly the same
tree uh simulated in each case but
there's three different types of pruning
this is what we call the Dinuba pruning
which there's a group of Growers very
conservative growers in the southern
soken they like to have all their trees
to really just grow like heck in the in
the second year in the Orchard and so
they prune them back to about a foot
stubs or 8 inch stubs three scaffolds
and a perpend on an open vase tree this
one's the same tree except it's sort of
our standard recommend a that is that
you leave these these scaffolds each to
be about a meter
long uh and this
is
yeah anyway uh and then we have what
Scott Johnson and and Kevin Day and
myself are sort of trying to promote is
leaving the tree less hard pruned
selecting some of the fruiting wood off
of here and so on and then letting them
go so we have a simulation now a movie
of of this this subsequent one year's
worth of growth in this
case
uh with for with music for your
pleasure oh I should say what we're
doing uh I forgot to explain what the
model does what the model does is
basically uh it grows the tree and while
it's growing the the growth of the tree
is totally dependent on the carbon
that's assimilated by the leaves of the
tree it basically simulates the
photosynthetic output of every single
leaf and um and then distribute then
that that carbohydrate is distributed
around the tree uh according to the syn
strength of all the individual organs
that are on there and then we have a
whole bunch
of uh submodels in there dictating what
the what individual Shoots look like
depending on if they're epicormic or
proleptic or what have you
uh and
um so you'll see the differences between
the three these two are going to grow a
little bit of fruit as
well so we have spring it's
blooming if you look carefully you see
some green fruit in here that turn
yellow we just had thinning there those
in the front you might have seen the
fruit some fruit
disappear it's simulating every hour of
every
day and now you're going to see Harvest
here pretty quick
there's
Harvest
ch
so um if
you um I I should have stopped it but
the tree on the left that was really
hard pruned ended up to be almost the
same size as a tree in the center and
that's and that's because yeah stop
there you go so this tree ended up to be
almost the same size as this one and
that's because by hard pruning like this
we grew almost exclusively epicormic
shoots which have no stop Point
epicormic shoots grow differently than
and this one has some epicormic these
really tall ones are the water sprouts
that came out of these high heads but
there's many other shoots in here that
are proleptic shoots and this one of
course had many many more proleptic
shoots and still had a few epicormic
shoots where we did a heading cut so it
sort of it sort of explains how you can
actually these Growers that do this are
are set on this because they get these
very uniform trees they have lots of
choices for secondary scaffolds and
everything um whereas you do these and
you have a little more random structure
because you're not forcing as much
growth but it explains why these guys
can be satisfied with this as compared
to the traditional system because by the
end of the season there's not that much
difference and that's really the way
what happens in the field as well
um but you might you you would have
noticed that there were more more fruit
obviously on these and so many of our
Growers are going to less and less
pruning because we're understanding this
more and
more so I want to go back to the thing
here I can get out of
this and back to this but I'm have to
going to have to go all the way back oh
no here we
are uh so yeah right
there so I I want to acknowledge our
collaborators on this project it's it's
been
basically uh 25 years of work um off and
on so in terms of the development of the
root stock initial the initial two Dave
raming was the USDA researcher the
material came from him Scott Johnson
Kevin Day and Jim Doyle we did all of
the field analysis and then control
controller 678 and
9.5 uh Fred Bliss was a faculty member
but Ali aletti was a technician of his
that did almost most of the work and
these guys also have been helping this
is a graduate student and then all of
the physiology initially done by WBO and
we had Boris bili from Italy Jordy
Marcel from Spain Luis Solari from he
was a student from
Uruguay and two two from uh Italy and
one from Brazil and then the modeling
stuff which I really just showed you a
little bit about and that's been sort of
the main occupation of my mental
whatever mental stuff I have left uh we
David D Silva in the last four years has
been really instrumental in that as well
as Romeo Romeo
favro uh is a really interesting guy
he's about 86 now and he was working in
our lab until a year and a half ago on a
voluntary basis for about six years
eight
years um he was a computer scientist
that was at the input at the very
beginning of introduction of computers
into the world into into Commerce he
installed the the first main computer
main frame computer in in Europe back in
the 50s
60s and then these two guys also worked
on the model quite a
bit so I think that's
it thanks for your
attention
yeah uh I have two questions the first
one is uh when did you exactly girle
those trees uh you mention that is a
month I mean two weeks a month before
Harvest or but no no that no in that
case we did it April we did it the first
one was April early April and the second
one I think was late April or early may
I think early yeah I think late April
it said it on the thing but I it was I
just want to make sure so you measure
the uh midday stand keep in mind that
our our our our Bloom and our our spring
is is around March 10 for for uh these
speach varities yeah with all that in
mind but do you think the new dylm
development provides a significant you
know provide significant amount of water
to to those plants let say 2 weeks after
the Garing that's my question apparently
okay now we know that the dylm the
initial movement of sugars up the tree
is all in the zyl the fl's nonfunctional
so the initial movement of sugar up the
tree in the spring is in the xylm so
there's got to be some functional xylm
there's no question about that but
apparently that that new xylm that's
being developed is more efficient or
is that's our only interpretation
and the interesting thing is we look at
we look at that water relations thing
that we see the difference in water
relations it holds up until about the
end of end of June if you measure the
difference in water relations between
trees on war root stocks and and
vigorous roof stocks in July and August
there's there's no significant
difference in the in the stem water
detention usually very difficult to
detect one and my interpretation now is
is
that um is that the new ring of xylm is
being formed and that's act and because
it's that the vessels in that ring are
smaller that that is
actually
hindering the the H hydraulic
conductance of that new Sho
gr and and and the growth of that tree
for that for that early part of the
season when the when you get adequate
new rings of of of U xylm then you have
enough vessels even though they're
smaller to to match the capacity of the
of the requirement of the top that's
that's our interpretation at the present
time
and do you has that been verified
anatomically we haven't we haven't done
that we haven't done that no we we
should do that additional thing looking
at the actually of the the and calculate
the total hydraulic capacity of of that
of the to ring what we did so far was
just look at the new ring all all that
xylm stuff was related to the new ring
but only one section of the new ring I
mean only a microscopic
field my second question is since the uh
D mechanism in pit uh is primarily
limitation of water transport do think
uh with the same root stocks will we see
less DF effect in New York versus
California how about it's a fact on
fruit size cuz water is so important for
fruit size uh well that's I think why we
get the the the problem with with
controller five it has it has small
fruit uh controller five was in the
early earlier nc-140
trial the national root stock trial uh
the people in New York really liked it
because for some reason it has higher uh
cold
tolerance that may be related to this
vessel size too I don't know yeah it's
much safer uh but but the root stop but
but the fruit in California is too small
to be an acceptable root stock for
commercial production in California now
controller six there the next step up
and it's a her blood by Oka one would
think that it would have root a fruit
size problem but for some reason and I'm
not sure we don't understand
why uh Harvest is delayed a week with
controller
six so we think that while it may have
an inherently smaller fruit size if it's
hard at the same time because you add a
weat to it it's able to make
up a bit of the
difference and so it has acceptable
fruit size
so we're quite excited I think actually
that's the other two are then getting
close enough to neag guard that is very
difficult to see a difference in fruit
size so yeah the observation has been
made with apple that if you grab an
inner stem into a three-part tree and
it's dwarfing inner stem the degree of
dwarfing be proportional to the length
of that right same in here same with
this I think the same so so apples and
n it's a more complicated
story but laxo was one of the other
people have reported it also but laxo
and um his student here uh early
student anyway they reported that Ming n
had a had uh a a lower water potential
trees on Sans on Ming n had a lower
water potential than than trees on
seedling or
big that was that was published years
ago already uh but they sort of left it
there I think sort of in the same
conundrum that big bank was in and we
were all in that but the muling N is
also different in that that you have
this overgrowth and there's signs of
some sort of fling compatibility or
something going on in there as
well uh so I think that I think that is
a more complicated root stock
situation but I think is involved but
it's certainly not the whole story yeah
um you hear now and again that
California might be having a drought
issue on the news and so I was just
curious given that you're conducting
hydraulic studies if you maybe had any
special challenges in your research or
something that you had you know that you
have to kind of make amends for I just
was kind of curious about that well
uh yeah we all have to make special
things this particular year because
water is on everyone's mind and
salinity what's what's happening now is
that the so California has a very
complicated water distribution system
all of the tradition many of the
traditional water districts on east side
of the S Valley and the center of the
valley they they all have these grav
grafing fed irrigation
districts uh and and many of those will
be probably getting something like 40 to
60% of the normal
allocation the ones the ones that are on
the uh and those are all local
Irrigation District more or less local
irrigation districts the ones that are
on the federal irrigation or state
irrigation projects like the California
aquaduct basically the the water on the
west side of the San Valley and the
water and that water flow into La all of
that's all of that's in in the
California Water
Project and what happens with that water
is it's basically water that's pumped
out
of uh out of the Delta before the Delta
runs into the the San Francisco Bay so
the water is fresh up it's pumped out of
that up the hill and then and then
reverse gra down the valley
and then pumped a couple more times
every time it gets too low pumped up
high or again
low but that water that water is is
um there well most of the Growers on
that side are going to get zero of their
allocation some of them
20% so those people are are the ones
that are going to be really hurting and
and much of that land this year the
Growers um some Growers of permanent
free crop also have uh have anual crops
Tomatoes melons whatever usually cotton
most of those grow if they if they're
growing two types of crop on different
pieces of land most of them will will
not plant their annual their annual crop
and they'll use whatever water they can
find to keep their perennial crop
alive uh and and they'll do that largely
by pumping the groundwater but the
problem in that area is the groundwater
depending on where you are it can be
very saline or quite
s so right now at the moment everybody
is flipping coins and drawing straws as
to as to whether the lack of water is
going to be the worst thing or whether
the sa the salinity of the water is
going to be the worst thing but but for
sure it's all going to be worse there
there's no doubt about that and then up
north in the s in the Sacramento Valley
there's also similar sort of water
distribution comes out of the Sacramento
River
Hub uh the rice Growers uh there's a lot
of rice in California believe it or not
and the drought State we have we grow a
lot of rice in the in the nor in the in
the Sacramento Valley there will be a
lot some of that won't be planted or
people may plant cuz those people will
probably get 40 to 50% of their
allocation and so a lot of that they
will plant half their land and use the
water from the whole allocation to to do
the half of the land something like that
because the price of rice at the moment
is really good so there's previously we
had when we had a drought a lot of the
price of rice was really low so those
guys up there sold their water to the
people down
south because we have all these water
conveyance systems you can do that
there's a water Market in California
uh but this year that probably won't
happen much
because um agriculture in California
barring the drought is is the
most uh lucrative I've ever seen it in
my in my 30 years
it's 35 years of being at the University
all many crops are in high demand with
high
prices and R walnuts and pistachios are
are are really the market is
unbelievable yes Alan had a question
Alan um yeah I just I wanted to point
out we got similar results as you
mentioned with with apple um what we
found was that at the top of the root
stock the dwarfing stock had a lower
water potential more stress but then as
you went out the branches there was a
decrease in water potential due to the
friction but that was the the slope of
that was the same regardless in the
Canan but what happened is when you got
out to the uh end of the branch you had
the same water
potentials but on the dwarfing stock you
got to the water potential with a 1 Meer
Long Branch and with the U more vigorous
one you started with a higher water
potential so so it took 2 m of growth to
get to that same water potential where
it stopped so the the outside of the
trees all ended up with the same water
potential but it varied with the root
stock at the big at the U center of the
tree really we never we haven't looked
at that down the shoot at all was that
with you and
Bill yeah Bill Bill yeah
okay I had remembered that part of the
St study I don't know that did you
publish that part of the study
um that was 30 years ago I think
so I'll look for it if I did that's okay
I usually just skim the papers for I
wanted to hear
anyway do you have any other questions
thought nothing else all right I'll see
you tonight Helen
okay
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu