this is a production of Cornell
University uh my name is Philip Lanza I
work with Louie um my
presentation is called harvesting
insights with agronomic
contextualization I like to thank chat
GPT for coming up with the clever title
for me again um so my presentation is
going to be in this format I'm talk
about why I'm doing what I'm doing then
go over my objectives briefly and then
take a few questions at the end if we
have
time um so as we know you know we have a
sustainability problem with large scale
agriculture we need to continue to
increase output to feed the world but
they're starting to have more and more
bad effects from over feralization you
know pesticide usage um pollution from
Machinery fossil fuel usage all of that
so it's a challenging problem um
thankfully a lot of people are studying
this we're working on improving things
and and maintaining sustainable
intensification so we don't have like
ecological and environmental disaster um
the thing that's kind of a barrier is
it's often difficult to get Farmers to
adopt practices you know so it's
challenging because there's a lot of
complexity in these systems and if
something goes out to a farmer and it
doesn't work then it kind of erods trust
between researchers and farmers and you
know that they'll be less likely to
adopt things so it's important important
as researchers that whatever we do like
the bucket says we do it
right so one way to address this is
doing on Farm experimentation this is
doing experiments on farms uh we answer
questions in production environments um
two main types are scientist Le which
make things kind of like this where you
know it's complete random randomized
block design or strip trials um
researchers design these so they're
replicated usually they evaluate the
dependent variable given whatever this
looks like a nitrogen trial usually
they're smaller scale because the
complexity of the
design doesn't allow them to be done by
like a farmer you know no Fields look
like this in actual production the good
thing is they produce clean data um it's
easier to evaluate and we can really
determine say like causality and things
from this the bad thing is they're
really done in production conditions so
it limits their ability to be
implemented you know know and work
exactly as we think another type is
farmered where Farmers routinely do
experiments on their fields um you know
whether doing like uh variety trial or
different nitrogen rates different
application timings these are the things
that we've been working with where you
know we don't impose any experimental
design the farmers do what they do
natively now the challenge with this if
you look at the top one this farmer did
the control around the border of their
field field which if you know Agronomy
is not a standard condition so basically
it wasn't an effective control but other
ones do more sophisticated designs like
this one at the bottom where they did
paired strip trials with a control
between you know and they really
accounted for their data well um so you
know the challenge with this is often
they aren't replicated you know a farmer
might do it on one maybe two Fields um
so you have maybe a strip to evaluate
other things are there are a lot of
confounding factors we have to account
for
um good and bad is that they're large
scale you know they cover the whole
field but that's a lot of data to work
with a lot of complexity to work with
and they're often subject to incomplete
or um inconsistent data a lot of farmers
say record their management data in a
notebook you know so there's no easy way
to get that if they even record it
sometimes like yield monitors break so
we don't get yield for the year
especially um the really good thing is
they're done in real world production
conditions these are things that the
farmers are interested in learning
they're more likely to adopt these
practices and the the findings the
strong point of this is they're
immediately applicable because they're
done on the farmer field so the
conditions are the conditions you know
so anything you find will probably work
and and be
applicable now one way to address this
as Lou said is is we're trying to apply
observational research methods to
agronomic systems um these are commonly
done in medicine social sciences and are
good for studying complexity also where
you can't necessarily impose a treatment
you know like you can't infect someone
with covid and say oh what what happens
you know you have to kind of use
existing data and
see you know what you can gather from it
so kind of data mining data driven
methods work really well um I like doing
data driven methods I don't like doing
regular statistics so great for me and
um you know they require context which
are kind of objective data to
characterize what's going on so for
purposes of agronomic observational
research in my projects I Define this as
the biophysical and environmental Co
variants present in the experimental
area so like soil properties weather
terrain weather all these good things um
One Challenge though is how do we
collect these data at the scale
necessary to do large experiments and
really leverage all the on Farm
experimentation going on one way is to
go out in the field and pull samples you
know we we do this it provides really
good data here we are taking so samples
and microbiological samples for a you
know biological nitrogen product um the
challenge with this is it's a lot of
Labor you know you can't send a 100
people out into a field to pull these
you have to pay to process them so that
limits it scale and then fields are
really big you know this one's over a
kilometer so to pull enough samples at a
density sufficient to fully characterize
it it isn't really
feasible um thankfully there are other
sources of context data that are online
um you know weather data Precision
agricultural sensor data like yield Maps
uh as applied maps all these things we
can use environmental data like from
different weather data products uh
biophysical data like soil properties
terrain data um and this is easier to
use but the challenge is it's still very
labor intensive because they're in
different sources different formats it's
hard to kind of integrate them and get
these raw data to produce
knowledge you know things that we can
act upon um so it also limits its
feasibility for a large scale
application which you know is better
than go and pull 100,000 samples but
still not awesome so we get to my
dissertation which is developing novel
tools supporting research in agronomic
systems with a focus on integrating
biophysical and environmental
contextualization data in on form
research that's a lot to say but
basically I want to make it easy for
people to use this context data to apply
obervational research techniques so that
way we can quickly come up with some
solutions to the challenges that we're
facing and you know sustainably produce
food to feed the world without
destroying the environment and the
ecology so here are my objectives the
first is to develop a tool I call geod
Dart to facilitate retrieval of this
cont contextualization data um the
second is to develop a system using
these data to identify areas of
anomalous crop response within fields
and then lastly demonstrate using output
from the stad system that these
techniques work you know and and kind of
do a proof of concept saying we can do
this we can go for with this and apply
it to other types of
experimentation I'm going to talk about
my first objective now it is developing
the geospatial data retrieval tool I
call geod Dart um it fa facilitates
retrieving contextualization data so you
know one challenge a lot of people can
do scripting to get things but it ends
up you know in a lot of different places
people need to learn to program to kind
of do this it's often challenging and
then you have to go find the script to
get this and things like that so I
wanted to make a centralized way to do
this and also allow people who can't
code to do this so I designed a website
it's the web-based user interface that's
pretty easy to use that then hits a
python backend to retrieve the data do
geospatial processing things like that
um quickly you know the data products
I'm pulling now are all from Google
Earth engine which is like a huge
repository of all kind of spatial data
sets um I'm pulling things that are
relevant to agronomic systems such as
weather via grimit which is a Daily 4
kilometer resolution data set Polaris
soil properties um after I did this I
found out there's some limitations with
it so I'm planning to switch to the
soless soil data set which is supposed
to be a good bit better um I'm pulling
hourly weather from rtma if you need
really fine temporal resolution you us
drought monitor which is 2 kilm spatial
drought intensity severity data set um
Optical remote sensing from Sentinel 2
and um we can calculate things like
vegetation indices to characterize crop
response and other things um and then
elevation data such as like uh you know
slope elevation aspect I'm going to
calculate things like terrain ruggedness
index and all this is from the USGS is
3D elevation program um one meter is a
lot better for infield usage but there
are some strips where it's Miss 10 meter
covers the whole country so where one
meter is not available I'm using 10
meter and here's a quick overview of the
user interface for the website this is
what people will be interacting with I
wanted to make it really easy to use um
the website also supports uh user
profiles so you have to authenticate you
can granularly say you can access this
but not this you can assign users to rol
say like you know an internal lab versus
once I make this public say like Farmers
so we can control what people access to
and and deliver relevant information
while protecting data privacy um so once
someone's logged in you pick what
product you want um you can pick active
only so when I implement the
functionality for Solus I'm going to
disable Polaris but if somebody wants
that they can uncheck that box and get
Polaris you pick what bands you want
from the data it all comes in as a
multiband roster so you say Okay I want
precipitation whatever whatever and
here's a completed Farm you can add
things like file prefixes to help
organize your data when it comes in also
I'm storing metadata about this in a
database so you can put form name field
name project name and then depending on
what product you pick you enter relevant
search criteria such as a start date end
date you can paste in your area of
Interest like a field boundary you can
also upload a file like a shape file
geop package geojson um lots of other
formats and then the system will extract
that for you
then you click submit download request
what that does is hits the python
backend which initiates the data
transfer and collection from Google
Earth engine if you want to clip it to
the area of Interest it'll do that basic
geospatial processing you can um
generate like vegetation indices so that
way if you want ndvi you can pull that
and this the overview of the system I
could talk a lot more about this but I
have 25
minutes okay um how I'm going to
evaluate this is basically if it works
designed um you know so all are all the
requested data products retrieved for
the correct ranges areas are the
metadata store correctly is it um
download L sent one thing I forgot to
say is right now if you're in our lab
we're going to store the data and index
in the database so we can do spatial
searches metadata searches to retrieve
it if you're an external user you're
going to get a link to download the data
and it'll stay there for 48 hours after
which it's deleted to conserve resources
but you know I want to make sure that
works um and we've used this in a 23
field year experiment to pull the data
everything works since then I've added a
couple of additional features I need to
go through and test but the plan is to
you know run everything again for like
20 fields for a growing season check
everything make sure it works if that's
good this objective is
good um next objective is to develop a
spatial temporal anomaly detection
system I call stads and that's to detect
areas of anomalous crop response at
subfield
scales um and why this is important is
because if you're designing an
experiment or interpreting results and
say you have a strip where it's like a
really anomalously bad area and you
aren't aware of that it can like skew
your results um so very briefly how this
system works in detecting the anomalies
is I have a group of field boundaries uh
that some crop scouting firms were kind
of enough to provide me with um we
filter using the USDA crop land data
layer to find right now corn fields if I
can't get enough data for The Scouting
to evaluate this I'm going to expand to
like soybean and wheat maybe um and then
from there we have the grain Fields I'm
clustering based upon um soil weather
and terrain characteristics so you know
I want to compare anomalies from things
that are roughly similar to where you
know it's accurate um from there I'm
generating um a trend surface using a
combination of random forest and then I
do regression cre on the residuals to
improve the accuracy of the trend
surface for indvi and how I'm doing that
I'm pulling each one of these pointing
like you can see one of all of these
data products at you know a 30 meter
grid Point by Point by Point um right
now I'm doing 100 meter but I'm going to
reduce it to um increase special
resolution and making a trend surface
from there where then you know it
predicts what it should be given ABCD
you know and then from there I'm
checking the actual ndvi and calculating
a residual so any residuals that are
Beyond a certain threshold right now I'm
using 1.5 standard deviations plus or
minus um will be identified as anomalous
you know and if it's below what it
should be that's negative deviant if
it's above it's positive deviant um you
know things I need to figure out are
like evaluate other Trend surface
production methods so I'm going to do
like a generalized additive model with
regression cing and I may do a it's
called B is
basian additive regression trees which
is kind of like a random Forest that
includes like confidence intervals which
would produce kind of more like
certainty um so I need to evaluate that
figure out makes the most accurate Trend
surfaces and then play with the
threshold to to find tune the system to
identify things better
um so that's how that works here's some
example output of the Prototype I have
now um red areas were identified as
being anomalously low indvi versus what
the prediction surface said this is that
30 m spatial resolution you can kind of
see the square size um and this is a
good balance between computational
efficiency and allowing the farmers to
manage it effectively um so these two
and green were kind of good they're
within the field you know that'll be
something we would Scout and evaluate
but I need to fine-tune the system
because things like this you know the
building is going to have a ninous low
crop response because it's a building so
I need to be able to detect these
objects in fields and say this isn't a
crop you know exclude this and another
thing which is going to be easier to fix
is um this strip here I think it's due
to mixed pixel effect because the border
of the field always isn't exactly
aligned with the field boundaries so
we're getting some kind of mixed effect
from the headline and the field which is
then negatively scoo that down um so
what I'm going to do for this is just
buffer in by like 30 m to to make sure
that all of the pixels we evaluate are
like pure pixels for for the
field and then the tempor aspect of this
system is for every overpass where we
can get indvi um I'm going to do the
same process and then uniquely identify
each anomaly So based upon whether it's
new stable growing shrinking by looking
at the area things like ratio of
perimeter to area we can tell if the
shapes changing um that'll give us
insights as to the cause you know and
this isn't causality where we can say
this is is definitively the cause but
based upon agronomic knowledge we can
kind of say well if this anomaly is
persistent it's probably something
that's persistent like a soil property
or you know just a block of concrete in
the field that we can't detect from
remote sensing whereas if it's small and
starts to grow it's probably something
like a pest disease or if it's transient
you know when it's dry and then it rains
and it goes away it's probably like the
soil moisture capacity is reduced there
for some reason um so using this I think
we can then Target more like focused
research and scouting to to Really
determine causality but in the short
term we can say okay well this is an
anomalous area we're not going to put
our trial right here or like we can
account for some uncertainty in our
result interpretation because this
included an anomalous
area so how am I going to evaluate this
this uh summer partnering with some crop
scouting firms right now Western New
York crop Management Associates maybe a
couple others um the plan is to have
them go Scout 100 areas ident identified
as being an anomalous and just look and
see you know like look at the plant see
if they're like really worse or better
and then look for things like um pest
disease weed pressure lodging nutrient
status saw moisture notable Weeds now
saw moisture you know when they go
through the fields they go kind of
quickly so it'll be like is it standing
water is it muddy is it very dry is it
you know
anything really visible we're not
pulling like a probe or anything um and
then just do like you know paired
sampling 10 meters in the anomaly 10
meters outside of the anomaly so we can
kind of comp compare and see well you
know the field should be more or less
the same in in this small area we can
see if this is like an actual anomaly or
just an artifact of the system and if
you know I think if I get over like 70%
I'll say this was successful the system
was able to detect things and I think as
I go through and fine-tune it detection
resolution will kind of
increase so the last objective is to
demonstrate that you know using these
observational techniques aided by the
tools I've developed can improve um kind
of result interpretation by doing a
comparative analysis of correlation
between soil health and yield which is a
commonly accepted thing we know this is
true um Harold and Jose were kind enough
to let me use their awesome production
environment soil Health Data which they
go and Pull and get like a lot of soil
properties and come up with a soil
Health score um we're going to get the
yield data from cooperator farmer and
and agronomic firms right now we have a
um an overlap of about 161 Fields where
they have data and we have the
boundaries I'm hoping to increase that a
bit but even if we get like half I I
think that'll be a good representative
sample to show the utility of this um
and then it's kind of a simple analysis
but there aren't as many confounding
factors so we can show really like using
this context will increase strength of
result interpretation account for some
certainty and um going to do this with
her without anomalies the
experimental design I'm going to segment
all of the fields into four groups uh
one will be all the fields with and
without anomaly so just like raw data
like we would do without any context um
next will be the ones where the Stat
system didn't identify any anomalous
areas then Fields with lower percentage
of anomalous areas and larger um how I'm
going to determine this excuse
me is I'm going to do a grid search and
just eval valate what percentage of
anomalous area has strongest correlation
um this provides kind of a more granular
evaluation than doing something like
quantiles where I don't know how much
area is going to be anomalous you know I
I don't know how that's going to fall so
this I think lets me get a better uh
idea of what what I should use and then
evaluate the correlation strength as
calculated by Pearson's R between the
soil Health score and the yield per acre
and my thoughts and and this will be
hopefully it works out that the fields
with no anomalies will have a stronger
correlation versus those with smaller
versus larger you know and then the ones
all Fields should fall somewhere in
there so my evaluation is like okay if
if the fields with no anomalies have a
strong correlation then we're accounting
for this it's strengthening result
interpretation and we're good and also
you know I want to demonstrate that we
can do this at scale and people can use
this to do other things um such as like
you know variety trials you can you can
use this context to do that you can um
plan Scout CR crop scouting operations
you can um do lots of other good things
any anything that's spatial I think can
benefit from this
technology so in closing I forgot to
reset the time I don't know how much
time I have left but i' like to thank
everyone here for com and watch me on
you know the wrong day and a different
time especially you know Louie and my
committee David Diana for helping me
really like strengthen my scientific
knowledge uh my family for moving across
the country with me so I could do this
um everyone in Farmers data lab Alex
Katie om car you know it's been awesome
working all with all of you uh everybody
in Dan's lab for giving me baked goods
and smiles and encouraging me and then
uh Western New York crop manager
Associates especially Avery de garer for
working with me to get data and give me
feedback on my products um New York so
Health lab Harold Joseph Ceda for
funding some work uh people in computer
science for helping me figure some stuff
out everybody on 10th for blad Bradfield
from like bringing light to Bradfield
and all of you for coming watching me so
thanks and um I don't know how much time
I have left but I'll take a few
questions
now we have some couple of minutes
question yeah what do you think you're
missing in the data stack that you're
developing what are the limits of the
data products that you have and what do
you wish you had I wish I had like more
consistent management data you know like
that's that's hugely important
uh we're working on another way to
collect that kind of like a web form but
you know that that's I'd say hugely
impactful on what happens also like
variety and things like that so yeah got
an idea for aw yeah thank
you H great talk I was wondering with
the geod dart um as you're developing
this or used by these Farmers um what is
your process for making sure that what
you're developing will be useful for
them how are you engaging them in
dialogue about the product that you're
developing sure sure right now it's it's
tail it for researchers um you know
future work what I want to do is put
like an analytics engine on top of it so
they can say Okay I want to get crop
response um driving you know driving
development for researchers I'm a
researcher I know it works we've talked
to people in the lab and try to make it
easy for us but also over the past
couple of years we've gone out and
interviewed Farmers about what's of
products they use how do they get their
data what would kind of ease their pain
point so kind of iners communication um
I think maybe a more formalized study of
like use case analysis might be useful
um certainly if I want to commercialize
it but right now you know at least to
get started I want to make it for
researchers so we can kind of use this
easier all right our speaker thanks
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu