this is a production of Cornell
University I'm going to talk a little
fast because there's a lot of stuff I
want to go over I'm from the state of
Minnesota crazy place the only place to
elect a professional
wrestler as Governor as governor and not
many places do that some things about
Minnesota second largest variation in
temperature in the continental US 38c
to-
53c 90,000 Mi of Shoreline more than
California Florida Hawaii and combined
we measure every
puddle the largest population of people
of Scandinavian Somalian M descent
outside of those countries so we are
somewhat diverse I'm at the great
University of Minnesota 55,000
undergraduates it's big School home of
Norman borlo won the Nobel Peace Prize
honey crisp apples from Jim Luby in my
department something happened
oh and where they discovered the
pacemaker which is that strange machine
down on the bottom metronics spun off of
um largest city is the City of
Minneapolis Minnesota a couple million
people and Minneapolis has a Park Board
I'm chair of the park board the park
board existed before the City of
Minneapolis and so I help run um a park
system with 183 parks and 50 recreation
centers 1,00 kid sports teams I have my
own police force which is
something
6,732 acres of land and natural area
that we manage and then there's a bunch
of other statistics I'm not going to
talk about that now but I do know there
are some people who are interested in
urban agriculture I'm instead going to
talk about plants and stresses in
Plants now some changes that have
happened since the 60s why did it even
get into this area the crops we grow in
the 60s which is the last time a lot of
work in uh CO2 photosynthesis and some
of that work in floriculture was done
has changed the industry was cut flowers
and potted plants now the industry is
based on bedding plants and the number
of species we grow is increased
dramatically energy costs have increased
and profit margins have decreased
dramatically in the industry we now have
HPS and LED lighting which was not as
common place back then and we have shade
curtains and environmental control
computers but we don't have information
to put in them and temperature and CO2
levels have increased when I was in
graduate school with Marvin the standard
was 333 parts per million right now it's
so there is little to no information on
lighting temperature and CO2 standards
for the current crops we grow even the
geraniums we grow now are different than
the geraniums that were grown in the 60s
and 70s and we don't have any
information to utilize this fantastic
equipment that we have that run our
green houses I also want to talk about a
little bit how we stress our plants out
on a regular basis and often don't
appreciate it we have cool season CR
crops and War SE warm season crops and
this is a relative growth rate curve of
two kinds of turf but notice with cool
season crops and I'll show you data to
this effect 20° there's a maximum C and
notice above 20° you actually start
having a decline and I'll start showing
that with photosynthesis and development
rate on some common crops we grow I
think we stress our plants out commonly
and have no appreciation that we are in
fact doing that and I'll show some
evidence of that I'm going to talk about
abiotic stresses is Neil mentioned I'm
going to talk about light temperature
and CO2 I'm going to talk a little bit
about biotic stresses and then I work in
a variety of other areas and I just want
to give you a little bit of an idea what
some of those are this is some data of
the average daily light integral of
moles of light per day in January
throughout the United States and you can
see that you as Minnesota is at 2 to
four and at most six moles of light and
that there are parts of the United
States that benefit greatly from adding
supplemental lighting and you can see
the Cornell is in there as well as
Minnesota why do we light well when we
do light there's some benefits here we
have a graph of Daily Light integral and
this is cutting yield per pot and this
is for taking uh cuting off of a pot
stock plants and we can see that as the
Daily Light integral goes up the cutting
yield goes up and we can also see with
two different levels of CO2 the yield
goes up but in generally yield of any
crop be it Tomatoes Greenhouse Peppers
lettuce dry weight is proportionally
increases with
photosynthesis this is actually a
picture from Neil I think isn't it Neil
you recognize that
picture Neil took this picture a long
time ago there's this is purple wave
petunia with night Interruption lighting
and this is supplemented with 150 micro
of uh additional High HPS light and this
is just to demonstrate both of these
have long days but which one flowers
quicker the one with the higher light
level or
par says standard photosyn synthesis
curve that's been used forever in the
day basically shows that as absorb light
or par goes up CO2 assimilation goes up
there's some region that's typically in
the winter in our area where plants are
light limited but once you get up to a
certain level which is typically around
4 to 600 micro saturation occurs and the
plant photosynthesis is CO2
limited so we started collecting data we
use a l core 6400 we did 25 different
species so we have huge data sets I'm
just going to show you some brief ones
to make some points this is impatience
you can see the
impatience
um par go as par goes up PN goes up
until you reach approximately 400 micro
of light okay a single no you'll see
some standard deviations so what we do
is we take five different plants so each
each one is it's five separate curves
from five separate leaves and then
that's replicated again three times over
time horizontal leaves
or one horizontal Leaf so we use a l cor
6400 which clamps right on yep and I'll
come back to some something related to
that question a little bit this is um
from a tomato grower this is bushel Boy
tomatoes um they each of these
represents a different cultivar I just
want to show that within a species even
within a single Greenhouse you can have
very different rates of photosynthesis
and you can have saturation occurring at
different spots this is 750 micro so
it's higher than the impatients and
notice that this particular cultivar was
still increasing so there's dramatically
different responses to increasing light
suggesting that even within the same
Greenhouse there should be different
light management strategies based on the
cultivar that's
used in addition we looked at some Leaf
filtering and this has not been
considered really but here's coas and
here's panicum a grass and a coas and
then we just measured light intensity As
you move down through the canopy showing
that you have significant filtering now
these plants were just barely touching
okay but this just goes to show you that
only 60% of the incident light in a
colia canopy actually gets to the middle
of the plant and by the time you get to
the bottom of the plant you're down to
18% of of Radiance that actually can
penetrate in contrast of course with the
grass it's better 80% and
55% and then we shade we have these
shade curtain systems you have them in
your Greenhouse but how do we decide
when to close the
shade who decides Bill who
decides you divine
it we Divine it there's no
information with which to use to
identify when we do this now I'll tell
you that most green houses use a
standard of 3 to 4,000 foot candles
which is comparable to around 600 to 800
micro and then the shade system starts
closing
also in our systems that we have if you
go out to your green houses the light
sensors that control the shade systems
where does where are they they're on a
weather station that's on outside of the
greenhouse
okay in general only 60% of incident
light enters the greenhouse you have
more than that because you have single
pane glass in a lot of your green houses
most places have exite or double poly or
another kind of poly that diffuses the
light so yours is actually better and
the shap cloth systems typically the the
standard shade cloth is 55% light
reduction curtain that comes
across therefore if it if you use a
typical shade system with 55% when it
closes at 600 micro of light okay
Radiance of the top of the canopy after
getting into the greenhouse and going
through a shade system is all the way
reduced to 198
micromols and that's at the top of the
plant and if you go to the middle of the
plant in a typical C canopy you're down
to all the way down to a third of the
actual light that comes in to look at an
impatience curve at 600 this is where
you're at getting into the greenhouse
and and the shade cloth system closed
and then this is halfway down on the
canopy down to
119 you've reduced your photosynthesis
in that particular instance from close
to 7 okay all the way down to just above
two a third of the photosynthesis you've
effectively starved your plant at that
point and green houses are routinely
doing this that they're over shading all
the time which is creating significant
problems that they're not aware of so
for instance in a ro cut rose Greenhouse
or a greenhouse veget tomato uh facility
they have more blind choots at in those
facilities with roses and they have less
fertile flowers with tomatoes and the
whole problem was because of the shade
system because they did weren't using
good numbers on the shade system the
solution first of all is quite simple
take the meter that runs the system take
it off the top of the pole outside of
the greenhouse and move it into the
greenhouse into the middle of the canopy
where the plants are
growing it's not too complicated okay
it's very simple and straightforward why
not simply set reset the figure reset
the Fig you can but the problem is this
that during you know we're in the North
and the sun comes up and up here it
comes up in Minneapolis it gets up 23
degrees above the Horizon on Christmas
and then goes back down again when the
light barely comes up like that more
skips off the glass and so still this so
in other words your what gets in the
greenhouse changes depending on the sun
angle so simply the best thing is just
put it in the greenhouse which none of
the greenhouse companies do and which
actually absolutely would be the best
thing for all of you to do and then run
the shade system off that that works for
any Greenhouse I don't know if a single
Greenhouse in the United States that has
the light sensor where the plants are
okay wishing topics the
temperature the world is a warm place
and it's getting warmer okay it's a
premise that that I work off of I work
in a lot of heat stress we are
routinely causing heat stress in our
crops and most of don't appreciate that
now plants naturally try to do things
they'll reflect light as best they can
in warm
places but we often will stress many of
our crops bushel Boy tomatoes which is a
large large Greenhouse tomato producer
their lowest yield is the summer which
is not what you would expect but that's
when yield is the lowest why is it the
lowest when we we started this research
project because of them it's simply
because of heat stress that occurs on
tomatoes okay species differ in the
optimal temperature for photosynthesis
and that optimal temperature can
actually change as a season
progresses okay it's my belief that
we're R routinely reducing
photosynthesis by growing plants too
warm I'll show you some
examples here's a curve this is um
pansy temperature C there's three light
levels 300 600 and 900 micromoles and
here's PN and you can see the pansy PN
is optimal at 20
C okay you can also see that as you go
above 20° C which the green houses
probably are even today that
photosynthesis starts to
decline and you can see this on the
plants here's two plants and sorry for
it's in Fahrenheit there's constant 20 C
on the left and you have 30 C on the
right you can pretty clearly see the 30
C pansy has less photosynthesis that's
it's occurred with that
crop there's a group of crops that I
would say are mid-range this is Gerra
and you can see it is an optimal
temperature between 20 and
25 and then you can see a shift so
further with po Zetta where you'll have
an optimal temperature with po Zetta
around 30° C and this is why we can
raise pointsetta stock plants in a
greenhouse during the
summer but a question we started asking
is why or what is the justification or
cause for these responses for these
curves to shift because the
photochemistry
should be essentially the
same we started looking at stomates and
just plain old stomal conductance and
stodal
behavior and if you remember the pansy
plot this is actually temperature versus
stodal
conductance you can see it's quite high
and as temperature increased the
stomates actually
closed the limitation that occurred with
photosynthesis may be associated with
closure of
stomates okay
okay if we look at
Gerra and look at the stomatal
conductance with Gerra we can see that
we also had here was around where we had
the optimal temperature and then you can
see the decline
again suggesting that frankly if the
stomates closes of course the plant is
going to have less
photosynthesis and that may be part of
the justification for
that something else we looked at is
shortterm high
temperature okay what we found was that
a short term and by what short term 2
hours okay now we focus on temperatures
that are not temperatures that people
would call heat shock there's lots of
research on heat shock and that
typically is at temperatures of 40 to 45
C we're looking at temperatures that are
30 to 40 that plants see on a very
common basis in a
greenhouse but we asked the question if
we let the temperatures heat up to 95
degrees fenhe for 2 hours
was there any impact on a plant and
there
was this is
a uh graph of par on the bottom versus
PN and you can see the a typical curve
right here but look at what happened if
the plants were exposed the 2 hours at
35c and we redid the curve we had a
fully a 59% reduction in the maximum
photosynthesis the plant could do we
went back in the next day and measured
again we were still depressed the next
day it came up it took 3 days 3 days for
the plant to recover from that single 95
degree
exposure we worked on some other crops
this is petunia this is glow lavender
Shades we saw the same response
significant depression and 3 days to
come back up so these short-term high
temperature exposures can have a long a
3-day or more effect Growers are in fact
doing this why because they want to save
money they let their Greenhouse
temperatures increase at the end of the
day to capture
heat and keep the greenhouse closed
hoping that they'll keep the heat moving
into the
night now the Israelis have did have
done some work with this actually as
well they did work with field
tomatoes and part of the they saw the
midday depression in photosynthesis that
often occurs and so what they did is
they irrigated the field tomatoes and
cooled the leaves when the leaves got
really hot at that one time of the day
and they've found the significant they
got a significant increase in yield as a
result of that and it eliminated the
midday depression of photosynthesis that
occurred from that high temperature I
wonder if we could apply some of these
Concepts in green houses as well or
Greenhouse tomato production essentially
anytime the temperature exceeds the
maximum you should do whatever you can
to try to reduce the
temperature um to the optimal
temperature range I'll mention one other
thing we called around then we started
looking for what are the fundamental
differences between heat tolerant plants
with respect to flowering and heat
intolerant so what we did is we called
companies that produce flowers beding
plants of different kinds send us a
geranium that's very heat tolerant and
send us a geranium that's very heat
intolerant and then we did
photosynthetic response curves and in
every case and these are across
companies and across species in every
case the heat tolerant plant which is in
red always had a higher photosynthetic
rate than the heat intolerant
plant suggesting that there may be some
association with heat tolerance as well
and it brings to mind we did some work
on some arabidopsis as
well everyone works on a rabbit opsis at
one point or another and what we did is
we looked at how different kinds of heat
stresses we did 1 Hour 2 Hour 4 Hour 8
Hour 16 hour how these different
stresses at different temperatures so we
imposed all different kinds of stress
because the the term stress is a
difficult term to Define because
because how do we Define it you know
what is it is it 8 hours at 28 degrees
or 1 hour at 36
degrees and what we found is a very
strange relationship and this is we
published this back in 2005 and we
looked at these are we evaluated a
number of different arabidopsis strains
but what we did is we put it onto a
degree day model and the data fit almost
too close it's one of these situations
where the graduate student comes back
and gives you something and you think
they had to have moved points but you
can see these points fit the models and
what this was was this is the data
suggested there was a cumulative effect
of these different stresses okay with a
degree hour concept over 32°
okay and that for whatever reason when
we exceeded
225°
hours okay over 32° you could see that
we went from no abortion to completely
aborting all the flowers on a Rabbid
opsis we don't understand this but it
didn't matter how the stresses were
arranged in other words a 38° stress for
3 hours hours or
34° for more time it was the cumulative
effect in degre hours over 32
Dees so taken together if you look at
the stomatal conductance stuff we
have it brings to mind a couple
questions do some plants either produce
more ABA okay those plants that were
heat sensitive do they produce prod more
AB in response to a Chron chronic high
temperature
stress or are they more
responsive to the high temperature
stress to the same endogenous ABA level
because the responses we're seeing time
and time again are related to stomatal
closure not any damage to the photo
system in the temperature range I'm
talking
about okay okay can stomatal
conductance after a single stress be a
way that we can screen for heat
tolerance
because after heat stress even a 2-hour
heat stress if the St stomates are
staying open and the plant is still
actively photosynthesizing it likely is
going to be more heat tolerant than one
that is not so this is a screen protocol
that can be
used
CO2 we went back and started looking at
CO2 all the greenh houses in the United
States people who've been around for a
while remember there used to be CO2
burners in green houses we got away from
them because the burners would not work
properly and they'd release ethylene
you'd have disasters and so people got
away from using CO2 burners so if you go
around to green houses now in
floriculture there's next to no CO2
being used here's
cyclen down here is ambient all the way
down here look at the degree of
responsiveness that you can get on
cyclan by increasing
CO2 here's Greenhouse Tomatoes now this
particular grower is Greenhouse tomato
Growers and Greenhouse vegetable Growers
do inject CO2 typically up to 800 parts
per million so you can
see that's here and some of these
species still would benefit but the
bottom line is there was huge huge
responses to CO2 more than what we
appreciate we went into the research
green houses and looked at what are our
CO2 levels on a sunny day in January
it's the meter reading 193 parts per
million 193 parts per where did the CO2
go the plants used it up the new green
houses we have we've spent so much
effort and time making them
tight that the CO2 levels in the green
houses are actually significantly
depleted significantly depleted and we
don't even really appreciate this to
give you an
idea this is 1 hour under would be
considered low light medium light and
high light started at 388 1 hour in a
low light greenhouse the rate the CO2
level drop to 370 1 hour in medium light
down to 340 1 hour in high light all the
way down to 310 in one hour in a single
hour okay now I can tell you if you have
all kinds of high pressure sodium lights
up there after 2 3 hours your plants if
they're down to 190 parts per million
they're not using all that light You're
simply wasting the
light the new open roof green houses
that people recognize gives you Superior
growth in the industry part of the
reason I believe is frankly that these
have CO2 levels that are similar to
ambient CO2 and they're not CO2
depleted the addition of CO2 is the
number one most cost-effective way to
actually increase photosynthesis in a
greenhouse today not all the lighting
it's number one if I take a CO2 sensor
and go into a canopy on a bench on any
of your canopies okay it you'll check
and you'll find that your CO2 level
inside that canopy is often around two
to 300 parts per
million okay even when the greenhouse is
venting because you get this boundary
layer that's that forms on the bench
itself in some cases doing nothing more
than circulating your air at least
equalizes the CO2 level within the
greenhouse so you don't have depletion
within a canopy at least you'll get up
to 380 if you're bringing in air from
outside
and I think in our experimental green
houses and in our growth Chambers we are
commonly depleting or growing plants and
depleted CO2 levels that are actually
dramatically affecting our results and
in some cases invalidating them because
the plant may not even be able to use
the light that you're providing in the
growth chamber
itself switch gears a little bit with
succulents there's a lot of interest in
succulents this is just to
show this is a crown of thorns and suck
respond as other plants to increasing
CO2 this is during the
day now there are plants the this is
aaria and aeonium these take up CO2 at
night not all what we consider to be
Camp plants actually do take up CO2 at
night we study a number of cacti and
they're taking up CO2 during the day in
many cases the assumption is that
they're only taking CO2 up at night and
that's not the case also orchids
phenopsis orchids will take up CO2
during the day but this is frag
midium and this is the beginning of the
night and this is CO2 uptake and you can
see pretty clearly that this Orchid
takes up CO2 at night only suggesting if
you're producing this Orchid that you
should actually be injecting CO2 at
night so there's
differences I'm going to move along
quick high temperature slowing of
development rate Leaf unfolding rate
this is an old graph I've used from
African Violets follows this standard
line so this is pretty common curve for
lots of plants we have we have an
optimal temperature and frankly Leaf
unfolding rate often is optimized around
right around 85 degrees
Celsius and this was developed here's
African violet you can see Leaf number
increasing up to here and then you can
see a decrease and this is what I want
to focus
on because we have decreases this for
whatever reason this temperature is
almost Sentinel to lots of things this
is melon fly egg development and doesn't
it look an awful lot like the graph we
just
saw but my point is this when the
temperature exceeds the Optima which in
Greenhouse production it commonly does
we actually slow the rate of leaf
unfolding and slow the crop down in its
development rate
okay these hot temperatures and right
now your leaf temperatures remember one
thing if it's 85° in the greenhouse your
Leaf temperature is above 90 and
approaching 95 you were actually on the
other end of that curve and your crop is
actually starting to slow it'll take
longer to flower it's underappreciated
area using the standard curve if we go
from 85 to 95 that same plant to unfold
one leaf will now Take 5 days instead of
3.3 you've slowed Leaf unfolding
approximately by a
third
so to come back again we have a number
of crops that are down in this area and
we have temperatures that are routinely
going from 20 up to 35 C and we are
routinely decreasing photosynthesis as
part of that process and we're routinely
decreasing the leaf unfolding rate and
actually slowing the crop development in
that
process and we are routinely closing our
stamata and someone was talking about
Edge burn on
lettuce well high temperatures
encouraging Leed burn on lettuce um you
can kind of understand where that comes
from if the stomates are closing of
course the plant is going to have
difficulty taking up calcium in that
scenario now we've gone through all
different kinds of crops I'm not going
to go through this and identified what
happens if you decrease
temperatures and the timing of that and
then we've integrated that into a
package that everyone has access to and
if you if any of you haven't tried this
program it's a wonderful program it's
called virtual grower it's free for
everyone USDA has it it's used for
modeling crop growth temperature you can
literally take your greenhouse and
identify how much more it's going to
cost if you switch the outer covering on
the greenhouse or not so that's how we
pull it together the last thing is
biotic
stresses I think most of us appreciate
that when a plant is attacked it
releases volatiles that go to other
plants sometimes within the same species
sometimes other species and tell that
plant that it's being attacked plants
communicate via volatiles
there's a plant this is from data that
is not mine from 2001 this is showing
allness that's uninfested and here's an
nness that is infested and here's the GC
depicting the
dramatic expression and variety of
volatiles that are produced after
infestation this is also a recent
picture just showing you the the degree
to the sophistication this is a recent
paper so the insect lays an egg this is
on a rabbit opsis that egg actually
produces a compound that stimulates
salicylic acid which is antagonistic the
jasmonic
acid okay so this actually creates a
system where the plant is not able to
defend itself so when the larv does
hatch the plant doesn't know it's being
attacked and is
defenseless started looking at what
happens if we expose plants to methyl
Jasmin one of the primary volatil that
plants give off
to warn that an attack has been made
what we did is we would
treat plants okay with methyl Jasmin and
then we would infest them with mites
okay and this is how many mites fled
fled the plants okay so you'll see that
in each case a plant that was exposed to
methyl Jasmin okay and this was for a
single hour resulted in a plant that
when you would put mites on it the mites
would
flee okay compared to the the
control also if we qu
Quantified if we come back to the Tomato
you'll notice the Tomato had significant
effect if we look at we quantify Proteus
Inhibitors which is one of the purported
responses that plants have in meth in
response to methyl Jasmin you'll see
with that with tomato that as methyl
Jasmin concentration went up or exposure
went up the plant produced more proteas
inhibitor in response to
that if we take that
further this is the number of mites that
were on the plant okay after a period of
3 weeks and you can see that in any case
whenever there was a plant that was
exposed to methyl Jasmine it had fewer
mites that was the same case for aphids
notice the control we had 22 this is
after 11 days with aphids 22 aphids we
had methyl silicate but Noti methyl
Jasmin we had a fraction of that we had
eight in that case
this is just a representation of some of
the work that we have but clearly in all
the studies we did after plant was
exposed to methyl Jasmin it actually not
only did the plants or insects try to
flee it but they actually proliferated
less now predation of any kind and
activation of plant defenses has a cost
for plants and so actually when you turn
on plant
defenses if that plant will actually
have less dry weight than a plant
adjacent to it if the defenses are
turned on the plant is spending a lot of
effort actually producing compounds to
defend itself at the expense of other
materials so there's a cost to this and
something that's also very interesting
is
that if you look at different kinds of
wounding responses you'll only
see response okay to a caterpillar not a
tearing saying that somehow the plant
recognizes a pest I don't know why this
is blurred on this one okay but the
bottom line is fac is
actually caterpillar
spit okay the plant actually perceives
the saliva from the
caterpillar and that's what causes the
chain reaction and response it's very
very specific so we're in the process
right now of actually determining
whether plants have vocabulary because I
think that the response to a white fly
may be different than an apid which may
be different than a might so we're
looking at those areas I will be very
brief new directions we're doing a lot
of new crop work this is with South
Africa this gives you an idea of some of
the gladiolas that exist in South Africa
we do ve we have very little gladiola
species in the United States we're doing
work with Cactus and succulents where we
we think that they can be new bedding
plants or new potted plants and we've
been identifying plants and protocols to
get cactin succulents to flour when we
want them to so you can have them
blooming all year year doing the same
with succulents of different
kinds then we identify protocols you can
pretty clearly see there when photo
period exceeds 12 hours with all those
species these are each calanchos that
they remain vegetative that if the photo
period is less than 13 hours they're
reproductive we've done a large project
on green roofs in the midwest because
the green roof work that's been done in
Baltimore and the east coast in Chicago
and Toronto doesn't apply to the Midwest
so we screened 78 species over a series
of years and identified what plants will
survive on a green roof in the
midwest work it's a crazy project on
grafted cactus okay someone say there
aren't many grafted cactus you're wrong
there's a lot of grafted cactus that are
in the world okay each of these
cacti is on a different root stock it's
the same Scion so the effect you see is
purely a root stock response there's a
lot of in lot of potential for this as
far as expanding the crop pallet there
is some interest in aquaponics I will
just mention a couple things there's a
difficult area we talked this morning
about how you have to optimize you have
to optimize the fish number that will
survive you have to optimize how many
plants a fish can fish population can um
support and then as the plants grow the
conditions that you have changes and the
market you know PE people are getting
tired of tilapia there's only so much
tilapia you can eat
right okay so and we think like we have
the Schlitz Brewery is converting into a
giant aquaculture facility in
Minneapolis they're going to be
producing more tilapia than we know what
to do with the interest in AR Growers is
frankly an alternative um aquaponic
crops and so what's an alternative crop
this is what's called a red claw which
it has no red claw it has a blue claw I
don't know why they call it red claw but
it's a large freshwood Lobster it's
actually a crayfish that gets a really
big tail from Thailand shrimp crabs and
freshwater oysters there's a lot more
interest in this and the restaurants in
the Minneapolis area are very interested
in this and there are some that have
some of these crazy systems where there
are fish at the
bottom this is LEDs in the center okay
and this is lettuce in this case but
actually they've switched to basil and
this
rotates okay okay my question was
why why not just gr B grow basil in the
greenhouse someplace it'd be a lot
cheaper but they they effectively do
this um and so it works and the the last
picture is this contraption which is
actually in California from two weeks
ago and someone has to identify
protocols for these guys this is Tom and
Jerry The Tom and Jerry work and they
see each other so they don't ever smash
into each
other and what they're doing is they're
spacing
plants so those guys will work for six
hours okay and then you put a new
battery pack in and then they going to
keep going there's no overtime there's
no Health Care there's no there's no
complaints but someone has to program
this thing about what a plant looks like
and what to do and there's actually a
project we're looking at this is a these
little helicopters with a little tank of
pesticide and the helicopters will fly
they will recognize an aphid and then
Spritz it and the intent is to use it in
Orchards so that these things will
Target Target the shoe
tips
so so in Minnesota none of the water
flows it all just sits like this in
these big mosquito pools but this is
land I have but any anyway I'll answer
any questions you may have I was
supposed to get done by one and I am
done 20 seconds
[Applause]
early
yes in some of your early slides you
showed photo excuse me you showed starel
conductance data uh the lore also
calculated CI internal CO2 what did that
look like and our stomate it's actually
optimizing their conductance to maintain
a constant CI so that they're not that's
a good question that's a good question
um we didn't find that to be the case we
didn't find that to be the case and the
other thing I wonder about is that you
know that as you increase CO2 let's say
in a tomato Greenhouse or something the
stomates actually close down size they
get smaller to accommodate some of what
you're talking about
um
but I don't know what impact that has on
on actual photosynthesis I still believe
that there's a
decrease and the short-term heat stress
we saw that
lag seems to support that there's some
sort of response that a plant has that
some of these plants are responding to
something and I assume it's ABA so so
the next step would be actually to look
at some mutants a to to look and see
what sort of response happens within
those muts themselves but as far as
interal CI we didn't find the
optimization or tried to get a constant
internal CI that was not the case but
yes we use the
light yes could the difference is the
internal CI explain why you were seeing
different right response Curves in the
same the same which could the
differences in the internal CI be
explaining why you were getting
different light response curves where
you had power versus PN with the same
you mean withy yeah the same species
different
writings how would you explain I don't
know I'd have to look I mean there seem
there clearly is inherent differences
probably from you know from the
parentage of these different cult bars
that impose the maximum rate that can
occur so I assume it's related to the
parentage because if you take a group of
species you'll find within that group of
species of within a Genus that they'll
be different maximum
levels you know maximum the animals that
you can
achieve does that make any sense
yeah related to that what you showed
were CO2 responses or or photosynthetic
responses that were parallel essentially
throughout the temperature range testing
so there must be some it wasn't just a
heat shutdown that was occurring uh for
the resistant versus the the yeah they
were
so there must be
some
humidity experim yeah with the liquor we
actually you can set a a specific
humidity level and
maintain B pressure deficit so you don't
so you can set it so that it doesn't
compound the
data action heat temperature yeah there
is there is very much with the vapor
pressure deficit but that actually
accommodates like
actually and also did you measure Ava
critical level no we didn't measure Ava
um the assumption is because we're
seeing the guard cells clo you know
closure of the stomates that Ava is
somehow involved with the process but
there's no evidence to confirming and
also no interaction for k+ and C++
deficiency or those no we didn't look we
didn't look for nutrient deficiencies
they were treated the same and the
responses were as you saw almost
immediate in some cases
so another question related to the Heat
and shade often times Growers would say
oh it's it's too hot so I'm going to put
the shade down in the greenhouse and so
what do you tell them now okay heat is
bad but shade is also bad so what should
they be doing you know with the Tomato
greenhouse and the rose Greenhouse this
started with the rose Greenhouse we told
them to shut the shade system
down and when they shut the shade system
down guess what happened to the blind
shoot percentage in the summer it
dramatically dropped and the blind
shoots they were having they weren't
having so it solved the problem
actually so there wasn't any problem
with the pl well the the the no not
let's just put it this way the heat
problem with the plants wasn't as bad as
the shade problem okay the shade was
more limiting than high temperature
reduction okay did it occur yeah so and
we have Rose data to show that it wasn't
but the shade where you saw I think just
in one example with impatience it
dropped lights down to nearly
third what about the period of Life
exposure not low light but highl because
Bob Lang hands when he was here told me
that you had to put the shade over 5:00
on luses because otherwise they had too
much light the period of photosynthesis
was too long to me this didn't make
sense but that's what he claimed now do
you think that was the time for pH
synthesis or was he in fact dropping the
temperature in some way maybe here to
defend himself have have you done any
experiments with the perod of
highlight
no I have not we haven't done that and I
don't see a rationale for it no I I
didn't see a rationale but the heat SW
up you put shade over 5m where where
there is a stress that I think occurs on
crops that we don't appreciate is
actually in the morning and you might be
aware of work done with photosynthetic
depression or in that case it's actually
damaged to the photos apparatus when you
have bright light and cool
temperatures in England in fact uh they
were able to attribute whether the corn
crop made it or not was associated with
how many cool bright mornings they had
there's actual clear photosynthetic
damage it's at the University of
Essex I don't know how often that occurs
in our crops okay we typically don't let
our crops getting cold but in some
locations they do and that actually
causes suppression long-term supression
as well cool and bright when we do our
temperature drop for stem elongation I
think the yellowing that we see is
actually that Co temperature damage to
the pH
system what of the Takeo messages I got
from your talk is that a greenhouse
while it's a controlled environment it's
still an imperfect place to grow plants
it's hard to you could do a lot more to
optimize carbon dioxide optim
light and optimized temperature then at
the end of your talk you showed
interesting slide with this rotating
drum and
plant which I think is pretty
unrealistic but maybe maybe it's not so
unrealistic to think about Factory like
Warehouse growing if you could optimize
all of those conditions maybe it could
be economically feasible well Bob worked
on this for a while right was interested
in this for quite some time and I think
it is possible to do it it's just
whether it's cost efficient to do it
okay the first thing I would do frankly
and we're in the process of doing this
at the University now this room is warm
and it's comfortable because the
thermostat for all of us is right here
okay so the first thing is to take the
light sensors and all the sensors
associated with plant growth and put
them where the plants are okay then when
so that's the first thing I would do as
far as L the other thing is I would find
out where your actual light levels are
because I bet you in NE grow Chambers
name GRE houses you are suppressing
growth more than what you
appreciate and I think that's occurring
across the board and I think it's
occurring in growth
Chambers um as far as factory production
there are definitely there are places
that want to do factory production but
in many cases it frankly is a lot
cheaper to just do traditional
production and I don't see the economics
to do factory production yet as long as
you
have accessible land in Minneapolis if
you drive 30 minutes you're in open
Farmland you really need to spend all
the money to do an intensive system in a
factory when you can have a
non-intensive system that may be more C
effective 30 minutes away I don't think
to say that but it's
reality those green houses with
deficiency of light system within the
canopy uh with the future of new
technology LED light system is it going
to
solution for that well you can create an
optimal environment at the plant LEL you
just need to know what the parameters
are that you need the question is
whether it's going to be
economical right I mean that's that's a
separate question because what I'm
telling you is our plant probably could
use more light what we're giving them
some point may be economical and some
point not so that it's and it's going to
be different you know frankly we just
discussed this before in New Hampshire
the cost of electricity is 12.2 cents
per Kow in Minneapolis is 3 and half
cents per kilowatt our economics are
very
different for
lighting CO2 you had some CO2 graphs but
I don't know if you mentioned the period
or the time that was done because there
are some experiments which show that if
you got a shortterm bursting growth but
if you have the CO2 present all the time
there's an acclamation that it comes
back it was before so have you found in
your that's a very good question the
answer is is no because frankly the
basis for adding CO2 to tomato green
houses and the increase in yield is
because they did a permanent increase in
photosynthesis but what we're looking at
is acclamation right now that bur and
that 2-hour high temperature pulse we're
looking at if we do it periodically
whether the plant doesn't depress but
actually adapts to that so we're we're
we're doing that actually right now but
um think it's a good point plan to do
acclimate um there was actually a recent
paper and rabbit opsis related to this
and they found that rabbit offices did
not that it was just perally
increased we have any more time other
questions for
John all right let's
[Applause]
thank
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu