this is a production of Cornell
University
uh thank you everyone for joining me
today and as the introduction alluded to
I'm going to talk about my experience
while on the Drear award and uh what my
main focus is in giving this talk is is
less to kind of walk you through my
experience in a chronological order but
more to share with you some of the
experiences some of the findings and
some of the things that I found to be
most interesting while experiencing the
biodiversity in South Africa
so I'm here in the Horticulture
department and it's been a number of
years working in Horticulture and as a
horticulturist whenever you come up and
you meet a plant you have to ask it
three questions
what is your name where are you from and
how did you get here and this is a great
picture of a ficus macrophila here in
South Africa this is meaning for scale
standing down here and these are the
kind of questions that I tend to like to
ask plants because they tend to reveal
very interesting stories and when I ask
this question of some of the plants that
I've experienced and seen throughout
visiting Gardens or other places around
the world uh one place kind of kept
coming up time and time again where you
just would find very unusual and
interesting flora and just something
that was just kind of outside the realm
of what we tend to tend to typically
find
so
as a lot of people know here in the
Horticulture Department South African
plants have had a large impact on the
Horticultural trade and you may or may
not realize this I'm going to go through
some examples right here of a bunch of
plants that you may not realize come
from South Africa so the zantendia the
calla lily is a very common plant that
is endemic to South Africa it has been
used and hybridized extensively for all
sorts of ornamental qualities
pellegonians the flowering geraniums a
plant that is completely ubiquitous in
use for planting and potting beds or as
a popular bedding plant is a genius of
plants that also comes from South Africa
nifophia the red hot poker a very common
ornamental plant that we tend to find in
Mediterranean climates and subtropical
regions is used extensively also comes
from South Africa
sterlitzia the bird of paradise and a
very interesting genus of plants there's
there's five species that comprise the
the Genera including some that grow as
largest trees but as we can see from
these pictures here also picked up and
used very commonly as a garden plant
ornamentally
the proteasier is a big is a large
family of plants but but one of the very
special components of plants that we
kind of see in South Africa a lot of
people when they think about the Western
Cape when they think about fine boss
this is one of the images that comes to
mind this idea this this protea this
this group of plants that is unique to
that region and we'll get into some of
these details as we go through the talk
uh proteas are used in as for fresh
flowers They're In the Flesh flower
industry but they also when you dry the
florets themselves can actually store
quite well and that's what this picture
is illustrating here on the right are
protea heads that have been cut and are
dried and are going to be shipped all
over the world to use for Cut Flower
displays
succulent plant biodiversity South
Africa boasts having roughly 30 percent
of the world's succulent plant
biodiversity and this is we find this
particularly in the Northwestern part of
the country
where we find all sorts of interesting
things like high diversity of aloes or
many of the plants in the Azo ACA family
such as haworthias or plants like
conifitums which are also commonly used
horticulturally people are very
interested in these plants for some of
the interesting adaptations they develop
but also because they're they're fun and
they're interesting and there's
something different we like to put them
in terrariums and other such uses such
as this
find them what used to be called white
books or lithos they're two different
Genera
uh and then the bulb biodiversity is
another
major you know we're going through a lot
of plants here and I hope to exposing
people to the kind of diversity that is
out there but here are just some some
great pictures of the bulb biodiversity
and even here in the Horticulture
Department we focus on some of our Labs
focus on
growing plants such as the ornithagalum
or as well as the um eukomis is another
Cut Flower and also bedding plant that
has also gained worldwide appeal and use
in the Horticultural world
and almost through one of the very
interesting things about uh about South
Africa is is known as some of the mass
flowerings up in namaqualand the
maquiland roughly refers to a region
that is the North Western uh part of
South Africa and they're known for
having these uh magnificent displays if
they get good rains in the in the winter
time when they get their precipitation
and uh and this is a phenomenon that's
been been noted for I want to say um
since the mid late or early 1900s and
just to kind of point out what's going
on here in particular this picture on
the far right this is a picture taken at
one of the national Botanic Gardens
that's actually managed more of a
natural area and what you're looking at
here is is you can kind of see is just
the the vast diversity of different
bulbs that are that are blooming and
growing in this one set of land this is
a landscape that has been managed
primarily only by weed removal and maybe
having having grazing that came in and
causes a natural disturbance and this is
a highlight it brings people to this
kind of part of the country where most
people wouldn't go for tourism otherwise
but you contrast this to the shots here
this is a farm that's also in the
namaqualand region but they annually
plow to encourage these pioneering
species like the ursinias here that
cause this kind of mass carpet blooming
effect and as you can see from the
picture it just goes on and on and so
these these images of the mass blooms
have really captured people's
imaginations this is a picture of one of
the first it was actually taken by by
Hans Hera the first curator at
Stellenbosch botanic garden where I was
spending my Drew experience and this was
one of the first photo color photographs
to make it it was a postcard actually
and to make it to Europe and kind of put
this amazing biological display kind of
on the world stage
and you also find some of the the weird
and the wonderful so plants such as the
hid Nora Africana here which is a
parasitic plant that grows on euphorbia
and it's a piper rails
so related to aristocia or the
Dutchman's pipe that some people may
know as well as wonderful plants like
wellwitchie and mirabilis which is in
the nutella's order a very fascinating
plant it's the only species in its whole
family and this grows in the northwest
region up into Angola and Namibia uh in
in kind of this fog belt and just a very
unusual plant people have been Wonder
Amazed by it and interestingly enough
Stellenbosch botanic garden was the
first Garden to ever grow this plant
from seed and get it up to a point where
it would cone and set seed once again
so through that kind of display of of
pictures that I just showed you I hope
to have revealed just some of the things
that really make the biodiversity of
South Africa so fascinating so
interesting and something that's pretty
unusual compared to what we may see when
we walk out of our door
so I think the the natural question that
comes to mind is is why is South Africa
so uh biologically diverse when it comes
to to this vascular plant Flora and I'm
showing you an image here of what's
known as a flower show it's a flower
show in South Africa and this is in
large contrast to what we may experience
if we went to a flower show maybe like
the Philadelphia Flower Show or flower
show in Europe a lot of these kind of
flower shows that we may be used to are
kind of more contrived their their image
we will go and we'll see a plant but the
plant may not be the main display of the
focus or focus of the display
uh it may be more kind of ornamental
ornate or the scene they create around
it is going to be something
um that they kind of focus on
in South Africa
there's a number of town that hosts
these flower shows and at these flower
shows what farmers and local people in
that Community will go out just into
their fields just around the roadside
it's just anywhere that's around and and
they'll Harvest these massive amounts of
of just plants are going around these
weren't grown ornamentally just for
these displays this is just the natural
kind of abundance that's around and they
bring them and of course putting
together is kind of contrived in this
kind of context of having so many so
much with biodiversity or the plants
themselves stuck together in one place
but I like to share this image just
because it shows both a different
perspective of how South Africans
interact with their Flora but also just
the sheer mag magnitude of the of the
diversity that's there and these are
great experiences for getting people
interested in Horticulture in gardening
but they also have a large educational
component where they actually have
sections where they label all these
plants and you can go and you can kind
of actually learn what's around you as
well
so to kind of put South Africa in
context and put the Flora there in
context I'm going to start with with
North America a place that we're all
familiar with North America excluding
Mexico is north of Mexico makes up
roughly 15 of the Earth's surface and on
that 15 of the Earth's surface we have
about 6.25 of the world's total vascular
plant biodiversity 20 000 species
roughly
now we jump to South Africa and what
we're looking at here is less than one
percent of the Earth's surface so zero
eight point percent and 30 000
individual species so roughly 10 percent
of the world's total biodiversity so a
huge you know a huge amount of
biodiversity and relatively small space
and this distribution is not even across
the whole country there are certain
areas that have more speciation than
others
so to give to continue to give people a
context we're going to work from a large
scale and focus in
now there's multiple ways how people
choose to describe the different plant
communities that are around them and on
the biggest scale those scale we
typically look at is known as floristic
kingdoms and floristic kingdoms describe
relationships that are primarily between
family and on the general level and they
focus on three main different areas they
focus on distribution of these families
in general either being Cosmopolitan
very widespread being endemic very
narrow only occurring in a very small
amount of space or having disjunctions
large barriers between different types
of families
uh redwoods are a good example of that
while in China you may have the Don
Redwood metasochoic of distributes while
in North America you have the coastal
redwood or the giant Redwood would be an
example of Distinction
and what I want to point out in this
picture you know we can see that the
alarctic kingdom is the largest the one
that we're probably most familiar with
here but if we look down to the tip of
Africa we see that there's one little
section here that stands out in in pink
here and this is known as the the cape
floristic region and the reason why I
show this picture and kind of point this
out is that even on this scale even on
the larger scale of the earth what we're
seeing is that the there's something
going on down there that makes uh the
Flora there so unique in its
relationships and families in general
that it that it highlights this one
region it's the only country in the
world that houses its own floristic
kingdom it's kind of a big way of of
looking at plants so there's some
subjectiveness to it but it's a good a
good General context
so now taking it one step down we step
into the levels of biomes
and what biomes primarily describe are
plants based on their structure how do
they overall look and on ecological
factors so the main factor is that
people use to describe Flores based on
biomes are going to be minimal uh winter
temperature seasonality of rainfall and
then summer air Rarity how dry it gets
in a region and these are kind of we'll
go we're going to go into some of these
in just a moment some of the kind of big
Landscapes that we may think of in the
northeastern part of the United States
for example we think of our hardwood
forest as being our predominant biome if
we went to the Midwest we would think of
what historically would be the Great
Plains as being another biome so big
kind of character you know the way the
floras grow the way they actually look
is the major kind of driver of this or
the way we describe it
um and
I'm going to go through a couple here so
we're going to start off with the
Savannah Biome this is found in the
north eastern part of the country and
these are areas that tend to be
dominated by a lot of grass and few
trees this is the area where you'll find
the beginning of The Baobab trees that
will continue some of the world's most
widest trees that you find that will
continue up into
subtropical and tropical Africa and
these are the Landscapes that support
the large mammals and that that uh
are major drivers of the ecology and
this land landscape here
the next kind of biome we stepped into a
very big one now is the forest biome the
forest biome is a very interesting biome
it's it's the smallest I think it's less
than a percent of the total biomes in
that map I showed you before you didn't
probably even notice it because they're
so small and this biome is very
interesting because it is a biome that
receives most of the most of the the
biomes are in South Africa are either
dictated by summer rainfall or winter
rainfall and that is a major definer of
the kind of plants that tend to grow in
these areas in the forest biomes they
receive rainfall all year round and that
is because they're on just along the
south coast of South Africa and what's
interesting about this biome is it's
very very concentrated and unfortunately
with the lights it's hard to make this
out what's interesting about this
picture here is saying it's a very kind
of
compressed where these forests actually
grow so this is along the South Coast as
you're kind of going north here and
pretty much where this picture cuts off
right here you end up in fine boss biome
so it goes from kind of shrubby
grasslands and then you come in down
here and you're in this this forested
area and you can actually see this
contrast right here this little bit here
is actually uh fine boss and then and
then Forest immediately stops off these
Cliffs so it's a it's a relatively small
biome but a very interesting one it's
where we tend to find obviously the Big
Trees things like the putter cup put a
carpus vulcatus or the yellow wood which
are some of their giant trees protocarps
are interesting some interesting
lineages in themselves having relations
to Flora in Australia or or New Zealand
and some large disjunctions there I put
this other picture up of tricocletus
cranatus it's related to the witch hazel
family which we may know from our local
Flora here and kind of one of the few
that is that is present both in in our
Flora as well as South Africa's
another major biome is the Kuru biome
and this is the kind of areas that
support a lot of this really interesting
succulent plant biodiversity they tend
to get winter rainfall and have
a lot of these interesting succulent
characteristics cam adaptation and do
interesting things like like grow as you
can see in this picture here they're
little kind of items that are just
eeking out in existence just between
these rocks where they're not going to
be exposed to direct sun and have their
root systems dry out
we tend to find a lot of biodiversity
here in in aloes or this near endemic
family Azo ACA
with things like the drosanthemums and
the conifitums as well
and last but not least on our on our
tour of biomes is the fine boss biome
and I think the fine boss biome is what
most people think about when when they
talk about South Africa it's the kind of
the concept that comes to mind and what
this biome is kind of looks like is you
have lots of restios lots of grass like
plants that we can kind of see on the
slide on the right and then on the left
this is kind of a more typical we see
proteas in the background but it's a
shrubby landscape it never gets a much
above three meters in height and this is
where we tend to find the highest amount
of our biodiversity and our highest
amount of engineism in our plants
just a few more images of what you may
find supports a large
bulb Flora as well
and just a few more pictures here for
for contacts you can see on this middle
picture here just the the size of this
of this flower head of this uh
proteus syneroides
so I've kind of walked people now
starting from a global scale we step
down to a more a more localized scale by
thinking about biomes and then the the
finest scale well pretty much the finest
scale that we're going to get into here
is vegetation maps and a vegetation map
is a way of defining your flora-based
based on more of the the species level
and more of the general level and what I
kind of want to point out just here in
this picture is that um you know as we
look at the northeastern part of the
country we're still seeing pretty large
swatches of a different color or swaths
of different color sorry of solid colors
but as we get down to the western part
we just see it it looks like someone
took paint and just like smacked it all
over the place we're seeing a lot of a
lot of different
interactions between all these different
specific vegetation types and so each of
these patches is big enough to be able
to Define them broadly by relationships
or likenesses between species in general
but even within that we see that we have
tons of tons of different vegetation
types going on and just a quick thing to
point out here
this is pretty much we're looking at the
fine boss regions in this area and this
is more of the succulent crew and these
are the main areas the Western Cape is
really the main areas where we find
these high levels of speciation uh
occurring Within These these families so
just another blow up of this area we can
see that uh it's it's on the coast this
is an area that primarily receives
winter rainfall and the the mountain
ranges here going both north to south
and east to west are major definers of
this kind of landscape
so the Western Cape as I've probably
hammered into everyone's head at this
point is highly diverse but it's hot
it's not just highly diverse one of the
things that make it very unique is you
have this high level of endonism and
that's why when you look at the
floristic kingdoms on a broad scale this
area really shows up so one out of five
families 20 of the families in in the
Western Cape are endemic and on a
species level up to 70 of species are
endemic and so what that means again is
plants that are occurring in just one
location but even in most cases a short
distance away you won't you'll find
maybe related species but not the same
ones
and so again it comes back to the
question of of why is this actually
happening and uh it's not an easy
question to answer oh sorry I got ahead
of myself here uh sorry the so the other
thing that defines the Western Cape
region other uh Flora there other than
the highest levels of of of endonism is
also uh what one botanist described as
the effect of excessive speciation uh
and the the most striking example of
this is is the genus Erica uh it's known
to grow in other parts of the world as
well but in South Africa out of the 860
species that are known globally 730 of
those occur just within this one small
area and there's other large examples of
this such as the geraniums the
pelargoniums or gladiolus or axolis
other plants that people in this room
may be familiar with having species
numbers that are high above 100
just found in the Western Cape
so again the question is why why is this
why is this happening and what are some
of the kind of major drivers that are
causing these this kind of speciation to
occur and there's three or four that I'm
going to present right now the first one
as I pointed out in the picture
previously was these mountain ranges are
very important part of the of the
landscape
uh in the Western Cape and the the main
hypothesis or Theory here is that these
topographically complex regions uh act
as Ice uh as barriers causing isolation
of plants within them so you may have a
plant that has distributed to a certain
extent and then for from changes in the
landscape or just over time there's not
gene flow is not able to move back and
you end up having speciation events that
therefore
cause some of these patterns that we're
seeing
a few more images of the
Topography of the Western Cape
the next is the adafik the the soil
properties of the region and and this
has been described as kind of a mosaic
if you looked at a soil survey map of
the Western Cape where you have in in
very close proximity to each other very
different soil types and the main Theory
here goes is that you're going to have
sister species that are related to each
other
but in different soils will have
speciated and
formed new ones as being the next kind
of major driver and the thing I I'm
sorry to scale back the other thing
about the um
the the mountain ranges the the other
major driver here that is important is
that in these mountain regions uh it's
considered to have a long period of
climatic stability and that is a you
know one thing you hear oftentimes cited
and
uh in some of the botany literature is
that these long regions tend to drive
speciation as well
and then the the last major major dryer
driver is fire adaptation this is
actually an image that was taken just
last Wednesday in the Western Cape
region in an area that's known as
silvermine and this is as it was kind of
burning and burning in full Forest this
is uh about a day later looks like
absolute moonscape
and uh like I said this just happened
last week and here's a picture of the
same region when I was out there in in
December so complete transformation
but but most importantly what this main
kind of the theory that goes behind this
are the plant's abilities and their
adaptations to deal with fire and the
main two different adaptations that you
tend to find are on one hand the
re-sprouters the ones who are root
systems are not completely destroyed by
these by these events but actually have
the ability to sprout up once again or
the receipters the plants that actually
need fire to act as scarification
or also just remove competition
to occur and the the uh the idea here is
that you tend to have sister species
that have different fire adaptations uh
So based on one of the other you have
this speciation events that occur
So based on kind of all these different
things I thought maybe South Africa
might be an interesting place to go and
have a look at plants and to study the
Flora and and to help out a little bit
so I put an application for the Drear to
work at Stellenbosch Botanical Gardens
and uh just experience this remarkable
Flora
and so to give people a background on
Stellenbosch it is the oldest university
Botanic Garden in Africa who was
originally established in 1902 primarily
for as a teaching Garden about 20 years
later it moved to the the location that
it's at now and early on they had a big
focus on succulent plants as I showed
that picture of the postcard before by
Hans Hera he was the first curator and
did a lot of work with this near endemic
family Azo ACA as well as some of these
other things like like well whichia and
at Stellenbosch the garden was
originally based off the uh the garden
design at Padova the world's oldest
Botanic Garden in Italy but over time it
has is changed
and Stellenbosch is in a pretty
interesting uh position and I'll kind of
go on I'll talk a little bit more about
this and when I talk about some of the
national Botanic Gardens but one of the
things that actually makes them stand
out and this may seem like a funny thing
since I just went on and on about how
interesting the floor of South Africa is
is that is that they actually grow
exotic plants they grow plants that
aren't from South Africa they do grow a
lot of plants that are from South Africa
particularly for their conservation
program but what this actually does is
it really creates an opportunity to
engage the public and to draw them into
the garden because uh you know for you
know someone like most people in the
room or myself you go to South Africa
because you want to see the floor you
want to see the fine boss you want to
see these these families that are just
totally you know different than what
we're used to but when you grow up
around that you may not actually realize
that what you have around you is so
spectacular unless you you know have
opportunities to engage with it so one
of the unique places that Stellenbosch
is actually at is that they can grow
things like Victoria lilies or strongly
load on the Jade fine or even do they
have Bonsai collections which which draw
people in and engage them with the
plants and the landscape in a different
way than uh some of the other Gardens in
South Africa can do
uh they support the educational mission
of the university and they do this
through labs and practicals as well as
collaboration with researchers the
example down here is they Stellenbosch
houses the living collection for Oxalis
this is one of those
Genera that I mentioned before has more
than 100 species in it and they they
maintain the living collection so that
the taxonomists are working on it on the
University can use it as part of their
research
and there's a really good relationship
for for both of them
Stellenbosch being a botanic garden they
they keep they have a plant record
system and they use the iris BG system
uh they're they're
as of right now some of the national
Botanic Gardens have also gone on board
finally but they're actually
Stellenbosch was the first Garden to
have a comprehensive plant record
keeping system and this is one of those
things that um you know most people kind
of maybe not think about playing records
all the time but it's one of those
things that makes a botanic garden
different than just a park the fact that
we that every plant that comes into the
collection is is labeled is numbered we
can keep up with the taxonomy we can
take images of it if it's wild collected
we'll take GPS points and and then
therefore you know that when you bring
that plant into your collection it's not
just something interesting to look at
but it also is a representative of that
population from the wild it brings a lot
more value to your collections and also
assist in things like when you're
actively involved in plant conservation
programs
they also run a
plant conservation program as I was just
kind of going on about these are the
three species that they focused on I'm
not going to talk in too much detail
about this but this was one of the
primary things that I worked on while I
was down there
this is a deceptive pointed out this is
a dresser origia it's it's a sundew they
grow around here as well but there's a
lot of diversity down there it's one of
the biggest in the world they're
carnivorous plants
um and this is a hat for scale but you
can just see the massive length of these
leaves and just a among carnivorous
plant Growers this plant has has gained
a lot of attention because it is just so
so weird
and uh last but not least uh
Stellenbosch botanic garden is another
one of its strengths and other things
that makes it stand out is that it is
not part of the national botanic garden
system it's a small garden there's only
eight permanent staff it's affiliation
with the university allows it to take on
initiatives and to kind of be very
Nimble and they may not have as much
capital or resources of some of the
bigger Gardens to focus on projects but
their small size allows them to make
kind of meaningful small impacts
and so my main goals I'm just gonna go
over there as well I was in the juror
experience was to go work at stonebosh
Buchanan Garden but it was to develop my
my field botany skills and some you know
I'm in the Horticulture Department some
person may ask why should you develop
why should you work on field bonding and
particularly in Botanic Gardens which I
hope to continue in once I graduate here
and I've worked in the past this line
between between botany and Horticulture
is is not not so well defined a lot of
the plants that we come to appreciate in
this day and age either as ornamental
plants obviously at some place at some
point came from the wild and Botanic
Gardens for a long time have had a very
active role in plant exploration and
also bring plants into cultivation so
then we can use them and various
different types of ways
it was also to help out in this plant
conservation program
it was also a reciprocal agreement so in
order to give some expertise and some
training to the Garden itself so I
helped out in doing I did a lot of work
on the plant records as well as getting
in and doing Horticultural work but also
did training I've got a background in
erebora culture so doing some work with
some of the staff and learning how to
tree climb how to do proper chainsaw
safety use
and a couple of these other kind of
skill sets that they didn't necessarily
have down there
and then last but not least was to gain
experience in Botanical Gardens and not
just at Stellenbosch but also with a
number of the other Botanic Gardens that
I interacted with while I was in South
Africa learning about how they conduct
Horticulture in this with these Special
plants that they grow there and also to
learn about how they manage their
Gardens and what their General approach
is and just kind of learning about the
management of how this is all done
and while I was down there I also had an
opportunity to have a look around pretty
much all the pictures that we've seen so
far are pictures that I've taken with
the exception of a few so this is just
an illustrator this is not all the
places that I went but this is just
illustrations of some of the natural
areas and Botanic Gardens kind of across
the country that I had opportunities to
visit and interact with
so for the last kind of part of my talk
I'm just going to talk about the state
of biodiversity in South Africa as well
as a little bit how plant conservation
is actually conducted since that was the
main kind of focus of my work down there
and
uh the the state of the biodiversity in
South Africa as I've kind of described
before is very fascinating uh but is
also very challenged
um one of the challenges that we have in
terms of figuring out how to do
effective plant conservation work is
that uh we still just don't know people
still just don't know with 30 000
species occurring across all of South
Africa people just don't even know what
the full extent of the Flora is so the
Flora is far from complete uh new
species are found all the time since
2009 there's been more than 300 new
species described and the the rate of
discovery cannot be kept up with the
expertise of taxonomists either in South
Africa or
um or or abroad since there's experts in
these groups kind of all over the place
many of the threats to biodiversity the
three main biggest ones are ones that we
are familiar with the loss of habitat
alien species species Invasion as we can
see
appear just marching these are the
Western Cape region just having
Fort Jackson march cross invasive tree
just march across the landscape as well
as a large one is unethical plant
collecting this isn't a picture from the
field this is actually a picture of
kirstenbosch botanic garden where people
actually came in at night and somehow
stole cycads directly out of their
collection which is
an amazing feat but really unfortunate
so
I'm going to go over some of the major
players in the way that the way that
um plant conservation is actually
conducted in South Africa and as I
mentioned before the national Botanic
Gardens are our major player in this and
they fall under the the purview of
what's known as the South African
National biodiversity Institute or Sandy
and sambi is a large blanket
organization they are a government
organization that primarily covers all
biological research that goes on across
the country so you could be have
entomologist ornithologists marine
biologists
botanists and so on and so on that are
under this
since they are very large it is they
they have a lot of resources and you can
make large impacts but as I was kind of
describing before they may not be the
most Nimble and be able to take quick
action which sometimes is necessary
and samby oversees the national Botanic
Gardens across all of South Africa there
are there's 10 a 10th has just recently
been added
and the national Botanic Gardens are
very interesting institutions they have
a strict mandate to only grow native
plants and this is kind of getting to
the point of what makes Stellenbosch a
little bit different and this is and
this is a wonderful mandate to have
because with so much biodiversity down
there it's important to have folks that
are that are really focusing on working
on these groups that don't grow anywhere
else and also to learn how to display
them and get the the public generally
engage with them so these are mostly
pictures all taken at kirstenbosch
Botanic Garden
another interesting thing about the
national botanic garden is they all have
contiguous natural areas that are
attached to them so as you can see from
both these pictures here there's
formalized landscapes in the front the
picture on the right is table mounting
off into the background that continues
off into Cape Town or a leopards Cliff
here on the sorry this that's on the
right hand picture
the left hand is the kirstenbosch and
these natural areas are managed they
they go on and make sure invasive plants
aren't coming in they do population
counts of species in there and it's just
a continuous part of the garden and the
garden experience which is a very
interesting this is this is a model that
actually Cornell plantations uses as
well they may not be contiguous but
plantations also manages lots of natural
areas and it seems like it makes sense
especially if you want to do plant
conservation work but it's actually
something that's fairly unique there's
not a lot of gardens out there that do
just kind of have this kind of dual role
of natural lands management as well as
cultivated landscapes
the national Botanic Gardens house the
herbarium and they have departments that
are work to do the work mostly on the
systematics and taxonomy of describe
actually describing the Flora of South
Africa
and they also like I mentioned have
developed Horticultural expertise in
figuring out how to actually grow a lot
of these types of plants and they they
put this out to the general public in a
number of different ways these are
examples of books of how to grow a lot
of these specific Genera or families of
plants that may be unknown to most
people and they've also had the ability
to to prioritize learning the
Horticultural
practices that are necessary to keep
these things alive so this is an example
of the succulent collection at crew
National botanic garden and
and and getting to talk to the
horticulturalists and the people that
actually work with these plants is very
very fascinating because the the amount
of nuance that they've developed and how
to take care of a lot of these really
interesting taxa is uh is quite
extensive and it's great that they that
they have it they're putting books out
they're they're creating a medium by
which they can express this to the rest
of the world
but the national Botanic Gardens aren't
the only players in town there also are
other other folks who get involved so
this is an example of a partnership with
industry and a group that I was able to
spend some time with the cape Institute
of micro propagation they primarily
focus on diesel orchids the genus of
orchids these are a couple pictures of
disa uniflora probably South Africa's
most famous
Orchid but but they're a private
organization that also does conservation
work so what that means is they go out
to the field they they're involved they
will
do plant surveys the GPS where actually
they find these plants they'll pollinate
take capsules bring them back figure out
how to get them into into culture grow
them on and then they'll do different
things with them depending on what
species they are if there's an
ornamental interest in them they'll
figure out ways to continue these these
plants in culture and then send them
internationally abroad to make some
money for the organization but then they
also will go back out and do replant
reintroductions the cape Institute of
micro propagation also worked with
Stellenbosch and on disa barbata which
is one of them has one of the smallest
populations of any disa and they're
doing repopulations using these kind of
methods and protocols
you also tend to find conservation being
conducted in places like private Gardens
uh in in lots of in the part of South
Africa that I was in there's lots of
Estates and and Vineyards
that are kind of a major part of the
Horticultural trade in general but one
of the interesting Partnerships that
you'll you'll find is is some of these
Gardens actually being active in plant
conservation and so the example of this
is the Silver Tree here on the right
leucodendron Argentia was known to be
kind of have one main population on
Table Mountain that over the years has
kind of declined kirstenbosch has been
active in maintaining that but the only
other known population a disjunct
population was also found and these
aren't these aren't the best pictures
but this is very close to uh
Stellenbosch the town that I was in
these these mountain ranges that are in
the background this the rustenburg wine
estate goes pretty much right up to this
mountain slope and on these slopes they
found a second population of this
leucodendron argentium and not because
they have to because they want to and
they're interested in conservation they
actually go out they remove invasive
plants and they monitor these
populations and try to keep them
straight thriving as well
there's also a big citizen science
initiative and and people who are just
generally interested in plant
conservation in South Africa and this is
one organized example of that known as
crew custodians of the rare and
endangered wildflowers and these are
folks who are
uh they're mostly retired but they're a
volunteer group that well it's based by
region they'll identify natural areas
within their region that um haven't been
surveyed and they'll coordinate with
samby and they'll go out and they'll
actually do these surveys where they
actually see what's going on out there
they'll keep population counts uh and
they'll and then they'll submit that so
they can be used for for consensus
across the whole country
another example of this
um
is a program known as ispot ispot is an
application you can get for your phone
and what it is is if you are out
buttonizing doesn't matter if you're
just walking around you're on your your
farm you're on your land and you see a
plant that you don't know is of interest
to you you can take a picture of it you
can post it up on I spot either attempt
to identify yourself or it will alert
experts and they'll come in and take a
look at these plants and identify them
and this is a great way of kind of you
know doing quick surveying on the ground
but what's been interesting about it is
as more and more people have been using
this program that there's actually been
a whole handful of species that have
actually been discovered because of this
process and this is an example of one
that we saw I saw one of the flower
shows where
folks actually someone just took a
picture of this and went out to the
expert they they didn't know what it is
they came and they did the field work
they they were able to describe it find
it Define it and therefore it was
introduced as a new species
so
um kind of getting towards the end of
the talk here why does it all matter
we've described how there's so much
biodiversity in South Africa and a lot
of it is is kind of under threat and and
this is the same challenge that plant
conservationists Focus have everywhere
in um South African itself about roughly
25 of the Flora is either threatened or
of conservation concern
um but
the kind of point I want to make here is
is that you know we all know that plant
conservation or any kind of conservation
is a very important activity to
undertake and instead of focusing on
what the sheer numbers are here through
many of the examples that I've shared
with you before I think more of the
point is that is that there's a lot of
interested parties and an interesting
collaborations that are being conducted
that really really look to address these
problems on multiple levels uh and I
think that was a really interesting and
Powerful finding for for me to have and
uh just just in general it's not just
that in on a Global Perspective that the
plants that we all
um you know are threatened or in Peril
but but there's also
um
I've been a restriction in
in the education
of how to actually you know conduct some
of this work so these are two articles
that came out just this last week in
popular media uh one is talking about
is talking about collections
specifically and the value that those
hold and the other one is talking about
field biology skills and how fewer and
fewer folks are actually being trained
in these fields so we have issue you
know we have challenges in conservation
not just on the plant side but also in
our education system and
I think my last kind of point is that is
that even though again we have these
challenges I think it's more of a point
of optimism that we still have places
like educational institutions
universities and Botanic Gardens which
are able to pull all this information
together and since I've been given this
perspective from the side of botanic
gardens these institutions really stand
out as being places that can do this
work not only on a theoretical level but
actually can get out there and do the
applied work and they can bring all
their resources they have to bear to to
this Mission so not just monitoring
these plants in the population in the
wild and monitoring populations but
actually developing Horticultural
protocols how to do institution exitu
conservation how to document the floor
of our world and follow up with the kind
of research that is that is important to
allow plant conservation to happen
and so that's kind of it so with that
I'd like to thank the Horticulture
section or department and the jurier
committee for allowing me to have this
kind of experience there's a lot of
Direction this talk could have gone and
went in a lot of different ways anyway
so if you have questions please please
feel free to come up and talk to me
about it I want to thank Stellenbosch
Botanic Garden in the university and in
particular Martin Smith the curator at
Stellenbosch and his wife mirica Smith
and their child Arya and thanks for
everyone who followed my blog and just
showing up today
and with that
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu