this is a production of Cornell
University well thank you very much Tim
and um thank you for the invitation to
Cornell it's great to be here and it
I've met some really Fascinating People
this morning including the parking
Warden
um so what I want to talk about is plant
fin typing but first I thought I don't
want to I don't want this to be the
departmental seminar commercial break
but I will talk about the Genesis of the
company Cubit systems it's an acronym
Cubit for Queens University biological
instrumentation and technology and the
founder members of myself that's me when
I had more her uh Nick Dowling was um
working in the lab with me and the lab
was uh run by David LEL who um as as Tim
just alluded to we were doing a lot of
work with with nitrogen fixation and the
um the oxy diffusion barrier in
particular non-invasive measurements of
nitrogenase activity and the company was
we we were helped to start up by partek
Innovations which is the Queens
University technological transfer
arm the first thing um that we developed
as part of our Research into plant
physiology was a differential oxygen
analyzer now in the Plant World
measuring photosynthesis and
respiration um small small tissues the
it's it's difficult to get measurements
of of metabolic rate and photosynthetic
rate um using oxygen as the as the
measure of activity um that's why we
measure typically photosynthetic uptake
uh as CO2 uptake rather than oxygen
release the reason for this is that the
atmosphere is about 350 po per million
CO2 and rising and um typically you put
a leaf in a leaf chamber you measure the
input CO2 to the output CO2 measure the
difference between the input out to
Output multiply by flow rate and that
gives you a rate sometimes you look at
an uptake of about 10 parts per million
against a background of 350 part per
million very easy to measure with a an
IR CO2 analyzer oxygen much much more
difficult the background is 210,000 part
per million but you're still only
exchanging 10 PPM measuring 10 PPM
against 210,000
very very difficult but we developed
this instrument which resolves one PPM
oxygen against air and people were quite
excited by it so park said patent it
let's form a company that's where
essentially cubic came from um the
instrument is very very stable you can
see here measurements of oxygen and CO2
looking at the respiration rate of a
potato now not very exciting thing to do
measuring potato respiration rate but
what it does illustrate is how stable
the signals are and that the respiratory
quotient of your potato is one it's
metabolizing pure carbohydrate right
more interesting though is to use this
device to look at flux of electrons in
our potato if we are metabolizing pure
carbohydrate and all the electrons going
through glycolysis in the CB cycle end
up um in the electron transport chain we
form water we get one CO2 produced for
every oxygen consumed so you got a
respiratory quo to one but if these
electrons are going somewhere else if
they're being dragged off to other sinks
then that respiratory quo changes so now
we can look at the fate of electrons if
we measure oxygen and CO2 at the same
time similarly with
photosynthesis if the light reactions if
all of the uh electrons generated in the
light reactions end up reducing carbon
dioxide to carbohydrate we get one
oxygen produced for every CO2 that is
fixed however if these reactions are
pulled off to do other things like
nitrate assimilation in the leaf and
what have you the ratio changes so by
measuring oxygen and CO2 at the same
time we have a synergistic measurement
of photosynthesis in which we can look
in changing conditions perhaps at where
the electrons are going we actually
developed an acronym which was Flux Of
reductant to Alternative sources and
sinks but we discovered that the
accident that the acronym spelled fras
and at the time we didn't understand
that fras was actually caterpillar Shir
and um therefore we dropped that one and
we uh we started to call it Dr which is
diverted reductant utilization rate
which nobody uses anyway so but we did
some uh interesting measurements one of
I thought I'd pull this one up it's kind
of cool we were trying to determine
whether or not the um the reductant
generated in the light in soybean pods
was actually used for fatty acid
metabolism and this was kind of
interesting so we looked at oxygen
exchange rate in the dark and CO2
exchange rate in the dark and there's a
net flux of CO2 out of the nodules in
the dark as and a net uptake of oxygen
and we turn the light on the fixation of
CO2 was not enough to create a net
uptake of CO2 but the photosynthetic
reactions were enough to have a net um
production of oxygen so in fact in this
circumstance we had a tissue which is
producing both oxygen and and CO2 at the
same time they both being evolved and as
far as we know that's the first time any
anybody's ever measured net flux of
oxygen and CO2 in the same direction at
the same time and the I won't go into
the details of the paper but we did
discover that yes the uh uh the
reductant generated by the Light
reactions of photosynthesis is involved
in fatty acid synthesis in the in the
nodule uh another thing we use the um
differential oxygen analyzer for was a
work with Steve long at the University
of Illinois and he was interested in the
question does elevated CO2 concentration
decreased dark respiration in soyan and
this has been a matter of contention for
some time that high CO2 you know this is
a case with global warming it's going to
be an issue if it affects D respiration
then you have to put this into your
models but there's some question of if
it does how does it do it and so we did
some measurements with a a Lor CO2
analyzer and yes at high CO2 levels
there was a reduction in Dart
respiration apparent reduction but what
if we measured this respiration rate
using oxygen uptake
instead we don't see a change um and we
came to the conclusion and as of others
since then that these small changes
actually in the resolution and the
linearity of these CO2 analyzers at high
CO2 have been creating an erroneous
measurement of Dart respiration so in
fact we came to the conclusion that it
doesn't that Dart respiration is not
affected at least at the the levels of
CO2 that that we
investigated um I thought the world
would be beating our door beating path
to our doors about the everybody here
should be now very excited about buying
one of these differential auction
analyzers uh in fact um yeah it it there
was a less enthusiastic response at
least from the plant scientists the
animal scientists love them uh so we
needed to make money and at the time I
was teaching bio 101 I had a thousand
students in my uh 101 class as Tony
would know he wasn't one of them else he
wouldn't be here now and
um the problem was that the kids were
given well they weren't given Lor and
things like this they were they
surrounded the one Lor in the department
and told not to touch it was a black box
with spat out numbers when they
measuring photosynthesis lousy for
teaching I thought there's got to be a
better way got to be a better way so we
developed some very lowcost instruments
for measuring carbon dioxide and oxygen
um that could be uh deployed in the lab
really really inexpensively using
inexpensive software we got from a
company in Portland Oregon which I'll
get to in a moment so and we've
developed this over the years so now we
have this what we call the qbx concept
where we have a pump a flow meter a CO2
analyzer an analyzer for measuring
relative humidity humidity and
temperature they're all modular but they
all fit into the box and um they're
inexpensive enough so that teaching Labs
can afford these and if anything ever
goes wrong with any of the components
one of the great things is you just
phone as we send you a replacement
component and these things kind of slot
out you put it in and you're ready to go
again within 48 Hours unlike the single
units from likeo 40 odd ,000 if the pump
goes you have to send the whole thing
back like or great I'm not denigrating
them they're wonderful instruments um we
think these are wonderful as well and
they''re used now extensively in both
research and teaching there's a
fantastic company called verer software
and Portland Oregon which which develops
the interface and the software for these
things we can get to eight analog
inputs the the manipulation the data
manipulation the software is great
wonderful graphical displays this is a
light response of photosynthesis you can
see the changes in the actinic light the
corresponding changes in CO2 the changes
in stomatal movement me measured as
relative humidity and then in different
um different pages within the software
we calculate things like stomatal
conductance internal CO2 Etc really
really really nice in
instruments end of commercial break um
what I want to talk about for the bulk
of this uh presentation is plant
phenotyping and um here Cubit systems
has formed a very very close association
with a company in the Czech Republic uh
called Photon systems instruments and
this company were the first company to
commercialize an Imaging system uh for
chlorophyll fluoresence kinetics and I
will talk a little bit about chlorophyll
fluoresence kinetics bit more detail
about that um later on in the seminar um
now then why has there been this
apparently sudden massive interest in
plant phenotyping systems the big a ag
biotech companies are are all looking to
get these there's there establishments
throughout the world who are really
really keen on on high throughput
phenotyping and trait Discovery well
this is a kind of depressing slide now
the next several slides these are taken
from a talk given by Eric
merie um at a workshop I was at in
Thailand two weeks ago he was kind
enough to send me these slides yesterday
so I've stuck them in my talk and I give
him full credit for them although the
work done is by other people who are who
are credited here and he was making the
point that we are in a extremely
difficult situation with respect to
feeding the world in 2050 this is the
increase in yield of various crops from
1961 to 2008 you see this linear
increase here this is the yield
requirement these dotted lines of each
of these crops based on population in
the year
2050 this here is the projected increase
in yield if we continue along these
lines which we've been going on so far
the result of this is that the land area
we would need to extend for each of
these crops to get the yield that we
require is quite enormous quite enormous
so there's a a going to be a significant
problem about feeding
people um I can't tell you a great deal
about this slide that said that it's
very depressing I haven't read I must
admit this paper I didn't have time but
the take home message from it is that
without adaptation to climate change
particularly to increase in temperature
the yields that we're looking at right
now the yields that have been increasing
are actually going to decline 17 to
15% um over this period it's it's a very
very significant
problem but the news is not all bad the
good news is again this is a paper by
Zoo
2008 but if you look at solar energy
what comes in what is potentially there
for the plant to use if you look at the
total amount of solar
energy you get a thousand say kles of
energy not absorbed by the chlorophyll
513 reflected or transmitted 49
inefficiencies within photochemistry is
about 66 which leaves us with about
372 K of energy then we have C3 plants
and C4 plants C4 plants use more in
carbohydrate synthesis than do C3 plants
so the result we've got 85 left compared
to 128 however the C4 plants don't F to
respire whereas the C3 plants do so now
the C4 plants are ahead with 85 and then
we have respiratory processes which
bring the total energy to 60
k for the C4s and 40 6 k for the c3s
this is the potential energy that could
be captured turned into biomass if you
like in reality only one to 2% of this
is realized which means that we have
scope for
increasing this energy uh conversion and
and and and and and capture um the
question is how do we do it so we need
to be looking at the various traits of
plants what is causing why are they so
inefficient and how can we put in some
amelioration um some of the reasons
there's poor absorption of light there's
forer protection mechanisms which kind
of uh get rid of the the light energy
which may be absorbed to protect the
thids the statal closure plants will
light saturate when perhaps they we
could change them so that light
saturation point would be higher there's
all issues to do with source and sink
relationship feedback against fotenes
this star accumulation all of these
things can reduce the potential gain of
energy by the plant there's a lot of
targets that are are that we can aim
at and you know looking at the light
response for photosynthesis and we can
see that here we're in the light limited
range then we're in the light such at
range we could perhaps push this up
higher and then we have problems with
excess light energy where we get photo
inhibition added to this if the plants
are stressed with abiotic stresses or
biotic stresses where High lights low
high temperature etc etc low water
availability uh pathogen infection it
pushes the whole thing down so we need
to find out what these traits are we
need to be able to screen lots of plants
and to pick out the traits of
interest and to do this um Cubit systems
Photon systems in the cze Republic some
other companies I won't mention um have
Divine de designed and developed
instrumentation for screening large
amounts of large numbers of genetically
modified plants different lines and to
be able to detect as rapidly as possible
those plants with with potentially
beneficial traits so we're looking for
high throughput solution I mean ideally
you'd want to measure meure thousands of
plants all at the same time of day and
you'd want to measurement photosynthesis
transpiration etc etc etc you can't do
that with conventional CO2 analyzers
oxygen analyzers you need proxies and
most of these proxies are Optical and
that's what I'd like to talk about now
in the uh in the bulk of the seminar so
we have developed a series of
phenotyping instruments which we call
the the plant screen
um uh series and they have they're
different designs but they have similar
components so in this particular system
it's a conveyor based system we have an
external conveyor belt which feed plants
into a cabinet the cabinet is light
acclimated it has LEDs above there's
automatic watering and weighing the
plants go in trays or pots they move
through they're light adapted or dark
adapted they're they can be watered and
weighed to with specific protocols for
Drought or water sufficiency even water
logging and then we look at the effect
of any treatments we do via thermal
imaging hyperspectral Imaging chlorophyl
florescence Imaging and all for
morphometric and and and color
analysis um I won't bother with there's
numbers of these things now installed
throughout the world um they come in
various sizes this one has been
developed for Pioneer for screening very
very tall maze plants this is at the
University of OLS um different picture
the same thing this is a close-up of the
system at the University of alets and if
this works which I hope it
will it will show us a
video uh speed it up of the plants
coming from the external conveyor into
the cabinet this is going about um four
or five times faster than the plants
would would would normally move um they
move through the conveyor
system to the uh Imaging stations this
is for measuring RGB and chlorophyll
fluorescence kinetics of which I'll talk
about more about later um and then
there's thermal imaging and there's
hyperspectral Imaging everything is is
controlled under very strict
environmental conditions so that the
light incident on the plants is
homogeneous there is automatic weighing
of the plants with the plants you'll see
the plants lift they're on load cells
here five of the plants are weighed at
the same time and there's automatic
watering of the plants and you can
program the amount of water delivered to
each plant so that the weight doesn't
change with time for example or you can
reduce the weight so that you get a a
drought stressed environment or a water
logged environment we have students
working with us doing Masters and phds
this is one of them uh the whole system
runs offer graphical user interface
where you can put in protocols for the
various Imaging systems and um data
acquisition and you can also do all of
your your viewing of the data on these
uh
screens um we also have systems which
are in which the Imaging is taken to the
plants rather than the plants being
taken to the Imaging stations some
people argue that if you got a plant on
a conveyor bouncing around then you know
over time you're going to get some
environmental effects of vibration which
are going to skew your data uh in that
case you can actually take the Imaging
system to the plant but I would argue
that a plant being outside of the field
environment not moving at all again
there's going to be skewing of it its
architecture based on the fact that it
isn't being buffeted by the winds Etc
but we do offer these options and we
build these things in controlled
environment rooms which we call
they control the environment very very
specifically uh we also have field
phenotyping systems of different sorts
this is a Gantry system in which the um
phenotype in the Imaging array is built
on a Gantry like a almost like an
irrigation platform which moves across
the field it advances it can move up and
down for different heights of plant it
can do hyperspectral thermal chlorophyll
fluoresence RGB Imaging it's it's also
got sensors for CO2 light wind wind
temperature ambient sensors and um it
advances scans across a transa advances
again scans again generating terabytes
of data in the process uh this is a much
more modest system in which the user can
just drive the system in the or push the
system in the field the Imaging system
is here it moves up and down this is a
smaller version of this in which the
Imaging array moves across a small
transa and it can be Advanced so the
field systems have the same type of
capabilities as the growth room and the
greenhouse based systems we're also
doing crazy things um the the reason I
went to Thailand was to I didn't realize
there's a big problem with flooding of
rice it rice in Thailand can be
underwater for a significant period of
time and under very deep water so
apichart who's the director of the
research center there has developed
these ponds where he's going to grow
rice uh under uh actually 5 m of
water and he wants to see what happens
phenotypically with time so we're
developing the system very much like the
field system there's rails that move
across the pond there's the Gantry here
the Imaging system is here it can be
moved up and down and can do the types
of measurements which I've um I've
already
discussed so what do you do I mean what
was the the operation of this thing well
first of all you have to tell the system
which plants you're studying so so if
you're using a conveyor based system
with pots in trays then you have a part
of the software which says whoops um
which says what are these plants where
are they within the tray or is the part
there are bar there are barcodes and
offit identification tabs and these are
collated against the map that you make
of the system in the tray register then
every time that pot or that tray moves
through the system or it might be a GPS
location in the field it Cates all the
data you've ever collected um uh for
that particular plant or pot um in the
database with that reference same thing
when you've got um trays on the conveyor
system the conveyor feeds into the
Imaging you can have lines which are
just sitting there and and under defined
environmental conditions uh for growth
you can have lines which are the
operation lines which are going to be
moving through the system and you can
randomize the plants on these lines so
that you're not always measuring plant
number one at noon and plant number 2
285 at 400 p.m. that would skew your
data as well so there are randomization
programs which allow you to move the
plants around uh in space and make sure
that you don't measure uh the same
plants at the same time all the time um
there's lots of automated experimental
protocols so that you can set up
lighting conditions preconditions
watering conditions and you say for
these given sets of plants over this
time do eight rounds through these
various Imaging stations and do these
particular measurements and those
measurements then all the data are
collated in the software the network is
we have the various Imaging stations
when you were're collecting huge amounts
of complex data like from chlorophyll
fluorescence or from hyperspectral they
have their individual PCS with their own
database which then transfers the data
to the main database for uh less complex
measurements such as RGB thermal and um
and color analysis the data goes
directly to the database uh the analysis
of the data can be done remotely from
any computer which has allowed access to
the central server so um you can have
numerous people working on the data at
any one time and it's really up to the
client to decide who gets the access and
how much access they get for both
control and for data manipulation and
you can recalculate data you can do lots
of wonderful things with the
software what do we use it for we look
for abiotic stresses biotic stresses
plant growth analysis trait Discovery as
I mentioned before nutrient stress
ecotoxicology and we do it in both the
uh the lab and the field so the various
stations that we have I'll just go
through them one by one RGB and
structural Imaging very straightforward
typically three cameras one above two at
the sides at 90°
uh that gives you uh rudimentary 3D
reconstruction it's better if you
actually rotate the plant on a stage
take multiple images from different
angles and then you can get a beautiful
3D reconstruction for your Mor
morphological studies then the software
will allow you to compute
numerous parameters morphological
parameters and you can plot spids to
show how different plants within a
population differ in terms of for
example the area the perimeter the
compactness the roundness ETC very easy
to compare them using these spidergrams
then within individual plants you can
see how these parameters individual
parameters change over the course of
time when you're doing a a Time course
study looking at for example plant
architecture this is all automated data
um you can look this is a a water stress
experiment the data sorry the data are
plotted conventionally as why is it
doing that it's doing that because I'm
not pressing the laser pointer uh proed
conventionally on time course graphs as
well to see how for example the eara of
the plant declines as drought kicks in
against the controls and again we have
the
spidergrams
um we also have automated color analysis
because color changes with respect to uh
infection with chlorop content with
carotenoid content and you can Define
your color groups within the software as
many color groups as you want and the
software will automatically say at Time
Zero it had x% of sick green y% of
healthy green and z% of Z green of of of
of dark green and then with time it'll
show you how those greenness uh
indicators change AO
automatically
um we have a 3D scanning option as well
uh these three camera um things have
been criticized by some people that you
can get uh uh some artifacts due to the
plant moving as you're rotating on the
stage it might be uh more convenient to
have the plant move across the plant the
the camera move across the plant so that
you scan the plant this can be done
really really quickly and gives you
extremely fine resolution downside is it
costs a lot more a lot more to have a 3D
scanner than it does to have three
conventional cameras with a with a
rotating
stage we trct Leaf movement using this
RGB camera these are overlaid responsive
a rabid opsis leaf leaf movement this is
zooming in on one PL the uh other thing
we can do is the software will
automatically allow you to segregate
these into individual leaves so you can
track parameters Leaf by Leaf not just
plant by plant and you can plot all of
those parameters Leaf by
Leaf thermal imaging I've been talking
to a number of people this morning about
thermal imaging we use Fleer cameras to
do this typically um these slides are
fairly self-explanatory we look at the
temperature of the plants and the leaves
as the Tomato open um the leaf greater
of Vaper transpiration allows the leaf
to cool itself you get some plants which
like to take a risk they leave the
stomato open they cool themselves
they're allowing CO2 going in but
they're losing a lot of water other
plants are more conservative and they
say oh highlight close my stomato um
because I don't want to dry out but whoa
my photo synthesis has gone down now
therefore potentially I've got less
Shield it's a balancing act and some
plants are conservative some plants are
Risk Takers you can determine you can
see the difference between by looking at
the leaf temperature the static clows
the temperature goes up quite obviously
um we can see it also in osmotic stress
this is false color images of plants
which have been sub subjected to osmotic
stress here against control plants and
um you can see the temperature profile
changes very very quickly and very
obviously the stress versus the control
plants hyperspectral measurements I've
talked to a number of people in the
department this morning about
hyperspectral measurements essentially
you hit the leaf with a broad wavelength
of light a full spectrum of light say
from 400 to 2,500 nanometers depending
on the biochemical status of the leaf
it's going to absorb or reflect uh
different wavelengths and by measuring
those reflected wavelengths and applying
them to reflective indices these
calculations you can look at the
biochemical status with respect to
chlorophyll content carotenoid content
you can look at highlight stress through
measure of PRI you can look at water
content as well and these are just some
of the dozens of reflective indices that
are available in the literature and
people are discovering more and more of
these as as time goes on um ndvi is a
measurement which indicates chlorophyll
content um amongst other things this is
a study in which uh arabidopsis have
been subjected to different
concentrations of Roundup and you can
see it 2% Roundup after 50 hours very
very different ndvi as as shown on this
false color pallette compared to the the
control
values and these data are also plotted
here to see the change and I'm going to
point out the where the change occurs
temporally because I'll be coming back
to this slide later uh relative water
content using hyperspectral measurements
there are water absorbance bands are
about 1,400 1900 nanometers when the
plant is fully hydrated these bands are
very very deep as you put the plant
through a dehydration cycle they become
much more shallow um easy to
see easy to visualize a false color
palette showing fully hydrated plants
and blue the less blue there is the less
water there is you can see over a period
of a drying cycle the water uh changes
in water content are very very easy to
see and we're at a point now where we
can resolve about a 1% of fresh weight
change in water using these
hyperspectral
measurements thing I want to focus on is
chlorophyll florescence kinetic Imaging
and because I think we do well I know we
do this better than anybody else in the
world and in fact We Do It um with a
greater degree of um of precision and
resolution and we offer a lot more
parameters that one can measure which I
believe are the parameters that people
should be studying rather than the uh
parameter that most people study which
is dark adapted Quantum yield FB over FM
chlorophyll fluoresence I mean this is
an ancient experiment everybody does in
in bio11 you shine white light at a
suspension of chloroplast you see red
light because it's fluorescing at a
higher wavelength why and how does this
happen well this is your Zed scheme of
photosynthesis from plant physiology
301 you get the absorption of a photon
releases electrons from p680 these are
accepted by primary electron accepted QA
pass through the electron transport
chain to photos system one light
absorbed by p700 releases electrons
which are taken up by ferrodoxin
ferrodoxin is used to reduce nadph and
that is used to reduce CO2 all works
very beautifully wonderful um problem
occurs during stress when things go
south in here or along the electron
transport chain when when there are
problems when the stata close and
photosynthesis is limited it does not
stop absorption of Light by photosystem
too it does not stop the release of
these high energy electrons but the that
energy has got to go somewhere and it
can be dissipated as heat through what
we call non-photochemical quenching or
it can be dissipated as
fluoresence and it's fluoresence that we
measure to get an indication of the
degree of stress the onset the time of
on stress and the progression of stress
in the plant how do we do this
well we start off by putting the plant
in the dark and we give tiny tiny pulses
of Light which are non non actinic in
other words they don't they don't um
stimulate the dart reactions of
photosynthesis um and the plant under
those
circumstances all of the
electrons in the electron there's no
electrons attached to the electron
transport chain it's fully
oxidized then what we do is we give a
huge flash of light usually 5,000
micromoles of photons twice full
sunlight for about 08 seconds
this means that there's a huge flux of
electrons from here through this
electron transport chain but they've got
nowhere to go because these enzymes are
not operating which means that you get
maximum fluoresence yield you get this
peak of fluoresence here and when you do
a couple of calculations you get what
you call the quantum yield in the dark
adapted State this is FB over FM and
typically in a healthy plant that has a
conservative value of about
8.82 and as plants become stressed that
value declines and a lot of people use
this as the primary indicator of stress
which in my opinion is not a good idea
for reasons I'll get on to later what we
do what we do in our Imaging systems is
we push this further After the Dark adap
adaptation period we turn the light on
and we continue to image the chlorophyll
florescence kinetics what happens then
is that you get an initial peak of
fluorescence because the the
photosynthetic enzymes not active but as
you get activation of CO2 fixation this
fluorescence becomes less because of
course the electrons are now flowing
through the Zed scheme and uh you come
down then to a steady state fluoresence
by giving a saturating pulse at this
point you can look at what is called the
quantum yield of of
photosystem two in the light adapted
State how efficient is photosynthesis in
the light adapted State we measured a
whole pile of other par parameters
now having measured that light adapted
um Quantum yield if we know what the
photosynthetic Photon flux density if we
know how much light we're putting in
there in terms of micromoles of photons
we know that one Photon releases one
electron we can we know what the
proportion of light activating photos
system 2 versus photosystem one
typically 50/50 and we know the
proportion of Light which is absolutely
which is absorbed by the leaf typically
about 82% we can actually get
measurement of electron transport rate
it becomes an extremely good proxy for
photosynthetic rate you would have to
spend a lot of time measuring
photosynthetic rate on thousands of
plants by doing chlorophyll fluoresence
over a period of you know a few seconds
to a few minutes you can measure
thousands of plants simultaneously
almost and get very very good proxy for
photosynthetic rate this is a plot of
the photosynthetic rate measured by um
chlorophyll fluoresence against a
similation rate measured by uh more
conventional means very nice linear
relationship so there is a there is a
very good proxy we do this in our I
showed you the movie so you've seen the
LEDs given the light pulses and the
saturated flashes to measure the basic
parameters and then the calculated
parameters the great thing about the
Imaging is that not only can you see
these values these these these
fluorescent values um on an average
basis per plant and per Leaf you can
also see them pixel by pixel so if
you've got a disease which is spreading
through the leaf you can see the
progression the proportion of that leaf
which is being
diseased so uh why is this so nice if we
go back to our ndvi measurement here we
see that chlorophyll degradation when
you've treated it with Roundup before
you see anything takes about 13 hours if
you look at changes in morphology we're
looking at 20 hours before you see
anything measurable if we look at some
of the itic Imaging with chlorophyll
fluoresence we can see the effect
starting within 2 hours so if you're
really interested in when the onset of
stress occurs then this is a very Rapid
Way of seeing that and then if you want
to do amelioration effects you can start
putting in your ameliorations here and
seeing what how it's reversed you cannot
do that easily with these other
measurements um drought stress in turf
grass some work we did for Texas A&amp;M um
quickly f over FM over a 4-day period
without watering didn't change at all
8181 it was only after 7 days that we
saw a change whereas these other um
parameters like the fluorescence decline
ratio which I'll get on to in a moment
and non-photochemical quenching had
changed quite significantly by four days
you need to do this in the light adapted
State you can't just do the F over FM
measurement uh again here this is the
fluorescence decline ratio is looking at
this peak value but were uh compared to
what happens here you can see the
changes in control values versus treated
values the differences occur in this
quenching area right so you got to
measure them you got to be able to
measure them to see them but that's
where you're going to find your
signatures for uh trait
Discovery uh salt stress in a rabid
opsis we look at FV over FM there's no
change in the parameter until about 4
days was if you look at the fluorescence
decline ratio it changes within two days
and youve just looking at the images you
can see the very distinct difference
when you apply these to a false color
palette this was interesting a study um
done by uh the young lady you saw in the
video she's interested in um starch
mutants of arabidopsis and how they
might be related to um osmotic
protection during drought stress and she
had mutants of phosphoglucomutase alpar
am beta ralas and um looking at the
fluorescence characteristics of these
there's no change in the Fe over FM when
you impose the D distress on them but
the phosphoglucomutase mutant if you
look at uh this parameter FP over fo no
change from the initial whereas the
others change very significantly don't
know the basis for this but it's
interesting that when you look at
survivability of these mutants it's the
phosphoglucomutase mutant which survived
and the others had a very very poorer
survivability so the conclusion for this
I would argue is that F FM in some in
some cases is valuable but it's a blunt
instrument for looking at stress
particularly rapid onset of stress um
light adapted kinetics provide earlier
indications and more significant changes
so you've got this balance between plant
phenotyping one in a huge throughput
which means measure everything as
quickly as possible
and the problem of measuring things
properly so you can collect a huge
amount of data very very quickly collect
a huge amount of useless data very
quickly or you can spend your time and
collect more useful data and it's up to
you to decide on your experimental
designs which of those two approaches
you you you're going to
adopt um just very briefly root screen
I've talked to some people this morning
about root screening so I thought I'd
throw this in it's really really
difficult to screen Roots phenotypically
very very hard they're in the soil what
are you going to do with imaging you
know it's it's very difficult using
translucent tubes is fine there's been a
lot of fine work done Imaging just with
RGB cameras plants grown in gels problem
is they're grown in gels they're not the
root characteristics are not going to be
the same as in the soil um in
translucent tubes is the same well it's
not the same because you've got soil but
you have to wait for the plant to grow
before the roots hit the periphery of
the you Bo you can actually see them so
if you're interested in what happens in
early germination Etc you're not going
to see it at all and then only 5 to 10%
of this roots are going to be visible at
the edge of a typical pot and you have
to extrapolate your morphological
parameters back to the whole root system
which is not something I would be
comfortable doing lowd do x-rays plants
growing in plastic beads these are great
wonderful uh you can actually there's
wonderful videos on the web of roots
growing when on on when they being x-ray
again they're imp plastic beads it's a
hydroponic system it's not soil ground
penetrating radar there's guys at Texas
A&amp;M I've talked to some people this
morning about how this is done I think
it's a long long way before we're going
to be able to see Roots using ground
penetration radar just too much
interference the one I think is most
promising is rotron studies uh this is a
system developed at ulic these are
rotron here the plants are grown the the
rotron these are root boxes with uh
with perspects in the front so we can
image the The Roots as they go through
the system the plants grow vertically
downwards and then when they hit this
45° angle they spread out so now we can
see a Much More Much More Much Greater
proportion of the roots then you would
in say a translucent pot and um some
nice data have come out of this I'd
refer you to this paper in functional
plant biology you know using a 16
megapixel camera they got very good
resolution uh looking at root length
branch in rate spatial distribution this
is something which we're hoping to
integrate into our into our plant screen
systems I'm just going to finish off um
I've been rabbiting on
um these systems are expensive don't
hide the fact they are quite complex um
very
sophisticated uh take up a lot of arer
typically in a growth room in a
greenhouse if you want to do thousands
of plants conveyor belt systems
you can do things less expensively for
example plant by plant if you have
enough people uh to go around your
plants and put your Leaf under this Leaf
clip you can get beautiful chlorophyll
fluorescence kinetics you can also do
this in algae uh using a probe which you
can put into a submerged culture it's
not Imaging data it's average data over
the area of the optical window of these
systems but you get the full quenching
parameters using this device this Floren
device um you also get downloads via
Bluetooth graphical representation of
the chlorophyll fluorescent kinetics so
you can go out in the field and you can
make lots and lots of measurements um
using a system which will cost you about
maximum about $3 and half thousand
including your measuring
photosynthetically active radiation even
GPS location in the field and all of
your kinetic
values um there's other devices
specifically for hyperspectral
measurements like ndvi and PRI these um
are uh specific for these a single pen
will do each of these my friends who I
dinner with last night now tell me that
they've been building systems for even a
tenth of the cost of this these cost
about $1,200 $1,300 these guys here at
Cornell they so bright they can throw
them together for 200 bucks so don't buy
them from me buy them from from those
guys yeah um I'm happy with that
uh what we have also though is a poly
pen which is a handheld
spectrometer and um there are a couple
of versions of this there's a spectr pen
in which there's no Leaf clip and you
can point this or any light source and
it'll give you a beautiful Spectrum it's
great for calibrating light sources it's
great for going into your growth rooms
and seeing whether your light yesterday
is the same as it was uh today etc etc
you can do all types of chrom
chromaticity measurements with it but
when you have the um the leaf clip here
you can get a full reflectance scan
across these ranges 380 to 780 640 to
1050 NM from which you can get
automatically calculated your reflective
indices IND indicative of the pigment
concentrations in the plant and and
various other biochemical uh status uh
uh of the plant as well so um that's a
very interesting thing what um I would
recommend if any of you have large
amounts of money and you uh you want to
spend it on plant phenotyping systems uh
you can make very expensive Mistakes by
going to the wrong place so I would
suggest that you try before you buy and
to do that all you need to do is jump on
a plane to the cat Republic this
beautiful place in drazo we have uh PhD
level plant scientists we have Engineers
we have programmers we have a wonderful
Research Center here we build a lot of
things on on site we have wonderful
engineering we can run proof of concept
experiments we have students there who
are doing their masters and phds from
local universities and universities
throughout Europe it's a great place to
visit these are great people to go out
drinking with and um good beer in the CH
Republic and I I please come over please
come and chat with me jump on the plane
we'll have some fun and we'll show you
the the stuff actually does work and if
you want to push it to its limit and you
want to push it Beyond its limit we're
also very very keen for you to tell us
what you want and your ideas how we
might implement it and how we might even
work together to push plant phenotyping
to the next stage so uh thank you very
very much for the invite and uh thank
you for your attention
well thank you this has been a
production of Cornell University on the
web at cornell.edu