This is a production of Cornell
University.
So thanks for being here. Uh good
afternoon everyone. Myself Shriant. I'm
a second year PhD grad student in plant
building and genetics. I'm from Mueller
Lab. Today before I would like to
explain the project that I'm working on
from past couple of months and before
diving into the project we would like to
I would like to explain some of the
fundamental concepts and essential to
build this project. So first what
exactly is a database? So database is
the system that is widely used across
the industry and academia for data
storage, data retrieval and data
management. So breedbase. So breedbase
is the relational database system that
is free and open source that our lab
developers have been built over the
years. They added a bunch of features uh
based on the brand building communities
request and now uh brand building
communities they can easily upload their
data into the breedbase and using the
analysis tools that our lab developers
have built they can analyze their data
and make datadriven decisions.
So using the breedbased instance our lab
also involved in developing a couple of
crop databases uh specifically for the
casawava casawa base musa that's for
banana am crop for ambase and sweet
database and there are many other crop
breedbased instances used by companies
but I cannot list them with this even in
the past year I worked on repetive
measurements in other words you can say
this as a time series feature uh it's
basically where you have a multiple
values for a given trade that you would
like to store. So this feature was
requested from UC Davis breeding program
and North Carolina State University
breeding program. Uh that therefore
we've implemented that. So with this now
I have a very good understanding of how
breedbase works and how the process of
breedbase actually is implemented. So
with this knowledge I would uh knowledge
and experience I would like to take
breedbase to the next level where I
would like to integrate artificial
intelligence in the breedbase. So before
actually diving into the what AI
application we will be building in uh
for the breedbase I would like to give
the uh brief statistics about the casava
base. As I mentioned in the previous
slide casavase is one of the largest
database as we have so far. So as of
March 2025 we have almost 240 GB of data
in the casava base out of which oh oh
sorry yeah out of which uh 12 GB is a
phenotypicing data. uh and uh why it is
not
working. Okay. Yeah. 118 GB is of
genotypic data and due to time
constraint I'll not go to the each
component of
this. I'm not sure why this is not
working. Okay. Yeah. Due to constraint I
cannot go through the each component.
However, I would like to pinpoint and
mention that Kasaw has been widely used
across the world in almost 550
locations. As you can see this database
is so much complex and it's a large
database, right? So we often use a
structured query language which is
called SQL language to communicate with
the databases. This is not the
observable trait in most of the plant
breeders or the community right to
communicate with the database. With this
in mind we would like to build a yeah we
would like to develop a chatbot uh for
the breed base using
LLMs. So first uh I would like to show
you the back end or the workflow how it
looks after it has been implemented or
deployed in the production site. So
imagine you are a user and you are
communicating with some AI. I hope
everyone have used chat GPT or Google B.
So they know right. So user might ask
hey how many trials do I have so far in
IIA breeding program. So then using the
rack technique that I'll describe in the
next slide uh they will extract the
trial uh column names and the table
names from the database for this
specific uh NL question that user asked
in the interface or in the chatbot. So
these both will be provided to the
fine-tuned LLM and LLM will write uh SQL
query which means it's another word
where you use to communicate with the
databases. So this will eventually be uh
executed on the database and that where
you get the output. So we do not like uh
we in addition to showing the value from
that we retrieved from the database we
would also like to show the generalized
statement along with the value.
Therefore this would be clear and
concise information to the user whoever
is querying.
Right. Uh yeah, of course it is true
that there are so many closed source
LLMs uh that are outperforming in
various tasks such as summarization,
code generation and lot many other
tasks. However, recently Stanford NLP
group have tested uh with the fi uh
various closed source models. They
fine-tuned their LLMs using those closed
source API keys and they found that
there is ineffectiveness in upgrading
existing knowledge. So what I mean by
that is once they fine-tuned their
models using this closed source APIs uh
after after that they modified their
data in the database and fine-tuned LLM
couldn't able to retrieve the updated
data and there are wide variety of
reason why this is happening but the
primary reason is uh closed source close
source LLM doesn't have a flexibility of
using different LLM techniques on the
fine-tuned model therefore you cannot
even improve the model accuracy or
performance right so with this uh I
referred a couple of times about the
closedource LLMs. So primarily those are
developed from open AI and the Google
and the cloud anthropic and the open
source LLMs are meta deepseek and
Microsoft. These are primarily deployed
on the hugging phase. From hugging phase
you can easily deploy onto your local
machine or the GPUs and then you can run
them. So for this project we will not be
using these closed source models.
However, we would be likely to use open
source LLMs uh to build this project. So
I mentioned LLM strategies in the
previous slide a couple of times, right?
uh first I would like to uh mention
about retrieval argument generation. So
as it is a $5 word and it's a simple
word as a name it indicates it's just a
retrieving. So basically if user ask
some question in the NL interface it
retrieves the table names or the column
names with respect to the database to
that question uh uh yeah to that
question. So it's not a high level of
coding that is required to implement
this technique or this objective. And
next comes the supervised fine tuning.
Supervised fine is a time consuming and
it's a iterative process and it's you
need to build a a training data set in a
way that it should include all the edge
cases even. So it's a high level of
coding that is also required. So next
last technique is reinforcement
learning. So reinforcement learning is a
branch of ML that is that we actually
basically use the AI train the AI agents
based on the trial and error method and
it's a high level of coding that is
required. There is no straightforward
mathematical framework or a mathematical
uh formula to directly deploy them. You
have to verify with a different
algorithms for this. With that, yeah,
with that I would like to thank my PI
for giving me exciting opportunity to
work on this and also I would like to
thank John for giving me access to the
GPUs to test it before trying to deploy
these uh models on the uh production
side. With that, I would like to open
the floor to any questions. Thank you so
much.
Yeah, last slide you listed a couple
different strategies. Is there any one
that you want to look at going forward
or are you going to try all three maybe
to see which one works best? Yeah, so
the question is uh in this slide that
I'm showing right now uh she mentioned
that I'm I showed here different
techniques, right? Uh do I use all of
those or do I use only one among among
the three? So these three techniques are
very important in order to make this
objective efficient. So you cannot use
only one. So these three techniques are
combined to build this chatbot. Meaning
all these three uh techniques are very
useful. So it's doing one one technique
is doing one job. You have to combine
all these three techniques.
Yeah. Like so you're using the cassava
data set to how hard would it be to then
use another data set for another crop
like to translate this to another crop?
Would you have to rebuild and train the
model all over again or would it be
easily trans? Yeah. uh the question here
in the audience is uh currently I'm
using the casava base for the initial
stage to build this uh if we eventually
in the future if I transfer to the other
crop or other databases how easy or how
hard is it so the simple question is for
our example we have a multiple crop
databases right so for casava base and
most of the databases we have a same
structure so what I mean by structure so
the table names column names all are
same across the uh different crops only
the values or some functionality might
change right so if you implement Kazava
base and it working fine as we expect.
So in order to scale up to the other
databases, we need to change the table
names and the column names in those
databases to specifically to those crops
in order to make it. Yeah, that's a
problem. Um yeah, so my name is Chris
Merate. I'm a fourth year uh PhD student
in Lar's lab uh in Cornell uh agreech in
Geneva. And today I would like to do an
updated summary of my work on mapping
QTL and identify u candy genes for seed
aeronomic traits in hemp F2 my
populations. So to start off I would
like to for for some of you that are not
familiar with this crop there are three
main market classes in hemp flour fiber
and grain. Uh for the flower obviously
the um the end product is the struction
of canabonoids for these flowers. Uh but
for all these market market classes
there are key traits to take into
account when considering cultivars and
when breeding um cultivars for the
flower per se uh the idea is to increase
the floral biomass. So flowering uh time
is one important trait to consider and
obviously canabonoids as well uh which
is not something that I'm going to cover
today. For the fiber the ideal is to
harvest the stem. So we also want based
on the eotype you can see here for
example is a tall non-branchy late
flowering cultivar. So one of the
important traits is flowering time as
well as biomass to ensure that we have
this accumulation of biomass and fiber
quality is another important trait. So
from this biomass that is accumulated we
can remove this bus from the herd for
the um uh to maximize the bass
production for textiles or the hair
production if the intent is for
construction materials. And lastly we
have the grain. Another market classes
that is embedded in it is the dual
purpose which stands for production of
the grain and the stock. So you harvest
the inflloresence and then you harvest
the stocks at the end. Uh so you can get
fiber and um and grain as well. Uh and
here the again one of the mark the key
traits to consider is flowering time
because we want to ensure that we
accumulate biomass so this crop reaches
a sufficient height for an optimal
harvest. Um and uh for incred sorry and
in mets meat sorry the uh goals whether
it's dual purpose or grain only um and
biomass as well because we want to have
that balance between certain
accumulation biomass for both fiber and
grain and obviously I'm not going to uh
forget grain yield and seed quality
especially the seat quality is another
important trait in this case what we are
considering quality right now is the
seat size as well as the protein oil
content
But speaking of um seat size, so here in
this picture you can see the variation
on seat size that we have in our general
plasm in Geneva. Um and from the
importance standpoint actually seat size
could be beneficial for stand
establishment. Uh from a consumer
perspective a larger seat will be more
appealing for a consumer and from a
processing point of view this we have uh
observed that larger seats may lead to a
better processing of these seeds. So
traditionally hemp hearts that you see
and you can access commercially are
seats that originate from cultivars that
are not that different from
um seat size that equates beli or felina
32 that you see here or perhaps even
smaller than this. So we're interested
in uh looking at the processability of
these larger seats that you see on the
left as well as of course the genetic
mechanisms underlying that um trait or
the seat size alone. So this hemp grain
which is no grain it's on a kein
actually uh once it's harvested it is uh
processed um and here you can you can
get two main components of the seeds the
hemp hearts which are actually the kons
of the seeds and the hemp holes the hemp
hearts are high in protein uh about 20
20 to 25% protein the fat is about 25 to
35 if I'm not mistaken and the holes
which are the perarb of this uh akin is
high in dietary fiber about 25 to 35% as
well But ultimately the end product of
these components become into hemp seed
meal, hemp seed oil, fortified foods
like baked goods as well as plant-based
meats and dairies that you can see here
highlighted in this um this graph. So
with all of this in mind, I established
three objectives and those are to
identify significant QTL for seat size
and aloromic traits and to compare uh or
determine the consistency of this QTL
between three populations that will
represent each of the market classes and
identify hopefully the candidate genes
within the 1.5 low interval for each of
these
QTL. So to start off uh in 2021 a high
canominoid F2 population was developed
crossing an parameial resistant colonial
individual of 58 NGCBD
um chron individual that is parameible.
The idea here or the main uh goal of
this uh was to characterize parame
resistance as I was saying however other
phenotypes were measured. uh for this
the crossing scheme was the selfing of
two uh selected F1s generating two f2s
and the idea of having more than one f2
is so that because h is highly
heterrozygous having more than one
population increases our likelihood to
capture the effect of alo present in the
parents. So here we have 214 and 215
with 366 and 304 individuals
respectively. U another important thing
to mention is that the flowering time
between these two parents is about a
week. Um so they probably relatively um
I want to say early but not too late
either. Uh for the green population in
this case we employ a dualpurpose green
line. Uh this one is 201179 or GBH 2011
1179 which is a late flower individual
large seeded compared and crossed with a
picodo which is a very popular Canadian
uh grain cultivar that has high protein
content that has u small seed and early
flowering. In this case, the custom
scheme was developed to a sip mating of
uh the F1s and we ended up phenotyping
only the females uh 198 of them. For the
fiber uh in this case we use fiber bre
to GBA 19 uh 1024. This is a very late
flowering a very large seated um uh
cultivar population and was crossed with
the first New York uh feral population
isolated which is Logan. uh this is a
very early and a very small seated uh
cultivar. In this case, we also did se
mating for the generation of the F2s.
But here we phenotype and genotype uh
females and males having a total of 445
um
individuals. For the creation of the
linkage maps, we use two genotypic
platforms uh genotyping platform sorry.
Uh for a high calamina population uh
21,04 and 21,05 we use an illuminina
array developed by Pho. uh here we ended
up with linkage maps that have uh
2,659 and 2,197 markers respectively.
Whereas for the grain FI population we
use an agulant sure select props set
that we developed in our lab which we
named hand select um and um this
eventually uh help us develop or create
a linkage linkage maps that have 748
markers for the grain and 922 markers
for the fiber. So with all this in mind
uh on all these methodologies so I
decided to look at the seat size in this
case we quantify that by the weight of
10,000 seats or thousand sew as you can
see here first in the high population
2004 we found uh five QTL that um are
associated with this trait and as you
can see here the uh largest peak is
located in chromosome one that explain a
good portion of the variance and it's a
very small region relatively speaking uh
in the genome and we see that the effect
of the AL is dominant over the B al for
the population we also find uh a QTL in
chromosome one but conversely this is
the only QDL that we find explaining low
proportion of the variance but in a very
large region and in this case the effect
of the AL over the B al seems to be
additive for the grain we have four QTL
identified and in this case we don't
observe this we observe that the largest
effect the largest uh peak is in
chromosome 9 instead explaining uh a
considerable a considerable part of
percentage of the variance sorry but a
large region and also seems to be
additive and in the fiber very interest
inly we only find two QTL but a massive
peak in chromosome 4 that explains over
60% of the variance in a population and
but unfortunately the region is quite
large it's 9.1 megabases and here the
additive effect uh sorry the effect of
the B al over the AL is
additive now for the flowering time. Um
this in this case we for 214 in the high
can population we find one large peak in
chromosome one again compared to the um
the one forc weight uh that explains
also a good proportion of the variance
and it's a small region uh the effect of
this alil is again dominant um as you uh
compared to the one identified in the
tasan ce uh for 215 uh we also also
observe another peak well two peaks
actually but the largest peak in
chromosome one explaining 20% of the
variance in a large over 20% in a large
region. Um and in this case the effect
is additive. For the grain, we only find
one um peak in chromosome one that
explains over half% of the variance. And
in this case, this alil seems to be
additive. And for the fiber, we observe
the most UT identified for flowering
time uh four one to five actually to be
precise. But again uh the most um the
largest peak is in chromosome one uh
with an additive effect uh but
unfortunately doesn't explain that much
of the varian. So what you see here uh
is highlights the importance of this
chromosome one or the presence of
flowering time genes in this uh
chromosome one u in the cannabis genome
at least for gen that we're evaluating
here and lastly for biomass which uh I
would expect that will coincide with the
flowering time and for this family it
does uh proportional variance uh same
with the genetic region but again this
uh is an additive alil uh compared to
the B al uh for hikabinoid 2005 uh again
there's a peak here there's no there are
not many doesn't explain much of the
variance but it's still there and I'm
seeing the same thing in grain larger uh
the largest peak or the only peak in
chromosome one equates to the one in the
flowering time uh explaining compression
of the variance but a large region but
in the fiber however uh we don't observe
that peak in chromosome one that should
coincide with flowering time but instead
is only uh in chromosome 6 which is very
interesting for us however doesn't
explain than much of the variance but um
uh is interesting
nonetheless and yeah so with that uh the
key takeaways are that the chromosomal
location for largest effect QTL for seat
size measure as a thousand C weight uh
differs depending on the location on the
population that we use uh the largest
effect of this QTL for flowering time in
all population was located in chromosome
one the largest effect UTL for biomass
seems to coincide with that for flower
in all populations except the one in
fiber which in chromosome
And one thing I don't know if you if you
caught it, but there seems to be a one
plyotropic dominant effect QTL in
chromosome one for this high canal
population in
214. Um so with that I would like to
thank all the members of the lar lab as
well as my founders funding sources
listed here and I will welcome any
questions.
The big range of planting densities for
hemp like super dense for fiber, super
sparse for canonoids. How'd you pick the
density or the densities used for this
study? And does that have like a complex
I mean does that impact impact flowering
time and total seedling differently like
in the fiber by parentals versus like
the canonoid or grain by parentals?
Yeah. So the question is if how I
decided the planting density and if that
affects the traits uh phenotype here. Um
so the plant density was y spacing. So
for example, one trait that will
ultimately be affected by a plant
density is yield uh for biomass as well
as um seed yield. That's definitely
affects flowering time however does not
seem to be affected by the plant
intensity. Uh and the seed size does not
seem to be affected either as well.
So I was wondering you have a lot of QTL
on chromosome one and you said it might
be due to the pleotropic effects from
that one parent population. Have you
looked further into those QTL to see if
it's like one major one or two major
genes that seem to be controlling this
effect or are there QTL in like very
different locations on that chromosome?
This is why I like you Emily. Okay, so I
did not have the time to incorporate
this in the presentation. So I was
hoping somebody will ask that. Uh I do
so we do have the sequencing the actual
sequence of the parents in this hikino
population. Um and we were able to have
um uh what is that called? um the
structural and functional predictions of
the genes located. So what I was able is
to section the regions of that specific
uh QTL and compare them each other with
each other and see what differs. And the
one that I identify as the one differing
is this Luke 7 like protein in
chromosome one. Uh and there is this G
insertion that causes a frame mutation
frame shift mutation uh in this habype.
Um this looks like protein is um oh
sorry um it it's
um uh homal to a luke 7 RL in the
arabidopsis um and this seems to
participate as an accessory protein to
the U1 uh small nuclear ribbonuclear
protein in the splyosome so it affect
it's it's affected or affects the
um RNA maturation of several genes and
group ineneral Germany actually
validated this by knocking it out,
knocking it out and testing like what is
uh upregulated regulated and what um
several um outcomes that they got from
that which uh highlights a plyotropic
effect um in the raidopsis um organism.
This has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu.