this is a production of Cornell
University thank you um yes as as Emily
said my name is Erin I'm a a fourth year
PhD student in Mike gors and I'm excited
to talk with you all today about uh
integrating data collected from
different proximal remote or proximal
sensors uh for improved prediction of
important
traits so proximal uh sensors PR present
a mechanism of field-based high
throughput uh phenotyping that saves um
Time and Labor as compared with manually
measuring
phenotypes uh so proximal sensors are uh
those which do not come into direct
contact with the plant um but are more
close by or uh proximal than remote
sensors such as satellites um so you can
see here some commonly used uh plat
platforms for uh field-based um proximal
sensing include um unoccupied aerial
Vehicles such as
drones um Gantry systems tractors uh
push carts um ground Rovers um and even
smartphones the uh sensors which can be
deployed on these uh different platforms
um include uh typical red green blue
cameras uh multispectral and
hyperspectral cameras which include
additional bands Beyond those um and
then we also have liar uh thermal and um
then uh radar which can sense um below
ground
trades um so these uh sensors have a
broad application to both uh breeding
and precision
agriculture they can be used to uh
forecast end of season traits um
therefore allowing selections to be made
pre-flowering and decreasing the
breeding
cycle um features from these data
streams can be used in phenomic
prediction where those features replace
um traditional markers in genomic
prediction um they can also be used for
um building populations for genomic
prediction genome wide Association
studies and the um increased temporal
resolution um lends um to studying
genotype by environment
interactions they have also been used
for uh stress detection and efficient
allocation of resources in Precision
agriculture
applications so uh due to the um
broad-reaching
applications um for breeding programs um
significant investment in um studying
the use of of these different sensors
and platforms for a variety of of
different traits have been carried out
in recent years including um
productivity traits such as yield
biomass uh quality traits such as um
taste and many others across a wide
array of
crops what this has ultimately led to is
a a large number of crop and trait
specific
algorithms in addition these uh data
streams are both very high-dimensional
and complex um a single multispectral
image can have couple hundred thousand
pixel values for a single plot and so um
how to effectively extract meaningful
information from the the data becomes
the challenge and we have ultimately um
relied on Manual curation of
features um in addition you can see
there's a variety of different sensors
which capture um wavelengths across the
electromagnetic spectrum um and
platforms which allow uh capture of
information at canopy subcanopy and
below ground scales um and while there's
like the you know unique information
contained within each of these um data
streams um this data is is usually used
uh separately from each other and
integration is uncommon and and Lacks
generalizability
so as an example um on the left here we
have um a kind of pictographic
representation of a multispectral image
which can be thought of as a grid of
pixel values for each band um the bands
kind of stacked on top of each
other um the most common mechanism for
extracting information from these is by
calculating vegetation indices so might
be familiar with the um normalized
difference vegetation index is
calculated by taking the relative
difference between the near infrared and
the red bands of the
image um ultimately reducing down to a
single uh value per multispectral
image um an alternative to this is uh
latent
phenotyping so latent
phenotyping um is a mechanism of
extracting features or information from
proximal sensing data streams using
unsupervised machine learning algorithms
such as Auto encoders so while the um
while ndbi in this example takes in just
the n and the Red Band um were able to
pass the entire um image um into the
model to extract
information um in addition where ndvi
reduces down to a single value
um we can uh extract a larger number of
latent
features um we specifically do this
using Auto encoders um which can be
conceptualized similar to uh principal
component analysis of without the
linearity constraints so it takes the um
input image and passes it through an
encoder to reduce the dimensionality and
find an
embedding that reduced space is then
passed through an analogous uh Network
the decoder to reproduce the original
image and um the model is optimized such
that the difference between the original
and the Reconstruction is minimized so
in this way the latent features um
should contain the necessary and
sufficient information to reconstruct
the original image um and are hopefully
the most relevant then and important
features are noise and and other
unimportant
information so our goal is to um make
use of latent
phenotyping to perform integration
across different sensors preserving uh
additional information that is lost with
traditional um mechanisms of feature
extraction and providing a a
generalizable u method of analyzing
these data so I'll I'll go through our
um end end pipeline of data collection
processing and Analysis through
extracting and integrating Laden
features so we have specifically focused
on multispectral images collected by
unoccupied aerial vehicles or drones and
uh lar scans collected by unoccupied
ground vehicles or the uh Rover here so
the multispectral images collected uh
blue green green red red Edge and near
infrared bands capturing that canopy
level spectral information which is
commonly um extracted as vegetation
indices the lighter skins can be used to
generate three-dimensional
reconstructions of an entire plot giving
subcanopy architectural
information these data were collected
for Maze hybrids planted as part of the
genomes to Fields
initiative um for weekly collections
from 2020 through 2024 uh for each
growing season we pause Rover
collections a couple weeks post
flowering um until inessence as uh
structural changes slow during that
time um ultimately giving a data set of
about 75,000 plot level multispectral
images and about 35,000 plot level Point
clouds so
the multispectral images are collected
by this drone here you can see the
camera on the bottom the raw images have
about 80% overlap with each other which
allows them to be stitched together to
generate a field uh scale image or
orthomosaic the field scale image can
then be split down into our individual
plot level
images the uh lighter camera is on the
back of the row over here which drives
in between the um two uh rows of maze um
the uh lar
scans um collect the uh distance emitted
light has traveled to the nearest object
um can be thought of as being in polar
coordinates this is essentially
converted into cartisian coordinates to
generate a three-dimensional Point Cloud
where each point has an X Y and Z
coordinate associated with it
um do further um processing on this to
remove arous points um do vertical
flipping uh kind of stacking the rows on
top of each other and then compressing
that down to a single uh
two-dimensional image or density map
which can be input into an auto
encoder so we have trained Auto encoders
for both the multispectral image
and the uh 2D density Maps uh you can
see examples here of original images and
as well as their reconstruction for both
the msis and density
Maps the uh latent spaces uh can then be
extracted from each of these uh trained
models and
integrated so once these models had been
trained and Laten phenotypes had been
extracted we wanted to first see what
kind of information was contained within
them so this is uh these are latent uh
phenotypes for a single uh field in a
single year um we calculated the uh
heritability for each of them in lar and
msis um and what you can see here is the
heritabilities range from uh near zero
up to about 0.9 uh so we're capturing
both
um heritable genetic information as well
as um is likely environmental
information uh the latent phenotypes
once uh extracted and integrated are
then used for characterizing manually
measured uh phenotypes for the gtf
fields
so for uh each of the eight ground truth
phenotypes that were collected as part
of the genomes to Fields project um
these were predicted by MSI Laten
phenotypes for all dates in the growing
season lar Laten phenotypes for all
dates in the growing season and then the
integration of the two and these were
compared against a baseline of 49
different vegetation
indices uh extracted or calculated for
all uh msis throughout the growing
season um what you can see here is that
um flowering time and Gra moisture have
higher um ndbi has higher predictive
ability for those
traits um for the uh remainder the
integrated uh L venot types have higher
predictability with um variation on when
MSI or lar Laten phenotypes are more
highly predictive um for example you can
see here um ear height and uh plant
height are have higher predictability um
from the lar Len space um as their
architectural traits if Mak sense um
overall we see a um
4.6 um% average increase in uh
prediction accuracy for the integrated l
in Space over vegetation indices across
all
trits um similarly the integrated latent
space outperforms MSI and lar latent
phenotypes by average of 5.1% and 20.8%
respectively so finally we wanted to um
look at how the uh prediction accuracies
changed with the addition of more
information throughout the growing
season so we iteratively added uh dates
of
information um for each of the eight uh
phenotypes here so as predicted with the
integrated Laten space uh we can see
some uh prediction accuracies don't
change for example um stand count which
isn't changing over the growing season
so um makes sense um some traits which
are are not very easily predicted um
early in the season uh and only see kind
of a large bump toward the end um but
notably there are some indices and
traits that have reasonable prediction
accuracies pre-flowering so um yield
here sees a 0.1 increase from the uh
pre-flowering uh predictions to the end
of um end of season incorporating all of
the dates um indicating the potential uh
foreing this data for um pre-flowering
forecasting so I would like to thank my
uh committee Mike Gore H tuon ying and
Margaret Smith I'd like to thank the
gore laab um and buckler La specifically
um Liam Wicks do and Nick pck for
helping with the efforts of collecting
so much of this this data over five
years um Kelly Robbins and uh Joe Gage
for their um assistance with modeling um
a Davis Peter Michael and zesu for their
um assistance and incredible work on the
auto encoder
modeling thank you so much and I'll take
questions
yes
Charlie the traits you're look you're
looking at these correlations with are
the traits themselves are correlated
with each other right so like you know
flowering time and yield so is there any
way to like kind of disentangle which
which of those the models or which which
of those the latent spaces kind of
capturing and which are like second
order yeah that's that's a great
question so the question was um since so
many of these uh phenotypes are
correlated with each other um is there a
way to disentangle which um the latent
phenotypes are capturing and which are
just correlated with each other is that
the question so
um I think that that is a great question
and we haven't done a lot of um
investigation
into
um which which latent phenotypes are
more highly correlated with which traits
um and what they're capturing um
ultimately the latent phenotypes are
still kind of a a black box for us um
and maybe relying on these um
relationships between um between traits
um it's kind of a yeah secondary kind of
selection um but uh that is a that is a
very good question I'll definitely look
into that more
yeah when we fly drones we like you know
have to do it near solar noon and like
you have to consistent cloud cover for
the lighter Rover are there similar
constraints and do those impact how well
certain data points can be integrated
into your
model so the question is um for uh
flying drones and collecting
multispectral images there are
constraints on time of day and cloud
cover and other conditions are there
similar constraints for the Rover data
um
so in so far as the data collection
quality there aren't really constraints
um the constraint would be
around when we can feasibly drive the
Rover so if it's rainy um of course we
can't or if it has rained heavily in the
past day or two and it's too muddy the
tires will you know just kind of spin um
so more constraints on the platform
itself than the the sensor yeah and yeah
very nice what I was wondering about
have you tried training between the two
reps it'll mess up your heritability
estimate but if we want to say we wanted
to capture really about genetics and
kind of ignore some of the environmental
ones have You' been able to does does
that work or have you tried that yet
yeah so that's a great question so the
question is training um between reps so
using one rep as the input image and the
the second rep as the output is that
that correct so we haven't tried that so
we've been when focusing on kind of plot
level predictions themselves um and have
looked less into kind of parsing out
those uh genetic and environmental
factors uh within the the latent
features um but that would definitely be
something that we should look at for for
the next itation it would also be
interesting to see if you could predict
liar use the liar to predict the other
one the MRI and as essentially make the
embedding space in between those two or
something like yeah oh yeah yeah that's
a good point thank
you I didn't quite file for latent
phenotypes um like in like a is there
like a an intuitive way you describe
those in terms of like okay they're kind
of analogous to this in a PCA or like
this and like weights in a layer or so
they're like dimensionless metrics on a
plot level versus like a or an image
level yes so yeah so um the you can
think of them as like the principal
components of some some higher order
object um that's probably the the
closest um analogous uh yeah kind of
conceptual way of thinking about
it um I'll do the last question um so I
know that of course L you work with work
with maze but I was wondering with the
Rover are there any kind of like
architectural limitations about what
crops that you can drag
them uh yes that's a great question on
the um limitations of the Rover
depending on the the um architecture of
the crop um so the uh resolution of the
lar scans um is on the order of
centimeters um so anything that is too
small um would not be able to be
resolved by um at least the quality of
the the lighter camera that we are using
um there are likely higher resolution
ones that could be used
um also anything where
um you have what you're trying to
measure may be blocked by kind of lower
foliage or something that might because
the you know the liar is going to bounce
off of whatever it hits first so um if
you have something where you have lots
of leaves or something and you want to
maybe get Imaging of fruit that's up
higher um the Rover might not be the
best
application yeah
thank you so
much thank you very much um good
afternoon everybody my name is SE and
I'm a third year PhD student at the
small grains lab with Professor sell and
today I'm going to talk about organic
naked barley and creating Innovations
for resilience in the state of New York
um first of all about naked barley
itself
um as one could imagine it's uh a part
of naked in there means just that loss
of The Barley Hull itself during the
Harvest process which is something that
occurs naturally thanks to the loss of
function mutation in the new Gene 8,000
years ago uh and this Gene uh apparently
coats the lipid layer that would glue
together the hull and the
kopsis um and it's visible here as we
see in
the um quick laser out here um on the
left we see the covered barley and on
the right we see the naked barley or the
Hess barley and there are two big
benefits about that so one of them is
that um when we have covered parley we
are relatively limited with the use of
that as if we would like to use car
barley in the food products we would
need to uh go through the lots of
processing steps to remove the H as it's
uh in digestible and with that we could
also lose important the nutrition Parts
like the Bran or The Germ of the seed
but with the naked barley uh this is all
going to stay in the grain after our
Harvest and we're not going to lose any
of those micronutrients and this allows
um those multi-purpose uses for the nak
barley and making it more digestible and
all of this together kind of indicates L
of potential for organic and small
farmers as in health healthy and and an
easy process
alternative uh in their cropping system
and um this is where we come in with the
multi-use naked barley project for
organic systems that's a collaboration
between five universities uh Oregon
State UC Davis University of Minnesota
University of Wisconsin Madison and us
here at Cornell and we have a quite a
wide variet of goals we're trying to
achieve with that project um most of all
about educating the public about the
naked Pary itself and the health
benefits of that uh combined with
working together with stakeholders to
build those markets for this naked
parley products out there um while at
those different universities we test the
existing CH plasm and also generate new
genetic diversity um in the face of or
like as an example with our breeding
lines that we're trying to get out there
that would be locally adapted to all of
those environments that we would like to
see the naked barley be grow so for this
we have different kind of populations in
our hands to be used as uh we conduct
Regional trials across all of those
locations uh we have diversity panel to
look into the genetics um in a much more
fine level and we also do have the
breeding populations that we are
throwing across all of those locations
to be able to select for local
adaptation and talking about local
adaptation the most important trait
we're trying to implement here in our
breeding process in upsite New York is
PR sprouting
resistance which I'm going to tell more
in the next slide a little bit so Bri
sprouting is something that can be quite
devastating for barley Farmers as an
example um as a definition re sparting
is something that's um defined as a
germination unwanted germination of The
Barley grains in the spike right before
the Harvest and as a result causing
damages to the grain quality and the
starch and the enzyme profile which
could end up with a complete yield loss
and losses of pro profit for the farmers
and from the perspective of a breeder it
is relatively expensive and complicated
trate the screen as we see here this is
the scale we do screen this tra in our
breeding program but for this to happen
we need to sample the spikes dry them
out and then miss them three days in an
artificial missing array in our
Greenhouse to be able to score um the
level of germinated grains in a spike
from 0 to
nine but luckily for us we already know
that a lot about the genetics of PR
sprouting uh from the work previously
done in s's lab by several grad students
and I'm just going to bring some of
those examples out here first of all we
had a forra student Dan Sweeny uh being
able to map the genetic control of be
sprouting in covered background uh going
from the qil to the Gene and also up out
to Al
levels as we see here as an example that
bar lines having two dormant GS in this
qtl have an average we have sprouting
score of
three but the parly lines having two
non-dormant lines have an average
sparing score of
seven and some work from another student
Travis Rooney who was able to um prove
the large effect qtl
having an heterogenic heterogenic effect
in the whole background and also how
using those large effect qtl Al as fixed
effects in the prediction models improve
the accuracy so this has motivated us to
tap into the genetic diversity of the
same genes and alals in the nakure plasm
and here is where I could come with with
come in with my proposed ideas for a
experiment with the naked parleying
population throwing those same lines out
on the field in two locations having
them genotyped with a USDA snip chip and
you typing all of those lines in a
greenhouse to measure their reever
sprouting
resistance and that would allow us to
tap into the genetic diversity we have
in the naked barley uh ger plasm uh that
would also enable us to verify what we
already know in the C CH plasm like the
genes alic effects and how how often do
we find those alyss in these Gene pools
um and also just to like test out the
predictive abilities with the naked germ
plasm um and as an outcome of that
um we do gain um a nice insight to
verication in the naked barley
background and also broading the overall
understanding of what's Happening in
there and allowing the Breeders to use
them in the future for their Selections
in this as an example for all those
different breeders in the same program
and uh being able able to advance the
materials in our program much faster um
with a good predictive ability from the
model and also being able to combine
those uh local adaptation traits
together with those beneficial traits
already in the naked body to provide
good varieties for local producers here
in Upstate New York to grow them out and
here I would just like to thank all of
our collaborators working with this
project and um yeah any questions be
happy to take him thank you so I was
wondering for your populations with the
additional germ plasm and snit chip are
you hoping to find maybe more genes
associated with the resistance toing or
more so like news that might completely
uh deter um new genes it's not that
likely so the question was if I'm hoping
to find new genes or new oals in this
naked Bley Jean Pool that might not be
present in the covered barley gin pool
and my answer to that would be uh I
think it's relatively unlikely to find
new genes but the diversity of alals
already present in those covered barley
Qs is it's it's pretty wide I think for
both of those qals together we already
have six different alil segregating in
those
so some Al and alic variation is highly
likely to be there that I'm looking to
see yes question is pre- Harvest
sprouting uh correlated or related to uh
any other trait you might be interested
in cooking time mot toxin you know post
Harvest
accumulation uh macronutrient profile or
anything um it is um so the question was
if we have sprouting susceptibility or
resistance is related to other quality
traits and as far as I know we haven't
tested them here at the Cornell but we
do also have collaborators in Oregon
State who have a baking quality lab and
they have found some um signs of
deteriorated baking quality as an
example of like early on bri sprouting
that has deteriorated the quality of the
bread or the dough they make out of it
so yes I I think it's a pretty clear
relationship with that any other
correlations or like what I've seen a
field what I've seen on the field is
relatively hard to see like in terms of
like you know what you see in the canopy
or the spikes
themselves Recaps uh is naked barley
more susceptible to to insect
damage um not that I know of and we have
not seen that so naked bar is more
susceptible only to the smart disease
because the hull is I guess like more
loose and I guess some of those
particles of this Fung can access the
Grain in those early stages much better
but with other diseases we haven't seen
any uh difference with covered barley or
also yeah with
insects I guess is there a categorical
difference in terms of nutrient profiles
like how holess Sals are three four
percentage points higher in protein or
anything like categorically different
between naked and hon barley yeah so the
question was about categorical
differences in the profiles of naked
barley and card barley and one of those
big differences is the better glucan
which is actually something that is um
FDA has suggested for people to consume
more as it improves the digestion of
people so so this is one of those big
differences but at the same time it's
it's good to keep in mind why it's low
in a covered parley because better
glucan can inhibit some of those malting
processes and in the making of Milds so
it's even though we want to develop
those multiuse purpose varieties it is
this is kind of a hard path to choose
from like I think with this we you need
to develop separate varieties one for
multing and one for like you know really
high better clue gain that would we
could advertise them like this yeah yeah
my name is Aaliyah I'm a second year PhD
student um all of my research has to do
with dowy moldy resistance in grap
Vine um yeah so with over 45 different
Hypes that can confer Dy mly resistance
and grape Bine there is a lot of stuff
to phenotype how do I phenotype it all
with is there a laser on here yes with
the black bird robot so basically this
how the scheme works is we go out we
collect leave from germplasm um either
from the field or from the greenhouse we
use a cook borer hold punch them out to
create these arrays of leaf diss that's
also pictured here um these Leaf dis
arrays will get inoculated and then put
into the Blackbird and imaged over a
number of days to capture the disease
progression um these images are uploaded
to to a convolutional neural network
that will pick apart the images and give
us a nice quantitative data set about
the disease severity on the leaf
diss I can't talk about the Blackbird
without showing you the beautiful images
that come off of it so this is a grap
Bine Donny mildo which by default has to
be my favorite
pathogen um so my whole first chapter is
a metadata study on the Blackbird robots
we really wanted to investigate the
trade-off between this High uh data
acquisition with the data quality to
make sure that we're conserving our data
quality and we wanted to know if the
system was really robust to the types of
human error or data variation that could
happen in the scheme so basically what I
had done was I have three um real data
sets that have come off of the Blackbird
that have resulted in disease resistance
qtl Publications I've simulated a bunch
of variation onto those data sets and um
I basically observed how the
significance of the LOD score changed
with those added errors and
variation um and I did things like uh
Leaf disk swaps Leaf disk frame shifts
to kind of capture the types of human
errors that could happen in the arraying
process different variation and disease
severity to capture um the types of
micro environments that are happening in
the trays that might impact pathogen
growth and also replicate subsetting
because usually when we do these
experiments we have up to eight to 10
replicates per
experiment so what did I find this is an
example of an intermediate effect size
qtl and all of these colored boxes
represent present the different flavors
of variation that I introduced in the
previous slide blue has to do with
variation in pathogen growth the pink is
the leaf dis swaps the Orange is the
leaf dis frame shifts and then the
yellow is the um replicate sub setting
so basically you look at this and you
say wow the Blackbird is very robust to
the types of human errors that can
happen but it seems to fall apart when
we pick apart the replicate
number that's great um more of the story
we were able to figure out that we are
not compromising any data quality by our
large volumes of data
acquisition um this is supposed to be a
lightning talk so I understand that this
is a great overview of my chapter but
happy to report it's been accepted to a
focus issue of phytopathology literally
this morning updated the um like First
Look copy so I'll make sure it gets in
the newsletter very excited and happy
about
this um so yeah what's the catch we've
all been slided by technology okay
there's veteran academics probably on
the zoom rolling their eyes at me like
I'm praising this robot and for what
there's got to be something um and I'd
like to introduce the bane of my
dissertation Leaf
hairs um so the Blackbird is based off
of RGB Imaging so all of the visual
wavelengths that we can see so if there
is morphology that is obscuring the
phenotype that you're trying to measure
in our case Leaf hair is covering up the
spanga of the Denny mildo the robot
can't see
it so how I plan to circumvent our Leaf
hair issue is with a hyperspectral
blackbird uh this robot is called the
hyperb bird um it's a lot less pretty
and a lot less user friendly than the
Blackbird because it's a prototype um
but I'm hoping to use hyperspectral
Imaging to kind of peer through the leaf
airs LOL I wish it was that easy we saw
from aon's talk that hyperspectral
Imaging is really complicated so what
does this actually mean uh well I'm
hoping that the bioch the biochemistry
makeup biochemical makeup oh my god of
the host versus the pathogen is like
distinct enough to where they have
different hyperspectral signatures that
will allow me to differentiate them on a
microscopic
scale and it's a non-destructive method
which is really helpful to me um
especially when you're um phenotyping
things like disease resistance
um yeah my hopes and dreams for the
hyperb bird uh number one we have to
ensure that the hyperb bird works again
this robot is a prototype um so we've
never actually published anything with
it and I hope to do that with the actual
Le hair themselves so hopefully they'll
have a use um and we have a
convolutional neural network on the
Blackbird that can also measure Leaf
hair so I'll probably um compare it to
that probably Leaf hair will be
conserved across Vitus considering a lot
of different Vitus species have the same
Leaf hair morphology and then after we
prove that the hyper bird can work in
this uh like phenotyping scheme then I
can do the thing that I actually want to
do which is discover new disease
resistance qtl on hairy
Vines um and then maybe I'll even take a
a step further for this last bullet
point
um make some inferences in the
relationship between Leaf her and
resistance this is supposed to be a
lightning talk um these three question
marks symbolize the 10-minute rant I
could go on about like this concept of
like Leaf hair and resistance and does
it confer resistance and does it not and
is a barrier and blah blah blah blah
blah anyway I'll save you the rambling
the important things are there is
conflicting literature and I'm very
skeptical of some of the phenotyping
methods that these papers have and we
might be able to solve some labrusca
Mysteries as well well all of these
hairy Leaf discs that I've shown you
they're labrusca um conquered grapes are
a labrusca variety and basically these
grapes have been resistant to Donnie
mildo for over 200 years and no one
knows why is it because of the leaf
hairs is it because of an unknown qtl we
don't know maybe I'll find
out and with that I would like to
acknowledge my whole committee and their
Labs especially Katie Gold and her lab
and all the engineers that contribute to
all these
robotics um I'm housed at the agch C
campus in Geneva um Sira subota he's
been really integrated into all of my
dis projects antis gen 3 not only for
funding me but for also just being an
amazing research group that is very
collaborative and supportive of each
other and with that I will take any
questions you might have yes so uh you
talked about one of your greatest
frustrations that you've been
experiencing with the leaf hairs I was
just wondering if there's like a great
Joy or something exciting that had in
the research okay I've complained a lot
and now Sam wants to know something that
makes me excited um I don't okay Leaf
hairs aren't all bad okay they um you
can kind of see in my one picture here
they they have great
diversity um they make the grapes really
fluffy and cute
um I don't know I I I really like all of
the research that I do and I me and
Lance had a conversation a while ago and
he was like oh like what's your favorite
chapter like what's your favorite
project and I feel like I have all of my
projects are very diverse and different
and I feel like I like them all for
different things uh most notably most
notably my metadata study uh is my
favorite right now because it's done
so hopefully that answers your question
I I find joy in diverse
things yes Ed it's kind of uh you know
when you have leaves that aren't hairy
uh is the infection can you see it from
either side of the leaf fairly equally
well or not so that yeah so Ed is asking
about the phenotypic expression of the
disease on the leaf dis and if we can
see it on both sides so that depends on
the pathogen so my pathogen Downey
mildew only uh sporulates from the
bottom of the leaf so on the top of the
leaf in the field you'll see some like
oil spotting or lesions but they're they
won't spoil from the top so on the
Blackbird we always phenotype from the
bottom and we always count severity as
the little fluffy spria that pop out in
terms of powdery mildew powdery mildew
only like spoiles on the top of the leaf
so when we do those in the black bird
scheme we put them right side up to
observe disease from the top so again
dependent on the disease that you're
looking at because I was wondering if
there's some way you could play with
light it's transmission and flipping the
leaf training a model so you train on
one side and the reverse side and then
with transmission if you could somehow
pick it up because you know I agree the
refraction off those leaves May
off the tri may be tricky right Ed is
offering that I instead of looking
through the leaf hairs if I flip the
disc over and observe some type of
phenotype from the top I mean we could
we haven't
tried um especially for the black bird
scheme they're sitting on agar so if you
were to put dyu upside down I don't even
know if that would like kill the OM
because you're you're cutting it off
from the outside you're not letting it
breathe in the field sure in the field
sure I could see like you see symptoms
on both sides of the leaves but um I'm
not sure on the Blackbird system whether
that would be
feasible yes you see the January paper
on on it was out Julius where they
did a reset for like RGB Imaging of leaf
hairs and if so what are your what are
your thoughts is that one the one out of
jki yeah yeah
I've I have I have
different um I have read that one I do
like that one um I'm sure that's great
we have a
different we have a different um CNN
that was made by someone else that um
like I have and know works so I'm going
to train against that but I'm sure that
one's great and fine I love Oliver trap
and the people that work at jki so again
sure that's
great this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu