this is a production of Cornell
University thank you very much Adam for
the kind introduction and uh um I have
never been
Etha and it's a place that every plant
scientist want to be and want to visit
right at least so dream come true so
here why there's two screen oh okay all
right okay uh tell you maybe you haven't
heard there's um this is being remotely
okay and video so um remote screen okay
all right okay so today I'm going to
talk about three uh aspect of uh my
research here and one is the center for
PL transformation at Iowa State
University which is basically service
center and then my research aspect in
the agrobacteria and as well as uh nanop
particle um delivery uh non DNA molecule
delivery in plant so um a lot of stuff
there and then there's a few slides I
maybe rush through and I apolog
apologize for that if uh you get
confused of uh stuff so first of all
talking about the plant transformation
facility at Iowa State University which
was established 20 years ago um 1995 I
um left my indust indry job where um I
used to be colleague with Jos Rose so um
and from ICI gust and mve to Iowa State
University take a position to run a PL
transformation facility um that time the
facility was uh basically was supported
by endowment uh Grant from Agronomy uh
and then the commodity Group which
heavily behind that and then also from
administrative uh um unit of uh uh cows
and plant biotechnology it's very
similar situation like today that we're
been talking
about so currently um we have five
permanent staff and I cannot four times
staff here
um we have Coe transformation specialist
soring transformation specialist rice
transformation specialist and they all
one person start from a the very
beginning to to the end of the entire
pipeline um they do not have hourly
students they work everything Al just
simple one person project then we have a
lab manager who does some molecular
biology work and then we have a
greenhouse dedicated Greenhouse manager
who do nothing but taking care of a core
and sing and rice count so this together
with myself we um run the the um the the
co and sving transformation we have only
three crop focused a very focused
project on that
um our transformation facility is under
a plant Science Institute which is a
umbrella Institute uh covers the
following centers uh genomics
bioinformatics um plant transformation
breeding and and the other few two uh
centers so we operate somewhat auton
autonomous but same time we get support
from PL Science
Institute and then we also Under the
Umbrella of the office of biotechnology
which runs all the infrastructure and
the centralizing um uh the facility
genomic informatics Frost hometry
hyoma um microscope Nano image and all
these things are very similar to here so
there's a we are the one of the 12 core
facility so this two unit support uh
collectively one fulltime um one
FTE here so over the past 20 years um we
have served 35 internal crop group and
basically cor soing R uh um uh faculty
researchers and then we have 161
external groups from 121 institution
institution from 16 countries so
basically everybody who does corn and
sorbing not rice rice a lot of people
can do themselves corn and sorbing come
to our facility majority at least 70 to
80% of the research in the field does
that from a uh receive service from us
so here is a summary of the growth all
our capacity to the other uh on the
other hand uh of over the year of our
growth and as you can see at the
beginning we creeping through all the
numbers and we didn't know we didn't
know anybody and then nobody knows us
and then after all these years and then
we are reaching really our capacity for
three staff member of course we can add
more people if they um but the cost we
want to keep down is we keep really
quality staff our staff are really very
experienced they are PhD level of uh um
uh scientist and then so they provide
service they at same time they always
tweaking the conditions always comparing
different um uh parameters so for here
the home transformation just shows how
uh the plant in our Greenhouse look like
and I really admire um connell's
Greenhouse crew uh this afternoon I to
the greenhouse I
just I can't say enough of good things
about it's just so clean and so well
organized and then you have those
incubator was 60
70 uh uh 1970s vintage and they well
well kept which means that this well
it's a very energy costing unit but they
are so well maintain uh you know lot of
unit lot of U institution you will see
instrument cannot keep more than 5 years
because nobody take care of them they
just get you know rotten and then be
abused by the student and all the things
but here it's a really amazing
infrastructure for the growth and uh
really
great so we do two type of uh M
transformation and then High 2 and then
b14 High two is a lab line and then
which is not very good for um agronomic
purpose but it's uh good enough for
study some basic things and then
transformation is easy that's why uh k 2
has been a working horse in our lab and
then but later on we were able to get
B104 transformation then b14 is a quite
good inbr and it's a a major uh inbr um
based on b73 so a lot of genomics can be
done with this um b14 however the
transformation frequency for these two
crops varies a lot uh which hand the
cause the difference in in the price as
well so when sometime uh The Faculty
like to use b14 for transformation but
the pricewise they couldn't afford and
that's one of the another things when
you are working with very concentr crop
and sometime and you have to face the
price issue for soing transformation and
the half seat method was actually
invented during the time when I uh after
the um uh arrived Iowa State University
and serving transformation patent has
been um uh established long time in the
late 80s but you know still very very
low frequency and very difficult to
transfer technique to the other person
um you have to be really well vered with
cell biology in order to run it so um my
effort uh this invention particularly is
skill transfer friendly means that you
know some of those basic uh knowledge uh
if the high school student was able to
uh understand the protocol and do
exactly what was demonstrated they are
able to achieve transic sorbing so the
skill um is not really quite uh the
important for the people to have so
that's very important if you want to
have your technology um expanded and
then be Ben benefiting uh more than only
just one your lab and so Sor
transformation we uh have this protocol
and the
um it's working very well but it's a
very toour capacity so then finally it's
a rise transformation which we uh
basically do
the Japonica rice transformation both
the bombe and then kataki using the
pretty standard and public uh protocol
and works very well but I think the rice
is not as difficult compared to recant
CH and sorbing here and most people can
actually establish for themselves so
what is a key limitation with our
facility after 10 20 years of working on
uh this service facility and I would say
first of all is the lack of our
Greenhouse space so basically we have
only 3,000 square ft and probably the
really the grow space is less than that
the 3,000 square ft in this case is war
to war space um according to um uh the
NY and for the greenhouse and Analysis
these are much less um we have to grow
corn year round in order to provide the
starting material which is immature
embryo and then we have to grow sorbing
to the maturity in order to get the
seeds for the delivery so we used to
grow transgenic corn to to seeds for the
customer now we cannot afford anymore
and because there's no space simply and
we just have to B all our uh colleagues
um to take the greenhouse to to take the
uh transic plantlet and grow in your own
Greenhouse this is very difficult for
oversea business and for Germany for
Austria for Belgium we can do that we
successfully sending all these
transgenic plantlet across
uh Atlanta no problem but when we want
to send to Mexico even on the same
continent we we we Face very very
challenging customer issue that's really
just basically we cannot um overcome
things we cannot control
over so
uh and then another major issue is
recruit and retain high quality staff um
I have three staff which would has been
with me for 20 years and 10 20 years um
we have lot of young stuff going through
and then two or three years later they
are gone for variety of Reason um and
lot of Industry does try to uh recruit
our staff because we do provide very
good Training and at the same time and
because there's no such a training from
master degree or whatever undergraduate
cell biology anymore so we are seldom
can find anybody who is able to jump
into the transformation and then um take
Taking project and go so that's why our
um staff has been steady but same time
we become worried because we are getting
old we we don't get any younger we need
to have a Next Generation who is able to
do the same job or even better than us
uh so those are the issue we are all
facing every facility um public
institution facing that same as um
Pioneer so I think we need to build a
robot so um I I'm not joking when I'm
saying this because the camera Imaging
system and computer system can allow us
to identify the type of a characteristic
allow us to pick those type of all the
thing recognize and uh pick them why not
so the next thing if you want to think
about reducing transformation cost we
have to invest into working with
mechanical engineering computer
scientists
um and in cell biology and then to build
up a a robot that will do the job
otherwise you will always cry and 20
years ago I think this I thought this
would be solved by now 20 years later
I'm still facing this issue so okay
instead of a um yeah crying over we
probably thinking creatively uh using
the new technology let's build something
we can do um transformation fast because
sequencing think about sequencing 20
years or 30 years ago we had to sequence
ourself manually this revolutionized our
sequencing capacity I never imagined
this could happen but um that's a real
now so because of
limited um staff and limited
infrastructure and restrict our ability
to to research to improve transformation
frequency and then at beginning of our
establishment facility I was able to
actually working to improve efficiency
but then when we become a popular we are
so overwhelmed by all these orders we
have no time and we have no material
even to use research so that's that's
major issues every facility they want to
start their um uh service they have to
include the research component in into
that so that's how much about uh
transformation service part and I can
afford to talk about it I'm sure we are
going to talk about a bit more in detail
and but I want to uh come to the second
aspect of my research on the uh
non-coding iring AG bacterial so I grow
up with agrobacteria that's my graduate
study and I was through into
agrobacteria world and but after my PhD
post I totally sick and tired of Agra
bacteria I don't want to have anything
to do with it I just want to use that to
transform plant so because also
partially I thought AG bacteria
everybody's know every bits of
agrobacteria anymore there's nothing
left for us to study so so um but back
now 6 10 years ago six uh seven years
ago I had a very weird conversation with
Stan gaving and uh we we have worked on
the NSF project and then and I have
conversation with Lis herela um who was
uh uh my my peer um colleague in
graduate student time about agrobacteria
we were asking how much do we really
know about agrobacteria and do we really
know every Gene of AR bacteria if people
try to know uh knock out every single
Gene of arabidopsis I don't know if
anybody has knocked out every single
Gene of uh agrobacteria in order to know
uh the uh the function of the Gene and
then to see if we can use this organism
and for any more uh transformation
frequency Improvement so that's why we
started a a a random project was let's
just sequencing the transcripton of that
because everybody was sequencing
something so
okay seriously and plus I have a good
friend in alumina what do you know right
you got to have friends in important
place and then they say well just threw
me in with this I just run it for you
and wow that's that's why okay you know
with no support and then that's your
friend who who who were help you to
float right so see this aluminous
colleagues uh name on that we uh
designed experiment together and at that
time even alumina never have dealed with
uh bacteria uh transcripton so it's very
exciting for them to so we published a
one uh we just use their very new
technology that time and then managed to
identify a lot of uh uh so we had total
of
840 uh 8 40 8 billion million reads so
it's a very high throughput compared to
4554 that time 4554 still is a important
Workhorse so my friend there saying that
okay look we can generate a lot more
reads for you right so yeah so we got a
lot of those uh data and we uh use our
we work with our uh bio um informatics
uh
professor and colleague on campus and to
was able to uniquely map U uh to take
the uniquely mapped um
transcripton so the first thing that we
try to evaluate is that okay we check
our ve opon Vance Vance opon is one of a
group of Gene which is very important
for agac imediate transformation DNA
transformation because they they were
only
activate during the time they interact
with plant so asinger is a plant signal
molecule which induce this agrobacteria
Gene come out so when you see these red
Peaks those are the V Gene which induced
by agrobacteria by the plant signal
molecule as on sering and blue are the
no inducers so when you look at all
these um uh transcripton they say well
yeah hey that's really what we have
known for all these years these are very
highly induced and some of them are not
and then to our surprise that we find
there's a bunch of six
antisense which sometimes non induced
sometimes induced and then that you know
immediately was very interesting for us
because the CIS antisense um on The View
on this inducible important Gene what
are they
right
so then we characterize most of those um
identified noncoding RNA they are range
from um 0 to 521 nuclear tide and
average lens 88 88 nucleotide and a
medial lens 61 that's their
characteristic and then 88% of the small
RNA are on two chromosome which is not
surprising um in agerial they have a big
circular chromosome and linear
chromosome and then two plasmid and then
TI plasmid is the one is most important
to us for the plant transformation
because the tdna the the the transfer
DNA is on this plasmid and V is on this
plasmid
so then
87% of antisense RNA are on the two
plasmid and 18 are on the complemental
strand of a b d e f k so those are the
characteristic which we found is quite
interesting so then first thing we next
thing we were asking is that okay CIS
anti sense um easily you could think CIS
anti sense probably are regulating the
the the strength upset to theirs right
so do they have really Target in TRS or
what so then we did this analysis on
trans Crypton we found out they actually
do not corate so the expression of the
op strand opposite strand of uh the the
the gene uh the transcript transcripts
they are not corated with that
particular expression of the antient I
mean the uh the the small RNA so what
they are doing um so one of my student
and Abby Johnson and decide to focus on
that uh the small RNA opposite to v c
and uh C1 and C2 gene on the ti plasmid
so if you look at this uh V opon and you
will notice most of V genes on the
opposite strand on the top string and C1
and C2 are the two Gene which only these
two on the opposite string so itself is
already weird and this C1 C2 has a very
strong expression of antisense in this
case so what is C what is the VC opon do
we know anything about this yes we
there's a bunch of a study have done uh
a while ago um
so I never paid attention to vsc1 and C2
because I think from literature people
always think that yeah it's doesn't
really abolishing the the pathogenesis
or veilance it's rather just
attenuates I don't know do you agree on
that so all this um publication just say
yeah it's lead to reduce so during my
time and if anything is not black and
white I was not interested in it has to
be black and white and that's easy right
you can publish science nature black and
white and if it's in between uh you
don't go very far so but a lot of things
is in between right you know so it
and then uh you look at the
VC um transcript you will see you will
see that transcript we see one
transcript is highly induced by ason
syon you can see the red peak come out
but vc2 seem to be not very enthusiastic
after induction at least in the
condition we have been testing over over
time vc2 is always very low Peak yeah so
then you look at the antv
C2 and then you see that region the
opposite strand you see the lot of
expression this ant C2 is predominantly
exactly opposite of C2 and then there's
not much of anc1 so there is this
transcripton wi of a you know coloration
and so that's a pattern we have we are
seeing okay so the hypo this is okay vc2
anti sense is maybe regulating vsc2
sense and maybe that contribute to the
low frequency or low
expression so then we did some coration
analysis expression analysis so we found
out the vc2 and anti vsc2 is actually
corated very well when you have a more
vc2 you have a more anti
C2 this look at this coration it's very
well
corated and doesn't look like the
expression of ant vsc2
downregulates vc2 in this case it's like
the more of this and more of that it's
like more of a stabilizer rather than
you know destabilizer I don't know so
that's a thing we are still addressing
okay so then Abby did some knockout
because study anti sense Smalling is
very difficult because if you you canot
delete them you delete them you delete
the the gene opposite right so you can't
really delete Gene you cannot knock out
using conventional way so Abby tried to
look at the uh the Upstream of this anti
vsc2 they he she found that there's a uh
putative promoter region of this so she
then mess up a little bit of the
promoter region delete that part so just
delete a little bit of this error and
and see what happened so after deletion
and then she found her anti vc2
transcript
reduce her V C2 transcript reduce as
well so the coration still goes you know
when you reduce V C2 anti sense you
reduce
C2 so it seemed to be there is this
still you know um positive coration
instead of a
negative down regulates that there's
something VC anti VC to the function I
don't I still don't know what is that
right so the possible uh explanation is
anti sense vc2 is binded to the sense
transcript and stabilize and stabilize
it post
transcriptionally and and then could be
the regulation of the C2 is is uh during
the transcription so some of those
things are still not very clear so then
another things we want to do is say okay
after you mess around this antv C2
region do you in do you get this
verance um level down or do you have any
impact on Vance so that's the first
thing usually agrobacteria people always
do that when you mess around with a
strand you first want to see okay this
did you make any impact on the Vance so
then uh in this case we use this uh kqu
uh model plant or or a typical uh acid
system that we use for agac verance acid
so Abby inoculate two strand one is her
deletion mutation one is a wi type on
this kqu leaf and then you know after
two weeks and she ask it for the tumors
and then she sees this you know
um
reduced reduce a phenotype of her
strength and the wild type has a lot of
tumor the
the this mutant strin does not so it's
very nice but when you look at the mall
you see it's all over the place and this
the best representative if you just
publish that you say oh my God it's
great but we know better now after 30
years and we know these things we cannot
just say oh here yeah this is what we
expect and we do see a lot of difference
and so that's where uh the complication
is okay do we really see true
attenuation or it's just random plant
response to the viance right so well
because we don't have anything better
than just do a lot and so we start to do
a lot and the same same time we just
Define the uh Vance uh by Zero no
response at all then a little bit of
response to number one and then two and
three so those are the things where the
typically we just qualitatively
characterize so then after that then we
again then uh count how many of number
one 2 3 4 and then and then then you
measure those uh and then you you you
you see how many of those are actually
from uh
scored zero and how many score one and
how many score three so looks like here
the wi type and score zero you have less
of Y type you have more of a mutant
strength scored um zero and then you
have a more of wire type score number
three so this is still very
qualitative and then she did uh a
statistic analysis on this uh man
Whitney rank summer test using this for
that and then
um so she has hypothesis is a mean ranks
of two samples are same or the
alternative hypothesis is a mean rank
the two samples are different so
according to her analysis here is uh the
hypothesis alternative hypothesis is
probably true here so you know it's
again to us it's I do not really I when
I read this data say oh yeah you know
there's probably difference but you know
do they do this really tell us anything
so but most important things we want to
study is what really that anti C2 is
toing doing C uh uh has effect on C2 or
any other uh genes so that the
subsequent uh the experiment we are
doing right now is do this uh RNA stab
stabilization stability analysis and
then also use a more of the quantitative
analysis see whether they there is any
uh U Vance an uh differences in in these
two different strand or different others
uh and small RNA so we have other small
RNA also in the works a lot of them
actually affecting the Corum
sensing and the conjugation and the
sensitivity towards pH as well as
temperature and those things so as most
of a non-coding RNA n funding there are
are a fine tuning of the their respond
to the environment and I think that
makes sense uh some of those bacteria
Fitness uh affected by the um the small
or the small the regulating the bacteria
Fitness in this case so um now to the
third aspect of my talk is about uh
using the nanot technology for uh the
non d DNA molecule delivery in this case
and this is collaboration between my lab
and with uh group in chemist Department
uh in Iowa State University and that was
led by Victor Ling that time and then he
unfortunately passed away five years ago
uh in the middle of our collaborate
collaboration and it was continued by
two of his students um uh bran twin
right now is a faculty in uh Colorado
School of mind and and and continue the
uh the nanoparticle research in this
case so and that biological aspect
experiment was done by my um post Fran
Tony and then Susanna uh Martin oosa so
basically at that time and Dr Ling have
synthesized a material called mesopor
cycal nanoparticle which has a very
interesting structure uh it's a highly
regulated material and it does not F in
the nature and uh it's very stable and
most important is that inside there's a
very large tal pore space allow you to
um incorporate or upload payload protein
or molecules that you want to carry
using this uh particular uh particle so
um and then this has also very
interesting um surface structure you can
really uh function surface functionalize
with a different molecule in order for
it's for the different application
purpose and of course all these part I'm
not able to go detail with that uh
that's all very chemical for me uh
so one other aspect of this uh silicon
nanop particle is that uh you can feel
that with a small molecule by simple
diffusion um then you can coal attach
the whole Poe uh in this case that uh
this molecule we put on the to to stop
this leaky from a pole are the gold
small particle which calent link to the
surface of the uh of the um uh the nanop
particle and then upon change of pH or
the induction of the um uh chemical in
the uh the meteor then you can open up
the uh pour and then have the chem
molecule released from inside so that is
this type of feature that I was
interested in to use for the delivery
for the plant molecule that I do not
want to have them uh immediately
released that time so back 2005 we
started this uh project and then uh in
2007 we succeeded to introduce um a
DNA introduce produc a DNA which coated
outside of the nanop particle but inside
of the pole of a mesoporus nanop
particle we loaded with inducible
chemical molecule so when we shoot these
two substance on same um nanop particle
into plant and we will be able we
actually add reagent in the meteor and
had the poe open release the molecule
inside of a mesoporus nanop particle and
then get a gene
expression uh for from the DNA that we
introduced so it was really the first
case that we able to demonstrate that
there's other way of there was more than
one way of introduce DNA or non- DNA uh
molecule into plant and then make them
do the things that we want them to do so
uh this will give us a lot of
Versatility uh in uh lot of delivery so
what the MSN over the current
transformation system can do is that it
can deliver more than one biogenic
species at a time in our first uh um
paper we demonstrate that we can deliver
a gene and infector and infector that
time was a chemical uh uh chemical small
chemical molecule so then you have a you
can deliver Gene and enzyme you can
deliver RNA and protein you can deliver
multiple substance in this case and the
advantage of use specific molecule for
in this case is um these molecule are
encapsulated and you can conture release
that's very important sometime you don't
want them to release all the time at all
the stage and then uh uh the other thing
advantage of using this particular MSN
is a Surface can be functionalized or
targeted desire the cell or
tissue so and after this project uh um
published immediately really literally
same day we get a phone call from pimer
saying well can you deliver something
else than DNA I think sure why not um so
then they start to collaborate with us
um they we said well no we need to
deliver a protein or recombinat in this
case crisper was not that time even
Talon wasn't even in the uh in in the
research area as hot as today yet so
their idea is again actually um joural
editing was not new at all back long
time ago that people has been always
trying to find the way that we can
specifically Target um a specific error
uh to make changes so the protein
delivery in general add in time has some
advantage over over uh the DNA delivery
it's a DNA free technology no need to
create
expression expressing line no need to
segregate progeny and transing activity
could reduce toxicity and of Target
mutations and some cases I think it does
save time in an analysis so the Kong the
disadvantage of that is you need to have
a protein purified in this case purify
DNA is lot easy to purify protein and to
get a lot of uh pure protein available
and to assess the protein activity is
not always easy and you can have protein
quantity there but you don't know if the
protein has enzymatic activity that you
want and then uh the efficiency
comparing to DNA expression is in our
case low and again the last thing the
most important is that after protein
delivery how do you select those uh
actually Ed uh so those are the issues
and for protein delivery but you know
here is illustrate what's U what we are
uh currently using our DNA delivery
system you have a plasmid which carries
nucleus in this case and you do the
regular genetic transformation and after
that you will have the enzyme and you
have this enzyme work in the plant and
then made the plant Chang into to the
desired place you want but that plant
still Carri enzyme which you don't want
so to get rid of those enzyme and
typically what we do we will do the self
cross all the uh cross-pollination self
pollination or cross pollination so then
you have a segregation for the next
generation and then you will find out
the uh the plant you use a PC and other
uh method to identify those plant which
has are addied genome but do not carry
the undesired nucleus Gene anymore so
that is what currently we are doing
we're still doing
that so it's not too bad but can be done
so the ideal situation is that if we are
able to just directly introduce the
nucleus using MSN or use some other uh
delivery method and into the comp plant
and once step you should get the addited
plant but without your nucleus because
protein will not last there so that is
ideal situation if we want to uh get
that so okay um starting
200 uh 2008 2009 we start to say okay
can we deliver protein uh we never tried
protein honestly until that time so we
purchased some egy gfp and and put them
together with um the nanop particle and
then we also try to code the
nanoparticle with a DNA expressed arop M
Cherry in this case so we are looking
for the cell in this case onion cell
which express both red and um the uh red
and then have a green color uh green is
simply the presence of the uh Gip
release from the nanoparticle red has to
be the DNA which carried through
nanoparticle but Express in this case so
we were able to do that immediately
after that we will say okay why don't we
just start to try this recombinat so
pineer provide us with a cray protein
actually you can buy it commercially
cray protein and then you load them onto
nanop particle in this case I want to
have to emphasize that part of the thing
I did not
um talk about it is optimization of
nanop particle bombardment nanoparticles
made by silica it's impossible to
bombard silica and that's just uh too
light to be manipulated so uh our
chemist group and managed to go plated
the silica with several layers of a gold
particle and then this is a silica
before gold um uh PL plating and this is
after six times of gold plating the um e
uh temm and sem and uh scanning
microscope shows that so no this is the
same thing but this temm scanning this
semm scanning so so the idea is to have
this go plated and then load it with a
protein cray protein and the same time
Pioneer provide us with a transgenic
maze line that transgenic maze line
carry this single Gene insertion this
single Gene insertion looks like this a
promoter drives a g Gene which is
a glyphosate resistant this is
selectable marker and you have a
promoter Drive the uh sign uh cfp blue
protein and uh you have a piece of red
frosen protein and then in between you
have a lock p locks P here so in theory
if the cray protein is working that two
locks P will recombine and then this
promoter will start to drive
the the DS Gene right so if a pal
artment if the cray protein is delivered
into this transgenic blue transgenic
cone we should see some sector of the
Red Cell because this is because of a
cray protein is working and then make
the locks P Rec combine and then delete
the middle part of the segment the blue
Gan blue jeans deleted and red jeans
hooked up with promoter and
express so this is what we actually
found that we were able to see trans the
red and then stable red core callous and
then you have this segregating um uh red
callus uh the con
look the half of them are the blue and
half of them
red cism and then you have also this uh
tassel this is the original transic core
you can see it's blue it shines in the
blue Channel but not in the red Channel
this is the after we combined the blue
color is gone and the Red Express there
so to do with the remote
oh
exciting recat working
that's so Grand Finale
that then we take all this recom uh
recombination uh combine lines and then
make the sequencing and then they have
they really had a beautiful precise exis
every single line of them sorry about
that um so um so these the original uh
the the the sequence and uh after
the lock p recom uh recombined fuse
together and then these are the um
protein bombarded line these are the
plasmic bombarded line because we also
introduce DNA as our control where DNA
introduced the line and then protein
troduced line they result the same and
so that was quite fun things to do and
then we show that we can deliver protein
and recombinat and then make it working
in the plant and exactly the place is
supposed to work so that was uh one
illustration all the demonstration of
the protein ch be delivered uh for
future nucleus aided genome editing um
so very final five five minutes about
okay Ms delivery and it's great and it
but it this disadvantage so what's the
problem here you have Advantage is that
control Rel and the major advantage that
we use this particular type of Nano
particle is a poor size
limitation so after we deliver qu
protein everybody is happy and same time
everybody start to say oh it's too small
the size because the pole size is only
10 nanometer that's the height so we can
push with the current formula and so if
we are going to uh deliver Talon or the
crisper all of them are much higher than
the pole allow us to upload and also
this encapsulate the protein release
maybe too slow for us what we want so at
the same time say will say okay well you
know nanop is great and can we think
about something else um well here is
something else as we we coined it we
call it called
prolistic so it's a
bombarded method for intell delivery of
protein only so um in this case we just
simply modify our current DNA delivery
system by lopiz the protein or air dry
the protein onto the carrier and then
bomat so um depends on protein we use
and we are able to introduce variety of
the protein in this case we have a GP
introduced and we have to we also use a
try labeled BSA which is a rather large
uh um protein the reason we use those
things is because they are cheap they
are color colorful and then cheap and
then BSA or GP is way too expensive and
then we also bombard the Gus enzyme um
that allow us to uh also be able to show
that actually can turn the blue when you
put the substrate there and then we also
uh bombard some of enzyme uh such as the
trene and rnes because once you bombard
those uh destructive uh uh enzyme you
should see the cell death in this case
so looks like we can bombard variety of
DNA just by the protein just by through
them in and that's one of the thing uh
we have been doing uh using the protein
delivery and um we also bombard the um
animal uh tissue in this case try to
broaden our patent claim right just
demonstrate that we can do it more than
um plant cell uh these protol listic can
be used to co- delivery DNA and protein
same
time um it's a very simple procedure and
you use a current existing Gene gun and
quite reproducible in our hand very
simple um no restriction on the protein
type and can deliver protein and enzyme
uh with a different molecular weight and
ISO uh electri Point all the tertial
structure the major part this advantage
to us is probably you cannot control
release you bombard that's it
so um with that I will thank um my
colleagues in the um PL transformation
facility and we also have a group people
who work on small artive noncoding RNA
then the nanoparticle work was a
collaboration with uh chemistry
Department as well as Pioneer and our
current founding for this particular
project that come from internal andn
Pioneer collaboration project thank you
very
[Applause]
much so that gen is very close and
converion with your G so possibly the
your G transer Serv reading through well
we thought about that we actually looked
into that it's not it's not the re
through actually there's a quite U uh
significant and quite uh clear stop
after V yeah we thought about that it's
a
true yeah we didn't test this little uh
cutive promoter area it's very very nice
promoter area but we don't know if it's
a to restart we haven't test this area
to promote enough it's a potential
promoting area that we have
so the other
Plasma's a massive
El oh yeah yeah exactly so right now we
try to
decouple so we have a promoter Drive the
top path and then we have a promoter
Drive bottom
path and hopefully that will help us
understand because we cannot believe
that we we have to overexpress and so we
decouple them by Drive top strand bottom
strands whether there is any coration
right so that's have you achieved
nuclear localization of one of these uh
PR realistically delivered proteins we
never tried to test with a nuclear local
we didn't put a nuclear localization
signal oh you are talking about uh the
protein yeah yeah I mean it looks to me
like they they get in and they diffuse
throughout the cell so I think they go
into the nucleus just fine
but that's good question we never would
actually look into where they are focus
into or get into the nucleus
localization
not so you expect the protein go into
nucleus I'm just wondering you're trying
to deliver cast n it's got to get to the
nucleus right and and whether that would
go in by chance just by being bombarded
all the way through the nuclear membrane
or you probably could just uh um have a
CL n have a nuclear localization signal
s soci together with that right so if
they have that for sure they will go
they will go in put the V of whatever
that V protein that we have a nucle
organization the V2
promoter will guide
you higher
efficiency thank you very
much this has been in a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu