this is a production of Cornell
University
just to kind of frame this I think that
we started with the recognition that we
had some shared needs and we definitely
had some needs for new resources here at
the county level that realized that
maybe some of those resources would
serve on a statewide level so as we
developed our pollinator garden I
reached out to Sarah and said hey we
have some grant funding can we
collaborate on
on curated or you know interpretive
signage for these pollinator gardens
because I don't know if you all are kind
of like us and that a lot of what we do
is what we can print on our printers and
what we can laminate on our laminators
and that's as big as as it gets and as
designed as it get so so those kind of
those kind of signs are not I think
they're great but they're not they don't
say hey this is a this is a garden this
is a learning space come on in and they
flap in the wind and they float away so
recognizing that we had some parallel
needs and we could develop these shared
resources I pulled a whole bunch of
people across the state and said hey
who's doing a pollinator garden this
year in terms of your extension duties
and a number were and would you like
signage so based on that we launched
into this collaborative process
which like many other things sort of
took longer than we expected because
life happens and then fairs happen and
then people go you know we're on
vacations and it took a couple of months
but we came up with some really
beautiful things and in doing that also
ended up developing a shared photo
library for other Extension educators to
use as well so out of it came this
wonderful set of products that I'm
really excited to be able to share with
people but as along with that are the
parallel photos that people could be
using and the parallel educators
resources that go along with it so
hopefully it's something that you can
just pick up for your program and take
what parts you need and it makes your
life easier so how this was at a good
reduction Sarah yes what fun okay
so we are storing a lot of stuff in box
so so Sarah if you want you could I'll
I'll be your clicker and you talk and
I'll click on what you'd like me to show
how's that okay so essentially what
you're about to look at is that like Jen
just mentioned she pulled lots of people
around the county to say you know what
kind of concepts you want to communicate
in in your gardens and from that
created draft of text that then I took
and and looked at and said I made some
suggestions as to how to organize it and
what we did is we came up with four
different signs with four different
concepts and in my mind the do you mind
clicking on the pollinator paradise one
first Jen sure
you know this is these four signs are
kind of like a menu of you could use all
of them you could use one or you can
select the ones that are most
appropriate for what you're displaying
in your garden but to me the pollinator
paradise is kind of the intro type of
sign that that kind of gives the why
behind you know it's at what it what is
the significance of making your home
landscape
pollinator friendly and so what you're
what you're seeing right now is the
graphic layout for that particular sign
and it has like a fun title that Jen
came up with and then it says you know
explore this garden to learn how you can
create pollinator habitat at home so
that's our main idea pretty much for all
of the signs but this one in particular
kind of gives gives the overview I mean
in the paragraph follow I won't read
everything word-for-word but the
paragraph following that you know sites
the significance for why it's important
to have pollinators they pollinate all
the plants we depend on for food and for
healthy ecosystems
underneath that it gives like a nice
just
basic here's what pollinators need and
all of all of the signs direct people to
more information three of the four have
QR codes so if people have smartphones
and like to use their QR we reader to
access more information and website they
could do so
the main idea behind these signs is to
really entice people with beautiful
images and not look intimidating like
there's too much text all jumbled
together but people can kind of pick and
choose the information they want to read
so the goal of this particular sign not
only to just you know let people know
hey it's a really good idea to landscape
your Agard your home landscape with
pollinator friendly
plants and also other aspects of it but
also like encourage them to say hey you
can do this and even you know go to the
0:c Society website and you can purchase
a neat little sign yourself that says
hey I'm doing this to make my pollinator
habitat friendly so those are the two
main concepts on this side and we were
lucky that Jen asked people around the
state to upload photos that they would
not mind us using so I had like 60 at
least images to choose from five so that
was like our main
I just felt like let's celebrate the
photos so
beautiful yeah I don't know if we should
oh go ahead which agenda do you want to
add something well a lot of educators
had noted over the last couple years
talking to educators around the state
that using finding photographs that we
have permission to use has been hard and
as we put more stuff on the web and it's
more like publishing and then suddenly
we get into issues with do we have
permission to use a photo so building
this photo library was a nice kind of
corollary you know thing to this because
it's something that we've needed but how
do you ever devote the time to it well
the need and having some grant funding
towards that is one of the you know one
of the things that helps you do it
incrementally so yay we've got
pollinator photos you know next what do
we you know what do we need to collect
so that was really great to to grow our
photo library that way so and also it
was nice about that is that they every
single photographer probably thanks to
your direction put their name as the
file name yeah so that it was easy to
credit everybody without saying hey I
want to use this you know be on the
Rebecca image who can you tell me who is
it was so he compared so all the photos
are properly credited to the
photographer's too so and and that photo
library will also be stored on the CCE
shared resource library that we're that
we've been piloting now for a while so
people can use them as well oh
okay or should I close this one and open
a different one sure unless anyone has
any questions about this one in
particular
let me open the chat pod
and this is Joe Allen I'm just curious
why when you're listing the reasons that
pollinators are in decline that you
didn't include climate change oh
that's yes it was in there at some point
was it yes it was but I think what the
discussion was was habitat lost part of
the climate change discussion you know
what I mean that was that was that was
in there originally as a as a point but
then somebody made the point that that
the habitat loss well there's also you
know it's human
that that was the issue with the climate
climate change what would you agree on
that
yeah yeah I mean I
it were not alike no it can't be
emphasized by saying like habitat loss
partly you know in part due to climate
change it's not like we wanted not
emphasized you know we didn't purposely
try not to emphasize that climate change
is a factor I think it was more like we
just wanted to be like direct about like
you know
what is what they're having that loss
and tell you yeah right and also trying
to be succinct I mean we there was a lot
of text and you don't want to dumb it
down you also want it to be unassigned
you have to be really careful to make
sure you don't you put digestible
amounts of text that people are willing
to read
do people feel strongly that it belongs
in there no they want to be changing a
lot but it came up a couple of times and
that that was kind of how we how how it
how comments winnowed it back down to
this because we did try to keep it brief
what do you think well the other thing
is you might notice that underneath a
list of what pollinators need there's a
QR code that that QR code leads to a
website that Jen created that gives
because there was like a whole like
checklist of specific things you can do
in your garden so Jen made this really
great web page I don't know if it's
mentioned there or if it could be
expanded on there right because we
couldn't get it all in the signs and we
and then it becomes an additional
resource for educators a that it's a
colonial web page that you could ask
your web master in your association to
clone that web page and then you would
be able to
add stuff in there that you know means
something to your county versus having
to create the web page from scratch so
yeah
we could you know it is it is in there
but it could be brought up more and if
you think it is if no people think that
this is something to change the other
beautiful thing about this is that this
is PDF and everybody has PDF editors you
can edit the QR code and if there's
something really important in your
garden that you're trying to highlight
there might be something that you could
you know there are places that you can
put things that make it unique to your
garden so we could look at that too but
so JoEllen I don't know if that answers
your question
it does but I can definitely see that
it's a space issue I
don't consider habitat loss
to be directly tied to climate change
which is one of the reasons that I
thought it should be in there but
especially if you're referring to it in
other places that they could find as it
is let's see if we really do the hook I
mean the process so you start with a lot
of words and then you come down to fewer
and fewer words and then you know you do
in order to make it short enough that
people will read it you definitely lose
some ideas yeah I mean I wonder if it
could just be like right on that last
line in the introductory paragraph it
says you know many of these pollinators
are in decline especially bees and
butterflies due to habitat loss and
upper pesticide use comma disease and
climate change it might all fit nicely
I'm fine yeah
yep I bet it was if it was bit I would
said really like to see it in there yeah
okay I mean I'm coming from a person
who's you know like really trying to
elevate our climate change
interpretation here that I I don't to
make sure yeah like it won't do
no yeah change we can make we're not
going to really expand on that in the
sign anywhere but I think it's just this
just gives you the why behind it so I
think that's very appropriate yeah
okay and and I if I I'm sharing my
screen I don't think I can actually add
a comment but if you look on any of
these box things you can add comments as
you use them say hey great I downloaded
it or this or that but we can't you
can't enter comments oh wait I can I can
add in climate change in there and that
will be a note for us too oh well if I
learn how to spell
[Laughter]
we know we don't you talk about me
okay so then I'll close this one is that
okay and then do you want to look at
another one in particular
no whatever you feel is the the order
that makes sense in your mind there
isn't any particular order of these
signs I just wanted to highlight that
the pollinator paradise was kind of if
you know you know you had a small garden
where you only had room for one to me I
felt like we just wanted to have a sign
that kind of you know was like just if
you were only to choose one to me that
would be the one that would make the
most sense that's all yeah and then this
I think the pesticides one because we
just talked about potentially
adding information to and this one has a
spot for adding and whoops I see if I
can get that little thing on the bottom
to go away but it's it may not go away
while you're looking at it this was a
sign right Sara that that you had some
room for additions
I think it was all seasons one where
people could put their own QR code to
create their own plant list is that what
you're talking about oh no on this one
you can write in on the right oh yes
yeah yeah Jen wanted a place where
people could could write a comment or
people could leave comments but you know
there might be a new a tip on you know
not having to use pests like in the
latest IPM practices that you might want
to say hey check out this article or
you could even laminate an article and
post it like the double-sided tape or
something but I was thinking like gel
markers like if these are created if
they're laminated that's very easy
because you can just use gel markers
right on top of that black space but if
you get them fabricated say at FedEx
Office or staples and it's just there's
usually a finish they put on it and the
gel markers that have been working
really well
with writing it on there and when it you
know when it dries it the rain doesn't
really affect it but it does take like a
simple green or just like a cleaning
solvent just to get it off there
great and that could be a space where
you know I think that this is a hot
topic often and there might be something
in the news or there might be a change
in pesticide labeling or whatever it
happens to be or even an upcoming
program that you want to highlight is
the spot where people could keep the
space alive you know it's a place to way
to change things or if you don't want to
change it you could pop something in
there again they're pdfs and all of us
have acrobat an editor PDF editor that
allows you to go in there and edit
things so
it's there it can be changed a little to
make it you know work for you so we did
write right up
you know places you could get them made
how you can mount them just the you know
the logistics of what the cost range is
we can go through that after is it okay
if we go through that yeah we're gonna
make sure we leave enough time for Holly
so maybe maybe actually we'll go through
that now I'll show you the signs quickly
just so you see them and how glorious
they are I'm sorry Sarah I think you did
an awesome job on them so and then the
photographer we had yeah yeah so this is
the idea be re go ahead generally you
know you go yep I would say the main
idea behind this one is to
further build on you know what
pollinators need is to really get into
the fact that having something in flower
throughout the growing season is very
important and this gets really into
specific to emphasize the fact that you
know certain insects really have
specialised with certain plants so the
far the right hand kind of shows how
there's specific relationships between
like Frankie I should know all these by
heart considering that I wrote type this
out but you can see the different
butterflies and then what they
specialize on but we also wanted to say
that it's you don't need just native
plants that have specialists that you
can also have lots of non natives if
they're in flower that really appeal to
generalists too so we want to emphasize
that on this sign and so this is the
sign in which there's a QR code that
says scan here to view a plant list on
our website and then it says www type
your website he org well I get behind
this one is that if you have a plant
list you'd like to post on your website
here's your opportunity to create that
page and then generate a QR code and
place it in over the QR card we have
here the QR code that's here currently
is the QR code for the website above
that talks about
plants and different regions that are
good good to plant like a whole variety
of pollinator so if you don't feel like
or don't want to make your own unique
plant list you could just take that text
away completely using the Adobe editor
and then just keep that a QR code that's
there does that make sense to people
because that's the one little tricky
part that I felt people might have
questions on
if that that's in the manual - so for
people who aren't on this phone call
that would that's
explained
okay yeah we should go sorry I know I
talk too much and everyone I don't know
oh and then is this the one we didn't
look at these are essential yes that's
yep
there we go the focus of this one is
just on beast specifically to explain
how they're in great decline and how
there's difference between honey just
kind of dispelling the information that
a lot of people sometimes get confused
on you know what height what's honeybees
versus the fact that there's still
thousands of native bees in the United
States but honeybees have you know great
function here as well though they're
introduced so it gets more into
just why they're essential then you
talked about the honeybees versus native
bees and then also generally felt it
would be a good idea to you know a lot
of you guys have said that you know
really dispelling the fear that bees can
sting you and that you wouldn't want to
welcome these into your habitat but
letting people know that it's mostly
kala native colonists not colonnades er
Holly oh so social bees that are likely
protecting their colony and that would
provoke them to be more
apt to sting versus solitary bees so
trying to say hey regardless of the fact
that they you know have attended the
sting they're very important so that's
what we wanted to decay a whole sign
just to bees
um we wrote a just a two pager that just
says
everything we just discussed so while
we're here that there are there are
going to be a whole bunch of supporting
resources for educators also in a
resources for educators things so
handouts articles that you could just
use on your local newspaper somebody
shared with us an announcement for a
pollinator program you know and how they
how they did so we shared that as well
as a template for someone to borrow from
and just you know try yourself to do a
program like that I'm not sure that I
have it here but the guide it's not in
here yet but the guy does go through
what you would
what you would do in terms of how to
print it right Sarah print how to print
you what size to print it on who to get
from how to mount it what you need to
change so kind of guide to go along with
it hey Jen this is Laurie one of the
things you were asking about is if you
could get some feedback on how people
are using it yeah I wonder if in this
guide
you put a link to a Qualtrics survey
although so then if an educator uses the
material they could fill out how it's
being used I mean it would be optional
but I think I think people will be very
thankful that you did all this work it
might provide you a little feedback on
how they're using it from I don't I
think I would ask why not right right I
think we had like assigning in a
visitor's log idea on there but maybe
that would be just more instant yeah so
that could be your visitors log and also
it could be like if you fill out this
form you'll be you'll be notified of
emerging you know changes in content you
know earth maybe other people have ideas
about what would motivate people to just
give you a little bit of information
about how they're using air or have used
it well I have to say the nice thing
about getting a lot of photographs from
people is that they want to see if their
photographs got used you another second
decision oh yeah no but that's written
brings another question how do we get to
people to know that the resources are
there and that they can use them you
know that's the that's the other thing
is getting the word out and I don't know
what that maybe I put it out on the Hort
listserv and say hey come come get it
you know I don't know yeah and the other
question I have is do you have an
evaluation tool
oh
gosh oh maybe it's coming
you what kind of to evaluate yeah I'm
for people who are visiting sign oh
oh yeah in the garden you mean yeah yes
that was one of our hopes to do yeah
how do we have you get people to
evaluate Sarah maybe you have a better
idea when people come to a garden how do
you get feedback from them
yeah that's always ongoing struggle I'm
actually right now testing that well I
mean essentially the best way to do it
is you know if we you know you eat we
have you look back at what your learning
objectives are for each panel and then
you ask questions to evaluate whether
what you know ask questions the visitors
to indicate whether those learning
objectives were met or not I mean so one
thing you and I could do John is sit
down and say for each panel say okay you
know here are the learning objectives we
felt were important on this panel and
then create some generate some questions
that if you know an educator has time to
ask a handful of people you know hey
would you mind taking five minutes to
answer a few questions that that is um
kind of a standard way to evaluate right
or you can have them fill out a little
form you know I often feel like it's
often more effective the visitor my more
likely to tell you the right the
information you're looking for is if if
you just
they spoke it because sometimes people
are like sure I'll write this to fill
out the survey and they never do right
right well that's that that would be an
educator would have to be there right
yeah or a person who's an interview
person like a person
yeah right I mean I know that like I
worked helped like a children's garden
with some interpretive panels and we had
a little QR code in the bottom and said
hey tell us you were here and tell us
what you liked about your visit and
that was one way that they're hoping
they're going to get feedback the panels
aren't up yet so we don't know if people
have actually done it or not I always
just say if you really want to get the
information you have to do in the
easiest way possible so it's like
dedicate and two hours for an educator
to go out there and ask ten people you
know it does very well right
and it's probably easier to do one a
garden day some of you are having garden
days and you've got folks out there and
you're doing programs hands-on to have
to have a volunteer assigned to just
kind of wandering and asking hey would
you mind answering a few questions
yeah awesome okay yeah great no I just
say Volunteers of the bet like that's
what I'm thinking that I'm going to do
for a project that I'm currently working
on here and have a volunteer hang out in
our welcome center for a few hours each
Saturday and ask people about the
exhibits that they're in interacting
with right because we do need that
feedback we put it out there and we hope
that people are going to come visit it
and then and then we see people wander
through or we know that they're down
there but we don't really know what they
think and Holly wrote some things in the
chat window about getting people to how
do we get it out she suggested maybe
you're doing a webinar and and or even
just recording a webinar
and it could be you know or even a
recorded PowerPoint that they could use
at regular Master Gardener business
meetings to let different associations
know that it's there and that the
volunteers might be interested in and
taking it in that next step and getting
them printed out and installing them in
their gardens because awesome they're
really yeah
the PowerPoint might be good for like
the first garden who puts them out there
to kind of show take pictures a each
step meaning like you know here's the
here's the material we printed on here's
how we installed it can even be like a
little YouTube video yeah we're down
there you know that like shows the
process yeah which is another great
project even that for a volunteer to put
together so yeah yeah cuz um maybe I'm
saying maybe that sounds too wishy-washy
but I'm thinking because I want to use
the pollinator paradise sign and put it
in our pollinator garden and so we're
lucky that we have a crew a construction
crew so I can make a request for them to
put it in but if I can say hey can you
tell me when you're going to make the
sign base I can go videotape them doing
it and then just kind of splice together
a little fun instructional you know
narrative to go along with it right yeah
yeah that would be probably till the
spring but yeah yeah I don't know but
that's a good idea I think you know it's
Anna wish I could be on the wish list
for sure oh yeah yeah so we took we took
a half an hour I and I hope that that
gives people some idea of what
what's out there what we did this is how
we're expanding our education our
display gardens here in Oneida County
and
one of the gardener's part of our
perennial garden a lot of people around
our area and probably throughout the
state are concerned about deer browsing
in their perennials so this is a sign
that we have in front of this garden
that is made up of deer resistant plants
and you can see she said visit Cornell
Cooperative Extension website factsheet
on the deer resistant plant and
there's the garden in our little plaque
would at st. pitchers right there in the
center of it and we also wrote a news
article for the local newspaper about it
too to bring more people out to see the
gardens this particular garden in the
butterfly house
their goal was to provide visitors a
place where they can learn about life
cycle monarch butterflies the types of
milkweed plants needed by caterpillars
and nectar producing life needed to
sustain the life of a butterfly
objectives they post a large graphic
display of the life cycle of the monarch
butterfly plant two types of milkweed
common and swamp and
explained with signage the importance of
preserving milkweed and what type of
monarchs use plant and label a variety
of nectar producing plants provide a mud
puddle for butterflies to use and
display recipe for mixture display fun
facts about monarch butterflies and
you'll see that my circle next slides
create a brochure that explains how to
grow butterfly garden at home in their
assessment as
visitors exit the butterfly house ask
them to fill out a survey about their
experience and knowledge gained and
you'll see our survey box and
I'll go into that and
we did have the spine soldier bug attack
our larvae of our
monarch caterpillars this
year and that kind of devastation to our
monarch display this year but here's the
signs they created that go throughout
the house
and then that's lifecycle display and
they're looking for a big laminated
poster from
educational site that would have the
monarch lifecycle little better these
were pictures that we took on one Milla
gardeners made over the years ago and
there's some butterfly Mud Pie
the recipe
right there and then take a survey this
is as they exit the butterfly house and
then we have the information box there
that we had brochures in about making a
butterfly garden and
like what plants the butterflies like
and then the surveys are in the info box
and they just leave them right there
with the pencils
and here's another sign right there
caterpillar systems for Chinese eyes to
Nancy and this was our we educated
public because many were coming to see
the butterflies and what happened to him
and we had those right on our door
posted an explanation of what happened
and when some kids came I was out there
talking to him and they seemed like the
explanation they learned more something
that there's predators to the
butterflies
and that was what they
we also had some other culprits in there
too Munson
so nice too
and our pollination garden and I like
how you did the signage for pollination
paradise this is well tying nicely for
the area and our Gardens next year
all-american selections we participate
in
that organization every year we sign up
to receive seeds which a local high
school FFA group starts the seeds for us
and
their annuals and also vegetable seeds
but this year their theme was pollinator
education and we participated in their
landscape design contest and this is how
we incorporate the
pollinator education into this annual
brick garden here and
we had a submit that we have the plants
all labels and they do provide some
labels for their plants and
we had a gentleman who has a friend of
one of the gardeners who made up some
recyclable water sources that the
pollinators could use that were creative
mold sponges in there to soak up a
nectar solution that they made and
one of the gardener's
grandsons was a member of a
Cub Scout or Boy Scout group and he made
a mason bee house and that was all put
in the garden and labeled there for
people to see and there's another shot
of the
nectar and
what is pollination
sign there and then the overall we end
up creating a mobile and then we have
beetles butterflies hummingbirds and
birds on there and it tells a little
more about the different pollinators and
it kind of moves around with the wind
and
all-american selections like how we
worked with the different community
groups
we involve 4-h ER and
AARC schoolwork kids help in the gardens
too and we received honorable mention
this year for what they did with the
education and that's kind of how we this
year have added a little more education
to our garden
and thank you Sarah for getting us
rolling Oh
Holly this is Jen that is really cool
that you worked movement into there
that's really awesome that that moves
people see things that move and it
tracks them you know
but I saw that a Fiona had a question
earlier and I think this is probably
something we all would benefit from
knowing is when you create interpretive
signage how many like how would you know
what's enough how many words should be
on a sign or are there any other
pointers I don't know if we saw that in
the chat window I don't know Sarah if
you have any rules of thumb that you
could share
webex undo itself or a fun presentation
I mean the quick and dirty I mean
there's a lot I could say and I
certainly don't want to take up
everyone's time but they're definitely
like there's definitely interpretive
research about like how many chunks of
words should be together
before people start getting tired of
reading it so I never exceed 75 words I
try and I try to even do a lot less if
possible in one chunk of words and
some people recommend you know don't
exceed 150 words per sign now I try not
to do that too much but I also feel like
the key thing about interpretive signs
that I feel is most effective is giving
a title that gives you the understand
idea of the whole sign an introductory
paragraph underneath that that again
summarizes what the sign talks about and
then the chunks of text that are kind of
secondary to that reinforce that main
idea with clear headings that tell you
what you're going to talk about so that
way people there's a hierarchy people
could walk by a sign they could read the
title may be the introductory paragraph
and they're going to get the main idea
you want to put forth and everything
else reinforces and gives even more
detail to that main idea to me that's
the key way to structure an interpretive
sign
and again try I
assume people aren't going to read
everything but I always assume that so I
assume that like there's like have you
guys ever heard of like the three-second
three minute and or 30-second
three-minute rule the people that most
people are going to look at a sign for
three seconds so in those three seconds
you're going to get them to read the
title and maybe the other headings the
thirty second people might read the
heading the main title the introductory
paragraph and the main headings to the
other places and then the three-minute
people will if you you know really stick
to you know 150 to 200 words might read
the whole thing but I give people the
opportunity
to dig deeper and the headings I feel
are the invitations to dig deeper like I
honestly when I go to a
Museum and I see like a whole long
paragraph I'm like those people didn't
want me to read it it's like they didn't
invite me to read it so I just I don't
I'm not a reader so I'm a good person a
great interpretive side because I don't
even like to read I
mean I like to read books but like if
I'm enjoying a garden I don't want to
have to read a ton of information right
you're moving yeah yeah yeah very
helpful yeah and so I mean I'd be happy
to do like a like actually prepare kind
of a presentation on what I've learned
in the interpretive realm over that you
know the course of my career with just
like the kind of tips and basics if you
guys are interested in that but but to
me it's like the key is inviting people
to want to read more if you don't make
the effort to try to rope them in by you
know headings that tell you what they're
going to read about no one wants to read
and then process what they just read
they want you to tell them write a
youtube video yeah it's like five
minutes or ten minutes yeah just like to
give a few examples and I feel like the
pollinator ones you know that you know
we graduate we haven't evaluated them
with people but we could I could use
that as a way to like you know what the
what drew me to design it in that way
yeah and then the other thing which I
think you did with Holly and her group
that was so critical is even before you
get to the signage mm-hmm you go through
that process of what are the messages or
the main goal of this space somebody
works through that process of
identifying their their main themes and
their what Holly was describing you you
took her group through is probably
critical to getting to that point of
where okay now I can decide what my
title is going to be because I know what
I want
yeah exactly
yeah it's like I'm creating what the
main theme is for the like for instance
the pollinator paradise our main theme
was here's the way you can create a
pollinator paradise in your in your
garden and you know Jen was really good
about creating catchy fun titles
now Holly I just wanted to know what the
mobile was made out of his at metal
it's a PVC pipe Oh
nice that's awesome when was it made by
the group that it was at the 4-h group
well I had one for ager and two Master
Gardener volunteers kind of helped to
guide her on it and
so and then we've laminated and used
rings we had like pull ties before but
now we have like the three binder ring
type things hooking to the sign and we
had to use them
duct tape to kind of reinforce it
because this fall the winds have gotten
stronger up here and that was kind of
tearing it before year one but I mean it
was fun to make and it's nice and light
and we can use it for other things to
cool and congratulations Holly that's
really an awesome thing to get
recognized you know and sometimes we
don't do a great job of Tooting our own
horn but you know that's really awesome
the gardener's yep they they do a lot
hard work and I'm glad they
participated in the contest huh
thank you
anything anything else is great very
informal actually I feel like we should
have like a workshop
on a regular basis for people to share
what they're trying and how they're
trying it and as you because as you said
Jen it was better to do it as a
collective yeah and then to try to do do
this sort of thing on our own because we
all have our own you know you just only
see one way right and so you get all
these comments and you always filter
them through your lens you know your
lens of what you need and where you are
working and that kind of thing but they
open the door to like aha you know maybe
we should try that or you get these
great ideas like we might steal from
Holly now of having something that moves
in the garden like that you know so yeah
so so it'd be fun that maybe maybe maybe
this is where Cornell plantations has a
role we come Cornell plantations for a
summer workshop
would be fine a son thank you are of
different signs and yes and other types
of interpretation besides signs like
creative ways you know - I mean signs
are great there they can be low-cost and
you know they're always there you can't
have people there all the time right
but there's we've been trying to add
mobile tools to give people guided tours
of our gardens and
yeah yeah I like like other people
sharing like Holly did and just like
Jenna and I did you know like hearing
the other creative ideas people have
been doing - so people can like build on
each other I'm sorry I just wanted to
mention really quickly because Jen had
mentioned how difficult it can be to
find images and the New York State IPM
program has a Flickr site and we have
albums specific to pollinators and also
bees and a wasp but I was looking at the
bee poster I noticed that you had a
photo captioned about how the the wasp
will collect wood fibers to build their
nests and it reminded me of a photo but
I was luckily able to collect showing a
paper wasps actually scraping the wood
off so it's good to know that those
kinds of things are available
and
Joe joylynn that was a great sharing and
actually somebody suggested that we
shared that we borrow some photos from
there which we did and and credited the
photographer's but did you do you all
have access access to that Flickr site
or anybody with a Flickr account can see
it right any I don't even think you have
to have an account to see it no you just
need to go to Flickr and our garden
based learning also has a Flickr site as
well it's not it well no it's not
available right now because we are I
think sarah has a few more changes to
tweak and now we're going to add climate
change if we can into that line um and
then that that will all go on to the CCE
resource educators resource sharing site
and at that point if you would like I
will just add you if you're not already
added but
we used to have slides actual slides
with a script so you would get rocks in
the mail yeah this is this is more of a
sandbox location
and and so what we're trying to
trying to get a little more
skill that sharing stuff that we're
developing
so people aren't developing the same
thing in
separate world
right although sometimes since we're do
we are
what I'm trying to say we're developing
them simultaneously that sometimes we
end up with this overlap naturally and
it was just because I put that query out
to the whole group on the listserv that
I think somebody from New York State IPM
said hey we have this whole file sharing
site on Flickr and I was like a
wonderland you know somebody opened up
the door to Oz in the back it was all
these wonderful photographs that I just
didn't know existed so it's just
throwing it out there and having that
that casual kind of conversation that we
have online that helps make those
connections I think
great well thank you yes thank you
everyone
at YouTube bye-bye
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at Cornell edu