this is a production of Cornell
[Applause]
University okay just to let you know the
reason I don't use PowerPoints is so
many of my colleagues have been telling
me that when I use them they just get in
the way
so so uh uh there are a couple of places
where PowerPoints would be useful but uh
you all have good imagination so we'll
uh we'll we'll work on that so let me to
start with um
I want to share with you uh What uh one
of my major concerns are now as we think
about uh the future in food and
agriculture issues and um as you
probably gathered from the introduction
uh I've been involved in sustainable
agriculture now for 40 years of my life
and during uh that whole time uh and
even today
still uh most of my colleagues who are
engaged in sustainable agriculture are
thinking about it in terms of how do we
make the current system a little less
bad and you know whether you're uh into
sustainability thinking about that in
terms of uh simply intensifying what
we're currently doing more which is of
course one school of
sustainability or if you're uh feeling
that everybody should go organic or if
you're feeling that what we really need
to do is become more environmentally
sound
Etc uh it's it's still all operating
under the notion that the basic system
we have out there the you know modern
industrial system is okay we just have
to fix it a little bit and uh my point
of view is that as we really think about
sustainability we have to think about
future
challenges and that approach to
sustainability is not going to work for
reasons that I'll go into uh in some
detail here in a bit but um one of the
resources that also helped me really
think about this uh and this kind of
transition that we need to think about
um is you know the world watch Institute
now publishes a state of the World
Report every year and uh in each of the
they they choose a different theme and
the stateof the world report in uh
2013 uh was entitled is sustainability
still possible and the lead essay the
lead chapter in that collection of essay
and the collection of essays in my view
are always really quite good those
usually diversity of group of people
that contribute to to each of these uh
annual
reports um and U and and all of the
essays in that report were good but the
lead essay was written by Robert
Eagleton who at that time was the uh
president of the world Welch
Institute and uh he coined the phrase
for his lead essay Su stain a
Babel and um and and the title of thee
was beyond sustainable Babble how do we
get Beyond sustainable of babyon I
always thought that was a really good
way to frame this but then he pointed
out that uh you know we now have all
these different views of
sustainability which he says uh uh it uh
reflects a cacophonous profusion of the
uses of the word sustainable to mean
anything from environmentally good to
cool and he points out that this is an
approach which has a high cost because
frequent and inappropriate use lulls us
into dreamy belief that all of us and
everything we do and everything we buy
and everything we use are enable to go
on forever Without End
Amen and I think that's a really good uh
statement about where we are today and
so this uh state of dreamy belief is
what we have to get Beyond and we have
to really address um some of the key
issues that we're facing so one of the
uh things that has helped me a lot to
frame this how do we now begin to think
about sustainability in a more
appropriate uh defensible way and um one
of the resources that's been helpful to
me in uh in thinking about this is um uh
an anthropologist uh who published a
book back in
1989 uh by the name of Ernest shusi and
the title of the book that he published
is called culture and agriculture an
ecological introduction to traditional
and modern farming systems and as you
would expect from an anthropologist what
he does is asks the questions how have
we as humans fed ourselves ever since
we've been on the planet and here's
where a PowerPoint slide would be useful
I actually have one but you know gearing
everything up for that uh and you all
have good imagination so what I'd like
to have you think about now is a
timeline of human history so if you see
the timeline of human history all the
way across the screen here and uh and
you know shusi points out that as
full-fledged human beings we evolved on
the planet about 200,000 years ago now
you know you can take it farther back
than that if you want to go back to the
Neanderthals Etc you know a million
years million and a half years whatever
but if you want to think about it in
terms of when we were what we see
ourselves as today as full-blown human
beings about 200,000 years ago so he
points out that for the first uh 200,000
years or the first 190,000 years we fed
ourselves as hunter gatherers so if you
think of this timeline of human history
you have to go at least about halfway or
a little better than halfway across the
screen right so we fed ourselves as
hunter gatherers and he points out that
feeding ourselves as hunter gatherers
was the most efficient Energy System
food system we ever had that we were
producing about 20 KOC calories of food
for every one kilo calorie of the energy
that we invested in making that food
available to us
and then about 10 or 12,000 years ago he
argu is when we we the ne the Neolithic
Revolution started in which we started
to do Agriculture and then instead of
Simply going out into nature and hunting
and Gathering what nature provided to
feed ourselves we started to manipulate
nature we started to do uh cultivation
we started to domesticate plants and
animals and started to feed ourselves
from that and as he points out this was
a very land intensive kind of
agriculture because we relied first of
all on the natural fertility in the soil
and then in addition to that we
primarily did the and this is not every
not every kind of Agriculture but the
majority of Agriculture was the slash
and burn agriculture where we would cut
down and burn the perennial plants that
were out there and then the ash from
that plus the natural fertility would
provide a fertile uh environments in
which to grow our food for you know two
or three or four years and then we would
abandon that and slash and burn another
place and raise our
food uh and uh he argues that from an
Energy Efficiency point of view this was
much less efficient we were now only
getting about 10 kilo calories of food
for every Kil calories of energy that we
invested so if you think of the timeline
of human history you go about halfway
across the screen and then probably
another two Ines which is that 10,000
years when we started to do Agriculture
and then he argues and this is the
important point for the point point that
I want to make here that in the early
1900s we entered into a third era of
Agriculture which he called I think
appropriately the neoc caloric era
because it's entirely based on Old
calories and then he argues that this
will of necessity be a very short period
of time in the timeline of human history
so you can think maybe a half inch or
less on that timeline of human history
and that's the agriculture that with or
that's the food system that we're
involved in now and any points out that
this NE caloric period is the worst
energy efficient system we've ever had
we now only get about 1 kilo calorie of
food energy for every 10 kilo calories
of energy that we invest in making the
food putting the food on our
tables and so as we think about these
old calories which support that system
as they no longer are available to us uh
and we have this terribly energy
intensive system we're in serious
trouble so if we really want to be S
serious about sustain ability this is
the picture we have to think about so
that's what I want to uh address with us
in the few minutes uh that we're going
to have uh together uh today I should
also mention that you know when you when
you read uh uh Ernest shi's view you
could kind of like you know so we were
hunter gatherers and then one day we
woke up and said oh let's be
agriculturalists now and then one day we
woke up and said you know let's be neoc
coloric producers now and uh as uh uh uh
uh colon uh tudge points out in his book
neanderthals bits and Farmers how
agriculture really began that that's not
the way it happened you know it happened
over a period of time that even when we
were hunter gatherers we started to do
some manipulations you know of nature to
try to produce more Etc and even when we
shifted from the Neolithic period to the
neocolor period you know that didn't
just Farmers didn't just wake up one day
and say oh we're going to start using
all these inputs now uh that that
happened over a period of time probably
really started in 1840 when eustus liik
you know published his paper about how
we didn't need to uh involve ourselves
in the laborious process of maintaining
the health of our soil anymore all we
needed to do is put in the three inputs
the nitrogen phosphorus and and uh
potassium and then we could produce all
the food that we needed uh and uh and
then it it really took us uh you know
about half a century to really fully
adopt the uh uh neocolor uh period
but in any case this the system that we
have now is based on a paradigm which is
really true of all of the industrial
economy and that's maximum efficient
production for short-term economic
return and every farmer knows that
that's what the the Paradigm he has he
or she has to operate under and um so
what that means is that you have to
think about this in terms of how you
accomplish that maximum efficient
production for short-term economic
return and of course the way you do that
is you specialize because that's more
efficient you simplify your management
and you go for economies of scale and uh
an individual who was very much at the
heart of this was Henry Ford and some of
us probably didn't know that Henry Ford
actually grew up on a farm just outside
of Detroit and he had already been a you
know adopting those principles in the
farming operation and then took those
principles uh when the EST L the first
uh automobile uh uh assembly line uh so
he once famously said that people could
buy any car they wanted as long as was a
black Ford Model T because that was the
only one he was going to produce because
that was more efficient and then of
course he didn't teach every one of his
employees to put a whole a whole
automobile together taught each one to
just do a simple piece of it and it came
through the assembly line and then he
was insistent on producing enough cars
so that even all of his employees could
afford to buy one that was the economies
of scale and then that concept became
adopted in
agriculture uh and especially after the
second world war and uh you know when
you drive through Iowa now for example
you don't see 40 different varieties of
crops the way we used to grow back in
the 1940s it's just two now just corn
and soybeans and that's it and that's
that again that
specialization uh management
simplification one of the reasons that
uh uh GMO crops became so popular
especially in things like soybeans is
that that when you use Roundup Ready
soybeans you don't have to have all that
complex management of trying to figure
out exactly when the weeds are coming
how you're going to control them you
just go out there and you plant your
soybeans you wait till the weeds come up
one spray of Roundup and the weeds are
gone and the soybeans grow on their own
that's the simplification and then of
course the economies of scale uh you
know average Farm sizes you know used to
be uh about a th000 acres in Iowa now we
actually have one 40,000 Acre Farm a lot
of the Farms are five and 10,000
acres so uh the question we really need
to ask is whether or not this direction
that we've taken and this kind of
specialization um simplification and
economies of scale uh continue to be
sustained into the future as we meet
these uh these new challenges that we're
uh that we're going to be facing so what
are some of those challenges well the
first challenge obviously is energy uh
our current system not only in
agriculture but our whole Industrial
economy is absolutely dependent on cheap
energy you know the amount of energy
that we're currently using is
unprecedented and uh we've had this
cheap energy because we've had stored
concentrated energy primarily in the
form of fossil fuels when you have
stored concentrated energy all you got
to do is you expend the energy uh to dig
into the Earth and extract that energy
and then process it and make it
available and uh you know back in the in
the uh 19 1930s and 40s we sometimes
forget I think that the first oil well
in this country was in 1859 and Titus
old Pennsylvania so about 150 years ago
and then we didn't go to the oil economy
the next day you know it took about a uh
you know 40 or 50 years to really get
fully into the oil economy so we've
really only been in an oil economy for
about a 100 years again a very short
period of time but during that period of
time uh it's been these cheap fossil
fuels that have driven not only our
whole economy of the especially our food
system so now and and you know right now
as we all know the oil prices have gone
down but I don't need to go into detail
of why that's happening you know it sort
of didn't work out that well for Saudi
Arabia anymore so they started producing
as much as possible so this is a short
period of time in the you know in the
energy uh picture and at some point
these oil prices are going to go up uh
torn Pickins who's an oil guy uh he told
us uh uh uh uh about eight years ago uh
uh that uh we should expect that uh
crude oil will hit $350 a barrel within
10 years um so uh we got a couple more
years uh to get to that point now uh he
probably didn't anticipate you know the
additional oil from fracking and all of
that and uh even if you discount uh some
of the ecological damage from that Etc
uh that can't that can't continue
indefinitely into the future so at some
point the oil will be $350 a barrel and
the question I like to ask and I spend
most of my time talking with farmers and
I really prefer to talk to a mix of
farmers you know some conventional
Farmers some organic farmers some CSA
Farmers some Market Farmers Market
Farmers Market Farmers uh around the
same table and then uh instead of
getting into an argument about who's
right and who's wrong what I like to do
is to say okay let's imagine that 10
years from now crude oil would be $350 a
barrel and let's imagine that uh
fertilizer prices are 10 times what they
are today because we're also drawing
down all of our natural resources and if
you want to read a really important uh
book on that uh Ugo bardy who's now
published a new club of Rome report
called extracted in which he goes into
great detail about all of these mineral
resources and these other natural
resources on which we've absolutely
depended where our industrial economy
are now essentially becoming
distracted and then um Michael CLA also
published a book called The Race for
what's left in which he also goes into
great detail on all of these resources
that we've been absolutely dependent on
in our industrial economy are now
becoming depleted and he presents a
scenario which is very convincing that
we could end up going into a series of
resource Wars to grab those last ones
that are left so we would use the
remaining resources to fight over the
resources and we still want to call
ourselves Homo sapiens but um but
nevertheless these are all possibilities
that we have to think about and then in
addition to that you add the fact that
we're drawing down our Fresh Water
Resources all across the planet and uh
and of course water is essential we're
currently we're using 70% of our fresh
freshwater resources just for
agricultural
irrigation um and part of that is
because of course we haven't paid
attention to what so Albert Howard
reminded us we needed to do and that was
pay attention to the biological health
of our soil so our soils don't absorb
uh right most most of our soils now have
become so degraded they only absorb
about a half inch of half inch of rain
water an hour uh and um so the rest of
the water runs off uh and so we have to
use more irrigation but we're drawing
down a fresh reader Fresh Water
Resources all across the planet then of
course we have to add the big elephant
in the room and that's climate change
and uh and all of these are connected
because climate change to some extent is
the result of the fact that we haven't
managed our natural systems and ways
that are self-renewing and
self-regulating uh and so we have to
begin thinking now about a future um in
which we uh uh you know uh take all of
those uh kinds of things into
consideration so uh now you can probably
come to the conclusion pretty quickly
and a way I said oh God it's all going
to hell there's nothing we can do about
it so I want to spend uh the next uh 15
minutes or so uh talking about a
different kind kind of future which I
think U is possible for us and um one of
the things that we have that's useful to
us that we do have some wisdom from the
past about how to do things differently
in a more sustainable way that actually
can accomplish a kind of sustainable and
again we're going to concentrate
primarily on our Agriculture and food
system and one of those uh uh pieces of
wisdom from the past is from Sir Albert
Howard you know sir Albert Howard
already uh and he published this book in
agriculture Testament back in
1943 and he already understood back then
that this direction that ustus V liek
put us on of Simply going back to using
these few synthetic inputs instead of
paying attention to biological soils was
the wrong direction in fact he referred
to what he called the NPK mentality he
referred to that as a form of banditry
because it was going to steal
biologically healthy soils from future
generations and this this was not
consentable and so in his book on page
four and and his idea his alternative to
this was to farm the way nature does and
on page four of the agriculture
Testament he puts that concept into a
summary paragraph which is a very short
paragraph which I've always thought is a
great concept a great statement for how
we need to think about how we're going
to redesign our food system for the
future and here's how he put that he
said uh you know we we can we can we can
summarize this in a in a few words and
uh what we need to do is to partner with
nature uh rather than to subdue or
ignore nature with the way West Jackson
would put it and so here's what he said
he said Mother Earth never attempts to
farm without livestock so animals are
always a part of a self-renewing
self-regulating system she always yees
mixed crops there are no monocultures or
at least very few monocultures in nature
great pains are taken to preserve the
soil and to prevent erosion that's how
nature functions
the mixed vegetable and animal waste are
converted into humus and there is no
waste everything gets recycled back into
the system in nature the processes of
growth and the process of Decay balance
one another ample provision is made to
maintain large reserves of fertility and
uh again even since we started to do
agriculture 10,000 years ago it was that
those reserves of fertility that we
depended on for uh you know for raising
for producing our food U the greatest
care is taken to store the rainfall and
both plants and animals are left to
protect themselves against disease now
some of my colleagues take exception to
that last statement you mean we just
ignore plants and animals we don't you
know we don't attend to their health
anymore well this is not what he's
saying what he's really saying in his
view is that if you manage our your
farming systems the way nature does then
the natural uh immunities and health of
the animals and the plants will pretty
much take care of themselves so you
don't need to bring in resources from
outside to to do that now the one piece
that's missing from his analysis which
I'm sure West Jackson would want to add
is that nature operates on the basis of
perennials not annuals um and so if we
were to think about this concept of
Agriculture and how do we with all of
our resources that we have at our
disposable today in our modern world how
could we use those resources to create a
farming system that that operates under
this principle of farming the way nature
does that I think is a is a huge
challenge for us and it's a challenge
that I think uh is uh is one that we can
address and one that we can come up with
and I'll mention a few details on that
in a bit here a second wisdom from the
past is somebody that's all known to you
here at Cornell and that's Liberty Hyde
Bailey and among his many Publications
was his book the holy Earth in which he
said what we need to do now in our
agriculture system is to come up with
this new hold we have to have this new
internal motivation that helps us to
recognize that nature isn't just a
resource out there for us to exploit and
use but we have to treat it as kind of a
sacred resource a holy Earth and we have
to learn to relate to that Earth in a
way uh that sustains its health and and
it and its Vitality uh and uh the holy
Earth is is uh again I think one of
those resources uh that most of us
should go back and uh this year 2015
this the 100th anniversary of the
publication of that and my understanding
is that uh Counterpoint press is going
to publish a a new uh edition of the
Holy Earth and Wendel Barry is going to
write the introduction to that so we
might want to take a look at that as a
new resource you know for our students
Etc and have some conversations about
again that wisdom from the past and then
you can also add to that list uh Alder
Leopold who's one of my heroes and you
know Alder Leopold was actually
influenced by the writings of Liberty
Hyde Bailey but even more so influenced
by his own observations of Nature and
how nature functioned and um you know he
came up with this notion that we now
have to think about the land not so much
as a commodity belonging us but as a
community to which we belong and that we
humans are simply plain members and
citizens of this biological community
that makes up this Dynamic Land
Community um and then he developed out
of that concept he developed his land
ethic but you all know so I don't need
to repeat that but then he ended up
saying so how are we going to implement
this land ethic and a land ethic isn't
something that's just written it's
something that has to be internalized in
us and so he came up with this concept
of we have what we have to do now is to
develop an ecological conscience you
know a conscience in which we all
recognize that land health is an issue
that has to be as important to us as any
other kind of ethical consideration and
but but how do we develop the
psychological conscience and that's
where he realized this was a difficult
task and that you couldn't simply do
this you know by writing about it or by
talking about it that this had to be a
product of social
Evolution but an ecological conscience
is a conscience about land health and
land Health in his view was the land's
capacity for
self-renewal so how do we begin to
relate to the land in a way and by again
by the land he doesn't just mean the
fields out there he meant the entire
biotic Community how to relate to the
biotic community in a way that it is
self-renewing
uh that it and and again this is
critical to how we think about the
future of our food and agriculture
system so the there's some others you
know that we could talk about let me let
me just leave with those three but there
we do have this wisdom in the past and
then we have the science of ecology and
evolutionary biology and
unfortunately in agriculture we have
applied almost none of the insights and
resources and research
from the science of ecology and
evolutionary biology and Agriculture and
in my view if we married that wisdom
from the past with what we've learned
from the science of ecology and
evolutionary biology I think we could
come up with Incredible new design uh
systems for a future food and
agriculture system and that's what I'm
trying to encourage uh you know the land
grant University that I'm involved with
and and others of us who because I think
this is a critical role um which our
university community uh uh can
address and when you think about it in
terms of the science of ecology and
evolution of biology a couple of things
stand out not only from that science but
also from some of the things that we're
learning uh at the Practical level now
is that critical in this in in this new
uh design of our food system is
restoring the biological health of our
soil and you have here uh great
resources in that uh uh in ter terms of
uh vaness who has been working with Fred
magof and others and developing actually
some metrics for how we major soil
Health uh but we need to really begin to
address that and figure out how we apply
that and how we uh begin to work with
farmers and not only farmers but other
people in the food system because if
we're going to if we're going to restore
the biological health of our soil we
can't continue to do maximum efficient
production for short-term economic
return we have to come up with a new
paradigm and Farmers can't do that on
their own we have to all become involved
in that because we have to create a new
food system and that new paradigm is
more a regenerative resilient food
system for Reliable long-term return
that's an entirely different Paradigm
but we can do that and we know how to do
that and if we redesigned our food
system it would encourage Farmers to
move in that kind of Direction and so
that's uh that I think is part of what
we need to uh what we need to address
and again we have some interesting
resources here you know and again I I
don't have time to go into all them but
but one that had really uh inspired me
over a long period of time is uh an
essay that Joe Lewis and his colleagues
and Joe Lewis was the leading Pest
Management specialist in the agriculture
research Service uh for uh I think
almost 50 years and in 1997 he and his
colleagues published an article in the U
uh National Academy of Sciences uh mag
proceedings and um there point in their
article was after 50 years of experience
he said we now know that single tactic
therapeutic intervention strategies for
solving pest problems are not
sustainable because as they pointed out
if you come if you have a pest problem
and you have this single tactic you know
you come in with a with a pesticide the
therapeutic intervention to get rid of
the pest that that's not sustainable
because what happens is you never get
rid of all the target pests so you
create pest resistance and you not only
harm the target pest but you also harm
other biological organisms some of which
previously served to help suppress pest
emergence so you're actually causing
pest Resurgence so this is not a
sustainable
approach and then they point out in the
middle of that article they have about
three paragraphs and they said we should
not expect any other different results
from genetic engineering than we do uh
from uh uh chemical technology because
it's the same Paradigm we're still doing
single tactic therapeutic intervention
uh to solve a problem rather than what
they said what we have to do now is to
transition to Natural systems management
and they finally end up at the end of
that article with two questions which
I've always loved they said instead of
asking how do I get rid of the pest what
we have to ask is why is the pest a pest
then that leads us to redesigning the
system in a way that suppresses pest
emergence and that's the direction we
have to move in and then they argue also
in there that we aren't just talking
about Pest Management we're talking
about you know all of our systems that
you know whether you're uh uh a farmer
or whether you're a school teacher or
whatever if you're addressing your task
as a single tactic therapeutic
intervention you're really not enabling
people to understand what's going on in
the system that's causing the problem in
the first place and that's the direction
we have to move in so I think this is a
brilliant article that I hope everybody
uh and it's still uh all you got to do
is uh Google Joe Lewis and uh uh and and
and the article will come up and you can
download it and U and read
it uh one of the other things that has
inspired me recently is uh uh Dan Barber
who's a good friend of mine who is a
chef actually and many of you I'm sure
know him or know about him uh he has two
restaurants in New York now actually one
at Stone Barnes where where I spent part
of my time and one in town and uh Dan's
published a new book now called uh the
third
plate and he argues as a chef now based
on his experience that uh the farm to
table direction we went from you know
industrial food production to farm to
table food production and that was an
important transition but we need to go
beyond that now because what he
discovered is that uh as a chef of
course what he's primarily concerned
about is getting that kind of quality of
food which has this exceptional taste
that satisfies his customers and along
the way he discovered that as a chef the
easiest way to accomplish that is to
find the farmers who manage their soil
for soil health because if you grow food
on soil that has healthy that's healthy
soil then you have food that has this
incredible uh taste quality and then as
a chef all you need to do is prepare
this food in a way that allows the
natural flavors to express themselves
you don't have to do all the
manipulation to get the food to do what
you want it to
do and then of course and Dan is also
very interested when a farmer farms in a
way that gets this kind of biological
healthy soil What does the farmer have
to do so he starts to visit the farms
and one of the key relationships that he
had was uh to Claus Martins who's
actually pretty close to you here and oh
and K Claus Martins was producing a
variety of Emer wheat that was out of
this world and this is what Dan wanted
and so he went to Claus's Farm to see
what klous was doing in order to produce
this emmer wheat and he discovered that
klous had to grow some cover crops from
which he got no income he had to have a
crop rotation which included Millet and
barley which there was no Market in the
food market so he had to sell that as
animal feed which he got less money for
and then suddenly Dan realized what he
was doing is simply cherry-picking this
one product from his farm for his own
benefit just like going into a
supermarket and just cherry-picking some
things and that was not the future of
the food system what we have to learn
now is he what he called eating from the
whole farm so he started to work with
Claus and they figured out ways that
they could Harvest some of the leafy
material from the cover crops which he
could use in his salads in the
restaurant and he started to design some
uh menus or some some items in his menu
made from the Millet and from The Barley
so he could actually buy those as food
props from from klus and this then
suddenly put Claus into a much better
economic situation and this concept now
of eating from the whole Farm is
becoming popular even in Iowa where some
people say you know we got to deal with
with Farmers differently here we got to
think about what Farmers have to do what
we want them to do and then how do we
reward for them for that in the
marketplace and this is a whole new
concept which is going to take some time
I'm sure to catch on everywhere else but
if it's catching on in Iowa it can catch
on anywhere
so so these are the kinds of uh
directions and again we could uh there's
all let me also add one other little bit
of good news here that's happening and
that's actually in the business world
because obviously uh uh people in the
business world have to begin to
transform their operations as well and
um there are two resources I want to
call to your attention and one is an
article that was published in the
Harvard Business Review a January
February uh 2011 issue uh by Michael
Porter and Mark Kramer who are two of
our leading economists which is
important to keep in mind here and they
wrote this article entitled creating
shared value and that article was
written to the business community and
basically what they said in the article
of creating shared value they said the
if we if people in business continue to
operate by what they call the old
Playbook you're not going to be
successful in the future and operating
by the old Playbook is getting your
labor and your raw materials as cheaply
as possible so you can increase your
profits in your company and
externalizing as much of your
environmental cost and your social cost
as possible to increase your profit in
your own company and if you're going to
continue to operate by that old Playbook
you're not going to be successful in the
future the reason is because our labor
and raw materials are now becoming so
degraded you're not going to have the
quality of those labor and raw materials
for to continue to be successful in your
business and if you continue to
externalize your environmental costs and
your social costs then your social and
natural capital in your community is
going to deteriorate to a point where
you're not going to be able to have a
successful business in those communities
so you now have to figure out how you're
going to do business on the basis of
shared value taking all of these
consideration these issues into
consideration in your business plan and
they make a very compelling case for
this and I know that uh Michael Porter
at least is now doing some workshops
around the country with people in the
business Community trying to help them
understand why they need to make this
kind of transition and then there's a
second resource which I think is in many
ways is equally important and um this is
a u uh a u his name is Andrew Winston he
has started his own company which he
uses as a consulting firm uh to work
with uh major corporations especially in
the Agriculture and food system and the
title of his book is the big pivot and
the subtitle is radical practical
strategies for a hotter scarcer and more
open world and his point in his book is
that if you're in business and you want
to be successful in the future you can't
just kind of you know make things a
little less bad and hope that you can be
successful because we're not in a
situation where we have a hotter world
that's the effects of climate change
which are already affecting our
businesses and we continue to do so for
in the future we're living in a scarcer
world where many of these resources that
I talked about are no longer going to be
there so you have to figure out how
you're going to redesign your business
to operate under the circumstances and
it's a more open world so if you think
you can work your way through this
simply with a better job of messaging
you're on the wrong side of History
because there are now the social media
and if you if you put out that kind of
mess message and it's not true somebody
will come up with a 10-minute video to
expose you and then it's going to hurt
your business so you now have to make a
big pivot turn and fundamentally rethink
and reorganize your system the guinea
makes a very compelling case for this so
these things are happening in the
business world as well as uh uh in the
um uh you know in the uh uh uh uh
physical world and I think you there
there's some other things we could talk
about here but we can maybe we'll get
into them my question answer but I want
I want to end with one other thing and
that is I think the role that the Arts
can play in all of this because if we
can't imagine a different way of doing
things in a better future and become
emotionally energized to do that it's
going to be very difficult to see how
we're going to make these big pivot
turns and I want to give you just one
example of the way in which the Arts can
be so
effective um Kathleen uh Dean Moore who
is the head of the philosophy department
at uh Oregon
University and she told me once that
when she got into the field of
philosophy she began to realize that
philosophers often use such dense
language they don't even understand each
other let alone the general public and
she didn't want to be a part of that
world so she started to translate these
important philosophical concept into
stories and in her book The Pine Island
Paradox at one point where she talks
about the difficulties and challenges
and and um and uh uh damage that were
doing uh with our Wars and with the way
in which we're treating our environment
Etc uh this simply can't go on so she
decides to imagine her daughter her
granddaughter writing her a letter from
a hundred years in the future and what
would she say to her and here is here's
the story here's the imaginary letter
that she puts out which I think is a
great example how the Arts can be used
in such a powerful way she imagines her
granddaughter saying how could you not
have known what more evidence did you
need that your lives your comfortable
lives would do so much damage to ours
did you think that you could wage war
against Nations without Waging War
against people and against the Earth
didn't you wonder what we would drink
once who had poisoned the ERS didn't you
wonder what we would Breathe once who
had poisoned the air did you stop to ask
how we would be safe in a world poisoned
by war did you think that it all belong
to you this beautiful Earth you who
loved your children did you think that
we could live without clean air in
healthy cities you who loved the Earth
did you think that we could live without
bird song and swaying trees and if you
knew how could you not care what could
matter to you more than your children
and their babies How could a parent
destroy what is lifegiving and
astonishing in her child's world and if
you knew and if you cared how could you
not act what excuses did you make and
now what would you have us
do and I think this is a powerful kind
of statement which can serve to energize
us you know because it's our
grandchildren that's going to inherit
the world that we're creating and so we
need to begin to take seriously these
kinds of transitions that we have to
make not only in our food and
agriculture system but of course that's
critical because we can do without a lot
of things in the future but we can't do
without food and water and so uh so this
is uh what I wanted to leave with you
today and
uh go to uh some uh i' love to you know
have your concept and I always say to
people I'm especially interested if I
said something you disagree with because
I'm a Russian German so I haven't had an
argument I haven't had a good day yet
so but anyway uh let's open it up and
then Matt's GNA repeat the question so
sure everybody hears
let's the concept of
uh changing farming and on a very um
what I personally partook was like on a
very local scale like it's on us to do
um more sustainable farming or go to the
farmers what do you think the role that
does the corporate farming play in the
United States how does that haveen to
change in the future because essentially
part of the problem is Corporate farming
and they manipulate the
farmers yeah well that's part of one of
the things that I didn't address which
uh we can talk about if you want is
you've got a culture
isue uh because we've all become a part
of the industrial economy the culture
which sustains that and you know Paul
Roberts uh C recently called the impul
society in which he makes a very
compellent case for the fact that the
kind of culture that we live in now is
all about mine and now um and of course
our corporate world also lives by that
culture and that trans and so you know
so we have this kind of uh uh economic
system now in which each of us feel we
have to you know capture as much for
ourselves to the short term shortterm
brand is and uh and of course
corporations corporations just don't
wake up one day and say I'm going to do
business that say how can I you know how
can I create my business in a way that's
going to give me the most profit and
that means you have to play out to that
kind of culture that's out there people
want to have the shortterm for
themselves so how do we make cult how do
we change cultural issues and that's a
you know that's a huge problem I don't
think that's going to happen from the
top down I think this these are changes
that have to come from the bottom up and
again one of the things that's
encouraging to me is there's a there's a
body of literature now that's coming out
which is helping us to understand that
these cultural transitions need to take
place and U Paul Roberts does a much
better job describing the problem he was
coming up with an answer but
nevertheless he points in these
different directions but marjerie Kelly
uh who published a book a few years ago
called owning our future she makes a
very compelling case that this economy
that we're in now what she calls the
extractive economy where each of us try
to grab as much for out possible that's
now increasingly becoming dysfunctional
again you don't have all the resources
to keep that working and you've got
these concentrations of wealth that
leave so many people out that it doesn't
serve the common in our community and
then what's starting to evolve now is
what she calls the generative economy
where people in communities are starting
to work together for what she calls the
common flourishing of life and uh she
gives some practical examples of you
know the kinds of things that are
starting to happen in various places so
I think if we can begin to point to some
of these generative economy
emergence and and some of them are
happening actually in agriculture she
points out that uh you know where groups
of farmers uh pool their production and
have their own brand and establish these
relationships with their customers you
know like organic valley and Shepherd's
grain and N branch and natural country
Beach you know the number of of mountain
they're actually now economically much
more successful than the corporate uh
you know individual trying to grab his
much and uh just as one example the
average age of fers now is
58.3 the average age of the farmers in
each of these uh I call the values based
value chains is in the mid 40s are
getting younger so we I think as we
start to see that there is a success
pattern that moves in this other
direction that actually is more uh based
on the common good and the this
generative economy this common fishing
flight that that actually works better
than where each of us credit gra for
ourselves and that could begin to to
take us in the direction of uh changing
changing our culture that I'm not saying
that's going to happen tomorrow but at
least it's already happening at some
placage I'm not trying to be cynical I
agree with everything you're saying but
I I just wonder about the political
economy you has power and influence to
do this at scale and I don't see the
incentives for business or the
politicians that fun to really change
our complete food system even though
it's necessary so we've seen all of the
indicators about climate change for
example we know it's coming it's
imminent and yet we're really struggling
to actually make significant policy
changes to reverse course there's a huge
momentum to keep everything the way that
it is related to the food system related
to
urbanization and our power structur so
how how do we grapple with that and yeah
really important question and I I don't
mean to uh pretend that that's not part
of our
culture but here's the other thing that
I think we need to pay attention to that
is that um uh you know uh in our in our
in our in our current system which you
know obviously still working for you
know certain segments of the economy and
uh and if it weren't working for uh
Corporation they wouldn't be doing it
anymore but you know again if you start
to look at the early indicators of some
changes that are taking place uh let me
just give you a couple of examples uh
cargo Corporation has one of been one of
the biggest uh Defenders of uh GMOs in
our food system and have contributed to
not having any labeling Etc they've not
come out with a non GMO variety of
soil uh the Hershey Corporation made a
decision here uh a couple weeks ago that
they're going to transition to a total
non why are they doing this they're
doing this because public is their
consuming public is increasingly saying
that we want to see some changes in the
food system now the important thing and
this is where the power part of it comes
the important thing about all of this is
that uh if you're in the food
business you C Food customers have a lot
more power than if you're in uh
automobile manufacturing or computer
manufacturing business because in fact
we had a um U Cooperative Extension
individual in Iowa who did a research
project this was about 10 years ago and
she made a case for the fact that she
thought that food customers had much
more power than any other customers
because if you're a company and you're
producing automobiles or computers as
she put it and if you lose a couple of
customers you can always get your
existing customers to upgrade more often
or buy a second car or a second computer
ET if you're in the food business and
you lose a customer you can't just get
your current customers to eat to so
people in the food business have a lot
of power so when she did in the course
that she was teaching she asked her
students to do a research project and
she asked the students to uh go to uh
supermarkets and um find out how many
people had to go into the supermarket
and ask the manager for a particular
product that they wanted in the same
week or how long would it take in order
for that Supermarket to start putting
the new part prod in sh and what they
found without exception was that if 15
students went into the same supermarket
and ask the manager for a particular
product that product would appear in the
sh and she used that as an example of
the
power in business so here's my view I
mean I fully agree with you that today
uh our political system is almost
entirely controlled by the vested
interest who the vested
interest Farm groups they're the input
suppliers food processors all who have
made huge investments in the current
system and they've made huge investments
in the current system because we all
said what we wanted to want food fast
convenient and cheap and that's exactly
what they delivered now after they've
invested billions of dollars we want to
go to say you know we'd like to have you
make some changes here
well it's not going to happen right but
what is happening and can happen is that
instead of us going to them and saying
we like to have you make these changes
is being working together in our own
communities and as you have more
customers that say this is what we want
in our food system and this incidentally
uh is beginning to happen particularly
in our Urban centers where there is this
Evolution What I Call Food citizens you
know Bill heern who uh he retired now
but he was Ro sociology uh professor at
the University of Missouri and Columbia
University university and he's I think
done more research than anybody else on
the concentration at the retail level of
food systems and how it's that
concentration which really controls much
of the food system but then and he told
me once he said if the industrial food
system were to choose an appropriate
local for itself it would be just e
that but then he said that is rapidly
coming to a close and and I think that's
very much true now because now it's not
that people are simply passive
resistance people are becoming active
engaging in their own communities and
you have a large number of people in our
Urban population centers where most of
these food citizens are that are
starting to say wait a minute you know
we want a different kind of food we want
this we want that um eventually our
politicians going to have to pay as much
attention to these voting populations as
they do to the best of interest and then
we'll have the possibility I think
because some changes taking place you
know at that National level when the top
down in the meantime we've got to be
concentrating working with people from
the bottom
of yes um just two two quick comments
one is I think your talk I've really
enjoyed your talk you're talking more
about the US context um I'm work very
much in South Asia where the issu are
just the same but more more of a problem
but one of the people you didn't mention
is that's the farmer and I always put in
my lectures that we we've got to produce
the food using resources more
efficiently we have to minimize the
effect on the environment but we've got
to maintain the livelihoods of the
people actually produce the food and we
all want cheap food cheap Che cheap food
is a political thing and uh if we don't
pay uh the farmers a fair price for
their labor um we're going to have more
and more Farmers leaving leaving the
area going to the urban areas like like
you see in India and China and and and
then what happens now another really
great question and uh and you're right I
was focusing primarily on our current
situation in the United States Again
part of the good news from my
perspective what's started to happen uh
in the developing world is uh more of a
recognition that for them to adopt
industrial system that we had in the
industrial world is not con serving well
we still got some pressure points trying
to bring that system to uh farmers in
the developing world but there's a
rapidly growing uh phenomenon now where
Farmers themselves are beginning to
recognize that uh way in which they can
be successful in the future is is uh and
and there's also now five un reports
that confirm this and that is that if
you want to be if you want to really
address the issu developing grow first
of all you have to work with women
because 70% of the world Farm is in
develop are women um secondly you have
to work with them in terms of their
local resources and their social uh
capacity for working together in a more
e eological kind of approach where again
they use you know kind of Nature's model
as a as a way of producing food andc um
and so these are these are things with
the v compas v v compas group growing
pretty rapidly uh I was mentioning some
people here that I'm working with a a
young man now was just 22 years old and
he lives in New York at the moment um
but he uh he has he has started a
nonprofit organization of his own mind
22 years old and he just got back last
week from spending I think four weeks in
India uh 6 weeks in Egypt and some 8
weeks in Africa and his whole approach
is he knows that there are individual
Farmers each of these countries who have
already figured this out and already
examples of doing this and so he wants
to try to connect other Farmers with
those Farmers so they begin to develop
kind of community approach this new
Direction and I'm going to
try get support other people with help
bring that movement there so again I
think there are some things that we can
do
but and then eventually you know Lauren
is saying this is not only the future
for the developing gr it's also
eventually the future from the world in
the us as we go through the challenges
we faces so you're absolutely right and
I didn't mean to exclude the farm the
only reason that I put the emphasis
where I did today is that I so often in
in groups of people who think this is
simply a farmer problem we simply got to
convince the farmers they need to make
these changes and I want to help us to
understand this is social issue
ecological issue that we all have
engaged in it but working with the
farmers individually
La yes so the the focus on obviously
production systems are focused on the
provisioning ecosystem services but the
other ecosystem services that don't get
a lot of attention some farmers are
actually supporting those conservation
practices contribute to those so is
there way to compensate or to
incentivize those other services that
that that are often ignored of course
yeah and we actually have a few small
programs like the conservation programs
Etc we're trying to address that but
it's such a minor part
of the public
support but you know uh a lot of these
challenges that I talked about there are
significant
RS that
the national political system would
address with relatively minor funding
comparing to the system that we current
subsidies but again uh that's in my view
it's going to be uh pretty much uh a
loss cause of thinking we're going to
get we're going to be able to convince
people at the national political level
either in Congress or USDA to do that
because they're under constant pressure
from the invested interest to keep the
current system going so I think we have
to bring this about you know to bring
the pressure about from the bottom up
and this is why my point about the power
of uh individual consumers and bringing
about these changes which we're starting
to see already now major companies
starting to even McDonald's
that
signicant direction so they're hearing
pressure from you know custom
to pay attention to that so I think
that's that's a better way to move not
that we should ignore you know USDA or
these other issues and continue to and
uh you know the the um natural uh the
national sustainable agriculture
Coalition uh which is a lobbying group
in Washington we're doing some really
good work to exactly what the think
you're talking about and get more
funding for conservation efforts Etc but
they're operating in this CL
what
theyy but I want to see continue to BU
effective and iue support them we to do
that but we shouldn't expect
suddenly wish I had better news for you
on the short term but on the long term
uh the uh issues
on yeah um so a lot of us are scientists
so we're we're all developing science
that changes the technologies that you
know affect the the the production
systems that be using uh presumably they
can they can change those production
systems in in ways that you might find
favorable more regenerative or more
extractive I think it's difficult to um
to tell at the outset which which way
we're going I mean so like to my
daughter from the fut my granddaughter
from the future is writing to me and
asking me why didn't I ask I would say
well I'm doing my best in trying to
figure it out
right but so do you have ways of of
helping people to figure out
like or what kind of uh tests
experiments do you propose people in the
science that they're doing sort of think
about the direction that that their
science
Le yeah you all have really great
questions and um you know again I think
again I try to I always try to look for
where are the little pieces of good
news talking about and for me
uh exp a
lot this
new I don't want to romanticize this I
to all of them Jesus resurrection but
there is a growing
they recognize this is their future this
is their world and so you know example
that
I know the young couple that's
managing operation
years years years they would no more
think of taking their boys to a shopping
mall you see these two
kids big smiles on their faces and
taking home to
their this is what this is what makes
them uh feel important and fulfill
and and it's their parents who are
really part of this millennial
generation who recognize that these are
the values that they want for their
children because that's what's going to
put them in a better position to meet
the challenges in the future and they're
not an isolated case and you know I I
would tell people when I my first
American history course was when I was a
junior in high school and on the first
day of our class uh a teacher got up was
a young guy could have been 25 years old
he got up in front of us and he said I
want you all to understand that only 20%
of the American colonists were in favor
of the American Revolution and he said
the reason I want you to understand that
is because the reason you should study
history is so that you can learn from
the past how you apply the lessons from
the past to your future so he said if
any of you are interested in bringing on
changes you don't need 100% when you
need
20% I've always remembered that and so
you know as I think about this
millennial generation now with these
different kind of values with they have
they're trying to their children um I'm
wondering you know do we have 20% up
there yet I don't know surveys as far as
I know but I do know in my own
engagement and involvement in the
various Enterprises that both I State
University of sow Center and other
places that I've been I keep running
into more and more of these young people
who are in there early you late 20s
early 30s and U there are so many of
them at least that already in this new
culture so I take again great insiration
from that and I think part of my
responsibility is what can I do more
support so I don't have a better answer
to your question than that but again the
fact that this is already happening I
think is something we can support and
more that we can do that may be a better
indicator of the kind of changes we want
to see if you want to see
so I think we're already over time a
little bit um I think br will be here
for a couple minutes so if we want to
just break now and thank for it again
and uh and then we'll be around a couple
minutes this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu