Howdy. Thanks so much for having me and
for being here. Uh my name is Alistair
Hayden. I'm currently an assistant
professor of practice at Cornell
University and before this I was a
division chief in the California
Governor's Office of Emergency Services.
So, here to talk a little bit about some
uh more disaster flavored uh OneHealth
uh items. And so, it's going to be about
uh wildfire smoke and how we can uh
protect ourselves in our communities.
And, uh just a quick shout out, I'm love
working with our extension colleagues.
And I'll highlight Adam Hughes, the last
name on the list here, uh is one of our
extension colleagues who we've been
doing a lot of uh work on wildfire smoke
with. and we are here to support um if
you have any questions or uh want to
talk through wildfire smoke or
disasters. So, you've been staring at
this uh picture here and you probably
have a guess what it is, but in case
not, uh I'll just start labeling things
here. We've got clouds. We've got some
wildfire smoke plumes up there in
Canada. And then, of course, uh we've
got a smoke plume covering New York
State and the region here. And so, this
is a satellite image on June 6th, 2023.
So, the first really really smoky day of
that uh smoke wave we experienced a
couple years
ago. Wildfires are kind of a
quintessential onehealth issue. Uh so
they burn through vegetation and then of
course anything else that's in their
path. But healthy ecosystems actually
usually need some amount of fire. Uh and
that's most famously true out west in
the California ecosystems. But there are
uh ecosystems in our biomes out here. Uh
the pine barons ecosystem is the most
famous one that needs lots of um
wildfire uh both here in New York and
New Jersey, but even some of the
hardwood ecosystems do need uh fire just
way way less
frequently. Uh we are in an era where
wildfires are really exploding. And so
this is a figure from a uh a recent
publication that kind of shows uh the
change. Uh so the y- axis is the amount
of uh it's it's a schematic. This is not
actual data but it represents actual
data. So the y- axis is showing the um
the average acres burned each year and
then the x-axis is showing us time over
the last several hundred years. And you
can see that in the present uh there is
starting to be an uptick in the acreage
burned by wildfires. And this is because
our ecosystems are getting out of
balance. They're not uh they're no
longer healthy. And so one reason for
this is climate change. And I see a
bunch of comments in the chat. Okay,
that's uh not things I need to answer.
Sorry about that. Uh so climate change
is one of the reasons but uh there's
several other reasons that are commonly
referenced uh by folks who study this.
So we have more people moving into
high-risisk areas. So uh about 80% of
wildfires in the US are actually started
by humans. Uh sometimes that's
intentional, but most usually that's uh
unintentional. Can be something as
simple as parking a hot car on dry
grass. uh wildfires start for all sorts
of reasons. Um and then a really big one
that's shown on this graph is fire
suppression policies. So actually our
our policies since the late 1800s have
been to put out wildfires and again
ecosystems need those wildfires and so
by suppressing them we are causing the
ecosystems to be unhealthy and then that
is leading to this uh increase that now
we're seeing in the uh frequency and
intensity of fires. So again, this is a
a classic one health uh issue because
there's a feedback between human and
ecosystem health and just want to say
the future will be
smokier. So this is why we want to talk
about wildfires as a public health
emergency. Uh so as you probably have
personally experienced, uh I assume most
people at this point have lived through
a smoke plume regardless of where it is
that you live. Uh you might have
experienced some of these annoying
irritating symptoms that are associated
with wildfire smoke. Uh but wildfire
smoke can actually exacerbate uh more
serious health conditions. So um asthma
uh can be associated with cardiovascular
disease and infectious diseases as well.
And we see increases in emergency room
visits and actually mortality. And this
is not uh or this is during wildfire
smoke waves. So, there's additional
health impacts in the long term uh that
are still only just being studied, but
these health impacts are all things that
can happen while the smoke is still in
the
air. So, what I really want to focus on
today is how to uh because you all work
with communities, um your frontline
workers, important for getting
information to your local communities. I
want to share with you what I understand
to be some of the best practices uh for
protecting from wildfire smoke in case
you get a a question about this. So, it
basically boils down to three things.
Getting good data and then knowing how
to protect yourself and protect your
community. So, the best way to get data
and the only way we recommend uh is
through this wonderful website
fire.now.gov. And this basically shows
air quality for the whole United States.
And it's got a uh some extra data that
makes it most useful for uh tracking
wildfire smoke plumes. And they keep
changing the formatting. Uh and it is a
federal data site. So we'll see how long
uh it remains
active. Um but to get all the data, what
I recommend you do is click the uh gear
in the upper right corner, and that'll
let you turn on some additional data
layers that are currently hidden by
default. And so I usually just go in and
turn everything on because uh I'm a big
old nerd and I want to see all the
data. So this is uh what it looks like.
Uh the last one I was showing was a less
smoky day. This is a um a smokier day
and I'm showing New York State
here. The big circles are official EPA
monitors. So, these are uh really
serious air quality monitoring stations
that are established by the federal EPA
as well as its state, local, and tribal
partners. And these are actually
defining your official air quality for
your region. And so, you can see across
New York State, there's only something
like 15 of those big um official
monitors. So, then we have the smaller
dots, and this is why I like turning on
all the layers. Uh these are independent
sensors. uh kind of community science.
So these are things that uh anyone can
go out and purchase and I'll talk a
little bit more about them in a second.
Uh they're lower quality data than the
uh official ones but they can be very
helpful for figuring out for example
where the edges of a smoke plume
are. And then uh the gray areas are
smoke plumes and these are observed by
satellites. And it's a little hard to
see here because this picture is all in
a smoke plume. So I'll just back up one.
And on this map, you can see that
there's a um a gray smoke plume covering
part of the United States. Um and the
smoke plumes, it's not necessarily smoke
at ground level. It could be a mile
above you. So, just because there's a
plume overhead doesn't mean you're
breathing the smoke.
So about these commercial sensors, we
worked with our um state uh cooperative
extension here uh local health
departments and one tribal nation to
distribute some of these commercial
sensors to some of the rural areas that
were further from established sites. So
we're working on uh promoting health
statewide and we noticed that there were
gaps uh especially in the rural areas uh
which is what this ugly yellow shading
is. I really need a better figure for
this. uh but we uh provided sensors to
our partners and then also some training
and assistance on installation and using
the data. And in case you're interested
in these, uh the ones we used were
purple layer sensors which are about
$300. Uh we got a grant to fund this. Um
and the reason we chose them was because
these sensors once you set them up can
actually send data to that official
federal website. And so these uh small
dots that you're seeing on the official
federal website are data from these
community established uh sensor stations
and uh they're working on getting more
companies air quality monitors uh able
to feed into that. So not trying to just
promote one company here. That's just
the one that I have familiarity with.
And I saw recently that uh there's
another company called Clarity who now
uh their sites their sensors also feed
to the site.
All right, I want to really focus on
different data sources for this um for
making decisions about air quality
because this is one of the primary
questions that we get during a smoke
wave. Uh there are so many sources of
data out there and they can say
conflicting things and lead to a lot of
confusion. So uh the
only the only official air quality data
comes from airnow.gov
And if you go there, you'll see a little
dial like this. And this is again a
federal website and it's pulling the
data from those official federal uh
monitors. And it's showing a couple
things here. So the first is uh I'll
first I'll point to is at the bottom. So
today's AQI is a 24hour average AQI.
And it's important to note that this is
a 24-hour average because that doesn't
necessarily let you know what is going
on right now. So, for example, uh there
could be really really bad air quality
while you're asleep and then you wake up
and then the air is fine. And so then
that average over the 24 hours could
look really really bad, but your
experience was actually while I was
outside uh walking the dog, everything
was fine. So when we're looking at
24-hour average AQI, uh what we are
recommending uh for decision- making
based on that is especially decisions
that are that might occur over the
course of a day. So you can see they've
got tomorrow's forecast. And so if
you're thinking about should I change or
modify my summer camp or activities for
um my outdoor activities for tomorrow,
the 24-hour AQI is good. Uh, so again,
this is great. It's official
high-quality data, but it doesn't
reflect what's going on right now. So,
the other thing you'll see on this dial
is what they're calling the Nowcast AQI.
And that's the dial part of this, the
the good. And that is really to give you
more information about what your air
quality is right now. And so, that's if
you're asking questions about like,
should I go walk the dog right now? uh
that is uh that is the data that you
should be using and that's less
appropriate for the decisions about
tomorrow. So again um good for right
now. But then both of these are good
because they're official data but they
come from monitors that might not be
that close to your location especially
if you're in a rural area. And so the
other place to get data from are these
commercial sensors which uh you can view
through that map. Um or if you get these
sensors, usually they come with their
own um data readout. And so these are
great for checking local air quality
trends. So you can for example yourself
observe, oh it was uh really bad an hour
ago, but it seems to be getting better.
So maybe right now is when I should pop
out um and take the dog for a walk. But
one thing I really want to warn against
with these commercial sensors is uh they
are less accurate and so the numbers
that you that they actually report out
especially during a smoke wave can be
off by a a huge factor like a factor of
five or so. And so you might observe
that your readout is going to say
something different than the official
data. And usually that's because your
your sensor is uh just doesn't have the
same level of accuracy, especially in
really bad air quality as uh the
official data. So I only recommend those
for trends. The really decision good
decision-m should come from the official
data sources.
And uh just to put a uh connect this
back to the fire and smoke map. I'm
sorry, it's small on the right here, but
the Nowcast AQI is going to show up as
the big dots on the fire and smoke map
and the commercial sensors are going to
show up as the small dots on that fire
and smoke
map. All right, so once you have the
data about your air quality, uh the next
question is what do you actually do? So,
we recommend uh using air cleaners and
we know they're they're very expensive
and can be hard sometimes hard to find
or purchase. And so, one thing that I
recommend and that I do um I do this
personally is you can make a very like
it's very easy to make, doesn't require
any skills, you basically just duct tape
a uh furnace filter to a box fan. And
so, you can build this uh air cleaner
for something like 40 bucks. Uh and then
you replace the air filters as needed.
But it's uh they're really effective,
they're really safe, they've been
tested, uh they work well. Uh so that's
for yourself and your family and an
indoor space. And then it's also really
important to look out for your
community. And so this is also uh air
quality can be communicated through
these um colored flag systems. And these
are basically the same colors as used in
that AQI. Um, but it's to communicate
what to do uh with your outdoor
activities. And when you're making
decisions about these, it's important to
remember that people might not have
access to clean air at home. Uh, so we
get a lot of questions about should we
cancel school? Should we cancel this
activity? Uh and you know the
recommendation is you know actually in
some cases the facility that you have
might actually be able to provide
cleaner air for your occupants than uh
people's home locations if they even do
have a um indoor home location. Uh so
it's important to think about all
members of your community when you're
making these decisions. And we have a
lot more information about this uh on a
a website that we put together with uh
some of the questions that we get
frequently asked during wildfire smoke
weights. So with that, uh thank you so
much for all your work. Uh thank you for
your attention and showing up here. And
there's my email in the chat if you uh
want to reach out to ask anything about
this. So, I guess yeah, when the smoke
wave hits, feel free to uh feel free to
forget about me until then, but send us
an email if you have questions when the
next smoke wave happens. Thank you so
much and happy to field questions now,
too.
Alistair on the thinking on the other
end of the spectrum as somebody who's
thinking about how to help us when we
have a smoke
event. You're obviously you must be also
talking with people who are thinking
about how to manage force to mitigate
the production of the smoke. Do you have
like your top three either colleagues
that you like or mitigation strategies
for forest management to reduce
uh
fire hazards?
Yeah. So
the with with the fire hazard
specifically, there's kind of a
two-pronged answer. So everyone I talk
to who's in this space basically we are
just so far behind on they they
literally call it a fire debt. We are so
far behind on the amount of fire that
needs to happen in these landscapes that
we just need more people working in the
prescribed burn space. Um there's a way
of conducting these uh simulating
basically simulating natural fires uh in
a responsible manner. Uh it's going on
in New York State. It's going on all
over the country. I think it's most
vigorously happening on the West Coast,
but it's uh it's everywhere. This is a
really classic landscape management that
we need um for ecosystem health to then
uh improve human health. And kind of to
then the other question or the other
other part about how do we protect
ourselves and prepare for wildfires. Uh
really there's a lot of there's been a
lot of research in building codes in the
last two decades. I think the 2008
building codes are uh that's been borne
out in a number of the recent fires. Uh
so the uh the California wildfires uh
since 2018 have supported this as well
as I believe um the Lahina wildfires. So
I'll start teeing up our transition to
Hawaii in a second here. Um but the
basically there are ways including many
lowcost ways of maintaining a home and
the landscape around a home that
significantly reduce the likelihood of
the home burning down uh when the
wildfires uh come through. if you live
in a high-risisk area. So, um that's
called home hardening and defensible
space are the two words that I recommend
people look up if you're interested in
that. And again, California has done so
much work on this. They have a lot of uh
the state government there has a lot of
public resources um about how to do
this, including a lowcost retrofit list
of how to do this cheaply for
yourself. Longer answer than you wanted.
No, I loved it. It was great. It's
exactly what I wanted. Um, uh, I want to
ask you, uh, while Scott is teeing up,
have you ever heard about the art
project from LA called Pigeon Blog?
I've not. Okay. So, in terms of filling
in data space, an artist in LA trying to
deal with an air quality issue, not
fire, but air quality issue, outfitted
pigeons with
sensors. and uh they all reported back
and it interpolated between the official
sensors. And so just in terms of the one
health working amongst and between
species to think about our shared
airspace, um I just think it it might be
like a fun uh side topic about how to
interpolate um air quality with with a
multiecies kind of perspective. But I
mean it could also just be a a a true
data gathering, right? I mean, it's it's
a I don't know. It it
it I'm going to just put it in the in in
the chat just because I think it's so
fun and fantastic, but um I really
appreciate your talk.
Thank you.
This has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu.