this is a production of Cornell
University
so um as Adrian has mentioned my
original interest and motivation was in
the well modeling of plans for U sorry
can we have this spotlights
out yeah thank
you if the uh the point was to model uh
plants for U visual purposes so let's
say to create scen such as this
one no have it down yeah because there's
lots of of images which are quite dark
thank you and
um and the question was well how to
generate this kind of scenary
easily so it turned out that the best
way is to actually try to simulate the
actual processes of plant
development and this is how I cross from
computer Graphics to developmental
biology and the big question is how
patterns and forms emerge in the process
of
development so this is actually pretty
much a fundamental question of
developmental
biology and if today I would like to
focus on a problem which we were trying
to address most recently and this is how
uh the forms of um leaves
emerge and this is a problem which is
particularly interesting because of the
huge diversity of Lea forms in
nature
moreover even so for us the difference
between compound and simple leaves is
such a fundamental one it plays for
example a huge role in the
classification of leaves to begin with
the question is is it a simple is it
compound it turns out that it is also a
very um labile feature of Lea form and
you can see that well often even within
a single H plant we may observe leaves
of very different forms such as in this
case if in well in the flame tree so
those are leaves which are picked from
the same uh tree and kind of seem to be
located there without any Rhyme or
Reason some are multilobed some are
simple and in this case there is no
gradient to
them this is another example in a silver
rward and over there well some early
leaves tend to be simple and then later
ones are well um well very well
dissected so
clearly a plant can produce this
diversity quite easily and the question
is well can we comprehend where the
diversity come
from
so although this would be a much more
kind of well nicer plan to work with if
you want to understand with the
progression from simple to compound
leaves but well I don't think that ER is
known about genetics of silver RW so we
started from well a plant about which
well something is known namely
arabidopsis and well so arabidopsis is
not at all the best plant for this
because well these are simple but they
have some
serrations so the question is well can
we understand where this ations come
from so if well I puted up with milto
santis then D for now at Max plant
Institute in
Cologne in trying to figure out what is
the mechanism of um patterning of the
serration
and several things came to picture
probably the most important is that the
serration correspond
with convergence points of pin polarity
so you can see here margin of the leaf
and pin proteines which are pumping oxin
are polarized in such a way that they
converge in the place which coincides
with the location of a convergence point
and by the way you are going to see on
all the slides or many slides either
letter o or p o is observation and P is
what we postulate on the basis of U
observations as the basis of model
construction which is supposed to
elucidate what's going
on so this is one observation serations
are coinciding with these convergence
points and the transport of oxen is very
important because if it is impaired by
NPA we have this kind of leave margin
without serrations and then also uh we
lose this formation of convergence
points so it appeared that the key to
the understanding of serration formation
is the understanding of the action of
oxen and how oxin driven patterning
happens so this is the question how and
where do the convergence Point
emerge so we created a model in which
which I'm going to show you VI and in
this model A cell is represented as a
square oxygen concentration as with
green square
inside fluxes of oxen are represented as
well White Lines or arrows to show
direction The Wider the line the bigger
the
flux and pin concentrations are shown as
bars shown in red The Wider the bar the
the
concentration so in
2006 my student alvare Smith and also um
Henry Johnson who was then a postdoc
working at University of California
Irvine and collaboration with
Caltech um came up with the same idea of
polarization which
is pins which are Transporters of oxen
are well as observed are localized in a
polar way to some
membranes so this kind of part of
interaction between oxen and pins was
basically by then quite well documented
but they postulated that pins are
orienting themselves towards neighboring
cell with the highest concentration of
oxin so the more oxin we have the more
pins are we going to have here so the
question is first can this kind of
feedback create a
pattern so here's a simulation which is
illustrating this
process we have a chain of H
cells and you can see this interaction
in if well this feedback in action and
it results in the formation of
convergence point and where oxen
maximum and if this happens on a longer
distance then we obtain a pattern of
approximately equally
spaced convergence
points so
this provides a mechanism for creating a
number of convergence points in the
margin of the leaf but before I um
proceed there I wanted to if dwell a
little bit on this model of
polarization
so so the model of polarization which
which was proposed by Smith and Johnson
Json if was in a sense nonphysical it
was because it was assuming that a cell
knows what is the concentration of oxen
in neighboring cells
and well this violate the principle of
locality it was kind of like well
guessing what another cell has inside
without providing a mechanism how it can
be done so this was an open question how
actually it may happen and um well
recently my poog mck cheslak well um and
and another perod student Adam Rion will
came up with the idea which is um
Illustrated here so if this is actually
not invalidating this mechanism of
polarizing towards the cell with highest
oxygen concentration but it provides a
possible mechanical possible
mechanical explanation so the idea is if
that to separate e flux and influx and
they already separated because they are
separate e Fluxx carriers inflex
carriers in the cell so moving one more
step we assume that the cell can measure
e flux and influx
separately um and it is actually
possible to come up with well actually
too many plausible bi biochemical
mechanisms for measuring unidirectional
fluxes so now it turns
out that if you assume well on one hand
we assume that there is a presence of
oxin e flux promoting pins this is par
of all theories of um Ox polarization
going back to success canalization
theory if we assume that the influx has
opposite effect then we have pure
canalization in the style of sax which
results in coordinated
polarization of all PS in one way so
this is good for creating long
coordinated files of cells like in the
case of when
if however we change the sign and influx
also polarizes pins here so whether
oxygen flows this way or whether it
flows that way it both has the same
effect of um promoting polarization of
oxid here then we are getting
convergence
points so this provides a plausible
mechanism in which a cell does not have
to look
into what happens in a different cell
it just checks what are unid directional
fluxes out and in and make decision out
of this uh moreover well um it can be
shown that this change of sign here can
be accomplished in a quite simple
biochemical Network by changing rate of
a single reaction which exp which would
explain why so often we see changes of
polarization from one to another
type okay okay so one way or another we
have a mechanism for forming convergence
points and now the question is how these
convergence points are if emerging in
the growing margin of the leaf and here
if well the postulate goes actually to
19th century where when
Hofmeister proposed well looking mainly
at filot taxis but this is more General
principle at patterning processes and
form ated what is known as the first
available space Theory According to
which new organs are
created wherever is enough space for
them so if we apply this to margin we
have the following situation we have a
leaf small one kind of leaf primordium
in which we have a convergence point
this convergence Point actually is the
one which patterned this the position of
this Leaf at the first place as a part
of filot
taxis now this leave grows and then it
grows the margin expands creating space
for new convergence
points
and this process continues so as margin
goes more and more convergence points
are
formed and if you assume according to
the observation that convergence points
correspond to the places where the leaf
grows faster outwards then we have well
a plausible mechanism of of um formation
of serration now the question is would
this work if it put all these components
into the
model so we created the model which is
shown here so this is kind of like in
the case of arabidopsis leaf more or
less um so again the basic idea is that
that we have a patterning process going
on on the
margin and each time where convergence
point is formed grows outwards is
acceleration
and is more accelerated when conc is
higher less when it is lower and pattern
is supposed to emerge so will a pattern
or what is the shape of a leaf emerg
from
this so here is this process kind of
with parameters more or less taken at
random you can see that patterning takes
place and so does grows you have
something like well let's let's call it
a generic L
Leaf okay let's check let's change
parameters a little
bit we are getting a different pattern
now does it correspond to a real leaf or
not
well it it actually happens to
correspond quite closely to I believe
and it is amazing although again we
don't have um molecular level data about
this how close this correspondence is
kind of L to L this one here this one
there this one here here here here here
there
okay so given that we don't have this um
detailed data of iy well can we
make an arabidopsis
Le so here I will show you this this um
animation which at first may look like
well we succeeded but I would like you
to to pay attention to a phenomenon
which actually is drawback of the model
which I'm discussing just now then you
are going to see that some convergence
points are shifting as the LI grows they
jump from one position to another so
let's see it
okay so let's look let's say at this
area
here oh it disappeared okay and here's
the similar situation
occurs so convergence points are formed
but they are not
stable as the things
grow now this kind of jumping of
convergence points have have not really
be observed in arabidopsis and the
question is so what is the mechanism
which stabilizes things there
sorry here we
go so in order to see what is the source
of this jumping we should we should re
examine the first available space Theory
again because there is an element there
which is actually was sort of
imprecise so here what gos suppose that
we have two existing
organs and grow takes place creating
more
space well final space is sufficient to
introduce another organ and one would
say and we can iterate this process
forever so again space
grows and we iterate it the point is
that is not the only possibility this is
another possibility that an existing if
well kind of prototype of the organ is
going to be shifted creating space for
another one so here Al nether nor the on
the left nor on the right side we have
enough space but if we can reorganize
things we create enough
space so this kind of possibility exists
but apparently is prevented in
arabidopsis and the question is
how so here molecular data come into
play again and it turns out that
conversion point is
flanked by areas in which um another
protein Capt cotons or cak is being
expressed and it if on one hand is is
present on one hand on another hand if
it is absent so in mutant entire pic
process is
destroyed so
based on this we amended the model which
I showed you this up theadi
model with two assumptions
regarding cak one is that cak is
absent where uh in convergence points so
um we we implemented it this by assuming
that high concentration of oxen
suppresses cak and the second thing is
that cak is needed for pin reorientation
to
occur so
then our simulation becomes like
this we start in a situation where kak
is present everywhere so kak is
represented as this um yellow
circles and then as the locations
where uh convergence points
appear oxygen concentration increases
but this increase of concentration of
oxin eliminates cak from the
air and if you assume that presence of
cak is needed for repolarization to
occur this convergence point now is
fixed because there's no cak there so
repolarization cannot occur
anymore so we have a pattern which looks
at first side similar but
cak is present where oxin is absent and
cak is absent where oxin is present in
high
concentration and this absence of cak
here fixes location of of
primia there is one more element to the
story namely that um it is known that
cak ere expression
makes indentation
deeper so we assumed that cak has
additional effect of suppressing growth
so we no longer have a simple situation
where the presence of well oxin Maxima
promotes growth we have also a kind of
well other side of the story that
presence of cak is creating
indentations and if you put this into
the model
now we have a situation here cak is
shown as as pink dots because yellow
doesn't look well enough of such size
thing you can see that pattern occurs of
indentations and serration but now there
is no jumping of
er of convergence
points so okay so the ability of
reproducing Y type was part of the story
but if there are also um other um
elements of validation of the model so
well if you create pin mutant well it
doesn't have serration because
convergence points cannot be formed if
we flood the model with oxen we have the
same situation as in reality that is
that again there are no serration formed
because flooding of uh
Le with oxen suppresses cak and
consequently pins cannot
reorganize um if we have cak well the
same story the absence of cak pins
cannot reorganize if we overexpress then
you have deerc
serations so this is kind of first step
in the modeling of um if in in the
modeling of leaf shape well we had grand
plan at the beginning from simple leaves
to compound well so far we have tiny
step in the direction we have
serration so can we understand well
situation where some Lopes or compound
this
occurs and for this again working with
MOS stantis and with my student Adam
ranion if we turned our attention to a
relative to arabidopsis which is kardam
P so even though it is a close relative
it is it has very different leaves so
this arabidopsis this is Camin huta and
the question is well where the
difference which to our eye is a marked
difference between these leaves comes
from
and well one element of the puzzle is
that it is related to the uh well group
of uh genes in nox
family of which BP which I don't dare to
pronounce because it has long name if is
representative so we see that an
arabidopsis in which nox gen are not
expressed in the
leaves well we have this kind of shape
if we ectopically express Express BP
then we are getting almost a compound
leaf and then in kardam huta where BP is
present where nox gen are present we are
in the leaves we are getting well
perfectly compound
leaf here is kind of molecular side of
the story or first microscopic so um in
kardam new leaflets are formed at the
basal part of of the
leaf so in arabidopsis there's no
outgrowth and here there is
outgrowth and if we uh show where
another noxe STM is expressed in kardam
we can clearly see that it is present in
this basal part of the
leaf so um this is one part of the story
regarding difference between um
cardamine and and if arabidopsis leaves
another element which is important is to
look at veins so if we look into kadam
Leaf we can clearly see that
leaflets
are growing in directions of veins so
this is something which was absent in
the model of kardam of arabidopsis which
has assumed well there's some growth OBS
serations there accelerated growth but
because the serations are small in which
direction they grow was not an issue but
if you have an entire l or entire
leaflet then in which direction it grows
becomes an issue so taking these two
facts together we created the following
kind of
hypothesis first that veins present here
visible here veins Define growth axis so
it is a postate because what we can
observe is only that if grow axis are
correlated with veins here we assume
that the mechanism which patterns veins
is defining direction of growth and the
second thing is that no potentiates cak
so basically what no is what nox is
doing is if well
first it amplifies the action of cak in
particular it amplifies this suppression
of
growth so the the reason why he SS occur
would be due to the fact that well
normal LEF maybe would like with like
this but KAG is expressed potentiated by
nox makes this big indentation and also
nox is needed for for for the formation
of new organs to uh to take
place so based on this we created a
model which works as
follows um so here's Le primordium near
the base we have expression of no box
shown in yellow and um and and the
tip convergence point is marked by the
convergence point of pin and presence of
axin K
noock oxin promotes leaflet growth so it
becomes bigger cak constraints
growth and also while um working
together with no they create this narrow
form at the
base however at some point new
convergence Point
emerges and then growth starts there
here farther growth further formation of
lateral LIF cannot uh happen because we
don't have here um no or cak
here this dominance of no and c has been
broken so growth occurs and the growth
is going to be in the
direction of um veins which we assume
are perpendicular to the original
Direction so let's see how it works in
an animation of
simulation so main growth direction is
established by this
axis and here at some
point um new convergence points occurred
and they grow in perpendicular
Direction and this process it
itates so we are going to see subsequent
um leaflets being formed in the basical
progression
okay so this is comparison with well a
young leaf of
kardam and we can see that well this
progression of leaflets near the base
was more or less captured by the model
however the shape of the terminal Leaf
was not really captured and the reason
for this is that when modeling the
terminal Leaf we did not really
incorporate vasculature there so now the
question is well can we
increase the very similitude very
similitude of leaves by looking at veins
more
closely and in order to do this we
developed model which actually operates
at a slightly
higher level of abstraction so we no
longer model explicitly interaction of
oxin with pins we are just using the
fact that um as a result of this
interaction new uh convergence points
can be formed at some distance so in a
sense interaction between pin and and
oxen is a way of measuring distances
along the
margin and this process is modulated by
the presence or absence of substances
such as cak and no which can which can
say that well even so distances are
relatively large but because of say
absence of cak or nox a new convergence
points cannot appear
there so if we look at things from this
perspective we have the following basic
model
so um things are happening on the margin
and within the lamina so gross centers
are formed by this distance measuring
process as the
margin um between growth centers so
between let's say here and
here growth suppression can occur which
is a region where at some distance from
convergence points where cak is
expressed creation of a convergence
point is associated with the formation
of
vein the first um Mid Vin goes to the
base subsequent mid vein subsequent
veins connect to the previously formed
vein and veins defined grow Direction so
for example here grow is going to be
upwards but here is going to be well
combination of this upwards coming from
this vein and lateral coming from
that and there is no which is kind of
amplifying the action of cxs and can be
expressed let's say in slightly
different regions
So within this model the key element of
uh gross suppression is the
substance red corresponding to cak so
that as leave margin
expands this cak region is broken and
here new convergence point is
formed so if we create this kind of
model and put these elements together
just the element which I
described convergence point on the
margin
veins uh connecting convergence points
to into Network and it's defining the
direction of growth and uh growth rates
and and possibility of creating
convergence points modulated by C and
noock we can get for example this kind
of growth
progression so
here
is a sample
simulation so now I have kept the the
leaf kind of of a constant size on the
screen so it's it's going to CH chape
size because if I made the really grow
the first stages would be very small so
things can be can be scaled so all
leaves as the leaf as it grows is always
scaled to the same size on the
screen okay and we are getting
quite a plausible Leaf of which which is
found simple leaf which well we could
try to say whether it is leaf of a
cherry or something like this but well
reasonable generic
Leaf by changing parameters of the model
we can easily change the form of this
Leaf so just by changing one thing which
is branching angle we can make it
looking like a g leaf
and here is well um maybe more
interesting fact that if we increase
the um let's say strength or impact of
cak if so that it creates de deeper
um
indentations then we have progression
from a simple to a well dissected form
or kind of
High LED and moreover you can see that
there is a difference in the underlying
architecture so what we have here for
example is um there are
no here the lateral veins to the left
but not to the right but here it
appeared to the right and here we have
to the right as well and it is so
because as this indentation was created
which was absent
here additional space has been created
between convergence Point as measured
along the margin and this provided well
room for well additional convergence
points and additional veins which
support the
system here are some examples in which
we have a interaction between um cak
shown in red and nox shown in blue which
creates deeper veins and I have example
which I would like to manipulate but I
need different glasses for this so sorry
okay so what I would like to show you
now is that by changing some quite
intuitive parameters we can obtain large
variation of
shapes so this is basic
simulation this kind of
highly loped
Leaf as shown in
here now let us suppose that the cck
that the impact of cak on if indentation
is decreased
so we are getting a leaf which has
simply still this basic form of having
three
Lopes but it is much more smooth because
well red color is not creating such a
deep indentations
now let's assume that the impact of blue
morphogen so nox is decreased as
well okay and lops maintain competence
of creating new veins
so now we are just
getting a simple
leave and now let's suppose that the
growth rates associated with vins are
changed
so now we are getting heart-shaped
Leaf let's see one more
example so coming from Canada I had to
model a maple
leaf so here it
comes so you can see that there are
smaller kind of indentations or which
are due to the presence of cak and
deeper ones which are due to the
presence of nox which is kind of more
sparely located at
C so if you further analyze the
interplay between kak and no um we can
create this kind of morphos space which
um okay so here it this kind of like
basic form if we increase repression of
growth by cak we are getting well kind
of form which is which simply has deeper
uh
Lopes if we increase it by noock we can
get to the point where you have actual
progress to a leaf which is compound
which has three different
leaflets okay so I could pretty much
move to conclusions here but if well if
um you wouldn't mind I would like to
spend five minutes talking about
something which may appear completely
different and I hope you will be
surprised that actually it is not so
completely different and it is in
fluorescences so this is a field of uh
well common
yo and this is if well kind of a picture
of Yo from the top and also diagrammatic
construction from which representation
from which one can see that actually one
uh feature of this infest and many other
many other
inferences together known as corms is
that they form a very flat
surface and this is related to the fact
that they are pollinated well mainly by
flies which actually are walking on the
INF forance and pollinating FL one
flower after another so from
evolutionary perspective it makes sense
for this to be flat but how this
flatness can happen in
nature so here is kind of well more
traditional point of view which looks at
inflorescences as branching structures
decorated with flowers so we have some
branching structure which is looking
like this and if we follow this
idea then the branching structure would
have to grow according to quite complex
trigonometric rules like for example in
order to bring this flower to the same
height as this one well
this S2 would have to be S1 cosine
Alpha and in order to bring this flower
to the same level well even in two
Dimensions it the trigonometry becomes
more complex and if we imagine if we
realize that is two
Dimension structure where
synchronization of this growth rate to
bring everything to the same level would
be well quite a difficult trigonometric
problem on which many people would have
well hard time well not making mistakes
so it doesn't look very likely that
plant is doing this trigonometry to find
out to bring or flowers to the same
level so this brings us to an
alternative idea in which if it is not
so that infloresence is a branching
structure decorated with flowers but
flowers are being created at the same
level and then branching structure is
just scaffolding with cre
well to support these
flowers and this is idea which is very
similar to the idea of development of
leaves so in this case in the well
should I
beem um actually in the infes and marem
in this case we we have creation of a
number of convergence points here I drew
this in two Dimension but I will show
this in three dimension as
well and then as a structure grows
vascular connections are created in the
same way but in three dimensions as
veins in a
leaf and then in the same way in which
indentations in leaf are
formed well we have these gaps in
between and eventually we wind up with a
branching structure
supporting all flowers at the
approximately the same level and the
only thing which we have to assume here
is that growth is roughly uniform
throughout the
structure so let's see whether it works
so first we have to
create well not a pattern of
equidistance convergence points along
the leave margin but on the surface of
the merem so here it is using the first
available space algorithm we have
vascular patter we have pattern of
a let's say m new convergence points but
the infloresence of Arrow is compound so
we need to go a little bit
further and
assume that the primordia which are big
enough can create higher order primordia
so this is the layout of individual
flowers actually flower heads
because now these flower
heads are connected into a branching
structure so this is how it goes each
time when a primordium
appears it is
connected into branching structure this
is three dimensional thing you can look
at this from the
from underneath and you can see how this
branching structure is formed as a
scaffolding supporting the flowers so
proper arrangement of flowers comes
first scaffolding comes
next okay so we have this kind of
layout
and if we now Place flowers where there
should be we are getting this kind of
model which is shown on the right you
can compare it to the model on the left
so this is totally different ball game
we no longer have leaves we have
inflorescences but this is the same
common denominator
formation of pattern of convergence of
convergence points on the margin of the
structure whether margin of the leaf or
surface of the SU app Mar stem
connection into vasculature and it f
grows I have
um
um yes one
second I got a little
bit
um have to go back sorry
all these things which I removed from
the
presentation okay so I was
here
okay so this looks like the same model
but is actually this is not a picture
this is actual 3D model and you can
see well
kind of like how this branching
structure and and layout of flowers
looks like but you can also see here
another thing if you zoom
in so for example you can see this here
or there what you can see is that the
petals are intersecting each other and
this is something which using computer
models is quite difficult to avoid but
if well nature clearly doesn't have
problems with this because as already
aristal observed in the in the place
where something is something else cannot
be so we spend actually substantial
amount of time trying to address this in
computer models as well and this is kind
of like well um current well stage of
this work so in this case we have
employed well um relatively
sophisticated algorithms for handling
biomechanically surfaces which collide
with each other and you can see that in
some cases for example in this petal it
is kind of deflected because there was
another one underneath which was pushing
it the same situation is here so we are
coming closer and closer to having a
real arrow through the modeling it is
amazing that actually
what where so much energy goes is how to
compute this this
intersections so concluding
synthesis growth of leaves but not only
of leaves actually of well um many
structures Pro proceed as
follows we have um interplay between
growth and form so form is a result of
growth growth of leaves in
fluorescences is driven by pattern of
convergence point on the boundary which
specify where to grow and vasculature
which specifies in which direction to
grow there is an interplay between a
pattern on the boundary and vasculature
namely pattern of the boundary specifies
where the veins start and then where the
veins end is determined by either the
base of the structure or presence of
previous veins which explains this
feedback loop existing veins help
determine where are going to where new
veins are going to
be and then there is this Loop which is
H to H Meister that as things are being
coming bigger they create room for new
elements uh on the boundary new
convergence points which are
placed uh between existing
ones and finally as if the things grow
they can modify vascular and Vascular
may have also um an impact on where
convergence points are
appearing so this leads to something
like well more General well um
conclusions conclusion which to me
actually is almost obvious except that
sometimes when I state it well I have
vicious opposition to the idea and it is
that mechanistic understanding of plant
form from molecular level patterning to
microscopic form appears to be within
the reach we are finding more and more
details and and well it might be so that
some theories which we have already will
have to be replaced by others or refined
like in the case of this AB gradient
patterning of oxin which is now being
refined to well a more posible
hypothesis but out of this a picture
emerges which can actually mean that
biology may be moving more and more in
the direction of physics where we have
some underlying principles and then lot
of
things emerg from this so um Ernest
raford famously said that well every
well all science is either physics or
stamp
collection and it seems that well
development of biology is moving moving
closer and closer to this well um
physical understanding of the world
where we have relatively small number of
general principles and lot of things can
be deduced from this and genetic
mechanism are setting up the playground
for for these processes but many of them
have self organizing character as shown
here so I would like to acknowledge Adam
ranion and Adam uh Andre Owens so Adam
ranons was the um primary person behind
the leaves Andre Owens is working on
tenses and we are collaborating with
milanes on leavs and reg bov from well
Johannes Gutenberg University in mines
on INF
forensis thank you very
[Applause]
much yes please you want to ask this
question based on the fact that the um
you had a mechanism with the cells were
sensing inux and in that there was some
asymmetry so um based on that I wondered
if your model a second order with
respect to space and time or first order
with respect to space and time um and
why did you choose it okay what do you
mean by first order with respect of
space and time and second order so for
example Max equations
which would model your ersion points is
second order and the
solutions are first order but um if you
put your
controls um two different um two
different in kns um and had them affect
the second order you'll get an
asymmetry then um differently than if
you put it in the first order so yeah so
in the so if to begin with in the model
with if in which we have um this um
polarization by un unidirectional
fluxes if
so it is described by by the set of
first order equations so we don't in
particular observe second order well
phenomena which would be kind of like
waves propagating
um which which which which is related to
well oscillations of this type do don't
don't occur which does don't does mean
that they cannot second thing is that
this result is quite new we didn't
connect it with cck and nox we have only
oxin and pin if well we have only we
have oxen pin and some
Network which is detecting
um the measuring outx and influx so
mathematical analysis of this of this um
entire model is still to uh to happen
but we have
done quite an extensive set of
simulations showing that we have well
this um convergence Point formation in
one case polarization if well um kind of
long distance polarization consistent
with canalization so coordinated one in
the other case that the switch from one
to another mode well that actually the
in the impact of influx can be very
small so if you look into the feedback
loop which is driving well polarization
of pins and compares the strengths of
influence of outflux to
influx forming a linear form so that
let's say over all polarization is well
outflux plus Alpha influx then if Alpha
changes the sign we have change of
situation from one to another type of
polarization but Alpha can be very small
kind of like let's say one thousand of
the impact of outflux so it seems that
influx is this kind of well controlling
thing so I may have not answer your
question well directly but I I told you
what what what we know the results which
we have now are basically simulation
results and we qualitatively understand
why it is why this sign of
um what the sign of of er influence of
influx causes this qualitative change in
behavior um but if unlike previous
models of oxen which have been
mathematically analyzed
quite quite extensively this one we have
not analyzed yet we have a paper which
has been accepted and and the main
attention of reviewers was actually not
on the mathematical analysis but was on
well what kind of um
potential mechanism
at the molecular level could be involved
and we HTI it about this so I could
entertain more discussion about this
than about well actual mathematical
properties of of the model okay yes so
what I find really interesting in your
models is that she using relatively few
variables I mean there's an interplay of
just less than a handful of genes that
would contribute to the and I wonder if
using your model you
can look like I don't know if it's
possible go outside of the Lea that you
looked at and try to predict if if
basically how close within reach are you
predicting what we see in in nature like
would can you tell if you missing a
character let's say it would be group of
species that has another Gene that is in
the same pathway can you can you figure
that
out so so here this more of a
hypothetical type of question because
well not not so much is known about well
what happens let's say regarding
different species of species of plants
what is actually known is Prim know for
arop cardamine and
tomato if so if but the models are
operating if in such a way that they're
assuming are genes which are cing
something so we are abstracting rather
than thinking directly in terms of genes
we are thinking about in terms of
geometric properties geometric pattern
properties which can be which are
dependent on the genes and then how this
geometric patterning processes result in
actual patterns so well kind
of primary role is if um in this models
is allocated to the way distances are
measured how the measurement of the
distances can be modified by substances
which are expressed on the on the margin
and a little bit combinatorics sort of
in this the in the sense of ABC model of
flower development combinatorics of this
morphogens on the on the margin so it is
very possible that there is there are
many genes which are involved because
many genes may may have effect of
increasing distances decreasing
distances so if so um the fact that we
can represent these things in terms of
um small number of of variables doesn't
mean that a small number of gen is
involved because well as I said they can
be well many gen acting in the same or
similar manner but at the same time the
fact that such a small number of
parameters involved I think it is
correlated with the fact that in in
which was my opening statement that in
nature this change of form is very
easily achievable especially the change
of form between simple and and compound
in spite of the fact that to our eye
there is a huge difference in this forms
but but to a plant this is not a big
deal so I think that this is actually
sort of guiding information that if it
is easy to do for in nature it should be
also easy to do well in the model and in
this in this sense is the fact that that
a small number of parameters is to me
kind of like well indirect well not
confirmation but a well signs that we
are probably maybe on on the right path
so and actually it is very satisfying
that it can be so now if you look
everything depends on the level of
detail for example if if if you look
into well kind of text on anatomy of
leaves or
or
also detail description of shape for
example there is entire classification
regarding well what is exactly the shape
of the tip are they like this are they
like this are they like this or like
that and the well if so we didn't look
into this in full detail but well our
gut feeling is that those might be very
much well again not controlled directly
by genes but mechanical properties of of
the margin and blade are controlled
result resulting in the different shapes
so
um so this is this is kind of definition
not not not the end of the story We
would like also to create more
comprehensive Mor morphos spaces I we
created a few of them I showed plus one
but I wouldn't say that that I feel that
we have covered the entire morphos space
of our leaves and but I think that is
Within Reach
okay yes so in your early models where
you're just looking at the effect of
oxin and not including KNX and and C um
you can pretty well reproduce the the
shape of a Rabbid opy I'm curious about
the relationship between the
concentration of oxin at the margins and
the rate of Le expansion which
presumably also your later models as
well because if you look at the the
early Lea oxygen concentration seems to
be relatively uniform around the
periphery that is the leaf expands that
gets more localized right but one of the
things that didn't that didn't seem
quite right was you saw very large
gradients and oxen concentration along
the margins of the leaves but it didn't
appear that there were large gradients
in the rates of elongation or or
expansion of the margins so you had high
concentrations of oxin in the
convergence points low in the in the
valleys there but the rates of leaf
expansion between those didn't seem to
be much yes so the example of of this um
arop Leaf is is perfect perfect well
example this category so if I what I
described is well um a part of the story
which is which was focused on the action
of the formation of serration but
actually this process is well
superimposed if on the Assumption there
is an overall if well gradient of leap
expansion so so so and then well in in
the paper where we describe this this
this model is described in painful
detail but this is this is the basic
part of the story that that that it was
focusing on theformation of additional
features right so you're looking at the
additional expansion that's caused by
the higho
in the case of arabidopsis and the
reason for this why it may be so
precisely that is that well if there's
no no there so there is not much
potentiation once we put the noock there
we have bigger effect and is what
happens yes please forgive me if I
missed it you might have mentioned it
but
you have you successfully mapped the
vascular architecture onto the leaf more
so in other words if the model has
looking traditional validation and
there's got to be or at least there
should be a reasonable one toone mapping
between the primary vascul and the
actual outline of the Le itself yes so
in some cases like for example in the
case of of of of maple here it is not so
far away um in other cases we are very
far because actually we are assuming
here that if well if from what I
described is kind of um evident that
that we limited
to nonre non reticulate vascular systems
so open vascular systems we don't have
loops but well Loops are well very
prominent feature of many many leaves
and so we so we don't have it there is
some rationale for this according to
scarpella model
of venation formation even in is the
case of when we have loops in a leaf
veins start in the way which are
described but a little bit later on this
connection between convergence point and
and actual base is and vein is is is
well disappears and a vein is being
formed so even in the case of leaves
which have loops
initial process is such as I
described or seems to be and nobody
knows
how actually well looped um um vation
systems are are created so we spent
considerable amount of time and and well
I I have another talk about well V PS
well specifically and we have we can
create some kind of of loops and it was
already part of the first model of
mesons that he had some kind of Loops
produced in in his model of vascular P
information but none of these models
actually is very robust or or looks like
very much like real thing so I would say
that well if if we have the situation
that vasculature if which is formed
initially persists to later forms rather
than creating
close reorganizing itself into Clos
Loops then if well we can see reasonable
correspondence between our vascular
systems and and reality but when Loops
are formed then then we don't and I
would like to at some moment to have
this well um moment of of of
Illumination and finding oh so this is
how Loops are formed but it didn't
happen
yet okay okay one more question oh
there's a lot of
questions okay so how it seems like you
can match the final form of the model to
quite well but how closely does this
match the developmental series like
halfway through through the simulation
if you stop it does it look like the Le
halfway
through yeah so if in the case of
arabidopsis it looks actually um okay we
we if as I mentioned basically we are
just assuming that that there's some
pattern of of of growth but there is
actually a sequence of emergence of
serration and our model reproduces this
this sequence correctly and so it is the
case in well in the case of kardam
however in the case of kardam our model
is actually describing correctly the
early phases and not the later ones and
the reason for this is that
actually in the case of um kadam you can
see this long sinin segments of Reis and
pules and if and actually it is not
clear if at all what factor create this
kind of very this kind of linear organs
so this is this is a good question and
people are looking for what gen can be
and and well one day there is some
candidate another day day is improved so
we assumed that there is something there
if but it has to do with no but no by
itself is not sufficient so so this is
an example where we we can
actually sort of simulate development of
younger forms but we cannot go further
away way and then actually there is well
lot of things which are related to the
fact that in many leaves especially in
trees leaves are developing initially in
a form which is folded so well the
question is to what extent the fact that
it is folded and within a bat which
provides constraints May provide an well
important developmental cues so if so
this is a factor to which to some extent
we have we have been looking at and some
other people have been looking at as
well but if it's the model which I have
shown it here this has not been
integrated so I would say that this is
that in some cases we can capture
this let's
take this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu