this is a production of cornell
university
well thank you all for being here today
i'm excited to
talk about what i've been doing the past
two years
it's definitely flown by
um so
just as an introduction to this topic
dawn mentioned that i had spent some
time at the birmingham botanical gardens
and
working in their native plant
collection
i really developed some interests that
were instrumental in
developing this topic public gardens
addressing environmental issues through
the use of native plants
so native plants have existed for
millennia have evolved
with their environments and have become
increasingly popular in the cultivated
landscape
for the purposes of this research a
native plant is one that occurs
naturally in a particular region state
ecosystem and habit without
direct or indirect human action
and to provide a context for this study
i am studying native plants in public
gardens
which are living museums mission-based
institutions which maintain
plant collections and plant records by a
professional staff and are open to the
public
the study of native plants are important
to botanical gardens because they serve
missions including displaying
biodiversity beauty and history
so when i began this study i started
questioning why native plants were
increasing in use
and one of my observation was that
they were being used to address
environmental issues such as food for
wildlife
a reduction in the use of chemical
pesticides fertilizers and water when
planted in their natural habitats
preventing the spread spread of alien
invasive plants contributing to
phytoremediation efforts addressing
climate change
and increasing ecosystem biodiversity
they also are valued for their aesthetic
beauty and regional sense of place
my research objectives for this study
are to understand how public gardens are
using native plants throughout their
gardens and program offerings what the
motivations are for doing so
and if they're addressing environmental
issues
native plants are supported by research
but i wanted to know what motivates
public gardens for using them
so i chose four u.s botanical gardens
based on preliminary interviews their
prominence in the field
and their collections policies i
conducted two to three phone interviews
to maintain consistency with leadership
staff of each garden including the
executive director director of
horticulture and director of education
when applicable
these interviews were followed up by
site visits when i had previously if i
had previously not visited the garden
and i conducted follow-up interviews
based on the need in the writing process
so now i'm just going to go through each
site
first site was the lady bird johnson
wildflower center which is located in
austin texas and it was created through
the vision of lady bird johnson and
actress helen hayes
their mission serves to focus their
displays in education around native
plants of the state of texas
the second site is new england
wildflower society's living museum
garden in the woods
it was founded and designed by will
curtis and they display native plants of
the new england region
education at garden in the woods centers
around engaging visitors to gain an
interest in using native plants
the third site was the blowdell reserve
located on bainbridge island washington
it was created through the inspiration
of prince blodel and his wife with the
mission of providing a tranquil visitor
experience
this series of landscapes spans over 150
acres and is picturesque of the pacific
northwest
the final site was the birmingham
botanical gardens which is unique to
this study and
it offers a variety of collections for
visitors to experience
including two gardens of nature which
focus on the display and education of
native plants
the collections were made possible by
donations of money and volunteer hours
by key individuals
so now i'll tell you a little bit about
what i found in the form of key themes
differences challenges successes and
practical implications from the study
so the first theme was the use of native
plants throughout the gardens and
program areas
as pictured here
native plants permeate throughout the
education and displays at the wildflower
center and at garden in the woods
while their styles vary at both of these
gardens teaching people to understand
appreciate and use the regional native
flora is in a sustainable manner is
central to the organizational goals
the use of native plants at the bledel
reserve is focused on providing a
tranquil experience
currently they do not have a formal
education program
at the birmingham botanical gardens
native plants are displayed in two areas
focusing on the biodiversity the state
has to offer
the barber alabama woodlands displays
mainly native trees and serves as the
hub of native plant education for
children
the call wild flower garden was
developed from an old stone quarry from
the works progress progress
administration and is pictured here
and displays herbaceous native plants
placing a special focus on those of wild
provenance in alabama
while native plants are not central to
their mission at the birmingham
botanical gardens they do offer
educational programming for all ages
that encourages a deeper engagement with
native plants
a second
theme was the motivation behind the use
of native plants
key figures played a role in
establishing each garden or collection
within the garden in each case of this
study
beyond that the key figures lady bird
johnson will curtis and princess bluedel
respectively at the wildflower center
garden in the woods and the lodel
reserve
were all influential in establishing a
mission that was instrumental in
determining the plant collections
policies at these gardens
a third theme was the motivation for
using native plants for environmental
purposes
each garden in this study emphasized
using native plants for a conservation
purpose
thus promoting an awareness and in the
case of the wildflower center and garden
in the woods the use and further
conservation of native plants
garden in the woods
further has
a display of rare and endangered native
plants
gardens also display native plants in
order to enhance their natural world so
as to bridge visitors to it
a couple of examples are
public gardens providing a place for
visitors to see
the effects of climate change on plants
and to see solutions on how to address
this issue
in the same way they are using native
plants in their natural habitats to
illustrate the reduction of water and
chemical inputs
some collections at the wildflower
center and garden the woods specifically
were established to address
environmental issues through their
research efforts
research areas included native plant
propagation carbon sequestration with
native grasses of texas
green roof composition
alternative turf mixes water runoff and
others
in the future each garden in the study
is increasing efforts to reduce their
environmental impact
another trend that arose in this study
was the focus of reaching three specific
audience groups
professionals in the lands in landscape
architecture architecture design
and contracting
young families and singles in their 20s
and 30s
by creating various educational programs
workshops and garden events towards
these different groups they hope to
garner their interests and further their
missions
there were two key differences between
the gardens in this study
the first difference was the specific
environmental issues that were addressed
because each garden resides in a
different climate zone in the u.s each
garden focuses on a different issue
for example the blue dell reserve in
washington state enjoys regular rainfall
however they are continually focused on
maintaining clean water sources
the wildflower center in central texas
places a major focus on water
conservation as they constantly face
drought
another major difference was in the
educational programs
offered
the bledel reserve was the only garden
in the study lacking a formal education
program although they do offer informal
programs such as walks and tours
education is completely focused on
native plants at the wildflower center
and garden in the woods
and recently the birmingham botanical
gardens
joined in efforts as all three of these
gardens offer a native plant certificate
program
these certificates are awarded
to participants through their completion
of required and elective courses field
trips
and volunteer service
each garden also experience exceptional
success in various ways of using native
plants
the three pictured here are ways that
gardens are disseminating information on
native plants
the native plant database on the
wildflower center's website is
internationally accessed and in last
year alone received 5 million hits
the recently launched certificate in
native plant studies at the birmingham
botanical gardens has had an
overwhelming success
in that their
response rate
and that they have had to create more
classroom space to meet the demand and
they have enjoyed an unexpected
revenue generated
the recent launch of new england
wildflower society's go botany program
a computer bit is a computer-based
broker program that is used to
facilitate education and displays in a
variety of settings and according to
staff is in high demand
success of the bloodell reserve comes in
the form of grant funding for
restoration programs which have
continually increased over the past two
and a half years
staff members also know the anecdotal
feedback from visitors
the key each garden
also faces challenges that affect their
displays and educational efforts of
native plants
one of these is managing invasive plants
today 1.4 trillion dollars or 5 percent
of the global economy is spent managing
invasive species
while historically public gardens may
have played a role in bringing invasive
plants in through plant exploration they
are recognizing their damaging effects
and costs associated with them and are
working to prevent their future
developments
other challenges included caring for a
large space with limited staff and
budgets
and overcoming the general lack of
knowledge of the value and importance of
native plants
just to be clear katie texas blue
bonnets are not an invasive
yes yes
that's a pretty picture to look at
thank you for pointing that out
using native plants in public gardens as
presented in the study culminates into a
group of practical implications
these are intended to build the success
of other gardens use of native plants
and how they use them to address
environmental issues
these include establishing expected
outcomes in their use
using them in a way that continues the
design of the garden
using their connection with native with
animals to bring in younger audiences
using them throughout the collection
instead of in individual collections
considering the environmental effects of
the design process
and to look at other organizations for
guides as creating successful displays
and educational programs
i conducted this study just to discover
how public gardens are using native
plants and if a main motivation is to
address environmental issues
i found that these gardens are using
native plants in diverse ways to not
only address environmental issues but
also to demonstrate that their value
goes beyond their positive environmental
roles
these gardens are able to display their
beauty encouraging and understanding and
appreciation of native plants
and thus furthering their use
so i'd like to acknowledge my committee
and cornell plantations for funding and
support throughout the process and the
other fellows in the program
yes okay did any of the places you
visited express a challenge of sourcing
their native plants such as propagating
them or finding them from commercial
suppliers and how did they address that
challenge
no they didn't because
all gardens have their own nurseries
that
it it really didn't come up
but
i think they're all um
some of them are wild collecting
seeds and
no it didn't come up in the interviews
at all actually
so
i think they're trying to actually
provide sources for people in their
community that do have challenges with
that
it's done both the blue dell reserve and
the birmingham botanical gardens where
it's a mixture of native plant displays
and non-natives
are the horticultures
taking measures in the
non-native displays to make sure that
they're not introducing invasives that
could migrate
into the native displays
i think that where that comes up is more
at the birmingham botanical gardens
the barber alabama woodlands that i
mentioned is
probably 20 feet from their japanese
garden
and the japanese garden does have
invasive plants so they are constantly
trying to pull those out
and that is something that they just
recognize as a challenge and it's
something that they have to do
um
at the blue dell reserve because
everything grows so fast
invasives are always a major challenge
and
the restoration programs
that
they are implementing
are really helping to address that
does that answer your question okay
yeah is there any external push
for
more more use of native plants at public
gardens generally speaking i know um
like chicago botanic garden is involved
in the
end of a plant like the seeds for
success program and things like that
so did you
get any response from the folks who
interviewed about external pressure
um
i think they are they're not sensing the
pressure but they are wanting to reach
out um the groups so these certificate
programs that three of the gardens have
they are really trying to reach
people in the industries like landscape
architecture
the
to encourage green building practices
and establishing plants in the correct
habitats
so i i think it's the pressure is more
than reaching out to people and not
they're not getting that from people
outside
um does that make sense
yes
so
i think a lot of the gardens in the
study have seen the growth but they
haven't specifically been tracking it
and that is something that i recommend
for future research to
really see what the impacts are in
numbers
this has been a production of cornell
university on the web at cornell.edu
you