this is a production of Cornell
University
thanks Megan and I'm really glad to be
here a little bit of a step
down campus from my previous home and
natural resources and across campus from
the lab of ornithology and I'm going to
be talking a little bit about work I've
done in both places over the past eight
to ten years or so largely focused on
keeping an eye towards effective and
intentional design of collaborative
research Endeavors that engage both
scientists and members of the public
and to start out I really just want to
illustrate this with a story and this is
a story of one of the scientists I
interviewed as part of my dissertation
research
his name is Jay Nichols he's a
researcher based at the California
Academy of Sciences
but he began researching the severely
endangered black sea turtle as an
undergraduate and graduate student in
the 1980s and at that point the turtle's
decline was really severe in part due to
overfishing and where Jay was doing his
research in Mexico turtle fishing had
actually just been declared illegal
so there was really basic research that
was needed on the turtles into where
they were how many were left what
threats were facing them what they were
eating where they might be found
and he did find success in answering
those questions
but in doing so he reflected to me as
part of my dissertation work
that the idea that you collect data and
I'm quoting him here and then use those
data to manage a species at risk or an
ecosystem at risk makes sense
but he went on to say
I was realizing that that's certainly
not enough and not just not enough but
the connection between the science and
the conservation action is pretty weak
he said something else needed to happen
now for Jay that something else began
through partnering with fishermen with
those very people in communities who by
the fate of a changing law could be
referred to as Turtle poachers but they
were Turtle hunters in communities in
Baja who had boats who knew how and
where to find the turtles and whose
cultural heritage and identity were
really linked to those Turtle
populations and some could say to their
survival
so these Partnerships that Jay began to
build with the communities with these
individuals grew into a network over a
course of a number of years a network
called Grupo torchigero which now
conducts regular monthly monitoring of
turtle populations
and these um these monitoring
initiatives carried out by local
communities now form the basis of
scientific data that collaborating
scientists can access and have used to
publish papers
they've used to leverage those data into
conservation action
and communities have begun hosting sea
turtle festivals and education events
and all of this together has
precipitated changes in harvesting and
management practices and the gradual
recovery of the sea turtle populations
so it's really difficult to draw a
causal connection between the work that
Jay has done with these communities and
with these individuals and the slow
start of a recovery of these Turtle
populations but nonetheless
something has happened here
that has
caused a change
and the work that I've been involved in
over the past eight to ten years at the
lab of ornithology has been looking at
what potentials there are for change
through Partnerships with the public
towards conservation among other
potential outcomes and what those
elements and drivers of change might be
some of the things that have been
complicating looking into this is that
these initiatives that involve the
public in scientific research have
happened in many different ways in many
different places and growing out of
traditions that haven't had much of a
conversation with one another about how
this work might be done and done well
and done intentionally to achieve
desired results
and so to look at what's successful
about these Partnerships sort of
requires defining a space and defining a
landscape of what it is that we want to
investigate and then what's shared about
those things and where we also might
identify critical differences that can
help us understand how these
Partnerships work
and so
I want to talk for a second about
terminology just very briefly because in
the opening and in the title of this
talk it was proposed that the term to
describe these Partnerships is public
participation in scientific research and
that was a term that we I was part of a
group that coined a number of years back
to acknowledge that although the lab of
ornithology does something called
citizen science
there was also research happening in
context where it's called volunteer
monitoring
Pro-Am Partnerships
community-based forestry that all shared
similar um
similar characteristics however
even though we coined that term public
participation in scientific research
you're going to hear me today default to
using the term citizen science and this
is largely because
the community has come around to
sharing an appreciation for this term
there are clearly some critiques that we
could make of this term and how it's
used but um the term has now found its
way even into the Oxford English
Dictionary and so while I think it can
be pedantic to share a dictionary
definition of a term in an academic talk
I'm putting it up here not so much
because I'm using that definition but
because it's actually in the dictionary
which is a huge
step in saying that this is a thing that
exists a phenomenon that's worthy of
um of attention and it's actually a
decent definition scientific work
undertaken by members of the public
often not always often in collaboration
with or under the direction of
professional scientists and scientific
institutions Okay so
citizen science
what is it good for let's just start
there
when done well
citizen science can give scientists
access to data that are otherwise
unfeasible to collect and that can
result in significant new scientific
insights such as
the landscape scale insights into bird
population trends that are modeled here
through data collected and shared by
amateur bird observers through the lab
of ornithology's eBird project
so citizen science is about data
collection
but citizen science by its very nature
is also about experiences and it results
in experiences for The Observers that
are taking part in that project and this
is a photo of Sherman's Creek a
watershed in south central Pennsylvania
where residents in the 1990s began
collecting Baseline water quality data
in the Watershed in response to planned
development that threatened this
resource
so this was a community that already
knew this Watershed intimately it ran
through their backyards it ran through
their communities but through
Partnerships with Scientists at
Dickinson College they and through the
process of data collection they came to
know that resource also scientifically
and they use those experiences and those
data to successfully ban the proposed
power plant in their neighborhood
science has a lot of essential to affect
quite a few different outcomes
and taken together the opportunity to
impact both science and learning
seems to offer powerful possibilities
for conservation action
and in fact back in 2009 when at the lab
of ornithology we did a quick survey of
practitioners of Citizen science people
who are running and managing citizen
science projects and ask them what their
goals were we found that they were
really pretty evenly split between goals
for science goals for education and
Outreach and goals for let's just say
conservation stewardship or or changing
Behavior somehow making an impact on the
environment
but we know that achieving any one of
these goals any one of these results
through citizen science or through
science itself requires really careful
and intentional work and planning for
any given project
and if we reflect for just a moment on
the turtle research example that I
mentioned from Jay Nichols
I'd like to suggest that
that J success may be due in a large
part
because he recognizes that conservation
and conservation action doesn't just
look and feel like this
like going out
and uh observing the turtles but
conservation action
is really a socially embedded
process
and whether we want to save the world or
a single species no matter how rigorous
or compelling the research itself no
matter how impactful the learning for
the individuals who take part
that science and that learning is
embedded and surrounded by a social
context of people and values and budgets
and priorities that also influences
decisions when it comes to conservation
and change
so citizen science
may be and we suggest can be a powerful
tool in these settings because it can
engage both the scientific and the
social aspects of conservation questions
um
but how can we
how can we make sure
that we think carefully about how to do
both of those things well both the
social engagement and the science
so this is coming back to uh research
that I started with colleagues with the
lab of ornithology and a number of other
different institutions back in 2009 2010
recognizing that many practitioners had
goals that fell into three categories
these are articulated slightly
differently here
but three categories related to outcomes
for science outcomes for individuals we
can say learning here and outcomes for
social ecological systems conservation
stewardship behaviors
we started looking at the way
participation might be handled and this
research started in the context of
informal Science Education so there was
an eye particularly towards the outcomes
for individuals here but recognizing
that all of these other things also fell
into the mix
and through research that was funded by
the center for the advancement of
informal Science Education
um we looked at a number of case studies
of National Science Foundation funded
citizen science projects to try and
relate participation and understand how
that public participation in scientific
research
might influence
all of these things and through that
work and some work that I'll talk about
in a in a moment
we came to understand
that that participation
around that participation it was
important to understand
two aspects both the degree of public
participation in the process of research
and also the quality of that
participation
and let me start with degree
so degree is is a fairly simple concept
a question of who participates and in
what or the depth of public involvement
in the research process and so through
the case report for NSF
we set up a rubric assuming if we if we
will if you want to accept that the
research process of doing science
involves all of these steps and people
can argue that you can articulate this
in different ways but for the purposes
of these of This research
um
we we know that science starts with
defining a question or an issue
gathering information developing
explanations collecting data analyzing
data interpreting results and asking you
questions and generally scientists
conduct this whole process themselves
but at times the public can be invited
to engage in different steps
most uh of the projects that the lab of
ornithology runs for example involve the
public at this level collecting samples
are of in the case of birds making
observations and sharing those
observations with Scientists but there
are some cases out there where
individuals can engage in a project in a
little bit more of a deeper way and in
fact even in some cases where they're
engaged in the entire research process
the Sherman's Creek example that I
mentioned earlier the community was
facilitated by researchers at Dickinson
College in
defining their own question and the
protocols and all the way through
interpreting the data and using those
data to make change in their communities
so in the case report
we propose the terms for these Styles
these approaches to participation is
contributory collaborative and
co-created
I wouldn't concern yourselves with those
terms terribly much except that I'm
going to use them in the graph that
follows to illustrate the kinds of
outcomes that we were starting to see
associated with each approach now I have
to say that data on the outcomes of
these Partnerships are really limited
there's not a lot of research that's
been done particularly into the learning
outcomes let alone the conservation
outcomes of Citizen science projects
particularly any that can draw clear
causal connections but those data that
are available really were starting to
suggest to us that those contributory
projects those where
participants were involved at the level
of collecting data through a protocol
designed by scientists where scientists
were using and analyzing those data to
answer a scientific question we're
really particularly well suited as one
might expect to be providing data for
good rigorous peer-reviewed
Publications
but those that seem to be having the
greatest impact on public learning and
on conservation action fell more in this
category now that's not to say that
these other outcomes didn't happen
through these other approaches to
participation it's just that it may be
more difficult or fewer data were
available
and again this was largely coming from
research that was
focused on understanding the informal
Science Education outcomes
but it came out at a time that several
other Publications were appearing with
very similar typologies of participation
for example Finn Danielson out of the
monitoring matters Network in Copenhagen
articulated very similar categories of
participation using different terms and
reviewed over a hundred
participatory monitoring research
initiatives around the globe and came up
with very similar results those where
the public were largely involved in
collecting data yielded precise and
accurate data however decision making
was slower there was lower potential for
influencing the capacity of he was
looking at stakeholders in the
decision-making process
with the flip side on the co-created
style of Engagement with higher
potential for prompt decision making and
state colder capacities however
expectations for data precision and
accuracy might be a little bit lower
depending on how that was handled
important ly however Danielson and
colleagues pointed out that this was an
area where you had to think not just
about the degree of public participation
but also about the quality of
participation
so while the degree of participation is
fairly easy to quantify quality is more
subjective and context relevant having
to do with things along the lines of
trust and fairness and credibility
and Danielson and others and some of my
work published in ecology and Society
draws on participation Theory where
there's a real rich and deep literature
that looks at
assumptions which would be easy to make
looking at the implications of the
degree of participation it really
challenges assumptions that more
participation is better participation
and really forces the question of asking
whose interests are being served and to
what end and also how those interests
are balanced in the design of a project
and I just want to give you two brief
examples where you can think there might
be some disparity between the degree of
participation and the quality of
participation and here I'm going to call
on our eBird project again where the
data collection happens at such a large
Geographic scale that it would seem to
minimize
project leaders ability to impact the
experiences of the volunteers in any
meaningful way
and that can in fact be difficult to do
when the geographic scale is so huge the
project approach that makes the most
sense is that contributory approach you
ask a lot of people to share a little
bit of data and it all adds up and makes
a big difference
but what about the experience and the
quality of participation
well just as one example I want to
hearken back to the early days of eBird
when participation in the project itself
was really sort of stumbling along in
the early 2000s the first few years of
the project
where even though we had leveraged the
support of a high-profile marketer to
get the word out about Ebert in all the
right journals to tell people to share
their brains with science contribute
your data and help make a difference to
Scientific researchers at the Cornell
lab of ornithology nothing happens
but
in about 2006 with the launch of what at
that time was called eBird 2.0 a
critical shift was made in the way the
project was rolled out and talked about
with a recognition that the birders who
were out there making those high quality
observations
sure what the scientists were going to
do with those data but
they love a place where they could
archive their life lists
and once we started marketing eBird as a
service once we considered the quality
of the participation for those
volunteers what they would get out of it
why they would want to take part
observations and contributions really
skyrocketed
this is another really quick example of
a project that unfortunately has folded
in the the past number of years in
Canada there was a nationwide set of
protocols that really asked people to
make basic observations of something of
Interest plants ice out frogs
and then Engage The Local communities in
in different areas in asking questions
about what they were concerned about in
their in their environment in their
communities
um and invited them to use some of these
protocols to help address those concerns
and there's a lot that could be talked
about here but I want to point out that
what I found most compelling one of the
things that I found most compelling
about this project at the time when they
were publishing was that where most
projects in the U.S were focused on data
quality High Precision accurate data and
could citizen science do this
they were asking this project was asking
are those data timely are they
accessible to the people who need them
are they relevant in the communities
where they can make a difference and are
they ultimately useful
so how can we start a conversation about
these kinds of qualities with the people
who are engaged in um
citizen science and public participation
in scientific research to better
understand the kinds of data and the
kinds of experiences and the kinds of
participation that can make a difference
when it comes to conservation
so just briefly I'm going to show you a
common framework that we've articulated
for the design of Citizen science
projects and I don't want to belabor
this but I do want to point out that a
common logic model can help us think
about how and why we design projects to
get to particular outcomes and that
through citizen science what we're
suggesting right now is that it really
Demands a consideration of both
scientific interests and public interest
at the outset in identifying the
question or issue to be addressed and
that this kind of conversation will
influence how the research protocols and
trainings are developed and the kinds of
experiences that are had by
volunteers as well as the kinds of
observations that they're going to make
and we have already talked about how
that can yield a wide range of different
kinds of outcomes
and through this framework we can start
to better understand how those inputs
can affect the outcomes
but here's where I want to focus in a
little bit more on conservation itself
as a concept
and this is because
um in in the field of conservation
there's more focused attention in the
past number of years on
um conservation evaluation how do we
know that we're achieving the desired
goals for conservation and margulis and
colleagues
um in that field have really started to
push people to I more clearly identify
conservation targets and articulate when
you say you want to affect conservation
what is it very specifically that you
want to change and how do you think
you're going to get there through the
work that you're doing
so they're asking people to articulate
both conservation targets and Pathways
and here's a really you know loose
example we can say that through citizen
science we're going to collect data
that's going to influence science and
that somehow that's going to affect
conservation we need we know we need to
do better than that
um
and so what are the theories that we
have around how citizen science very
specifically how citizen science might
be making a difference for a particular
conservation targets
and here's where I want to share a
little snapshot of some of the research
I've done through my dissertation
research where I've talked to scientists
about the work that they've done in
projects that they've committed their
careers to in many cases
um
because this is difficult work
engaging the public really is not easy
and it's risky and so what significance
and potential might scientists be seeing
that would really influence their
commitment
to Citizen science to weather their
critiques and pursue this difficult work
I mentioned that I talked to scientists
I did in-depth narrative interviews with
nine individuals who are in many cases
high profile scientist Terry Rood is a
Nobel Laureate for her work with the
ipcc on climate change
and I asked them
in in a lot of different ways why it was
that they were doing what they were
doing and how it was that their science
that they're citizen science worked and
what it was that they were affecting and
not to get into the details here but
what I heard from them were many
different conservation targets a wide
diversity of conservation targets that
fell into categories for science yes
they were doing this because they needed
the science they needed the data but
because they also saw potentials for
changing the experiences of individuals
and because they saw potentials for
changing conservation
and so drawing on the work of margulis
and all at all to identify conservation
targets and also identify Pathways to
those targets I worked with the
narratives of these scientists to start
to look at how their experiences were
suggesting that their work could affect
their desired conservation outcomes now
I do want to point out that I'm not
suggesting that this is actually how it
works but how they saw it work there's a
lot more research that needs to be done
to see if these pathways are actually
successful but I want to share just two
of them with you and if these two that
I've circled here one is from Jay
Nichols who I mentioned earlier
and here I'll just share a quote from
his interview he said
following the excerpt that I that I
shared earlier you can't just create the
knowledge and hand it off and just
expect action from the authorities here
he's talking about management agencies
because they just don't have the
capacity to do that
if we keep expecting them to take the
reports and the data and turn it into
action it's kind of a ridiculous dream
and it's been a bit of a dream all along
I think it's pretty clear to people that
the way it's going to work is for people
to use this knowledge themselves and
create movement or action or change or
whatever it is that they're after so
this is what Jay saw as the potential
for citizen science in part because of a
practical theory that was telling him
that the data and the management
agencies weren't going to do it
and the pathway that he articulated
related to Citizen science was this the
community members by being involved in
data collection were creating knowledge
that they themselves had access to
and that by defining goals related to
that knowledge for sea turtle protection
they would take knowledge based on that
science
to create change now I did mention that
I can't say that this is actually the
way it's happening but I can say that
it's not unfounded Jay's work has
resulted in communities making change in
Marine protected areas where they are
residents and so there's reason to
really consider that this level of
Engagement can result in actual use of
knowledge use of Science and
science-based action for management
so I just want to share another
Pathway to illustrate a different kind
of conservation change and this is from
Bill McShay Bill's a landscape ecologist
based at the Smithsonian conservation
Biology Institute in Northern Virginia
where he's done work to understand
mammal populations and their influence
on on grasslands throughout Northern
Virginia and in other ecosystems around
the world
in Northern Virginia he said though he
said to me if you really want to do
conservation on that ecosystem you've
got to be working with private
landowners remember this is Northern
Virginia most of the landscape in that
area that's grassland is held um by by
private individuals
he went on to say and their antsy about
government people and official workers
they seem to be much more receptive to
citizens to the general public to the
birding Club they seem to like that
better than the government's going to
send a team of people onto your land to
see what you've got so it seems to work
best and it in this case was Bill
working with volunteers to go on to
these private lands to do Point counts
of bird populations to do butterfly
monitoring surveys and while they were
there
um
here's the pathway that bill saw as
happening between that interaction so
this is the point he wants to get to
that the landowners Implement grassland
restoration practices and here's how he
saw it happening he needed to conduct
surveys
the private landowners allow access to
Citizen volunteers not to the government
people but to the citizen volunteers and
while they're there the landowners talk
to them they ask them what they're doing
why are they doing it and that
information that informal sharing of
information both the science and the
context of conservation has more of an
impact than visits from state employees
resulting in Bill theorizes and in some
cases has seen
changes in their actual management of
their lands
so
these are just a few possibilities that
really suggest
that attention to the social dimension
of
um
citizen science a public participation
in scientific research attention to the
public interests to the degree and the
quality of participation as well as the
scientific needs not instead of but as
well as the scientific needs can be a
step towards conservation and
importantly a step that is commensurate
with the science and not in opposition
to it
and I'd like to suggest that these
insights can invite us to think both
more critically and more expansively
about Concepts like public engagement a
concept that's a key mission of our own
Institution
um
and public engagement can mean many
things to many different people
it can mean
um
research that is shared with the public
scientific knowledge that's disseminated
to the public but I'd also like to
suggest that public engagement can
effectively involve inviting
participants to be part of the research
process
um
this does have to be done carefully it
does have to be done where it's
appropriate to do so not all science is
appropriate for citizen science or for
public engagement but in places where it
is and where there's a potential for
that to have an impact
the evidence is suggesting to us that
more than just the science must be
considered if we are to get to
conservation action through that
research
and I want to wrap up with something
that may seem to be at first like a
little bit of a non-sequitur
and that is that back in 2011 I I helped
convene a 60 person
workshop at the American Museum of
Natural History
which was examining citizen science and
conservation called engaging and
learning for conservation through public
participation in scientific research and
there were a lot of great insights that
came out of that event as to what the
potential of Citizen science was and how
to work together
but through evaluation we also gained
some insights into the practitioner
Community themselves and here's one that
I want to share just because it was so
telling in its honesty and this was
shared by presumably a scientist who was
in attendance there a conservation
scientist Anonymous said even though it
makes me uncomfortable
after this event I'm thinking about ways
to communicate and interact on a regular
and frequent basis with the Science
Education community
and one of the reasons that I'm sharing
this is that if we if we have a hard
time interacting with our colleagues
across campus
that that can make it even more
difficult and daunting to think about
interacting with the public effectively
and so I'd like to suggest that as this
conversation about public participation
in scientific research grows
and as the field expands which it is
um that it demands that we step outside
of our comfort zones not just with the
public but with our colleagues and
making this a truly interdisciplinary
practice because both Jay and Bill and
the other scientists that I interviewed
for my research they're not working in a
vacuum they're not working alone they're
working with colleagues to share
insights as to how to effectively engage
the public
in new and and potentially different
ways to do both science and
conservation
as as an aside just before I close with
a few questions I will note if anybody's
interested in this opportunity to engage
across disciplines and engage with other
colleagues who are involved in public
participation in scientific research
there's a conference being held in San
Jose a pre-conference of the aaas annual
meeting on citizen science and our call
for proposals has just closed
unfortunately but we did receive over
400 proposals for talks at that
conference so it's shaping up to be a
really
important event and well attended
so I actually want to close with some
questions that were um that were offered
by Megan and I'm going to put her on the
spot here because when we were
corresponding in advance of of my coming
here to give this talk she was
suggesting some questions that really
resonated with thinking that I have and
asking ourselves as a community
um
how might we do things like develop
opportunities where appropriate
for public participation in scientific
research how can we consider both the
science and the conservation
possibilities of Citizen science
and lastly and this I think is maybe one
of the most important things as this
field grows and people step into this
practice how can both students and
faculty be supported in engaging
thoughtfully and effectively in a
practice that can go against some of the
traditions and expectations particularly
in academic departments to do things in
new and different ways to achieve the
results that presumably we all want to
achieve for conservation through our
science so I will close there
thanks
yeah absolutely I'm going to repeat the
question just for the benefit of Geneva
and the camera why conservation aren't
there other potential outcomes that are
just as relevant and just as engaging
did I get that right and that's that's a
great question and I really should have
given a little bit more context in the
beginning that this is my personal bias
I was doing my research largely in
relationship to informal Science
Education and conservation but the field
of Citizen science is much much broader
in fact there is work now coming into
conversation under the term citizen
science and it's really important to
acknowledge that that term citizen
science is now being used to understand
activities that haven't always fallen
under that terminology but there's
research now that's being discussed
under that term in public health
for example certainly a long history in
astronomy research in water quality
monitoring so conservation yes is one
you're right very um timely topical
um point of conversation it happens to
be an area and we can talk about why
this might be but an area where a large
large number of Citizen science projects
have been focused and increasingly
citizen science is now showing up in or
moving into areas like
microbiology
neurobiology even but that's that's
fairly recent but yeah conservation is
one action-oriented and social
scientific
just one example of change
yeah that's a great question
um that Don asks about uh the have there
been any studies to corroborate the
accuracy of of Citizen science data
um there's I'll I'll offer two answers
to that one is yes hundreds but the
other answer is the only study that
matters
is the one that you do for your project
because what matters is the design of a
given project does it meet the goals
that you set out for your project
whatever those might be now a core need
of that is that citizen science is
science there are some things that have
been called citizen science that really
we could make an argument is largely
just education work and the science that
results is secondary
education is important engagement in
science is important but citizen science
really has that core of useful usable
scientific data now the usefulness of
those data may not show up for many
years that's possible
um but the science is important
any given project is going to have to go
through the difficult work of making
sure that their project is designed in
such a way that it can produce those
usable data
but yeah there are there are hundreds of
papers for individual discrete projects
that do show that
yeah that's a great question the
question is does the public have a skew
or a bias towards certain organisms or
topics
and you know one of the
the lab of ornithology I'll say in some
ways was very lucky
in its history with citizen science
because there were a lot of people
already bird watching a lot of Highly
skilled people already bird watching and
our scientists very astutely were able
to capitalize on that there are
certainly other taxa for which it has
been more difficult to design citizen
science projects and some of the reasons
that we started the words the work that
we've done at the lab of ornithology to
look at the practice more broadly of
Citizen science was because we were
getting asked questions by people saying
I want to design eBird for
seahorses for example I want to design
citizen science for
jellyfish and we were realizing that you
can't just take an if you build it they
will come approach to Citizen science
because that's certainly not the case
however there are now projects that are
successfully engaging people in doing
things like
um
folding proteins
there's a project called fold it which
I've just started playing with and I
don't understand
exactly how people get turned on to it
yet but it's it's gamifying it's there's
a learning curve so you really have to
commit to it and yes any project is
going to attract a certain subset of
people who have a particular affinity
for doing a certain thing
um but but projects have been successful
in enticing people to do protein folding
to look at jellyfish to do a wide range
of things and it's the onus is on the
project developers to really find out
what those public interests are and how
you can make your project resonate with
the people you're hoping to involve in
it or vice versa understand where
there's already attention going on to
something that's of interest to you like
with birds and see how you can
capitalize on that interest I will just
caution though that I think you
mentioned something about school
um that some of my early research was on
student science Partnerships and could
students effectively be motivated to
collect accurate data and there's a sort
of one step removed question there about
or assumption about motivation which is
that students when they're in a
classroom are a captive audience yes
they'll be there to take part in the
activities
but the motivation is probably going to
be more along the lines of I'm doing it
because my teacher said so
and yeah she will find some that you
will be able to excite about it who
might not have been excited had they not
been exposed to it through school but
school is not necessarily a guarantee of
some kind of motivation
yeah that's a great question I I didn't
put data in there just because I was
trying to make the extreme results as
visible as possible but I will also say
that that one thing I want to make very
clear is that those were typologies that
were developed just to help us get a
handle on the landscape of what was
happening and no one project is a hard
and fast
contributory project for example or a
co-created project projects can be
designed to offer
primarily a contributory experience or
primarily a co-created experience but
individuals can engage in a project in a
wide range of approaches based on how
engaged they they may choose to be so
for example in the Sherman's Creek
example where the community was engaged
in water quality monitoring there were
some people who really just collected
the data they showed up and they
collected the data and it was a smaller
number of people who did the whole
process of data analysis protocol
development and so forth so those aren't
hard and fast categories the lines are
slippery and blurry between them and it
really was a rubric for trying to draw
some general conclusions that would
allow us to understand the landscape so
um
I that's in a way that's a that's a
Dodge of your question but I hope it
gives you a more helpful answer
okay well our time is up and I want to
thank Dr sir for a fascinating
presentation thank you Jennifer thanks
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu