this is a production of Cornell
University great thank you joh for the
introduction uh thanks for everyone for
being here yeah so I will be going over
the three chapters of my dissertation
today and all of them revolve around the
concept of molecular diversity of soil
organic matter how deep composition
affects it and how that affects its
persistence as you all know soil organic
matter is the fraction of so soil that's
consists of plant or animal tissue in
various stages of
decomposition soil organic matter lends
many physical chemical biological
benefits to soil
function and then another large function
that so organic matter provides is the
ability to retain organic carbon in fact
soils contain three times the amount of
carbon as the
atmosphere and the balance between soil
organic carbon and carbon stored in the
atmosphere as carbon dioxide or methane
is really um dependent upon microbial
respiration of that carbon so this
actually a very old question of what
retains or what what are the controls
that are
um influencing the retention of
carbon so this is such an old question
um one of my favorite papers to go back
to every once in a while and read is
this paper from 1925 by someon Waxman
what is so humus and he asked
this important question which is really
driving question in my re research as
well which is why does a part of organic
matter decompose rapidly and a part only
very slowly he points out the economic
importance of this question at that time
really they're thinking of nutrients and
nitrogen and um the minerals that plants
need to grow for us there's this added
economic importance for climate
change so the current view of how we
understand organic matter
being uh cycled in soils is that there's
this uh Continuum as organic matter is
progressively decomposed it becomes
smaller and smaller along this Continuum
it has the ability to chemically
interact with minerals um through
absorption or dsorption and then also
physically by being occluded or released
from
Aggregates so this process along with
some of the bigger environmental
variables such as temperature moisture
PH soil microbial Community overall
impact the retention time of carbon and
soils more recently though we've been
thinking about some other
processes that affect organic carbon
cycling
and probobly S of the heterogeneity of
soil itself as a control and soil curent
cycling so there's spatial heterogeneity
so the collocation of organic matter
minerals microbes there's temporal
variability and then there's the
molecular diversity so variability and
organic matter
properties of course what I am focusing
on so I Define the diversity as the
number and abundance of distinctly comp
distinctly different compounds in soil
organic matter and being clear that I'm
talking about diversity of molecules and
not diversity of microbes right
now so the big question to my
researchers really does molecular
diversity affect the composition of so
organic matter I hypothesized that as
diversity of molecules um increases we
would have slower rates of decomposition
because the energy return on investment
by microorganisms to use each of these
individual compounds would become
unfavorable they had to make new enzymes
or upregulate new metabolic pathways to
tackle each an individual each you know
new compound that they come in contact
with so that's sort of the step one
hypothesis is that diversity slow
decomposition but that decomposition
itself
might increase molecular
diversity as um microbes add all these
new compounds in there metabolism to the
pool of organic matter it might actually
increase molecular R cell so there's
this feedback loop between decomposition
processes and molecular diversity that I
am also going to try to um
untangle some more Foundation
information how am I measuring and
quantifying molecular diversity this is
you know there are studies that are
looking at they often call it hemo
diversity and those studies are more of
a qualitative and I really wanted to be
quantitative quantifying all of this so
to do that I'm looking at the dissolved
organic matter pool from soil organic
matter and this is where you do a water
extraction you filter at02 microns and
that's the pool of carbon it is actually
the most bioavailable and um usable by
micro the next step is actually identify
those comps and to do that I use
untargeted Canam liquidar master Tre so
lmss where I can then identify the
different compounds based on mass to
charge ratios and retention times so you
match those with known um standard
libraries I use c18 and Hill columns for
polar and non-polar compound
identification this just an example
Spectra where you have the mass charge
on the X AIS your inity on the Y AIS
which from two different soil samples
but each of these different Master
charge ratios could be considered a
unique molecular compound and then it's
height use to calculate the relative
proportion of that compound in your
sample I use three uh big types of
calculation to quantify molecular
diversity and these are really borrowed
from apologists trying to apply them to
molecules so the first one is just
molecular richness and this is just the
number of compounds and this is the most
basic form of the recity
quantification which gives you really no
information about the molecules just the
number and it treats all rare and common
compounds as well one so it's is equally
weighted the next one is an abundance
Spas M diversity equation where then you
take into account the proportion of the
molecules across
samples this so I use Hill numbers when
the Q quotient equals two and this is
synonymous with the Simpson diversity
index but it gives you effective number
of compounds back instead of arbitary
index and this uh favors the common
comps but again it's sort of Laing
information so the next step is to add
information about the molecular
properties so using a tree based
molecular diversity
equation I use R's quadratic
entropy and so the H numbers is a
probability equation ENT equation it's
different in that fact and it also
incorporates a distance Matrix of a
mular property of my choosing so it can
be something like oxidation state or
mass that gives us an idea of maybe how
that molecule deaves in soil system so
just as ecologists want to know the
types of organisms there so you know a
gorilla and a lizard are very different
in an ecosystem and here say lipid and
organic acid might also equally
different we need to know the properties
when we're calculating
diversity I also use the terms Alpha
molecular diversity and beta molecular
diversity and I Define Alpha molecular
diversity as a diversity within one
sample and beta moleular diversity as a
diversity of cross sample cross
treatments
businesses so when I first started my
PhD I a lot of literature literature
review on what did we know about
molecular diversity in natural
ecosystems and really the only um field
of scientist that are working that were
working on quantifying this were Marine
scientists or aquatic systems um
specifically foring di Mar group has a
lot of work around this and it comes one
paper where they did try to
quantify uh diversity in a way that we
did and so this is a marine DM
incubation and so they did molecular
richness molecular abundance and then a
trade diversity equation where they use
the oxidation state of carbon and really
what they found is what we hypothesis
where there be this increase in
diversity initially but then over time
it um plat or declined and then there's
this anyway def in functional
diversity in their system so we wanted
to know so this is a a marine system
with continuous mixing and no minerals
and no plant roots and you know it's all
homogenous so what do we find these St
TR in a soil
system this really where we got to my
first chapter which is really do
ecosystem Properties or U microbial
decomposition affect molecular diversity
so this is really a step one improving
ground um does molecular diversity even
vary across landscape in these very
different
ecosystems and can we measure it too and
quantify it so I used soil samples from
six different
ecosystems that we did as a larger
collection effort with some posto in
johann's lab and I grouped these samples
by vegetation class so dominant
vegetation
class so and soil order they're
representative in in two different ways
and you can see from these photos that
they're very different for one another
and they
grouping I also took samples from the
litter layer down to the SE Horizon so
that I could use soil depth inter
propoxy for duration of decomposition we
know that organic matter found and the C
Horizons is generally older than that
found in the L layer or a Horizons this
is why we could use dep as a prop for
time and I hypothesize that because
micro orms are on really all the action
they're the one they're are going to
have a greater control on organic matter
molecular diversity than the plant
letter inputs themselves especially when
you get down to the SE
Horizon jumping right into the results
here I'm showing um hydrophilic and
hydrophobic compounds identified using
lcms on the Hy of colums and for this
project I actually use negative and
positive mode and either on water and
methanol extracts s about that and most
little thing about these um so this is
molecular richness and a molecular
diversity abundance whole numbers and
then dysfunctional or tra molecularity
equation in Chanel C and depth is on the
on the y axis you see that there's this
decline in this Alpha with uh soil depth
but the most noticeable decline really
is from this litter layer the litter
samples down to your first mineral a
horizon I also want to point out this
very interesting Trend um in the
for the functional diversity with the
hydrophobic compounds I going tuck that
away for another chapter but there's
this in this initial increase and
decrease with dep
there so if I separate these out by
ecosystem and I'm just showing molecular
richness you can see that generally
there's always going to be this decrease
in richness from the litter layer down
to the a horizon but there's variation
once you get to the mineral Horizons and
of course there are a lot of different
properties that soil have that could
cause this and for example the and the
grass a large increase from the B
Horizon to the Horizon and that holds
true for the hydrophobic compound as
well and so we thought you know this
must be some sort of environmental
variable or so property and so I did a
whole bunch of regressions with all the
other properties that we had measured
such as um soil texture Sandell clay
hydroxy attractable oxides iron aluminum
magines um carbon concentrations
nitrogen concentrations watering
capacity we actually found no consistent
and um significant relationships between
any of these properties in our molecular
diversity
indices however we did not measure any
microbial information for this
project so I thought okay if there is
this decrease in molecular diversity and
richness with
Deb then are all of those compounds that
are accumulating the seiz in the same
microbial
products they must be similar across
ecosystems so to try to answer that
question I did an upset plot analysis
and these plots look a little bit more
complicated than they really are so I'll
walk you through uh the different panels
so there's a letter a and b so all the
compounds are separated by
Horizon then I bin them into basically
two different categories one is does
that compound occur in all the compounds
denoted by these black dots or is it
only in one individual e
so the intersection size is the number
of compounds and then the ecosystems are
also have the number of compounds that
are within that individual ecosystem for
that horizon or layer next to and
they're all colored by compation so for
the litter layer there are 471 compound
layers that were shared across all
50 and then by the time you get to uh so
the T SES is our next one here it has
only 40 unique compounds
and the litter layer for
the
that's most notable finding from these
is that by the time you go from the
litter layer to a horizon there's
already a 65% reduction in shared
compound and then once you get to the
Horizon there's only 75% or there's a
75% loss of shared compounds so the L
layer really shares four times the
number of compounds as the subsoil
and in this way so we're losing richness
but we're actually increasing the
similarity across
ecosystems this is further displayed by
a nonmetric conventional scaling plot
just ordinating the uh hydrophilic
compounds and you can see that the liter
layer here these dark green symbols
cluster together really closely whereas
all the mineral samples kind of mismatch
over one another and in fact the
ecosystem P did explain 10% of the
variance but Horizon explain 21% of that
clustering further dri Point home about
the similarity in the sub soils cross
ecosystems um the N
aak the average break index by Horizon
each ecosystem and you can just see that
there are more yellows and oranges OCC
the horiz that just more of the
similarity
across so to summarize this chapter and
really this is a the title pad line of
this paper that came out last summer PN
is that decomposition decreases
molecular diversity and ecosystem
similarity in general we found a
decrease in alha diversity with depth an
increase
diversity with depth though so the
diversity AC cross ecosystems uh
increases and in general there are more
shared compounds in the litter layer
compared to the Sea Horizon meaning
there's probably more sight specific
compounds that microbes are making in
the subsoils compared to what's being
inputed by the the
litter so really this is a study about
molecular diversity across soil depth
for time and time of you know Millennia
long periods of time of
decomposition but really I wanted to
next now like okay what about true time
and and time that I can measure in the
lab and would we find similar Trends
over shorter periods of De competition
time you how long did it take to get to
these
Trends so my next chapter is essentially
that is how does molecular diversity
change over
time and can we identify the microbial
products or the diversity of those
products and how that contributes to
those changes and so to do this um I did
a very simple
I'm calling it a long-term time series
experiment but really it's relatively
short it's only 220 days PhD is only so
long and so I used one microbial
community and one plant litter type and
incubated that for 220 days and
destructively harvested um microcosms at
14 different time
points I then analyzed the de extract
with the ATR ftir and um to and then
from there selected seven time points
then analyze us lpms to quantifi molec
diversity so the more and then the next
layer is then how do I identify
microbial products to do this we um
wanted to try to use an isotope label of
o08 instead of a carbon substrate label
since there's some issues with using a
carbon uh labeled carbon we want use o o
is normally used by microbiologists um
to do stable isotope probing to identify
which microbes are actually present in a
community because all microbes use water
for the most part during their um
metabolism and respiration processes and
they generally take up the oat and add
it into their DNA and then you do the
see what prob figure's active in your
community we wanted to know okay well
can we then use it to know which
compounds the microbes are producing or
oxidizing um or maybe they're in putting
some necromass that has this O8 in it
and we uh submitted a proposal to msil
and got an msil exploratory research
Grant to explore this and try it um so
we I chose two different time points day
six and day 59 to then take a subset of
sample from the me uh
microcosms and added either natural
bonus water or 08 or biotic and a biotic
so it you know Parks out which compounds
are actually being uh produced with the
O and then we did
uh water methanol formal extraction but
I'm going to only be going over the
water extraction results today with for
transform ions resonance Mass
spectometry primarily and again I
hypothesize that because of micro are
the ones you know not only are they
transforming the organic matter by
cleaving all the different plant litter
compounds and you know oxidizing hyding
fermenting everything they're so they're
making all these different metabolites
enzymes product organic so the more
active a microbial population is the
more diversity of compounds you will
have so these are the results from the
lcms uh long-term time series
experiment
and sorry what we can see is that these
Trends actually are very similar to M
profile Trends where duration of
decomposition is on the xais up until
202 days U panel a is molecular richness
the number of compounds we have our
abundance diversity H
numbers and you see these large deines
and richness and diversity in the
beginning of the
decomposition for this project I use a
multivariate molecular trait diversity
equation where I use the nominal
oxidation state of carbon oxygen and
carbon ratios hydrogen and carbon ratios
number of nitrogen uh atoms and Mass all
in one equation to try to get this whole
mole
picture and what we found is that
there's actually instead of an initial
decrease there's initial increase in
molecular trait diversity so diversity
of uh molecular properties is increasing
initially as microbes are decomposing
the
lit I'm a big fan of Breakers
dissimilarity indices so this is showing
again the dissimilarity across time
points and the most notable thing and
you can see it here is that you have
these larger differences from day 28 to
32 so bigger changes in the in the index
bigger changes in color and by the time
you get to day 60 this is really a flat
toil there's not much change happening
see that with the Curve as
well so
the can't tell if that color is bad um
the
O8 results from the FTR if you're
familiar with ftss you're familiar with
these van prevalent
plots these plots have oxygen carbon
ratios on the X AIS and hydrogen carbon
ratios on the y axis these are um
Elemental not mass
ratios I'm showing
the so the top um left plot is the O
isly enriched compounds from J seven and
then on the right is the are the non
isotopically enriched and then the
bottom two panels are
60 these PL each point is an individual
Peak identified with mass spec and then
the coloration of that beak is the
relative abundance across
samples often with uh V prevalence you
use some sort of bridge sort of
uh try to understand the properties of
that molecule and
here there's some different zones so
this one is more these compounds are
more aliphatic these would be more
aromatic mid aromatic you know low mid
High oxygen
regions to the right these are just
calculated bar plot of the molecular
richness of comparing the enriched to
the non-enriched for day seven and day
60 and then also Hill number diversity
and then our molecular trait divers
multivision okay complicated your kind
of explain so the most important thing
you take from this figure well not most
important but the uh most obvious one is
that the non-rich pool had many more
compounds than the enriched pool and I
should note that the the compounds that
these enriched ones they were incubated
for 24 hours so this is a snapshot of
what microbes are producing within a
24-hour time frame at these two
different
heades but non andrich are more Rich
more
diverse not that surprising they're just
kind of the background
but if you look at the the molecular
trait diversity there's actually equal
trait diversity when you're considering
these Peak and these at the early time
point so even though they differ in
number they the trade diversity is just
as
large however by 60 there's a um decline
in trade diversity you can see that
there's some loss of these
aliphatics uh well ala Regent seem to be
lost but the overall
tra diversity between day7 and B 60 does
not differ and if we go back to our our
time series uh plot these two time
points are essentially the same as uh
these on the longer scale and so it's
kind of like we're we're picking up on
maybe the shoulders of trait
diversity for day seven and day 160 we
kind of missed that initial Peak for the
overall
background or also that there maybe
there's a lag where the microorganism
Community starts making uh fewer and
fewer diverse
compounds and then it takes a little
while for that to be shown in your
overall
C okay also looking at what compounds
are being produced and consumed over
these two time points day7 day 60 this
is just a heat map of the different
compounds identified with lcms for day 7
and day 60 this is adjacent to the O8
labeling experiment
the brighter colors mean they're more uh
abundant higher relative
abundance and so what we're seeing here
is that the the sugars and sugar
alcohols at day seven are occurring in
higher
bonuses and then at day 6 there are more
of these organic
acids meaning that perhaps microbes are
you know suing these carbohydrate from
the Fresh plant litter inputs and then
producing a whole bunch of organic
organic acids during their um
metabolism this is just sort of an
overall snapshot of what I think is
happening for this this chapter where as
you introduce microbes to plant
litter there's going to be this initial
de orance during rapid microbial growth
they're going to be consuming all these
different uh simple sugars but they're
producing a wider range of compounds so
this could be they're producing Amino
sugars organic acids IES um etc etc and
that's where you would get this increase
in molecular trait diers you're increase
in the different types of compounds that
you're finding in the full of organic
matter but with no new added plant
litter or you know substrates microbial
growth is going to end ultimately slow
down and then they're going to have to
start recycling some of their own
microbial product and that's where you
would get sort of this U Decline and
molecular treats everything comes back
down to Baseline and microbes then start
producing more more moleculars similar
compounds at this point may just all
micob
products so this was a study for one
plant letter type and one microbial
community and my next question is really
does this hold true for different plant
letter types in different microbial
communities and microbial
diversities so there is an aish
relationship between microbial and
molecular diversity and we've seen it
using uh thiser in 2022 that is
established across different
biomes and a relationship strength is is
varied across biomes but really I wanted
to know okay is this establish
relationship true in with different
plant litter
types and for different microbial
communities so this is my third chapter
type microbial community diversity
molecular diversity
of so to do this I uh used five
different plant litter types these are
from similar Samples used in my first
chapter and then from the same location
where I took the plant letter type I
took the a Horizons Minal a Horizons did
a soil wash to generate a microbial
community and
not so this paper really S L Type and
microbial Unity are synonymous not sort
of dis that
relationship so that's watch then I have
the high M diversity Community which is
you know 10 to zero my stock community
and then we did a Serial dilution of
those communities 10 to the minus 10 to
get this low microb diversity community
and I say we because my undergraduate
Caleb levit and I worked on this for
almost entire semester just getting
these communities together um
was a amazing okay so then the plant
litter that complimentary to that
microbial inoculum was inoculated with
either the high or the low microbial
Community incubated for 150 days and
then at the end of those that incubation
they were uh the DM was analyzed for
mole diversity using ltms again and the
microbial Community was analyzed using
16s r r sequency using the Alum platform
and I hypothesize that again it's more
about microG community structure than it
about where they came from but again
those two are are difficult to
um thankfully um these dilation
treatments had an effect on the endpoint
microbial community so these are the
results from the end of 150 days not the
starting point of the inoc inoculum but
the end of the incubation for microbial
richness microbial diversity and
microbial phenetic
diversity and I am talking about
microbial diversity now and molecular
diversity so I'll try to help you keep
them
separate for microbial more this trait
diversity I'm using a microbial
phylogenetic diversity index using Rous
CTIC entropy again but for this I'm
using the genome size the number of base
pairs the average number of base pairs
per sample and this is try to get
um again an idea of that function of the
microbial community in the soils not
just who's there and how many of them
are there but what are they
doing so there's about a 40% loss in MO
uh microbial richness for for the
ecosystems and then a shrubs is just you
know a Death Valley sample it's very
unique and just kind of a Bugaboo but it
was not affected of richness but it did
uh portion of those individuals was
alter and then we have differences in
col andity as
well just ordinating the
communities um and by litter type and
treatment it's the PCA plot showing how
they cluster and showing that the litter
type
more explains the variance of the
clustering than the D treatment which
did have that but you can notice that
the Del treatment actually brought the
micob communties closer together in
terms of composition
and if you're looking at the soil order
the composition the relative composition
would be generally this loss inalis and
areas L
but compositional um and there's
generally more
single I'm so sorry for
my new
language starting a suite of um linear
regressions so here I'm plotting my
microbial diversity indices on the x
axis against my molecular diversity
indices on the Y
AIS so I have mobial richness molecular
richness have a significant relationship
here R 10 the microbial diversity using
Hill numbers isly related to the
molecular diversity with Hill numbers
and then actually genome size rather
than the diversity equation with genome
size was very strongly related to the
molecular trait diversity so there's
something
about uh micro the microbial community's
uh function that is related to trait
rather than just the number of micos
which is I think more often what people
think about is Rich microbial richness
is related to diversity in
general so to account for the dilution
treatment and the uh litter type
Community type
I did a multi-level correlation analysis
where it takes into account dilution and
going type as random effects into the
model and that just kind of proves the
point that genal size is the most
strongest predictor of molecular trait
diversity and even though this this
interesting Trend where richness is
related to richness and diversity
diversity still holds true but
weaker I noticed something else
different when when I was looking at
these these regressions is that the
non-diluted communities actually appear
to have stronger relationships with each
other um
than with the mo
diversity then the diluted Community if
you look at molecular richness here on
the it actually is correlated to all of
the indices but this relationship with
molecular Origins is greatly
improved same for uh microb diversity
and molecular diversity and then
similarly for genome size the r squ here
is 66 for molecular trait diversity so
there's something happening here that I
find very interesting and I don't know I
don't necessarily have the answer yet
about the disruption caused by my
artificial um dilution to try to get
this bigger range of diversity has
disrupted the microbial Community
functioning
somehow and it could be they're taking
out the you know members of the
community that are involved full
metabolism or thus like kind of the
whole chain disrupts but these are just
final usings but in general genome size
is still the best predictor of molecular
tra diversity for any of
diversity so I'm gonna wrap up a little
bit on this big question of does do
molec diversity influence organic matter
mineralization R that's you know where I
started and I have not explained this
experiment yet uh but at the end of the
incubations for my second and my third
chapter I saved the Doom from those end
points when I sent it off for alus
analysis I held him back and then took
that DM and added it into a new
microcosm carbon normalized across each
microcosm uh which had you know clean
sand and then added one micr Community
to that microcosm and then measured
respiration over the next 10 days so
this is cumulative respiration on the Y
AIS and then either molecular richness
my molecular abundance diversity or
trait diversity on the X on the top
panels and then molecular properties on
the um bottom panel so the oxidation
state of carbon molecular weight or
degree of saturation which is a hydrogen
carbon
ratio and once together the two projects
they
essentially The Experience were done in
the same
manner and overall what I found is some
some weak correlations that I don't
really believe in for molecular richness
and diversity which are just really
being pulled by some um a few handful of
samples but there actually does seem to
be some pretty good relationships
between molecular properties and the
respiration rates of that
D whereas with the oxidation state of
carbon imagine that as these values
become more positive
that compound is more oxidized therefore
more readily available to be used in
comparison to so more negative values
that are more a more reduced compound
which have higher energy yeld that are
more energy costly to use same principle
for molecular weight where the bigger
the compound is potentially the more
difficult is to be degraded but these
are these are average values for an
entire pool of carbon in a
sample so yeah
um so coming back to this feedback loop
of decomposition and molecular
diversity and really what have I learned
about decomposition in Rel diversity
over the last six years overall
decomposition um in the short term
increases molecular trade diversity once
there's a fresh plant litter Supply
Rapid growth um and all these new
compounds are being made but over time
without any new
additions you ultimately get this
decrease in the number of different
compounds and trait diversity over time
if there's really no new food sources
during microbial
activity molecular diversity is
influenced by microbial diversity and
Community functioning
potentially and it's influenced by
litter type and the fact
that you know that could cause faster SL
of growth perhaps but liter type inputs
don't actually determine the end point
diversity of B so just because you know
lit a has a higher starting point
molecular diversity than lit B it
doesn't mean that L A after you know 200
days of decomposition is still going to
have a higher diversity than L
B has more to do with the the microbial
population and ultimately that microbial
molecular diversity May influence
organic carbon persistance but there are
truly some some big furtile to overcome
in terms of instrument capabilities and
some experimental barriers to really
getting at this question we're talking
about small molecules that we're trying
to identify all of them um and one pool
and quantify them it it's very
challenging all right that I just want
to say thank you and um want to thank of
course my committee members and all of
my collaborators or people that have
helped me along the way let me use their
lab let me use their equipment um given
me advice and then um my my funing
opportunity that I've had while I S here
and I just also want to shout out for
the sh noack small grant program that
has been you know I wouldn't have able
do this research really without that in
the beginning and the for Center grate
research grants also largely funded This
research and so that um any questions
that
right wait sorry can you repeat the the
question yeah my question is
that only measure moleular diversity of
or
is right right do you want essentially
is especially off of a fresh plant
litter anything that you measure is
already going to be like a d microbial
products because the atic decomposition
plant L is probably quite small and what
we're measuring is really all microbial
products from D is that what you're
getting at
[Music]
yeah yeah I
don't yeah we everything that we measure
so this is one of the challenges with
the lcms is everything that we measure
has to be filtered at 02 microns and
then the instrument itself actually only
measures between like 200 and a th000
dolins so everything below that is what
we're measuring we would have to sort of
do some sort of both analysis where then
you can quantify molecular diversity on
that and we did try diversity
calculations on Nexa Spectra or ftis FTI
Spectra but it's very
difficult
yeah
questions I had a question um at the
very beginning in uh in the depth
profiles um the sort of eyeball that
there is in the in the hydrophobic
compounds there's an increase in
uh functional
diversity can you speculate why we see
it there and not for the hydrophilic
compounds does that have anything to do
with the analysis or production is that
a true ecological yeah or mixing or
movement or one thought about that is
that for the the hydrophilic they're
much I mean they're hydrophilic so
they're more polar and they can move
through the so profile probably better
but the hydrophobic ones are really more
in
place yeah they're sticky the minerals
and all that why we seeing that trend of
last longer with the hydrophobic
compound that
are back slides
yes I just a little bit nerv
some little clueless here but when the
title says it's the big question and the
two experiments really occupy different
parts the
gra yeah
so so we so I did the experiment
separately for each
project but when I analyze them
separately they have different Trends a
little bit which made me nervous about
making any declarative statements about
those Trend when they differ by project
so I wanted to lump them together and
see these are normalized by the amount
of carbon that was in the microcosms
too so yeah they they're different you
really draw a line through
like one there bottom bottom right I
know that just
wonder anyway just yeah this is more
just sort of amings on on the big
question and my best attempt to answer
the gain that I have
yeah there's so much that's fascina here
I'm sorry about listen this but you
mentioned something about thetion
disrupting function
something like how the microbial
diversity might be working
together yeah this is something I had to
consider when I was doing these zal
dilutions that I could just be
completely disrupting the function of
that Community through that process even
though it's already a disruptive process
to get to my stock Community the the
Next Step appear to really disrupt any
relationships so I'm my thought process
was we thinking about this after lab
group meeting recently well if a whole
Community every every individual has a
role in producing a certain mcab or you
know product that then this organism
uses and then you know it's like that
Chain Reaction they're all like working
together say you take out some of those
those species then you don't have the
next person to eat that and then that
was disrupting that Trend in terms of
diversity of molecule
diversity this where I couldn't quite
see through but are you saying that you
feel your observation support that idea
that the community does have this sort
of pass along collectivity it's possible
I have to look into the data and look at
more of the um Med faculties that are
present like do that and see I'm losing
certain Pathways that would then maybe
be like
next it's my best my
best five different systems or some nice
number at the beginning in chapter one
were they replicated like you really see
that each one of them is somehow
coherent microbial
phology or is there sort of all sorts of
variation within as much
across for sorry Which chapter one yeah
um were the three replic sort of
Representative they go together
all yeah they there were definitely some
variations within those triplicates
because there like there's good
difference between some of them but we
tried to want them in the best way
possible where the soil order was the
same and the dominant vegetation type in
general assignment so some of them were
better they had lower
variances had a lot more
[Music]
in these samples there's not a way to
distinguish between depth and time we
didn't measure like c14 on any of them
and that's also really difficult to do
on D anyway but um so it's really just
using de as a proxy for a time and and
assuming that what's deeper is
older potentially um you could
use I mean in general think about the
the the samp that are in the Northeast
are going to be a lot younger than those
in the Southeast so there's going to be
an age discrepancy already
that I know maybe used account
for I have
not that's
yeah it um ripping off I guess what
Rebecca was saying um do you think that
the dilution step maybe lowers genome
size which would for the lower divers
doesn't appear that the dation actually
lowered the average genome size for the
most part you have some oddballs out
here which are driv in this relationship
but
they're kind of in the same range maybe
slightly
lower I'm not sure if it's St yeah what
do best the Illusions do to the
community and
how right what does it mean that these
are correlated with diversity of
Mo yeah but it's obviously there's a
difference somebody
somebody we love to talk more about this
this is more of just like interesting
finding where I thought I was creting
like this perfect you know diversity
grad
micro the rations Community yeah yeah
great thank you very much r
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu