this is a production of Cornell
University lights the ultimate source of
energy on Earth through photosynthesis
it provides us with clothing food
housing for people that work with plants
it's absolutely essential for
germination phototropism flowering
pollination I see it as a first
principle in the plant World in fact
this is my high school textbook for
biology and it's life is the light is
the energy for life and it goes on to a
chapter telling us what is light at the
time actually I did stage lighting in
high school and my goal was to for those
that are older to do light rock bands
with chipmunk but it didn't happen
although I did work on light and how it
activates cells for Peter Hepler and at
the um time we looked at everything to
understand it based on chemistry physics
biology history and philosophy and
you'll see that approach here
today so as Socrates said follow
everything to the end wherever it leads
you and I ended up becoming a plant cell
biologist and light
microscopist wrote two books both in the
Third Edition and uh throughout these
books there they I try to help people
understand and actually that's really
important to understand um light and
cell biology based on chemistry physics
um history and
philosophy so let's start from the very
beginning oh just came out last week
and God said let there be light and
there was light and God saw that the
light was good but let's get in a little
more
detail okay so Christian hyans figured
light was a wave it couldn't be a corpal
because if it was a corpal then if this
person was looking at the bird and this
person was looking at the flower the
corpal would hit each other and just go
everywhere so light must be a wave
well Newton said no no no light can't be
a wave because if you take a human here
and you shine light on it waves tend to
go behind something next time you're
walking by water and you see a stick
coming up you'll see the waves go around
but Newton couldn't see that so he said
light must be a
corpal okay this is what corpal look
like this is what waves look
like if it can't be a wave and it can't
be a
corpal maybe it can be a
particle and a wave or corpal and a wave
or particle or two and that's what I'll
come back
to Thomas Young actually repeated
Newton's experiment and found out that
the light that hit both sides of the
barrier actually went
around that Newton missed this and
actually my students do this every year
although it's really easy with the ler
and very difficult with sunlight in
England because you don't get much
brightness and coherence but anyhow this
happened so this was evidence that light
behaved as a
wave there's light hitting two different
holes they come out and they make a
pattern like this and Thomas Young said
it made this pattern because when the
crests came together you'd get
constructive interference if the PR were
out of phase you'd get destructive
interference and that would account for
the light and dark
bands you know Thomas Young might have
been kind of bright because he started
off doing
botney here's his first paper on a
perculia okay so light seemed to be a
wave and James clerk maw Maxwell showed
that it was electromagnetic wave so
here's how he showed it he took
Faraday's experiment that when you move
a magnet through a coil you create an
electric current in that coil so see my
thumb that's the
magnet and my fingers are the um current
in the
coil that's what this symbol
means that you move a magnet up and down
and around it you get a Circle or the
curl of the
current ampere showed that if you have a
current moving across an electric field
it will generate a magnetic field around
it this equation set my hand is now the
same as the equation you have a current
going this way make a magnetic field
that goes around it anybody clear on
that okay we'll get past the vector
calculus now Maxwell also assume that
the Divergence of E equals zero that
means that there's no sources of of
electric fields or no syns for electric
fields in other words there's no
electric
field oh wait a
minute isn't light the Carri
electromagnetic force we'll put that
aside and this
here means that there's no magnetic
monopoles that means you can't have just
a North magnet without a South Magnet or
South without a north and that part's
actually
true okay the Maxwell math was a little
too simple here because this says as
soon as you change the magnetic field
you get a change in the electric
field in other words there's no cause
and effect
relationships it happens
simultaneously same thing here have a
change in electric field instantaneously
get a change in magnetic field and that
shows up in his wave equation notice
that the electric and the magnetic
fields are in
Phase okay so as long as we assume
causality doesn't count Maxwell's wave
equation is
good oh let's also assume that
conservation of energy doesn't count
because here you have zero energy
maximum zero maximum
zero okay there's a few flaws in
Maxwell's
equation we're going to question these
assumptions Einstein actually questioned
the assumptions he said we should
remember that the elementary Quantum of
electricity um Epsilon I call Q is an
outsider in Maxwell Loren's
electrodynamics the fundamental equation
of Optics will have to be replaced by an
equation in which the universal constant
Epsilon probably at Square also appears
in a coefficient I have not yet
succeeded in finding a system of
equations suitable for the construction
of the elementary electrical Quantum and
the like Quant the variety of
possibilities does not seem so great for
one to have to shrink from this task and
I
didn't and I'll tell you how I found the
way okay but let's start from the very
beginning
okay in the
beginning there was energy and one of
the forms of energy four fundamental
forces one was electromagnetic force and
it split and gave rise to matter and
an here's a symbol of a photon giving
rise to a particle and an antiparticle
it's called pair
production okay there is antimatter in
itha bananas which are full of potassium
mostly potassium 39 have a sizable
amount of potassium 40 which is
radioactive and it decays into argon 40
by emitting a positron so positron is a
particle of antimatter and there's about
one produced every 70
minutes also a cuga medical center
there's pet scans positron emission
tomography where you take take fluod
deoxy glucose this is really interesting
Otto varberg found out that cancer cells
ferment they don't respire they ferment
you would think it's the opposite but
because they ferment they need tons of
glucose so you give the body fluod deoxy
glucose and it goes right to those
cancer cells the Florine gives off a
positron the
positron beats with an
electron from the
cancer it gives
off gamma rays and you have detectors
that now can localize the
cancer using positron emission
tomography and last week we
heard that Margaret uses positron
emission tomography to look at
grafting okay so there's two
complimentary processes peer production
converting light energy into matter and
antimatter and Annihilation converting
matter and antimatter into light energy
all based on equals
mc2 now some of you must be
thinking if light can turn into
antimatter and
matter and matter and antimatter can
turn into
light could it just be that light is
made out of matter and antimatter
okay let's look at what the big boys say
about matter and
anti there's something called charge
parity time symmetry that if you want to
convert a particle of matter to a
particle of antimatter what you do is
you change the
charge you change the spin the direction
of Spin and you change the direction it
moves in
time okay so if this is positive
positive
positive this is negative negative
negative product of this is positive
product of this is negative matter
equals the minus of
antimatter who here has seen time go
backwards I want to start with the
assumptions of a scientist that what you
see is pretty close to what's real let
necessarily but it's a great first
approximation okay so I've never
seen my any manner going backwards in
time I've never seen mitosis or myosis
all those other cells that are made come
together and make one cell although 30
40 years ago I published a paper in the
Journal of very producible results that
said I
did okay okay and are Elementary
particles mathematical points or do they
have
extension I me what is actually the
definition of
matter definition of matter is something
that has mass and
extension for example compared to
ideas Robert Hook wrote micrographia in
1665 here's his microscope and he said
I'm going to start this whole field the
microscopy like a geometer would I'm
going to start with a point so he looked
at the point of a
needle and he saw how blunt it was it
had
extension he looked at a line next like
a razor blade and saw how unline likee
it
was okay so this brings us now to about
8 to 1900 and Lord Kelvin who actually
came to Cornell and said it's the
prettiest campus in the
world gave a talk which was
entitled 19th century clouds over the
dynamical theory of heat and
light and in it he said the beauty and
clearness of the dynamical theory which
asserts heat and light to be modes of
motion which is
waves is at present obscured by two
clouds how could the earth move through
an elastic solid such as essentially is
Luminous iferous
ether okay so water waves move through
water seismic waves move through Rock
sound waves move through
air what do light waves move through
they move through the Luminous ether
luminiferous ether but if you figure out
the speed of light and the transvers of
the waves that ether would have to be so
viscous that would have stopped the
Earth from
moving so it was a real conundrum and
remember how I told you that Maxwell
didn't put any of the electrical
properties into his light
wave he put them all into The Ether so
the little balls of the electric current
and the big ones are magnetic forces
moving around in circles so here we had
this ether that was thick enough to stop
the Earth from moving that would carry
the light
waves and then after Michaelson and
Morley did their experiment that said
doesn't matter which direction you move
in The Ether the speed of light's the
same Einstein said then there must be no
ether just must be people's imagination
and he banned The Ether it was God so
have now we have no ether and now
there's some room for some the quantum
mechanical
Photon there was one
other Cloud over 19th century physics
and that was um Maxwell bolt boltzman
doctrine that said that pressure is
caused by molecules which are
mathematical points moving and hitting
the edges of things and the more you
heat them up the faster they move and
the more pressure they exert and the um
and certain um and and they would hold a
certain amount of heat based on these
motions so you heat the molecules up and
they move faster so they're using that
heat up and they're holding that heat
but there were some molecules that held
even more heat than like helium which is
a mon monoatomic
gas things like datomic gas es like
hydrogen so it turned out that hydrogen
held instead of three half KT of heat 5
half KD because they had rotational
motion so they can save that heat in
rotating more and actually there's
vibrational moment Mo motion too in
other molecules for example bromides
2 um that has 7 KT of heat so the more
What's called the re of Freedom you have
the more types of motion you have
translational motion rotational motion
vibrational motion you can hold more
heat so everything just didn't work like
a mathematical point
and Lord Calvin wanted to point that
out now will I sorry I spelled that back
I spelled that wrong that's the right
way the um will H we wanted to apply
Maxwell boltzman movement of particles
to understand black body radiation he
figured the molecules inside the black
body were
moving and as they were moving as you
heated them up theyd move faster and
they'd give off higher energy light and
it seemed to work pretty well for
example this red this black line is the
actual data and the red line is his
theory and of course all of us as
biologists we jump at this and we'd go
out for a beer and celebrate I mean this
is really great but physicists really do
know how to measure
things and it wasn't good
enough so plon looked at this and said
how can I improve
this liit one of the inventors of
calculus had the law of continuity
nature doesn't do anything in jumps
everything is continuous if you read
Origin of Species Daren will say nature
does nothing and jumps although he says
it in Latin I will screw it up so you
can look it up so what planks assumed
that just maybe if these oscillators
these atoms in the wall somehow
discreetly sent out light now this was
like a combination of the atom and the
light so it wasn't like a photon yet but
there was a discreet thing then he could
model the black body radiation
perfect and the discreetness related to
the energy of that oscillator light
combination which was equal to what
boltzman called Plank's constant times
the frequency of the oscillation or
light or Plank's constant times the
speed of light divided by the wavelength
C speed of light equals wavelength time
velocity I
frequency okay but Einstein out planked
plank he said I'm going to make light
just a mathematical Point as discreet as
you can
get it seems to me that the observations
regarding black body radiation
photoluminescence production of cathod r
on and on everything you could see can
be understood better if one assumes the
energy of light is this continuously
distributed in space according to this
assumption to be contemplated here when
a light Ray is spreading from a point
the energy is not distributed
continuously over ever increasing spaces
but consists of a finite number of
energy Quant that are localized in
points in space moved without dividing
and could be absorbed and generated only
as a
whole okay how do you get a wavelength
which is a in a mathematical
Point okay Robert milikin tested
Einstein's idea that if you shine light
on a plate electrons jump out and you
can measure the speed of those electrons
or its kinetic energy by putting a
negative charge here and preventing them
from jumping off the plate he did that
and he found out as you increase the
frequency of light you increase the
kinetic energy of the um of the
electrons and the slope was exactly
equal to Plank's constant first
measurement of Plank's
constant okay then Johanna Stark said
well if this light thing is a particle
that's moving in One Direction it must
have linear
momentum so we know the energy is HC
over
wavelength in mechanic X linear momentum
energy is equal to the linear momentum
times the velocity of that ball so for
light Quantum it would be equals
PC so for a like Quantum the linear
momentum would be e over C which is H C
over wavelength C which would be
wavelength over I mean plug constant
over wavelength that's the linear
momentum of a photon the shorter the
wavelength the greater the momentum you
kind know that x-ray would like knock
you over where radio wave would just go
through
you actually I want to do you a little
calculation for you because Einstein was
really kind of screw on his okay so if
classically P equals MV and for like
Quantum P would equal
MC and since we know that eals PC or P
equal e over C then P equals e over C MC
just take this
part move the C over and you get equals
MC s so actually I just derived equals
MC s only from the mechanical properties
of
light and that's kind of
happy uh
oh but E equals mc^2 is kind of like too
big because in classical mechanics the
energy equals 12 MV
s so forant Quantum that would be 12
mc^2 so where' the other half of the
energy
go I'm want to answer that in a
minute one more thing Richard Beth
measured the anual momentum of light
angular momentum classically is the mass
times the angular frequenc angular
velocity times the
radius he sent polarized light through a
b refringent plate and it rotated and he
measured the angular momentum of each
Quantum was H over 2 pi actually
independent of wavelength and frequency
it's the same for every single Photon
wherever you are that's ual
momentum so this is the quantum
mechanical Photon it has a speed a
wavelength a frequency an energy a
linear momentum and angular momentum
although since it's a mathematical Point
nothing's spinning
just a number they're all
numbers and I don't want you to
forget
interference that
Thomas
um
name Young thank you I've got to old um
new because as by hour just we know
there's moreo butterflies or beetles
that when the light hits and goes
through a thin plate or separate at
points you get these beautiful blue
colors and you get those beautiful blue
colors as long as this distance is less
than about a wavelength so you can have
photons that are about a wavelength
apart you'll still get these beautiful
colors that'd be really difficult if FL
were mathematical
point and just because this is a plant
biology seminar plants also use
interference to make some of those
beautiful blue colors okay so Einstein
sort of
neglected
interference plank when he introduced
Einstein for membership nominated for
membership in the Prussian Academy said
sometimes as for instance in his
hypothesis of like Quant he may have
gone overboard and the speculation
should not be held against him Neil's
Bourne is Nobel dress said in spite of
its theistic value however the
hypothesis of L Quanto which is quite
irreconcilable with so-called
interference phenomena is not able to
throw light on the nature of
radiation Robert milikin said the
conception of localized light Quant out
of which Einstein got his equation must
still be regarded as far from being
established until it can account for the
facts on interference and the other
effects which seem thus far to be
irreconcilable with it we must withhold
our full ascent and Henrik Lauren said
the hypothesis of concentrated Quant is
directly in contradiction with with
observed facts namely that what is seen
in the phenomena of
interference but then Arthur Compton did
this great experiment it was like a pool
table he took a photon and shot it into
a electron and the electron went back
using up some energy and the photon was
scattered in this way with a little
longer wavelength if you use
conservation of momentum conservation of
energy and Einstein's special relativity
it all worked out
Compton got the Nobel Prize and from
then on everybody believed the photon
was a mathematical
point when I was working on my model I I
talked to Kurt Godfrey and he said
there's nothing here it's
done science has changed though science
used to be a way to understand the
world now it's a way to predict what's
going to happen and that's a fundamental
difference that's why I'm a
pirate I think I can safely say says
Fineman that nobody understands Quantum
mechanic David merman here at
Cornell declared himself to be among
those who feel uncomfortable when asked
to articulate what we really think about
Quantum Theory writing if I were forced
to sum up in one sentence what the
Copenhagen interpretation says to me
it'd be shut up and
calculate although just recently Jim
bagot and unfortunately died um halron
um started to question this lack of free
speech in science shut up and calculate
how Einstein lost the battle to explain
Quantum
reality actually Einstein really
questioned quantum
mechanics he even questioned his point
like Photon he wrote to Loren I'm not at
all the opinion that one should think of
light as being composed of mutally
independent Quant localized in
relatively small
spaces so I tell my students the most
effective tool for your career in
science is to have a
rug and a broom and if there's
inconvenient facts theories or whatever
you just put them under there
John F Kennedy wrote in profiles
encourage the first pressure to be
mentioned is a form of pressure rarely
recognized by the general public
Americans want to be liked and senators
are no exception we prefer praise to
abuse popularity to contempt we get you
we are anxious to get along with our
fellow legislators our fellow members of
the club to abide by Clubhouse rules and
patterns the way to get along I was told
when I answer of Congress is to go
alone but on the stairs up to our Dean's
office it says to be
defiant defy disciplinary boundaries ask
new questions Inspire pioneering
Solutions is it just aspirational not
something you should actually
do I have no sense of
self-preservation I got the courage and
education award for being fear this when
it comes to
anything I want to tell you about my way
of doing
science so I'm looking here in the
unknown I'm using my left brain and my
right brain left brain's trying to take
things apart and analyze them get those
facts right brains trying to put them
together to make a picture but I also
turn around and I look at the past to
see if that structure is as good as
people think it is so for example a tree
may be shading all those lateral buds
that aren't
growing but when the trees drop down
those lateral buds have a chance now to
grow and I'm just looking at those
lateral
Buds kugi and ran will recognize Makoto
fujimura is taking those old pieces that
had just been laying around under the
rug there and getting some very fine
gold and putting them together and
making something that's even better than
the
original CP snow said that no scientist
or student of science need ever read an
original work of the past I'm just out
of curiosity anybody read that April
1953 paper by Watson and
Crick one two three four
five
okay I think it's bad advice and you
should go read it
okay I'm A Simple Man 1 two three
Infinity after that can't do enough
controls can't understand things can't
remember
things I'm just not smart enough for
this kind of thing so I try to find the
fewest number of First principle ideas
that I can put together and I have to
really question the assumptions to make
sure they're true and coherent
non-contradictory so
challenging two assumptions that the
elementary particle is not a
mathematical point and that time goes
forward and
backwards Ben Ginsburg came to my lab
and he was looking at the caros
cycle caros cycle is a thermodynamic
engine that you heat it up the Piston
goes up you cool it down the Piston
comes down and it converts thermal
energy into work
energy there's no change in entropy
there's as much entropy formed as it is
taken away in the cycle so there's no
relationship to the order of events and
time and entropy yet you can only go
clockwise in the cycle you can't go
clockwise to counterclockwise to do it
so there's an order of events in time
even though there's no
entropy so when Ben told me this I said
this is great I grabbed his arm took him
to the physical science Library which
existed at the time put in a VHS tape
refinement talking about the reality of
antiparticles and it what fan said was
part antiparticles are particles that go
backwards in
time so if this machine were made out of
antimatter according to Fineman it
should just run in the opposite order
but since I believe that there's only
one direction in
time and we published on this I said
there got to be a new symmetry instead
of having positive and negative time
let's have positive negative mass and
figure out all the mechanics on how
everything
behaves so I came up with a new symmetry
instead of CPT symmetry substitute a
time for ma for Mass so it said that
antimatter is the same as matter but the
charge the direction of Spin and the
mass the sign of the mass
changes negative mass is something that
exists in um theoretic iCal physics this
is um Tommy gold his Bondi who wrote
this Tommy gold was at Cornell and also
initially helped me with my work on the
photon so as botanist we know that
plants respond to gravity we know
something about gravity if I'm dealing
with negative Mass I wonder how it works
with
gravity his Newton's universal law of
gravitation this is the causal Force
this is the response Force the little
Mass moves moves in response to the
gravitational force actually if you put
these two together the little masses
cancel out which means the direction of
acceleration depends only on the sign of
the mass of the Earth so if that's
positive both negative and positive mass
will accelerate to the Earth this will
accelerate to the Earth because the
attractive force it goes the same
direction this accelerates to towards
the Earth because there's a repulsive
Force but it goes the other way so it
goes towards
ear if we made up the situation of
having a negative Mass Earth since
that's negative they'd both go
away actually if you have two masses
that exactly the same size the positive
Mass would run away from the negative
mass and the negative Mass would be
attracted to the positive Mass so we'd
have this thing actually Chase each
other
it look like this and if you want you
could call it
massless but the trouble is it will
chase each other to F to Infinity faster
than the speed of light and that's a
problem because light only travels at
the speed of
light I walked over to Ed Sal Peter's um
office and told him about my idea it
turned out he came to Cornell to
actually work on could the photon not be
a elementary particle and um and and
um this had paper by firery and yang had
just come out suggesting that misons
weren't Elementary particles but part
matter and
antimatter Louis de Bry had postulated
this before that the photon was made out
of two semi photons made out of matter
and antimatter but they were massless
and electrically neutral
okay so plants have action potentials
actually the alal cells I have down in
my lab were the first cells that were
shown to have um Action potentials
Monday I'm giv a lecture of neurobiology
on plant Action potentials so we know
about plant
electricity philes took Amber anybody
know the Greek word for
Amber
electron so he used took Amber rubbed it
with fur and it attracts little pieces
of straw complete Botanical
experiment okay Latin word for Amber
suum succinic acid was first isolated
from
Amber okay and you can catch fossils in
Amber okay Cavendish made a torsion
balance he put these huge big lead balls
and saw how they attracted each other
and calculated the gravitational force
they said actually weighed the Earth
from that which in fact he did
kulum created a much smaller version of
this instead of N9 pound lead balls he
used little
piths from the Elderberry so if you've
done the anatomy you might have taken
the pth plants it grows out there in the
courtyard and I used it to help you
section very light and he found out that
the force of attraction or repulsion
depended on the charge and the distance
between them as well as a constant which
has electric permitivity of the vacuum
okay
opposite charges attract like charges
repel and if you divide the force by one
of the charge call it a test charge you
get the electric field around a charge
electric field radiates out from
positive charge in in to a
negative between two charges you get a
very strong
field if a charge moves you make a
magnetic field the more the faster it
moves this is the velocity the charge
the greater the magnetic
field here's another constant magnetic
permeability that gives you the
quantitative difference all right so I
have these two positive positive
negative Mass things that are moving
together as a photon but they're moving
FAS than the speed of light so I have to
slow them down to the speed of light and
actually speed of light is equal to
inverse of the electric permitivity and
magnetic permeability so there's some
electrical magnetic components there
that may be
important so if you have a positive
charge move or charge moves it generates
a magnetic field and that magnetic field
actually generates an electromotive
force in the opposite direction that
slows this down it's called
self-induction or the electronic State
and Maxwell said this is actually the
fundamental Quant qu in the theory of
electromagnetism so we have these two
charges two masses two charges the
positive chass moves away from the
negative Mass but as it moves away since
it has a charge it generates a magnetic
field which generates Electro motive
force in the other direction to slow it
down so now this catches up so you
actually get two particles in a wave and
that's what it looks like and here's
kind of a model
okay now I want to talk about the
rotational motion if eal mc^2 equals H
new then we calculate the mass of a
photon and if we let the angular
momentum equal MVR the classical
quantity and that set that equal to the
quantum quantity by doing this we use
Neils B's correspondence principle and
since the angular velocity is equal to
the angular frequency times
R we get this equation and from that we
can solve for the radius of a photon so
the radius of a photon is wavelength
divided by 2 pi so that's how wide it is
or half
wide so we have these two things that
are moving like this with angular
momentum so each Photon for example an
x-ray would be tiny kind of like a
particle and an INF
red um Photon would be very
wide since the radius is wavelength
divided by 2 pi the circumference is 2
pi r is actually equal to the wavelength
and that is the fundamental wavelength
in a
photon okay this looks messy but it
really
isn't this is the
three-dimensional equation for the
movement of these semi
photons there's the
radius and cosine means it's moving in a
certain way or sign so to have a cosine
and sign means it's moving in a circle
to have a cosine and a minus sign moving
in a circle in the other one so this
just says the photon semi photons are
moving in a circle and this is a
vibrational frequency I had to
just created them out of my own head to
make sure they didn't crash into each
other because if they crashed into each
other they turn into light and I didn't
want that to
happen so this is what it looks
like that's a
photon and it's difficult to see the
three dimensions so I divided it now
into to resolve what it looks like as
it's coming to you or looking from the
top and youbody see the particles in the
wave same
time do it
again okay Schrodinger wasn't able to
come up with an with an equation for the
photon he could come up with one for
electrons which is Spin
one2 and in his equation this n equals
one I made this n equal two for a
photon this is the kinetic energy this
is the potential energy this is the
total energy I'm just going to say if
you solve this you can solve this
equation if you make a wave function
that describes your Photon so here's my
wave function in Ence cosine plus I
that's the circle and it takes a certain
amount of time to go around the circle
all right there's the wave function is
now it has this I in there imaginary
number so with the imaginary number
people don't use real space people by me
physicists don't use real space they use
what's called phase space or
configuration space or imaginary
time
okay but I look at this as a transverse
plane where there's actually rotational
motion p wessell in 1799 was a
mapmaker and he figured out that he
could use imaginary numbers to make
ordered peers with the xaxis gives you
the
longitude or the real axis gives you the
logitude and the imaginary axis gives
you the latitude just keep two numbers
that you can't add together it keeps
them separate is easy for the
bookkeeping so the energy of the um
biner Photon that was um twice as big as
just the translational energy you add
the rotational energy and you get the
full energy
okay now I just want to
add kum's
law to
the um wave equation
so
this um and this is the wave equation L
and this is kum's law we do it the X Y
and Z plane for the two photons that
gives us the electric field on each one
and I can sum them together to see what
the electric field caused by both both
are also I could do the same thing for
the magnetic field and here you want to
use the velocity instead of the position
but you get the velocity no I'll just
show you in a second put them together
and you get the magnetic field so
imagine this is positively charged and
the blue one's negatively charged here
if they fly over this this electron here
they're going to add no electric field
they cancel each other
out as they widen and separate
they'll put a little bit of electric
field on here a lot none and then an
opposite directed
field so we actually have a sine wave an
electric sine wave going over that
electron and here's what it looks like
in Vector form the pink wave will be the
sinos soidal electric field and the
green will be the circular magnetic
field there'll be a quarter of a
wavelength out of phase in
orthogonal going to hit an electron boom
send it up into another
orbit Einstein wondered what would
happen if he traveled at the speed of
light for Maxwell's equations everything
stops so Einstein concluded time must
stop but for here it actually keeps
going because the two thing are self-
regenerating because they're out of
phase so this is what it looks like
sinoid electric field pulls an electron
up to the next
orbital this is for hydrogen here's a
hydrogen atom there's the electron
photons coming up
dorion very much like
photosynthesis just a quick thing
there's kirkoff defraction equation
describes how things look in a
microscope it works for everything the
trouble is it's not consistent with
Maxwell's equations okay if you have a
spherical particle in a microscope it
doesn't look like confocal microscope
doesn't look like a a sphere it looks
like this proloid
um form and kirkov defraction equation
describes this perfectly but it doesn't
it's not consistent with Maxwell's
equations because Maxwell's equations
has two waves that are in phase and
that's not allowed with the assumptions
of the Kirk off defraction
equation so po cor SEL Hans bet all said
Maxwell's equations don't
work okay but everybody lets it
go but the Viner Photon has the way the
two Fields out of phasee there's a
picture of the binary Photon in plain
form in Maxwell's
equations still have an electric field
still have a magnetic field have an
electric field magnetic field always but
with Maxwell's equations they disappear
and that's why they won't describe the
fraction okay the point spread function
is what we use to tell the relationship
between our image and real
it these are the typical equations that
are used and actually you can't find a
derivation for them anywhere Zeiss
published them once that was enough but
there's no derivation as a matter of
fact they use different functions to get
the axial resolution and the lateral
resolution using the binary Photon I can
make um use just one function and just
say that the axial is about three times
greater than the lateral resolution
because the photon is travels about
three times more distance than it is
wide so taking the geometric properties
of the
photon okay in one cycle the photon goes
like this and this is pi times greater
than
that polarized light is completely
understandable when you have a sine wave
like this photons have no Dimensions no
sidedness can't understand polarized
light that's DNA is a fiber cable from
typher Just One Last
Thing Einstein predicted that Starlight
would go by the Sun and have what's
called a double deflection so you turn
the telescope up higher and you see the
star here even though it's really he
said it has a double deflection because
the mass of the Sun warps both space and
time but what think for a second if the
photon from the Star had zero
translational energy it would just fall
into the sun if it had infinite
translational energy it wouldn't be
bent the fact that it's bent twice as
much as just a Newtonian corosal would
be bent means it has the translational
energy is only half the energy the other
half is
the rotational energy so you don't have
to say time space is together and warped
and all that stuff you can just say that
the photon has a few more properties
then Einstein gave it as a mathematical
Point Loren wished that physics would go
back so he can imagine things in space
and
time the young guy said no no no I think
modern physics has definitely decided in
favor of Plato in fact the smallest
units of matter are not physical objects
in an ordinary sense they are forms
ideas which can be expressed
unambiguously only in mathmatical
language as ideas have no
extension but I think a photon is a
physical object has extension and could
be pictured in ordinary space in time so
I think on the surface quantum mechanics
and relativity may seem to be
profound but deep down I think they're
superficial
okay that's it I'm over so any
questions Wy showed sweeping things
under the
rug as opposed to using that as material
for a testable hypothesis oh yeah why
not can you not derive testable
hypotheses from uh whatever you want to
call the the trash you were sweeping
under yeah so let me give you my own um
so first of all if you're going to shut
up and
calculate environment there's no test of
hypothesis all right but I'll give you
one of my things so I have these masses
at the end of like a
string I don't know the shape of those
masses say they're more than a
mathematical point then the um positive
charge say could pull push apart the
other possible charge and they'd split
Point Caray say you need a point Caray
force in order to pull them in and then
um so if you if you have that other
Force then what's the shape of the
electric field is it exponential instead
of linear as I showed it that's called
the ukawa force there are actually uh if
you have an open mind sweeping under the
rug could just be collecting facts that
need to be
tested
um I read half the
paper right here in the early part of
the paper today you mentioned that the
you know the into matter creates
possibility of you know the one chasing
the other so translational motion how uh
in your model does the rotational
momentum and rotational motion come into
play okay the paper discussed right
translational motion but how do we get
that rotation oh how do we get the
rotation yeah oh so so um angle momentum
is conserved yeah so once it's
emitted it's emitted with one wavelength
and therefore anual Mo momentum um so I
I can just say it as an
atom a bore atom you know each electron
stays in its orbit because angle
moment oh yeah and in this case we have
two particles but there's no what's the
charge between the
um those fields that I showed you
actually take into consideration the
threedimensional
charges that are there but it doesn't
really answer your question yeah yeah it
it's a sort of a description of the
charges that but not an explanation
yeah that's right that's right that's
right I need to do that or we can do
that how do you prevent them from
hitting each other
so that um longitudinal
motion actually um prevents them from
ever touching each other yeah yeah but I
created that just on a whole cloth in
order to make sure they don't touch each
other but actually um it it it worked
out kind of nicely the entropy of a
photon is
3.6k so the entropy of a single particle
is 1 12K
and um so you add degrees of freedom and
you get more so 3.6k is like basically 7
half K so you look for seven types of
motion and so there should be about
seven types of motion
but but I just sort of made up that
vibrational
thing I originally had a much simpler
formula but the photons wouldn't
interfere constructively and
destructively The Way You observe so I
had
to add like a square two two Pi s Square
term and got it cosine squared instead
of just go
on uh really interesting to um I was
wondering so the Super comium Con
reactor in um
Japan showed evidence for free neutrinos
that are free from electrons and
different flavors producing different
Halo effects and these neutrinos are
undetectable by our sensors except when
they interact with another particle when
they hit an electron and produce light
so how does your model account for the
production of Light by a particle that
moves faster than the speed of light
because we assume that
light has a set limit of its
speed then this particle couldn't be
carrying so um the center of gravity of
the photon actually moves at the speed
of
light but since it's vibrating like this
has to move faster and slower on both
sides the average is always actually the
speed of so the photon itself moves at
the speed of light um one thing about
neutrinos U Max Bourne initially and and
um and then de Bry thought that once
neutrinos were discovered that the two
part
would be neutrinos and since neutrinos
may or may not have a Magnetic Moment
it's not certain and may or may not have
a mass it's not C I mean this is is even
more certain I think than the neutros
the um these particles I'm talking about
may be similar to nutral nutral and anti
nutral so how would the interaction of a
nutr with an electron produce photons in
that case is it oh I I um
I I can only answer very vaguely and is
that if you have an interaction that's
going to cause that lead to a certain
energy
production if that energy production
could give off a photon of whatever the
particular wavelength should be but I I
can't really answer that
question this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu