this is a production of Cornell
University thank you so much Andy and
thank you everyone for being here is it
is it circular bionutrient economy or is
it the pizza either way I appreciate
you're being here um so okay so uh I'd
like to thank the the section of s and
crop science for the invitation and to
say that it came about because I'm
trying to recruit a student who's a real
circular by Neutron Economist and this
section would be a better uh host for
her she'd rather become a soil scientist
than a plant pathologist that was was
the consensus but really my my desire to
be part of this family is uh arises from
the deeper considerations that Andy
outlined I think um I think of myself as
in part of this sort of one Health
framework that planetary health is
determining soil health or influencing
soil Health which influences plant
health and which influences human health
and so seeing myself within that I'm
sort of shifting from the plant Health
to the soil Health which seems to be
something that's going on in in the
broader sips Community this word cloud
that uh these word clouds that just
presented at the 10 anniversary party
show 2020 I'm working solidly on
genomics of resistance and by now much
more interested in soil carbon so um I
wish I could say I was driving that
change but I think I'm just reflecting
maybe a shift in interest that's broader
than myself um so my interest in
bionutrient circularity I share with a
number of people in this room and um I'm
very keen to help as we try to you know
improve our our internal capacity for
analyzing nutrients contaminants and
other materials internally here at at in
sips and at Cornell because um I think a
lot of us are suffering from limitations
in that
regard so today I'd like to talk about
this idea of circular Food Systems
circular B nutrient economy um as Andy
mentioned the professional pivots that
got me to this place and sort of some
initial progress in a in a long process
Explorations experiments some of the
downside risks how can change happen
here and in Africa as
well and before diving in I want to
thank my the wonderful colleagues in my
lab I think Christina known to many of
you as could be thank for a bunch be
showing and um Florest is our lab
manager and we got a great team of
people um many of whom are
undergraduates some of whom are present
here um Johan's lab is a important you
know key collab ators in this area
schano and Global development as well
and Charles Mig is my my lead partner in
Kenya and we have the pleasure of
working with the Richard Institute and
The Wider soil Factory Network on this
sort of
topic so the basic proposition that I'll
be
um putting forth today is um the idea
that we would redirect our bodily
nutrients in the um particularly in from
urine from The Aquatic
environment to agriculture so um now
since we direct those nutrients into the
Aquatic environment it's a hazard for
that you got harmful algo blooms
nutrification and so on if uh and in
many situations the the land and
agriculture are suffering from depletion
of nutrients and carbon or nutrients in
this case so the the extent to which
this is a big deal depends on the
context so globally speaking urinary
nutrients would account for around 19%
of the synthetic uh nitrogen that we put
on our crops uh about 11% of the
phosphorus um and in uh the US is sort
of bit less than that because we Import
and Export so much nutrient in the form
of food and fertilizer um but in many
African countries you know it's the
amount of nutrients in our their the
urine there would be exceed the amount
of nutrients they apply as as synthetic
fertilizer so they could do much better
with agriculture if they were
redirecting their nutrients and so um I
don't know if any of you have seen the
the peaw we have on
um egg quad for for some festivals but
with johann's Squad we're like able to
show with that that in New York state if
we could take the urine the urinary
nutrients from New York City and apply
them it would cover much of the nutrient
Farms of New York in
Paris the Environ the agricultural
environment around there which is a lot
um could completely use uh suffice its
nut nitrogen needs and about half its
phosphorus needs if it used paris's
Urban uh urinary nutrients anyway so
where you are the the details depend but
it's generally I think a a proposition
worth considering so I was standing on a
bridge in nem ner a while back watching
this camel come into town with a bunch
of cow PE a load of cowp HMS on its back
there's a festival coming up and I'm
thinking how long can this go on they're
bringing all the carbon and nutrients
from the already depleted agricultural
soil into the city where it's you know
winds up as being
pollution for the urban and Aquatic
environments and globally speaking 2.3
billion people lack even basic
sanitation and 80% of excr go untreated
into the water ways while we're further
depleting our agricultural soils like
this the fundamentals are untenable here
and then so I'm thinking like how can
this you know what can we do about this
and then later on I'm with these farmers
and uh this is this is actually from a a
video take by my son but um these these
uh farm this farmer group 10,000 farmer
group led by let me knew Ali here they
they were asking themselves that
question like we you know where are we
going to get our nutrients and so they
started applying uh urine to their
fields and um it's gotten to be a big
thing now so I was really inspired by
them but then I realized well actually
it's not just some backa Beyond people
in a remote difficult situation they're
doing that the French are super into it
they've got companies that are making
fertilizers from uran they've got an
entire neighborhood of Paris that's you
know Plumbing for this um I kind of like
the way they show that yellow gold rush
they got style of course and even the
way they show the fact that um most in
terms of our food that we take in the
nutrients we take in most of them come
out most of the NPK come out in our
urine relatively little in our feces in
contrast from the micronutrients are
coming out more in the poop so we have
risk of having not enough of some of
those micronutrients we use urine as a
fertilizer I also really like the way
these are showing this bigger vision of
okay uh food comes into the city from
the from the countryside it should be
coming out as biow this is their kind of
signature move for how to technically
pull it off the carbon and nutrients
should return to Agriculture and I think
you'll recognize that as you know a plea
for sort of circularity in the food
system so we we live in a um
indescribably wasteful era I mean if you
the more you think about it don't think
about it as much as I do it'll wreck
your head but um so this is provoking a
lot of people start thinking about
circular economy how can we design out
waste keep materials in circulation and
regenerate
nature this being a very powerful
thought these being very you know
practicable tactics and stuff so people
generally distinguish between how you go
about it for biological materials and
how you go about it for technical
materials are quite different um in
terms of the the literature on circular
economy I did a citation search and you
find that um over the last few years 27
to 2013 you go from 800 and some to
8,000 and some citations um per year but
most of
them the vast majority are about the
technical materials and only 15% have
relevance to the food system as
indicated by searching circular economy
and food system nutrient or agriculture
so we're bringing up the rear and it's
it's more complicated people often think
of circular economy as these neat Loops
phone to phone carpet to carpet um for
for organic materials it's more like
this beautiful tangle of these different
things and this is from a nice paper
about contaminants so it's complicated
operationally materially it's
complicated downside riskwise
and we we have fewer tactics at our
disposal if you're going to be doing
technical materials you can reuse repair
refurbish remanufacture repurpose but if
you're looking at Biologicals you're
with a much smaller set of r words but
you know we we as johannas had Point has
pointed out we can also kind of simplify
the concept for how do we how do
we bring the the carbon and nutrients
that we in our food system back to the
soil and then back to our food and I
think in some ways in some moments that
allows us again to simplify in plus a
lot of this work is done by organisms
so um it's while
it's conceptually more complicated it's
technically a lot of times more easy
because you're your various uh your
biologies doing the work for you okay so
this is a while a minority of circular
economy literature it's still a very
happening literature um I don't know if
people remember aim doberman's talk here
a few years back um so he's got
synthetic fertilizer as a foundation of
the circular food system or circular ish
food system but he's pointing out that
we could do much better about bringing
hope products from animal and plant
agriculture back into animal PL
agriculture but he notably sort of
wouldn't
acknowledge excr in this Vision so
johannas and I like call him up
afterward like a what's up with that um
he and I worked at the international R
Research Institute millions of years ago
and we co-wrote sdg2 so I'm like aim
this is not our first spute but he
wasn't budging he's not ready for it he
is interested though in animal nutrients
anyway uh johannas is working on him
stay tuned
um but so here is my you know kind of
simplified view of the the conventional
linear food system um we were I guess
crops are around 70% dependent on
synthetic nitrogen at this point they go
through crops livestock and people your
veg or otherwise and we have these
massive
byproducts crop residues animal and
human excreta and food waste and more um
and then a lot of really hideous harms
deforestation because of the
inefficiency of the system greenhouse
gases driving climate change nutrient
pollution destroying our aquatic
ecosystems um these are no joke if we're
looking at the planetary boundaries it's
nutrient pollution and contaminants that
are kind of two of the
Blockbuster horrible things we need to
work on so I think we we are working on
them um and we need to be and I think
circularity is one of the ways we can
improve here um so so if we look at
these three byproducts of the food
system we just put in a paper from our
nefa team you know just in the USA alone
human and animal ex oppose a five plus
billion dollar a year
opportunity so I'm calling those the
organic underutilized resources just
because it sound
sounds kind of nice even though it's
slightly perverting the thing so how can
we make use of those materials
better
um so doing anything as demanding as you
know circularizing the food system has
has many Frontiers technical legal
regulatory operational sociocultural so
starting where we are we're technical
people well we can use if we're clever
enough to use a a series of
transformation approaches together you
know we can turn those waste products
into resources there do some extent use
these resources anyway already we could
do a lot better um biological processes
like composting aerobic digestion like
soldierly larvey Livestock in general
pigs and chickens and whatnot can
transform these organic waste into into
useful Foods those processes are just go
better with biochar every biology works
better with biochar and biochar works
better if you've dried and chopped and
you know pilled your material so how can
we bring these together to more
efficiently um circularize the food
system so um so we've got these three
material Transformations and we're
looking to turn a whole bunch of hours
including the three I've mentioned but
also invasive species agroindustrial
products and uh byproducts and more into
feed uh food fertilizer Etc soil
amendments in order to improve food
security carbon sequestration reduce
emissions provide sanitation improve
public health and employment in order to
make all that happen we not only need
this sort of technical angle but we need
a lot of social um you know to really
transform the food system we've got to
change how we think and feel about
excreta another wayte how we process
we're so centralized and these are low
value gross messy things and centralized
models really can't make any sense with
that and obviously there's a lot of
legal regulatory change that needs to
happen to make this possible but um so
so we need to conceive of that luckily
there's some nice synergies that can be
found amongst these methods carbon and
nutrients play nice together biochar and
biology as I mentioned if you start
co-localizing activities and
coordinating sectors it can start to
actually pick up speed and make sense we
have a lot of work to do to make all
that happen but but you know it's it's
worth it I would
so this is sort of
a an eye full of what a circular version
would look like with maybe these
biological and thermochemical processes
together making these um these waste
products sort of work for soil and crops
for people and and animals and including
insects um okay so so how did I come to
this uh this view of things priorities
this kind of summarizes why
working in maze genetics and you know
there's only so much genetics can do
when you sort of look like that and acts
like that and it's not only poor yield
but it's a poisonous yield that you get
when when it looks like that I really
enjoyed those years of maze genetics
starting with trying to understand the
inheritance of a a suite of diseases
that affect you
know our major crop in the United States
as well as in Africa got really sucked
up in these ear diseases that um provide
these pervasive toxic effects you know
and how the specific traits of the ear
and the plant determine uh resistance to
those those uh fungal pathogens and
their microtox and um products so get a
whole bunch of stuff on lot of genetics
and some grain sorting work and other
stuff um but I came to the view that
there were a lot of trade-offs involved
so for genetics and breeding for grain
sorting and biological control there's
massive clear tradeoffs and the win-win
that I could spot was enhancing soil
health and working with people to
improve system
Health just a couple of glimpses of our
results that are relevant a Kenyan
student um worked with a simit to look
at couple of places in eastern Kenya
just highlighting here the same season
low nitrogen and high nitrogen all the
mot toxin indic the alot toxin
indicators here and also true for fum
monocenter are way worse with the low
nitrogen than the high and looking over
here at a different site
the low nitrogen looks a lot like the
low nitrogen here but with even more
astronomical levels of Alin toxin um
then with an eye in the sky we could
actually predict you know based on
available
scoil parameters and drought indicators
we could predict to some extent alox and
in a few surveys that we've published in
these papers Will's paper came out right
before he lost his job usad
unfortunately um
but this made me feel like
uh toxic grain is a symptom of these
larger challenges we've got soil
depletion and drought that come together
to stress our plants and that leads to
again poor yields and toxic yields um
and what looked to me initially like a
you know proud to be so integrated about
our microt toxin work to looking quite
inadequate you know we really have to go
before the season and look at soil
health and resilience after the season
to look at surveillance from um
satellite
data pop data but also bioindicators of
MOT toxins and it I started to feel like
we're we're strapping urine bags on
babies and going to hospitals for for
urinary athlex and biomarkers and like
wouldn't it be nice to have sour
sanitation Source separating sanitation
that could also contribute to a
surveillance program so I end up
thinking well shoot if we're got to I've
got to handle the urine anyway why would
I do it in a baby bag why not you know
do it as part of an integrated circular
system where the we we're monitoring the
crop the the food and the the body and
we're using the body product again to to
fight the
problem so so how can we build that soil
Health where can we get that so a carbon
and nutrients I think you can probably
guess where I'm going with that um so
back to those people in n in
ner um I was really proud that my
program was funding this farmer
organization and supporting them not
only to come up with I mean they didn't
we didn't support them to come up with
the idea they came up with well yes we
did we got an agronomist talking to the
farmer leadership who suggested Ur as an
alternative it was not popular initially
but after a few years hundreds of
farmers are using urine as a fertilizer
and they're able to publish their
results with this the first author there
is a young woman that is not a normal
thing in that culture but so I was real
proud of how that worked out so this
inspired a lot of other people to at
least consider that the film that my my
uh son made was um prompted by be Beth
mcki a graduate from this
department um Janice no sir and um she
Beth brought that video to East Africa
to to Lobby the farmers in the East
Africa to consider these findings and
you know slowo but making progress um
and then this is another thing I was
pleased but from my mcnight I was a
scientific director for couple of
decades and that n this that ner work
was something like and I more in
response to that I asked this other
group to I worked with them to get them
a grant and they're looking here in
another West African country this is
Burkina Faso this is aagadu sort of the
Agricultural area around it in a broader
Bina they bring in a bunch of nutrients
into wagadugu from you know the
Hinterlands and then they say your
nation constitutes that's uh major
uncontrolled nitrogen flow is by far the
fattest Arrow coming out of there
urination this is from the end of the
abstract urination constitutes a
dominant nitrogen loss pathway and urine
collecting initiatives could provide
valuable fertilizer adapted to local
agricultural requirements and
constraints increasing the urban system
sustainability by enhancing Regional
food provision as well as reducing
sanitation induced water pollution so
that the first author was a guy I
learned a lot from when I was on
sabbatic in France um and appreciate the
way they sort of work this out um so it
isn't just you know West Africa um
there's Dynamic this is sort of very old
idea and you know pleasing government
and Grandma you know the idea of
projecting the beauty of bodily
circulation and pro projecting the
practicality of it you know why the heck
we can't do that and spare no
accumulation of phosphorus nitrogen and
carbon compounds in our waterways so
this is nothing new we're just trying to
gain momentum here um hard to do in the
United States for some reason but when
the conflict started in
Ukraine now three years back um I got
interest from a a New York Times
Reporter who's a friend of my kids and
um she wrote that article about peace
cyclers there immediately spawned a rash
of other propaganda I mean other
articles in
various I shouldn't say that but one of
them was about the work in ner which I
was really pleased about that anyway so
so this is sort of becomes part of my
mindset how do we make change partly
it's sort of getting our fabulous work
into into the news um okay
so um what are we up to around this
around here um so if you think about P
you can either use it as is but it's
heavy and you know low
value or you can make it into a fancier
fertilizer so if johanes and I John he
represents this soide more and I'm more
over here but we both are fans of both I
suppose um so my thinking about the the
just using p as is was really focused on
an interest in that per Urban population
so 40% of humanity lives in per urban
areas many of these people are living in
slums informal settlements these per
urban areas are like too dense maybe to
farm but here there's some space to grow
things you're told to go you know
implement this kind of garden
but then the soil people have access to
it's full of heavy metals can we use
crop residues together with excr to be
able to do this but
safely um so I started with straw Bell
gardening because it's kind of a
thing I'm calling it grow as you go or
you go gardening because of the P
component I loved my my Musgrave Farm
manager for support not only tolerating
but supporting me to get going on this
while I was trying to be you know the
maze genetics continues um you know you
might might not have seen the somewhat
mediocre straw Bell gardening there at
Caldwell as well um so that was sort of
exploratory then then we sort of shift
into more experimental mode here um my
must grave Farm manager introduced me to
the uh dilman Hill Farm managers with
the hint that that was a much more
appropriate place to work dilman Hill
has a legacy of heavy metals from its
time as a Orchard piece of the orchard
where they're using um arsenic and Leed
as you know as as pesticides in the
orchard business so you know working on
raised bed gardens are similar um makes
a lot of sense there psychically and the
student environment is great there um
Jesse's here somewhere I
think um so just a couple of messages
from that work so far I'm sort of
leaning on 20 2023 and 2024 findings
from our dman Hill machine um first off
um plant um you know the the kale in
2023 grew um
similarly um with urine as with Miracle
Grow on soil so Ur is good fertilizer up
to a point um but our our substrates
really suck so this is wheat straw oh
not so good um really bad With Ur way
better way worse than with Miracle Grow
but in general Miracle going year on our
par on Ma over and on soil but our
organic substrates are looking really
not competitive here Jensen there um so
we did a little experiment mixing up you
little comparing virgin wheat that was
in the barn with weathered wheed that
was sitting around outside for a year or
so with composted wheat that we' used
for the straw gardening with fine Stover
and a mix of those two and um within
without biochar here um and and
basically you have to kind of age you
know the wheat quite a bit to get to
what fine Stover is on day one out of
the barn um and there's sort of a hint
there not significant but maybe blending
is better no biochar effect
detected um we uh the regulatory
authorities thought it was going to be
World War III when we applied urine on
the plant science Barn after a
considerable struggle with the
authorities and and after a tough start
for the for the best guest hour
substrate which is now mix of composted
wheat compost and different levels of
biochar we actually came out on part
like head of the commercial potting mix
across that trial and looked like it no
World War III really you don't smell P
after like the first imediate
application if you put it on a soil or
soil likee
substrate okay so so generally P works
well our hours work well if you blend
them right um so we're trying to kind of
hit bionutrient circulated against
conventional they've got the high yields
we've got these other arguments they've
got a lot of you know the dings on them
that I mentioned in the
downsides uh presentation but we got a
bunch of downsides too and one of them
might be that there's a lot of salt in
our diets and therefore in our urine so
there's a bunch of other problems as
well so hitting the salt here I'm just
looking at the kale tissue yeah the kale
came out saltier on Weeds more so on the
hours than on the soil the substrates
came out saltier on the hours and also
on the soil um but would really have a
big effect on the yield we're doing some
wash out experiments I'll mention here
so this last year we did three different
experiment a lettuce a tomato and a
lettuce experiment I'm sorry showing the
Tomato because I won't say anything
further about that for the moment but
just to show that on this incredibly
badl looking mix of wheat straw ma
rudely CH ma right off the combine and
so some compost plus minus biochar the
plants really are pretty indifferent I
mean they're just they're they're quite
competitive with soil which is totally
weird and unexpected um so again we're
we're benchmarking well in terms of
lettuce yield soil's a little worse off
here probably because we overdose the
synthetic a little sorry the synthetic
on soil because I think we did a little
initial overdosing but you can see that
it's growing quite well urine versus
Miracle Grow here um so looking now at
um water flush level we'd put up the
high tunnel at dilman so we could manage
the water trying to explore this issue
of what about the salt levels and so
this is the first lettuce season on the
organic underutilized resources more
water is better more water is better on
hours on soil and this is sorry on I I
screwed that up did I no oh sorry urine
synthetic
nutrient um our soil our soil so the the
urine is doing sort of better overall
and more waterers better so is it a salt
thing um it seems like not as far as we
can tell um this is the one of the few
cases where we get a biochar effect
because usually we're not stressing it
it seems biochar steps to the rescue
apparently when there's either water
nutrient or other or too much ammonia
stress in this case this is the low
flush medium and High flush different
amounts of water per 20 lit
sack and um the urine treatment I
thought would be getting better over the
time but with no biochar it's getting
worse by this third season and it's much
worse with Ohio wash out so maybe the
biochar is just holding nutrients for
that um for that crop when the high wash
out is just washing nutrients out of the
this is all the hours so um anyway
that's the the only significant effect
here but it is quite striking that our
third season the third season with this
set of same set of sacks are starting to
look pretty pretty shabby with urine so
there's something something is maybe um
there's something that we need to amend
possibly those micronutrients that are
initially supplied by the organic
materials and they're not adequately
provided in the in the
urine anyway so glad that Jesse's here
because he and colleagues and Christina
we're also exploring this idea that that
we can frame this issue as a matter of
nutrient sovereignty for people for whom
that concept is Meaningful so the new
our buddies in New York feel like that
kind of resonates with them the um black
gardeners um organiz ation they like
that concept apparently and um so this
is an experiment with some uh
indigenously uh crops of interest to the
indigenous students that Jesse's
representing and um that's uh skunk
beans and tobac and uh ceremonial
tobacco and these are urine plus or
minus would urine and synthetic plus or
minus uh uh wood vinegar and we testing
other other fertig against fish effluent
from the aquaculture Enterprise FR from
the Black soldierly Enterprise and the
the tobacco showed a strong yield effect
um where synthetic and urine were fine
and these others were not um beans did
not show a strong yield effect but they
showed a very strong uh protein content
effect per nitrogen effect so um I
thought that was quite interesting and
um notable that the these pale plants
you know clearly weren't getting
nutrient Le treatments the fish I flu
and fr um and they they responded by
just having more carbohydrates and less
protein um so anyway going forward we're
looking at how different ingredients
especially non ours the biochar the
mineral component that we could dope in
there and fertig can influence the
biology the chemistry and the physics of
the situation we're looking at um
Christina's leading work on nematodes
and fungi uh Forest is working work with
uh Steve vanic on ecoplates to look at
the bacteria populations and communities
better understanding the chemical
situations here and some of the physical
Transformations that occur um size
particle distribution shifts and how
they occur um so so we're excited about
some of the experiments we have on
greenhouse gases in in particular now in
this this uh in this winter um
Christina's done a bit of work on that
on a larger scale thinking here about
how com what are the implications for
these matters when you're looking at
composting a domestic and Municipal
scales which is a big deal because
legally you have to compost if you're
big operation New York State Vermont
everybody has to compost everything
organic and uh it's not going to be all
Yugo gardening um do we have
implications for for larger scale
composting and here Christina is
comparing um leaves uh without biochar
fertigated with water or urine leaves
with 5% biochar water and urine and you
can see that without biochar urine is
getting a lot more nitrous oxide
powerful greenhouse gas and that's not
the case when the 5% biochar is there so
this is very preliminary
a b uh it's also expected based on the
literature C I think it could be a big
deal because I'm a master
composter um I didn't hear word one
about B Char the entire Master
composting training you
know and I feel like yeah we should be
jamice we got to make put this in here
and we know that composting can lead to
high greenhouse gas emissions especially
you start using urine which I'm pushing
for but biochar mineral additives can
reduce ghd production during composting
this again is you know somewhat
established not not to Gene bone and
satisfaction apparently but we learned
about green green brown green right
green green and brown composting
sandwiches I think it should be black
and gold you
know that's my serial residues anyway so
I think there are practical implications
there that we could work on um and and
we are sort of reaching into the
community with our Yugo gardening at the
soil Factory these are PE powered raised
beds with yard waist and whatever we've
got stuffed inside we put urine around
the we frame it in straw bales and put
Ur on the straw bales and then between
Seasons dump that now onto the garden
and rebuild it with new straw
bales um nice indigenous
um uh gardening component to that really
nicely um and then this is sort of some
of those same types of gardens up here
at the dilman hill D an organic farm um
again because it's suitable because of
that contaminated soil Legacy um we you
know leasing with our friends and family
down in New York to see you know does
this have implications for green cities
they're interested in using biochar in
the Bronx and that it's quy Joseph's
terms so I think we we' got a nice
collaboration sort of inching forward in
that
regard anyway so how about
contaminants
um I'm not going to say much about it
but there is some emerging literature
people often ask you know what about
pharmaceuticals we take in a lot they
come out you know just like our
nutrients come out our P so do our
Pharma anyway there's in uh some initial
indication from other groups that this
uh High nitrogen fertilizer value and
low uptake of Pharma it's probably not
fair to just leave it at that but I will
leave it at that now um I did spend a
year working on this n National's panel
about exploring linkages between soil
Health and Human Health and
contamination was one of the big themes
that came out there so that gave me a
chance to kind of get on the boards with
my mot toxin point the links between
soil health and mot toxins this point
about
excreta but you know just this issue of
of contaminants is huge in soil Health
more broadly nothing you know with or
without you know anything to do with M
with what I'm talking about today and um
yet this circularity will only compound
those concerns um and I just want to
point out that one of the the raay of
hope that our committee found was that
paralysis in my primitive realization
here in a contiki um the of any at any
scale the process of you know heating
material Organics at really high
temperatures can break Bonds in organic
contaminants your Pharma your P even and
also the product is helpful in
immobilizing the same bad things
including you know non non-organic
contaminants heavy metals and stuff so
so this is something that I think is
important in that
regard so
oops um I wanted to update you a bit
also about what I'm most excited about
which is what what we've got going on in
Kenya both in Rural and in urban
contexts so I'm bringing you here to the
Republic of Kenya and it's little corner
of Lake Victoria so that's Lake Victoria
the Kenyon corner has this little pinch
off thing called the nans go where
you're getting increasing likelihood of
harmful algal blooms as you get a little
piece of the lake pinched off you can
see that they're they're becoming
increasingly likely wherever People Meet
the lake so land and Lake not friends
here a simplest thing you could do is
just put pee on the farms so so this is
going on in our in mumas here so I'll
start at mumas and then take us down to
the city um but the farmers were not
super Keen they thought that was gross
um when we discussed all the possible
things you can do if you're able to sore
separate urine you can put on your crop
on your raised bed your compost or you
make this nice fertilizer they were down
with a compost angle they they know they
need to improve their soils they're
making compost and they're like okay
with the idea of doping it up with their
bodily nutrients they got super pumped
about this if you're in mumas now and
you pee you're a kid and you pee here or
there like you always used to do you are
in trouble because you need to be
gathering that up for your crops so
they're big into the um composting they
they form a farmer research Network um
they've got formal experiments informal
experiments um the the farmer leader
Haron here still wearing his badge from
our C Ben meeting
um um he he dug out all the pitet trees
and he included the material oh I know
as a way out of of me I'm like also not
having about that but it worked great I
got to say anyway they're going gang
busters and moving back to kumu on that
nansa Gulf um we got excited about the
you know hot quenched there's some
evidence from the literature that hot
quenched um biochars performs
particularly well so it's going be hot
quenching um in three years of
experiments the the P quench biochar was
performing with the chemical fertilizer
against the water quenched and control
and you know we want to improve the
rigor
and uh design of these experiments but
you know we're we're encouraged by the
fact that that this stuff is performing
well so far and and what we want to take
it bigger now henya is the home for the
biggest sour Sebring Sanitation Company
in the world cergy they serve as over
150 plus PE thousand plus people in
Nairobi they make
fertilizers and other and black soldier
flies and other products from the poop
there they dump the pee um so they're
already showing that you can tie up
sanitation and fertilizer production
there to some extent and they've got a
sub uh whatever a a branch that's moved
out to kisuma in Western Kenya uh and
this is their fact toilet Factory on the
on the wastewater treatment plant um
territory they also have in the same
town you know really vibrant uh
Community Based organization called Kia
Kum kisumu Young agripreneurs that's um
Roy who runs it and they've got black
soldier flies producing all these AG
inputs and consolidating product and so
you know obviously I had a bright idea
that they could team up so last time I
was in Kenya uh we all came to the table
our dining room table at our Shack there
um so that's Florence who runs Fresh
Life in kisumu that's uh Roy who runs at
Kia that's Charles dega my my big
collaborator uh this this individual is
paid by Johannes to coordinate the
regional circular B economy Network Eric
Bala that's uh you may know Bella from
from here who also co-runs that that
Network um and they're like heck yeah
let's do it so so here's that map
of the neanda informal settlement SLO
there um
uh reaching out to the the water body
there the wastewater treatment plan and
agriculture here and the more middle
class neighborhood here so Florence
provided the the
GPS uh locations of all the toilets they
service in this slum neighborhood and um
Keith at man Library helped me map it
and I you can see the different
collection paths so we we can choose you
know and take as many of these
collection paths as we want for for our
experiments or our business here so
we're starting we worked with a I worked
with this
uh um operations research team at here
at Cornell to kind of figure out how we
could work out the logistics and
hopefully keep keep working that out um
I'm working on a system Dynamic model to
show in principle how the positive
feedback loops of getting more people to
to to to pay for the sanitation service
because the cost is lower if if he is
taking the job of surfacing the toilets
off the back of fresh life and making
fertilizer and then you get a positive
feedback loop as we put
more nutrients into the corn fields get
more corn out get more maze out pize
more get more yield Etc um photo credit
David work in progress um I rarely do
anything but I'm making the darn models
I want to credit but thank you David for
um so anyway so there's a lot of
challenges I mentioned of which
sociocultural are obviously leeding
lights there um so just to say that um
how do we how do we change how we think
and feel about our excreta um this is a
tiny slice of the porta potties if
you've ever been to Slope Day you know
porta potties as far as the eye can see
I should make a video of how many I mean
you can even have cuter porta potties in
that for heaven sake so we you know so I
really we really want us like do some
you know go big to collect our PE here
we did a little collection effort and at
forch Fest one time these two young
women are the only people who took the
time to look at my technical information
around the subject they turned out to be
Cornell engineers and they got us into
the um Cornell Chronicle for their plant
Parenthood app um I'm super obsessed
with potties yeah Yan probably Gonna
Roll his shut off about the potty but
you know how to make the potty
experience more fun and beautiful and
and uh you know save the world while
you're peeing uh so we got a couple of
collection points here Cornell Public
Health student is helping helped us make
some nice propaganda about that um so
you know just collecting once a week off
a couple spots please contribute to
plant science and Emerson um she also
made some more outward leaning sort of
gardener oriented propaganda here um not
sure we've had any impact the soil
Factory is sort of all about this sort
of subject and johannas put on this
Workshop where we made all these cute um
kidney books and art products around
circular B neutrient economy
um sorry to keep giving you credit you H
but really making this East African
circular B nutrient economy Network
happen so it's got a biochar an excr
component this is the carbon Trader
showing us how it's done with this
ridiculous but very enlightening skit
that they put on that's the Cornell
delegation David and others um the rich
Earth Institute gets credit I think for
for bringing a Global Network together
we just had that 10th Annual sum Summit
Christina was there in person
many of us there were were there
virtually um but they're really making a
very Dynamic many-dimensional
Community come to life there so so
what's it really going to take to drive
change you know we talked about the
opportunities local nutrient value nut
nutrient sovereignty environmental
health uh you know us in our fabulous
activities but really maybe it's the
past crisis where we can't we can't land
apply our product anymore and there's no
carbon going back to the
um to the land um more more than half of
us biosolids are now land applied we now
recognize the hazards if you bring
nutrient your bodily nutrients pre
contaminated with all sorts of gross
things including pasas I think if a few
wastewater treatment can't plants get
hurt by these major storm effects you
know people are going to think twice
about putting in the many billions
billions of dollars it takes a up one
plant um sea whether there's a disaster
or not sea levels and then 10 million
people are out of service on the US
coasts if the if the water goes up three
feet long before they're washing away
the plants it's going to corrode them
and put them out of business 10 million
people with three three meters a heck of
lot more with with more than that and
then just even maintaining wastewater
treatment plants and running them cost
one to two% of the global energy budget
so but I really think that we've got to
play our role here we've got to show how
it's
done Christine and I are teaching in
class about this but know can we please
get the N nutrient producers serving the
nutrient users the farms and whatnot
using you know learning how to use these
different transformation methods you
know using our food waste and excr more
creatively anyway it's a journey but
hopefully you know we'll individually
transition through this disgust to to
Comedy to embrace collectively from the
sort of dealing with nutrients as a
problem to dealing with them as a bloody
resource
and and seeing that as part of a wider
transition to a circular
eony
you yeah I'm sorry I didn't like longer
but well really excited about the ideas
you presented really interesting um I
know you said you didn't want to focus
too much on the issue of pharmaceuticals
and the urine but I I do have a concern
about particularly hormones and birth
control hormones that I know come out in
urine and are very prevalent
particularly you know places like the
United States um and I'm wondering if
you envision some kind of regulatory you
know testing either for plants or for
urine going onto plants you know how how
would we make sure that we're not
getting into another loop of you know
contaminant spreading like happened with
biosolids or sludge well the hormones
are are are such a identifiable in
particular question I think we you just
ask and answer that question yeah the
problem I have is that there's so many
Pharmaceuticals out there that if you
take it as a class it's much more
difficult to answer but you can assay
for hormones probably with a simply Lia
or something I mean you can ask that
question so I
haven't but I think it's very
practicable to ask that question does it
get into the food or not into what
extent um it seems like there' have to
be some regular testing not just a
one-time thing you know if it's a
regular application that we're using as
a food system supplement how would we
how would we I think you can ask as a as
a science question to what extent do
Pharmaceuticals come through the soil
plant food access I think that's
something you could ask and then you
don't have to test every food item you
know it does or does not come through if
it does come through then we have to
pull the nitrogen out the phosphorus out
without the whole GES right so and
that's very doable that's what we're you
know Johan that's I'm giving yanas that
angle I mean I work on that too but but
um but in principle I'm sort of a dump
it on person um but I but I take your
point that if you've got a specific
hypothesis you can test it then you can
know it's not going to suddenly start
accumulating in plants when it doesn't
accumulate PL right so so I do think
that if you have a particular system and
a particular um hypothesis or particular
question then we should definitely add
and it's probably actually known and I
just don't haveen to have it on thank
you so much thank
you it strikes me there must be a lot of
research on this in China uh when I go
to uh villes in China and I visit
friends houses it's the recyclable
toilet and you know that's been going
for a long long time and my point is
they must have done also research on
these things that are now coming into
the stream so I'm just absolutely I mean
they get credit for like the time of
Memorial category for sure they're sort
of the you know have have done have kept
their food system going for all of time
with that very explicitly as an accepted
practice more lately I see it
unfortunately that they're kind of going
modern and to some extent walking away
from that but it's still going on in the
Hinterlands and they are a part of that
Dynamic e research ecosystem for sure
you know if you're tracking the
literature you can Bank on them being
really doing a lot of cool stuff a lot
of it's frankly you know over my
head but I mean but but credit to them
for going into it and yeah I had
actually hoped to go to to China last
year to sort of do a circular economy
tour partly to be like trying to Lobby
to not have them walk away from their
historical ownership of it topic but
take credit and pride in that maybe and
and recognize the fact that they in fact
are on the Innovations FR here for
it questions
forca give her one
more this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu