issues or concerns that they've had with
what they've been doing um in order to
do deep Zone
pillage recommendations to grow I
got can I see it I
didn't
um are there particular
photos either of you would like to put
up
there go ahead I don't have a problem
the only one of mine there is 13 or 20
20 20 is my okay 20 is my little tiller
see you did H pictures up there huh I
told you you had pictures up there I
know that's the only
one
okay but you also have an uner I've got
a six row uner for the for my main crops
cuz I'm primarily a grain grower but I
built that two Row for my strawberries
and uh it's a pretty simple little
machine and as you can tell right there
it works awfully good if you're as long
as you have your cover crop or
clean ground ahead of time in other
words that's a field that had Rye in it
was sprayed in the fall and I use that
for strawberri so I'm doing that about
the first week in April or last week in
March as soon as I can get in the field
to get it ready so I can plant my
strawberries in April and uh all it is
is two chisel Shanks and then two sets
of closing covering uh for um cters on
the back to shape up a ridge um it's a
two machine I pull it about 13 or 14
inches deep and I'm pulling it with a 30
horsepower tractor right there is all
but there's no fancy equipment on it if
I had the only thing I would have to be
different if I had a uh a cover crop a
heavy cover crop ahead of time I'd need
a cter in front of that to cut through
and there's a tool bar in the front
there I made so I could put one on but
I've never needed it so I've only got
just the the chisels in the middle and
the cters in the back and how deep are
the chisels about 13 or 14 in
no fertilizer or anything on mean it'd
be easy to put a little tank on there
and run a a hose with a nozzle down the
back of each chisel point you could put
fertilizer 8 in deep if you were going
to grow sweet corn or some other crop
that needed nitrogen you could put it on
with that 8 Ines or so put about half
your nitrogen on early with that and
then put the other half on top when you
plant your crop but I don't need it for
the berries so I don't do
that any question questions about
that and then uh where is an unreferred
slide um
Betsy
yeah why machine isn't in there it's too
big Betsy where is an uner slide over
number number 16 looks like a good bit
okay one above it too isn't it one uh it
might be one right that one there yeah
that might be an unreferred that's there
that one is the one above it
nine yeah that's an unre machine yeah
that's like
mine yep and uh the advantages
disadvantages of
that
well that that the only difference
between that and mine I've replaced
those baskets on the back with CER
Packer uh little rollers CER Packer
Wheels I think it makes a little more it
makes a better uh rad to plant in
because it firms the soil a little bit
uh I like that machine because it's got
the straight Shanks we've all we're
trying to do with that is to make a slot
in the ground that the plant roots can
follow down is below the compacted
layers I like that better than the
parabolic shanks because the parabolic
shanks pull up more Stones than that
will so that's a if you're in a Stony
situation that machine is a cleaner one
to run um I've been using my for 15
years and it pulls you know takes about
half as much power to pull it now as it
did when I started it gets better and
better every single year in fact I'm to
the point now on my gravel and good LOM
ground I don't do that anymore I just
strip till plant on top of the ground
but in the heavier ground heavy clay I
still do that and uh but I put Coler
Packer Wheels on the back to break the
clouds up and do a little compaction on
that road firm it up before I'm going to
plant I prefer to do it in the fall if
somebody body needed to know when in
which case I take that back piece right
off I don't need to firm the slot and I
don't need to use the basket so I just
have the closing discs and the big shank
in the front in the fall and then let
mother nature take care of of uh firming
up the row and then just went and plan
on it in the spring so I prefer to do it
in the fall if I have a choice um loosen
the ground and get that slot made so
that freezing and thawing and whatever
will take care of it but if you have to
do it in the spring then you need either
that basket or color pack of wheels or
something on the back or you're going to
have the soil is going to be too loose
to plant in well you can plant in it but
it's better if you put something on the
back there that doesn't really break up
the clouds that well no that was a the
problem George did mine before I started
um he and I talked about I said I wonder
what would happen if you put a color
Packer wheel on there cuz I've got
cloudier ground than he does and works
better yeah that he did it afterwards
and that was uh that seem to be the
answer for breaking the clouds up yeah
especially in that um we had a dry year
and then we really wanted people to go
to the culter Packers to seal that
moisture that's right that's right if it
was wet um maybe then the basket's okay
because it'll probably break the clouds
up if it's wet anyway the question in
two things in the heavy ground which is
where that thing really is needed you're
going to get clouds if you get clouds
you got to do something with them you
don't just leave them there to dry out
and get hard and then try to plant
through them so you you know if the
basket will break up your clouds fine
and dandy if won't the cuip Packer
wheels will do a better job of that but
if it's really really wet you're going
to get too much with that you know then
you got to take the spring off and do
everything to keep it so it doesn't push
down quite so hard and so it's a it's a
question every year what the ground is
like what kind of soil is it what field
you're in you don't do it the same way
in every field every year you have to be
able to make some adjustments but the
the shank the The Cutting disc in the
front the shank and then the two closing
discs stay the same no matter where you
are and that's all you use in the fall
and and that's another reason I like to
do it in the fall because it's generally
drier in the fall the soil's in better
condition and you're not worried about
it wet in the spring because if you do
it in the fall make your Row in the fall
it'll dry out in the spring if it's a
wet spring all by itself and the clouds
will be gone from from Mother Nature so
you don't have to deal with those issues
if you do your your deep tail or your
ripping in the fall I think that's a
better way to
go one of one of the things that uh I
would have I've kind of toyed with the
idea of adding to mine was um a set of
rolling baskets not rolling baskets but
um trash uh trash cleaners in front of
the the Ripper Point
uh yeah um just when we're using the one
row Setter to set either seeds or uh
transplants trash can be a problem if
you let it get too too tall and uh even
if you kill it round up if you let it
get Woody at all you got to kind of keep
it you spray it when it's in a grass
single blade form or you're going to run
into problems well um okay we've got uh
what what slide is that that you're
referring to here now with the Trash
Wheels let's
see um can you hear me Carol it's number
eight number eight okay
yep so when I built my unit I didn't
leave enough room to put any stuff on
um I didn't really think about pre roll
I was trying to get um a real aggressive
point on the thing to get down deep and
um I've tried to put stuff after it and
it doesn't really work I guess I could
probably put a set of roll cleaners
right before my my Hiller disc in the
back um you know that could possibly
work or run it after run the Hiller disc
and then run these after um I've kind of
I've looked at the things several
different ways and I've got it set
pretty good so it works well the way it
is so I just I've never really taken the
time to mess with putting these things
on but see those in that picture are
like my planner you put those on the
front of your planner yeah so I'm I'm
wondering why you couldn't put those on
the front of your transplanter that's
where they belong clean that road just
before you get right there with the
transplanter yeah but you have to don't
you have to go like 5 miles an hour or
something make work they'll work that
slow yep on a transp well I'm not sure
they work place inther half properly the
floating ones which you know got the
depth B
that's that does a nice job of cleaning
even at the like a qu M hour half really
just like a garden R okay okay trying to
R the cloud and that's then you don't
have to deal with garage out of the way
but they got to be free floating right
at least might they got to have those
Wheels Treader Wheels on the side depth
wheels so they don't go too deep
okay the floating ones will never make a
gouge a trench great too many get you
know our complex topography Hills
sideways everything they they will gouge
on you sometimes that's not good you go
too fast or you have them too deep and
then you end up with a depression with
all this junk on the side collects water
and yeah collect it collects water and
it's it's murder if you got uh
processing snap beans or dry beans
because you've got your row is below is
starting below the level of the soil
snap beans need to have that mini Mount
still intact so that so um uh Carol and
um Jim and Lynn and George um I have
this picture up this is Anu um of the
The Trash Wheels and I do know that umer
has made an adapt uh they have created
um a mounting unit for in front of the
cutting disc that you can actually put
trash CLE that's where it belongs right
on the disc that's where it belongs
right in front of the cutting disc
they've made a unit so I wanted to make
sure folks are new about that um I
before we move around for questions I
wanted to see if um uh Lynn if you had
any other comments on how you got
started
um well basically I was struggling on on
either dry years or excessively dry
years or excessively wet years um my
ground would pond on a wet year and on a
dry year nothing would grow um that's
kind of what got me started into it and
between a little urging from George and
um Gary site we had tried Zone tillage
without any
ripping first year I had tried it I I
thought that's where I had to go cuz it
worked it was beautiful we got a rain
right after I planted everything came
out of the ground the pumpkins were
beautiful that year the next year I
expanded again had George uh plant my
winter squash in pumpkins and it was a
total failure it was so dry that year uh
the plants didn't germinate when they
did germinate they really didn't grow
well um the missing ingredient seemed to
be the ripping and making that slot
giving it a place to grow uh the
following year if you go back uh um do
your pictures there I started out with a
one shank Ripper that I it was just a
subsoiler I had that I used for some
drainage it's picture number
six U that's that was my first
experiment right there I I took that
went down through and I ripped four rows
um in the middle of a tomato field on a
clay null where nothing would grow
anyway with the attitude that if nothing
if it doesn't work well nothing was
going to grow there anyway so I'm really
not out anything um I went through with
Then followed up with a a cub with
Hiller discs on it we went back and
forth through a couple times break the
clouds up trans used a conventional
transplanter planted into it first thing
I noticed was the transplanter worked
better than it ever had before planning
on that mound a nice soft Mound second
thing I noticed was again it was a it
started out to be a really dry spring
the transplants hit the ground and just
started running from the minute they hit
the ground the the plants looked way
better than the tomato plants on either
side of the four rows the test strip all
season long I mean us the they grew
faster it looked like I had you know
used a different fertilizer program or
something everything was the same um we
had pictures somewhere I don't know if
we have them here today or not but the
final result with the the yield
difference was
unbelievable uh quality everything the
tomatoes were bigger there was more
tomatoes on a plant um so that was
that's what got me started and I've been
experimenting ever since um I think it's
pitcher 28 or 21 or something um the
following year I built a two row unit
which included the Hillary disc try to
do everything in one
pass was in the PTT you sent us um yeah
but she cut some okay would so many okay
it's similar to George's actually but
the only difference is I've got straight
Shanks on mine um and I've got a a set
of spider wheels that run behind the
Ripper
uh Ripper shank to to kind of break up
the clouds and um it does roll some of
the side and stuff out of the way a
little bit and then it's followed up by
two Hiller discs they um the
concave Hiller discs okay to to throw a
nice the mound I throw is probably like
8 to 10 inches high I like a good High
Mound so after it settles you you've
still got a mound there but um every
experiment that I've done with this so
far has been positive um from planting
four rows I've take that two row Ripper
and go out in the middle of a 10 acre
cornfield and rip four rows plant
directly into it you can drive across
the end of the field on a pickup truck
don't even get out of the truck the corn
is 6 Ines to a foot taller than the corn
on both sides of it it's just I haven't
had one bad experience with it yet it
seems for me it's been the way to go you
you had a significant compaction problem
yes on a light soil right yeah it
wouldn't per at all
right which is Not Unusual on vegetable
soil till panss yeah so so I um I wanted
to just H here um I wanted to take a a
minute to go around all the locations
and see if we had any questions because
we wanted to move on to some of the
Growers on Long Island who have used
different equipment so before we move on
I'm going to just look at the Growers
that are here with us in the room in
itha do you have any questions for
George yes go ahead George when you when
you uh till in the fall do you have a
hard time finding your rose in the
spring no no CU I end up with about a 6
in 6 to 7 in wide clean tilled strip
there with a mound and it's still
visible in the spring I mean you have to
do fall weed control is the best option
for Zone tillage anyway and so the
strips are still there in the spring I
don't have any
trouble we have one more question from
itha are you doing that zone tilling in
the fall into into a cover crop that'll
winter kill or into a rye that's still
alive in the spring or near uh no both a
lot of it is into soybean ground that's
going to go back to sweet corn or
something so there isn't any cover crop
there it's too late I may plant Rye but
then I do the the Deep till early enough
that the rise is barely coming up it
comes up afterwards and then we have to
kill it in the spring but but um I've
done it when like I for my pumpkins I
usually do it either very late in the
fall or very early in the spring into
standing rye and again I don't have a
problem getting through the Rye or
seeing the rose when I get ready to
plant killed R it's killed R yeah right
so you won't you won't want to try to
plant into green Ry well you don't want
to plant in anything green if you can
help it that side it'll just it'll make
a mess and it'll ball up and you you've
got to kill that crop whatever you plan
into make sure it's dead if that if that
zone Builder has a good cutting disc
ahead of that shank you can Zone build
through anything but you can't plant
through anything green you want to make
sure everything is dead when when you
get there with the
planner takes about a month um you want
to spray what I found is 3 weeks to four
weeks before three weeks yeah yeah can
hear me um can we move on to Long Island
any questions for George or
Lynn go ahead go ahead and ask a
question yeah we've got a couple
questions okay what kind of PL what kind
of planter are you
using me yeah John Deere John Deere
7000 same here um I also use a
conventional it's an old uh new idea
transplanter yeah um I use that then I
have a newer style with a uh the finger
pickup uh for the the transplants also
but there's nothing I've done nothing no
modifications to the transplanters we
just um if you if you build a clean
Mound that's something I failed to
mention earlier too you're going to have
seasons where you you may have to go
back over over that where you ripped I I
with a two row Ripper I will go through
it One Direction if I don't have a nice
clean seat bed I will turn around and go
back the opposite direction uh at the
same time and that usually does enough
to it breaks up the clouds and clears up
the gives you a nice clean seed bed a
nice mound to plant into um make sure it
looks good you want it to look the way
you got to be happy with the way it
looks or you won't be happy with the the
end result so um just make sure you got
a clean place to
start any other questions from Long
Island yeah I'm just wondering about
having a rolling basket followed by a
Cula Packer or some of our Growers have
tried two rolling baskets just to have a
really good bed and this would be um
Zone building in the spring what do you
think of those
ideas uh don't see any reason it
wouldn't work I've not done that I've
either had the basket or the CER Packer
I haven't had both but I it should be
all right I think the key in the if is
to have the CER Packer one place or the
other so you get the firming up of that
row if you're going to do it in the
spring you don't have very long for
mother nature to do that for you so you
want to do it
yourself
okay to
Jeffer I I have like two questions one
is uh there was a comment made that
someone doing the ripping along with the
Zone building after a period of time was
able to not do that ripping anymore how
long did it take before you got to that
point I don't know I'm at the point and
it's been different each field is
different um my heavy ground I still do
the ripping the heavy clay because it
just seals up so hard every year but I
haven't done any ripping on some grally
LOM around where I live probably for the
last oh I'd say 5 years and I've been
doing zone tillage for 15 or 16 years so
I probably could have quit quicker the
ray rosson when I started tried to tell
everybody that you could do it two years
in a row you do your ripping one year
and then you split the middles the
second year and then you don't have to
do it anymore as long as you don't mess
the soil up and you may have been right
I don't know I never had nerve enough to
do it that way so I probably went six or
seven or eight years before I quit doing
The Ripping on the good soil but the
heavy clay I still rip every
year thank you and then the second
question is you have a John Deere 7000
do you have a gang of couters in front
of each planner row nope I I have a I'm
uh up until this year I've had the old
unur cart that had a tank and cters on
the cart three cters to the row and pull
the planner behind it this year I'm
going to have a set of uh Trash Wheels
like you saw on that other picture on
the front with a single disc fertilizer
applicator off to one side for each row
and I won't use the card anymore I don't
need it the cart was needed when I
started because if you put the cters on
the planter 15 years ago you couldn't
get the planter in the ground the ground
was too hard so I got the cart which you
could put 500 gallons of fertilizer in
or water or whatever for weight and you
could get the thing in the ground but
I'm to the point now I don't have any
problem anymore so this from now on I
won't use the cart I have the same 7,000
planner but it has a a no till cter just
one cter in front of each row uh does a
pretty good job I have two neighbors
that have switched to uh Zone till not
if you want to call it that both of them
have kiny Planters and they started with
a cter like the one that's in that
picture there the a single cutting cter
in the front no till couter with a
fertilizer unit on and they don't do the
Deep ripping anymore they're in the same
shape I'm in uh but they're grain
producers and they have a lot of trouble
with that getting the planter in the
ground so everybody around me has taken
the no till couter off and the
fertilizer opener they've gone to a
smooth straight slicer disc for the
fertilizer opener so that they don't
have trouble with those openers holding
the planter up out of the
ground great um why don't we move then
last to Massachusetts Andy do you have
any questions from Growers at your site
do we have any questions on uh these
folks equipment
situation let me uh hand off the mic
here uh I think it was George who said
he only goes 13 inches deep is that
really adequate to get the plow pan on
your Fields because here our Fields have
been farmed about 350 years and packed
continually and I have to go down 17 or
18 in to get below it wow okay what I
was talking about was that two Row one
that I built for my strawberries there's
no compaction layers in that field cuz
I've zoned tilled for years so I go down
12 or 13 in when I plant strawberries
the big machine that's the regular under
Earth for planting soybeans or sweet
corn or pumpkins I go about 17 or 18 in
if in the clay in the fields where I
have done it a number of years and I
don't have any compaction anymore again
I still only go 10 or 12 in there's no
reason to go any deeper if you don't
have a density layer and it pulls a heck
of a lot easier 10 in deep than it does
18 so once you've done it a few years
you can quit going so deep if you don't
mess it up and go back in there with a
plow or disc or something and put a
layer back in you need to measure your
compat right penetrometer you need a
penetrometer or a a tile rod or
something so you can detect where your
compaction layer is so you can rip just
a little deeper
right which is I check every
field um uh is there any other questions
there I'm sorry any other questions
here looks like that's it okay great
Lynn um I'm sorry I cut you off you had
a comment no I just start to say I I
check every field um I go around once or
twice and I jump off and uh take the
penetr and I'll check in the rip and
make sure I'm I'm breaking through the
hard Pan um then that's how I determine
how deep I have to go in each field so
most of the time I just run it all the
way down but um you can tell I just kind
of listen to the Tractor you can some
Fields you can you can tell it's pulling
a lot easier I'll just jump off and
check in if I don't have to run it as
deep I will tend to pick it up a little
bit and uh do it that way so great um
all right I think what we want to do is
um uh we' got one more question can we f
go
ahead Yes actually I have two questions
one question would
be assuming it's dry enough in the
spring is there any good reason not to
do the no tillage preparation in the
spring because conventionally on Long
Island we have Sandy loyal uh LOM soils
if we do feeli preparation the season
before in the fall we have wind and or
water
erosion I I do all of mine in the spring
um I cover crop with Rye on all just
about all of my ground um and again like
I said three weeks to four weeks before
I'm going to rip I'll go through and
spray with Roundup and then go back
through um and and do my my tillage and
that that seems it's been a pretty good
combination for me so I don't have a
problem with spring as long as you can
do the ripping two or three weeks ahead
of when you're going to plant to let
that row get healed up and if you put
the CER Packer on the back you'll do a
little better job the problem is that
slot will stay open and you'll have
loose soil for a while for a short
period after you do it until you get a
heavy rain or until it just naturally
settles in so I don't like it in the
spring if you got to do it with right
away and then try to plant right
afterwards we had a trial in Wayne
County uh with Mike stanard some years
ago on beans and the guy ripped today
and he planted the beans tomorrow and
they were terrible because he's planting
beans in a 1inch wide slot that's
nothing but a big air pocket you have to
either do it in the fall or do it far
enough ahead in the spring so it heals
up all righty um let's oh can we um hit
our mutes thank you um I think it do we
have do we have Thomas on I don't see
him on yet okay all right so we wanted
to move to uh Long Island because we had
a Growers that were using some slightly
different uh some different equipment
there um and uh so do we have Jen
and yeah we're here Anu okay um so I did
make um I did put all of the pictures
for Jen's setup um on a PowerPoint and I
think Betsy sent that out this
morning um I will put it up on our
screen as well so you can all see
it so go ahead
Jen I'm just waiting for the picture so
I know what I'm talking
about hi this is Thomas I am
connected oh okay Thomas we'll be right
right with you okay I didn't see that is
a uh no till grain drill that we
purchased the sunflower 7t
wide um 7 and 1/2 foot wide so that we
can no till cover crops into the fields
that we are resting for a year we grow
pumpkins specifically one year at rest
one year is in pumpkins and one of our
biggest problems is fyora and keeping it
away because we don't have enough ground
to rotate in so we're trying to build up
the soil um to protect itself against
the phyas so the noil drill is given us
some options to try other cover crops
this past year we tried um oats and
Alfalfa uh that's it going down the
field um so you can see that it it does
a nice job in in the field without
tillage um we also used it to plant
sorghum Sudan grass and third we planted
our Rye in the fall um which is about
about three bushels to the acre and then
we use the Rye in the
springtime as the mulch for the
pumpkins that is our Zone Builder that
was earlier in the season when we were
just testing it out and we had what
they're called the shark tooth reduced
um residue managers and there in the
front of the couter and then we also had
shark tooth behind the couter and we
found
we had about four bushel of Rye to the
acre this past year so there was a lot
of residue on the field and we found
that the even the two sets of shark
teeth residue managers were not clearing
enough to make a nice zone so what we
did was we got more aggressive residue
managers behind the couter and there
should be another
picture that might be the one I can't
really see it
well and that's it yeah that's right
that was earlier in the season there
that's the two shark teeth and right
there there's hardly any residue but the
pictures previous that's where we had a
ton of residue so we found that putting
the um more aggressive residue managers
behind the cter really helped push more
of the Ry
away this was our first year using this
Zone Builder um originally we've used a
water wheel transplanter to transplant
our pumpkins directly into the dry and
we were noticing that they weren't there
wasn't as good of a stand they weren't
growing as well and we knew that they
needed more and this Zone built up a
nice 8 in zone where with fluffy soil
and they grew very well um we just need
some more time to perfect it those are
some of the strips that you can see that
we prepared and um it made a nice little
Zone there and you can see the amount of
residue in between and there's a lot of
residue there even with all of that
residue though we had some trouble with
weeds so that's one of the questions
that we have is weed management and also
with that is also the and there's the
pumpkins and we put um tea tape down so
that we can water and also fertig with
and another one of our questions is
fertilizer inside this
Zone and is it being is are the weeds
taking away from the fertilizer and how
we can compete with the weeds so there's
two issues in here it's the taking care
of the weeds and also knowing if if we
need to do something different with our
fertilizer at this point in time we have
purchased a John Deere planter a pea
planter corn planter that we would like
to try seeding the pumpkins in the
ground rather than transplant planning
because it would take a lot less time
and
labor I don't know if there's any other
question how did you manage the Rye when
you got lot you said you got a lot of
Rye there how did you when did you cut
it at what stage did you cut it and how
did you get it that that manageable
we've tried several different we've
tried cutting it tall we've tried
cutting it short we have a flail Chopper
that we've used um we've had difficulty
with that when it's got too gotten Too
Tall so we use a ro rotary rotary mower
we'll cut it down and we'll go through
and fluff it up again um what we're
really interested in is rolling we had
just a roller that we used to roll our
lawn and we tried rolling some of the
the Rye and that seemed to but we found
that you can't go in the same direction
that you are with the Zone Builder
otherwise that ride just wraps right up
so we're considering trying this year
going Crossways and so we didn't know if
anybody had any um experience with the
rollers because there are rollers
available that we've seen on the front
of tractors right in front of their
planter and they go through and roll and
plant right at the same time so we're
interested in that as well we've rolled
high ride with a color Packer and then
planted right in
it pumpkins came up but we had problems
with
fertility oh sorry about that um Jen uh
I wanted to see if there was any
questions any of the questions from
Massachusetts from any of the Growers
there with the
system um we have one here hold
on this is Wally
zakowski we try and plant in as big a Ry
as possible but we don't cultipack it or
roll it or anything we just spray it
with Roundup it's usually in the head
stage when we do it and uh sometimes it
works and sometimes it doesn't it has to
be really really dry when we're working
it though so you don't tangle up when
it's wet it's like wire um I don't know
what's the advantage to knock going to
ride down that's what I don't
understand can you answer
that yeah I can answer it but give me a
half a day to think about it my
understanding is if you Let It Drop and
I've heard that from Steve gr that it it
falls in various directions and so it's
harder to plant
into so we've what we've done is we roll
and then we hit it with Roundup and
that's just to keep the drift
down I don't think you could run a Zone
Builder through large dry so if you're
looking to build a zone that might be a
a
problem the person from Yeta that we
talked with uh used the
analogy you you couldn't comb your hair
if one end wasn't
fastened and so rolling it down gives Z
more of an opportunity to
work I wonder if you could kill the Roy
when it's standing and go through the
Zone Builder when it's standing without
knocking it down cuz then you don't get
that once you knock it down even if you
go straight you still get that it's not
perfectly straight you still get that
mixing you know
and if it's but if it's standing you're
not going to get that
mixing it's upright you might be able to
go through with the machine and make a
and make your
Zone what about after with a planter
though the after the cedar or the
transplanter cedar cedar would go right
through it cuz you're not going to so
why don't we do we have any other
questions from
Massachusetts especially this if you're
not going to knock knock the dry down
doesn't that affect the light light
getting to the crop of
pumpkins it knocks down when you plant
it guys when you run the wheels of the
tractor will run it over and it'll knock
most of it down you're better off we
found George does it and I do it too go
leave it standing and go through that
way let the wheels of the tractor knock
it down both between your deep tillage
and your planning um it opens it up it
knocks probably 85 90% of it down then
the rest Falls within a couple weeks it
it'll fall down um it looks good after
you've finished if it's really dead the
cold through cut the qu the key is you
got to get the round up on the gry far
enough ahead so it's dead when you go to
plant it and I agree with Lyn I think I
can get through it with a Zone Builder
and the planner much better if I haven't
rolled it the one year that I did try
rolling it that it got too big you have
to go the same way with the roller you
can't go backwards or it all balls up
and I can't roll my field precisely
enough to know exactly where my planter
is going to go so I had big trouble that
year if you just kill it when it's about
24 inches tall or 30 Ines high and let
it fall down and you've done it three
weeks before you're going to plant
pumpkins your planter won't have and the
Deep taer won't have any trouble going
through there yeah and it even if you go
the same direction it still tends to
wind up on the on the wheels of the
planter y um I found it's far better to
just leave it standing when you go
through it and um it it doesn't seem to
ball up at all once in a while you get
some but for the most part it'll it
won't plug your wheels up and you don't
have to get back and chop that stuff out
of
there great thanks Lynn um uh because we
are behind schedule I'm going to ask
folks to hold their questions for Jen
and we'll come back to