get sorry we're a little bit late but
welcome everybody glad that you're here
and again um just to make sure that uh
just for the sake of being able to hear
each other that when you're not speaking
or we're not entertaining questions or
hearing from growers at your location
please hit the mute button facilitators
that would be awesome
okay so this is our second
um annual sort of video conference
focusing on transitioning to reduce
tillage
um i have a powerpoint that i'm using
and i'm assuming that
uh the powerpoint that you guys can see
that if you cannot see it please let us
know
all right
i'm gonna move to um just basically a
quick overview again of what our effort
has focused on we have been focusing for
the last several years on really trying
to help growers um
uh increase the use of reduced tillage
in their vegetable operations
so our efforts
the upper northeast and cooler areas of
the northeast
and we've been focusing our research and
education efforts with growers on
overcoming basic challenges that we know
exist and we're trying to overcome them
looking at weed management issues
dealing with soil quality soil
compaction
ensuring that we can actually get timely
harvest
of the crops that we're growing
dealing with pests and
looking at harvest strategies
there's been issues with processing
crops that we've had conversations
around
the other area of work that we have and
that we help people to develop and
identify equipment or strategies that
are appropriate for all scales
so much
there's a lot of equipment out there
that's available for larger operations
that can handle the four rows or six
journaling higher than that but dealing
with a small scale operations two-wheel
uh setup we've been really interested in
trying to work with growers and
developing units that are appropriately
at scaling
and then finally we want to we continue
to work to do demonstrations on farm and
on station we've got basically
a really exciting collaboration now that
goes across the northeast
to really test and make um make some of
these demonstrations available to
growers so they can actually look and
see how our crops performing
so um one thing that i wanted to do is
to highlight really quickly uh some of
the work that's going on we just got
funded recently by northeast sayre
and the focus is to look at deep zone
village which we're going to talk a lot
about today um to try to actually
address a particularly um uh difficult
pest
by toddler capsule
and our reason for taking this on and
looking at this is that we believe that
the soil management and soil quality
improvements in doing deep zone tillage
will actually reduce the speed of the
development of the disease in fields
that are affected
and um and so we have trials that are
going on um on farms that have a history
of the disease and we are looking for
more collaborators for this coming year
um but what we want to do is to be able
to uh look um both we have on station
trials at research firms believe it or
not we do have research farms at halfway
top or capsi and in fact it cultivated
in some ways
but we also then um doing charles on
farm over three years where we set up
fields that are paired
with deep zone tillage and then their
traditional conventional tillage
whatever you might be using
and on those fields we want to actually
look at soil moisture
soil water management changes in the um
the amount of saturation that we see in
fields and then eventually with a
susceptible crop see if we actually do
delay the onset of pcap
and so that people can harvest for a
longer period in those years we might
have
conducive
sort of moisture conditions for the
development of the disease
so
if you are interested and i put this out
there now so as we go through the day
and we have these conversations around
equipment and management and other
issues that if you are interested in
collaborating with us we would welcome
that uh we are looking for growers um
that have uh fields with a history of by
toth their capstone
and um you'd have to come we'd like to
have two fields on any farm so that we
know that there's different rotations
that people are using at this time and
so we want to be able to uh set up
fields where we do zone telegen part and
conventional in the others
and the goal is that over the next few
years that you're working with us that
you do grow a susceptible crop in these
fields at least once so that we can
actually look at the disease onset
and then we ourselves the team will
actually be at your firm and doing soil
health tests looking at
soil health soil quality water
infiltration soil moisture retention and
other aspects of how this system affects
soils in those particular fields
and as part of that we want to be able
to get a sense from all of you who are
doing these trials as to
are you seeing other benefits of doing
some improvements
until around labor hours school
practices management overall
impressions with the system
uh in addition particularly in new york
we have funding to help offset some of
the cost to set up a trial so if you
don't have this equipment but you want
to try zone tillage
we have some funding from both new york
farm viability we were reinstated with
our funding with that group
for one year and at least for one more
year we're not sure what the status is
of the new york farm viability institute
but we do hope that they continue to
receive funding to help growers
in agriculture in new york
but between farm viability and the the
new york state specialty crop research
initiative uh we have cost share funds
and these funds can be used to sort of
supplement and help a lower the cost of
renting equipment depending on the size
and certainly if you're four row or if
you can handle four row equipment you
would look at renting from a dealer and
we have a network of dealers around the
state that are willing to work with you
and we can help
pay for some of the transportation costs
the rental costs and then um
the per acre cost that they charge
or if you have smaller system we at
cornell have several different units
that are two row um that we have
available for use on farms and then on
long island and in western eastern new
york there are also two road units that
are available
so i just wanted to make that aware make
you aware of it if you're interested in
working with us and doing a trial or
setting up a trial
definitely contact your local extension
educator because they would be the ones
to help facilitate this and then we
could get
sort of talk with you about how to set
up one of these trials on your farm
so this is just a picture of one of the
units of jim capron who's in western new
york helped us build this unit and the
objective of this trial unit is to allow
you to do some deep placement of
nitrogen or uh if you're using
conventional dry fertilizer you can put
this on it's two-row only
but it is set up to actually do some
fertilizer placement
experiments uh we're also building a
very small lighter weight unit that um
that will work with smaller tractors and
this is using a yeoman's
plow these plows were developed in new
zealand for managing moisture and water
on pastures but they create the same
kind of
disturbance fracturing deep soil that's
compacted and creating a nice area
that's worked
for planting in order for direct seeding
or transplanting vegetables
and then we also have a two-row zone
builder that we have taken to different
farms
around the state to help them set up
trials and test
deep zone tillage
and this is a picture of the unit that's
in eastern new york that chuck barton
has and i know growers have used use
this trial unit for doing demonstrations
so with that i just want to make sure
that you're aware of the website where
we have case studies and other
information
previous people's experiences
from trying uh zone fillet on their
farms focused on vegetables and again if
you are really focused on vegetables i
know we get a lot of folks coming that
do field crops as well and that's great
but we don't talk about them too much
um and so with that i basically just
wanted to give you an overview and a
highlight
as far as the next part of our agenda
we wanted to be able to
um move into a conversation on equipment
and and have a chance for growers to
learn and share from each other
about different equipment that they're
using and what their experiences have
been
betsy do you have a copy of the current
and um and so uh for this part of it we
do actually have
um we do have a powerpoint that if and
we have some pictures that we can put up
uh based on if growers have anything
specific that they want to be talking
about around their equipment
and then after that point at 10 o'clock
we'll have to break and then we're going
to bring thomas bjorkman in to talk a
little bit more specifically on cover
crops and the tillage radish there's
been a lot of growers interested in
tillage radish
and so we want to have the chance to
talk about um that some cover crops and
how we integrate cover crops into these
deep zone tillage systems
and then we're going to focus in on weed
management issues
uh there's some specific questions that
growers have generated that we've asked
rich vana to address for us
and
he and robin belinder have been talking
about some of these issues so he'll be
talking to us about that and then we'll
come back at the end on more
experiences related to fertility
management that growers have been using
different strategies
so again we're connected this morning um
together and so it's a chance for us to
be able to learn across these different
locations i'll learn from growers in
other parts of the region as to what's
working and what's not for them
we're going to when we break for lunch
we are happy to buy you lunch today
but we do encourage you afterwards is
that we want to have time and local
discussions
both if you want to participate in these
trials and work with us to do
demonstrations or to actually get
involved with the phytophthora
experiments
please do uh think about that and talk
with your educator about that
but also we want to have a
have local discussions on what do we
need to know what other research
questions or other issues need to be
addressed to help growers take up these
systems and we need feedback from you as
you think about
how you might apply these on your own
farm
and then
also we have a short evaluation that
we're asking you to take for us
all of this work is funded by grants and
they always want to know um how are we
doing and what are we learning and our
our what else do we need to do or focus
each of work on
so with that what i might i'd like to do
is um i'll quickly uh check in with
folks if there's any questions about
anything i've said or any questions
about the agenda
how i'll do that is i'll go side to side
so let's start with carol in western new
york
are there any any questions before we
get started on the equipment section
carol what questions before we start
looking at and discussing equipment
no
no no all right
all right how about new mass
uh andy anybody have questions
so far
looks like we're good
all right um how about log island
we're good
okay and um jeff
uh no questions here i i do have one
question related to the powerpoint that
was sent uh with all the equipment is
that something that you'd like us to
show before we have that general
discussion or not
um that powerpoint has pictures that
growers may refer to in the discussion
and so that's why we sent it along so
you could actually have something to
look at
okay thank you sure alrighty