good afternoon everyone I am Kimberly
Davis with Florida A&amp;M corporative
extension and I am the extension
disaster education specialist as well as
the crd program leader so my focus of
today's um topic is going to be building
climate resiliency through D disaster
preparedness
education and I live in the state of
Florida
so you know what that
means lots of disasters Florida ranks
number five in the top five among those
with that have a lot of billion dollar
disasters every year and a lot of
disasters period so far this year we
have truly been slammed with hurricanes
and tornadoes and flooding so that's why
one of the things that we focus on is
building disaster resiliency through
preparedness because we know that a lot
of the disasters that we're having now
they are really a result of climate
change that's why we have extreme
flooding extreme heat events extreme
drought so we want to focus on training
our citizens how to be better prepared
and more resilient to respond to the
various disaster that they may face this
is just a snapshot of this year
um in the this corner this is these are
are all really happened in this area
because we haven't really been slammed
in Tallahassee but this year we were so
this is a flooding event that happened
not far away from campus um in earlier
in in
September this is really student housing
around the corner from fam's campus
this is one of the Hurricanes that we
had that happened down in Tera County
which is 50 miles from campus this is a
tornado that hit campus this is another
tornado um a h exis a hurricane that
happened in the neighboring County and
this is a wildfire wildfire that
occurred in Central Florida and these
all happen in vulnerable and at risk
areas so that's one of the focus one of
the things that we focus on at Florida
ANM extension is that that we work with
communities that need a little more help
so this is why we do this so what we do
is we do disaster preparedness education
we do environmental and conservation
education and Community resilience and
mitigation planning these are the things
that we think help to build resiliency
in communities because you need to be
prepared for disasters and when you
better better stewards of the
environment you lessen the impact of
course of climate change and then we
talk to our communities about things
that they can do to be more resilient
such as resiliency and mitigation
planning so one of the main programs
that we have is the family extension
disaster preparedness education and
safety program and this program is
really to work with our vulnerable
communities our youth our families our
seniors small farms and businesses when
it comes to disaster preparedness we
want to reduce the vulnerability of our
of of these citizens when it comes to
Natural hazards and emergencies through
an enhanced all preparedness education
Outreach programming we want to increase
their their ability to prepare for
respond to recover from and mitigate
against Natural Disasters and we offer
programming in all those areas and we
want to make sure that they have safe
communities and homes because that's
really important when it comes to to
being resilient to climate change and we
promote preparedness throughout the
entire year so in Florida some can can
happen any month so we want to make sure
that we are prepared for anything in any
month because the for the photo that I
showed you of the tornado that happened
in May so we weren't expecting um
Tallahasse had never really been hit by
a severe tornado but we know that we're
with the changes that we have in our
weather in anything is possible now so
that made us more alert in Tallahassee
because before coming to FAMU I was
actually the State Environmental
scientist for emergency management and
we never thought about tornadoes even
though we prepare for disasters
throughout the state but it was rare
that tahat would have the magnitude of a
of a tornado that they had back in May
so that's why it's really important and
then the pictures that I did show you
those happen in the most vulnerable
count areas in our city of
Tallahassee and believe it or not that
occurred in what we what is known as is
zip code
32304 and that is in the in the capital
of Florida that is the poorest zip code
in the State of Florida who would think
that the PO zip code would be in the
capital but it
is so that's why another reason why we
focus on that programming and that zip
is really within walking distance to our
campus so we have funded projects to do
this work I know Jennifer said that
we're volunte volunteers but volunteers
need money too so we do have funded
projects that help us with our
programming um we have a USDA Grant an
1890 capacity building Grant building
Community resilience to strengthen
capacity to climate change and natural
disaster we also have a southern S Grant
which is targeted towards small scale
Farmers we have a NFA rapid response
Grant and what that is is after the
storm happens nifa has rapid response
monies available so that is using we're
using photo voice to go into communities
to see how they are recovering
connecting and healing and then we do
two programs that are targeted towards
Youth and teachers that is the fam Sumer
sea science and Environmental Education
Academy and it's funded through
Mississippi state for a grant they
received from NASA and we have
strengthening forestry and conservation
education which is f funded by the USDA
Forest
Service the disaster preparedness and
safety education we deliver programming
that focuses on the five facets of
Emergency Management and that's
prevention preparedness response
recovery and mitigation and we focus
primarily on youth families seniors and
small scale farmers and remember a
family is also of one so we just focus
on everyone that needs to be prepared
especially those in socially
economically challenged urban and rural
communities so in Emergency Management
there are five phases there is
prevention and that's going to be those
actions that you take to avoid the
incident so we do do things
um to help with prevention um so
prevention may be something simple it
may not we may not see it as a climate
um related but a mass shooting being
able to being able to prevent and what
to do when it comes that happens then we
have preparedness which are those plans
that you do immediately before disaster
occurs such as um getting your emergency
it then there's the response phase which
is the immediate actions recovery which
are those long-term actions after the
storm and mitigation so mitigation is
really where you are building that
resiliency because mitigation are those
long-term actions that you can take such
as when you live in a flooded area one
of those long-term actions may be simply
to get your home elevated so when you
think about building resilience and you
think about litigation it could be that
but because we work with vulnerable
populations we teach them those things
that they can do that may have a lower
cost because it cost a lot to mitigate
your home but there are some things that
you can do that are are that are more
cost efficient for mitigation so if you
live in a wind prone area you may just
use ply board um to learn how to
mitigate your house or hopefully we
working with our we have we do an energy
efficiency because I am the crd program
leader and under our crd programming we
do Energy Efficiency so those are some
of the things that you can do especially
for extreme heat understanding Energy
Efficiency and energy efficient measures
so FEMA um defines resilience to
disasters as Community resilience the
ability for the community to prepare for
anticipated hazards adapt to changing
conditions and will stand and recover
rapidly from disruptions so that's why
emergency preparedness and disaster
preparedness is important because you
want communities to be able
to respond quicker than they would if
they weren't prepared because we know
disasters cause so many different things
health related social economic and
environmental conditions that weaken the
community so and we know that a weakened
Community cannot also can't with withand
to climate change as well so that's why
it's important that we are working with
our communities and doing those things
so every year fima does a national
household survey but the survey that
really caught my attention and the one
that I like to use in my presentations
is the one from
2021 because we have been doing a better
job at preparing so this was the one
that was really the catalyst to us um
doing disaster preparedness and
resiliency because we found that there
are differing needs for historically
underserved communities and as I
mentioned a few few minutes ago we want
to promote lowcost ways to bridge the
gap for those that are social
socioeconomically
disadvantaged so that was one of the
things that when in this survey that
really stuck out that when they surve a
home homeowners and renters a lot of
them responded saying that there needs
to be a way that they can prepare at low
cost ways because as I mentioned if
you're flooded one of the things is
elevating your homes and another thing
is actually getting your home acquired
but just think about if your home is
acquired out of the flood zone now you
have to worry about did I get did I have
enough equity in my home that is enough
to buy enough another home will I be
able or do I have to rent so those are
things that you have to think about and
we think about and work through with our
communities when it comes to building
resiliency because some things may work
for other communities but for
historically underserved communities
those things just don't work and one of
the things that we do for preparedness
is that we work with the youth because
what does a child do a child will simply
go home and say hey Mom hey Dad guess
what I learned today hey Grandma I
learned
that these are the different clouds so
in one of the photos this is just
teaching kids about the different clouds
so they can understand well When I See
This Cloud especially a nimal cumulus
cloud that I think I need to go inside
because it's going to be some severe
weather and then ducking cover teaching
them just when there's a tornado they
need to be able to Duck and Cover how
tornadoes are made so we teach them
those things using a stem approach so
that when we're teaching them stem we're
teaching them the science behind storms
we have as I mentioned we have the fam
sea program which is our sea science
program so that's really focusing on for
example one of the activities that we do
with the kids was how can you protect
your home from extreme heat so we do an
activity where the kids design a home
that can withstand um extreme heat and
what kinds of materials
a home would need for extreme heat so
those are some of the things that we do
with our youth so like I said when they
get home they're hopefully the
activities are exciting that once they
do them and we tell them why it happens
and what you can do that they go back
and um share that with their adults
because youth are really really
important when it comes to preparedness
and can you tell yes I was I started out
as a family 4 agent so 4 and youth
program is very dear to my heart so
working with our children and making
sure that they understand and not only
that we also teach them how to um
environmental stewardship we teach them
about single single use of plastics so
all this goes into our preparedness
because we know that Plastics are a big
driver to um climate change and not only
that another thing that we're doing with
our youth is that we're teaching them
about to just get the food that you're
going to eat because we know that a lot
of food goes to the landfills and that
creates a lot of messing gas so we teach
the kids just just don't just eat what
just get what you're going to eat so
it's just those simple things when we
are doing preparedness in these classes
with our kids that we're helping them
not only are we talking about disaster
preparedness but we're also talking
about environmental stewardship and
conservation
other thing is that when we're working
with our adults we do a lot of community
workshops on preparedness especially
with our seniors and our um our our
single moms as well as families we do a
lot of preparedness workshops and we do
community resiliency planning so we work
with communities that need to understand
what are the flood zones in your
community what are the different um what
are the different risk in your community
so when they understand that that they
can better be better prepare and do
mitigation plan planning because under
um FEMA every state has a state has a
mitigation plan so we make sure that
communities understand that everyone's a
part of the state has a mitigation plan
and that if your community does
mitigation planning you can help your
community better withand to disasters so
the main thing about our building
resiliency is changing the outcomes we
want to change the threat change the
impact and change their survivors so
that is the end of my presentation thank
you thank you
Kim um there's one question for Kareem
uh from kareim can the curriculum used
with adults and youth You Youth be
shared with us very
interested yes it can be I forgot to
mention I am a part of the extension
disaster education Network Eden
and the curricula that we use we make
sure that we post the curricula on the
Eden Eden website and I'll post it in a
minute and you can go to Eden because
your extension and you can get anything
that they have and some of the
um some of
the information of course you know
because we're extension and we share
resources it it's friendly where you can
put your logo on it and and and tailor
it to your needs so there there is the
Eden website and the youth curricul that
I use FEMA has a program called Step so
I'll put that in as well and what we did
with um with step I worked on the actual
step part but Illinois Extension made
step into a 4 program book so if you're
4 there is a 4 program book for disaster
preparedness as well so I will um put
the link for Eden in here and and that
step for each program is on the Eden
website as well question which is from
CJ Kelly Kim have you noticed push back
from folks who do not believe in the
driving forces of these
disasters actually I haven't and then
you know because I'm in the State of
Florida there there certain words that
we use and we don't use but um I think
because like I said when Tallahassee got
slammed and the areas that got slammed
that are getting slammed I I think
there's been a wakeup call so
I haven't had the push back that I
thought I would have so which has been
good because I really when I go into a
workshop I do go with that mindset like
okay there's going to be a denier in
here but I haven't had that push back
yet thank you um Kim that was a
wonderful presentation I'm definitely
going to be looking up some of those
resources you
mentioned so thank you for sharing all
that um my name is Megan Krueger and I
am an evaluation and research specialist
at West Virginia University but also
serve as an environmental educator in
some
capacities um my presentation today is
going to go over a grant-funded project
that we have right now calling uh which
which is called preparing agents of
change for tomorrow um building youth
confidence and capacity for climate
resilient Futures in Appalachia
okay so the Catalyst of this project was
a major um natural disaster flooding
event that happened in West Virginia on
June 23rd
2016 um we had a Thousand-Year flood um
which was catastrophic it was caused by
a storm that uh delivered about a
quarter of the state's annual rainfall
in just 24
hours and
um it had over a billion dollars in
Damages and you can see some of the
other uh sad uh impacts of that
storm um this storm took a lot of people
by
surprise um a lot of these damages that
happened were really highlighting some
of the vulnerabilities that we have in
West Virginia and Appalachia and a lot
of the underresourced communities that
we have especially in the southern part
of the state
um we have a lot of social vulnerability
a lot of issues with infrastructure and
this flood just really highlighted a lot
of those
problems um these are two photos from
that flooding event um that happened on
that day uh you can see just how much
water uh was dumped in this area and if
you've been to West Virginia you know
that there are a lot of valleys and
these valleys um have have rivers that
run through them and um they can put
people at extreme risk when these
flooding events
happen uh we also know based on some
research being done in the State uh from
our University that uh flooding is
expected to get worse in West Virginia
um we have um seen predictions that
because of climate change and increased
pre uh increased temperature that we
will have increased precipitate a you
can see on the image on the on my left
anyway it's the the state the country um
this is from risk factor and it just
shows uh where people are most at risk
for flood damage and you can see this
dark blue area is where West Virginia is
um you know even though we are not a
coastal area um we still have a lot of
risk of riverine flooding and flash
flooding and uh it is expected to get
worse we also have this county map here
um where you can see the percent change
of properties that are at risk for
flooding by 2050 compared to
2020 and um you can see some of our
counties are at 40% more properties are
at risk for damage um West Virginia
University is up here in in this part of
the state um but we work with extension
in All Counties um so we're really
looking at this
um so yes despite West Virginia being
one of the most flood prone States uh
there's a significant lack of
preparedness for these environmental
challenges especially as flooding is
getting worse we already know based on
um surveys and opinion maps and Yale
climate opinion maps that over half of
our state are having some issues with
denial uh with existence of global
warming and it does complicate efforts
to build um Community
resilience so our solution was um this
project we saw a funding opportunity
from Noah's environmental literacy
office and we developed a partnership
between extension at West Virginia
University and two other um Labs uh one
is the mountain hydrology lab which is
out of our forestry uh college and one
is out of our geography College which is
a resilient communities
uh lab which had originally been working
on food deserts but now has also been
working on climate related disaster so
the preparing agents for change for
tomorrow is um in one sentence summary
is a comprehensive initiative to enhance
climate resilience through youth
education and engagement across West
Virginia and this is the first kind of
Statewide initiative we've had uh to
build resilience to flooding in West
Virginia
so the idea of this project which was
funded um about a year and a half ago so
we're about halfway through it um is to
really build confidence and capacity for
flood preparedness and resilience
planning so our idea is that if we build
self-efficacy in youth confidence in
Youth and hope um that we will increase
youth's climate literacy and
resilience we have a comprehensive
theory of change which is one document
that um really um was provided to us by
Noah that is available to everybody and
and I it's going to be in the chat it's
a great document and anyone can adapt it
so what we did is we took Noah's um
theory of change that they they put out
to everybody and they said you know try
and adapt it for your state see how you
can do it this theory of change is
supposed to n Essence build resilience
in communities through a couple
different Pathways and the pathway that
you can build is dependent on where you
are and what you're doing so we're
choosing this pathway of Youth and so
this is our adaptation of the theory of
change so youth will youth go through
three tiers the top tier tier one is
where we get most of our youth in this
is done through an in school programming
through extension our extension system
has uh really great uh robust School
enrichment where extension agents go
into the schools teach about different
things agriculture stem so on and so
this tier one mirrors that and so in
tier one youth are in the schools um and
they're taught uh through a five-day
program and you can see some of the
outcomes that we aim to reach uh in this
tier one so we want to increase their
awareness of vulnerabilities in their
community of hazards in their community
of climate change itself of how
communities can be more resilient and
just even basic things such as Watershed
Dynamics and then after they go through
this first tier of programming they're
invited into the second tier which is
smaller of course because not everybody
will choose to join but those that do
will be trained by um people on our team
and graduate students to understand how
to actually map uh vulnerabilities in
their Community they will co-create uh
vulnerability Assessments in their
communities um and then communicate that
to others in their community and then
the final tier three which is where
we'll probably have the smallest amount
of of Youth participation but the most
meaningful if you think about it is that
the youth will go through a Leadership
Summit and we are going to train them on
leadership communication and then have
them present their ideas and some of
their concerns about their community's
vulnerability to um the state government
during a legislative day which we have
each year and then we hope to continue
mentoring them to become decision makers
around building Community resilience and
kind of really in essence um making a
peer network of Youth throughout the
state that have similar interests and um
want to these kind of change makers in
their community and assist with reducing
you know impact of
flooding so we've already um created the
curriculum for that tier one that I
mentioned and it is an in school
five-day curriculum that is for high
school students and um we've already
piloted in two high schools and have
some some good results so far uh the
five classes kind of move a student from
understanding floods and waterways all
the way into understanding hope and
resilience and so in the first class um
we kind of introduced them to a their
Watershed and it's surprising that a lot
of them don't know what their Watershed
is or really like what water is even
around them and so we do an activity to
map what's Upstream of them and what's
Downstream of them to really kind of
place them in where they are in their
Watershed and um we do that through some
different
visualizations um that we found and then
we go back the next day and we really
kind of do more of a science heavy
lesson on the science behind floods and
we talk a lot about riverine and flash
flooding and we visualize um rainfall
using Legos and so this was an activity
we adapted from the jet propulsion
Laboratory um called precipi towers and
in this one um students actually look at
real data that um was collected in West
Virginia about annual precipitation from
the past 50 years and they build Lego
towers to show how much precipitation
was for each year and then the average
and so then they can see in the past 10
to 15 years how much physically that
Lego tower is is towering over that
average precipitation and we've had
really good uh feedback on that because
it's something Hands-On that they can do
and helps them understand like how do we
even know where this data is coming
from uh we also look at some simulators
of like what's the difference between
flash flood and RI River and flooding
and then the third class we're talking
about place-based information West
Virginia so how do you um know your risk
as an individual person or an individual
community and so we talk about how we
identify vulnerable people in places um
you know using FEMA resources um and how
to understand like what happens if
there's a flood am I at risk and there's
some tools we use where they can put
their address in um on their Chromebooks
and see like are they in a flood zone
and some of them were and they didn't
even know and then the fourth one after
we've kind of scared them a little bit
not intentionally but you know they're
like oh no so we talk about preparing
and responding and so we talk a lot
about flood safety tips like what do you
absolutely not do during a flooding
event what should you do during a flood
event how do you be prepared and then we
give them a list to start building a
household emergency kit um for flooding
and then the last class is kind of
building that hope and resilience so
there's a story map published by um
Kentucky uh Red Cross where they did an
amazing job at showing kind of how that
Community responded uh to the 2022
floods and going through all the
different things Community level
engagement neighbors helping neighbors
and we talk about how um you can be a
helper and you know how Community plays
a role in in building resilience and
your neighbors and your friends
um so that was the the pilot of of tier
one which we've done twice now and then
we've also piloted that tier two I
mentioned and this one is more intensive
um it's actually starts as a a whole
weekend workshop and the students come
to campus and they come for two and a
half days and they really learn a lot
about mapping Community vulnerabilities
they go through different activities
like mental mapping family Mapp mapping
environments and then finally Community
mapping they walk around campus and they
start identifying where they think oh
this could be a risk for flooding
there's erosion there's you know water
coming over the road things like that
two minutes okay and then um they also
start understanding vulnerability
through the built environment and social
vulnerability so what's the difference
between you know our vulnerabilities um
in the built environment and what kind
of pre-existing social vulnerabilities
are going to make those things even
worse um we're evaluating the program um
we're evaluating the outcomes of the
program and the youth participants we're
measuring their levels of Hope around
climate natural disasters at the
beginning and the end trying to see like
where they are on this hope Spectrum are
they feeling despair are they feeling
hopeful and then we're also measuring
their self-efficacy confidence um around
being prepared for flooding and then of
course their knowledge increase on
climate change um we're hoping that um
eventually we'll be able to see some
intergenerational learning taking place
that's kind of The Next Step we're
hoping to see some of this knowledge
we're um partaking like on the youth to
their parents or their caregivers
changes in knowledge attitudes and
behaviors um so we have about two more
years left on the project we're going to
finalize the curriculum run the program
consistently over the next two years but
we're hoping to make it sustainable by
branding it as an extension program
that's offered via train the trainer
workshops where any extension educator
in the state could go and take this
program and do it in their County um so
that's the plan um we're already seeing
really good uh feedback so far but I
will um keep talking about this as we
learn more thank you so much when you
try to assess
hope how do you connect that to doing
like in other words you're trying to
assess it but then you're also you know
it's kind of like one of those things
you never really want to leave
open-ended right like you kind of want
to like prompt it and then you want to
take it Forward how are you taking it
forward and Jack if you could start
sharing your
screen do you mean Taking It Forward
like continuing the
conversation continuing the conversation
but also enabling and like an powered
action
like you know figuring out where they
are at in their hope spectrum and then
trying to connect it to a
doing oh yes yeah that's a really good
question so right now we're in the
process of creating an instrument and
we've been testing it so there is some
validated scales on Hope but none um
that we found specifically related to
flooding and so right now what we're
doing is adapting a scale uh to to
measure hope around flooding flooding a
natural disaster and we're testing it to
see if it's measuring effectively doing
some different statistical tests on it
and so I think that once we get to that
point we're going to have to
conceptualize how people fall in that
scale and where they fall and if they're
like low hope versus medium hope versus
High Hope and I think that will only
come after we keep developing this
instrument right now we're not giving
them that information we're kind of just
testing it as of right now oh there's
four open questions how did I miss that
can you have a time do you have a
timeline for when you hope the t2t will
be available to Cooperative Extension
Personnel train the trainer oh train the
trainer yeah uh no we don't yet um we
will we are working with Eden uh we
finally got delegates now um for Eden
and so once our curriculum is finished
we plan to upload it onto there um we're
going to start train the trainer in West
Virginia first and then if it works well
we would be open to doing it
elsewhere also Kim if you could uh find
the adult curriculum um as well as the
step curriculum link Karim I think I put
the step in the answered
Q&amp;A um but you're asking specifically
for the adult
curriculum um for Eden in Florida I
think um well my name is Jack voy um I'm
a senior in environmental engineering
here at NC State and I just finished up
my semester and I also do some research
in the Coastal Engineering department
and I'm from the coast as well so a lot
of these issues really strike home with
me and this summer I had the opportunity
to work for a new initiative called the
Coastal Community commity resilience
immersive training program or secret for
short and this is really a huge
collaboration between americore provided
funding uh the coastal resilience and
sustainability initiative here at NC
State and the Keenan Institute of
engineering and Technology also here at
NC State so this was a really big
initiative and we've got to go out and
work with a local County Jones County
which was a was really great u in terms
of giving back to Community after I've
been kind of doing this work here at NC
State all through the computer for a
while so I just wanted to quickly
highlight uh the team we had here
because as I'm the one presenting to you
today there was uh five other
undergraduate students who worked with
me um and the whole body of our work
that we went through uh really wouldn't
have been possible without having these
six undergraduate students all working
together in a team uh towards one goal
so that was a big part of how we're able
to gather so much data and how we were
able to engage the community so
frequently uh going down and frequent
visits every week throughout the this
10e program we
had so our approach we were aiming to
follow the model of a North Carolina
division of coastal Management program
called the resilient Coastal communities
program uh and this program essentially
is just a four-phase program that it
aims to create uh on the ground uh
construction projects that can tackle
climate uh solute uh climate problems or
flooding issues uh a lot of this has got
to do with storm water and you know
increasing capacity for areas
that this money probably wouldn't be in
the in the works for a while if it was
they weren't able to facilitate the
funds through this so our aim was to do
this for a community that was not part
of the uh C the coastal area management
act or k as this rccp program only
applies to those K counties that you
could see outlined here in green and
Jones County even though it's not part
of K it is only 50 miles away from the
coast and they've had some severe
impacts from hurricanes recently and it
seemed like a really great start to aim
our project uh but the only part of this
4 phase program that we were doing was
the uh first phase obviously as we were
not quite getting out there and getting
shovels dirty
yet so our approach uh we reviewed
existing documents that we gathered from
you know like land use plans anything
that essentially that Jones County had
already had in the recent years and then
we developed a community engagement
strategy in terms of you know how are we
going to go out there and approach the
community and how are we going to take
that uh the feedback they give us and
taking an account into our work so we
after that we wanted to identify and map
all the critical assets uh natural
infrastructure and some of the socially
vulnerable populations within the
county and we also wanted to conduct the
risk and vulnerability assessment that
was the aim of that phase one of the
rccp that I showed you
guys so all deliverables uh there was
two final deliverables that we finished
with uh one was the risk and
vulnerability assessment that I talked
about that aims to kind of be phase one
of rccp that Jones County can now go use
in applying for some of these grants um
but we also wanted to make a more
consumable uh media that we made in an
args story map um this map kind of
starts out with some cultural assets to
really highlight some of the key areas
that we we were heard from Jones County
people were very important to them as
well as going into some of the the data
about the flooding issues that has
occurred recently
so a quick assets overview um we were
able to really get a large quantity of
assets with the six undergraduate
students we had and we're all
engineering students so we're all very
interested in stat statistics and you
know different ways to manipulate them
and just just using rjs and different
tools to really you know do whatever we
can we can think of doing um this is
some of the just basic things that we
were able to quantify um Jones County is
a very agricultural County even though
it's close to the coast so productive
land and its ability to grow crops is a
with a huge emphasis on some of these uh
during these flood
events here is US uh meeting with some
local government officials with uh
initially on June 3D with Dr Georgina
Sanchez and Dr Rebecca Ward our advisers
who kind of led us through this program
uh we basically got a crash course on
the entire Jones County history that day
and everything that was going on and
basically got up to date immediately
with the state of it and kind of the
sentiment that people had about the
storm even six years later as hurricane
Florence was the the main storm that
people seem to be worried about and that
occurred all the way back in
2018 and we immediately got invited
again a couple weeks later to uh
exercise a hurricane exercise which is
basically a mock hurricane where the
National Hurricane Center came and kind
of walked through all the local
officials on how you know how the the
reports go out how they should take into
account and the emergency manager is
essentially assigning jobs to all the
different local officials in Emergency
Management time because Jones County is
a rather small County and a lot of the
local officials have to wear multiple
hats in the sense that they have to be
prepared to be Emergency
Management facilitators in some in some
way uh when these events occur and we
also got to speak in front of the Board
of Commissioners meeting to kind of
introduce ourselves to the county in a
more broad sense and try to try to be
good stewards and local champions in the
sense that we're there to serve the
public and listen gain feedback and put
that into this
report we also surveyed local residents
at uh two different areas um one was
just a restaurant called agie pizzas and
sub it just happened to be near a lot of
the uh town offices that we had
initially gone out and met at and when
we went in there to get some food the
first time we realized that it was a
probably one of the higher foot traffic
areas in the entirety of Jones County
and one of the few restaurants that
remained open after this storm and we
realized we could you know gain some
feedback from the community there and
take that into account for our report
and we also wanted to to get different
senses of more vulnerable communities so
we also sent out a couple coordinators
to survey people at The Filling Station
was such a nonprofit which is giving out
uh food and we want we just wanted to
get as broad of a resident pool as we
could and take into account as much
feedback as we
could so this is some of what we heard
from the residents we asked them what
they were what they thought was the most
important or they were most worried
about out of all these either either
environmental hazards or Community
assets um you see schools was the main
Community Asset people worried about and
with just shortly behind Public Safety
in the emergency medal services uh and
then flooding and hurricanes was clearly
the kind of runaway environmental hazard
which we kind of expected coming in
after hearing uh the the stories about
hurricane Florence back in
2018 here's just a couple pictures from
hor hurricane Florence this is uh in
poville and that man right there is
walking across uh the bridge that you
can see here to the right and the US
Geological Survey meter readed over 20
feet of flooding above the normal Water
Crest so this was a extreme event a
500-year flood as they call it but I'll
kind of get into later why what a lot of
our work does is breaking down what that
500-year flood means and and how we can
kind of move forward as extension
coordinators and science communicators
better in communicating this
issue so here is just some of the data
that we compiled from different reports
and satellite imagery and FEMA flood
plane data um this is Hurricane Matthew
which was two years before Florence and
Florence and we just essentially use
this data to take addresses different
critical assets that we found and mapped
and kind of see where they were in the
storm extents and the flood plane
extents and doing this allowed us to
really think about the differences
between these things and kind of
communicate some of the maybe the
misunderstandings and flood data that
people have when they're on the
ground so one of our main messages was
flood planes they flood even though it's
a 100-year flood plane it's only
supposed to have a 1% chance of annual
flooding um we thought that
communicating a 26% chance of flooding
over a 30-year mortgage is a bit more
effective in terms of describing what
this really is and the reason that fem
flood planes are created is because they
flood so we wanted to make sure that
just because you know it hasn't flooded
this often and this is oh this is the
first time your house is flooded in a
flood plane you know they these were
created because they're they're flood
and they're a low-lying
area and Beyond the flood plane as well
there we wanted to quantify kind of
differences between the flood plane and
like this 250 meter buffer zone just
outside because a lot of that really
kind of breaks down the issues in
development and discussions in the
area so we were able to quantify that
even though there's not a ton of
infrastructure within the flood plane
you can see almost a third of police
stations addresses and buildings in
general and over that a productive land
was inside that 250 meter buffer zone
which really kind of illustrates the
problem that we have as did Hurricane
Florence extent outside of the flood
plane and in way into that 250 meter
buff Zone and maybe even beyond that at
certain
points another thing I want to discuss
quickly was uh buyouts FEA buyouts was a
big part of discussion in a big point of
contention I felt um in Jones County 111
people sought buyouts which was the most
in the state during this hurricane
Florence but they are the fourth least
populous County and there's a lot of
issues with FEMA buyouts in terms of if
you don't have a deed available if
you're not owning the property uh
there's if there's just some
stipulations in the sense of who gets
the buyouts and also this is a small
County and decreasing that tax base and
property taxes is a huge hit in terms of
the income they're making each year and
actually SP ending to make it a more
resilient future for the Jones County
residents quickly I wanted to show this
map because I think there was a nice
story with this map and I was really
excited about making this at first uh
this is poville and I kind of overlapped
the flood plane and then the Hurricane
Matthew extent and hurricane Florence
extent and then both and I was really
excited about this map and I thought it
might provide really good data for some
people down there on the ground but then
I sent this map to the mayor of poville
and he told me that while the Florence
data was actually not quite as large as
it should have been as this satellite
imagy was taking a couple days after
Peak flooding the Hurricane Matthew data
actually overextended and showed too
much damage as a lot it was only a
couple houses that actually had water in
uh inundate their their homes and damage
anything most of the flooding imagery
from Matthew actually was you know
relatively o overestimated in terms of
the way it's shown on this map so I
wanted to kind of share that and show
the importance of creating Community
connections because without that I might
have just gone along and thought this is
a great map and I can't wait to show it
to everybody and tell everybody this is
exactly what happened but I I was able
to ground truth it by sending it
directly to the mayor poville so that
worked out well
this is the final map I created and we
took a step back in terms of including
all the addresses and kind of focusing
more on these critical assets and I also
put in the 500-year flood plane here
because that was something we heard a
lot about it was a 500-year flood plane
it was a 500-year storm and I kind of
wanted to show that this flood extended
to the 500-year flood plane and some
points Beyond it seems like from some of
the imagery and videos that I've
gathered from this day
and while 500-year flood plane it's not
a storm that's going to happen very
often you know with increasing
uncertainties and the climate future and
lack of different
flood flooding uh issues being accounted
for in these FEMA flood planes they
shouldn't be the end all Beall in terms
of understanding a flood plane and how
you accept and intake the data and I
think there needs to be a lot more in
reach
and ground truthing in terms of
communicating how these floods are going
to go go ahead in the future and what
the work we need to do to ensure that
people are safe and understand some of
the risks that are coming forward so
thank you and any
questions Jack before you leave the
screen can you go back one
image or maybe two now yeah this one so
when you ground truth I first of all yay
congrats I love that um when you ground
truthed with the mayor um but didn't you
say that actually the Florence was
expanded further so yes and that's why I
included this image up here because uh
this image up here up here where my
cursor is right here that is the schools
that you can see over here and you can't
see it in the imagery here but there is
water all under schools and there was up
to three feet I believe of water in
those schools they they had to build a
brand new school and by the time they
got into those schools there was mold
growing in it so this was kind of a way
of me being having to step back and say
oh you know sometimes it's easy to
overlook and not realize oh yeah that
was taken two days later and there's
clouds over the peak flooding day and
they weren't able to get satellite
imagery and it was really kind of a
great experience in terms of
understanding the importance of
community engagement and how
that can really create like a nice
feedback loop in terms of research and
also
education okay and Megan has a question
in the chat or Mara sorry Mara has a
question in the chat
um asking about liar maps and the role
in the 500-year flood plane delineation
do you have any thoughts on that um I
mean I'm not really sure what if exactly
how the 500-year flood planes are
created entirely I'm I looked too
directly into that in the lar Maps but I
think there's I'm not exactly sure if
they account for the different hurricane
precipitation all the different flood
effects because we heard ground truth
thing on the ground that uh the river
that this Trent river flows into where a
lot of the flooding comes from that
River was flowing backwards during
Hurricane
Florence and things like that you know
I'm modeling I'm doing a lot of coastal
modeling myself I'm not even sure where
how you start to model that how you take
into account wind Tides hurricane you
know the hurricane Vortex winds in
general and how you take all that into
account it's it's really difficult and I
think it's something that we have to
communicate and be honest as modelers
that models aren't always correct you
know okay I'm gonna ask another question
um
so if you had your magic ball or
actually your magic wand
um uh how would you reorganize the FEMA
buyouts so that um because all the spots
you showed look like they needed to be
bought out period right like so I mean
it's not for lack of logic for buying
them out um what what would be your one
sort of policy drive or wish for making
that a more Equitable system
well I don't even
know it's hard because you know I
understand the need for deeds and these
things to ensure that you know people
aren't you know trying to take advantage
of the system I understand that but I
think in general there just needs to be
more maybe competition because I know
that there some byouts were facilitated
by the NC office in
resiliency and maybe just more programs
besides FEMA to maybe even just you know
try to make them compete and make it
easier for people to facilitate bi if
they really want to but like I said at
the end of the day I kind of was
thinking about that a lot and then I I
also talked to the county manager and
realized you know buyouts really can't
be the end all be all when you're in a
really small populist County because
they need to get money so they can make
more resilient you know infrastructure
too so I don't think there's really an
good answer there but I think in general
there needs to be it needs to be easier
for people to get money in these
disaster events they shouldn't have to
struggle and you know go through this
over and over
again does anybody else have any other
questions either from the panel or in
the
chat okay well I want to thank you all
for joining us today and thanks
especially to Jack Kim and Megan for
presenting the recordings will be up
approximately 7even days from now from
on the necki YouTube channel I just put
it in the link I wish you all a very
warm and
festive um next month and be looking for
our events on the third Wednesday of the
month at 2 p.m. okay hope everybody is
well this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu