this is a production of Cornell
University so um thank you Lori and the
department for having me here it's my
first time over to Ithaca I really
enjoyed my drive over yesterday as I was
telling Lori I don't get a lot of time
alone and so the sixh hour drive
actually was
fantastic uh and it was a beautiful day
I couldn't believe how warm it was when
I got here so um yeah so we're g to talk
about aspir jillis today I know perhaps
maybe an organism that you don't hear a
lot about um here at Cornell but I was a
card carrying plant pathologist uh at
one time and so this was I had fun
pulling this paper it was my very first
paper I published as a graduate student
I worked on this in the late 90s using a
technique that the students probably
don't even know what it is anymore
random Amplified polymorphic DNA markers
to look at the genetic diversity of
ferum exist from isolates isolated from
common bean and sugar beats in the
Central High Plains region which is
Colorado um wyom
and Nebraska so that was a big part of
my graduate school work and then I moved
on and we did some functional genomics
analyses in this really interesting
interaction between alterar brat ofle
and a rabid opsis and so what I thought
was you know really exciting about this
work was the fact that alternaria was an
actual primary pathogen of of a
arabidopsis unlike early days some of
the systems that were being worked on um
at the time and so we thought that was a
nice introduction into how these basa
causing the these disease of the Brasa
plants were being mediated by the
alterar eugenus and so again grad
students we use things called Express
sequence tags back then which you
probably don't know what those are
either anymore thankfully because you
can do things like RNA seek now um so
why am I here and what do I do and in
and as far as the students in postdocs
go I'm happy to talk about how I ended
up switching into human fungal
pathogenesis during my postto at lunch
if you want to hear that story um but um
really we ask very similar questions to
what you ask when you're trying to
understand how fungi caused disease of
plants and part of that reason is is
because antifungal therapies are not
effective in a significant proportion of
patients that have these invasive fungal
infections just like fungal pathogens of
plants cause significant crop losses
throughout the world despite use of
antifungals and other management
practices so these organisms remain a Hu
a huge
problem so kind of a big thing for our
field I mean most of you when you woke
up this morning you probably weren't
thinking about getting a an infection by
a fungus and when I first was introduced
to that fact that fungi might cause
disease in humans as a graduate student
um when I made the switch I was like
what really like it's just not something
fortunately most of us grow up worrying
about and so recently the World Health
Organization though has recognized now
fungi as a critical group of pathogens
to study and so in 2022
the who came out with their critical
priority group and so the organism that
we work on we're going to talk about
today aspil Huma goddess is the mold but
you see Canada Albans and Canada orus
these are yeasts and cryptococcus is a
fascinating fungus it's a bidom my se
but it also was a
yeast and so why why did the who
suddenly in 2022 become interested in
these infections and that's because
medicine has changed and the world has
changed dramatically with climate change
as well as advances and immun therapy
and so many of the chronic diseases that
we treat in the clinic now the therapies
we use to treat those diseases Target
the immune system and so what we're
seeing is an increase in infections
caused by these fungi but as plant
Pathologists you know these fungi are
everywhere but yet we only you know not
only but we see predominantly these four
organisms showing up in these patients
so there's something unique about their
biology that allows them to cause
disease in a Mamon host so just quickly
asilis like the screen's a little bit
behind there we go a little bit of a
delay um ASP regillus was discovered in
1729 I always like to talk about it's
named after the aspergillum um if
there's any Catholics in the audience
that's the the the the the holy water
sprinkler and so you can see the kapor
which is the asexual uh development
structure of the organism looks just
like the ASP Gillum he was a priest so
there you go aspil
asilis as the genus and then fumigatus
is Latin for smoke and so this is a
culture of ASP regillus fagus grown in
the lab and this green coloration here
is the canidia and it comes from a a a
molecule called dhn melanin that
actually happens to be a veilance factor
for the organism but importantly those
canid are coated in hydrophobins and
those hydrophobins make the organism the
canidia very hydrophobic and so they
disperse into to the air uh and so if
you take a plate of aspergillis and you
just open the lid you see smoke come off
and that's where it got it's named fuma
Godus for for smoke it causes a pretty
broad spectrum of disease um and so that
you know we're going to talk about
invasive aspergillosis today which is a
systemic infection but chronic
aspergillosis is increasing in frequency
now um and there's many manifestations
of aspil Lois that relate to what's
called a th2 type response or
so it's an organism that causes a very
wide spectrum of human disease in a lot
of different patient
populations so this is a CT scan uh from
a from a patient at Memorial SLO
ketering Hospital not over in New York
City and it's from one of the patients
of my collaborator uh Dr Tobias Hull and
what I'm trying to illustrate on this
slide is that ASP regillus one is a
pulmonary pathogen and so in red you can
see one of these lesions forming in this
patient's lung
and the Crux of the matter is is that
our optimal antifungal therapies which
aren't that effective in Vivo have to
Target the organism in the right
physiological
context and in our field that that that
that's
actually a significant
challenge um and so how do you actually
identify infection micro environment
relevant Therapeutics and a little bit
of a maybe a bit of a spoil ER for later
in the talk but the way we've done this
in our field for years and as plant
Pathologists you do this too when you go
to inoculate a plant with an organism is
there's a big bottleneck here to get
these um you know morbidity and survival
curves or plant death curves with our
mutant fungus this is the result you
want to get right so you make a fungal
mutant using fungal genetic approaches
and you hope that that mutant doesn't
cause disease in your animal or your
plant and you get this beautiful
survival curve and you get papers and
grants and you identified a drug Target
but the problem with this is that often
in the what is often the case is to get
a curve like this you fail to initiate
an infection so these mutants tend to be
very sick and they are incapable of
initiating that infection and so in the
agricultural setting that could be very
powerful right you could easily develop
something you could spray on crops for
example to prevent Spore germination or
prevent the development of an aoria that
you know initiates the infection but in
a Maman system we can't predict who's
going to get one of these infections and
so prophylactic therapies are less um
are less a less viable alternative for
developing new Therapeutics for these
diseases so what happens is is the
individual gets an infection that's been
established and then we have to treat it
okay so we wrote a little piece on like
just talking about the importance of
these high impact virulence factors
which are important for initiation of an
infection but really unclear in almost
every case because we don't really have
the great tools to look at an
established infection we're not sure if
they're disease progression factors
because this is what you'd really want
to Target when you get sick you go to
the doctor after you get sick so we need
to treat these infections in in in this
in in a different context than we often
are studying them so how we approach
this in my lab and so one of the ways is
we've gone in to try and profile the
infection micro environment this is an
old experiment it was one of the last
ones I did as a postto with this idea in
mind to try and understand what the
physiology of the fungus was in an
established infection so a bit of a busy
slide it's a it's a 1nmr Spectra and so
we have animals that were inoculated
with just saline and then animals where
we give ASP regillus the canidia through
the airway right right so they just
inhale the spores they run around they
just inhale the spores and then in the
lung what we did is you can actually get
fluid out of the lung all the Bal
bronchial
alage right and you can take that fluid
and we did metabolomics on it and we got
a big surprise and the surprise was is
these red arrows are metabolites
associated with fermentation
particularly ethanol so lactate alanine
acetate those are all metabolites that
likely are coming from the host so we
can't rule out that the fungus isn't is
is making those in Vivo but the ethanol
the ethanol we knew had to be coming
from the Fungus and so this really was
the piece of data that I started my lab
on because the the idea was is that when
do microbes ferment most microbes okay
they ferment when oxygen becomes limied
and so you might be thinking well wait a
minute you're in the lung you're talking
about an obligate aerobic filamentous
fungus and you're telling me that it's
fermenting and it doesn't it grows in
the absence of oxygen or at least with
limited oxygen environments but I would
argue that aspergillis and a lot of our
filament of fungi that we study out in
the soil they're really good at
recycling carbon and nitrogen for most
of them that's their ecological role and
in compost piles it's the number one
place where we could go out and get
environmental isolates of aspila hum
Godus when you turn over your compost
pile and you see the smoke come out the
spores a lot of those are pagus for a
couple reason reasons one it's
thermotolerant it's one of the few
Thermo tolerant filament of fungi it can
survive up to temperatures of 70 de C it
can grow in the lab at temperatures at
55 degrees C very rare for the
molds secondly if you go to your garden
store what do they try and sell you they
try and sell you devices to oxygenate
your compost to speed up microbial
metabolism to degrade the compost faster
which tells you that compost become
oxygen depleted very rapidly due to
microbial metabolism so aspergilus it
turns out also grows very even though
it's an obligate AE it will not grow
anerobic but it can live anerobic
it loves to grow in these low oxygen
environments okay so what we ended up
finding you know at first no one
believed us but you know the ethanol
data we went and showed them we used the
tool from cancer okay so in cancer
hypoxia or oxygen deficiency is a really
important part of the tumor that confers
drug resistance to a lot of cancer
therapies so as as tumors develop they
become hypoxic in the middle so there's
tools to investigate that so we showed
this is a lung so here's an airway the
aspergillus came in through the airway
the green is ASP regillus growing out in
the lung tissue and the red now is um
showing you a region of the lung that's
defici in oxygen okay so it's it's
called pidol hydrochloride it forms
protein adox On th res res only when
oxygen levels drop below
1.5% so at the site of infection just
like in a compost pile the organism is
is having to deal with these low oxygen
environments okay so an important Point
here is that hypoxia was recently
awarded the Nobel Prize for how mammals
another obligate aerobe how they respond
and sense oxygen levels through the hif
one alpha pathway really beautiful
science it's a really cool mechanism
related to pral hydroxylase which is
uses oxygen as a co-actor to hydroxate
hif one when Oxygen's abundant then when
it drops you don't get the protein
hydroxy and the transcription Factor can
go activate the hypoxia response but and
I think this is relevant for Plant
Pathology is it oxygen demand hypoxia
occurs the physiological response when
oxygen demand exceeds the supply so that
can occur at any oxygen level and so
when different fungi induce a hypoxia
response really depends on their oxy
requirements and the oxygen levels in a
given environment okay so something to
think
about and so we studied this for years
um a lot of papers you know we really
got really lucky we found this
transcription Factor called srba that um
as you can see when you make a null
mutant it cannot grow in hypoxia it's
the dream result it's why I'm still here
it's why I ended up getting a job this
Gene I love so much we continue to study
it in different ways um so you you know
it abolishes hypoxia Fitness it
completely abolishes virulence of the
organism the nice thing here I'm not am
I showing you the data nope not showing
you the data but you know this actually
does initiate an infection this mutants
but then once the hypoxia sents in then
the mutant stops growing completely and
the animals are all able to survive so
we actually do have a project it's kind
of our latest paper looking at how to
Target this pathway
therapeutically it was a gift that kept
on giving because the AOL are the main
antifungal that we use in the clinic
just like in agriculture for antifungal
um activity um you can see that the
aspergilus wild type strain here is
completely resistant to azol but this
azol VOR conazol it's susceptible to so
that is the primary therapy in the
clinic if you get one of these
infections but our mutant was
susceptible to both lonol which is used
to treat yeast infections and then the
AOL so virulence drug susceptibility was
the best Gene I could have we were lucky
okay and um you know just to throw again
this that seems to happen in plant
fungal pathogenesis as well so these
this is the fermentation pathway in
fusarium that was shown by a group in
Spain to be really important for uh
causing fusarium
wilts uh which was which is exciting
which suggests that think about it so
where's are the roots full of oxygen
they're actually pretty oxygen deficient
especially when they get water locked
and so a lot of these root path
pathogens in particular must have to
deal with low oxygen environments and
able to thrive within a plant and then
um in Magna pora um uh Wong Hong Le's
group um actually ended up studying srba
in
magnaport um and show um that magnor as
it penetrates through the aium also
experiences an oxygen deficiency and it
was kind of fun I was at a GRC once and
Nick talbet was giving one of his
amazing talks looking in the tissue
watching um uh magnor invade and he was
losing gfp signal and he couldn't figure
it out like and I went to him I said
you're losing oxygen as you get into the
plant and uh so anyway really kind of
cool gfps requires oxygen to to
sense so that was all fine um I could
have talk I talk to you all day about
srba but we wanted to find um other we
had evidence to suggest that there were
other regulatory Pathways that were
dealing with the response to oxygen in
the fungus and so you know we um I've
talked to quite a few people this
morning about RNA seek and Lor's
teaching a class asking you students
that are in the class to look at an RNA
seek and pull jeans out make a
hypothesis and and and hopefully find a
gene that's related to a specific
function in phenotype it doesn't work
that often I hate to tell you it's very
frustrating um you can learn a lot from
RN seek experiments but often you know
the gene that's at the top of your list
isn't the one that's driving the
phenotype you're interested in and so we
went through that with low oxygen and we
ended up deciding to let the fun tell us
so long story short how we came about
this is we started screening
environmental and clinical isolates
another tip for students there's a lot
of genetic heterogenity within the
organism that you study and so we often
study reference strains for many years
uh in our in our respective Fields but
there's a lot of cool genetic diversity
out there you can do screens without
having to do any kind of recommed DNA
experience just go get a bunch of
isolates and screen for phenotypes and
now with genome sequencing as cheap as
it is um you can you can actually track
down the mutations that are causitive in
many cases but so that was our idea here
so we did we we set up an experimental
Evolution experiment with a clinical
isolate that really struggled to grow in
low oxygen environments compared to a
lot of the other strains that we had
looked at so we ended up
passaging uh the organism for about four
months under low oxygen environments we
passage the spores we collect the whole
population each passage to try and avoid
bottlenecks and uh we kept passaging
and we ended up this experiment just
kind of taking the lab in a in a very
different direction than one that we
were previously um working on which is
what what one of the fun things about
science is so we got a strain and as you
might expect um we did recover a strain
that became more fit under the low
oxygen environments that was the goal of
the
experiment you know if if you're
following along you might predict that
the strain
is a little bit more pathogenic right so
if low oxygen environment is important
for progressing disease um I actually
shouldn't say pathogenic I should say
virulent a little bit more ver okay so
the ability to cause the disease is the
same but the the progression of the
disease was increased more rapidly um
potentially because the strain is a
little bit more fit in that low oxygen
environment so those were all great
awesome the unexpected part that threw
us for a loop was this right here so if
you look here's the strain that we
passage the parental strain this is what
it look like in standard lab
conditions here's the strain that is
resulted from the experimental Evolution
experiment hopefully you can see there's
substantial change in the colony
morphology of the
strain what was interesting to us is
that the other condition where
irrespective of the evolution changes
Colony morphology is low oxygen we've
done a lot of experiments and the low
oxygen environment is one environmental
condition where we see these these
morphological changes within the
colony and so we really became curious
about the if this adaptation to the low
oxygen environment was being driven by
the change in Colony for was this
causitive or was it correlative um and
so we really dove in and started to
investigate this in order to do that we
had to quantify the morphology and so we
ended up um quantifying the amount of a
colony that is vegetative so not
undergoing asexual reproduction and then
one thing that was
repeatable was the development of these
furrows so these colonies that were
coming out of low oxygen always furrowed
so this rugos Colony the the micology
term is a rugos colony and you know
surprisingly if you look in the
literature there isn't hasn't been a lot
of as you know in bacteria there's been
a lot of work done associating different
Colony morphotypes with pathogenesis but
in the fungi less so so again functional
or just
coincidence so the the conceptual switch
here for us was that really started to
think about these colonies as
communities and that the structure of
the community um likely is is is driving
the emergent properties that arise when
you have a community of cells together
and so at the end of the day now we
started referring to the so you know
micology the term is a melium and
functionally in the bacterial World they
call these
biofilms so they communities of cells
attached to a surface that produce an
extracellular Matrix and so what I'm
showing you here is these colonies of
molds this isn't exclusive aspergillus
other molds do this too they make this
beautiful extracellular Matrix that
helps connect these colonies and these
filaments together and so by any
definition these mold colonies are a
biofilm and again going back to that CT
scan thinking about the physiological
environment in the host that the or that
we need to treat well here's an here's a
picture now of Josh where's Josh he's
right here during his PhD developed this
technique in our lab called funpack
where we're able to clear tissue and
then look at the fungus within the
tissue as for gillus after it initiates
infection when you're progressing the
disease this is what you have to treat
is these
biofilms so they're adhered to the lung
tissue they're producing Matrix and
that's what you have to treat so
suddenly we like wow like we've maybe
been studying this from you know we
often study Fung look at the stress
response by kn ating canidia onto a
plate and so are you you know is the
stress response to the antifungal
killing the canidia or is it actually
impacting the Hy it can be hard to parse
that apart by using spot dilution
assays um and so this led to a lot of
questions for us so you know first um
what can biofilm morphology tell us
about the evolutionary pressures faced
by ASP regillus in the environment in
the
host and then how do these population
level scale morphotypes relate to spefic
specific phenotypic states that we care
about like virulence drug susceptibility
and then persistence within a a human
host or a plant
host um and then of course you know I'm
fungal genetics by training I love
genetics and so what are the genetic
mechanisms that facilitate the biofilm
Form and
Function and then you know home run
would be to identify small molecules
that Target these mechan because our
current antifungals are really
ineffective against the bioil state of
the organism
so um just kind of hammer home this
point that the environment thinking
about the evolutionary pressures the
organism face when we grow asparagus in
the lab the likely the reality is we're
growing it in a condition it does not
really face much in the environment it
does not see 21% oxygen okay it is in
the soil it is in compost and so you
know that because it canidates the
moment you drop it on a plate so
conidiation generally is a stress
response in fil fungi and it is oxygen
dependent okay light and oxygen makes
sense you're in the soil it's dark no
oxygen growing vegetatively but you come
to the surface that's when you want to
release your propagules you have light
you have oxygen and so in low oxygen
environments we get this induction of
these rugos colonies okay um you know
it's hard we don't have an incubator to
completely um Shield out light but you
can get these colonies that are
completely rugos producing very little
spores in response the low oxygen
environment and so the strain that we
evolved we ended up calling hm because
it resembled the low oxygen colonies of
the wild type strain but the reason we
gave it a specific name is the HM
colonies here's an example right here
they do this when oxygen is
present okay so they look like the low
oxygen colonies in the presence of oxy
okay and we we have a the quotation
there okay so we have an hmph so nmor
strains can switch between the two
different morphotypes but hmph are
locked into this rugos colon like
stat and so some other ways we've
Quantified this biofil morphotype
convince you that they're very
different the delay between my computer
and the zoom
screen there we go okay so if you want
to do genetics you need quantitative
data so one of the things we looked at
we can use confocal microscopy to set up
these submerged biofilm cultures the
nice thing about these cultures now is
we don't get asexual
reproduction okay which we don't see in
Vivo and these filaments they look a lot
more like that image Josh took from
theong so we've kind of really moved
heavily into using this model as a a way
to to study mold biology now in the
context of infection but quickly H morph
andm morph you should see some
difference how the Hy are orienting
themselves within the community and what
you're looking at over here is
quantification of the angle of departure
of each H within the biofilm from the
surface and so H more are growing more
horizontal and with the delay here I'm a
little worried these move oh okay good
we
go so the enmor biofilms you get this
really
distinctive sorry for the computer issu
not sure what's going on on but um these
really distinctive colony biofilms where
the hyy grow vertically so one of the
hypotheses we have in the lab right now
is that is actually aerotaxis and so
we're hoping to figure out what the
oxygen sensor is is it actually
aerotaxis or could the other Nutri
gradients that are forming that are
driving this as well but that's our
favorite hypothesis right now and then
if you look at the H morph colonies now
hopefully right away you can see there's
a lot more space between the
H and as this thing starts to
rotate hopefully you can start to see
that the H are growing they're longer
before they Branch they grow more
horizontally which helps create that
space and so the hypothesis here is
these strains now um are able to since
there's more mass diffusion capable
since you have more space between the Hy
the gradients that develop being are
less steep they have more access to
oxygen they have more access to other
nutrients and when you quantify
biomass in these strains these guys
always grow more they generate more
biom okay so I'm not going to go through
all the genetics um so you're probably
wondering what happened in the evolution
experiment so what happened is we found
a fungal specific Gene that was
unstudied in the subt Mir region of
chromosome 5 like my students worst
nightmare are you kidding me an unknown
unstudied Gene that's only in um the ASP
regillus genus and
so um it was but the good news was it
was clean it was a very clean experiment
there were three other Snips that were
high impact um after four months and um
this one was the one and so it has a
nuclear localization signal which I'm
going to show you in a minute it has
this one domain the secondary structure
is a beta Alpha Beta beta Alpha Beta
Motif which is a nucleic acid binding
domain it could be RNA it could be DNA
um and so it was in a gene cluster that
pops up here I heard AAL was here is
that right AAL yeah okay so we're
working with AAL on this now so it's in
this Gene cluster in the Subic region we
called it hack for hypoxia Associated
cluster this is seems to be a regulator
of the cluster because if we knock this
Gene out the other genes in the cluster
their expression turns
off um the AL itself that arose the AL
is both necessary and sufficient so we
can take the evolved Al put it into wild
type strains and we get this beautiful
rugos
morphology but you also can just take
the wild type O Leo which is silenced in
the wild type strain that we worked on
and overexpress it at an ectopic
location and get the beautiful
morphology itself so what happened with
the AL the alil actually increased the
expression levels of the transcription
of of what this Gene is and um we don't
know why could be transcript stability
um it could be increased translation
rate we we we don't we're not sure but
you increase the levels of this Gene
called hrma now um You induce expression
of all the genes in the cluster which is
great and it turns out there's another
Gene that we're working on with the meal
that was unannotated in the genome this
is a there's a lot of cool biology in
these fungal genomes don't necessarily
Believe The annotation you have if you
guys use fungidb like take your genome
sequence use seek load it up you'll find
all kinds of new genes that are not
annotated I find a new Gene every day in
our genome just that's I do for fun at
night I just scroll through I'm like oh
yep there's a new Jean right there
guarantee you will find new jeans and
some of them are really important so
here's a meal stuff that we're work we
just submitted this paper with an Neil
So it turns out that that Gene cluster
is on one of these giant Starship
elements and uh the paper here shows
that we found a lineage of asilis where
the cluster is moving um and so which is
really exciting we still don't know
where the genes come from um they
clearly are recently evolved within the
lineage they don't look like they're
bacterial um but you know sub there's a
lot of cool stories about subt Gene
expansion and parasites for example
malaria the reason you don't have a
malaria vaccine is because
subt um antigen variation it all occurs
in the subt region of malaria parasites
they just keep generating new antigenic
variants with these new genes so um
there's a cool can to the story from
running cormax group in canand Gada with
a subt region controled adherance to
surfaces a lot of cool stuff um a little
bit more about H RMA it goes around the
nucleus we think it's in the nucleis
we're still working on that you can see
the beautiful
localization it does have that signal
and then what we did is we knocked out
the nuclear localization signal protein
spine not showing you the Western blot U
but we we get rid of the colony
morphology if this protein cannot get to
that nucleolar or perinuclear
region all right so what's driving the
phenotype so the title of my my talk was
a little bit provocative cancer-like
metabolism so a couple things I told you
that
hmph occurs when Oxygen's
around and so one uh piece of data that
we got it was which was really
fascinating to us is that even though
ASP regillus is oblate arobe this is the
parent strain what we're looking at here
is the ability of a of a biofilm to
consume oxygen you can see very rapidly
asparagus consumes all the oxygen that's
available to it that's within the
biofilm so the fungus itself is inducing
a hypoxic micro environment in its
Colony it's just wild okay and then
here's our evolved 20 string which is
growing more it's producing more biomass
if you remember from that data but yet
it consumes less oxygen so there was a
disconnect there that's when we kind of
started thinking about cancer a little
bit um
one of the uh major challenges though
the difference between a cancer cell and
a fungal cell is all this Matrix and
this polysaccharide so fungi make this
huge cell wall we don't have cell walls
around our cells and fungi are
decreasing secreting this out into the
environment and so here's a temm image
of the parental strain you see that
beautiful cell wall here's Matrix on the
outside of the cell wall now but our H
morph strains you can see the cell wall
is different it's a lot thinner and then
the Matrix is balling up outside and so
it still produces the Matrix but it
secretes it
away from itself that may be important
in pathogenesis and we know it's
secreting it away because we can stain
for beta glucan which is what most of
this electron translucent layer
is we use a probe it's called dectin one
it is a pattern recognition receptor in
your immune system that detects fungal
beta gr so
um just like plants plants have pattern
R receptors they have you know Kit's a
great one in the plant fungal
pathogenesis literature this is the beta
glucan receptor in humans so we use it
as a tool we tag a Flor for to it and
then it binds beta glucan you can
quantify how much exposure you have a
beta glucan on your fungal cell so
consistent with that we have
that um and so when you have
more beta glucan exposed the immune
system is going to see it more and Hyper
react and so we actually think that
that's what's driving the increased
disease progression with these H morph
strain computer's really slow okay so
post damage so with these H morph
strains so this is an assay where you're
looking at tissue damage based on
release of an enzyme when sells lice in
your in in your tissue and so here's the
wild type strain this is an airway so
the funguses in the airway the parental
strain all that black is the aspil
scrolling as a bofilm and then the
purple those are neutrophils that are
coming trying to kill the fungus but
look at our H morph strain look at the
airway there's not you know the fungus
is spread out it's a whole another part
of the paper again the biop morphology
in Vivo and in vitro actually plays out
we don't get those tight I like we do in
the wild Tye they're actually all spread
out and then here look at these Airways
completely full nutr and so we think
that's being driven by the beta glucan
which is hyper inducing inflammation and
then you know the animals here basically
can't bre okay from these
strains okay so how is it doing that so
the the metabolic challenge here for
these organisms is to make this cell
wall and so what we've done recently is
a metabolomics experiment comparing H
morph to enmor fungal metabolism and we
got a surprise so in the hmor strains
anything in red is basically gone and so
what we're seeing here is an increase in
pentos phosphate pathway
intermediates and that's important
because that's where you get a lot of
nadph from and as I'm going to show you
in a minute to make a fungal cell wall
you need a lot of
nadph okay
and I showed you earlier when Oxygen's
low ASP regillus
permanent okay so what we think is
happening here the glucose is flying
through glycolysis to generate reducing
power as well as intermediates that are
needed to make the cell wall when oxygen
is limiting and so here's beta glucan
it's easy so the reason these hmph
strains have more beta glucan because
you can just take glucose 6 phosphate
and shunt it over to Beta glucan in a
couple steps you need a little bit of
nadph but that's it there's like one
enzyme here one here and one there it's
a really simple molecule to make
relatively speaking for a fungus the
tough one is kiten kitan is essential
for fungi it takes glutamine acetyl COA
a ton of NPH multiple steps including
the formation of UD glyc knac which is
important for epigenetic regulation all
other uh parts of fungal biology to make
this this is a ton of reducing
equivalents and carbon that are needed
to make a molecule of kiten very
expensive aspergilus makes galacto manin
which is part of the Matrix that it
secretes again multiple steps require an
NPH all coming off of fructose 6
phosphate so now you have a competition
to make kiten or galacto
manin and then the main polymer of the
Matrix is this molecule called gag which
requires UDP gnac from galnac from UDP
gnac so again really a lot of pressure
being placed on this molecule to form
this extracellular Matrix okay and so
how does organism do this well there's
plenty of oxygen there's no problem but
in these H morph strains where oxygen is
apparently limiting they found a way to
do that and so one of the cool things
that fungi apparently can do is they can
do reductive carox in the TCA cycle so
to run the TCA cycle in Reverse okay to
generate that reducing power that you
need to make that cell wall okay and so
when this happens Alpha ketoglutarate
gets carboxilate to isocit
okay and that gets converted to citrate
which goes out it can be converted to
acetal COA which you need for the kiten
biosythesis okay and the and the key
trick
here
yep um the key trick here that tipped us
off that this was a cancer-like
metabolism was this molecule right here
two
hydroxyglutarate it is produced in
cancer cells okay and we haven't seen it
before in fungi so what that molecule
told us is that in these hm strains the
TCA cycle is running in reverse and we
think it's running in Reverse to
generate NPH and the intermediates
needed to make a cell wall when oxygen
is limited it's a really cool mechanism
in order to maintain a structure that
you need to
survive um and the cool thing is you get
a ton of Ned Ned to keep glycolysis
going from that process too which is
absolutely essential so some of you may
have heard about this so this is the
cancer model so the warberg effect was
discovered in 1924 by OT warberg it is
high rates of glycolysis in the presence
of oxygen for Mamon
cells the cool thing and you know how
this exactly Works people are still
working it's a huge area of cancer
research but it provides intermediates
to make lipids and nucleotides and Maman
cells but in the fungus we think it's
providing the intermediates to make the
cell wall and so these H morph strains
are having a warberg like metabolism
in response to an oxygen deficiency now
the question then becomes that is not
answered in the cancer field and we
don't have the answer either in fungi
but maybe we can get there why the cells
get locked in this physiological state
so we have the genetics and we're trying
to figure that out why do they stay this
way why don't they just flip back to
regular
metabolism so a little bit of support
for that model if you actually take
these H morph strains and you put them
on uh media that you are forced to use
respiration instead of glycolysis we
completely can change the cell wall and
we completely flip the morphology back
to the wild type black Colony
morphology just a check Lori when's the
seminar end sorry one one perfect okay
good all right um so you may be asking
is this matter in Vivo well I showed you
the H morph strain so G glycolytic
intermediates this was Josh's white
whale in his PhD we'd argue about this
in my office so there's a there was a
decent amount of literature saying that
those
respiratory carbon sources that drive
respiration were probably the main
carbon Source in Vivo for asilis so our
whole model would kind of be a mess and
not relevant to what's going on in the
lung if that was the case Josh was
convinced there was glycolytic
intermediates available to the fungus
within the lung and so before he left
the lab he made this mutant called pfka
phosphor fructose kinas
you can see it can't grow on
glucose okay but can't grow on La it
grows a little bit on lactate you can't
see it on the slide here grows fine on
protein goes fine on acetate goes fine
on glycerol so it's a great mutant to
test his hypothesis and um you know he
unfortunately came and joined Lor's lab
before he was able to do this experiment
but I can tell you the new PhD student
was really excited because the pfk
mutant cannot initiate
infection so the the interpretation of
this this experiment is that glycolytic
intermediates are yes driving invivo
fungal initiation of the infection so
this glycolytic metabolism is essential
for ASP regillus to progress disease so
you'll get one more paper out of your
PhD okay this isn't a lab artifact um
these are different clinical isolates
that we've recovered now from a bol
malignancy patient patient with cystic
fibrosis patient with pulmonary invasive
aspidisca
H morph morphology so this is coming out
of patients and in fact if you go to the
literature 1975 you can see the first
example of this so again these are two
different patients two isolates from the
same patient one's H morph one's not we
don't know because genome sequencing
didn't exist back then if these are
related but we have data now from
patients at
Dartmouth where
we get isolates from the same patient
here we go
maybe there we go so these are all
isolates from one patient different
Colony morphologies this one is very H
morph like these are all related there's
only a couple hundred Snips between
these four
colums okay so inv Vivo adapting this
this H morph like physiology which again
we think is because of the low oxygen
environment found in the tissue this
provides a way for the fungus to
maintain
viability to make it cell wall when it's
missing I think here's 's about 12
patients that we've looked at with
cystic fibrosis that are infected with
asilis and we see H morph isolates u in
pink here in almost all the
patients so these tend to be a rising
inv Vivo in response to a low oxygen
environment we're using this I mentioned
to you guys early on you don't
necessarily need to do a recombinant DNA
based genetic screen we've taken these
isolates so here's two from a patient
with IPA they are only nine non
synonymous high impact Snips different
between these two this was a home run so
this is my new students project and I
think um Gillian will appreciate this
one um the mutation is an
Lea and so this the H morph strain has a
loss of functional eel of L laa which is
a methyl trans Ras Nancy Keller
originally discovered many years ago
that regulates secondary metabolism and
fungal
development and so here's the parent
strain there's nothing wrong with the
alil in the strain that evolved in the
patient we lose this Lea uh there's a
stop code on that causes a a premature
stop and we can do all the necessary and
sufficient alal swaps so here's the
parental strain that we work with in the
lab often here's our control strain our
H morph strain here's the mutant of
af293 from ny's Lab it's hmor which we
went back and looked at her oh there it
was it was in her paper um and then
here's the Al from the patient that we
put back into the mutant and it's
non-functional and then if you take the
clinical strain that has the loss of
function Le and you put the wild type
alil back in we can completely restore
The Colony morphology so this is a good
one because it gives us a genetic
regulator we know something about for
how so the idea here now that this is
potentially an epigenetic regulator of
that metabolic switch which is which
which is cool because in cancer a lot of
the regulation of the warb effect is
done through epigenetic modifications
and cells so early days on that but
pretty
cool so just to kind of finish up um i'
I've showed you that these hmph strains
are important in progressing disease
it's not a lab artifact they're
happening out in the clinic the cool
thing is is that these hmph strains have
this metabolic rewiring that's driving
glycolysis and reductive carox we think
the really drives cell all homeostasis
and that in that context these strains
become fit in low oxygen environments
and then are able to cause disease and
damage to the host and so
um I think with that I will finish up I
was going to show you the drug
resistance stuff but we'll
just skip the drug resistance stuff and
stop
there happy to take any
questions students first
I'm curious if I'm understanding
correctly wouldn't it make more sense I
mean I know this is the case wouldn't it
make more sense for the wild type that
evolved in the higher oxygen environment
to have um uh like Colony morphotype
that creates the low oxygen environment
to promote growth as opposed to the
phenotype the one that involved in the
low oxygen creating that
so the wild typ string the one that has
the the less clear cut nice looking
morphol yeah so I think the answer is
this I didn't show you is that those H
morph strains are more sensitive to
oxygen so I think in the wild type
strain if you were to adopt that
morphology as so some of the the the
furing we see we think is a stress
response to the oxygen that's a
available in the
environment and and so in the W the
reason the wild type strains haven't
been selected for this in the
environment is because of that oxygen
sensitivity that's our working
hypothesis so like if you take hydrogen
peroxide it just nukes these H Mor strs
and so we think
because as you reduce um electron
transfer through the um electron
transport chain you release a little bit
of Ross and so these H morph strains do
that far less we've measured that and so
we think when you have more oxygen
around when you ramp that up and those
strains would become more susceptible
and so you there' be so in the lab like
a a 5% Fitness defect you you don't
think about or care about but out in the
environment that actually is a huge uh
disadvantage so that's our hand wve my
hand wavy answer cool
thanks it's a nice like segue from that
question do you see a difference either
transcriptionally or genetically in
oxygen sensors so like loin like genes
or anything between doing the HP yeah so
good question so there is a globin like
Gene in fungi it's called fungi
globin um you know I haven't scooped too
many times in my career but that was one
time so we found so that Gene is
regulated by the transcription factor
that I um started you srba and so based
on that data someone pulled it from our
RNA seek and they published a really
nice paper on it um but but it's really
the function it's a globin it likely
binds oxygen they didn't show that in
the paper but in bacteria bacteria have
a homologue and in bacteria it's been
well studied as a molecule for grabbing
oxygen and moving it across the
different side of chromes in the
bacteria cell membrane um so it's likely
doing something like that in fungi but
we didn't see any differences in that
Gene transcriptionally in our between
our hmph and
NPH thank
you um off of that also I'm curious um
with the morphology of the hmph strin do
you think that it's just like the
horizontal growth is just a lack of
clarity overall or is it like
directionally
horizontal that's a great question so U
I have a postto lab is super interested
now so I don't have an answer but he did
his PhD in Rob aro's lab who self
polarity uh lab and so he's super
interested that very question great
question it could also potentially be
have to do with the um cell wall not
being able to support vertical growth
that's another model that we thought
about that the cell wall is weaker um
because they can't make as much kitan um
as the the wild type strain so you can't
get that vertical growth but the
polarity question you're
very when you're looking at your h mark
stengths
specifically do you see an incre
production of other ve compounds like
specifically yeah good question so if
you look at our the RN
oh yeah sorry um the question was is do
we see changes in secondary metabolite
production between hmph and nmor like
with biotoxin and so with gleo toxin no
but there are other secondary metabolism
clusters that are differentially
regulated between hmph and NM morph and
definitely could be involved in the
virulence um phenotype that inflammation
could be involved in dictating how the
colony organizing itself for for
sure especially with the Lea result that
we got recently in the clinical
isol so as a clarification are the
clinical isolat is it easier for the
host to recognize it because there's no
Matrix there yeah I mean e you know yes
so definitely like you know both in
vitro with macrophases and neutrophils
like when they see the hmph strains the
cell to activate rapidly you know
through a decton one dependent mechanis
um it turns out that didn't time of time
one of my students the experiment to do
was to take decton one knockout mice and
see if that eliminated the virulence of
the hmph strains because we thought it
was all this nutrifil that were being
recruited but um like plants humans have
evolved many receptors for these fungi
so when we got rid of detin one we
really didn't see any change in the
progression of disease or the
inflammation but there are known there
are other receptors of beta glucan
within the system but the answer to your
question is yes they definitely are re
form
what happens if you coinfect like your a
great question so we've done those
experiments in the lab and it's wild so
you can take up to like 10 to one wild
type to one cania of hmar and after
three days the whole colon is
H1 so we haven't done it in the mouse
yet but we've done it in the lab we have
I should have so that really cool you
can do different H morph always wins in
the lab condition
have you ever done the reverse Evolution
experiment where
you and just repeat it in
high yeah I bring it up quite often in
lag no one's yet taking me taking me up
on that one um so but it's
um great
question
have does it have what an yeah it does
yeah I'm sorry had to skip through the
the the the second part I mean I show
you one piece of data here
um drug data here it is so this this is
um voriconazol and ampeter B these are
the two antifungals we use in the clinic
to treat aspergillus and so this is the
viability and you can see the biofilms
as they develop become completely
resistant to those
drugs and so there are mutations in the
targets that have been discovered there
are mutations in the drug e flux pumps
uh for the aols that have been
discovered in clinical isolates and so
it is a huge uh growing issue
particularly with the agricultural use
of aols out in the environment that we
the story in the in the field is that
that is selecting for these Target based
and e-lux pump based
mutations just a quick aside since um it
was shocking to me that
there hasn't been any cross talk between
a antifungal development and human
antifungal development those two haven't
talked and so the story here it's a sad
story so this the azol story is one
that's emerging this is the drug but the
second one is there was a new antifungal
in phase three clinical trials it's
called a Laur the dhodh inhibitor it
looks great in the clinical trials and
then out of the blue it turned out U
Monsanto had already developed it as an
a
antifungal and they just released it
last year for use in the fields and in
the lab all it takes is like two
passages on the Monsanto molecule to
develop resistance in the Target Gene in
aspergillis so it's a so what's going to
happen to the human drug is very unclear
now it actually failed it um it didn't
fail the clinical trial but the FDA um
didn't approve it um in part because
they of the resistance this year so
what's actually going to happen there
we're not sure but it's a great molecule
but so we need more cross talk between
the two different groups to make sure
we're not targeting the same mechanism
um given how quickly these organisms
develop
AMR all right well thank you so
much this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu you