this is a production of Cornell
University thank you Bob so you're
welcome I'm going to have one question
for you today okay and that is is um
when you gave this talk to what I'm
going called The Firm conference you um
this was also on it
okay when you gave the results the talk
to talk to the FR conference one of the
questions from the audience was how much
participation did Ethel o
Bailey um how much did she contribute
over the years and what are some of the
activities that she uh contributed the
activities that she contributed on not
only at the aarian but when they did
traveling so could you talk just a few
moments about that are
you um she in the ear after she
graduated from Smith college she came
home and she went on some of the early
trips obviously the one to venezuel wh
and the one to uh Panama I believe also
to Brazil but at some point I think she
mostly was and at she came along as a as
an assistant right and uh I know at one
point she uh had a conflict with bile
and uh with liberty and
she said she wasn't going as a slave or
a or or a servant or something like that
and she just didn't she didn't like not
having a little
more respect maybe is a good word well
we have to remember that Bailey didn't
drive right and that was that was
another thing that she did was uh she
had she had a license she was the first
woman in if to have a license and she
she drove them all the way across the
country and back on a couple of trips to
collect plants in the southern part of
the country in the winter they like to
get out of it go where plants were still
flourishing in the warmer parts of the
year so she did that and uh she also did
much of the organization and processing
of the specimens later um often the the
labels are in her hand I mean some are
by him as well but she did probably most
of the mounting and proration she did a
lot of that uh she also was a a
profoundly good kind of uh editor and
and information gatherer and organizer
in other words being the cator was not
just the bearing but it also involved
Cur curating organizing the information
that they accumulated which was all done
by hand in those days because they
didn't have computers yet so I
understand she also did editing yes she
did books she did she she helped helped
with a refining editing and and uh just
maybe streamlining some of the stuff um
that was and some of the I mentioned in
what I talked about several of several
of them and particularly the big the
Hest encycloped things like that those
big huge efforts like that it would take
a huge amount of effort and cooperation
to prod those kind so I understand she
was a major contributor to her a second
yes
her name is on the first one too right
and the encyclopedia is so you actually
knew her because she came in and
volunteered yes for the for after she
quote retired at age in
1957 and um she retired in 57 she came
in until she
1983 right and you know I had some I met
her a few times during that and and so
she worked with within two weeks of her
death as I recall was more like a month
yeah but it was pretty closed yes and
she she used to sit inside the front
office of theorum and it was sort of
surreal to go in there because her
father's lifesized portrait when he was
Dean was well one of them anyway when he
was de was in back of her on the wall
she looked just like him uh except she
was and so it was sort of startling like
you took a double tape when you came
into the office and she sat behind
a series of cabinets that had thousands
of 3x5 cards and what she she did all
day essentially was go through the
incoming SE cataloges and she would have
them open propped open and every single
entry in the catalog would have an x on
it when she she would find the card for
the company the or you know the nursery
she write you know like say you know
1980 page seven Burpee under under burp
card and then she do that every year for
every catalog that came in so she did
all of that and there are thousands and
thousands of those cards that are still
an aoran so would you have any idea how
many by the time of her death
approximately how many catalogs were in
that collection I think they said i'
said in here I think it was 80,000 wow
that that's a lot of it used to be on
the old hortorium website when we put
the first version of it off it probably
still is if they have one I don't know
there was a time a huge collection and
they had and Bailey just kept they were
resources for his developing career in
Horticulture and of course that the
teaching of that was new in the late
1800s as well not maybe not new but it
was being crystallized in the United
States at least and so he uh he just
kept all of them and so they had full
runs I think it was Harris and Rochester
didn't have volume one number one and we
did because of that because of his his
being so well organized to itself well
it's a great it's a great archive it's a
great archive and I would say probably
in her later years that was her major
contribution was the colle when she
retired that's basically what she also
it was interesting she used to drive her
car way up into her 90s and so she had a
she had faculty status and she parked on
Tower Road right near Plant science it
was a red car remember at the end I
can't remember the color I went wanted a
ride in at one time either toyot
or a small car and she went out with
bundles of unmounted plants under her
arms because she listened to uh the
Opera on Saturday afternoons on the
radio and uh she mounted plants and she
would bring them back Monday morning all
flued and that's special that's the
other thing it's wonderful that she able
to do all that work and and just keep
herself going you know she was she lived
alone until the last year or two w it's
amazing her contributions and people
don't a lot of people don't know of her
contributions she was as I said she's
anung hero
in Artic culturing Bond and she uh I
think she also logistically she like did
cooking and things like that when they
were in the field there's a story
somewhere where they they were put up in
a local Village in in in South America I
think and they they were given an empty
Hut and a chicken that was alive for
dinner so they had to dispatch it and
cook it inse there they they had an
amazing life and she she would not talk
about it and Liberty would talk to her
for just a few minutes according to
reports and then you know he said well
let's get back to the pl they didn't
want to do that and she came from an era
when women were didn't talk about
themselves too much but she did share
one time that when they were in
Panama she uh the colorful version is
that she took a refreshing dip in the
local pool and the log came coming and
she just just escaped the snap of
Jaws so that this she didn't say it
quite so dramatically but it was it was
fascinating to hear her talk about
anything like that and she had been all
you know in many parts of the world in
Europe and and all the way to China and
Japan I think they touched down and Soul
on the way Japan to China too and then
to the New Zealand trip he he did a in
1914 he did a series of lectures in but
that were invited in New Zealand so they
took a steamer all the way and all the
way back and it was in that context that
he had the peace to to write the holy
Earth
M well it's a long trip very long it can
be 16 hours from LAX airport today so
you can imagine on this team how long
and they probably stopped the different
points with mail along the way
so I have a slightly different question
now that has to do with photography so
we we know that we had Bailey started
taking pictures and he did cyano types
and um took Pi a lot of
plants obviously cultural Plants and
Things did did was Ethel involved in the
photography do you think or did she
print the photos or did you ever hear
that she was involved in
that I don't know I I would guess not M
but I know they there there were reports
they developed the negatives in in the
field and at one hotel they they had to
use the electricity for lights at night
or something to print them and it knock
whole electricity out but I I think
probably it was he and she did then she
would deal with getting them onto sheets
with the PS making the envelopes to put
them in so any negatives that I found
and he had he left glass negatives by by
seven glass negatives he had a camera
obviously they took that format um
really they were in paper they were
going to prer envelope but all the
reason I'm asking is all of them had
Bailey's writing I didn't see El writing
I don't think she directly involved in
that except with handling the later the
film negatives which is what we almost
totally have at at the theor and one of
his larger photo projects I think was
when he um did the work on the curits
when he made all the crosses and he made
he made sure he took pictures yeah he
did a big book of cyano types I F1 and
then the f2s and maybe further on tours
for years that was one of the
interesting things we show he certainly
put a lot of effort into that genetics
project and it was something was very
interesting right it was in the I think
it was in the 1890s when the first came
here okay well thank you B thank you so
much for sharing your information with
us today this has been production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu