this is a production of Cornell
University
I
want to show you a rare work at the
crossroads of criminal justice and
education these are two key
controversies in our society and their
intersection is not random we know that
people who end up caught in the criminal
justice system come from neighborhoods
with low quality schools
amongst many other things the experience
of incarceration tends to make tall
barriers to higher education even taller
meaning it's much less likely that
someone wind up in college if they end
up in prison first today I direct the
Cornell prison education program I
have something boastful to say here
about our program but i think it's not
necessary now that Don's giving that
lovely introduction the work i'll share
with you today is from the work i did
before cornell my project was an attempt
to do things in horticulture education
that were new new in prison in
particular possibly new an education
that we've known because of the
oddness of the environment of prison and
the constraints placed upon what is are
now the status quo things we expect from
a college classroom
so what's new about it is not so much
the style of horticulture education that
i was getting at or implementing or how
it was sort of somehow trying to do
something fundamentally different from
campus what is remarkable about the work
is how far i got in trying to make
things the same to how horticulture
could be taught at a good college campus
I see I'm as I'm looking out at you I
see several folks who participated in
the Cornell prison education program
welcome actually could we get a show of
hands quick from who you are so there's
there's several people here in this
section over here who've been involved
in this and so they will understand very
well and and some of them with no
background in horticulture the challenge
of this talk which is trying to both
introduce
things about prison I presume for most
folks in here you've never been to a
high-security prison in America and at
the same time talk about the challenge
of doing education and at within that
the field of horticulture in particular
and what we try to do to have meaningful
labs and activities for students in
prison
so I was trying to demonstrate that it
was possible to do good education in
prison in the field of horticulture and
I hope to share some of that with you
today they're going to be three sections
to this talk maybe I tell me if I talk
too fast i've been told i can go rather
quickly but I've got a lot i'm trying to
do it i just laid out i'll try to
introduce quickly higher education in
prison itself and i'll give you a quick
five minutes on the cornell prison
education program then i'll talk a
little bit about the challenges facing
horticulture education and really still
education in per se but but specifically
horticulture and then i'll talk about
some of the things I did to respond to
the challenges
so this five-minute second is actually
something I do on campus to introduce
the program when we're recruiting
faculty graduate students and
undergraduates who participate in our
program here a quick introduction to why
we would do college in prison
introducing the Cornell prison education
project itself and then the broader
context of correctional reform and what
we think the outcomes are when we put
post-secondary education in prisons so
education in prison is nothing new this
image on the left over here is actually
100 years old Auburn New York a prison
we work in today
classroom adults learning grade school
level curriculum that's the reason we
call them correctional centers in
American societies there's this image of
rehabilitation in prisons the idea is
that you don't just put people in a cell
and abandon them for 10 years and expect
something dramatically different to
happen you rehabilitate them you offer
them program do you educate folks here's
an image from the 70s at when the Pell
grants were made available for the first
time you had financial aid in the United
States college programs entered into the
prisons and there was a era in which
college programs flourished in American
prisons
speeding into the 80s and 90s America
was reeling from questions of what to do
about crime a lot of people its many of
us may be too young for this but if you
can remember the drumbeat of politics
back then was there's too much crime
this other politician hasn't been harsh
enough about crime this guy here thinks
people in prison should be taking
college classes I don't think so this
person here since you should only get
six months for this crime we're going to
give them 20 years and you see over a
couple of decades this trend towards
punitive pneus taking away programs from
people who've been convicted of crimes
specifically the crime bill of 1994 made
it illegal for people in prison to
receive Pell grants overnight we end up
with a lot of empty classrooms where
there used to be college classes
so the question then is really what do
we want to do when we when there's harm
in society when someone's convicted of a
crime we send them away to a prison what
do we what we want to have happen with
those individuals currently these are
the status quo here we have a lot of
exercise yards you've probably seen
these images if you read the New York
Times just kind of a drumbeat right now
of we aren't doing a lot of productive
stuff in there we might even be making
folks more dangerous making license
plates actually happens it over in
prison that's a photo from there and
this is a site that I saw actually down
the hall from where my classroom was in
Illinois where a gym is turned into a
bunk bed unit because of the
overcrowding of prisons because people
don't to spend money on this but they
don't have another answer right now
currently than just more and more
incarceration do you end up with that so
it doesn't even taking away exercise so
okay so now we've got folks that are
literally just in a sort of refugee kind
of situation this is an image from a
Cornell classroom happening at Auburn
prison we've got a pair of graduate
students at the front here aidan Lear's
and dance Anakin the year before both of
them pulled down professorships aidan's
at suny oswego and then how did Grinnell
teaching a literature seminar these are
students many in the room will recognize
from this section over here
having a conversation about literature
then these classes count in our
partnership with a community college
towards an associate degree Bob in the
room here in this photo along with Ron
Seaver as well as the president and
provost of cayuga community college who
work with Cornell in order to make an
associate's degree accessible to these
15 men who graduated on this particular
day in 2012 and in the middle we have a
philanthropist key theme of this work
without financial aid you basically have
no tuition revenue the folks that are in
America's prisons are of the lowest
economic strata so there's really no way
to fund college in prison let alone
combat the political that makes it so
difficult to do this without someone
providing private dollars and typically
not the students and here are the three
persons that Cornell operates in Auburn
Correctional Facility up in Auburn the
medium security prison-- down here in
Moravia very similar to the one I'll be
discussing the day in Illinois and a
maximum security prison in romulus
called Five Points correctional facility
very quick slide about outcomes this is
a an image of a couple of our former
students Sean who I presented at a
conference in nashville with last week
is now part time student at Columbia
John another one of our former students
is a carpenter in town and here is
actually participating in building
homeless shelters with an organization i
think in kamon county and some of our
undergraduates as they go out into the
world many of whom get involved in the
intersection between criminal justice
and the other fields they've studied in
wearing green chords and the graduation
ceremonies are undergrads wear green
cores to symbolize the the green prison
uniforms that our students on the inside
of the prison walls
they're good question done um there are
no prisons that have a mix of both
genders so so just to go back is it
there yeah these are all male prisons
and so yeah we could talk about that one
day so a lot of questions it raises for
folks Oh
ah
yes to Geneva the question was those are
a lot of women coming from Cornell and
to a prisoner the prison's male and
female are mixed and the answer was no
these are men's prisons and that that I
can kind of guess where that
conversation would go let's maybe wait
pull off on them
Willard okay so actually the woman on
the line here is sharing that right next
to Five Points correctional facility
right over here there's a drug treatment
and rehabilitation center which actually
is one of the main alternatives I kind
of count that as a non prison in a way
it's a it's a confinement facility but
it's intended to be a short stay and
release where you're being treated for
drug treatment and it is a
co-educational
thank you
okay I'm trying to zoom ahead here so
let's talk a little bit about this
product I hadn't Illinois and the
challenges faced by a person who wants
to just bring a solid horticultural
education into the place folks who want
to do something positive with their
lives have a chance to do something
better why am I going back to the
challenges after having just spoken
about the denial of financial aid and so
on because there are many other issues
both broad and specific to this
presentation which undergird the work
and present tremendous conflicts the
broader problem is that we have 2.3
million people in prison about 6.7
million people under correctional
supervision that's parole and over 70
million people currently alive with
criminal records as we think about these
the challenges to employing and
generating you know gainful positive
futures for our society out of that
negative resume that all those folks are
carrying with them that's what we're
trying to combat here as an institution
of higher learning we're in a position
to offer education right so that's what
is a university do in prison probably
educate but generally the population we
find in prison lacks access to good
education they haven't had a good
background they don't come from the best
high schools they aren't web designers
already they aren't coming with all the
skills that a lot of our students would
come from
they come from communities with
inconsistent
institutions inconsistent mother tongue
languages and there's no ladder in front
of them good high school to a good
two-year college to a good four-year
college and so that's usually the path
that we try to construct on the inside
in this case in Illinois I was really
trying to defy the odds I might have to
fly through some of this but the main
thing the folks have been in prison
before you might chime in in the QA
to work within the system to change it
is tremendously difficult any campus
educator who doesn't know the
constructional environment what might be
surprised to learn that now generally
there's no one on one conversations
there's no internet there is no email
there are no office hours there will be
no phone calls or notes with your
students there's barely any library
resources of an academic type you can't
just name drop in your class because
your students can go to Wikipedia and
look up the name of that person that you
were referencing now common items are
considered potential weapons or
contraband including scissors large
paper clips DVDs chewing gum sugar
packets anything made of metal or glass
etc you can imagine now that why I'm
saying a majority of what I'm trying to
do is just do a normal education in
prison because what you see a lot of
times when you go into prison is these
kind of aberrations of reality why are
we doing it this way it's because these
rules have made it impossible to do it
in the regular way to put it in
perspective many of the things I
accomplish in the Illinois prison system
thus far have been impossible for us to
accomplish here in upstate New York with
the Cornell prison education program a
lot of that derives from the fact that
the program i did in Illinois I had made
this decision to try to work inside the
system i infiltrated the system as
opposed to Cornell's which is from
without
so just to give you an image of this
teachers generally I presume in my
colleagues throughout the world don't
have the experience of calling a
watchtower on a walkie-talkie to tell
them that they're moving 11 inmates to a
garden with shovels I had a
walkie-talkie I had keys and I had to
secure every single tool when they
weren't in use on the other hand I was
the only person in the facility during
day shift with a PhD I attains the
Appalachian dock folks who knew me as
the one person around was highly
educated and trying to create an
intellectual culture there and I was
really trying to understand the
structural challenges that that were
surmountable to make it possible to have
a real rehabilitative educational
program there so those are the
challenges facing horticulture in prison
I will do them quickly the anti
rehabilitation culture of the prison
competition from other units in the
facility and then inmate cynicism and so
if you think about it this is really the
overall anti a rehabilitation and the
sort of inside of the components of the
prison and then person by person
challenges there's a lot of challenges
so after the denial of Pell Grant so we
might be feeling this this week in our
country a lot of ways a change in policy
or a change in
political era will come with a feeling
of mandate and so correctional staff are
in bold in the feel like it was all
right to oppose all forms of Corrections
in the 90s um not just formally because
there aren't Pell grants but also
informally to say dr. Owens is here I
don't see why he has to come in here I
don't see his name on the list I'm not
gonna let him in today and just and just
this kind of micro
resistance to education barriers were
set up everywhere we lost the keys to
that classroom we're not using it today
this type of thing and this persists to
this day there was rampant racist and
sexist statements in my experience of
working at this prison on a daily basis
and this is something I think even our
folks at work at from the program at
Cornell don't hear as much that the
gender binary of the systems really
makes a very very macho environment in
these places that's why i Don's question
is really right on what's what happens
when you send women and it really
permeated the day-to-day experience of
the facility I'm going to talk about the
this in a little bit more detail so I
actually kept the log of all the stuff
because I this was upsetting it was
traumatizing to me I was hearing my
students described in a way I didn't
like right and people opposing my
mission so this is my therapy I actually
would just say today someone called one
of my students a dog today someone
called one of my students a you
know these visas these kind of racially
loaded words and i worked with this
author james Lowen
who is at american university in DC he's
a historian he wrote this book called
son downtown's he would grow up in
Decatur Illinois I mean so he remembers
there were these towns called son
downtown's Ivan if you've heard about
them the quick thing is towns in the
early 20th century in Illinois would
have put signs on the border of the town
who say things like whites only within
city limits after dark or the more
common one and a slightly more vulgar
one if the Sun Goes Down and you your
ass is brow and you better get out of
town or a lot of times there's a dark
colored donkey you know just running and
I was the image and this was a way of
announcing that these towns didn't let
black people live there you could work
there but when the Sun went down you had
to be out of town
so why are we bringing this up I worked
in a place where there are a lot of
sundown towns in the past now there's
prison towns let's look at carterville
real quicks is up from some of my
research this is actually a place where
I had to go for my training it was a son
downtown in the old days wore black
folks go if they could work in
Carterville in the old days but they
couldn't actually live there this little
town called cope up here this is all
documented in that book I just
referenced City Council statements
real estate records and so on and so
when I went to carterville for my
training I just check this out because I
was curious I'd already been working in
the department of corrections I was like
what's going on here and so I went to
cope i went to carterville and i went to
john logan College which is where
they're now it's now the training center
for Southern Illinois for the Department
of Corrections I don't think most people
would know the John Logan if you go back
in time was the guy basically made his
political career on what's called the
Negro exclusion eggs and quotes like
this language anymore but his career was
started in trying to exclude black folks
from Illinois has really Illinois Smoove
we remember it today is the land of
lincoln so I know this is my colleagues
in Illinois sayings it done before and
this is some of this stuff you know
people want to hear this today but this
is empirical this is this actually
occurred and i want to say specifically
here I went to cope because I was
driving from northern area here it's not
an all white sorry is not an all-black
settlement and
carterville is not an all white
settlement today it really is not the
Sun downtown system so don't misconstrue
what I'm trying to say here we no longer
live in the system cope is basically we
call it like a trailer settlement a lot
of low income my folks there when i went
to john logan College a lot of black
folks were going to college there so
we're really not in that system anymore
but that was a legacy where are we at
today this is the 1952 map of where the
Sun downtown's were in southern Illinois
and so cities that are denoted by all
caps and bold where the known sundown
towns of this region you see I've got
carterville on the red block there
that's the prison I was working in and
it extends up to Northern Illinois a lot
of people know about Cicero and certain
cities of her famous for this up north
today this is where we have prisons in
jails in southern Illinois and so these
are basically prison towns jail domes
and so you know we could say to
ourselves well maybe we've just
completely got rid of racism in the
sixties all went away there's nothing of
nothing correlating between these two
whatsoever it just happens to be a
comparable number about 50 to sundown
towns in about 60 46 jail towns
this is the thing that really drives the
field in a lot of ways this is a
charter this will be hopefully out in an
article next year in american studies of
the incarceration rate in the state of
illinois and so you can see if we're go
back to 52 we've got around 8,000 people
in jails and prisons in illinois and
about a sick and these pie charts down
here carry along they don't always
report demographic data for various
reasons in the correction system but
about sixty percent white back then and
about less than a quarter in 1999 the
last time i had data and so this is
basically up to the time of the work I
was doing now the other thing I want to
point out here is the line the dashed
line is just counting facilities
according to this numeration here so the
best time in a certain sense to be in
prison in Illinois would have been here
because the number was the lowest about
6,000 people in jail you had 11
facilities that means people are the
most space the most the highest inmate
to staff ratio if they were involved in
programs and and then when you see them
starting to close prisons here while the
number keeps going up we're both 50,000
right now that's the overcrowding so
anti rehabilitation culture of the
prisoners very true this just made the
whole project all the more loaded
because not only are you trying to say
hey could you help this student get from
the housing unit over the classroom this
person's later whatever but you've got
this constant drumbeat of these folks
are really not worthy of things not
always in explicit racial terms but a
lot of times in terms of just because
they're considered criminals or inmates
they just don't deserve an education
that's just the mood of the police
alright competition from other prison
functions so here's how the prison works
this is an actual prison it's a google
map the orange house units X houses as
we call them had 400 people each of them
a once missing left wing it's solitary
confinement unit over there was cut off
that there's a school in gym that's
where my classroom was perimeter fence
keeps everyone in and then this extra
fence there blocks off the exercise yard
and in the purple room there you have
some folks making cardboard boxes in
prison uniforms every prison usually has
some industry where they try to produce
something about 20 inmates had access to
that out of about 1,600 1,600 inmates at
this facility ok but so here's the thing
the prison administration and security
personnel in general preferred to
limitanei moving all together unless it
was completely necessary so just to get
a student from the school building to
the garden which we'll talk about in a
second was a tremendous act of acting
asking for permission and you can this
is how they like it so here's an ex
house in Illinois the grass has been
pretty poorly treated they know no one's
moving there's no trees there's no
people this is just a completely
controlled environment you can see if if
people didn't want to send folks after
the exercise yard you could just say
exercise in here today
so when I was in this area I had to
watch towers on the other side of the
garden and so there was always this kind
of constant surveillance of things and
so and you can imagine then if you've
got a party that's in the watchtower
it's kind of looking to stop education
they basically had a kind of constant
micro managerial kind of thing they were
doing of saying I think I saw someone do
something wrong there uh so they can get
on a loudspeaker from a from a
watchtower and say inmate so-and-so come
over here or you need to go back to the
classroom or whatever so this is these
for the resistances zooming in a little
bit more you can see here's the school's
I'd have to walk out here to do this and
you can see there's a greenhouse so this
is actually I mean the main thing years
this should be an environment of a huge
opportunity that's a 0.9 one acre garden
space that's been pre-established at the
prison and a greenhouse here's the thing
there was this grounds crew at the
prison
which yeah I'm going to break the seal
and say the prison was corrupt and stool
pigeons got to be in the grounds crew
and so the grounds crew got the green
house and the garden before I
established this sort of funding
apparatus by which we could have a
horticulture program and I had to work
really hard politically to get access to
this greenhouse for my students and I
could not get access to the greenhouse
so that was the place that basically a
collection of ten inmates on this
grounds crew which would do lawn mowing
including lawn mowing outside of the
fence driving tractors around raking
leaves to the extent that retrieves
getting ice off the sidewalks they could
hang out in a greenhouse in the cold
winter when all the housing units were
fairly cold and most people didn't have
any space because we're stuck in a small
cell they could be in a greenhouse
growing poinsettias for the
administrator's office and so they
didn't they never in the two and a half
years I was in this program let our
program use greenhouse this is really
problematic this is actually the only
photo I have of myself in the classroom
and so this is actually the classroom in
the school building you can see these
tall sort of warehouse like walls no
windows
at me I'm in a green hoodie here hit no
idea camera person was coming um you can
see some of the students here you can
also see there's some folks on computers
back there and yeah so imagine after the
first frost when the garden is
effectively not useful any longer in
terms of doing new projects waterlogged
etc that you know the grounds cruel
control of the greenhouse is
particularly frustrating and
talk more about that so the inmate
cynicism about vocational you so finally
then you have this question of how do
you find good students in here I'm try
to do this quick this is actually the
only thing that the state of Illinois
does in terms of post-secondary
education opportunities when
universities and colleges don't have
proactive campaigns like Cornell's and
the University of Illinois program
that's where I came from
so here's Danville it's got three types
of courses that are offered automated
technology horticulture and career
technology what are those three things
the
automotive
quickly got automotive tech that was um
doing custom paint jobs on correctional
officers cars and trucks for free or for
the cost of the paint souping up their
engines I remember people detailing
carburetors and putting like insignias
and American flags on the different
parts of the cars and stuff and that was
that and then career tech was a six week
class and what you learned how to turn
on a computer and use Microsoft Word so
that's that's the status quo and to
which what you're about to see me trying
to do comes in a brief comment on jobs
everyone always wants to
exclamation of this it's just one paper
of chart
from 2012 study comfortable time in
Indiana right next door to where we were
at in terms of what kind of job outcomes
in a group of five thousand or more
folks had over five years sequence and
these red blob boxes are just trying to
show any overlap with in the way this
paper defined it the categories of
post-secondary education that are
offered in the prison it doesn't even
get into what are the cells just put
asterisks
academic programs have a much wider
range of outcomes I was just talking
with Tommy ervell one of our folks those
in our program the one of Columbia is
now an uber driver another who's now at
Lehman College is a registered nurse
another who's going to
that school of business in baruch
college is a paralegal John's a
carpenter so carpentry so there are so
there's some overlap but our that's the
whole point of having a liberal arts
education is we think that this liberal
arts education will lead you to a proper
consideration of having a examined life
finally good time is a hundred-year-old
concept that
going really fast that's what I said I
wouldn't do check it out there's an old
idea in prison which is you got a bunch
of people there in prison they did
something bad they're gonna get released
one day a lot of them are gonna come
back to prison for doing another bad
thing what if you could take some of
them figure out some activity to give
them that would guarantee that when they
go out there productive and they become
taxpayers and they don't come back
that'd be really valuable to the state
right so you could take that activity
and actually credit them and give them
time off their sentence you could
incentivize them to become these good
people so that's called good time
so a hundred years on that has become
the most pinata concept it is so
bureaucratized and and barrier ridden
that it's almost impossible to implement
this in a good way if nothing else I'm
highlighting here that the very
definition of it in Illinois said that
people who had violent offenses sex
offenses or anything involving a weapon
so even if I go into a store and no one
gets hurt but I said I have a knife on
me you're never getting good time
crazy review I won't even explain this
to you but basically the time it takes
to get a few months off your sentence it
starts all the way in the courthouse
before you're in prison and extends all
the way to the day of your release and
there's six different layers of review
you basically would spend more time
doing the getting the good time than
getting off of your sentence by now here
the actual people that got good time
from my program at about 120 people over
those two years take classes with me 14
students were eligible at all everyone
who's eligible tries to do it and they
fill out contracts typically I've got
about three out of it if they were to
take all my courses so days are credited
towards release from prison and then the
rule in Illinois as you get half of that
number of days off of your sentence so
you can actually calculate out the
number of days or in this case I did it
by years of
sentence reduction that my course
generated multiply that by the cost per
person in prison and there's a cost
savings to the state of about 35
a thousand dollars I just want to point
this out
these ones with parentheses these are
folks that didn't get the credit in the
end their contract was voided because
again they did you know inmate was out
of place got written up throughout their
good time or whatever had had a pen that
was unauthorized throughout the good
time so there would have been actually
much more but in eligibility and
that that kind of constant rule
micromanagement interviewed with this
finally this is the real point
people then become hugely cynical about
this so some of these these are my worst
students because these are the folks
that were basically like okay I'm stuck
at Danville I've got another three years
in prison what do we got here automotive
tech I don't want to go detail some
officers car career-tech well that's
only six weeks so I'm only getting like
just turn on a computer and get out of
there only thing you can get a couple
weeks off your sentence anyway there's
this doc scott guy and he's like making
everyone got to a garden okay I'll try
that and they would be the students that
would be there saying if I get out of my
chair will I lose good time if I get a
c-minus can i still have a good time if
I don't come to class tomorrow because I
feel sick am I going to get good time we
credit the day for a good time if I
leave early today because I have a virus
and so that was just the constant
conversation and so this actually
is just another barrier so it's just an
example of a on the individual level
bear here to this stuff okay
is what we want to hear responses to the
challenges I need to underscore how rare
and unheard of this work is you will
hear me now reference a garden with
hundreds of species of plants a library
with thousands of titles on itself
computers in the classroom
students participating in the
construction of meaningful projects
aimed at helping their fellow men this
is really against the odds and the
infighting environment of prison and
against considerable resistance of
course said there's not many times i'll
spare you
here's the three parts of this are two
parts of this sections can be quick so
we can have some QA this is
fundamentally everything this education
work is about is trying to respond to
this contentious environment and really
hopefully particularly this week
creating an environment where people can
really have a discussion with each other
and try to understand each other and try
to move forward into a fruitful future
together and then I'll talk a little bit
about some of the specific things that I
did there's a classroom my top guys in
2013 for the University of Illinois and
my other hat which is an educational
researcher and I just want to point out
like look at the mood in this room so
it's an all-male facility right these
guys are not in a mode of being
dangerous
psychopathic leave any little micro
thing they do is going to be a trouble
these this is a community that formed
around our program you can see part of
the library here's the library's spread
over three rooms the way that we did it
we get to sit at seminar tables we're
reading research articles and I know all
these people this is the main difference
between folks that do this work
firsthand like some of the folks here in
the room and folks that talk about this
and write about it but have never
visited I know that Johnny page is in
governor State University today Michael
Braun guy from New Jersey like me
cavanon Elam is about to publish an
article in Harvard educational review
came out of some of this educational
work we did there the prison's trying to
block him from publishing it it's on a
really dangerous topic of how education
for prisoners could enhance democracy by
having people have informed voices so
Harvard likes it administration not so
much
this guy's a person who's now a teacher
in a Catholic school and morelia in
Mexico he was deported even though he
was
brought to us when he was one year old
sentence without evidence at the age of
15 he did 15 years and the person who's
my age and has now been moving living in
Mexico where he'd never lived before and
and he's a Catholic school teacher and
is a wife of the friend of mine she said
working like college so these are all
people with names to me they're all
people that are actually doing things
that are good and that's that's the
thing to remember through all this let's
get into what i was doing here this is
actually i didn't know they were going
to take this photo either it was the day
of my job interview where they said look
we till it up the land for you check
this out and i talked to a bunch of
people who know nothing about
horticulture who hired me to do this all
right and I provided the funding for
myself so you know back to the
fundamental challenge of having no
tuition money now we're looking at a
USGS soil survey for the site here's
where the garden would be the
interesting thing here is that you can
toy folks to be familiar with it so
you're looking at a Caitlyn series but
the Midwest soils are typically mala
cells and alpha cells
the garden was in a particularly boggy
area this is one of the things that made
this land not too valuable to the
Mennonites who are actually who sold it
to the state in the early 80s and made
it into a prison so it turns out the
garden is right in the spot that made
the site completely invaluable as a
place to do agriculture I surrounded by
corn and soybean fields oh and also just
no here's the Indiana border so I was
comparing to Indiana for you basically
and you're you're in a Cell on that side
of building here i'm looking at indiana
all rights get in here
so we made maps of this stuff this is
this is by itself a huge feet imagine an
environment in which a string that's
this long is considered contraband
because you could put it around
someone's it's never happened in this
prison but that's the type of thing they
say in the kind of constant looking for
criminality mindset that runs the place
so let alone a tape measure which is
metal which even worse so we actually
had to manufacture the tools to do this
and I would send supplement what we were
doing with satellite photos as you can
see to try to produce
sufficient drawings to show what we're
trying to do the red lines in this case
are digging little channels to drain the
things so they wouldn't allow us to
install culverts because you can hide
weapons and culverts so so we had to do
this type of thing you can see I'm just
trying to get the water to go in one
direction away from here and right away
tremendous food waste going on in prison
so the goal in New in Illinois is to
feed people on one dollar per day or
less the result is very low quality food
and the result is inmates going to the
cafeteria getting their food presented
to them eating the cookie and the rest
gets tossed so we very quickly got into
this composting work an image of what
we're trying to do the first year that
of course this is a final crown sighs we
didn't get any access to bring in full
size trees so we bought bare root
seedling trees and grafted trees in
order to start implementing this it's
just an image of what it looks like the
first year shouldn't be much information
here but you can see the stakes are
where we're putting the trees and
mulching it with grass clippings and
leaves and fresh compost we've made here
to be where we got by May so you can see
then a lot is is food so for another day
the whole thing of bringing nutritious
food into a place with the cafeteria
dynamics like I described is going to
have its own excitations and conflicts
latent into it now and we start getting
into this drought period this is
actually kind of devastating so there
was a drought right around a lockdown so
we couldn't go out there and water
plants they wouldn't let inmate movement
back to that and so this is where you
start getting triangulated by all these
constraints it must have rained one day
and someone took a photo it's the only
photo I have looking that way that ever
was taken so this is that building where
they make cardboard boxes the greenhouse
here and you can see we're starting to
put compost piles out here and when the
lockdown continued that you're in the
drought continued you can see the yellow
beds represent beds that basically
tanked when it got too dry the irony of
our waterlogged soil having been trained
properly
we had to find some other activities so
I've worked at the construction class
when they wouldn't let our students move
they actually produce proper compost
bins
and we get a
sort of rebounding of the garden when
they let us back out there and September
then it's a frost so again now you got
to imagine I've got a good six months or
more you know usda zone 5 so by seven
months in which it's not reasonable to
think that you're going to have much
productivity if you plant plants so what
do we do
we start dividing up the garden beds and
offering the men opportunities to kind
of compete with each other to do better
designs for the different sections of
the garden we had competitions for the
spaces that were common
weird things like this showed up on the
computer this was made with ms paint i
think and cut and paste i actually don't
know how mr. Stilson did this this won
the competition not because it's
reasonable because this looks like water
to me and i don't know what that would
do for the flower and crab apple or
whatever that is i think i'm not even
sure what species he thought we were
gonna plant here and when this is pretty
two-dimensional but um the idea was we
want a picnic table a table and to try
putting some elevation to one of the
trees so that because people like
sitting on these little Stoops
and that then made it into the design
right so we actually you know started
kind of doing this type of thing
we ended up with river birch as the
species we were trying for there and you
can kind of see as we're going along
hear that a lot was developing in 2013 I
should say for another day there was a
whole project of Illinois at sporting me
across the state to implement our
composting system i'm not i'm going to
tell you about that but the composting
thing was huge because of the tens of
thousands of dollars of waste expenses
that the facility incurred and this
being a way to process things back into
the site we started using the
construction classroom which is
abandoned to produce cement papers by
hand and to teach the dynamics of
construction and portland cement and
angry and all that stuff and get these
things out here so you could walk
through the Prairie you can see this was
supposed to be getting designed as a
Japanese garden we had a lot of ideas
and cornell university offered me a job
so that's where we stopped i want to say
i needed to get out of there just you've
heard me i'm coming i'm giving you
actually a fairly sanitized version of
this this was
grading psychological work for me i was
working every weekend i was constantly
bringing in books pdfs trying to get
clearance through a bunch of people that
didn't want me to do this
so i don't recommend anyone do this I
mean I was trying to I was doing the
Superman thing the sort of martyred
teacher trying to make it possible to do
this thing in the impossible environment
and when I left a lot of my students had
also done this educational academic work
with me and they said what are you going
to say when you leave here I said I'm
gonna say this is my time in the
trenches I tried to get into the system
and make a change and we're still hated
here there's still a bunch of messes
with what this is there's lockdowns and
for nothing if we uh here's a satellite
image they mowed it after i left i'm
told so this is supposedly September of
2013 you can still see some shadows
which suggests that maybe some some
shrubs there have survived but you can
see the paper stones you can see the
curly river
and I could say a few things about the
other stuff we did and then you can ask
me more about this so other responses to
some of these challenges I've laid out
to you there's this greenhouse
simulation type of thing I did with grow
lights we tried to make labs work very
challenging design competitions practice
exams and student produce field guides
you've maybe seen one of these things I
generally don't love these things I mean
makes a lot of sense to do without the
lights but if you've got nothing but
vertical space this is how you do it and
this is in an all cement room and I got
two of these things on that state budget
based on the fact that i used the logic
of good time i got the state to give me
an appropriation to buy two of these
things and give every 12 trays of plants
they could mess around with in the
winter and i would engage the students
in the real study of biodiversity so we
had a student from cameroon we studied
the plant the flora and fauna cameroon
we started growing baobab trees from
seed and these trays and declared that
there would be a bell bad bonsai garden
anyway
we also got say cold frames that was
another things we put cold frames there
and also in other places in the garden
that we've walked by as a way to try to
get movement and try to get
truly normalize it at the facility I
don't know why I'm showing this one I'm
showing this one because you see these
things on people's desks those so you're
not out of glass but there were peanut
butter jars that people would buy in the
commissary I mean the guys would scrub
them clean and not really allowed but
somehow they ended up in the classroom
and what I'm doing there is people
should be familiar with it's the soil
shake test it's an old trick to
introduce people to sew a particle size
you know shake up a sample in some water
and it's sediments out and you know you
can use this oil triangle and give some
approximation of what type of so you've
got so this is the type of thing I would
have to do is like figure out what could
happen through this and what could
happen through that I'm just giving
examples from the soil class because
that's happened to be one that I had at
hand we actually did soil pits dug them
and check out shovels and checked out
the different
stratification of soil layers I would
take peds of the soil home photographic
because there's no cell phones in prison
there's no cameras available take it
home photograph it and add it into the
worksheet so people could see what we're
getting at and so all these other things
you might be surprised to hear you can
have a piece of string you can have a
piece of metal but
what it looks like to get a bunch of
inmates to dig a 60-inch soil pit right
next to the fence of a prison inside of
two watch towers with a hose sitting
around that you could throw over the
fence I mean that business with this you
get an image of kind of my world just
trying to explain that to a bunch of
correctional officers folks that we're
using the Excel things started to offer
to make crossword puzzles every again
we're in soil here but this would be an
entire week production they trade it off
and do a kind of blind review of each
other like okay we got this thing and it
was actually I'm widget eyes Dwinell
things so that when you type in wrong
letters it would give you the sense that
you got them wrong and there's some kind
of winning up the whole thing
field guys this was another thing that
the skin keeping the students occupied
in thoughtful activity all day we that
we allow the students to produce this
field guide thing in them in PowerPoint
getting towards the end I know we're
getting late um there's one birch tree
in the entire place we show so I bring
in images of a show it was actually
there there were this was a section
header so is this is no frills
PowerPoint feel good but this is a plane
you saw all the time you were always
kind of amazed we haven't even touched
on the fact that most of these guys are
coming from urban areas where there's
not a lot of plants and I would say the
name of the plants in the sidewalk and
it was always like doc knows like way
too many plants and so this is a way to
kind of say bring in a picture that give
us the name we're going to compete with
you arrive and we're going to note these
planes too so the weed section you'd see
personally and people particularly loved
it there this was like semi edible plan
or whatever but it's also ubiquitous in
Chicago the animal one is actually
really interesting because a lot of this
animal diversity only showed up because
of the plant diversity that we had with
the perennials and the drainage regime
and doing different things to make
habitat not intentionally for the
animals but as a side effect
so this is just a short list from an
early version of this
this is an animal those ubiquitous in
Chicago and some people don't even know
it's also in the prison you can hear it
so this is even to have this in a prison
environment where you could hear
look at and learn the name of and the
habitat of animals that you're seeing in
great flocks I mean I'm talking about
you got dumpsters of wasted soy food for
inmates covered with crows every morning
and people don't know if it's a crow or
a grackle or a starling or whatever this
was a real moment this was probably most
interesting over the years when we have
that drainage change we got there late
goin crawfish returned to the garden
probably from there from hundreds of
years ago right there somehow they were
hanging out in the drainage ditches I
suppose around the prison and there and
someone who's staying in the garden you
hear this holler go up there's a lobster
in my garden
and of course the watchtowers are like
everyone hold still and it really like
what's going on but so obviously this is
a way to side of codify and make it into
a learning moment when these things
would come around finding these things
in your guard but is that a good thing
do I want this bug in here is this a bad
thing what it what our worm castings are
all over my garden bed we put a lot of
compost in there and this is the final
thing I'm going to say about this and
I'll just do a wrapping statement we
basically had you can't see the cursor
here but we made these it's a hypertext
so you know again absence of computer
literacy a real liberal education you
don't need to just give a career tech
class you can teach writing you can
teach genetics and through that
introduced to people to reading pdfs
could be email other things in this case
hypertech so you could click on the the
word crawfish and you'll go to it you
could click on the word earthworm and
it'll go to that slide so so folks we're
actually getting a very elementary
introduction to how the internet works
have you been in prison since the 90s
you've never lived in a society that has
cell phones just think about that for a
second how are you how do you get a
housing today computer you get a job
computer just imagine what folks are
facing when they come in
closing comment these were attempts to
bring horticultural education into
prison as I said at the beginning the
point near was not that I was trying to
develop a special prison education that
is totally different but rather than
education that would be to the greatest
extent possible the same as a good order
culture education would be at a decent
quality college campus I really only
know of one other program that got as
far as the Danville project in terms of
including a pedagogy of sustainability
it's called the sustainable prisons
program it's I got to visit it when i
was at UM never ever been state college
in washington but none of the other
projects i've seen have been as hands-on
in the practice of food production while
simultaneously introducing an academic
body of scholarly research and building
ladders of opportunity that lead up to a
university education and so on the
limits to what was possible here were
largely the consequences of my decision
to work inside the prison and for
various reasons while there are
different limits I'm inclined to say the
better point of leverage is to work from
without the prison system i really do
think that is the proper place for
universities to work and that's where we
find the work of the cornell prison
education program and that's it i thank
you for your time i welcome your
questions and you're welcome to contact
[Applause]
we're supposed to many unfamiliar to you
can describe how the university without
an agenda what is that
well the main thing is
frankly the the psychological turmoil is
much lower for someone that at least him
come back to campus at all times and can
have a community it really that's what
the corners of education program is
provided it is a sense that we were not
to prison since there's a reason we're
not
fundamentally we're trying to create a
culture of learning
provide opportunities to people who are
willing to work to apply to our school
to gain a positive credential that will
deal with them for the rest of life in
prisons are about these people have been
caught doing something wrong we're going
to detain them and constrain what
opportunities they have and give them a
permanently negative record for the rest
of area so we have to be different from
it we can't just know this kind of
dialectic you can try to have a spot
where there's a collaboration
but working there I felt myself becoming
I can't really don't know how to put
this and that's what happened to those
other teachers that are described I
haven't even talked about the GED
teachers I mean you've got classroom
that if gonna turn into a piece of the
prison garage because of the bad power
day and I don't want to run a program
like that I don't think that's the place
the university's ultimately find
yourself the best position to do real
research on what else bonita we
fundamentally sign you off if you're
never going to be able to publish
anything ever going to talk about
anything to get there and I mentioned it
down when I started is one of the
reasons they really put the fright into
you of police power and so yeah a very
hesitant and skittish to say anything
the repercussions would have gone to my
students who I want to see turning into
those jerk
other question yeah so in the court of
garden based learning we work with folks
statewide and the number of settings and
we have for many years and our our
guidance to folks whenever we begin
working with starts to do a really
stellar job with something really small
working with everybody across all the
layers of administration and to do a
beautiful job you can always grow and
you know just watching this I'm both
like wow and tired out from the
presentation if you were to do it again
and looking back on what I mean you
called yourself you know the Superman
approach what would you do
initially and do just an absolutely
stellar thorough thoughtful amazing job
knowing you know all the rest can follow
if you have a successful experience how
would you begin again can you briefly
yes so this question is given the hell
expensive and Superman light that I was
attempting to be here and that I've
heard that definitely let's
get out of this
what would you say to someone else who's
coming into this what would you do
different and would it be worth it to
consider us a small good success instead
of a big for now
yeah I think that you've barely got some
some insights there and as candidly I
was really trying to
provoke the edge between the very tight
environment and you know the liberal
education interested in seeing being a
contributor to come just a few things I
would refuse to take this job if they
didn't give a winter break a spring
break a summer break and some off time
for the students particularly in the
winter I'd be fine to be that intensive
for nine months and had to be a
nine-month of what they wanted it to be
12 months I mean I work today and after
before and after Thanksgiving it worked
December 24th January first and these
guys were abandoned by to put everything
else so a lot of us here notice who were
from the prison program when you leave
those students in the prison it can be
emotionally hard to do this and so it
became a way that I dealt with it was to
just dive in the better thing would have
been to say was have a period of rest if
folks at voc and let they'll get over so
the teacher can put her
I would also start off with a kurta I
basically developed this curriculum no
know how much it is just to develop a
syllabus I at least be developed nine
courses on those for six months that
I've been cut quite the teaching load
was absolutely unsustainable and
community colleges are often guilty of
this as a las through their budget
but I handed this off to another person
who took this on it and I gave every
single powerpoint presentation I had
actually begun to the fluoride set up a
situation like this you could do over
their projections the library was in
fact the cold Frank were there walks in
security tool room the grow lights the
tools to inmates that were assigned to
be assistance to the program in that
person learn after teacher so but at
least if I started there I think would
have been interesting to see if I can 85
years two minutes instead of two and
then we have um Cornell program is
there's a kind of dynamic carriages
there's a lot of time I found in group
that really extends them so far but then
is also very exposed because the
facilities the correctional folks see
those like individuals as having pushed
it too far and so you see the initial
group kind of pulled back a little bit
in another group I don't make something
sustainable this program still exists I
don't know the current teacher so it was
hard but I know they've got those
computers there and they've got these or
some version of what we started
thank you for doing this really I'm
really moved by your work there but I'm
wondering if you have any hope for shows
like orange is the new black what do you
think that could kind of galvanize
people towards prison reform efforts
just by bringing it to more to the
mainstream media and letting people see
the micro aggression with some things
that you're talking about that's
actually a very good question you know i
think that the media has played a big
role in the past years of
wanting portrayal of carceral spaces and
that'd be an example of it because
pluses and minuses to that show when
you're really in these places you and a
lot of people think that one prison
they've seen is representative of the
whole system and so any writer or any
person like me can fall into that
fallacy but i think that there's a lot
better in just because i know i haven't
seen the series full but i know there's
a habit of going back and showing where
these stories started and you heard
almost everyone that I've got a story
about it's like starting at the age of
12 certainly be 15 from the first
incarceration of hers and so it's hard
for us to blame our own built-in 15 year
olds for everything they can do because
they're obviously making bad choices and
so similarly there I think some of that
work is actually really good in building
some semblance of empathy between groups
the probably don't meet each other
even better I think its programs like
Cornell's programs which this semester
sending over a hundred people into three
correctional facilities to actually do
that ectly know these folks to actually
know what's going on when math phobia
kicks in and you realize i'm actually go
to college and I just had a real
psychological barrier around algebra and
I can get a college degree unless I get
past this but here's some folks from
Cornell a totally different community
than me totally different level of
access to the resources coming in anyway
and saying we're going to send you a
tutorial we're going to fizik and help
you with this we're going to let you do
it a second time review this past
failures and making it possible and
giving folks a chance to decide whether
they want to do it or not only you learn
the personality the life stories opposed
to do all this we're not there is
personal counseling but I do you think
that that actually there's a movement
for college in prison that's the reason
the White House was interested in this
work when begs the way to us this
Wednesday the one of our former students
to talk to the secretary of education
about the future through school and it's
because we need to bring people together
and I think that shows can try to do
that but there's also definitely not
sometimes they laugh at that I mean
sorry sometimes I can tell like before
laughing ready is it because that
character is
tragically sad and this is a quirky way
presenting is arif laughing at them
because they're being humiliated and we
kind of enjoy seeing people
impossible situation and all kind of
contortions to survival present building
I
think we're out of time but i want to
thank wrong for a fascinating
presentation so much
this has been a production of cornell
university on the web at cornell edu