this is a production of Cornell
University all right well thank you all
for coming and thank you for inviting me
um this is my second trip to Cornell I
gave a seminar in Hort the old Hort
Department I guess about 10 12 years ago
and I can't remember for the life of me
what it was on so hopefully it wasn't on
this but um what I'd like to do today is
talk about uh some of our work on co2
concentrating mechanisms in higher
plants and I'll give a bit on the uh C4
Evolution story and some of the facets
that we've been doing with that and then
I also want to talk about some
interesting things we've observed that
are going on in C3 plants to give you a
sense that they're much more Dynamic
than we thought in terms of how they
manage photorespiration and deal with
the problems that causes uh and in some
ways take advantage of it so with that
I'll get started and uh this is an old
graph that uh Ed tolber put together
from some years ago um it's the bicycle
diagram that shows C3 photosynthesis and
photorespiration and it's useful because
it sort of gives a highlight of the
start of our problem which is the
photorespiratory
uh the photorespiratory challenge that
plants face so as you're all aware CO2
here gets taken up by rabisco and bound
to rubp and carboxy to produce two pgaas
and then using energy in the form of ATP
and nadph they're made into sugars and
some are regenerated back into rubp to
maintain the photosynthetic carbon
reduction cycle but in atmospheres of
low CO2 like we've had in recent uh
Millennia oxygen can be taken up by
rabisco and bound to rubp in the rubp
oxygenation reaction and this produces
one PG and one one PGA and one two
carbon molecule called phosphoglycolate
shown there as PG now the
phosphoglycolate has no known use to the
plant and if it accumulates it's toxic
so the plant has to deal with it and
using energy they metabolize it back to
PGA but in the process lose previously
fixed CO2 which is uh a bit of a waste
and because oxygen is taken up and CO2
is given off this is called
photorespiration now photorespiration
has a strong environmental dependency in
that worm temperatures and Rising
CO2 uh influence the rate at which it
occurs if you're at high
CO2 the CO2 suppresses the oxygenase
reaction and
photorespiration relative to
photosynthesis here is quite low even at
higher
temperatures temperature promotes
photorespiration by uh promoting the
oxygenase over the carboxy reaction and
if you look at current CO2 levels which
are uh now 400 PPM but correspondingly
in the chloroplast they would be here
where these circles are as temperature
rises photorespiration can rise to quite
high levels as you see out here and if
you close the stomates as you would do
on a hot dry condition you can have
photorespiration rates that can become
exceedingly high and potentially
exceedingly
inhibitory now to deal with
this uh well so this just shows the
result of photorespiration on net
photosyn is here we have temperature
going up and at current atmospheric
levels or at least a few years ago and
21% oxygen a typical C3 photosynthetic
response would be this with a big drop
off at higher
temperatures uh but if you reduce
photorespiration by going to 2% oxygen
or high CO2 then you can see the impact
of photorespiration by comparing the
differences in rates and you see that at
high temperatures this difference
between a photoes Iration free and a
photorespiration inhibited C3 plant are
quite large not such a problem at low
temperatures now because of this strong
inhibition it's been understood for
years that carbon concentrating
mechanisms have evolved to deal with the
problem um
and uh the carbon concentrating
mechanisms that would have evolved
typically came up in dry environments
here where much of the C3 Flora has been
inhibited by the photo respiration
reaction due to the heat of a desert Aid
place like this as well as to stomatal
closure to save water in these
conditions which reduces CO2 around the
chloroplast photorespiration is also a
serious problem for much of the C3 Flora
in places like the tropical rainforest
where high temperatures that you would
often encounter uh would lead to
substantial oxygenase
activities now the most famous of the
carbon concentrating mechanisms that
have evolved is of course C4
photosynthesis because a number of C4
plants are important for our food supply
and collectively it provides about a
quarter of the total terrestrial primary
productivity on the planet just a quick
review C4 photosynthesis has occurred
when the reactions of the rabisco and
the C3 metabolic cycle are
compartmentalized into the bundle
sheath uh and no longer expressed in the
misail tissue and instead in the misail
you've had the upregulation of the C4
metabolic cycle which begins when pep
carboxylase takes pep carboxilate it to
a four carbon acid
oxaloacetate which is then reduced to
melate in the most common form of C4
that travels to the bundle sheath where
a decarboxylating enzyme NAD mic enzyme
acts upon it to release CO2 produce
nadph and then also create a three
carbon residue pyate that has to go back
and with energy be re phosphorated to
pep so with each turn of this cycle CO2
gets pumped into this bundle sheath
where Risco is localized raising CO2 to
levels that suppress
photorespiration now uh a key thing I
just want to emphasize here is that
energy is required to drive this cycle
so we can think of this as an actively
driven energy dependent carbon
concentrating mechanism
two other well-known carbon
concentrating mechanisms are cam
photosynthesis which uh you see here
which is basically the C4 type system
only instead of spatially separated
between a misail and bundle sheath it's
temporally separated between day and
night at night the stomates open CO2
comes in is carboxilate by pep C to OAA
which is reduced mate that's stored in
the vacu during the day the stomates
close creating a diff use of barrier the
melee is released decarbox releasing CO2
which builds up to
um uh suppressed photorespiration at the
rubisco site in a different group the
algae mini algae of all a wide variety
of forms you've had the evolution of a
bicarbonate pump typically where an atpa
pumps protons out and in a code
transport mechanism they bring
bicarbonate
in and then in a specialized compartment
in the chloroplast called the pyranoid
and UK carots and the carboxysome and
pro carots Carbonic and hydrates
converts the bicarbonate to CO2 which
then builds up to high concentrations
around rabisco and suppress
photorespiration now again I want to
just emphasize ATP is needed here so
this bicarbonate pump is an actively
driven CCM and then the rebuilding of
the carbohydrate pool that will provide
the pep at night ATP is needed so the
cam system can be considered an active
pump
so in these active CO2 concentrating
mechanisms you need the energy to
concentrate the CO2 the rabisco is
localized to a CO2 enriched enriched
region and you have a resistive barrier
to slow the efux of CO2 and the C4 the
resistive barrier is the bundle sheath
wall um in the cam it's the whole uh
epidermis with closed stomates and then
in the algae It's a combination of a
water layer and the pyranoid or
carboxysome uh boundary so again there's
the examples of these active
systems
and as you probably would as I've
mentioned raising the CO2 through this
pumping mechanism reduces
photorespiration it doesn't get rid of
it but it reduces it down to a few
percentage points of photosynthesis a
second key thing of these CCMS is that
by raising CO2 up to these high levels
they overcome a SAT a substate substrate
saturation of rabisco that's present in
the current environment so here we have
the carox capacity corrected for
photorespiration here we would say I
have a curve at 30° this is just a
rubisco substrate response to CO2 here's
the current CO2 level which you can see
leads to substantial substrate
limitation and then if you raise the CO2
level to what you have in a C4 or a
pyranoid then you begin to approach CO2
saturation so in a low CO2 environment
this is a substantial benefit that
plants would have with active
CCMS now there 's a lot of interest
these days in how when and why active
CCMS have evolved and with C4 we've been
working on this um a bit in the last 15
years I got on to this when I edited a
book C4 plant biology in the late 1990s
and uh a nice thing about editing
books is you find out how well the field
is really understood and with respect to
C4 I found out that when it came to
evolutionary questions things were
pretty
rudimentary so sort of a
state-of-the-art at that time we thought
there were 25 independent lineages we
knew they all occurred in advanced
angiosperms there was speculation that
C4 was maybe 10 million years old the F
genetic understanding was pretty poor um
and we knew there were a number of
species that had traits that were
intermediate between full C4 and full C3
type species
this philogyny that Toby Kellog
published in the book in her chapter
sort of summarizes it uh here we have a
philogyny of the Carol fil class kopil
and if we just look at amaranthus here
which is a group known to have some C4
species you can see that it's not well
distinguished from other group species
within the amaran kopia alliance uh we
didn't know whether there were C3
species here because it hadn't been
fully surveyed and we didn't know
whether there were sister groups that
might have intermediacy and this would
be true of most of the clades where we
could find um C4 species being
abundant and so we really couldn't
address evolutionary issues because of
the rudimentary state of the flyo
genetics due to low species coverage due
to an inability to know who were C3 and
who were C4 and then also poor
resolution so beginning spurred on by
this from the uh
editing job I did on that book um my
co-workers and I here's Tammy Sage one
of my co-workers uh we went to various
herbaria around the world Q New York
Botanical Gardens Missouri Botanical
Gardens and we went to the this uh
herbarium specimens in these clades
where we knew C4 occurred took little
pieces of samples and measured the
carbon isotope ratios uh
which uh are easily distinguished
between C3 and C4 so C4s have a carbon
isotope ratio of -8 to -6 c3s orus 20 to
minus 32 easily determined with a mass
spec at about $5 an assay so we could do
thousands of assays and so we did
thousands of assays on many plant groups
and then we teamed up with philogynist
from around the world working on these
groups Thomas bourch for example with
the amaranth
and we were able to get them to get
provide more detailed analytical
philogenetic assessments of the groups
we were interested in and then we mapped
C3 and C4 onto these philogynes and so
here's just the
amaran and by doing this having a more
detailed phogy because we had something
to bring to the table which is the
Isotopes we then mapped it on and in the
amaran you can see cleanly there's five
distinct origins of C four uh in
amaranthus in irva small one in tioma a
smallish one in alternanthera and then a
relatively large one in what we call the
gids a five generic group uh Gina and
its
allies and now we could go and to these
Branch points and ask what's going on
here uh do we have intermediate species
and can we put that intermediacy in a
philogenetic context
okay here's one that we just published
last year on the group bfis we have a C3
ancestral CLA that's in assister
position to a C4 clay and we have this
intermediate CLA branching here that
through a preliminary survey of cray
type anatomy in the leaves looks to have
a lot of intermediate States and so now
uh in six weeks I'm going to South
Africa with my PhD student and we're
going to collect a bunch of these guys
so that we can develop a living
evolutionary model of
C4 now between our efforts and efforts
of others in the field we've been able
to come up with a pretty good map of C4
evolution in the in the higher plants
and as you see here uh there's a cluster
in the grasses the sges and grasses are
collectively the graminoids there's a
cluster in the carop feles order and
then there's a number of scattered
groups of varying sizes uh in the
angiosperms and when we go and look
carefully we can identify over 60
independent lineages of C4 Evolution
which is kind of surprising given that
it's a fairly complex trait
um now with this uh ability to use the
philogynes we can also go and use a
molecular clock approach to estimate
when C4 evolved in these distinct
lineages and my colleague Pascal
Christian did this in a paper that uh he
published for grasses in 2008 and then
we published for grasses and UDOT in
2011 which is summarized in my annual
review
here and this shows the spread between
the um stem node and the crown node with
the midpoint there for 46 lineages of
grasses and UDOT and you see that
beginning about 30 million years ago
based on molecular clock approaches the
C4 lineages diverged from ancestral C3
lineages and as you come forward in time
over the past 50 million years you get
more and more lineages appearing now we
can link this up with changes in Earth's
climate and atmosphere so if we look at
atmospheric CO2 content shown here this
beginning here correlates with a drop in
atmospheric CO2 down towards levels
similar to today and consistently
geological Studies have shown C4
Isotopes and fossils and then evidence
of big expansion of C4 grasslands and
other ecosystems in the subsequent 20 to
30 million year
period now recently what I wanted to do
is look at this in a little more detail
and on the next graphs I'm going to show
you responses related to the midpoint
between stem and Crown nodes uh
in these projected dates so what I did
is I went and was able to estimate the
number of species for uh each of the
projected C4 lineages and now we can
estimate the time Origins for 52
lineages which is shown here and what
you can see is that using the midpoint
just to keep the graph kind of clean
here's the range between crown and stem
nodes for the 52 of the 60 lineages you
can see that the older lineages are the
ones that have become the most
specious with three grass lineages
chlorid doids
andropogon and the melind group being
the most specious the UDOT which tend to
be about as old as the grasses the older
ones are more specious and as you come
down to the younger groups such a um you
find that in grasses in the red
triangles OTS in the black circles and
sges in the blue symbols in the last 5
to 10 million years all the groups are
fairly small in terms of species number
and then we can look at when these
lineages occur just to the number of
lineages as a function of the last 30
million years starting here uh 20 to 30
million years ago and then a burst of
evolutionary diversification in the last
15 million years now this is a recent
CO2 graph with oxygen isotope data that
gives a climate proxy I'll just focus on
co2 this is a paper out of Mark pagani's
group at Yale that used a number of
proxies to estimate CO2 levels over the
last 40 million years uh here we are
today 40 million years ago and at the
time 40 to 30 million years ago CO2
levels are projected to be high by a
number of complimentary proxies and then
in the late oliga scene about 25 million
years ago the CO2 level drops down a
little bit of a drop here and then over
the last 15 million years it's been
about what it was um in recent
geological time with a drop down to uh
below 300 PPM in the last ice age now
putting on this graph from the previous
panel I showed you to just allow you to
look at CO2 versus C4 evolutionary
diversification you see in these higher
CO2 periods a few groups diverged um and
then in the low CO2 periods of the last
20 million years is when most of them
diverged and then if you look right
after this little drop from about 500 to
somewhere around 400 PPM that's where
you get the greatest level of Divergence
so that looks like changes in
atmospheric CO2 were one of the drivers
or perhaps you will preconditions for
evolutionary diversification of
C4 now we've been working on how C4
evolved and uh beginning with work by
Russ Monson in the genus flaria and
continuing with many other groups I
picked up on this you know in the last
15 years and we've come up with a
conceptual model for how you can build a
C4 plant and it basically follows as
I'll explained so from an ancestral C3
condition you have anatomical
preconditioning which we suspect might
be things such as um close vein spacing
High genetic
duplication um and then we you we
propose that you have enlargement of
bundle sheath cells with more organel in
the bundle sheath cells so that the
bundle sheath becomes physiologically
engaged and
activated and then we have mitochondria
for some reason and moving to the inner
bundle sheath wall and together at this
stage you get what we call the protoc
cran condition because you see hints of
crayons Anatomy starting in these
otherwise C3 plants and then you get a
key mutation where you lose glycine
decarboxylase expression in the misail
and it's only expressed in the bundle
sheet cells and associated with
mitochondrial enlargement and further
elaboration of misail to bundle sheath
Ray shows you get what's called a
photorespiratory CO2 pump or a condition
we call C2
photosynthesis and once this is
established you get upregulation of the
C4 cycle which then leads to full C4
photosynthesis so what I want to do now
is to show you some of the evidence we
have from two groups uh heliotropium and
nne one's a UDOT one's a grass for this
particular model
okay so before I begin I want to just go
over photorespiration a little bit so
some of this might make sense so here's
the photorespiratory
pathway uh phosphoglycolate made by the
oxygenation of RVP is converted to
glycine in the proxy this goes to the
mitochondria where an enzyme glycine
decarboxylase acts upon it releasing CO2
and Serene and the Serene is made back
to PGA and the CO2 Pres presumedly is
able to escape from the
cell okay now this CO2 under high
photorespiratory conditions actually can
be viewed as a resource and if the plant
can uh compartmentalize the release of
this GDC it can actually set up a
condition where this CO2 can drive
improved
photosynthesis and so Russ Monson
proposed some years
ago that you get a specialization of of
the photorespiratory pathway into two
cell types the misail and bundle sheath
and this simply happens when you lose
GDC expression in
misail uh
mitochondria and if you have enough
mitochondria in the bundle sheath which
you can have in a physiologically
activated bundle sheath then the
photorespiratory glycine that's produced
will have to flow from the misop which
is much more voluminous into the bundle
sheet cells where it can be acted upon
by DDC to release
CO2 and any chloroplasts then that are
nearby can take this CO2 and assimilate
it at a much higher efficiency than what
occur out in the misail so you would in
essence then get a a CO2 concentrating
mechanism formed simply by the
relocalization of
GDC so we went into heliotropium section
orthos stakis which Mike Frolic had
identified as having C3 C4 and C3 C4
intermediate species and taking Leaf
samples we characterize their Anatomy we
developed a philogyny which is shown
here and we looked at some of the
physiological and more recently some of
the molecular traits now the species we
collected are heliotropium calula and
telum here at the base of the orthos
stakis clay we got heliotropium kinsky
and procumbens here further up the CLA
we got a C4 heliotropium texanum and
then these two
intermediates convol aium and grei so
you see a sense of evolution
philogenetic um progression from a
distal to a more or from a basil to a
more distal series of branches with C4
being acquired in the more distal
branches now here is the anatomical
progression that we see
as we move from a more basal to a more
distal position and this is typically
C3 small bundle she cells without many
organel in this heliotropium telum you
begin to see inflation of the bundle
sheet cells but not many organel
heliotropium karwinski you begin to see
sort of a rounding out of the bundle
sheath cells into something that sort of
looking like yeah preliminary first
phase cran Anatomy here's here we have
Troian PR cumbin with pronounced but
smallish bundle sheet cells and here we
are in the intermediate heliotropium
convol aaum and you can clearly see a
bundle sheath vascular patterning
becoming more pronounced and in the
intermediate heliotropium grei it begins
to look almost C4 like with big bundle
sheets and then here are your
C4s now the data compiled from
this shows that the misail tissues drop
off in their percentage of the leaf
cross-sections in the C4s but not so
much in the c3s OR intermediates but the
big change is a buildup of bundle sheath
volume as you go along this this
philogenetic gradient from the basal to
the more distal c3s and then into the
intermediates and the C4s and this is
seen also as a reduction in misail to
bundle sheath ratio vein do density
doesn't change because the c3s has start
out with a high vein density that's
similar to the
C4s which might be a preconditioning
trait now we look at organel levels in
these things uh here we see organel per
bundle she cell uh and this is for the
chloroplast this is for the mitochondria
and then this is looking at the position
of those organel the percent of organel
in the inner bundle sheath going from
the basil species in that clay C3 is
guys into the intermediates and then
finally the C4s and you don't really see
any C3 progression In chloroplast
numbers the intermediates have much
higher chloroplast numbers the C4s have
variable um this has few chloroplasts
but they're gigantic the mitochondria in
the c3s you see uh relatively low here
but in the bundle sheath of heliotropium
kinsky I we see a significantly enhanced
number of mitochondria and then they get
to be quite high in the um
intermediates now the positioning though
shows a dramatic change as we go up the
philogyny towards the more distal
branches you see a progressive shift of
chloroplast POS positioning from the
outer half to the inner half such that
by the time you're in the intermediates
most of the chloroplasts are on the
inside and the mitochondria seem to show
the same shift so there's one C3 a
second C3 and a third C3 species as
you're going from basil to the node
that's sister to the intermediate and C4
branches we looked at glycine DC carboxy
a
localization here's the C3 each of these
brown spots is where you have staining
for gine decarboxylase in the
mitochondria this would reflect a
mitochondria and you see in hel rium
telum the basil C3 it's scattered
throughout the misail heliotropium
Kinski which is a few nodes more distal
towards the C4 clades you see the
glycine decarbox is scattered throughout
the misil but you see this
characteristic or this uh interesting
banding right around the inner part of
the bundle sheath hopium procumbens you
see that banding a little more strongly
this is physiolog ically a C3 species
and when you get into the intermediates
you see no decarbox expression out in
the misail and it's all concentrated
into the bundle sheath especially along
the inner half of the cell lining the
vasculature and here's another view in
heliotropium grei a C3 C4
intermediate and heliotropium texanum
shows a typical C4 pattern where GDC is
restricted to the bundle
sheath now I want to look at what's
going on in
karwinski a C3 species
physiologically and here you see this
vasculature which is larger and more
pronounced it's not huge by C4 standards
but it's big by C3 standards and here's
the GDC stain and you see there's a lot
of GDC staining along the inner part of
the bundle sheath cells here's the GDC
out in the
misail so we looked at the transmission
electron micrograph at was what's going
on and there's very few mitochondria
visible in this outer part and instead
they have lined up onto this inner part
here where they are associated with a
few chloroplasts so we've had in this C3
species that's sister to the
intermediates a polarization of
mitochondrial
distribution now when we go to the full
C3 C4 intermediate heliotropium
convum a very fairly pron Ed bundle
sheath enlargement very pronounced GDC
localization to the inner part of the
bundle sheath and when we look at it at
the tem we see a very high number of
mitochondria here here here and this cap
of chloroplast layering over them and
this is along this inner part of the
bundle sheath here's another view
here and
so this then is the classic c3c for
intermediate anatomy and physiology and
the idea is is that photorespiratory
glycine formed out in the misail has to
travel to these layer of mitochondria
here to be metabolized and release CO2
which these chloroplasts can scarf up uh
with high
efficiency and here's a diagram of this
mechanism where photorespiration
produces glycolate which is made into
glycine it comes into these
mitochondria because mitochondria out in
the misop have no GDC mitochondria and
the bundle sheath have the GDC the CO2
is released upon metabolism of this
glycine Serene goes back to complete the
photorespiratory cycle this CO2 builds
up to about three times maybe four times
what otherwise would be allowing these
chloroplasts to operate at high
efficiency and the effect of this on
photosynthesis is visible here C3
photosynthesis that photosynthesis is a
function of intercellular CO2 in the c3s
you have a high CO2 compensation point a
shallower slope than you would in a c4 a
uh slowly saturating response and in the
C2 type this is based on C2 or this is
based on
heliotropium you have a reduction
in
CO2 compensation Point slightly bigger
initial slope and an overall improved
photosynthetic performance at low
CO2 now I switched into talking about C2
photosynthesis and this is a term that I
coined uh to ref to try and come up with
something that physiologically describes
this
metabolism separate from the term C3 C4
intermediacy which had been used
previously and it refers to the two
carbons in this glycine molecule that
shuttle CO2 into this internal
compartment of the bundle sheath in a
similar manner as the four carbons in
melate that shuttles CO2 into the bundle
sheath in C4 and the reason I came up
with this uh is because we were running
into confusion between what is a C3 C4
intermediate trait and what would be um
a physiology that could exist in a much
wider range of plants than those that
are evolving towards
C4 now just quickly another group The
narachan we've been studying and this
has C3 C uh C3 C4 intermediates and C4
species we collected eight in the Wilds
of Australia in sites like this here's
the intermediate species neurac minor
growing in a in a pot a a rocky pothole
that's been formed and here I just want
to show you bundle sheath and misail
this is actually a specialized layer
called the misto sheath it's not
anatomically proper bundle sheath but
it's a vascular sheath layer and I want
to look at the mitochondria per cell GDC
per mitochondria based on um the number
of gold particles appearing in an imino
blot stain and the GDC Percell area
which is
uh GDC per mitochondria times the number
of mitochondria and I'm expressing this
as a function of CO2 compensation point
where C3 values are high right here and
C4 values are the zero ones right there
now in the bundle sheath we see the
number of mitochondria per cell going up
as we go to lower CO2 compensation
points and then it comes down into the
C4 the GDC perito goes up as we go to
lower CO2 compensation points and
correspondingly in the misail the GDC
levels come down in a progression and
then the number of gold particles per
cell area which is a function of mitos
and so on you see going up so you're
getting a lot more GDC in the bundle in
the sheath cells and a bit less out in
the misail so you're seeing a similar
pattern to what we see in heliotropium
in this grass group of gradual
enhancement
of GDC in the in the sheath cells while
the misop prog expression goes
down okay now through the taxonomic or
the philogenetic work and the isotope
work we've now identified uh a dozen
independent lineages where this C3 C4
intermediate condition is is sister to
the um uh C4 condition using this
pattern of C2
photosynthesis but we've also identified
four clades with no evolutionary
relationship between C4 photosynthesis
and the expression of this C2
photosynthesis type
metabolism now here we have this again
and what I want to emphasize and this I
got to thinking about this and thinking
about the fact that this metabolism does
not necessarily have to be associated
with C4 evolution
that it could operate as a Bonafide
carbon concentrating mechanism in its
own right and a key thing about this is
no additional ATP expenditure is
required so you have a buildup of
glycine from high
photorespiration and by a strategic
relocalization of GDC into this one
compartment where chloroplast can be
enhanced you can affect CO2
concentration without spending any extra
energy so we have then a passive CO2
concentrating
mechanism and it's kind of interesting
to think that in the case of C4
Evolution the evolution of this passive
mechanism to scavenge
photorespiration or or built the bridge
if you will to the C4 condition by
setting up this um structural misail a
bundle sheath system and upon this you
could then layer on the active C4
metabolic
cycle now this pyramid diagram just
shows the diversity of photosynthetic
CCMS inorganic pumping of bicarbonate
cam C4 and now the C2 passive
type but it got me to thinking what
might be going on in the
c3s are they playing with
photorespiratory CO2 to enhance rabisco
efficiency and so we decided to go and
look for passive CCM type conditions in
the C3 uh flora and I'd like to begin
with
rice now we went and looked at Rice
misail cells uh as part of the C4
engineering project and one of the
things that struck me about these in
this longitudinal section here is the
chloroplast form this dense layer around
the periphery of the cell here you see a
nice view of
that and the mitochondria here here here
here are all positioned to the interior
of this chloroplast layer which is quite
thick and where you have gaps between
chloroplasts as right here you get these
extensions forming where the chloroplast
blbs out to form uh a seal between the
two of them and block off direct e-lux
Roots out of the cell here we see
transverse sections and you see there's
a chloroplast in these lobed protrusions
of the misail cell here's my mondria to
the inner part and here's these
extensions what we call stromal
extensions and here's some high mags of
the extensions here you see an extension
sealing off a gap between two
chloroplasts here's a bunch of
mitochondria sandwich between the
chloroplasts here's a case where the
chloroplast has actually been enveloped
by these chloroplast extensions and
there's another case there and this got
us to thinking what could possibly be
going on here we did an imuno gold blot
for rabisco and found that in these
extensions or stromules you have Risco
present here's a mitochondria that's
blocked off from the periphery of the
cell by the stromal
extension and so we then redrew the
typical appearance of a C3 Leaf to
create it something like this layered on
the photorespiratory cycle here oxygen
is being uh taken up carboxylating rubp
to form phosphoglycolate the glycine
then is metabolized by GDC in the rice
mitochondria CO2 is released but it's
released into this internal space and
the only way out is through a
chloroplast or the stromal extension
which gives rabisco a chance to capture
and refix this CO2 and under high
photorespiratory conditions this surge
of CO2 produced could potentially
enhance the amount of uh CO2 in the
chloroplast and improve rabisco
efficiency so to test this I formed a
collaboration with Tammy Sage uh my
faculty colleague Ace of cousins floran
bush is my postto and in a paper
published in PCN a few years ago we
presented the results of our study now
what we you wanted to do is to measure
directly the amount of fixation of
photor resir and respired CO2 by
chloroplast before it can leave the cell
to do this we used a pulse Chase system
with carbon 13 where we first loaded the
leaves with carbon 12 and then we all of
a sudden switched them to carbon 13 a
pure carbon 13 CO2 source so
assimilation of carbon 13 measured by a
mass spec would give us photosynthesis
this way and then we'd be able to
measure the respiration signal by the
carbon 12 coming off and the carbon 12
that was refixed here would presumably
be coming from these
mitochondria okay and through a series
of
mathematical uh calculations we were
able to estimate a number of
things and we did the measurements at
350 PPM and
30° and in rice which has chloroplast
coverage of the misil of 99% so 99% of
the misail exposed to intercellular
space is covered by chloroplast we
measured the total reassimilation of
photo respired and respired CO2 was
about 51% and 29% of that was coming
from CO2 that was directly reassimilated
from
mitochondria and we modeled then that
the increase in chloroplast CO2 due to
this was 14 PPM and this led to an 11%
enhancement of
photosynthesis now we repeated the
measurements at 200 PPM which was the
CO2 level 20,000 years ago here the
total reassimilation was estimated at
59% of respired and photor resir CO2
intracellular reassimilation was
38% we estimated that the CO2
concentration inside was enhanced by 16
parts per million from this photor resir
CO2 and that boosted co uh
photosynthesis by
33% over what it otherwise would have
been and at these low CO2 conditions
this level of enhancement is actually
starting to become
substantial we did the same for wheat
wheat also forms these stromules here's
a mitochondria and there's two stromules
this is the view you would get if you
were looking at the wheat cell standing
face on and you can see the high
coverage of chloroplast with only a few
gaps between them and so this
effectively forms a
cage that will force photor resir CO2
through the chloroplast as it's
diffusing from the mitochondria to the
outside of the
leaf and we just did these measurements
at 350 PPM and we estimated that the CO2
concentration in the chloroplast from
this
[Music]
so we call this refixation of
photorespiration for the hot uh dry
conditions that you would have in these
kinds of environments
and so one of the things we want to do
in coming years is actually screen wild
populations in these environments prone
to photorespiration for this kind of uh
anatomy And it raises a paradox of the
modern biosphere which is the CO2
concentration in the recent atmosphere
was quite low it got down to 180 PPM
20,000 years ago which in the tropics
would cause high levels of
photorespiration it averaged around 230
240 PPM throughout the Ice Age based on
Ice core records um and so these
conditions would be strongly inhibitory
because of increased
photorespiration you had C4 plants out
there who would have provided very
strong competition yet despite all of
this 90% of the Earth's plant species
are
C3 and most of the C3 plants occur in
the
tropics most of the low latitude biomes
are dominated by
c3s and C4 is actually rare and absent
in most life forms such as trees and
Vines so although C4s do well in certain
situations like grasslands they are not
the dominant vegetation of the warm
parts of the planet even in these very
low CO2
times um and so we're wondering whether
recycling a
set or compensate for these low CO2
conditions
now we've come up with the term passive
CO2 concentration to describe the C2
photosynthetic system that can lead to
C4 or can exist independent of any C4
Evolution and we've described uh some of
the criteria that would fit a passive
CO2 concentration so CO2 around some
rabisco is enhanced by strategic
placement of MIT andrial CO2
assimilation or CO2
emission no extra energy is required
hence the passive aspect you need a
resistive barrier to slow the efux of
mitochondrial
CO2 the Risco needs to have specifically
enhanced photo CO2 and photosynthesis in
these regions where the
selection You could argue that it's a
Bonafide adaptive feature um in and of
its own
right and of course if it enhances
carbon gain and fitness so I've
described C2
photosynthesis but we're arguing that
this mechanism seen in rice and its
allies here is also a passive CO2
concentrating mechanism it's not a huge
impact but especially at low CO2 it's a
significant impact that could maybe
enhance plant Fitness enough to offset
the
potential uh for say out competition by
C4
plants now when we think about passive
CO2 systems we got to move and think
Beyond just photorespiration but also
respiratory CO2 and where you get thick
respiratory CO2 tissue such as stems or
fruits then by putting a barrier in
place you can actually have a passive
CO2 concentrating mechanism so here we
have the stem of a birch and you have
this particular sclerotic layer a scorin
layer in the outer part of the stem
here's the florum pinka and the
chloroplast and the florum pinka are
autof floring showing that they're
fairly potentially physiologically
active respiratory CO2 produced in this
stem could diffuse out but get held up
by this scoren layer and potentially
build up to a point where photosynthesis
in this FL layer and maybe down here in
the pith layer is enhanced so that
rabisco can operate very
efficiently in
cinella you have a condition where a
thick cortical layer could provide a
resistive barrier and then you have
these lacune that form and diffuse up
from below ground tissues bringing
respired CO2 with them and alining these
and by linning these below ground or
these laun from below ground with
chloroplast the CO2 that's coming up
from below ground from Roots and tuber
romes and even soil respired CO2 could
allow these chloroplasts to operate with
high levels of
efficiency so these may fit the criteria
of a passive CCM and it would be worth
going back and looking at many of these
species to see if these are specific
adaptations to improve the carbon
balance of these plants um
in geological times of low
CO2 okay so if
uh that's it uh just a quick thanks to
my funer insert my various posto and
grad students uh who have worked with me
on the project Pascal Christian who we
collaborated with on a lot of the phog
genetics and with that I'll take
questions
[Applause]
guess the obvious question is why don't
all CS do this they
me do what do do do which of these the
traic traic but that Rice does uh they
may we've looked at a half a dozen crop
species and they all do it to some
degrees some of them don't do it as much
as rice rice and wheat stand out in
having a very high chloroplast
number so you get that complete sheath
around the periphery that's expensive in
terms of uh nitrogen and other things
and when you go to low nitrogen you see
the chloroplast becoming fewer in number
and they spread apart gaps form between
them and then you see the refixation
potential going way down as CO2
presumably leaks out much more readily
so there's a cost associated with it um
but one of the things you see in the C3
plants is the chloroplasts tend to be
very thin and pushed up against the
periphery indicating that evolution is
made for these small thin chloroplast
but a lot of them uh when you go to the
C4s for example you don't have that you
have fewer chloroplasts than many of
them are much bigger because they don't
have photorespiration occurring out in
the me so they don't have this
evolutionary uh imperative to have to
deal with so yeah but most seem to have
the ability to do this if they have
enough nitrogen and can build enough
Chlor yeah so obviously there's there's
potentially a lot of inits to making
this decision between a c2v mechanism or
not but how about temperature because
temperature affects the CO2 and oxygen
solubility do you see with increasing
temperature among C3 species a greater
propensity of C2 concent all the C2
concentrating mechanisms and all those
cles that I showed you
um are very high temperature climate
plants okay so if you go to lower
temperatures then you see less you don't
see any of them yeah yeah so the C2
mechanism that we see um all those
groups listed
here actually I think let me see if I
got a picture of one of these guys
growing in its natural
habitat there this is the natural
habitat curve C2 this is the Mojave
Desert surface temperature here during
the growing season is 65 C the leaves
are working around here's the leaf
temperature um starts off at 20° by the
middle of the day it's approaching 50
this is its growing season and it's
supported by Monsoon rains that provide
summer moisture um so at this condition
especially at 300 or 280 PPM the
pre-industrial CO2 L that would be
really high photo respiration so that's
a big slug of CO2 which on the one hand
you could just let it go away or on the
other hand by strategically placing your
GDC then all of a sudden it's a great
resource to to
exploit yeah so following up on that a
little bit I mean I buy that C2 is a
precursor or whatever the
C4 but why is C2
maintained do you see environmental
segregation between c2s and
C4s you might have expected everybody
that's in that kind of environment to
eventually evolve towards a C4 and C2 to
no longer be extent yeah um well
everybody in this kind of environment
um c3s do do well but they may be doing
well because they're kind of sitting
still when it's this hot they use early
morning hours and close their stomates
and sleep through the afternoon they
take a Festa or they may be operative
off seon during the winter or something
so you do see a lot of the c34 such as
um some of these guys just shutting down
when it's this hot and there are C4s in
that same these
grasses yeah there C4s now one of the
things about these c2s is they tend to
occur in these Oddball
environments or they tend to occur as
weeds so for example the one that occurs
around here is a a mugo vertic Salada
which is called carpet weed and it grows
on peop patios and lawns in July and
August it's it's a fugitive species so
it's sort of escapes competition by
growing in these opportunistic but hot
sites so if you have a black top in your
driveway and you don't pull your weeds
you're going to get carpet weed growing
in Cornell in this kind of otherwise
moist climate but it's a very hot
micrite on that black top um so yeah
these guys grow these very extreme
sandings rocky surfaces gypsum
surfaces uh or they grow where there's
low competition due to extreme or recent
disturbance um so they're kind of
escapists the reason we think that is
because once C4 evolves as the gas
exchange diagram I showed you it's
Superior and it just excludes these guys
out they they're not strong competitors
whereas the C4s
are Dave um it was a great fascinating
the work that's been done in the
elucidation of the anatomical Evolution
you didn't mention much about pep carox
lasis versus Risco and I wonder if you
just said a word about pep carox where
that fits into the history whether there
were other avenues of evolution and pep
carox analogs and also kind of related
to that could there be some reason why p
carox is a challenging enzyme either to
evolve or simply for a plant to maintain
that reduces the prevalence of C4 well
um so pep carboxy is uh the problem it
has in the existing C3 metabolism is
that it doesn't lead toit CO2 fixation
so it it's a Gateway into the KB cycle
but the carbon it produces OAA CB cycle
intermediate
and then melee to run it through the KB
cycle you have to go off that CO2 fix
during CB cycle metabolism so you don't
get net
fixation it's it actually serves a sort
of a Gateway in and out of the cev cycle
and and in and out of fatty acid
metabolism and other things that need
the CB cycle so to re-engineer pep
carboxilate to fit into a net CO2
fixation Loop you may have to go and
screw up the CB cycle metabolism which
would be a pretty big deal and
challenging for plants Pepsi a itself is
quite ubiquitous in Plants it's used in
many physiological functions and it's
there in in all of the land plants um so
using it is not a problem you just need
to upregulate it but you have to couple
it with something that leads to net CO2
fixation and the only carboxy AE in your
carry outs that we know does that is is
ristic now maybe if we wanted to get
into synthetic biology and genetically
engineer completely new photosynthetic
thing we could pull a bacterial enzyme
out a bacterial carboxilate and then put
in some things and create a new fixation
scheme and that's been discussed but um
technologically we're not quite
there um do you follow the evolutionary
speciation based trajectory from C3 to
C4 in the increasing the importance of
metabolite transport between the bundle
sheet and misop cells you follow that do
you see increasing number complexity
of well that's something that's
something we actually want to go to all
all of these intermediate guys we got
most of these in collection now various
stages of
them go back these guys so we have most
of these in
collection but most of them only have a
few so you can't really get an
evolutionary progression because you
only got one or two inter immediate
stages okay most of them seem to pick on
the pure C2 metabolism so there's not a
lot of variation the different the
exception isaria here with
nine but then this one blus that I
mentioned that we just did the phogy on
it could have up to 30 intermediates and
based on a preliminary screen with the
Varian material looks like there's quite
a bit of variation in this
intermediate uh series of traits
that's where you can go in and look at
when along this so-called evolutionary
progression you get step changes or
gradual changes in the buildup of plasma
do mod or changes in misil
chloroplast which we've done for flaria
we look at where this change in
misop chloroplast number occurs and it
seems to occur progressively that's just
coming out now plant cell
theology so yeah we can do that kind of
thing but we need to have very specious
intermediate groups do you have any
question
sorry among all these biogenetic studies
you seen any evidence that C4 breaks
down and falls back
C uh yeah there's a few minor things um
elsis has pretty good evidence for
reversion uh there's probably a
reversion in um a in um the um suu group
in the um
um which is in uh oh I forget the name
of this family now but there's good
evidence for reversion there in a group
called suian the genus but and there's
possibilities in the kipot AC that
you've had loss divers application of
the reconstituted C3 and then
reacquisition of C4 from that but is
that a real loss and reacquisition or is
that multiple evolutionary events and we
need much finer plal genetic detail to
be able to address those hypotheses and
that's one of the priorities for coming
years is to go into these groups that
look to be fairly Dynamic and see
whether they're dynamic or whether you
just got multiple C4 spinning off of
some
predisposed C fre
ancestry
so I'm afraid we have to stop
discussion this has been a production of
Corell University on the web at
cornell.edu