this is a production of Cornell
University our topic today is actually
around what a practitioner needs to
understand with regard to field safety
and there's a number of aspects to it
that I want to just highlight to really
give this subject a solid treatment I'd
have to spend a lot more time uh on each
individual aspect but I want to give you
an overview of the kinds of things you
need to think of and just really go for
the loow hanging fruit if you if you
don't if you're having a hard time
getting your arms around what is field
safety by the time I'm done you should
at least have a good understanding of
the things you need to have on hand to
make sure you're going to be successful
should this ever come into question for
you now when you think about the
intricacies of field safety there's two
components to it right you can have
field hardness that you're likely to
fall on and get hurt or you can have
high traction which oftentimes leads to
what we call non- contct injuries and
you can get knee and ankle injury so
we're talking about hardness that
causing con concussions and fractures
and tractions that are knee and Ankle
injuries and of course what I've done
here is look around the particular issue
and say what are the thing what are the
aspects of that hardness that involv the
soil and the grass what are the aspects
of that traction that involve the soil
and the grass and then you know the non-
contct football injury risk is one of
the things that we constantly will come
back to so we're worried about risk from
a perspective of hardness and traction
and for the purposes of my time with you
today I'm strictly going to talk about
surface hardness but I want you to
understand that there is a very
sophisticated aspect of of safety with
regard to
traction now in New York state we have a
law now that has been passed to protect
uh athletes at the Scholastic level from
D further damages from concussion there
the law the concussion management and
awareness act has now put into place a
series of uh steps and methods and
procedures and
diagnoses education plans that then
govern how when an a concussion is
suspected how it's diagnosed what kinds
of treatments are provided how long you
have to be away from the sport this has
become a very very very important aspect
of Athletics at the Scholastic level and
what's been fascinating to me is in this
entire act that I've read at length
there's virtually nothing about field
safety there's nothing about field
hardness it's really all about sort of
determining was a concussion happening
and um you know what do you do with the
athlete nothing about was it caused by
some sort of malfeasance on the field so
I'm drawing your attention to this
particular act because I think it's not
going to be long that there's an aspect
of this act that's going to impact the
way we manage our field so just like the
child safe playing field Act that is
governing whether we can use pesticides
or not uh that we can't use pesticides
on school grounds this concussion
management act right now it does not
have strict legislation regarding field
management but it could
eventually now there's a number of
papers that have looked at field in
injury associated with the field it's
typically done by medical professionals
Sports Medicine doctors uh sort of
epidemiologists people who study sort of
spread of disease and injury and things
like that and a lot of times it's
related to surveillance systems uh NCAA
or High School athletics has an injury
surveillance system that they look for
where the injuries occurred now the
other aspect of this that's very
important is the field quality and often
times there's a disconnect between the
injuries that are reported and the
quality of the field now this particular
study published in the American Journal
sports in 2004 looked at 250 games over
a 5-year period in high school sports
they looked at natural Turf which they
didn't characterize the quality of that
natural Turf and field Turf which is a
um a particular brand of Synthetic
infill Turf where you have the fibers
and the rubber now I don't know that
anything is specific and there's some
sort of controversy between the field
Turf people and this study but for now
it's a good indication I use this
because it's a good indication of the
things that actually will and could
happen now you have total injuries
injury rate per team game you've got
substantial injury and severe injury so
substantial injury is you miss a couple
of games severe injury is you miss
months maybe even the whole season now
if you look at the differences between a
natural Turf system and a Synthetic Turf
system the first thing you'll notice is
that the Synthetic Turf system has a
higher percentage of total injuries
occurring on Synthetic Turf however when
you look a little more closely you see
that the severe injury ratings on
natural Turf is much higher than it is
on Synthetic Turf so while you get more
common injuries on field Turf and
they're primarily epidermal rashes rug
Burns and some muscle
strains the concussions as we indicated
a minute ago uh is what we are focusing
on here in New York and maybe field
hardness is much more common on natural
Turf now here's where the tricky part
comes it's entirely possible that these
fields were in terrible shape because
one of the things we know is if you've
got grass you're likely to have a more
cushioned surface so there could be
these fields that they're playing on May
have a significant amount of bare ground
exposed which could lead to these
concussions so so just so that you
wonder oh you know do I have to about
one surface or the other from a safety
perspective they each each surface has
their concerns the concussions on the
natural field and the epidermal
abrasions on the field Turf now why
would you well it's just a rug burn why
is that a problem well the rug burn is
in fact a serious wound where blood
vessels can be exposed and athletes that
then go into sweaty whirlpools or sweaty
weight rooms or or go back into the
locker room and start touching things
with an open wound the potential for MCA
methylin resistance stafilic cacus orus
this sort of lethal fatal disease that
can happen to people that can they can
contract in those situations is very
common where you get a lot of these rug
burs so basically the solution to that
is not to spray the field with
disinfectant because that's not the
issue the issue is to treat the wound
keep it clean hygiene is the primary way
you avoid any further problems from from
this so just an overview of because you
get a lot of question about natural
synthetic it's an overview of this
issue okay so let's look a little bit on
Synthetic Turf
safety if we're just honing on Synthetic
Turf because I'm going to spend most of
my time talking about natural Turf but I
want to make a point here on Synthetic
Turf there's two additional health
concerns on Synthetic Turf you need to
be aware of one is that there's been a
long time concern about the presence of
chemicals in these products
lead in the paint that they're making
lead in the plastic that the Synthetic
Turf is made out of and also
contaminants in the rubber that makes up
the infill but the fact is the body of
research done shows done with this and
and a lot of it was done by the New York
State Department of Environmental
Conservation has done a thorough review
of this and you can go to the dec
website and see that report which is you
know mostly very in-depth deep than
science that I barely have can
understand but the the conclusion was
that there's minimal health effects
related to the chemicals used in the
Synthetic Turf process but the other one
that's real is the heat on an 80 to 85
Degree bright sunny day temperatures on
the Synthetic Turf system reached
between 120 and 146 to put this in
perspective you can fry an egg at
152 so this kind of safety is a serious
problem imagine you're playing on a
summer day on a synthetic turf field and
someone gets injured and then has to lay
on that field with waiting for
assistance about 5 or 10 minutes on a
Surface that's 140° will create first
and second degree burns of the skin if
their skin exposed so you want to be
very careful generally what we say is
Synthetic Turf in Northern climates is
ideal for the shoulders of the season
the spring Sports and the late fall
sports are good to play on these systems
when the grass is no longer growing but
when the grass starts growing in the
summer months and you know the heat is
building on there you best stay off of
them because water uh will decrease the
temperature but temperature increased
back up to 90 to 120 within 30 minutes
so the heat is a serious concern with
Synthetic
Turf now when we're talking about
hardness and we're going to talk a lot
about hardness um of these systems you
have to understand the way we look at
this basically if you look at this as a
head when it's dropped okay if the
surface is is hard and not sort of
receiving of the D of the of the weight
the energy the downward energy is then
reverberated back into the head and this
is where the damage can occur however
when you have a softer surface right and
you drop your head or fall on the
surface the energy in that dropping is
dispersed into the turf rather than back
into the head that leads to the
concussion so this is an example of how
a ground could cause a
concussion now we have very particular
ways and standardized methods ASM
standards for how field hardness or
Surface hardness is assessed now this
was started many many years ago in the
80s there was some re research at
Michigan State that looked at how to
determine field hardness and they
borrowed some technology from the
pavement industry to see how firm the
pavement is they used to drop a
specified weight down from a known
height and measure hardness and then
they adapted Turf scientists adapted
that particular um method of measuring
surface hardness into Turf which has
then led to the f355 standard and the
F-1 1936 standard um that basically
tells you if you're going to measure
surface hardness this is the way you
have to do you have to have a consistent
way of doing it so that the measurements
all mean the same and then we ultimately
report it and you'll hear it often times
referred to as gmax testing now gmax
testing assesses the risk of
lifethreatening head injuries it does
not assess the risk of bone or joint
injuries which could occur but right now
we're focusing on head injuries and so
impact testing as a concept is a weight
is dropped onto the surface and the
shock of the impact is measured as
negative acceleration so you drop the
hammer down this tube this is a very
sophisticated gmax device 20 G for
something like this you drop it and
following the method and then the rate
at which it decelerates or stops is an
indication of how the energy is
transferred back into the head or the
hammer and then that is reported as
gravities and the gmax is maximum
deceleration the higher the value the
harder the surface now there's two ways
of doing this the kle hammer was the
original way that was designed by the
turf scientist to sort of look at field
hardness now what's not been well
established in this country and I'll
I'll show you some data from Australia
in a minute is can you correlate the
drop of this particular device to the
risk of head
injury now a different device the gmax
testing that follows the F-1
1936 uses a 20 pound weight which may be
more simulating what a head would do um
and the the shape of it is concave like
that um so the the the CLE is for the
natural Turf but not well correlated you
can't substitute this for the gmax and
there's some sense of there are people
that are trying to do it but you have to
be very careful so here's the two
devices that they use to measure this
now again this is only an accepted
method for Synthetic Turf and here's the
setup this is the $20,000 setup that you
get where you lift the hammer and then
the reason this is an accepted method is
it tells you did you drop the hammer
right is it moving at the right speed
there's a number of quality controls
that this system does that you can't
with the simpler kle Hammer that I'll
show you in a second 20 lb missile drop
from 2 feet you drop it three times and
the second two readings are average so
the very very specific way that field
hardness is tested now if you have a
Synthetic Turf how often should you test
it now first of all when you buy a
Synthetic Turf and it's new you want to
do it and establish a baseline because
if the contractor leaves the site and
leaves you with a field that is already
too high and unsafe you have no recourse
so make sure first of all you get it in
the spec that the field has to be built
so that when a gmax test is done at the
end it reads a number this or lower all
right so F certainly to establish a
Baseline and also to make sure you got
what you're paid for and then annually
thereafter on heavily used Fields so you
say heavily used Fields wait a minute I
got Synthetic Turf yeah Synthetic Turf
wears out the infill moves for those of
you that play lacrosse on the Synthetic
Turf you know that the gold mouth is
constantly having the rubber pushed away
and the fibers degraded and you'll often
and almost always get a much higher
reading by the go mouth than you will
away from the gold mouth because the
rubber compacts or wears away and
therefore the surface becomes harder so
annually on heavy use fields and then if
you have reports of a serious head
injury and the field is implicated go ra
you know immediately find someone in the
private sector and there's a number of
people particularly Dr hmel at Hummel
and company that can go and do this gmax
testing for you to create a body of
evidence that you may need in a legal
case now let's talk about natural Turf
no one would argue certainly being on
natural Turf uh on a summer day would be
preferable uh but certainly a
well-maintained grass field uh can be
safe or a well-maintained synthetic
field can be
safe if you're going to maintain a cool
season turf field and you're worried
about liability and risk management as a
school board member in a local community
here I I am concerned about that one
place to start is that there is an ASM
standard for maintaining cool season
Turf on athletic fields it's uh
f260 and this is a document you should
have you should understand should have a
basic knowledge of you know what's in
here and am I following and doing my due
diligence so this is number one
something you should have and also in a
more plain English approach to what's
involved in a safe field that you might
give to coaches and players and
community members administrators is
something that the sports turf managers
have developed a foundation for safer
athletic fields has a whole four or five
page very in plain English natural grass
athletic fields for safety and I have
the website there but you can go to
stma.org and access this
document now when you get involved in
the legal end of this process you have
to sort of learn some jargon and one of
the most important parts words in jargon
and field safety to see how involved you
may be is the duty of care a duty of
care is a legal obligation on an
individual organization required that
they adhere to a standard of reasonable
care reasonable
care this would be considered reason
able care so get this learn this it's
very generic it ought to be something
you can easily commit to doing
reasonable care we performing any acts
that could be could foreseeably harm
others right are you leaving rocks
Exposed on the fields it is the first
element that must be established to
proceed with action and negligence so
let's imagine an athlete is using your
field and falls and hits their head and
there's no grass there and someone
realizes that person's concussed and
they are going to seek remediation for
the damage that might have been done to
that child or adult on that field the
first thing they're going to do when you
get a lawyer involved is their
negligence and negligence could then be
established if you weren't taking
reasonable
care now let's look at potential risks
now this is from um a cfers and beard
publication from the late this is one of
the foremost turf grass scientists in
the United States dropped the kle hammer
on a number of different surfaces all
right where a cement floor was as much
as 1,400
G's uh the a football outdoor for your
artificial
175 you know you don't think about this
but in tennis if you fall and hit your
head that can't be good basketball court
that's not going to be good baseball
natural Turf Bermuda grass field so you
can can see very hard to
softer what's not well understood and
not well established in this country is
what how does this correlate to head
injury they've got it for the gmax
testing they don't have it for the CLE
Hammer
yet now as we're talking about legal
things that's the kind of data that a
good lawyer is going to start pulling
out and so as a school district as a
member of a school board I am constantly
mindful of
the management of risk in a school
district whether it's how a teacher
manages their classroom it's how what
kind of cleaning products we use to
clean the bathrooms to all the way to
how the fields are kept so from a risk
management perspective knowing that
field use with that wears out the
centers of these fields often you can
see the wearing out
here knowing that that's one of the
primary ways the turf gets less safe is
do we have enough space for the amount
of use that we have is the space
appropriate for the type of use for
example you know here's a lacrosse field
are they going to be all right playing
lacrosse on a little bit of dirt skin
here is it appropriate for that use and
is the space managed properly do you
have enough room is it appropriate to
play that sport
there and are you managing it properly
so those are the things I'm thinking
about out when I'm thinking about moving
further with regard to this now one way
to get your arms around this is for
communities led by the groundskeeper
with a board of education or Community
Sports people to go out and assess the
field now we developed a tool many many
years ago that's very simple for the
average person to fill out if the
grounds manager is there that grounds
manager can answer a question about
whether it's the field is watered how
much fertilizer they put on
what the mowing height
is and that's it everything else can be
answered by a lay person that might use
the field and then you get a number by
answering these things so here is a
Hector soccer field where we rated these
numbers and it came out with a 31 and
we're saying if you get between 21 and
35 you should reassess your management
program unless the quality you expect is
less than three but you've got to wonder
from a safety perspective whether that
field is at risk so if you're over 35
you've got to think about renovating
those fields if you're under 21 you're
doing pretty good so this this uh Travis
High School football is obviously doing
pretty good so an easy way to get
everybody on the same page and have a
conversation about the fields as you're
thinking about risk
management
now no one's going to argue
that a grass field is really good when
there's grass but in fact there's data
to support
this it starts out first of all by
understanding your soil this is the
amount of fine particles so when you go
from here you're probably talking about
a high sand content all the way up to a
really clay soil along the bottom here
and this is the hardness of that
field all right so when you dry that
soil down right you can see without any
grass
cover without any grass cover as you add
more clay particles if you have a clay
soil field without any grass cover you
can see how hard it gets as it dries out
the more clay you
add and then
however when you have 100% grass cover
you can see that the grass
mitigates the hardness so what's the
message here well I'm trying to give you
really simple things the simplest thing
is if you have a natural grass field
make sure you've got vegetation I'm
going to say vegetation because we think
generally broadleaf weeds are not as
traffic tolerant we're still getting
some more data we've had some new data
from Tennessee that's indicating they
don't hold up as well they wear out much
more quickly and that's a problem
because you want to have a great grast
or vegetated Surface to mitigate the
hardness here especially for those of
you without irrigation as The Field's
going to dry out more now I spent a
little time in Australia this past year
and traveled around looking at sports
fields and number of conversations with
the grounds industry over there and they
actually have guidelines that they've
developed from a number of studies
conducted in Australia on Australian
Rules football fields because they play
Australian Rules Football
which is this sort of gayc football
rugby soccer thing it's they play on a
huge field there's 17 guys on a side
they're very no equipment it's shorts
and a t-shirt that's it and they've
actually developed a system using the
CLE which we right now in the states
have not adopted but this is what they
have done in Australia where they're
grading it as too
low all the way to
unsafe okay so it's safe is between 31
and 69 the preferred range is between 70
and 89 now they're also measuring this
with related related to traction as much
as field hardness that you could hit
your head on so that's probably why the
preferable range is good here and this
is considered unsafe because the
traction is probably really bad it's too
soft so you can have a field that's too
soft and you see that with Muddy Fields
an ideal field and a field that's too
too hard all right again we have not
adopted this but these are good values
to just sort of start with now if we can
agree that grass is good just having
this so soil covered is good then we've
got to think about how to maintain that
cover because overuse will result in
Failure so what we want to do if that
fail point is usually you know over here
we want to move that fail Point further
over so that the turf can sustain itself
longer and one of the things we've done
with this is some of our work with
intense overseeding where we're
overseeding on a weekly basis during the
traffic period light frequent amounts of
seed thrown on a regular basis to
maintain Turf
cover where normally the traffic would
wear out the turf to this so you're
talking about is this safer than this I
can't say specifically but in general we
know the more grass you have the safer
that Field's going to be so here's the
study we did we took this field we moted
at 3 in we traffic the equivalent of
five games between the 20 and between
the hash mark so lots of traffic there
was no water we watered we we fertiliz
twice a year we used a drop spreader
because the soil is
exposed from the traffic so you to get
good so seed contact under high traffic
you don't have to Slit seed in fact
several Studies have shown slit seeding
makes it worse because slit seed starts
to dig things up and then you've got Ry
grass Blu grass and tall fescue now
here's the only two pieces of data that
I'm going to show you we did this over a
threeyear
period and the rainfall amount in the
first year was 20% below normal so here
is the treatment 2 48 and or 10 pounds
of seed per
thousand this is Turf density 20% Turf
density which means the grass is not
very much 85% means you have a lot more
grass and then in a dry year weed
density you didn't see a big difference
in the amount of weeds that invaded
because there was no water for the weeds
to grow we looked at Turf quality which
I'm not going to worry about and we look
at gmax which I'm not necessarily going
to talk about but essentially you notice
as you go from 20% Turf
cover at 130 gmax down to 85 % Turf
cover at 55 that the turf gets softer
now this was true for both perennial Ry
grass and for tall fescue this did not
work for Kentucky Bluegrass because it
takes much longer for the Kentucky
bluegrass seed to Germany so fast
germinating plants like penal Ry and
tall fescue will work fine now the
second two years of the study did the
exact same thing but we got regular
rainfall matter of fact above average
rainfall and what you see is what
because of the traffic without any
seeding there's no Turf left lots of
weeds no Turf just a little bit of seed
2 lbs per thousand per week gave us
85% gave us 85% Turf density and did a
really good job of controlling weeds
Turf quality was excellent and field
firmness or field hardness was much
lower so when you have you know if you
have the if there's going to be rainfall
you have to be able to irrigate as
little as 2 L pounds of seed can be
enough to turn a field from a disaster
into a safer field because I can tell
you if a kid gets hurt on a field that
looks like this they're going to come
after someone for reasonable
care so let's look at this if you're
looking at an American football field
you're looking at between the hash marks
and between the 20 yard lines that's
where 80% % of the traffic in an
American football field occurs between
the 20s and between the hash marks
that's your high traffic
area let's go through the economics
people say oh my God throw seed every
week how you going to do that well let's
go to the two pound rate per thousand so
let's say we're putting out 2 pounds per
thousand assume a125 per pound some
people can get it cheaper so that's a
weekly cost of $2.50 a th000 that area
between the 20s between the hash is
16,000 Square ft so assuming these seed
rates cost of seed weekly cost per
thousand multiplied by the area that
you're going to treat it's $40 a week
for
seed let's say you did it 13 weeks in
the fall and 13 weeks in the spring
soccer or football in the fall lacrosse
in the spring that's 26 weeks it'd be
$1,000 in seed costs so it's not a
burden for most even small school
districts like mine could afford $1,000
receed now here's an example of a trial
we did in the Albany area Dave chinery
our extension faculty in the Capitol
district has done a lot of work with
this repetitive over seating and this is
one of his trials where they had played
football played football on it did the
over seating and then left it for the
next year they didn't do it again and
you can see in these plots
where they overseeded and where they
didn't where they didn't this is loaded
with crab grass and where they did
there's very little weeds growing in
there at all so obviously there can be
some weed control associated with that
now another way to get a safe field
especially if you're you know really in
a pinch and have to get that field in
shape really quickly which what the
professional athletes do and there's a
shot at a professional stadium with the
installation of what we call thick cut
sod where normally sod would be cut
between between a half and 3/4 of an
inch here you're talking about an inch
and a half to 2 in of soil underneath so
it's a very very heavy s so that when
you lay it you can play right on it
immediately because it won't move well
people say oh how how can we do that
well thick cut s is roughly 60 cents a
square foot your go mouth area that's
bare here is roughly 10 by 10 all right
60 cents a sareet foot by 100t gold
mouth area
$60 and you could do it a number of
times that it's always going to be safe
for those athletes there so many people
have started to consider this because we
know that having grass is the key the
first step to making that fi safer I'll
turn your attention back to this
standard that this is the minimum that
you should be doing you got to get your
hands on this and understand what's
involved in it and then simply Focus
focus on keeping the use to a level you
can manage and then try Innovative
things like the regular over seating to
keep that grass in place because that
natural Turf surface that has the grass
on it is always going to be a safer
surface in general than bare soil and
then the synthetic and natural Turf
debate is going to continue with no real
clear answers until we get our arms
around exactly um how we can use the kle
values in natural Turf so I hope I gave
you a little little bit of an overview
of this particular topic I know you're
going to have a a lot more time to
discuss this over the course of the day
and thanks for the
time this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu