this is a production of Cornell
University I'm going to uh how to I'm
going to take you on on two Whirlwind
tours of the garden one that
shows the weaknesses of the
garden and one that I hope shows our
strengths I'll then try to slow
down and talk a little bit about the
context uh of this Garden both in the
past and today
and the last part uh I hope that Don REO
will appreciate it the last part is of
my presentation will be about our
attempts to to Res to respect the past
and prepare the future that is to say
how how do we cultivate this space how
do we cultivate a historical garden and
why do we do it that
way what is it the same as in the past
or not in some sense it's public garden
management so here's for a whirlwind
tour of the garden first first with its
weaknesses then with it with its
strengths first weakness is when you
work in the garden that's what you
see if you walk up the ramp that's what
you see if you walk down the steps on
the other side that's what you see if
you go look up that's what you see above
the peach trees if you keep walking you
go through a door and you see a wall
without trees that seems to be falling
well not let's say just unkempt if we go
to the back of the garden you start
seeing that the tops of the garden
Gardens the tops of the walls are not so
good either the bottoms of the walls
neither I'm not that's not good English
but I'll
survive the walls are
separating when we're against the trees
we haven't taken off the ferns or the
Mosses if you're at the bottom of the
wall sometimes you're not quite sure you
should walk through the
door if you look up you understand why
the bottom of the door is not working if
you walk to the very back
you notice I I shouldn't point this out
but I'm going to anyway we still have
asbestos in the
garden it's covered by Moss
though um but we have we'll have to get
rid of it one day this is what our
garages look
like we haven't replaced all the windows
the car model is from the
[Music]
1970s if you try to leave the garden you
start to see there were some reparations
but some of the edges are not all that
good and this is what's left of our last
Greenhouse from the 19th century the the
others were
destroyed sometimes walls actually fall
down this was a year ago this is the
same wall from the other
direction this is what it looks like
today we're getting
there uh it's actually a type of Youth
build program that we're going to
rebuild the wall this Summer concretely
that means I didn't spend any money to
do
it uh because the entire Garden which is
I have to remember this uh 24 Acres 9 .4
hectares is um we I manage it with
€40,000 uh not counting salaries but the
total investment of how to say
functioning money is $40,000 so let's
say $50,000 for 24
Acres so and I still have to mention a
another uh another big
problem oh I I forgot I want to mention
something else
uh this presentation is rather
General and for those of you who would
be interested in a history of plant
selection in fruits and vegetables you
have to stay for Soho afterwards just
wanted to mention that and I also wanted
to mention that I was an undergraduate
and that when I was an undergraduate
here I never imagined I'd be coming back
for a second time to give a talk here
just thought I'd have to mention
that the biggest problem is actually not
all what I just showed you the biggest
problem is this the biggest problem we
have in this Garden is
drainage it was built on an old swamp
and they put in a massive drainage Pro
um system in the 17th century it hasn't
been properly kept up and so we're faced
with some real questions of uh rudis
ciation and
um other difficulties of that
type so that's those are the problems
but you'll notice that I use this as a
punctuation it's how I change from one
suff to
another what of our strength so let's do
another Whirlwind tour of the garden but
this
time a little bit better and we're going
to start in an early winter morning and
we're going to go to a late fall
afternoon so if I go towards the
sun I find myself in the Alleyways we're
in a regular Garden created at the end
of the 17th century this whole system of
perspectives of straight lines but that
aren't all that controlling if I go
forward I go toward
spring for me it's the most anxious
ridden part of the year I think it is
for any fruit grower uh it's not the
moment where I'm working the most but
it's the moment where I sleep less least
if I go through the door and I take a
right I go toward
summer it's the king's gate in the in
the back King's gate is the last
original gate this gate is the last
original gate of the palace ofite we're
going to see more General later you'll
see this is still the Whirlwind tour um
if I go around the central Basin and I
look the other way I see the cathedral
next door which is younger than the
garden the cathedral dates from 1742 the
garden dates from 1678 or was begun to
be constructed in 1678 and when and
generally when I look at this
church the first thing I want to do and
the only thing I really want to do in it
is go to the
top that's what the garden looked like
when I arrived about 10 years ago you'll
see a lot of
dirt if you look at more or less the
same time of year a few years later it's
changed it's gotten there's a lot more
grass a lot less dirt visible a lot less
herbicide use we're going to talk about
that if we go towards
Autumn you can see some of our fruit
tree shapes some of our cabbage patches
that if you look at more closely this is
a a bardi it's a 19th middle 19th
century uh parat tree alth the the
variety of middle 19th century the
actual tree is about 140 years old a
five tiered flat isia tree we have 68
different fruit tree shapes in the
garden this is going towards the Autumn
the colors change and this is the
setting sun behind the creator of the
garden whose name was Batista
Cantini
punctuation those are my two Whirlwind
tours now let's try to get a bit more
specific and try to give a context try
to understand the old uses and the New
Uses of this
Garden so this is of this is the palace
and the kitchen Garden is right
here a close and you see the Grand Canal
and a closer look that was a early 18th
century map this is a middle 19th
century uh map just because it has a
nicer closeup and nicer colors you can
see the kitchen Garden better you can
see the extent of the palace you should
realize just this is the only thing
that's really new about well this is a
bit mean of me to say the only thing
that's really new about
basically is that when you go when you
walk this you've walked 600 M so you've
walked not quite half a mile but that's
a single facade the basic innovation of
VSA is its size uh after that there are
some technical innovations about how to
make flat glass how to drain but the
basic thing about valide is just its
size so it ends up with a kitchen Garden
which isn't an acre or two acres but 24
Acres what does it look like today
that's what it looks like today an
aerial view from a few years ago you can
see the size of the palace you can see
the the oranger which has approximately
2,500 potted large potted plants that go
in and out and you have the kitchen
Garden here huh with the school that's
in the garden along the buildings
because today it's a
school we'll get to that this is just
just to try to point out how the garden
changes this is a mid 18th century it's
upside down but you'll see why uh this
is a mid 18th century
map this is a mid 19th century
map the big difference is that aren't
all that obvious
okay here you have three Gardens it's
going to become one or
two here you have diagonal walls they
will disappear you have 11 Gardens here
we still call them the 11 Gardens but
there's only five because because some
of the walls got taken
out okay there are other differences but
basically the shape has stayed the same
the big difference you can see here is
the number of glass
houses in the mid in the mid 18th
century there was lots of glass uh glass
jars glass Bells I don't know you call
them in English CL you say CL I should
have know I should have known
that uh and lots of hot beds but there
weren't much there weren't many green
houses actually I think you see one on
the on the image the only Greenhouse
that existed at the time was right
here and in French the word for
Greenhouse is s s e r r e and everyone
thinks that that's a greenhouse
originally a is a place where you which
means that you
you reorganize no you store things and
this was the but it's not a
greenhouse it's where everything was
stocked so this this map why is it
important although it's upside down
because in 1874 which is when mid 19th
century I exaggerate second half uh is
in 1874 a a school was created in the
garden and since 1874 the kitchen Garden
is no longer under the administration of
the palace so it's been 140 years now
that this Garden is separate from the
palace always in a school when it was
first created it was the national school
of of French horiculture today it is the
uh uh national school for landscape
architecture this is the map we show
today that we give to our
visitors the idea is you come in over
here this is the entrance today although
the historic entrance is here you come
in here the departure is always here for
the visits but 2 three four and we take
you around the
Garden today it's no longer the
Landscape Horticulture school it's the
landscape architecture school
and the logo for the school National
School of superior means higher
education it doesn't you know it doesn't
mean that Superior to
others it simply means that it's it's
not Elementary or secondary school after
secondary scho com super universities
are superior okay so it's part of the
University system uh but the logo for
the school is a
um my my English is
terrible uh is a stylized version of the
of the Central Square of the kitchen
garden and that for me is very important
because it's a question of how do you go
from garden to
landscape uh and the
pedagogical how to say the the
educational progression of the students
in the landscape architecture school go
from a first year about Garden creating
Gardens to a second year about larger
Urban spaces or larger spaces and a
third year working on Coastal or uh
railroad tracks that that that that that
cross entire Landscapes so the the idea
is to go from small to large from
microcosm microcosm to
macrocosm the school is present in the
garden but you do have to understand or
realize
that there's some kind of fundamental
contradiction between a historical
garden and a landscape architecture
school
um they think of themselves as as
conceptor artists creators often at
least in France I'm not sure for
here uh they're not
gardeners and on the other hand there's
a historic Garden that tries
[Music]
to that communicates with them but in
which essentially they come and see
things occasionally here they discover
what soil
is and three days a year they actually
work in the garden this is a rare
picture
this is three days a year okay actually
it's three days a year the first year
two days a year the second year one day
a year the third
year so one of the main projects in
terms of restoring this garden and I do
like Landscape Architects don't get me
wrong I just want them to be more aware
that once they've created something you
have to manage
it uh there's a landscape architect in
France you might have heard of whose
name is j clo who had a phrase one day
that I really liked he said Landscape
Architects shouldn't be paid until 10
years after they've given their
project but I don't think landcape
artics would agree and I understand that
they wouldn't agree so what how do how
do how can we make these things work
together well if I try to zoom simply on
this picture I see this behind it and
the project to try to make this school
work together work with the garden
together is in that building in those
two buildings to take some of the spaces
that are in them and use them to create
a residency for international Landscape
Architects where they both will be
interested in what the in teaching with
the students of the school and also in
working with the garden the ideas that
they come and we find a space within the
garden to work with them try to to do
the two together so we're in the process
of actually raising money for this and
we've raised not that much but
some and we will start uh we're we're
looking for
essentially €3 million EUR and we've
already raised over half of it so we're
getting there it's not a we're well on
the way and we'll start construction
we'll start redoing because you don't
see it very well in this picture but
we'll start redoing some of the problems
on the Windows uh and at the end of the
summer and installing some of the spaces
we'll all be we we will already be
receiving some International artists uh
this fall
that's the aerial view and as usual my
punctuation because all this is very
important
but what's most important to
me is not just the
students it's the
gardeners because the space doesn't
exist without gardeners without a you
know a garden doesn't exist unless there
are gardeners you can have a forest you
can have spaces without gardeners but
you can't have a garden without
gardeners and and what they do when I
arrived in the garden 2004 both these
men were working Jac and fris and in
2007 2008 they retired both of
them and they had to be replaced well
the idea was to replace them before they
left so that there would be some
transmission and they were replaced
essentially by these two young
men who've grown a bit older since this
picture to do the same things that were
being done
before so we have 68 different fruit
tree shapes this is one that's
particular has each one has a name by
the way
and there actually there's we have a
list of over 250 that we would like to
make but got to keep all of them going
this is one that takes a good 25 years
to make it's called the
vas so that's an early 20th century
picture this is an early 21st century
picture this is a fruit variety from the
middle of the 17th century one of the
ones that was uh originally cultivated
by lantin so the creator of the garden
and that we still have in the Garden
today
this is a uh and that was that this is a
mid- 18th century print but this is a
17th century pair that we still have in
the Garden today and that I chose to
show with our
450 uh different historic well not just
historical 450 different fruit
varieties if I go to vegetables the
person who is now responsible generally
responsible what I call the the captain
is Christine Christine du I always feel
like I don't do my job properly if I
don't talk about the gardeners they're
the ones who are outside when it's cold
not me I'm here with you I hope to come
back here with this summer with her
we'll see if it works or
not uh somehow or rather I'm in the
position of a coach I try to give a
perspective I try to create a plan I try
to make sure that they can work but
she's the one who gets the work done
what do they do well with uh she's
particularly on vegetables but she also
takes care of the fruit uh this is the
the the vegetable team in their
different
areas of predilection whether it be
herbs greater production or tropical
plants for
David we use old cataloges not so much
to um recreate but to find to have ideas
about what worked then what works now so
in 1909 among the most popular tomato
fruits were this one here uh which one
the laa the
there it is five
what I'll get it and we still have it in
the garden
now we have generally we don't we every
year I was talking to Mr Christopher
Dunn this morning about how he functions
with the vegetable garden and we do much
the same thing actually we can't do
everything every year it's not possible
so we have about we try to have a
selection of between 300 and 400
vegetable varieties every year and the
idea is to have some that what we are
what we call collection we try them out
and some that we are producing and
you'll see why I talk about that in just
a moment because we sell everything we
produce I'm forgot where I was so we
have some in collection some in
production anywhere between 300 and 400
varieties every year every two years we
try to choose one that we get to know
better so we will do one year 80 tomato
varieties but generally we do between 25
and
30 we do the same thing for example for
for beans this is a late 18th century uh
drawing we have beans just want to
remind you that it was a tropical plant
at one point uh we did one year we had
had over 100 varieties of beans and
everybody thinks that these are in terms
of the people who come to visit the
garden yes they're also for the
gardeners because for them to know about
being they have to try them out and if
we want to be able to answer questions
from our from our visitors we have to
have the knowledge so if we only stick
on the 15 or 20 Bean varieties we're
used to we can't answer the questions
that people come to see us so every year
we try to take eggplant or Peppers or
scallions onions we try to do every year
try to try out as many as we can find
but generally in terms of what we
produce for
regular um production we're we're about
100 varieties but we go up to 300 or 400
depending on on the Year we're doing but
we're not just fruits and
vegetables there is a small group one or
two gardeners who work on General uptake
we have a small do you say
Rosary you say we have a small Rosary of
about 60 different varieties we have
about 800 different taxons of ornamental
plants on purpose or not on purpose
they're there the older person who was
there in 2004 the younger person who's
there
now we have a young team what do they
take care of well we have this 200 long
meter Terrace that has two sides of
boxwood that's what it looks like in
Winter that's what it looks like in
summer that's already a bit of work and
there's box in many other parts of the
garden as well that needs to be taken
care of is there a boxwood blight here
as
well I I want to tear them up
anyway they smell like piss in the
summer uh in the
spring and they're totally unproductive
and they're not existent in in this
Garden in the 17th century they were
introduced in the 19th and I want to
replace them by herbal uh aromatic
herbal borders the gardeners are in
revolt against me uh because it's more
work and basically that's the only thing
I can say about box is that the reason
box exists is it's less work than the
rest I hope the people who like box
don't disagree too much but I haven't
found another reason for box
yet we have a fretum which is in some
sense what's left over from the
Horticultural school when it was there
and these are two of my favorite plants
in the fruit ofum we have so 174
ornamental shrubs that are stuck in a
corner of the garden that's a zanto
simul which is a Sichuan pepper and a P
with my French
accenta so ponus whatever all the orange
trees are are grafted on but it makes
great yellow fruit that you can grate or
use to aromatize to ARA to flavor
uh jams and I'll talk about that in a
little while too but the real point of
all these gardeners is
this the real point of this kitchen
Garden has always been to be a kitchen
Garden because so far that's not what
I've shown
you we produce about 40 tons of fruit we
produce about 20 25 tons of vegetables
and it all gets sold in a small space at
the
entrance some people think that's a lot
I think it's very little for 24
Acres uh the gardeners think it's a lot
of work and I understand that
but I did a simple calculation just the
other day if I take 40 tons of fruit and
I transform about 15 into juice and
jam that only leaves me with 25 tons if
I have a 10% loss 20% loss storage
everything else I'm down to 20 tons and
if I try to do that over 52 weeks I come
out with only 1 kilos a
week that's not that
much so 40 tons is not right
oh I'm I'm I'm I talked about jams um I
have a present for
Don and I have a present for Soho but
they'll have to choose how they want to
work this is our mug and this is two of
our Gams two pair varieties so you'll
have to choose afterwards but that's
what we do that's what we do that is you
know that is how we make our money
that's how we equilibrate our budget our
budget it's it's a public garden owned
by the state but we have to make a
living and I think that's very important
uh in terms of public garden management
the idea that a garden can be productive
can be visited and can
produce produce we do everything jams we
make the jams ourselves we also dry our
own Peppers our own uh we make our own
provance mix and we even have
Partnerships with uh a Tea Company this
is our mug we even have a partnership
with a Tea Company where where there we
have a particular apple variety which I
adore which is called and it's called
Canada Canada but nobody wants to buy
anymore in France because it's wonderful
cooked but people don't cook apples
anymore they always want to eat them
fresh and they want to eat them raw it's
very difficult to sell several tons of
this apple but it has a wonderful flavor
and a great Aroma we found a solution we
sell it to a Tea Company they extract
the aroma they use it to flavor their
teas it's our biggest
seller I'm trying to remember what I
haven't told you
yet and in terms of the time
okay and once I talk about
food the what I think is probably the
most important
thing people come to this Garden because
it's a historic Garden they come there
because it's ver they come because Louis
the 14 and there's this image there's
this there's this
trademark here you have David the one
who likes tropical fruits and who's also
one of our best
ambassadors they come for that reason
but we want them to leave with a better
understanding of today's contemporary
Stakes
for fruit and vegetable production and
consumption how does it function I mean
I I I've taken groups of I used to think
this wasn't true but I've taken groups
of not so young children into the garden
and shown them the potato plant and had
them say to me where's the
potato and I've shown them uh pea plants
and and I've even taken adults into the
garden and showed them a spinach plot
and the person said I wear the spinach
and I realized that the person could
recognize it when it was on a on a shelf
because it was separated it was only
spinach but when it was mixed in with
galinsoga or with something else and it
was close to the ground they couldn't
recognize it so basically when they come
in the garden they come to see historic
Garden we want them to leave with a
better understanding of fruits and
vegetables so that's what I'm going to
try to do now this is David talking to a
group this is what we try to show to our
groups this is an exhibition I did in 20
we did in 2007 about fruit varieties it
was an ex we took uh three editions of a
book a s a book from 1768 was
republished in the early 19th century
and we tried to put the varieties that
were in the book out and we tried to
show that the three versions of the same
book didn't describe them the same way
and that somehow or other people should
give up on trying to give a specific
name to a
variety we did an exhibition about beans
where I discovered something rather
important for me at
least industrial how to say those beans
string green beings that were breed to
flour at the same time be harvested at
the same time to stand up
to uh transformation into whatever are
often not good when you eat them after
transformation but but when they're
actually out there and you eat them
fresh you can pick them yourself they're
actually excellent so the problem really
is on the the processing side because
some of the the industrial varieties
that everybody is screaming about that
they're not good when they're in the
processed food can be excellent when
they're in the field and that was I
thought that in terms of trying to
understand how our agriculture functions
that's an important point to say that
modern varieties are not necessarily bad
they can have some real interest
including taste the question is how
they're used afterwards so maybe we have
to not just yell at the farmers we have
to try to educate people to cook
better we did an exhibition this was
purely for the landscape architecture
students this was my this was this is
what I call thumbing my
nose we did an exhibition about
pollination because I was tired of
getting comments about Landscape
Architects who didn't know about plants
being
allergenic and I did a presentation in
front of the Board of Trustees of the
school and I mentioned a landscape
architect who had populated a who had
planted a school yard with lots of beach
lots of birch trees and birch trees are
among the most allergenic what I didn't
know when I did this presentation was
that the president of the Board of
Trustees was that landscape
architect but it still went over fine
because the students did learn that
plants were
allergenic how to bring people to the
garden we have we've been having this
will be be our eighth or ninth year we
have a it's a school it's a school of
landscape architecture we have a a
festival a modern art festival in a in a
historical Garden every year it's
essentially dance it's essentially
conceptual
dance uh in a movement in France called
non
dance and I think that's wonderful I
think it's a great example of bringing
people to a historical space to remind
them this historical space is always
about being being new it's not about
being old and when it was created it was
created to be new so let's keep using it
as a space that's
new every year we have a annual Harvest
Festival you can't do without it it's
the moment of the Year where we have the
most amount of things to sell and so we
need a lot of people to buy them and
it's also the moment where we can show
the most diverse things of what we do so
every year first weekend of October we
try to present the 70 or 80 varieties of
fruit that are still available that we
can sell at that point and as many
varieties of
vegetables this is an example and this
is where we get to how do we cultivate I
look at the hour
we most people will see Lou burn which
is one of my favorite pairs on the left
and Cal blon which is one of my favorite
apples on the right I often compare Cal
blon to Jonah gold as the example as the
difference between bordo and
California uhoh I I got myself into a
now I tell you why I I do I don't
usually say that one
but California wine this was where there
no there he is for me it's big juicy
fruit right away it's wonderful it's
it's it's it's how to sayon it's a it's
explo it's an explosion and if you're
used to
California and you drink a generally
you're disappointed it's like what you
know it's not as big it's
not Jonah gold you taste it it explodes
in your mouth it's a it's it's a
wonderful Apple you taste the Cal and
the first thing you say is oh it's an
apple and then 30 seconds later you say
wait there's still a taste there there's
a little bit of fennel there's there's a
little bit of mint but there's the apple
is strong and then 2 minutes later it's
still in your nose and you're saying
what what's it still doing
there that's the difference between a
California cab and a bordo
cab Cal but that's not I see I'll show
you what I see I hope that some of you
see it
too how many people see apples repairs
on the market with
scab that's what we do all the time and
I hope that people can get used to it
we're not
organic but we do spray and even if we
do spray with non with Organic they
still have to get dressed up that way
and uh we call it our chernobil suits
and how do you do that in a public
garden above and beyond I do not know
the the the regul the how to say the the
rules in the States but in our case uh
there's even on copper sulfate there's a
24-hour limit before going on to how do
you do that in a public garden that's
open seven days a
week and how do you do it when you're in
a public garden that produces fruits and
vegetables and next to the trees you
have strawberries and just stay on
copper sulfate if I remember right it's
21 days before Harvest what do you do
well you can say you sprayed the trees
and not the the strawberries so you can
still bring the strawberries to the
store ethically I'm not up for it
okay how do we do it well we find
Solutions one way or another our first
solution is we no longer treat the
Central Square where the fruit trees and
the vegetables are in the same place I
have not asked for an organic label
we've noted a 60% lowering in Harvest
uh but we're still making it and we're
going to probably do something that's
going to shock not you but shock the the
people I work for or the people who are
guarantees in terms of the state for the
preservation of historic monuments I'd
like to tear out the pear trees and put
in plum
trees slightly different shape two
arguments first of all it'll give us
time to know how to cultivate pear trees
without treating them because for the
moment we don't
know uh and plum trees only last 20 25
years in espell shape so it's just a
time
period and the second reason is because
palm trees we can treat them during the
winter when we don't have many
visitors and they are vigorous enough to
survive most attacks until we Harvest
them in
July we'll see but it has been 320
340 years now that it's been the Central
Square has been cultivated with pear
trees and some people take me to be a
bit
radical the other choice of course is to
find solutions to phyto that's what I
worked on when I was here at Cornell I
spent hours in the lab trying to go
through to try to find mutant
spores well we do treat them with copper
sulfate but we do it very specifically
in specific situations and not all the
time and sometimes we even do it when
visitors are there because it's a way
for them to go and to talk to them
because in the states if I remember
right only 2% of the population is
agricultural today in France it's not
that much more it's for
there is a a huge
educational Diffy
um challenge in terms of getting people
to know where what they eat comes
from it's also when and this is I tell
on purpose four here galinsoga is North
American Plant this is a curbit also an
North American Plant or American Plant
uh where where are the squash in there
have to get people used to seeing see
that too and even the gardener is happy
when he finds
one they react poorly to this they react
poorly to the one
before this is my favorite way of
dealing with weeds in a garden at least
in our garden I think it's perfectly
fine I think that if we did the entire
Garden in black plastic that's woven
though uh and biodegradable but I don't
think people would appreciate it either
but this is how we deal in a historic
Garden with uh producing tomatoes
peppers we do some green
manure And when they see this they don't
understand when they see this they
understand a bit better but I'm not that
much more satisfied because if we have
too much filia fil whatever in the fall
we we create problems for our honey bees
because they're going to be harvesting
later they're not going to be able to to
dry out the nectar as long and we're
going to have honey that freezes so we
have to be careful about our green
manure as
well people complain when they come to
the garden and they see this I
complained to the Garden when I arrived
and I saw
this because that's how it was dealt
with before we're now at zero herbicide
use but we do have more
grass and I think the next three
pictures are probably what I would like
to show you most and probably the whole
presentation was just for these
three wonderful fruit tree shapes what
do we do with our soil this is herbicide
used since
1969 that's when Jack who I showed you
on the first picture arrived he spent a
year with a hoe in his hand and he got
sick of it and he started using
herbicides the garden was cultivated
with herbicides almost entirely up until
2005 in 2006 we said we have to
stop but we had to find
solutions that was the first
idea but it took a lot of work
geotextile the idea was to have
something clean underneath the plant
something where we could still still
continue to see the tree because we're
also dealing with
Aesthetics the solution we have today is
this
one uh because we found a machine for
mechanical cultivation under the trees
that we adapted from fruit from Vineyard
culture we still have to mow the lawn
but we have other ideas for that where
we let them some of them flower but the
basic question is what are we doing in a
historical Garden how does this function
are we a professional Fruit Growers
searching for solutions for professional
fruit growing are we a historical Garden
trying to be faithful to what the people
did 300 years ago and my answer is
both we have to find solutions to both
300 years ago they were already
producing in large quantities for the
king's table today we have to continue
producing in large
quantities 300 years ago they had
visitors today we have visitors we have
to keep those two together we both have
to take into account modern techniques
modern uh limits and we also have to
remember the intentions with which it
was
created and for me what here the
difference between
this oops sorry
this picture and this picture is a
difference in how we relate to our
environment in the first picture we're
producing fruits that's it we have fruit
tree shapes we're producing fruit in
this picture we're managing a space and
as soon as we start managing a space
that has ideas about production we're
also producing other things we're also
taking care and this is very easy to say
and I'm sure you've heard this lots of
times but we're taking part of an
ecosystem and we're taking part of both
cultivated and wild this is one this is
the largest wild uh French solitary bee
Zila cook this is we have a huge
population of this
uh Med uh that nobody really understands
why we have it we have it in the garden
and I've tried to study it a little bit
and it's an interesting conundrum we
have it because we used herbicides
because it likes sandy soil that doesn't
have plant on it they want to make its
Burrows to make its nests and so when we
no longer use herbicide we are in part
eliminating this wild beam we'll find
we'll have to find some
solutions beneficial insects of course C
up I couldn't resist sorry for the
Eternal ladybug and it's
strawberry I always thought the walls in
the garden were there for
had to say heat that's what everybody
when I arrived in this Garden everyone
told me the walls are there to
accumulate heat I think the walls are
there to accumulate beneficial insects
and vertebrae that eat the ones we don't
want because I think in terms of the
heat it works it works even better when
you prob put the tomato plants out in
the middle of the garden and you put the
tomato plants against the wall even a
North facing wall you still have
healthier tomato plants I think it has
to do with its
environment we even have a hawk that I
found that I got a picture of the other
day so I had to include
it I'm going to go very quickly this is
you have to the Garden is inserted in
the town on the one we have one side
this one side is the park the three
other sides are in the
city so if we use some kind of General
mem or uh a pyra or when we used to be
have to use rootes you're always blowing
excuse my language you're always blowing
all the insects away and we have no way
of recuperating them other than within
our own garden so when you're in this
kind of how to say Urban desert on one
side or diversity desert on the other
you have to find ways of creating
diversity within the garden itself this
is the fruit of Sedum this the where we
have all the different shrubs that's
part of it it looks a bit more unkempt
than you can imagine Vite to generally
be
well that's the garden I work in we've
included some uh within the fruit
growing areas we've included some uh
nonproductive Hedges and we can we
really see the difference between the
side and it's not proven scientifically
though I'd love someone to come study it
with us uh we the impression the
gardeners and I have is that the side
towards the shr towards the
nonproductive Hedge is less attacked
than the one that's
not and we've had that same experience
with our prairies that we've sometimes
replaced the grass with because we got
sick of
mowing um or rather the budget couldn't
deal with all the mowing in this case we
intervene three times in the year once
to prepare once to seed and once to mow
as opposed to mowing every 12 days and
we do that in several
places throughout the garden this is my
favorite current experiment this was a
picture from just 3 weeks ago um this is
our I trans formed a space that was just
below the offices of the director of the
school that used to be a a lawn okay uh
and just below the windows of the last
year students into a permaculture
experiment uh and it's quite I shouldn't
say I the GU after working with some of
the students of the school and the
gardens this is how we transformed
it uh so we're working and actually it's
based on a kqu
um I someone nodding their head I'm
trying to remember his name f there's a
a vegetable producer just outside of
Quebec who's written a book in both
French and English that takes up on
Elliot Coleman's uh book and we're using
some of those techniques there Elliot
Coleman and fan using books from the
middle of the 19th century from Parisian
gardeners we even have some not just
insects but some geese and some chickens
that help out I call them their they're
our gardeners as well we have some sheep
that we I hope you're not going to be
shocked by this that we regularly kill
and
barbecue
uh that's also part of educating in
terms of food
um it always gets me angry when people
only want they don't want to see the
carcass the angry is not the right word
disappoints me I think we really have
food education to be done I don't think
everyone should be Carn carnivorous my
companion is a vegetarian it's not a
it's just just think about knowing where
things come from before making
decisions this is my dream actually this
is I'm almost finished I've been pretty
good uh people often think we do
exhibitions for people to see outside I
do exhibitions for I want the gardeners
to see what we're doing or where we we
should be going I think we could
probably eliminate some of our tractors
we have small garden tractors with some
donkeys and I think we'll get there in
the next two or three years actually
because it's a it's a different
relationship to the space it's a
different way of working and it's a
great way to try to make more people
come to this Garden to see how we do
it don't forget it's about
food it's about
gardeners it's in a wonderful space and
it will always be a school thank
[Applause]
you this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu