this is a production of Cornell
University
thank you
it's always a pleasure to be among the
soil scientists and particularly Tony
who was very generous with his time in
teaching us about his work as a
scientists many years ago one of my
former students interviewed Tony and
that interview was edited into something
that we call an oral history profile and
it was included in that 2010 book that
Tony mentioned and I'll be quoting you
in a few minutes
so um
I am as some of you may be
fairly agitated right now and
angry and worried
not just about what happened in the
election but about deeper issues and
questions that have to do with
the state of our society how well how
divided we are and how well or how
poorly we understand each other how well
or how poorly we listen to each other um
it's not irrelevant for me to say that
at the beginning of this
session because the the theme or topic
or idea of civic science is very much
centered on
relationships between scientists and
non-scientists that include a lot of
listening and a lot of understanding and
a lot of dealing with difference
mmm
so this is a topic that I have been
working on for a number of years I am
I've got as most of us do way too many
balls in the air and so things proceed
more slowly than they should but I we
had an NSF workshop on this theme as
Tony mentioned in 2014 or working on
both an essay and a book project related
to this theme of civic science the theme
resonates across a lot of my work so
it's it's something that isn't just
contained there I feel rather strangely
double miked here so I don't feel like
I'm on an interrogation stage or
something and then I see this one person
sitting there Geneva like the judge
sitting sitting in front of the court
so civic science is a term like a lot of
terms we hear about
that first of all it has a it has a
history of us as a specific term
part of its genealogy is that it was
first actually maybe first probably not
first but maybe first used in
in a talk that Neil Lane gave when he
was the director of NSF
and he was speaking to a meeting of the
american association for the advancement
of science and talking about the role of
science and scientists in society and he
used the term civic science to talk
about
basically the the idea that scientists
should be communicating to the public
more frequently they should be taking
more time to be helping the public
understand science they should be taking
more time to share the results of
science to be bringing scientific
knowledge and ideas to the public at all
kinds of variety of ways not just panels
in Washington DC not just media
interviews but in community settings as
well
mmm that is not what i mean by civic
science the definition that he gave is
not it Oh Civic science is also not
citizen science the way I'm talking
about it it's not
applied research it's not activist
science it's not it's there's all kinds
of turns out there it's none of those
so I want to share a bit about how I
have been coming to find and discover
this idea of civic science my work
and how I've been trying to make sense
of it and some of the questions I have
about it I'm sorry to be relying on on
notes a lot here but I want to be
careful and as i mentioned i'm fairly
agitated right now and suffering from
lack of sleep my wife is a state
legislator she was just reacted to her
seventh term the new york state assembly
so I was up all night the other night
and
apologies for my own trouble
so civic science is not a dreamy
theoretical thing that some egghead
professor like me and development
sociology made up and is trying to
you know sell to two people it's not
that it's a discovery it's a way of
naming a discovery out of my own
research out of other people's research
I'm primarily a historian but I come to
the work of history with a lot of tools
from a variety of disciplines i'anson
technology studies development sociology
narrative in Korean analysis civic
studies political theory public
philosophy I draw from all of those in
my historical work
mmm
civic science is something that is
deeply rooted in
land grant colleges of agriculture
including this one very much so but it
is not contained to those colleges as a
historical trajectory
just one of the things that has happened
recently in the in the literature's that
I pay attention to historian from
Harvard named Andrew Jewett is published
a book recently that I wrote a review
for for a journal it's called science
democracy in the American University
from the Civil War to the Cold War what
he does in this book is he traces what
he refers to as a history of
scientific Democrats that's his turn
from the Civil War to the Cold War and
what he's tracing is something that is
not there's not a lot of awareness of a
whole variety of places and there's a
lot of critique of and push back again
what he's tracing is this history of
thinking and work about how democracy
sorry how science the methods and
processes of science have huge deep
cultural and political significance and
and
possibilities
and so there were a lot of people who
thinking these are mostly people in
fields like political theory and
philosophy and psychology and those
kinds of fields a lot of people were
were deeply convinced that if we could
spread
scientific the what they people like
John do is do we variously referred to
as the scientific spirit or the
scientific morale Liberty High Bailey
wrote about this which I'll come back to
if we could spread that if people could
could learn to see the world using some
of the methods and processes of Sciences
this would have huge transformational
implications for our culture and
ones that are aligned with what we
usually referred to as democracy and you
know most of you in this room i'm
assuming our scientists we can think
about this you do experiments you make
them visible in public what you did what
you found and it's up for debate other
people can try and see if they find the
same thing or something different
there's real deep democratic
possibilities in that kind of thing it
comes out of the whole notion of who
gets to create knowledge
well based on the work of science
anybody who can learn these methods and
processes can take part in that it
doesn't come just from the church or a
dog love or the government or the King
you know these are big historical
things I'm talking about here anyway
there's so there's this long tradition
of that
so
civic science is connected to that as
I'll talk about a little more clearly in
a minute at the at the center of civic
science as an idea
the way I'm understanding it is that it
represents a particular way of answering
a set of normative questions
about the roles responsibilities
purposes and war work of scientists and
scientific institutions like
universities
in the civic sphere or in civic or
public life it's about the Nate that
questions about the nature of the
relationship between scientists and
non-scientists
particularly in societies that that
strive to be or want to be democratic
so civic science represents a way of
answering these questions
so it's important to note normative
questions are not empirical questions
they're not about what is or what has
been or what could be
they use this troubling word in the
Academy we have a lot of problems with
this word the word is should
Civic science represents a way of
answering a set of questions by taking
up by taking the word should and
answering it not just inferior ideas but
in practice in the world
so the prevailing way of answering this
bundle of questions about the role in
relationship between science and non
scientists and science in the public
sphere the the prevailing way of
understanding that is that the it's
basically an expert client relationship
science scientists scientists scientific
institutions produce stuff
which is communicated out to the world
and
they produce stuff from a place of
detachment from
that world and why is this this is to
use the fancy academic words there's an
epistemological
reason for this because one of the most
fundamental questions we could take up
in a day in any society is how do we
produce knowledge that people can trust
trustworthy knowledge how do we do that
where do we do that who does that so
there's a whole way of kind of
prevailing sense of well you need a
detached thing that's outside the biased
and messy world of the marketplace and
government and this you can't trust
stuff that comes out of there because
it's going to be self-interested in bias
so you need someplace that's apart from
that
where people can
pursue work from a objective
disinterested unbiased these kinds of
words people use perspective so that's
the sort of a typical way that we look
at the the set of normative questions so
about what we should do what our
relationship should be our meaning
scientists so civic science as I've been
learning in my research and work and it
have been understanding coming to
understand doesn't dismiss it's not
about dismissing questions of
trustworthiness and of course in a land
grant institution we're not just
interested in trustworthiness we're
instance interested in knowledge people
can trust and use that
the use piece is pretty important
so the civic science tradition that I'm
uncovering and try to understand doesn't
dismiss all that it doesn't say that we
that we should never have
people working from a place of
detachment in laboratories on campuses
up on hills like Cornell here the
classic ivory tower it doesn't say we
shouldn't have that what I'm finding in
my own work and this is definitely
influenced by my own perspective which I
need to be transparent about the fancy
word for that is reflexive to be
reflexive is to be conscious of your own
biases and political views and and to be
candid about those and I definitely have
them and that'll come out in a minute
so the tradition that I'm uncovering
doesn't reject all of that what it does
and the best way to understand it is it
expands and broadens the ground and the
set of possibilities
for how to be a scientist
for you're not it means that science
scientists don't always have to be
detached in laboratories up on hills
that sometimes you can be there and you
can be out in the and
telling this people in this room of this
this is nothing new this is what people
have done in this college for over a
hundred years
but not everybody thinks about that or
understands that
what's important about Civic science I
think
which moves us to the place of deep deep
deep complexity way beyond what I'm
going to be able to do here with you
both because of time and and other
issues it's important about it is that
it doesn't just expand these
possibilities of how to do work
it also opens up very distinctive kinds
of promise promises possible of meaning
and significance of the work
and in doing that it opens up very
distinctive kinds of challenges and
problems so what I want to do today
hopefully in enough time for us to have
some interaction
because I could go on for way too long
in my agitated state I want to I want to
begin with a couple of historical
artifacts from our own college here at
Cornell
brief historical artifacts
then I want to very briefly and very
superficially start taking up the task
of interpreting those artifacts this is
the research of that I do as a scholar
so i'm working with original material
and data and as a historian I don't just
paste and copy that data I have to
position it in a narrative position it
in a in an essay that interprets the
meaning and significance of these
artifacts have to put them in context
and I have to use tools to be able to do
that so I want to I want to very briefly
sort of show you
sort of the inside it's like walking
into my lab in some ways it's like the
the inside nuts and bolts of how we work
with this of this material
thinking of these artifacts like you
would think of plant material or poor
soil samples
then I want to turn to the issue of
actual practice of civic science in
contemporary times this is what I'm
going to quote you
I'm going to quote somebody else more
than I'm going to quote you I'll save
you
and then I want to conclude by just
naming some of the challenges and
questions that arise for me and thinking
about this theme and before I plunge
into this I'll say that I am approaching
and doing this work in many ways out of
a sense of urgent necessity because I
think institutions like this are in
trouble
and I think our communities and our
society is in trouble and beyond the
trouble I think there are enormous
incredible possibilities that are
untapped positive possibilities that
Civic science I think has a big role to
play in opening up both in dealing with
troubles but also in opening up
possibilities
so here are the artifacts I'm just these
are two things I found in my historical
research the little little data points
through a moment in time so the first
one actually is from 1920 to the former
director of Cornell Cooperative
Extension a man named Maurice chase
burritt MC birotte we were up in a farm
in western New York
graduate of Cornell
it's called the County agent and the
Farm Bureau a real barn Buster barn
burner kind of title right whale want to
read this was 19 22 so it was very
pretty shortly after the farm bureau was
created we know the first one was in New
York and broome county and
shortly after 1914 less than 10 years
after when the National extension system
was created and this County agent thing
was it was a big deal
he this guy went on I don't know if
anybody knows who he was but he had all
kinds of roles in New York agriculture
and state and United States policy mmm
so at the end of this book
he he actually didn't write this here's
not to go to it he says at the very the
last two pages he said summarizing then
the ideal expressed this volume for the
Farm Bureau movement may be put in the
form of this brief Creed and then he
lays out what he calls a farm bureau
Creed
so here are four sentences from that
we believe in self-help for ourselves
our community our country in our own
abilities well developed and properly
supported to solve our own problems and
in local and voluntary leadership
and here the next three sentences
we believe in a program a definite
carefully considered plan of work local
and conception and in character which
looks toward the solution of the
problems which are vital to the welfare
of the farm and the home this plan of
action for the organization should be
made at home by those most concerned but
with the best expert advice and
assistance and then the last sentence we
believe in a partnership between farmers
and the public agricultural agencies
between practice and science for the
working out of this program
so these are sentences about self-help
that there's a fierce voice of
independence of you damn well better
respect us
because we're going to solve our own
problems but we want to be in some kind
of relationship best assistant
assistance best expert advice and
assistance
they're talking about a partnership
so here's the next
little artifact
in 1949
the history of Cornell Cooperative
Extension was published it was called
written by Ruby green Smith who spent
three decades as the home bureau leader
in the state of New York
and she gave it the very wonderful title
the people's colleges and this is just
one little this is like a 600-page book
which Cornell University Press has just
republished in the past few years I
wrote the preface for the new edition
it's easily available
very interesting history
so here's a passage here's a little
passage from that as another artifact
I'm just pulling this out of one of
these it's on page 544 on Facebook all
right here it is
extension workers need to have faith in
spiritual values and
to recognize the human relationships
that contribute to what the ancient
Greeks called the good life
they should believe that in the kinds of
homes farms and industries which are the
goals of extension service man cannot
live by bread alone
that it is not enough for people to have
food shelter and clothing that they
aspire also to find appreciation respect
for individuality and human dignity
affection ideals and opportunities these
are the satisfactions that belong to
democratic living
so as a
historian I I have I came into my work
being fascinated with these land grant
colleges because I was deeply interested
in the question of what is the
relationship between higher education
these colleges and universities and the
public and communities and what's which
quickly goes to the place of what are we
supposed to be doing what are we what
are these institutions do what's our
work and as I've been doing this
research now for 20 years
I've been finding this really these
really interesting voices that you hear
in these two passages from Cornell
they're not speaking about the kind of
thing we would expect to be hearing
about certainly not spiritual
issues about the extension agent or the
Extension Service what is going on in
these passages
so moving now to the next thing I said I
was going to talk about how do we
interpret the meaning and significance
of those two artifacts that I just
showed you as discoveries from my work
and
you know I have hundreds and hundreds of
other other discoveries like this the
sort of pattern of a way of thinking of
things being said
so as I mentioned this pushes us in in
really complex territory because in
order to interpret these kinds of
passages not only do we have to put them
in their context of their time and place
not only do we have to put them in some
kind of historical trajectory we have we
need tools just like you need tools to
in those of you or soil scientists to do
your analysis and work and so we use
tools in in the field that I work in
that basically as a historical
sociologist and that sort of place in
the development sociology field we as
conceptual and theoretical tools and
frameworks to
make sense of these things in addition
to the historical tools
and
the other part of the complexity of
course here is that we're not just
dealing with
determining what happened it's back to
the empirical versus normative we're not
just determining what this person said
this thing in this year
we have to work with trying to
understand what were they trying to
argue
what what is the cultural significance
the larger social political significance
of what they were saying we have to we
have to engage in those kinds of things
this gets us in all kinds of trouble as
you might imagine because we then engage
in all the debates about difference that
that people have about the answer to
normative questions of what we should do
what we should not do
so
as I said I sparing you all the complex
details of the fine grain nuanced and
jargon Laden material that i would have
to open up to to talk about these
conceptual and theoretical frames I want
to just do something quickly to sort of
it as part of the work of making sense
of those artifacts part of it includes
going back in history because we have to
situate it in a historical trajectory so
I want to go back and then I want to go
to the present before I conclude with
with sort of questions and concerns out
of this so let me go back first
because both of those artifacts in
making sense of them get us to the place
where we're asking questions about
scientists in scientific institutions in
the case of those things we're talking
about Cornell's College of Agriculture
and in those days college of home
economics as well
we need to be thinking we need to be
thinking about a historical trajectory
of those institutions
so
so as I've done my historical work one
of the things I've seen moving back to
the mid 19th century is the presence of
two
that I think the work of civic science
and the idea of civic science has
brought together and continues to bring
together in its contemporary practice
even though it's mostly unnamed mostly
unfazed
so the first one of course has to do
with things that I would assume many of
you are really familiar with
and centered on and to get to this I'm
going to quote Justin Smith moral
who as many of you know was the author
of the moral Act that was passed in 1862
so I have working on a paper about his
vision and the vision of Jonathan
Baldwin Turner who was a contemporary of
his who many people think is the real
father of the land grant act um
so here's a passage from
the speech that
[Music]
Turner gave to
let's see this is 37 Congress so this
was in June of 1862
so here's jet imagine the floor of
Congress 1862 Justin Smith morals on the
floor and one of the things he says is
this an
American farming the land is held until
it is robbed of its virtue skimmed of
its cream and then the owner selling his
wasted field to some skinflint neighbor
flies to fresh fields with the foul
purpose to repeat the same sporulation
and
thus annual exodus which prevails over
all the older states and even begins
upon the first settlements of the new
states before the remoter borders have
lost sight of the savage as his language
painfully indicates that we have reached
the maximum population or land will
support on the present state of our
agricultural economy we bring forth new
states by the litter and when we want
more like our Norman ancestors we commit
grand larceny and annexed them this
progress seems wonderful
but with it appears the bitter fact that
these new states in half a century a
brief time in the history of the state's
become depleted and stationary this
early maturity is followed by a sudden
berenice the phrase in these days with
soil exhaustion that was the term that
they were using right so out of this he
paints this grim picture of basically
how the land in the in the US has been
totally destroyed by this horrendously
bad farming and then he issues what I
think of as a prophecy of doom
he says should no effort be made to
arrest the deterioration and spoil ation
of the soil in America while all Europe
is wisely striving to teach her
agriculturalists the best means of
hoarding up capital and the lands on
that side of the Atlantic it is easy to
see that we are doomed to be dwarfed in
national importance and not many years
can pass away before our ships will be
laden with grain not on their outward
but homeward voyage
then with cheap bread he says then with
cheap bread no longer peculiar to
America our free institutions may be
thought too dear by those of whom even
empires are not worthy the men with
hearts hands and brains vainly looking
to our shores for life liberty and the
pursuit of happiness this is the grand
political rhetoric of course we expect
to hear
so what we begin to hear of course here
is a the argument for land grant
colleges why do we need them and what we
also here is what their work is
what their job is
what the consequences of their jobs with
the meaning and significance of their
work is and that is centered mostly
around economics
but it also has an ecological dimension
there's a historian from Yale named
Stephen stole he's written a really
beautiful book called the larding of the
wiener
gorgeously written history it's a bit
traces the evolution of the
sustainability ethic in the 19th century
beautiful book so there's a presence by
the time he's making the statement some
really strong ecological thinking about
and many of you know this I'm sure
better than me the history of soil
science the history of this kind of
thinking yeah
hundred years yeah yes it's not saying
exactly the same thing she was saying
but so so we start to see this in his
rhetoric but here's one other little
thing that he says I'll just give you a
little nugget of
so what I think what I think moral did
is he basically he painted a picture of
what was happening
which was really was almost all negative
was really pretty much all negative he
then made this prophecy of the doom that
would bethe which he used this really
apocalyptic phrases about skeletons and
starvation mass starvation everything
and then he said but he was the way we
can fix all that
and and his answer this is somewhat for
those of you this all this mythology
about people like moral and the land
grant act ppl makes frankly they just
make stuff up about it it sounds good
but when you go back and actually read
what because everybody thinks yes he was
for education no he was for science
everything everything he was talking
about was the answer is science not
not education he talked about education
that but frankly it was about science
but
he also said he liked everybody who's
complicated he said contradictory things
and he said a lot of
things about different stuff and here's
one little glimpse into that so part of
what he said is that government should
aim not only to elevate and build up a
nation that is great in its resources of
wealth and power but greatest of all in
the aggregate of its intelligence and
virtue he said that effort should be
made to satisfy and elevate the manhood
and that word was an italic of the mass
of the people
statesmen and legislators he wrote he
said should aid to elevate the class
upon whom they learn first lien for
support and upon whom they depend for
their audience
he also said that every nation should
not only be giving should be giving all
men must succeed not only in giving all
men quote an opportunity by their own
labor to obtain a substantial support
but also a higher and possibly more
difficult task which is to combine the
largest freedom with the largest rewards
of labor
free government and personal
independence
something that moral argued was key to
securing quote the immortality of our
Republic
so he's not just talking about
economics he's not just talking about
soil depletion and ecology he's talking
about something we would put have to put
under the category of culture
political culture political ideals
so part of making sense of these
anecdotes is going back and
understanding the ways in which the
people who build these institutions
worked at these institutions who were
political advocates for these
institutions understand what they were
supposed to be about what their work was
supposed to be and we find in moral
science as the centerpiece of
the positive thing that would have to
contribute to the world but we also find
all this stuff about in those days there
was a
gets into the weeds with political
theory but republicanism was the
political philosophy the public
philosophy that a lot of people worked
out of not democracy democracy was still
emerging as an idea that was seen
positively many of you may know that
Plato rejected democracy thought it was
a really terrible thing it was actually
asking the mob to rule which you know
was asking for mob rule so he rejected
that and the founders of this country
also rejected democracy they wanted
instead a representative Republic and so
they were grounded in this philosophy
that scholars refer to as republicanism
civic republicanism is one of the
strains of that moral was in that
category and so he he paid attention to
what he referred to as virtue
and I will say to you that this is one
of the reasons why the moral act
has the sentence in it that talks about
liberal and practical education
for the industrial classes that word
liberal signified that the education was
not to be narrowly technical or
practical but liberal and practical for
reasons it had to do with the
understanding that we need to be
educating and helping to create citizens
in these days and a republic not just
technicians and here is where my next
piece and the history comes in and I'm
going to be done with the history and
this comes from Liberty hi Bailey
because there's this it's situating
these artifacts
one historical trajectory is this whole
thing about the land-grant institution
and a lot sorry one of the whole thing
about soil exhaustion about all the
things that had to do with bad farming
and science was was was the key is the
key but the other historical brand
narrative that we need to situate those
artifacts in is a narrative about
oppression and
freedom and liberty and self-rule and
the word we use a lot today democracy
and nobody has spoken to this more
eloquently and concisely that i have
found in the period i'm looking at than
liberty high bailey and he did so in
many places but the most eloquently in
his book that was just republished last
year for its hundredth anniversary the
holy earth his 1915 book
there's a passage in that book
section in the book i think it's called
the democratic agriculture and the
democratic basis or something like that
I've erased out the header of that
here's what Bailey wrote in this passage
this again brings us some something into
view that is absolutely
essential for interpreting the median
significance of a farm bureau creed
artifact and the ruby green Smith
artifact here's a Bailey set for years
without number
four years that run into the centuries
when men have slaughtered men sorry when
men have slaughtered each other on many
fields thinking that they were on the
fields of Honor when many awful
despotisms have ground men into the dust
the despotisms thinking themselves
divine for all these years there have
been men on the land wishing to see the
light tried to make mankind here hoping
but never realizing
they have been the pawns on the great
battlefield
men taken out of the peasant trees to be
hurled against other men they did not
know and for no wards rewards except
further enslavement and
this next sentence goes right to Justin
moral in the land grant act they may
even have been developed to a high
degree of manual or technical skill that
they might better support governments to
make conquests
then he says they have been on the
bottom upholding the whole
superstructure structure and pressed
into the earth by the weight of it so
here's Bailey in 1915 giving us a
sweeping view of thousands of years of
human history and the farmer the person
on the bottom the peasant the oppression
of that person used by governments used
by kings maybe even trained technically
in
laboratories in universities and
colleges
but then he he says and he's telling a
story or Bailey is doing a grand
prophetic narrative piece of work here
then he says the 19th century brought a
parting of the ways in the United States
that
force hold the end of this terrible
story of the pression narrative
impression
during this time Bailey wrote farmers
and others at the bottom began to
receive recognition not only for their
economic value of their work but also in
according to Bailey most important way
for their humanity and dignity and their
agency in standing as citizens in his
view this multi-dimensional recognition
was what inspired the creation of the
united states department of agriculture
in nineteen eighteen sixty two
land grant colleges in 1862 agricole
experiment stations in 1887 and finally
the National Cooperative Extension
system in 1914
quoting Bailey quote a new agency has
been created in the agricultural
extension act which was signed by
President Wilson on the eighth of May in
1914 a
new instrumentality in the world has now
received the sanction of a whole people
and it almost staggers one when one even
partly comprehends the tremendous
consequences that in all likelihood will
come of it
then he conceptualizing extension work
in political rather than narrowly
technical terms he pointed that the
problem of relating quote in baileys
words all this public work to the
development of a democracy I
am not thinking so much of the
development of a form of government as
of a real democratic expression on the
part of the people agricultural is our
basic industry as we organize its
affairs so to a great degree shall we
secure the results in society in general
and then Bailey went on to talk about
higher education and he said hi Rick
average occations engagement with
farmers needed to take the form of a
democratic Association that is deeply
educated for him it was imperative that
quote education should result or
function politically this is the ex Dean
of a college of Agriculture this college
of agriculture perhaps has an ex Dean
he's saying he said these kinds of
things when he was still the Dean it was
education to result our function
politically with respect to the kind of
education that should be provided by
land grant colleges of agriculture
Bailey wrote
and this goes right back to Justin moral
this is Bailey interpreting the meaning
and significance of the land grant act
of liberal and practical education of
his role as a scientist of the role of
others of his colleagues and this
institution this is what he's doing is
how I interpret what he's doing when he
wrote this
it is not sufficient to Train
technically in the trades and crafts and
arts to the end of securing greater
economic efficiency
this may be accomplished in a despotism
and
result in no self action on the part of
the people
every democracy must reach far beyond
what is commonly known as economic
efficiency and do everything it can to
enable those in the backgrounds to
maintain their standing and their pride
and to partake in the making of
political affairs now if you can't hear
the Farm Bureau Creed's words resonating
in that quote if you can't hear what
Ruby green Smith said resonating in that
quote I'll go back and read them again
so we're discovering something here
that's really interesting that speaks to
these normative questions of the role
none of this is anti science none of it
none of this is against scientists doing
work in laboratories and Bailey was a
fierce defender of
bass what we would call basic research
fierce defender of that he pushed back
very hard against what he were thought
of as the totally irresponsible
demand by politicians and by the public
that everything scientists did at these
institutions that have immediate
practical usability he pushed back very
hard against that because he said every
creation of knowledge is a contribution
to our Commonwealth
and other reasons why he was against
that
so
I
got years of work I'm doing in
interpreting all this and tried to
develop this idea out of this history
and heritage of thinking at work going
back to the 19th century but it comes
into the present what I'm talking about
and that's what I want to so I'm going
to quote you for a second but the for
quoting you so I I in students and I
have done a lot of I
become fascinated with all of this not
just as some thing to read in the
archives people who are no longer living
but wondering wow that all of this is in
the DNA of these institutions I wonder
if that's still happening today I wonder
if do we have people saying some our
things who are scientists like Bailey
was or administrators what are people
how do people today talk about their
work what is the work that scientists at
institutions like Cornell are doing when
they're out beyond the campus so we've
been I've been spending years doing
these oral history interviews finding
engaged scientists and inviting them to
sell stories about their work and
experience about their lives how they
became an engaged scientist
so I published several books of
collections of these things with
analysis and interpretation
one of my favorites which is unpublished
because the Don world when we publish it
yet
is a weed scientist one of your friends
may be named Don Weiss from the
University of Minnesota is anybody know
down wife you know that way so I just
want to read a couple of passages from
his profile which I which begins to help
us move beyond just kind of the idea of
civic science and but what does it look
like in practice what are the elements
of practice and civic science what a
civic scientists do
what am i sup with that one of the heck
am I talking about basically you know or
would beyond some philosophical thing
that has grandiose pneus to it so here's
like two passages i want to read from
Don's profile and he invited him to tell
his life story how did you end up as a
weed scientist at the University of
Minnesota where did you grow up so he
grew up as a Mennonite on a farm in Ohio
raised by Mennonite parents but he got
all the way to the place in his story
where he was talking about his getting
the job at the University of Minnesota
so I read you just a passage from from
that when I arrived here at the
University of Minnesota which was in
when I arrived here at the University of
Minnesota the position i got had two
obligations it was an 8020 split twenty
percent teaching so that meant I would
be teaching two courses my primary
responsibility in teaching was to teach
the undergrad weed management course at
that time the student population was
about 80 to 120 students the other
obligation which I found very intriguing
was the 80 % research I had no extension
our outreach component officially result
the research component was to work on
perennial weed management and grass seed
production in northern Minnesota
although I did have the opportunity to
work on perennial weed management and
other cropping systems statewide my
primary responsibility was to work with
a group of farmers in Roseau and Lake of
the Woods counties and a series of other
border kept bordering counties on
perennial weed management in legume and
seed production
the University of Minnesota College of
Agriculture specifically the Department
of agronomy and plant genetics had
developed a relationship with the area
of the state that goes back a number of
years probably back to the late 40s and
early 50s there was a group of
scientists from the st. Paul campus who
were breeding grasses and leg and
legumes
it just so happened that at the time
some students from northern Minnesota
were attending the st. Paul campus and
had been taking some courses and and
learned about these breeding programs
and found that one of the faculty had
developed a series of varieties of
bluegrass
I'm Way out of my depth here talking
about what he's talking about so I'm
just reading you what he said one of
them was called Park Park Kentucky
bluegrass in the interaction that the
faculty members had with the students
from that area of the state they decided
that they would try some of these
grasses in northern Minnesota
first the climate was ideal for growth
and development of Kentucky bluegrass
plus the community and the students were
interested in bringing that crop to the
area of the state because of his risking
the riskiness in producing annual crops
so in the late 40s relationships of
developed and Kentucky bluegrass seed
production started in that area my
position was created as a result of
trying to expand grasp legumes seed
production in to other species other
than Kentucky bluegrass now he talks
about the problem with expanding that
the reason they wanted that person to
deal with that problem had do with
reducing the risks then he says a group
of farmers had organized called the
northern Minnesota bluegrass producers
they developed around this initial
opportunity created by the University to
produce Kentucky bluegrass they then
wanted to move forward to create new
opportunities they had organized to ask
the experiment station and through the
experiment stations of legislature to
create this new position
his faculty position so it was pretty
well set up ahead of time that the core
group that I would interact with and
northern Minnesota was this loose-knit
group of seed producers when I
interviewed at the University of
Minnesota I interviewed not only on this
campus I interviewed him on the campus
but also interviewed with those farmers
and those farmers had direct input into
my selection so I didn't develop this
network I was brought in as part of this
network that had developed years before
my arrival I was brought in as one who
could fit into that philosophy and be
willing to work in that community and
help them develop these new economic
opportunities so here's a little glimpse
of the historical reality it's a little
moment in time one person's career
as I've researched across institutions
around the country this is in again in
the DNA of these colleges this
relationship here's a scientist whose
whole position is grounded and defined
in relationship to pacific place
specific people
so what becomes important is what is
Don's work and donna is a good friend of
mine he was a director of mesa the
minnesota institute for sustainable
agricultural i was doing my PhD in
minnesota and he's a real smartass joker
and he has the habit of always saying
i'm just a weed scientist but he's not
just a weed scientist he's he's fiercely
engaged in the world and in his field
and the institution and you know he's
he's a philosopher he's a civic educator
he's all kinds of stuff so I want to
read one more passage brief passage that
begins to give us a glimpse into his
practice and it and I would I'm naming
this as Civic science you could name it
anything you want but I'm naming it a
civic science in with respect to this
whole set of discoveries that I'm making
and the tools i'm using to analyze it so
he's just giving us now a little glimpse
into what he does know each spring we
not just my project but Nancy elke was
reported one of his other colleagues fly
to northern Minnesota and spend two days
with the farmers and other members of
community I need to emphasize that the
network of people that supports the
grass seed industry or university
personnel extension with in northern
Minnesota as well as bankers processors
and community members so it's a very
broad set of players who are active in
helping set the agenda and providing
leadership for the research and
education program each spring we get to
each spring in March we get together we
go through a two-day discussion which is
made up of presentations discussion and
future planning so the research agenda
that I carry out is not just my research
agenda
it is a research agenda that has been
developed I would say even approved by
this network of people it becomes my
obligation to carry out that work in
partnership with them as well as to
report back to them help facilitate the
conversation around results and help
them provide the leadership for taking
next steps and the next series of
research questions which should then be
carried out to answer questions for that
community
of course there's a wide range of
interest in that setting we have
individuals who want to sell inputs so
they would like to see cropping systems
develop that use of certain specific
inputs why so they could make a profit
selling those inputs such as herbicide
fertilizers etc we have a set of
processors and marketers who are
interested in getting seed from the
farmer to process charging the farmer
for processing and then taking the seed
and marketing it we have the farmers who
want to control the processing and want
to have a greater piece of the pie of
marketing so you have a full array of
interest it basically comes down to
facilitating this group of people in a
way that they continue to remember why
they are doing this work this work is
being done to add stability to that
community to really develop sustainable
systems
so the conversations that we've had over
the years really come back when these
issues develop to remind them of what
we're trying to accomplish together
that's been part of my primary
responsibility I
remind them why they created these
positions dr. Ellen's position Nancy L
Keys position and my position in the
first place I have told them that and
had that open up the conversation it is
a group that allows that to happen I
remind them that many of them are are in
that community because of this
relationship that has developed between
that community community and the
University of Minnesota
all of that came out when i did when i
said to don because i knew him you're
just a technician oh
you your weed scientist technician all
you do is you go out to the community
with a clipboard and you say what are
your problems what do you what do you
need what do you want and then you go
back to your lab and you just cook up
the answers and then you give them
through that's all you do I
sometimes use this strategy and doing
interviews but only if I build some
level of trust because it's
disrespectful if you don't do that
but I knew I knew because I knew him
that that was not all he was doing that
he is not just a technician with a
clipboard and you hear it in what he and
his response he reminds them of why are
we here what are we doing he's conscious
of the differences in interests and
for God's sake this is the first time i
discovered that weed scientists were
civic educators
that they knew that
they it's ingrained in him and it comes
this goes all the way through the
history of these institution and by the
way none of this is perfect it's deeply
flawed Don Weiss is not some perfection
her heroic figure up on a pedestal all
of this is imperfect it's in completely
done it's messy and all that kind of
stuff
but what we see here is a practice of
civic science in which scientists and by
the way Donna's produce hundreds and
hundreds of published articles in the
top journals in his field and gotten
hundreds of millions of dollars of
funding so it's not a either you do this
stuff or you do the science not an
either/or it doesn't mean that Don does
everything you have partners who do
that's why you have the extension
facilitators in the local community
there's an ecology that's required to do
this Civic science work so now I want to
get into my closing here to just say
out of what I've I'm just in the middle
of this work so I'm sort of dumping out
all the stuff that I'm discovery and
trying to make sense of it in real time
here but certainly what emerges and this
are a set of challenges and questions
that I want a name very briefly the
first one of course that a lot of people
named when thinking about this this
tradition of work in land grant colleges
is money right
capacity I've been at Cornell since 1999
people like Heidi in the back and and
and others in this room can tell you who
have been here longer than me we have
lost faculty we have lost capacity in
this institution to work with people in
the state of New York they've lost it in
Minnesota they've lost it in a lot of
other states public disinvestment in
higher education has
eroded the the tradition of civic
science of science scientific work
engaged with like Don's work and Don
tells a story about when he started his
job all the money he got from the
experiment station and it was enough as
he put it to run a show
he could run a lab he could open a lab
up on what I gotten any talks about how
today you don't get that so you got to
go to
industry and that opens up a whole set
of challenges so money is an issue it's
a challenge public disinvestment loss of
capacity but this isn't just about
capacity and now I'm just going to give
you the tip of a very big complex and
deeply contest a deeply I
want to say controversial that its
controversial for a lot of people in
different ways so
divisive well I don't know it's not just
about capacity it's about
the way that scientists are trained the
political influences on science and
scientific institutions there's a woman
named Stephanie Lee who is a development
scholar she's an anthropologist and a
lot of work in Southeast Asia she wrote
a book called the will to improvement
will to improve sorry I think it's
called a world home brew
and she talked about two practices that
are central to the realm of development
work and by the way land aunt work his
development work
in the 19th century what they were doing
is they're trying to change the way
farming is being done and trying to
change the way people are eating change
the way people raising their kids
its development work right so there's
two practices she is identified in her
work both of which are anti civic
science and
they're parallel there come their
companion practices one of them she
refers to as rendering technical and
the other one she refers to as
rendering non-political
so to summarize a very complex story
what this means is you come into a
situation that is multi-dimensional
there's all kinds of stuff happening
like just think about the two northern
counties in northern Minnesota that we
got a glimpse of in Don's message
there's all kinds of political and
cultural and economic
things happening and
this process of rendering technical is
to strip all that out and say this is
not a problem of politics up here
there's just a problem of science of
science technical science
and
surprise when you do that it then the
technician is able to provide the answer
hey I got the answer for that if you
leave the politics and stuff in they
don't have the answer
so when you rent when you do this when
you render something technical when you
render it non-political you simplify it
and we all know this you simplify it too
much you have suddenly produced a real
problem and your intervention is going
to be a real problem this is this is I
said this is a divisive or controversial
whatever a lot of you know this is
basically he's pointing the finger at
institutions like our College and if you
loo do the history and stuff you can see
the ways in which the college if you
know this big expanse of thinking of
Bailey Ruby green Smith has flattened we
don't hear this kind of stuff anymore
and in all kinds of reasons why it's not
just about people being bad people this
is a complicated thing this is what we
do in my field is really trying to
understand that use robust tools to be
able to do that so that's another
problem
there's another reality that's really
important is that we don't have very
good public cultures in these colleges
or in our fields for that matter a
lot of our a lot of what we do is based
on a theory of change bets we're making
if we do these things that this will
happen if we assembly in firm ation
parents will raise their kids better or
eat better or whatever and
those theories of change need to be
subject to critical evaluation how well
is that working out
we don't have very good public cultures
in these institutions where we create
spaces to really engage around them or
to hold each other accountable for more
than just the technical piece and this
it takes time this pushes against
cultures in disciplines and fields
there's all kinds of reasons why this is
a challenge
there's also a problem with with overly
ideological politics and morally
righteous politics which tends to
polarize these kinds of things here I
come right back to the election where I
started you know instead of instead of
creating a space where we can hear
across lines a difference and speak to
it respectfully but also critically we
have a we have a sort of zero-sum these
people are totally right and good and
these people are totally bad and evil
that is death to civic science
because citic science is really grounded
here's where my own bias comes in a more
of democratic populist politics so I'm
going to stop here that's a little
glimpse and all as I went too long and
I'm sorry about that well
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell edu