This is a production of Cornell
University. All right. So, um, today I'm
going to be talking to you about two
different parts of development. So, I'm
going to talk about things happening in
the flower and things happening in root
hairs. So, that hasn't made it onto our
website yet, but we've been thinking
about root hairs a lot in the past
couple of years.
Um, so first I want to talk so what
you'll notice is when I have a flower up
here that means I'm talking about
reflection and when there's a root I'm
talking about below ground stuff. So my
first lab is communication in plant
reproduction. And um probably I don't
need to tell most of you here but what
happens is we have pollen lands on a
stigma. There's communication between
the pollen and the pill. If it's a
compatible interaction, a tip growing
pollen tube will grow and then it needs
to make its way to the ovules which
contain the female gitapytes. Um, and
during this process, there's a lot of
intercellular communication occurring as
this pollen tube encounters various
different cell types. I think it's six
or seven different types of cells. Um
the pollen its whole purpose in life is
to carry the two sperm cells to the
female gamitaphyte so that double
fertilization can occur to make the um
embryo and the
endosperm. Um and the female gamitaphyte
also has these specialized cells called
synergis. And synergis are my favorite
cells. So they're hloid cells. um
they're not gametes, but they're in
charge of telling the pollen tube what
to do when it reaches its target. Okay,
so we basically have two highly
polarized cells that need to talk to
each other during pollen tube reception.
And so we have tip growing
oops tip growing pollen tubes
um that grow by adding material new cell
wall material and new membrane only to
the tip. So they don't get wider but
they get longer. And then inside ovules
um we have these synergs
um that are also highly polarized
cells. It's the stick. Um and we can see
here the two synerggets. Here's the egg
and the central cell. And these
synerggets have a highly specialized
region called the bilopform apparatus.
So this filifform apparatus. So this is
a scanning blockbased SEM through an
ovule showing the two synergs. Here's
the egg central cells back here. And we
can see there's um dark material here.
This is a membrane rich
region. And if we segment this
um we can see that it it's um looks like
fingers that project up into the
cytoplasm of the synergy cell. And this
is where all the action takes place in
the communication between the
synergy pollen tube. Um, and we know
that communication is very important
from some studies that were done by
Higashyama and Hamura back in 2008 where
they took a ovule of terinia and placed
it on pollen tube growth media and then
they germinated. They had a pistol over
there and let pollen tubes come out. And
what the scientist is doing is moving
the ovule away. And what I hope you can
notice is the pollen tube is following
the ovule. And this suggests that the
ovule specifically these two synergs are
emitting molecules that then the pollen
tube has a receptor for and the pollen
tube can change its growth direction in
response to signals from the female
gitaphyte.
um Picosiana's lab um identified these
signals and they're actually small
cysteine rich peptides that they named
bur and then the pollen tube receptors
for these slurs
also. So that's first indication that
synergies are really important for
telling the pollen tube what to do.
Um second um in this study this was done
in Ulu Genlaus's lab by Queen Yo who was
another postoc when I was there and what
we have here are two synergas expressing
calcium reporters and then we have a
arriving pollen tube this is a minute
timer and I hope you can see and red
means high calcium blue is low as the
pollen tube starts to talk to the
synergs we get these calcium
oscillations happening in the two
synergs also So calcium levels increase
greatly in the tip of the pollen tube.
And in this case, after about 40
minutes, the pollen tube then starts to
grow again and it gets up near the top
and burst to release sperm
cells. The second synerg stays alive and
it acts as a backup. So it can attract a
second pollen tube by sending out lures
again to get another pollen tube to come
if the two sperm cells from the first
one can't use. So then the same process
can repeat itself. And recently a group
in China showed if both tries don't work
then the central cell can also send out
a signal and attract another pollen tube
to try yet again. So the plant really
wants pollination double fertilization
to occur.
So when I was a posttock in the gross
lab, we were taking a genetic approach
to try to understand um the molecular
recognition of fallen tube synergid
communication which we call
um fallen tube reception.
um and two and so mutants on the female
side that disrupt this process, they can
still attract a pollen tube, but the
pollen tube doesn't burst. So, it
doesn't get the signal it's okay to
release the sperm cells. Instead, it
keeps growing around and around. So, the
first mutant discovered was feronia, and
this encodes a receptor like kynise.
It's expressed in synerg, but it's also
expressed throughout the plant um in
most cells except for pollen.
Um but its gamophetic phenotype is that
if you have a hetererozygous feronium
mutant half of the ovules will remain
unfertilized because the polyry doesn't
get the signal to burst. Um when I was a
postto I was working on a second mutant
which we named Nordia. These are named
after Ruskin goddesses ofility. That's
not me naming them. Um but this one was
really interesting. So similar phenotype
pollen tube overgrowth. pollen tube
pollen tube doesn't get the signal to
burst. Um, in some ovules the palm tube
can burst. So it's not an all or none
like the feronia phenotype. Um, and so
we see lower levels of infertility than
in fonia.
Um it's also shown um in Ulie's lab in B
study that the those calcium
oscillations if you quantify them we can
see in wild type we can see in both the
receptive synergy and the non-receptive
synergids we have these calcium
oscillations
um and we also have it in the pollen
tube as well and then after the pollen
tube burst um we see the pawn tube's
dead now and then also the receptive
synergid the and or the receptor synergy
will die and then the other synerg stays
alive. In feronium mutants, those
oscillations don't occur at all and
either the receptive or non-receptive
synergid. But in Nordia mutants, they
occur, but they're at a lower amplitude.
So the idea was that the reason why
Nordia mutants aren't an all ornone
phenotype is that sometimes
stochastically you get enough calcium
oscillation that then the pollen tube
gets triggered to burst.
Okay.
So from all this and from work that
several labs have done there's a model
that we have feronia and and a a GPI
anchored protein called laureli that are
found at this film apparatus and they
act as a co-ceptor for Ralph peptides
from the arriving pollen tube and this
co-ceptor then triggers a signal
transduction cascade which leads to
calcium oscillations in the synergy
Um and then I'm going to talk a little
bit more about this Nordia NTA and what
happens to it during this
process. Okay. So how does Nordia
control the amplitude of synergic
calcium
oscillations? So Nordia is actually an
MLO protein. This stands for milder
resistance locus O. Um the arabidopsis
genome has 15 members of this family and
all of them are predicted to have seven
transmembrane domains.
um and a big extra extracellular loop.
Um there's two cyines that make a
dulfide predict a d sulfide bond here
and then this cyine and this cysteine
make another bulfide bond in the c
terminal tail. There's a calm modulin
binding
domain. Um malo proteins have been
popping up a lot lately. So they were
originally discovered in the context of
powdery mildew infection. So they were
discovered in barley and if you have a
barley malo mutant the plant becomes
completely resistant to powdery mildew
infection. Later it was found that clay
five malos and arabidopsis play the same
role. So a triple mutant becomes
completely resistant. Single mutants
have lesser degrees of resistance. Um
nordia is involved in pollen tube
reception. And then there's another four
mls 159 and 15. If you knock all of them
out, the pollen tubes burst early, so
they can't maintain their
integrity. Um, the MLO disease um
phenotypes are conserved across monocots
and died. So basically any plant that
gets infected by powdery mildew, if you
can find the right MLO and knock it out,
then the plant becomes resistant. So
this means that we don't know what those
MLOs's are actually doing for the plant,
but the powdery mildew takes advantage
of them. Um we also showed back when um
I was a posttock in collaboration with
Ralph Pensrugo's lab that feronia
mutants so the receptor mutants are also
resistant. So this gave us this idea
that there's conserved
pathways. Um and so we have powdery
mildew are a tip growing cell that must
communicate with and penetrate make
a interaction with a plant cell. Pollen
tubes are also tip growing cells. they
must communicate with the female
gamitaphyte to deliver the sperm cells.
And in both cases um it was shown that
malo proteins actually accumulate they
become polarly localized to the site of
tip growing cell
communication and nordia also does this.
So before pollen tube arrival um nordia
is localized in the golgi and then when
a pollen tube arrives there's signaling
that moves it to that
polaratus and we can see that here. So
these are
synergs before a pollen tube arrives we
see these punctate pattern um which with
complete overlap with GG and then when a
pollen tube arrives we can see this
starts to accumulate um at that filorm
apparatus. Okay so we wanted to take a
closer look at this accumulation. So
what we used was a semi-invivo pollen
tube guidance and reception essay that
had been developed by Lelayor Bovida and
Ravi Ponu and several other groups in
the plant reproduction field and the
idea is that you can germinate pollen on
media and it'll make a pollen tube but
those pollen tubes can't be attractive
to so what we need to do is to apply
pollen to a stigma give it a few hours
to grow through and then we cut the
stigma we can put it on media and
arrange of ovules around. So then we can
follow what happens to the pollen tubes
and what happens to our nordia protein
during pollen tube reception. So here's
a live movie of this and if you watch
this ovule right here we can see when
the pollen tube approaches we see a
shift in the
geop. So that was exciting. Um but we
didn't know if that was a cause or a
consequence. Um, and so Jing, my former
PhD student, did a lot of live imaging.
So we have a DS red labeled pollen tube
and then we have Nordia GFP. And I hope
you're can be convinced that we see a
shift in the signal. Um, we can look at
time here and we see that this actually
happens um starts to happen as soon as
the PL tube makes contact arrives at the
synergist.
Um at this point we wanted to test
whether this was required for pollen
tube reception and so we took advantage
of an earlier study we had done where we
expressed different MLOs's under synergy
specific promoters to see if they could
complement the media phenotype and we
came upon one of the MLOs's MLO1 that
actually constitutively goes to the one
expressed in synergype
[Music]
um but we thought we could take
advantage of this to try to do some
domain swaps to manipulate nordia
accumulation patterns. Um and I should
also mention in epidermal cells, so this
is in tobacco transient expression,
Nordia goes to Golgi and Emilo one goes
to So we did a bunch of domain swaps and
we found that the C terminal cytoplasmic
tail was sufficient to make Nordia and
Nordia chimeic protein accumulate mostly
at the film apparatus. And then we
tested whether this could complement the
Nordia mutant phenotype and it
complements um just fine. So I'm going
to show a lot of these graphs. We have
percent unfertilized ovules. Sometimes
it will be percent ovules with pollen
overgrowth. And we can see in Nordia in
this experiment it was about 40ome
percent. And our Nordia MLO1 was able to
complement. So that meant it wasn't
dangerous to have it there early. One
hypothesis was maybe it's poisonous and
it needs to stay out of that region
until it's necessary. that did not seem
to be the case. Okay. Um we also knew
that feronia itself is required for this
trafficking of Nordia to the filiper
apparatus. So in feronia mutants nordia
stays in the gg. It doesn't go.
So the obvious question was can we take
our constitutively filiperitis localized
nordia which we now call
FAordia can that complement the feronia
phenotype. So we did this experiment. So
that's faordia. This is regular nordia
and we put it in a feronia background
which has 80 to 90% infertility and we
can see we start to see seeds
developing. We can quantify that. So
bonia here this is a homozygous bonia
mutant with 80% infertility. We can
complement the phenotype um to about
half using
our so and we can also check pawn tube
overgrowth is the same thing. So yeah we
can actually bypass a very important
signal transduction pathway by just
moving a protein to the place in the
cell where it needs to do its action. Um
and also we showed that bronia is not
necessary for Nordia to perform its
function or the MLO to perform its
function. So at this point we still
didn't know what MLOS stood molecularly.
Um but we came up with what we called
our booster signal
hypothesis and that was that feronia was
absolutely required to give a signal
that would lead to pollen to bursting.
um but also it causes uh trafficking of
Nordia to this filiper apparatus which
then helps to boost the signal to make
sure that the ties burst. So if we take
out feronia and just have a a Nordia
mutant or and just have Nordia film
apparatus the FA Nordia um it's able to
to do it do the function. Um so that was
our booster signal. Um and somehow we
also think that veronia either by
increasing calcium leads to this
trafficking or it's directly somehow
intersecting and causing Nordia
trafficking. Okay. So the question was
what are signals X and Y from Veronia
and Nordia? Are they the same molecule?
And for this um we went back to we and
others went back to this this
observation that in Nordia mutants the
calcium oscillations occur at lower
intensity and Shang Lewan's group in
um tested the hypothesis that maybe are
actually calcium channels and so they
took all 15 arabidopsis malos expressed
them in cost seven animal cells and they
found some of them could conduct calcium
um but Nordia couldn't and Malo1
couldn't. Um then they took advantage um
so then they took a closer look at where
these proteins were going in the cost 7
cells and Nordia GFP actually looks in a
pattern very similar to Golgi. Um but if
they co-expressed with feronian laureli
the protein would go to the plasma
membrane or if they used our faordia
construct um the protein would would
start to also
appear. So that's that and then they
tested whether the plasma membrane
localization of nordia or faordia would
lead to calcium um in intake into the
cells and indeed it did. So the
conclusion was um malos or maybe calcium
channels they need to be a plasma in the
membrane to do their job. Okay. So now
we know um Nordia X downstream of
feronia it regulates calcium influx into
the synergists. Um another question
we're trying to answer in my lab is how
do those calcium oscillations in the
synergists lead to pollen tube rupture?
Stay tuned. That's a really hard
question to answer. Um, but we think it
might actually be related to not what's
going on in this cell and this cell, but
what's actually going on. So maybe we're
depleting calcium outside the cells and
that's allowing cell wall changes to
occur that are then going to let that
pollen burst. Okay, now I'm going to
change gears a little bit. We're going
to go underground. Um, so how many
people in this room had heard of Feronia
before I mentioned it in this talk?
Yeah, it's pretty famous now. um its
first first publication was that it's
involved in pollen tube reception and
since then it's been implicated in a lot
of different things. So immunity
um not just the powdery mildew but also
bacterial immunity um cell growth stress
responses morphagenesis
um cell wall mechanical integrity it's
been proposed to be a cell wall sensor
and so we made a hypothesis that maybe
there was a conserved signaling module
where feronia activates an MLO
downstream and this helps cells to
communicate with their external
environments. Um so what we did is we
took our FA Nordia GFP which is a gain
of function channel and we expressed it
this time with the feronia promoter. So
it would be expressed everywhere where
feronia would be expressed and also with
the 35S strong promoter that would be
active in sporidic excels. And then we
tested what phenotypes of bronia could
we complement with epordia. And so first
we looked at just our
uh pollen tube reception phenotype that
we had studied using a synergy specific
promoter mid98. And we found that both
the feronia um promoter-driven faia
could complement at about the same level
as
mid98. But surprisingly the 35S promoter
um construct could complement
completely. And the lore had been that
35s is not expressed in excels. it
actually is sometimes so not all the
time it's a positional effect but 35s
can be active
um the second phenotype that we tested
so it had been shown that so when pollen
tubes leave the transmitting tract
usually only one leaves at a time and
this is a there's a feronia mediated
gating mechanism here that sort of opens
the gate lets one pollen tube bell and
then recloses it and the phenotype in
feronia plants is that more than one
pollen tubal leaves the transmitting
tract at the same time. Sorry, this is
getting cut off. That one's fine. Um and
indeed uh this was with an inner
specific cross. It also happens with
conspecific crosses or FA Nordia could
also complement that. So just having an
activated MLO channel is
enough. Um interspecific uh pol crosses.
So if you cross a rabbidopsis theiana
with a rabbidopsis liada um one
phenotype is so pollen can germinate on
a stigma send a pollen tube through but
in a lot of ovules the pawn tube doesn't
get the same reversed
um and if we express epordia or if we
overexpress nordia itself we can
actually improve inner specific che in
specific crosses
um interestingly in a feronia background
this doesn't work anymore
So we need feronia for epinordia to be
able to do its job in these inerson
processes which is still a mystery.
Okay. Finally a lot of people have
looked at feronia root phenotypes. Um so
feronia roots actually are longer than
wild type roots. This is all in a
rabidopsis. Um but the more striking
phenotype is that feronia root hairs are
stunted and they often burst early. So
they can't maintain their tip integrity.
That phenotype is completely
complemented by expressing FARIA with
either the 35S promoter or with the
Feronia promoter. I'm only showing the
35S thing here. Um we took a closer look
Oh, sorry this looks bad. Um, we took a
closer look at Veronia root hairs and
what we saw was that not only do they
burst early, they tend to be more
triangular shaped and also we also
sometimes see spherical root hairs. So
they've completely lost their polarity
and those phenotypes um can all be
complemented by having our FAordia
construct. Also the the if we add
faordia the root hairs become more um
less triangular in shape. So this is
measuring width over base tip width over
base width. And we can see we go back to
um finally another phenotype of feronia
is that the plants are dwarfed. Um and
that phenotype could not by either
feronia driven epordia or
yeah. So from this we conclude that some
but not allianotypes can be
complemented. So pollen tube overgrowth
poly tuby from the septum primary root
length abnormal root hair growth but
interpecific pony reception and
vegetative orphasism cannot. So what we
think is this with army knife verunia
some of the things it does need calcium
downstream and some don't and so the
ones that need calcium we can bypass
with with an
MLO okay so what about calcium so I told
you MLO's are are thought to be calcium
channels we know from lots of groups
work that there's a tip focused calcium
gradient that's established after root
hair initiation and it's linked to
polarized growth root hairs
Um I showed you earlier that we have
this calcium gradient or calcium
oscillations that occur in synergs upon
pollen tube arrival. Um and that this is
also linked to being able to have a
pollen tube that burst and releases its
sperm
cells. So we decided to take a look at
what happens to calcium in feronian
fenordia root hairs. So for this we used
um an AR echo marker just because we had
it in the lab. We understand that
chameleon is better. Um but we used
light sheet imaging to capture images
every 3 seconds for 12 minutes from
growing root hairs. And then we measured
what was happening with calcium at the
tip of the root hair. Um here's the
light sheet system. So this allows us to
do sort of 3D
um imaging in time.
And here's what we see. And I'm going to
need to do this. So in Colombia, you can
see these calcium oscillations root
hairs. In Feronia, we can see round
spherical root hairs. You can see some
root hairs trying to grow. And then
these flashes are root hairs actually
bursting. And when we add fayordia back
in, we now recover tip growth and we see
oscillations occurring again.
Um, we also
um quantified this and again I'm sorry
about the quality of that picture. I
didn't realize it did this. Um, but what
we see is in Colombia, if we just look
at the oscillations, this is from one
example. Um, versus Feronia, we see in
Feronia, they get very erratic. Um, so
they're kind of out of control. In the
spherical root hairs, we see very little
calcium. But if we add back in um 35 SFA
Nordia, we can restore the calcium
oscillations pretty much to
normal. Um so so that's good, right? So
maybe we're complementing Feronia root
hair phenotypes by restoring the ability
to do calcium oscillation. So that FARI
is a synthetic fusion protein. So we as
then asked the question, is there an MLO
involved in regulating root hair growth?
And what we did is we looked at some
single cell data publicly available and
we found that emlo 15 is really specific
to root hairs. Um we can zoom in right
here. So green is is high expression
here. Um and when we look at reporters
we can see strong expression of 15 at
the tips of root hairs. And if we get an
MLO15 mutant, we see dwarfed root hairs.
Um, a phenotype that's similar to
Veronia but a little bit
more. So next we looked at root hair
growth in Colombia versus Malo 15. So
first number of root hairs doesn't
really change um but we see final length
is much shorter. And if we just measure
root hairs along a root um from the tip
up to the hypocodal, we can get a faux
growth curve. And we can see pink here
is Colombia. Blue is emo 15. So it grows
less. And our malo 15 GFP can complement
and maybe even get longer root
hairs. Okay.
And we can also show um that MLO15 root
hairs shown here in blue grow at roughly
half the rate of wild type and they're
very similar to feronian root hairs that
are still maintaining growth haven't
burst yet. Okay, run out of time. Um so
question is does 15 subellular
localization change during different
stages of root hair
growth? Um like like we see with Nordia.
So here's some light sheet with um
envelope 15 GFP. We can see it's very
tip
localized. Um if we look more closely we
can see it's not there yet during root
hair initiation and then it comes on
once the bulge starts to be made and
then it seems to be being trafficked
down to the
tip. Um, we also see if we look at old
root hairs that have already stopped
growing, we it seems to be that the GFP
signal gets sequestered maybe in the
GI. So the idea is that once growth is
no longer needed, you don't need MLO to
be there at the tip. So then it gets
endocytos. Okay. So last question, does
Malo 15 also affect calcium dynamics in
root hairs? So we did the same
experiment. We used Colombia 15 and then
a 35S MLO15 construct that complemented
the MLO5 mutant phenotype. And just
roughly at first we could see okay MLO
15 root hairs seem to have dimmer signal
but this is not a ratio. So we looked
also at patterns and in wild type we see
a frequency that's at this about 0.0
um four in Colombia. So that's every 25
seconds there's a peak um in 35s 15 this
gets completely deregulated and we've
got peaks all over the place different
frequencies and then we recover it back
to almost the same
frequency express it. So this so from
this we made a model that somehow during
root hair tip growth again we have
feronia
um acting to control what's happening
and maintaining tip integrity
um probably there's other calcium
channels also involved in setting up um
calcium gradients that's been shown
several CGC channels are involved and
then maybe the MLO's again are acting to
boost that um signal and then we've also
also got some data I'm not going to talk
about but that we can also recover
reactive oxygen species accumulation in
root hairs by just um adding in a nordia
construct. Okay. So to conclude we have
signal mediated trafficking of the
emiloprotein nordia from the golgi to
the film apparatus during pollen tube
reception. This increases calcium
transport into synurgids and mediates
signaling that leads to proper
communication and pollen tube rupture to
release sperm cells. Um feronia
signaling is required for nordia
trafficking. Um but epordia and bypass
feronia in both synurges and in roots.
Um and finally we've discovered a new
function for an inflow m 15 in um tip
growth in root
hairs. So I just want to leave you with
a couple of thoughts here. Got a couple
of minutes I think. Um so what we think
is maybe these mllows are kind of acting
like the volume knob on an oldfashioned
radio, right? So so you you set your AM
or FM
um band and then you tune in to a
station, right? So that's maybe what
Baron is doing. It's helping to tune it
in and then we have these MLOs's that
are then able to like to turn up the
volume so that you get the proper
response happening. Why would you want
to do this? Right? So especially in
pollination and reception um you want to
make sure that if you've got the right
pollen tube you want to really ensure
that it's going to burst. And so
synerg arrives they're lur factories. So
they're pumping out these attractants
and then when the pollen tube arrives
they need to stop attracting and they
need to switch to reception mode. And so
you could imagine um if you don't have
the right lians the Ralphs that are
going to trigger feronia then the ovule
doesn't want to waste time in that
pollen tube. However, if it has the
right lians it wants to make sure that
that pollen tube will deliver its sperm
cells. So I think that's part of this
signal mediated track. So let's let's
keep it at a level where we can kind of
trigger it, but then once it gets
triggered, we really want to make sure
it happens. And maybe in the inner
specific crosses, what's happening
that's causing pollen tube overgrowth is
that there's just not quite enough
triggering and it doesn't reach the
thresholds that then the
epordia do its job. Okay. Um root hairs
similar deal, right? You want to keep a
balance. too much calcium is bad as too
little. Um, and maybe modulating these
MLOs's helps to sort of keep things
moving in the right
direction. All
right. Um, want to leave you with one
more thought. So there are actually 17
feronial like genes in rabbidopsis. So
most species these are big gene
families. Um, there's 15
malos. Um, lots of these now have
functions assigned to them. MLOS's were
working on filling out this this what
functions are for all of these. Um but I
think it's interesting to think about
especially with plant reproduction. So
so far seven feronial like genes have
been implicated um in places like the
stigma pollen tube tip growth um in the
transmitting tract and at pollen tube
reception. Um and four MLOs's have been
implicated on the pollen tube side. So
with pollen tube tip growth
um and pollen tube reception. So we also
think there's more malos
involved places. So I think this is a
really interesting um conservation. Um
and here I list some of these the genes
that have been found. And I think if
you're thinking about any process where
cells are talking to their external
environment, um often there's calcium
involved in this and and I think having
this ability to to work on the volume
knob um maybe has great advantages for
plant
cells. Okay. So with that, I'd like to
thank the main people who did this work.
So um Jen and Yan did the early work
with the live imaging of voluntary
reception. Um, Yan did all the faordia
and synergas and then Sienna um did all
the root hair stuff. So we had never
worked on roots in my lab. She figured
it out. She went to Chris Digger's lab,
learned how to use the light sheet and
calcium stuff. And she's finishing her
Phy this spring
and was slow to look for postocs. So if
anybody wants a really great postto,
Sienna's your girl, let me know. And
then Somia is a new student in the lab
that started a year ago and she's
working on um Nordia trafficking and
trying to understand how that's working
within synergists. And I'd also like to
acknowledge the National Science
Foundation. And with that, I can take
any
questions. I'm wondering if you'd be
willing to share how your thinking is
emerging on the functional
uh need for
oscillations and the mechanistic basis
for oscillation. So, I was just talking
about this with Maria. Um, I don't know
like is it we, you know, we said is it a
red herring, right? How how do we is it
really needed? At least in pollen tube
reception, if you damp down those
oscillations, the pollen tube doesn't
burst. So, we do know something's going
on, but like I said, we're now starting
to lean more to it's what's happening
outside the cell than what's inside. Um
yeah and I'm still I don't think the
field really
knows but we do know in in Fonia we do
see these really aarent oscillations
which is very bad for root hair
correlates with bad um outcomes for root
hoops. Yet another do the
oscillations function like a thermostat
that the oscillation itself isn't so
important but you're trying to get a
certain amplitude
possible. So um so the question is do do
the oscillations function like a
thermostat and Mark Johnson's lab at
Brown University they did a bunch of
interpecific crosses
um looking at synergas and oscillation
patterns. So some of them the pollen
tubes could make it and then they don't
burst. They didn't see any correlation
between frequency or amplitude and the
ability to receive the volunte. So we
know they need to happen but I don't
know it was kind of disappointing. We
all thought oh this is going to be the
thing. Um but yeah it's good
mystery just hey that was that was that
was a great presentation. So thinking
about the bursting
mechanism, I can imagine there could be
it could be that you get perturbed cell
deposition growth and so t pressure
blows it open or it could be cell
degrading enzymes from the Yeah. So or
both. Would do you have any any idea as
to how that operates? No. So I mean
people think that so there's a
similar binia like K Ralph stuff there's
a paracrine signaling and so people
think okay that gets disrupted
um but what's weird to me is the pawn
tube drives up
stops and then there's communication and
then it doesn't just burst it grows
again and then
bursts and
So they're still intact enough to allow
that last growth
phase. I'd like to hear your opinions as
a cell wall person.
Um but yeah, I mean it could be that
degrading enzymes are
activated somehow.
Um
yeah from that then what what happens to
the film membrane is this burst open
too. So the filerm apparatus um the
gicost lab has showed so it's
invaginated
membrane and it's kind of as the palm
tube grows in it expands like a glove
like a balloon right or like sticking
your hand in a glove. So part of it
could be you need to change calcium
there so that it actually can can loosen
somehow and there's little bits of cell
wall there. It's not completely covered
with cell wall. Um, yeah, old literature
said it entered the synergy and then
burst. That doesn't seem true. Has
anybody looked at pH dynamics? Because
if you got a drop in pH in a very
localized way, an expansion suddenly
active and that's it. There they go.
I'm not aware of anyone doing that. We
tried some in vitro. Yeah. stuff. But we
need to put
the extracellular
pH that could be a way of achieving
extremely localized very rapid or
listening at that spot.
Let me just wonder about calcium in that
that facility. So so calcium comes from
the cell wall right for right. So I kind
of wonder whether calcium dynamic at the
tip integration from the cell wall can
contribute to the burst or activity of
the enzymes or so it's I mean one
hypothesis is pectin cross linking
there's a lot of pectin in two cell
walls so maybe you're depleting I don't
know if it would be enough to deplete
and then
cause changes in cell wall
sure that be part of
about how MLS got co-opted for
pathogenesis.
Yeah. What you're saying? Yeah. Okay.
But so how would that happen? They're
modulators.
So yeah. So that's a good right because
it's not like a resistance gene. It's a
susceptibility factor, right? And so if
MLOS's were there during monitoring of
cell integrity and things, right? So you
have
Veronius related monitoring cell wall
integrity, then bringing in a backup MLO
to turn up the volume. Then maybe
somehow that you could imagine that
somehow crossed over to
um pathogens being able to take
advantage
Um it's pretty amazing how ethnicia
complments most of the feronia
defects. Did you see any negative
tradeoffs of Yeah. So Margaret's
question is are there negative tradeoffs
of overexpressing this epordia
plants look completely normal. We've
done all kinds of measurements. grows
out size is the same. Everything looks
fine. Um, but they do have differential
responses to
stress. So, salt and drought. We're
collaborating with a physiologist in our
department to do a bunch of water
regulations. So, maybe it the plants are
primed to be able to respond to certain
stresses. Yeah, I was shocked. It's like
this is going to mess up the plant.
We're deregulating calcium and it
doesn't. So it just shows you that
there's a lot of compensation that can
occur.
On the stress topic, so in your slide
you mentioned that foria somehow
medulates heavy metal
stress and so I kind of wonder um with
regard to root hair growth. So iron
deficiency causes root hair growth.
Uhhuh. And so I kind of wonder what your
thoughts about like is
feronia in war like anything known
because I haven't we've not tested it
but we could or yeah I mean I think is a
weird one. So basically labs have done
transcrytoic stuff pull downs any
interactor you look at you can find a
phenotype that fits what you want to
see. Um, so definitely there's some
stuff with translation
and messenger RNA processing. I don't
think that stuff is going to be
complemented with an MLO with that being
pretty fun. Um, but yeah, there's a some
stuff in the literature I'm not sure
about, but it' be it's very easy for us
to test. We could test
that. Oh, one more thing. I also have an
open postoc position for at least a
year. If anyone's interested, please let
me know. Could you check online if any
question over there?
No questions.
Thanks, Sharon.
This has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu.