your mower blade needs to be sharp so
that you're getting a clean slice of the
leaf blade which then minimizes stress
to the plant the plant uses less water
but more importantly a dull blade
increases your fuel consumption 20 to
30% so if you don't have access to a
workbench a small table will work fine
and your basic seat clamp now when I'm
sharpening the blade won't move around
on me it'll make it a lot easier to keep
the same Ed Edge one thing you want to
check for when you're inspecting these
blades are large dings or major
scratching pitting on the front of the
blade another thing to look for when a
blade is pretty much on its last legs
you'll have a crack starting to form
right here when that happens that means
you have a compromised blade it's beyond
the point of sharpening it you should
replace it so nothing bad happens I like
to use two hands when I'm using a
file not to apply pressure you're not
using a lot of pressure when you're
operating file you're just letting the
tool do its work you're just guiding it
along you'll notice that I'm really not
pushing it's down at all other than to
keep it flat on the
blade this is a single-edged file
meaning it only has grooves in One
Direction so you can only move in One
Direction which is always away from
you one thing you want to stay away from
is rolling your hand hands when you're
running a file you're going to round the
edge of this blade and that's not going
to do you any good it's probably going
to make it
worse so try to stay keep it
flat if you have major dings in the
blade on the front edge it may not be a
wasted blade you can still use it but
you are going to want to file that edge
down I like to wear a glove just in case
I slide off when I'm filing that I don't
cut
myself you'll notice that I'm always
moving away from me
so this is a small balance it's under
$10 it's something you can find at your
Basic Hardware Store lawn and garden
stores so we have our mounting hole your
Center screw that holds the blade in
place we also use this hole to set on
top of the balancer the balancer has
ridges on it to accommodate for multiple
sizes of main Center holes so we've
actually lightened up this side we
haven't lightened up this side yet if
it's not balanced it's going to wobble
when it spins that's going to add to
wear and tear to your blades it's also
going to add to streaking and your
cutting it's going to give you an uneven
cut when your blades aren't balanced
properly if the blade comes out of
balance where you take more metal off of
one end than the other that can also
affect fuel consumption and the quality
of cut you're going to get as well when
you're putting them back in you can
essentially tighten it up by hand almost
90% of the
way try not to overtighten it because
you got to get it off at some point