this is a production of Cornell
University yeah so um thanks Luke for
the introduction and um yeah so I I want
to share some of what I've been doing uh
and listening to Luke and and preparing
for this uh if you sum up everything I
did for a short period of time it seems
like I've done a lot of things and
that's a a really nice thing to reflect
on um so
I uh I did make this plan for what I
wanted to touch on today
um I prepared for this and I ran this a
bunch of times so I can either either go
really quickly and be uh way too quick
or it might be a little bit over so I'll
try and be cognizant of time I apologize
in advance for any discrepancies but
what I want to do is I I want to talk a
little bit about how I got to do what
I'm doing and some of the stuff I did
during PhD which was working on te and
then how that led to plent plent
interactions and then working on stuff
we've done recently things we are doing
and things we hope to do um and yeah I'm
going to hope to leave a lot of time for
questions uh so far everyone I've in
interacted with here has been both kind
and smart so I I really want to hear
what you all have to say um so I go up
there uh I've been working on a farm
since I
was 11 I've been driving tractors for a
very long time um and this
was I
guess uh pretty diverse I Ved on
multiple crops but uh working on crops
is actually not where my interest in
plans plants came from I fell in love
with plants here uh these are meadows
that are very close to my home where I
uh would hike as a child and and uh this
is one of my favorite places in the
world and when you look at where I got
interested in plants you can see just
how many plants grow here together so in
a sharp contrast to the monoculture you
see behind of of grapes and and almonds
and olives and all that uh you have
legumes here and cereals here and a
whole bunch of other genres and and
families all growing together and and
they make it work and I think that's
what Mak
them as much as us what makes them
appealing is how diverse they are how
interesting they are and how they well
how they get
along um but there really wasn't a study
The Meadows behind your house class so I
went into crop science instead and uh so
I started learning about te as an
undergrad working in uh Professor Yoshua
sanga's Lab at the Hebrew
University and
very early on it picked my interest
because um I found out that te has a
very large demand in Israel which is not
where it's endemic to te is a Serial cop
that's endemic to Ethiopia if any of you
uh are unfamiliar and um in the early
90s there was a big uh wave of rep
patriotism of uh Jews who came from
Ethiopia to Israel and they contined to
consume te as their
staple being recent immigrants this
wasn't the best well off population and
at the same time the cost they paid for
the staple flour was three times as high
as that of wheat flour which to us it
made a screen to High Heavens and we got
interested in lowering the price by
producing it
locally and on top of that farmers in
Israel as well as here always needed
more corops in the rotation we always
need more things to grow we need the
diversity we need those changes and
there was a specific need for a short
season seral crop that can utilize
excess nutrients and water from the soil
for specific Farmers specifically those
who grew carrots and potatoes they had a
large interest in the so with all that
in mind we said hey let's work on it
let's see if we can go with
Ean and starting off we had some ideas
of how TEF grew but we had a lot of
questions and all of these were
nonobvious when we started started so we
were going off of some ideas we got from
people who came from Ethiopia and were
farmers previously and I spent
substantial amounts of time trying to
adapt practices used in small holder um
traditional farming in Ethiopia to
highly mechanized irrigated agriculture
like the type we have and we had to
answer each of this so literally which
planter to use for these tiny seeds when
to sew how to irrigate we use sprinklers
or pivots uh how do we even get the
right yields what sort of genetics we
needed for those yields um and then
later on WE focused on lodging which I'm
going to touch on heavily in this and
then we also had the question of how to
harvest which actually uh became the
easiest one to answer I went on YouTube
I Googled te and we found a video from
Idaho and pl I wish everything was that
easy um but everything else we had to C
so we literally had to ask that question
and so um we did get some answers I
won't go into the whole process of this
but we did find that if we so in early
spring we got up to 150% more yield
compared to some other periods
throughout the time so the the timing
was crucial and then we also found out
that as luck would have it there was a
planter that was heavily sold back home
in the 80s a Great Plains planter that
had a small seed uh chamber in it that
fit very very good and it was pretty
accurate in in sewing densities which
you'll soon soon realize is very
important as well we also tested uh what
the right density of plants was and we
found that that produced really high
increases in yield as well and P seeds
being this big which is about between a
fifth or a third of a sesame seed so
teeny tiny uh we had to find out if we
can sew them or actually cover them with
soil and not put them on the soil
surface which which was what which was
what farmers were doing at the time
since they looked at these PL and said
this this is never going to make it out
of the soil but we actually found out
that they can make it from pretty
substantial depth and that if we covered
them we decreased sea desiccation so we
got better establishment and we got
better Anchorage so the roots the the
shoot to root Junction happened below
the ground and that improved the plant
Anchorage which is a major determinant
in logic
and as for the genetics and how to get
the best yields
we I feel like I'm I'm it's like I want
the lottery there's a lot of luck
involved in this is with any science but
we wanted to work on the we needed
genetics we reached out to Ethiopia it
was made clear to us that that's never
going to happen and not a single seed
was going to leave their ger plasant to
come to us so then we looked locally and
we went to a conference we spoke to
someone who worked at Israel Gene Bank
said hey but we have tests and then we
found out that we actually had a
collection that was collected by the
USDA in the 50s and 60s B here something
was done to it and then for whatever
reason it was shipped to Israel to be
shared with Israeli uh researchers and
basically disappeared we don't know who
who ordered it who got it who maintained
it we knew nothing so we started with
those
somewhere uh pretty obvious uh mixtures
of different colors of seeds and we had
to uh sort of stabilize them genetically
we did a single seat descent stabilizing
phase and created a panel of uh just
under 300 lines we then used that panel
for two things one we tested it in a
bunch of different locations trying to
see if anything stands out and if we can
see a line that's readily adaptable to
Israeli agriculture uh which I'll I'll
share I I've said it to some of you this
morning I just found out that one of the
lines we started licensing is is enter
the final stage and not only that but
it's the line that's named after my son
so that's pretty
cool um and so we Ed that panel to uh do
a GBS we then use that GBS data to do a
preliminary gwas and try and map key
trades to specific Losi and we were able
to find hits for a lot of important
traits but the the really cool thing we
found is that multiple sites were shared
between the three biggest things we were
targeting so days to heading grain yield
and lodging index all shared specific
locations on the genome which was a very
exci excited fine uh both muluken who
worked on this with me and I have since
finished and moved to something else but
I'm really hoping somebody picks this up
because I think it's really
interesting um yeah and then the big
issue we were dealing with is lodging
which is what you see here and what I'm
I'm about to say is it's somewhat
contested in in the te science ecosystem
so I hope nobody gets offended uh
lodging generally is the permanent displ
of a plant from the upright position
that that part is not contested uh what
is contested is if this is root lodging
or shoot lodging so in the literature
root lodging is a partial uprooting
which I think that's what we're seeing
here but and shoot lodging is a bending
of the shoot which also happens except
it happens after this so I'm going to
say it's root lodging if you're
contested I agree with you uh uh and
then uh it's it's a big issue so
compared to a three or supported growth
this leads to up to 50% yield reduction
in both biomass and grain yield and this
environment that's created here is the
the perfect place for bugs and and
fungus and pathogens of all Natures it's
a big big issue and to make things worse
it makes it really hard for the
Harvester to go over it because those
plants just stuck under this has been
possibly less of of an issue in Ethiopia
where the the most of the harvesting is
still manual but it it's still all of
those losses still apply there as well
so we saw this and I was a TA at the
time uh which I loved and I was a TA for
intro to plan science and one of the
things we got to talking about we got to
talk about is um shoot development and
the effects that shading has on things
so we said hey maybe you know ta brain
at the time maybe uh the plants are
sensing shading thus they are becoming
taller thus they're losing their
Anchorage because their center of
gravity Rises maybe that's why they they
topple over so he said okay what causes
this and possibly higher densities right
there's there's uh it's a pretty short
jump in in my brain and then we tested
so as a context to this when we started
out the data we had was that people are
sewing up to 20 kilograms per Hector
which is a lot it it's the seeds are
tiny we're talking billions of plants
per a few meters it's it was very dense
so we said okay this is probably too
much let's cut it so we went to uh 9
kilograms which is about half all the
way down to 300 to um 3 kilograms per
hectare I'm I'm sorry for stumbling we
we don't really use hectors in Israel we
use dunams because hectors are way too
big in the country's weights
so um but when when we did this we found
that the plants growing in in lower
densities were taller not shorter so it
didn't seem to be that effect also we
found that lodging was reduced and that
got me interested and I was trying to
yank those plants out and I also found
the plants here just held on to the
ground more that it's called Anchorage
and that pointed to another thing that
pointed Us in the direction of root
logic
um so that I felt was interesting and
then I said we got to thinking what in
the root could it be and this is about
the time that uh Jonathan Lynch who um
the time I was afraid of now I know him
is actually very nice uh he had a paper
about root cortical enima and that got
us thinking about maybe that's what's
happening maybe some of the areas of the
cortex are deforming and then the
connection between the side that's
attached to the soil and the side that
is definitely connected to the Chute
maybe something there breaks and when we
looked at it we saw that some of the
more lodging resistant lines and they're
not not resistant completely but more
so they produced less root cortical en
Kima and they also produced it sorry
later in the season so they had
improved uh retention of the C of the
cortex
what we think is happening is that with
the partial uprooting there's a
significant secondary uprooting that's
happening inside the root so the steel
could be just moving inside much like a
fiber moves inside an electrical wire
because it's not connected and that
could enable some flexibility to enable
the pl to switch without disconnecting
because we're not seeing the roots cut
but we do see the plant lying on its
side so that could be and uh
I'm really happy about this this was a
simple light microscope I was lucky
enough to know the right people and I
can show you what it looks like under a
uh scanning electron micro microscope
which uh was done by other people in our
group and that second uh work also found
that other metrics of the root cortical
area changed uh but it seems to be the
case it seems to be that if a plant
tends to Lodge that root cortical in
kaima is developed more and vice versa
so we don't know what starts the process
but there's definitely something going
on with root Anatomy when it comes to
lodging and because of what we knew
about the densities and the changes we
found based on densities that got me
thinking how are plants telling one
another what's going on how are plants
picking up signals that make them change
their anatomy and their development
resulting in lodging or other metrics
and that's really how I landed in um
plant plant
interactions um which is sort of the uh
in between stage between my PhD and my
posttop and so uh this is not new to you
uh PLS grow in uh diverse communities if
you don't believe me
there um but also under cultivation so
poly cultures have been used for
thousands of years you all know this
three Three Sisters Garden idea it's
amazing uh it's
an embodiment of symbiosis right because
the beans grow on top of the maze
getting support they fixate
nitrogen as a as a way of repaying the
the corn is the way it's depicted at
least and then the squash grows and
covers the soil taking advantage of
excess um radiation so we know this
happens and we know it works sustainably
but for all we know about plant plant
interaction the below part is less well
known and I can tell you why because
it's really hard to stop it's it's a lot
of hard work and it's the the invisible
part right and and I'll spoil the the
rest of this but I also focused on root
exit dates which is the invisible part
of the invisible part so uh it's hard to
study but it holds a tremendous benefit
potential because there's a big emphasis
on soil plant soil and plant microb
interactions and those plant plant
interactions specifically in inas
species ones they Cloud our view they
produce noise to other questions that
we're asking and so I think that's
important I was lucky enough to get to
know Jesse laski who also thought that
was important and I won a b Fellowship
to go and get my poster with him that
has been the
previous uh two years and pretty short
time before I came this paper came out
from the lasy lab which showed that in
arabidopsis plants if all other things
being equal and no shortage of nutrients
no shortage of water the presence of
competing plants inter and intas species
caused changes to development and in
this specific paper they were also able
to mimic it by using um a strol lactone
standard and got similar responses so we
had an idea that the root exod dates
played a role here and I was
uh amazed at this it's a whole new topic
and I spent some time thinking about how
plants communicate with one another
excuse the very um I'm not a good draw
I'm not good at drawing and less so on a
computer but we can think of some
channels of plants communicate we talked
about shading there's volatiles above
ground there's stuff that plants exude
towards one another of course there are
microbes that are either shared or are
used to trans to trans transfer cues so
and of course we can talk about micro
isy uh these are all things that we know
I can also say that I knew this was
important because uh we know that
agriculture is becoming ever more
intensified so we know plants are
growing in higher and higher
densities and it is my hope that with
with regenerative agriculture and with
um newer more eco-friendly systems we're
going to
mix some cors in the same time so inter
coping became something that I was uh
interested in as
well
and um the other question I had being
that I worked with um PL selection and
breeding before was is this breedable is
this something we can breed for and it's
this is not a new idea since the uh at
least the late 60s people have been
talking about doing the selection of new
lines under higher densities because
agriculture was expected to keep on
intensifying and you probably know about
the leaf angle changes in corn that make
the plants fit better together and share
more of the sunlight but these are all
above
ground uh below ground traes that could
benefit higher densities were less well
documented at the time so that was
something we were very interested
in and we also thought that because
seeds are sewn very close to one another
and they take longer to shade one
another other than to start exuding
towards one another probably root to
root sensing happens before shading so
to try and and check what the effect of
this was and there was a paper that
showed that you can even transfer um
flowering signals through root exit8 so
there was definitely enough evidence to
support working on the communication
belowground and trying to remove that
from the context of above ground um
interactions
so we tested 10 sorum lines some were
land races some were Elite lines all of
which we grew under high high fertilizer
abundance with either uh drought
conditions or well water conditions and
we did not allow plants to shade one
another what we did was we divided we
had focal plants of the 10 genotypes we
tested and we grew them in pots in
circled by multiple plants or a or a
single genotype that was the same
competitor for all of these 10 lines so
one competitor competing against 10
lines and we at first use these plates
to push the plants to the side uh the
plants lifted the plate like with no
issue at all then we tied them off to
remove the leaves from being able to
interact with one another and that did
produce stress but we didn't see really
signs of stress of those competitor
plans and then we asked the question how
does this affect
um the productivity and the development
of plants and what we found was that the
presence of competition which is the one
on the the second Flo to the right
produced a smaller plant reduced biomass
reduced the plant height and reduced the
leaf area and that was on par with the
control of a non-competition this is
supposed to be
non-competition uh a non-competition
drought so drought
and the presence of neighbors led to
similar reductions in productivity in
sorum and this is intas species so sorum
a sorum plant sensing neighbors around
it reduced its productivity almost like
it was experiencing drought and then we
looked at photosynthesis measurements of
stomatal conductance and and PS2
uh activity sorry and we saw a reduction
in that as well so not only is it
smaller it's producing less it's less
productive and this could be I can um
put this in a in a uh a very kind
context of saying it's just trying to
share it's trying not to steal
everything it's making itself small as a
sort of um con survival through
conservation or it could be that there's
something going on there that's reducing
its activity similar to what we found in
arabidopsis
before so we
saw that below ground interactions led
to this reduction and we said okay so if
it's below
ground there's multiple things we can
think of it could be removal of
nutrients on a very M micro scale so
close to the root maybe that's what's
going on or maybe it's a biochemical
thing maybe it's an exudate thing the
plants are exuding some something that's
causing other plants to reduce their
activity and if that's the case then we
use this very high-tech system of a
bucket and a funnel in a tube where we
grew Source plants SE in a pot we
collected the leade from this pot that
had all the Riso deposits from the same
competitor genotype and we transferred
it to a Target Port that either had
actual competition in addition to the Le
shate or just this leate and we were
wondering if is this que transported by
exid dates and if
the nature of that interaction will be
different the answers are very
straightforward yes there is a signal
that's carried by exid dates and no it's
not different in nature it seems to be
the same thing and what we found here
was that the presence of the leate of
competing plants was similar in its
effect to physical competition plants
grown in the same pot we also found
something that is very uh important for
my uh current response to reviewers
where we did not see a heightened
response when we had both competition
and leate cuz some of you are probably
thinking allelopathy and autotoxicity
auto toxicity when it is created
produces a linear response across almost
all concentration so this would have
been here if this was a natural
autotoxicity uh effect and I'm a little
bit bitter about it because I had paper
eject um and so that was one thing we
did and working with sorum I uh was
interested in what it did to other
plants and there are two reasons for
this one is when you dive into the
literature about sorum there is a ton of
papers saying that if you grow sorum the
weed population is decreased which
didn't sit well with my experience of
seeing weeds in sorum fields but I was
interested in it uh and then another
thing was that we did a lot of work in
Jesse laski's lab about working with
striga and sorum stga interactions sta
is a parasitic plant in subsaharan
Africa that picks on S plants and is
it's a major yield reducing element uh
and we were working on it and one of the
one of the things in the process of
working on it was getting good exid
dates to germinate striga seeds so we
had that system and I was wondering and
I was lucky enough to know Dr Caroline
Lowry who worked with me on this uh if
we could see an effect this plant plant
interaction between the root exod dates
that works so immensely on striga seeds
on some key weeds so um both Comm both
common water hemp and fox taale are this
is giant Fox taale are major weeds in
Pennsylvania and we looked at
germination and we found yes the the
plants that were 5 to 14 days old we
grew them in nutrient solution with then
transfer them into di water for 3 Days
let them exude and we use that to
germinate seeds and we found that those
exid dates reduced germination of both
these species both Fox taale and common
water hemp were um less germinated a
lesser extent when exposed to these exid
dates and we were wondering if that was
if there was a killer agent in this is
this a thing where the seeds just die
there's a toxic element to it so we
checked for seed viability and and it
wasn't and so with with us seeing no
reduction in seed viability what we
think is happening is that there is a
secondary induced dorcy that's happening
in these seeds which seems
to go along with gap sensing which is a
thing that small seeded weeds are known
for that if they see the light see
parenthesis but if they sense the
sunlight and if there's a niche that's
available for them to occupy they will
germinate more and perhaps what we're
seeing is that those exid dates serve as
another agent sending the message of
this area is taking there is no Gap so
this is what we're thinking and we also
looked at early development and we saw
in common water we didn't see any effect
because the seeds were so tiny we need a
smaller ruler to teste this it's just uh
it was all within noise but we found
something interested that with uh giant
foxtail the seeds that did germinate
developed much quicker so they elongated
much more they produced a higher root
mass uh when they were exposed to these
exod dates how
time
um so I'm going to run a little bit
through this but all of this work on
sorum led us and my reviewers to talk
about
allopathy which I dove in I jumped into
that rabbit hole and I can say that the
original paper the seminal paper for
allelopathy says that allelopathy is any
interaction between one plant and
another not necessarily delerious and
with that yes what I'm seeing here is
allopathy it's just not autotoxicity not
allopathy in the common way that it's
spoken you'll excuse the football joke
um and with this in mind and these paper
being written I started a new postdoc
working on
intercropping with uh the understanding
that with newer practices coming along
we're going to need inter coping to work
and uh the benefits of inter coping
depending on who you read are immense
anything from nutrient availability
going up to pest resistance going up to
higher yields they're all presented as
possible and for us they fit another
idea that my current advisor Dr GUI Wang
uh has in mind where if
we convinced Pennsylvania Farmers to who
are growing silage to replace 10% of
their corn plants with soy and sorum we
can get a higher protein intake higher
protein content in the silage we can get
a higher sugar content making the in
sealing process
quicker without substantial yield
reduction making a better product
quicker for the um for the the cows to
eat and the secondary effect that we are
also very interested in is because
there's a lot of dairy farms and a lot
of cows producing a lot of manure that
manure gets put on the fields the
farmers then get find if there's
leeching of nitrogen or runoff of
phosphorus because it leads into the
chesap bay and causes a lot of troubles
and there are evidence in literature
where if you grow this you get higher
nutrient upake and so this is why we're
interested in this and we got to
thinking about those three Corps and a
lot of everything I'm going to present
in the next couple of minutes was done
by these three women uh Risha over there
and Marin and dirra and they did basic
things they undergrads and I'm very
lucky to have had them work with me and
we were wondering imp planting these how
much longer do I have if you want leave
time for questions we should stop around
one oh perfect um so I can slow down
um so we got thinking about how those
fields of inter coping might look like
and what the practices might be and to
me it was very obvious that we should
tell the Farmers plant the soy and sorum
first let them establish their slower
growing you you Americans you did a
great job with your corn it grows so
quickly I was amazed the first couple of
times but you know not the same effort
has been done on soy and so and so I
said let's plint those first let them
establish and then put in the corn but I
was uh assured that there's no way the
far are going to go twice there's just
no chance so basically we knew that soy
and S are going to be germinating in a
in an area that has corn plants that are
bigger and already exuding so we got
thinking what what would the effect be
what would the exudates do in terms of
early development which we did in these
germination papers and uh to actual
germination which we did in Petri dishes
so we grew these all three species in a
uh hydroponic system we then transferred
the exod dates two plates or to these
tubes to see what the effect was and
this is what the seedlings look like in
germination paper and this is what we
found so we saw that for corn any sort
of exid dates that you put next to the
seeds reduced its germination rate so
there is a heighten s sensitivity there
we also found that s does not care it
will just germinate and we found that we
saw it's small picky so so with corn and
sorum there was a reduction in
germination rate with soy exudates soy
seeds germinating in soy exid dates no
substantial
reduction and we also looked at
germinating Dynamics so this is a
hydrothermal hydrothermal timeline
model um which we applied to the
germination
data um and what we found was the water
was constantly the fastest to induce
germination we did not find any effect
for corn between soy and uh corn and we
saw a reduction in sorum for all three
of them so it produced it germinated
less and slower so there was an effect
but it could be by the way that that
slower effect is just the decomposing of
the exodites we don't know how long some
of the compounds in the exod dates live
for we've not done that metabolomics I
don't even know what those compounds are
are
yet uh and then we also did some uh
early development tests and we found a
response in corn in terms of total root
length for the exid dates once again soy
and corn did not really induce a strong
response but with sorum we saw a
reduction to the point of uh to the same
level of water so basically once again
like I showed you with the fox tail the
seeds that did germinate here developed
quicker on the same time period they
produced more
roots and it could be that they're
trying to compete more in terms of uh
the shoot dry weight we saw that the
plants the corn plants are germinating
in corn exid dates were the biggest and
there was a response we also saw an
interesting response in soy where the
shoots of plants of seedlings in corn
exod dates of soy were the biggest so
maybe once there realizing they're under
competition they carry things around is
what we're
thinking um we also looked at Sho root
ratio but um for lack of time I might
not go into it so now we're analyzing
this data and we're thinking about what
we want to do next so the literature now
has two different opinions and they're
both equally as loud if you
want um so it could be that corn plants
up take more phosphorus by the sheer by
just sensing the existence of soy plants
next to them it's possible it's been
claimed in the literature other papers
say no the actually the exudates from
soy plants make phosphorus more
available and that's why there's in
increased uh uptake there's also a paper
that showed that there's higher
transcription of phosphorus Transporters
in the in the roots of uh corn plants
grown with soy but recently there's been
a c correction thing added to that paper
where if you look at it it's not really
happening so I don't know we're very
curious about this because if we can
cause plants to uptake more phosphorus
just by putting in exodites it's like a
bio stimulant we just have to grow them
in water and use that water in
irrigation and bang we get more
phosphorus in the complex if that exists
it's amazing another thing we were
thinking about and I'll maybe just uh
say that quickly and jump to my summary
uh is there is a claim that soy plants
will fix more nitrogen when they're
grown next to corn to me that is not
evolutionary stable there's no reason
for a plant to be altruistic it could be
that they're expecting some nitrogen
deficiencies later on but these are not
plants that have coevolved for a very
long time so we're very curious about
this and this is what we're planning to
do now we're going to ask these
questions and uh the first thing we're
doing is growing all three oops
all three uh plants in a hydroponic
solution with high nutrient availability
to try and see what the roots do we're
later going to try and grow them in pots
and see if we see elevated uptake which
I don't know what to expect it's a very
interesting situation where I do
actually have a two-sided hypothesis I
do not know what to expect the
literature can point you in both
directions it's exciting types um but if
if any of it works it's amazing it's
it's something that uh
I'm I'm very hopeful can lead to better
outcomes for farmers and then one last
thing I wanted to say is that I recently
partnered with the Botanical Society of
America uh for which I'm hosting a new
podcast um and sorry Jen I just realized
you were on the last one too um and I
think it's super super important for us
to uh present our science in a more
approachable and easy to find way for
the general public I think in this day
and age and I was strictly warned by uh
my advisers to not talk about politics
but I think we all do what we do because
we believe it's true and I think truth
needs to be as easily accessible as
misleading information and this is my
small attempt at doing that this should
be launched in the next month and if any
of you are working on anything related
to plans and are either members or of or
affiliated with the Botanical Society of
America reach out to me I would love to
have you on it's a really fun experience
I'm fun to talk to on zoom and it's uh
it's it's a really easy experience and
those are expected to have a big crowd
um one
o'
yeah all right so I think we can start
with uh questions in the room I have a
slide for that
hi um so some research in our lab
suggests that maze plants through
different compounds as they develop did
you play at all with the age of your
maze or other plants and capturing their
exod dates did not am expecting to and
uh the reason for that is that I had the
fortune of uh overlapping with Eric
laoren Paul who is a big vegetative
phase change expert so we know we know
it's true we even know it from strier I
I agree with you 100% we've not done
that yet uh it's something we're
planning to do but I I I couldn't AEO
those definitely
changes yeah uh thanks for the
presentation I was wondering so plant
plant interactions I I've done a little
bit of work in like uh crop weed
interaction same thing right plant plant
are you familiar with like Clarence
Swanson's work from the University of
gal I'm not okay well I it's interesting
because I think it goes along nicely
with this research where um he also
proposes that um yeah like crop yields
being limited by weeds yes there's like
a fertility and shading element but even
before any of that he proposes that the
primary thing that is limiting these
yields are just like a sensing of
somehow this weed or this crop is
sensing that there is another plant
vicinity and and I thought that was like
when you got into like exod dates and a
leathy and and also a lot of the weed
biomass work that we do is like all
above ground but so much is happening
underneath I I fully agree yeah so it's
like plant plant interactions but also
like yeah crop weed interaction same
same kind of deal yeah and and that also
uh feeds into some work that's been done
in penate with cover crops where they do
mixtures and those those mixtures
actually do better than monoculture so
maybe we should probably be looking
deeper into this excuse the pun but um
yeah yes um thanks thanks great talk uh
yeah so plant breeding is in part A
numbers game we have to we have to
measure lots of as many plants as we can
just to do
selection uh you you you mentioned
idiotypes I'm wondering if your research
suggests some kind of intercropping idot
type that is faster to measure than
say growing the intercrop and making a
biomass cut and separating out the
species you know like that's slow like
like is there something that that that
comes out of your work
that that we could select on that would
by indirect selection improve intercrop
performance I have to think about it for
a second no you're good um well for one
thing is as a way of making the
selection more high throughput and and I
S touch on that with Greg I think if we
did Hydroponics and we played around
with the species in there allowing for
greater interaction and looking at the
performance it's not the field it's very
artificial but it might give us a Way
Forward I think uh so the way I had
envisioned it is with the nft system
where the top length is the exuding one
and all of the rest are experiencing
some sort of a gradient of exposure
um I don't know the the the thing we
wanted to achieve with that solum work
was with we wanted to get uh RNA seek
data from before and after the exposure
to the exod dates in the exate transfer
thing as you know life happens we missed
the deadline of one grand and then my
fellowship R out we did not end up doing
it I think we could see stuff there I
think if we did this in an environment
that had multiple nutrients availability
or varying nutrients availability we can
tease apart The receptors on the root
that re respond to that specific element
and that might give us a a better Target
for breeding uh I definitely think it's
worthwhile I've been hearing that we are
running out of Al for a very long time
and the root is maybe an an resource I I
don't know but I do think it's it's a
possibility
Yeah question online David looks like
you have your hand raised did you have a
question there yes um so this sounds
like it's so I work with Clarence swon
quite a bit um and our hypothesis is
that you know the plants recognize each
other and that's why you get sort of
reduced yield and if that's the case
then it should be possible to identify
mutants that don't respond to those
chemicals right that just ignore them um
have you thought about looking for
mutants that uh uh do not respond to the
the exate uh chemicals
um I have not we did hope that if we
grew land races we might see variation
in the direction of response we did see
variation in the magnitude of the
response to exit dates so there could be
some differences there uh it was a very
small sample it was 10 lines and they
were mixed between land races and Elite
lines so it wasn't a really good panel
to ask a question um I I would imagine
it's there we've not done this I will
say that uh we looked at or I looked at
some strigolactone sensing mutants in in
P doing some other work and I I'm less
convinced that strigolactones are the
key agent in this sensing but it I could
be wrong about this and the with sorum
those mutants Wen weren't readily
available for us to use it will be a
logical Next Step um which were hoping
to achieve you know grants becoming
available again permitting and such
excellent um just so you know we do have
a lot of RNA seek data online uh for
plant uh weed interactions you're you're
welcome to to mine it for whatever you'd
like
so thank
you all right any any other questions in
the room I think that's it on all right
so let's thank the speaker once again
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu