This is a production of Cornell
University.
Thank you everybody. I'm stunned by the
turnout here and I hope I will do the uh
your expectations
justice. When Angela got in contact with
me, she asked for something that would
stimulate discussion and and obviously
would have something to do with soils
and carbon cycling.
So the the
general thrust that I chose is this old
thing that we all um learn at the very
beginning of our scientific careers.
This be careful with correlations. I
think uh that that is this this mantra
that that is very early in our
scientific education as a maybe maybe
the data look good but but always be
mindful that you need to have some sort
of underlying explanation and I thought
uh I use this as the framework for uh
what I actually want to get across so I
don't want to tell you that you need to
be careful with
correlations it May it may look like I
was going to do that over the next let
me say five or six slides but don't
don't don't fall into that
trap. So what do I want to talk about?
Um first of all
uh the the talk about carbon cycling is
um replete with the use of this word
control and it it pays to think for a
moment what what a control is. So when
you want to know what a what a word
means you go to the dictionary don't
you? And uh when you go do that then you
find that a control is defined as the
power to make decisions or the ability
to direct actions
or an action itself or a method a law
that limits the amount or growth of
something. So a control is perceived as
something that is
actively doing something. Uh when
we accept
this choice of definitions, then uh we
we are immediately aware of the
relatively complicated nature of this
um thing control.
When we have actions, decisions,
methods, laws, abilities, then we have
to accept that this this this entity,
this this this concept of control is
variable, dynamic, adaptive, structured,
multifaced. I could go on uh and you
know, if
I put a little effort into this. So what
I what
I'm trying to get across here is
controls are not single numeric values.
one
number is not a control or even a
sequence of numbers is not a control. Uh
and and even simple mathematical
functions or algorithms do not qualify
as
controls. Always when you follow that
Mariam Webster definition. So now let's
try to find the connection back to
carbon cycling. Um when people talk
about carbon cycling and when they model
carbon cycling then they often use
controls with the
um with the interesting development that
they multiply over the years or the the
controls that are being talked about
increase in number. Uh we can broadly
dist distinguish environmental controls
which include drivers such as moisture,
precipitation, radiation. Uh heat is a
form of radiation. But there's also uh
visible light uh ultraviolet light, high
energy radiation that might be ionizing.
Structure of the
environment can be parameterized as
total pore space, poor size
distribution, preferential flow paths,
mineral surface chemistry, resources. So
all these are environmental factors that
are known to have an influence on the
cycling of carbon, oxygen availability,
you take the oxygen away and things slow
down dramatically. uh alternate electron
acceptors. You take the oxygen away but
you provide nitrate and things keep
going at least for a larger part of the
microbial community. Proton
concentration other words for pH
catalytic metals organic co- metabolites
that will return mineralborn nutrients.
So something in the order of 11 or 12
environmental
controls, substrate controls. So the the
this refers to the fact that the the
object of decomposition has certain
properties which tend to um be of of
relevance for the decomposition process.
So which are these properties?
Bioenergetic potential. How much energy
is stored in that organic molecule? Uh
how attractive is it from an energy
viewpoint to the
decomposer? Oxidation state of the
carbon mainly. This is a important
variable that determines how difficult
it is to get at that energy. But then
also we we are not just decomposing
things for energy, not us and not the
microbes. we sometimes need nutrients
and in in in that case the stochometry
of the nutrients is important. Uh and
and this not just for the the big ones
the big uh mass nutrients but also for a
plethora of
micronutrients
assimilability. So
your your your compound may be um loaded
with energy, contain tons of nutrients,
but it may have some other feature that
prevents it from being
assimilated. One one really important uh
number here is molecular size. When we
go above 600 Dton, we get into real
problems getting this compound through
the cell wall from the outside to the
inside. And uh the the way these these
things are done in nature means that
threadlike molecules have are much
easier to taken in.
So but not everything's a threat and
this is what we mean with assimilability
and parametric
uh expressions of assimilability can be
aquous solubility molecular size
linearity global structure all these all
these features
influence control uh organic matter
turnover accessibility where is it is it
far removed from the decomposer or is it
closed by is it co-precipitated with a
mineral phase kind of mired in in
concrete? Uh is it absorbed encapsulated
in aggregate?
Um and that's another dozen or so
individual controls that we know have
something have the power to influence
the turnover of carbon. So, and I'm not
done yet. organismic. So the yeah the
decomposers the those who are actually
doing the business they have different
lifestyles grazers predators microisal
free living fungi bacteria aa microbial
diversity who is there who is dominating
the microbial community how many of them
are
there how active are they are they all
dormant uh or are they competing with
each other massively are they
synergistic are they cheetahs
There is such there is such a
thing. Those who lie and wait for others
to secrete all the expensive enzymes
and growth stage
um physiology of microbes and especially
the the chemistry of the extracellular
polymeric substances that they secrete
change as a function of growth stage
within ours.
ability to use oxygen. That's the that's
our this is the second most
electronegative element in the periodic
table. And it's the the strongest
electron catcher. When you have a system
that contains oxygen, you can make these
large energy gradients that really drive
things. And when you when you cannot
take advantage of this and your energy
gradient is only like that, such as
between your substrate and iron, for
example, then the energy that you can
harvest is much smaller. So you you if
you really want to have things turn over
quickly, you want to have
oxygen and that uh is reflected in the
biology of the of the decomposers. So
some of them uh are really specialized
on this that but others once in a while
we run out of oxygen and then you have
uh those who are
absolutely unable to deal with oxygen
organisms that probably are somewhat
left over from the days two or three
billion years ago when there was no
oxygen free oxygen but then there's all
kinds of integrates here. So,
so, so what what I have here is
something in the order of 30
or if if we were to engage in a
collective brainstorm, we would be able
to come up with another 10 or 20 within
15 minutes, I'm pretty sure.
So, the challenge then is to how do we
constrain this? What
matters? Who or what controls the
control?
Is there a hierarchy of
relevance? Do they depend on each
other? Uh is is is the control number
seven uh of the same importance in uh
Cornell as it is in
Corvalis and in the reactive the
respective soils of course. So how have
people dealt with this? I mean we are
not we are not the first who who realize
this this multitude of
possibilities. Uh so others before us
have realized the same thing and they
have developed strategies how to deal
with this and one of the strategies was
the idea to look for a master control
for one parameter or for one
item that controls it all. the one
ring and that one ring the first big
popular one ring is what we call
substrate quality. That's that's the the
first suggest just suggestion of a
useful master control that
uh was extensively tested by the
scientific community.
So I'm I'm presenting two examples for
the application of this principle of of
uh substrate quality in the function of
a master control. You probably have all
at some point heard something about umic
substances and there is a paradigm
that's still standing paradigm that
these umic substances tend to have old
radiocarbon age because there is a
process that is called humification
which makes them highly
aromatic. And this then explains their
resistance to
decomposition which explains the the
high
radiocarbonate. And this goes back to uh
a benchmark paper published in
1967. So it is needs a little
explanation. So you have a a graph with
age on this axis. High age is here 1500
years. The numbers are bit bit small but
um so old carbon is here and this is
1500 years 1,500 years. And then you
have an an a a a uh index for
aromaticity. This is the the the ratio
of the light extinction at 400 and 600
nanometers. This uh this is a a way of
determining how many aromatic compounds
are in that specific
uh solution. So when you are high on
this axis the aromaticity is low and
when you are high on this axis the the
carbon is old. So so
the the young carbon or the young age is
following this red line and the the that
age gets older as the aromaticity goes
down increases. I'm sorry the the the
brown line goes down but that means the
aromaticity increases. I'm was
practicing this for a couple of times
and I wasn't
so at at this point I want to come back
to my little introductory remark about
the importance of correlation uh and uh
our our joint love for correlations. We
all when we see something correlate like
this the the age goes up when
aromaticity goes
up then we all love this. We cannot we
cannot avoid that. We we we really like
this type of observation. And what we do
then is we we inadvertently
instantly in invent a model some sort of
explanation. And in this case, the
explanation was was really plausible um
because we know that aromatic rings
require a lot of activation energy to
break
them. So it makes it makes total sense
for these two parameters age and
aromaticity to
correlate. But in order to to
demonstrate that they do indeed causally
uh generate this resistance to
decomposition, one would have to
demonstrate
that. And
uh actually went one sentence ahead of
myself here. I was I was going to u uh
mention that this is these ages here.
This is what we in carbon cycling models
consider the passive pool. You probably
have heard about the active, the
intermediate or slow and then the
passive pool. So this is this is what
gave rise to this passive pool idea 1,
1,500 years of turnover
time. So what are the issues with
causality here? This this was accepted
an accepted relationship and it was an
accepted is still an accepted model.
This type of inference informs the
community land model which is supported
by NSF and DOE and which is the basis of
climate modeling at this time as we
speak. So what is the issue with
causality? So I'm saying that the ideas
behind the the correlations used in the
existing CLM are not based on causality.
can
um decomposer organ organisms have no
way to sense how much 14 C or 13C is in
a glucose or in a uh a lipid. Uh they
cannot make a a selection based on 14 C
content or 13 C content. They recognize
the glucose or they recognize the lipid
and then they decide whether they want
to engage. So old age is not an argument
for stability.
It it it were an argument for stability
if the decomposer would have a mechanism
to select for young versus old which
they don't. They go for chemical
characteristic and not for radiocarbon
content or 13C
content. Fungi are absolutely capable of
decomposing condensed aromatic rings.
There's a huge literature and I I I did
just did not put it up. you just Google
P ages and fungi and you you get 10,000
hits or
something. So the the mechanistics me
mechanistic assumptions behind that
little logical chain that I had on the
previous slide are not
corroborated. The the other thing or the
third major argument here is the early
researchers were working in Canadian
grassland soils. grassland
soils and they had an important piece of
information they did not have that we
have it
today. Uh so
they see this 14 is a function of
aromaticity and they don't know a
important feature of these grassland
soils that we know today. And what is
that
feature? the the aromaticity in these
soils does not come from whatever that
humification process
represents. It was supposed to be here
the
map. So you have these grassland soils
which are zonal soils. They are all uh
uh along uh
the some somewhere between the 20th and
the and the 50th parallel. Actually a
few down here in Argentina as well. Uh
this is a a map using the FAO soil
systematic. So it has the f theoss,
shooms, castinos. These soils are
broadly equivalent to the salt taxonomy
molly
souls.
Um these grasslands in their native
state, they burn regularly and that
loads them up with black carbon. BC
means black carbon. So here's the data.
So the this study is based on 28 soil
profiles very uh rigorously investigated
with radiocarbon 13C uh markers for
black carbon and you find that there is
something of the line was not drawn here
but there's something of a correlation
between the black carbon in grassland
soils and the carbon stock in these
soils and the the takeaway message here
is that grassland soils contain between
1 and 5 kilog kilogram of black carbon
which is more or less a a a
concentration of aromatic
rings.
So we are we are facing a long-standing
paradigm and there is abundant evidence
that the mechanistic underpinnings
uh are no longer valid. Let me put it
that
way. Oh yeah and this was published by
Rodenov in 2010.
So, so let's leave the the long the slow
pool, the thousand-year pool uh behind
for a moment. Um there's another example
of this attempt to to use a master
control to describe carbon turnover and
that is the paradigm that litter
decomposition rate should be a function
of the lignon nitrogen ratio.
Um this is a
absolute citation classic here. Milo uh
at at all
1982 and and this was the work where it
was shown for the first time
that the the biomass remaining after you
expose litter for a certain amount of
time or let it decompose. The amount of
litter that remains after time X is a
function of lignen nitrogen ratio.
Basically you have high nitrogen the
litter is decomposed quickly and you
have low nitrogen or the inverse is uh
little lingine high lignine then uh the
litter goes away uh uh much slower.
So which leads to this uh this general
um
paradigmatic statement that liter
decompositions depends on lignine
content. There is one one caution that
one should immediately become aware of
when one looks at this graph. So if this
is a categorical predictor then the
green and the blue should be on top of
each other. But apparently this
relationship can be modified and here we
we run into this issue with our
assumption that a master control may
help us to get a handle on the multitude
of controls. Um if for whatever reason I
want to be able to distinguish between
ecosystems apparently just one control
is not going to carry the
day. So this is by by the way uh the the
the experimental evidence that gave rise
to this idea that we should have a
slowpool in carbon cycle models. So
because this this type of material turns
over on an annual multi-annual time
scale 10
the the issue with this is not only that
the green and the blue were not on top
of each other. The issue is also that
um the this this old assumption lignen
is only decomposed after the label or n
containing organics have been used up.
So this is the the this this back and
staff 1980
uh this litter decomposition model. So
you have the mass of the litter the blue
line mass on this axis time on this
axis. As as time progresses, the litter
comes down, the mass comes down. And the
the underlying idea verbalized here was
that the lignon doesn't
respond until the the uh label stuff
which would be the area under this curve
here under until that that is uh
decomposed. So the idea the bugs or the
decomposers go for the easy stuff first
and then they have used that up then
they eat the basically they eat the
candy and then they go for the potatoes.
So and and and
um again this is this is somewhat
plausible because it it is in line with
some of our own behavior. Just was
talking about the candy and the Yeah.
No, this is we we have evidence that
processes of this kind can work in this
in this fashion. But is it is it
actually what is going on
here? And then there is new research
that shows vigorous enigma decomposition
is going on only as long as there are
these
easily decomposible things. So the the
the mass loss now again the litter mass
loss the whole litter mass loss uh
described by the blue line but the the
lignon gets decomposed here at the at at
the front when you have these things in
order to help decompose the lignon but
when you run out of the accessory the
so-called co-
metabolites then the resources to to to
do business with the lignine are no
longer there and then the the line
flattens
out published in
2011. So and the the old model 1980 so
it's 30 years and new evidence has come
around. In both cases, it's it's not my
intention to to criticize the the our
predecessors, but it's my my intention
is rather to to point at the need to uh
be careful with these
correlations and uh don't trust them too
much. Uh because if we do do, we might
miss the the things that are really
going on. So yeah, and I was going to
point that out, which I believe I did.
So is
substrate quality an appropriate master
control? Well, based on the evidence I
have just presented, I hope you uh can
uh join me in saying that is probably
um not
so. And if if that is not so then um is
there is there maybe some other master
control? And here we come to work that
was published in 1988 81. So large
differences between the turnover rate of
particular compounds in liquid microbial
cultures and in
soil indicate that soil provides a
measurable degree of protection. So the
the those who set out to get a handle on
the controls focused on the substrate
and uh but then somebody
realized the the soil controls the
matrix of the soil controls decomposer
as de decomposition as well. So you have
you may have the substrate somewhere
here but then uh it matters what kind of
matrix this substrate interacts with if
at all.
Interestingly, look at that
date that that that kind of thinking
came around more or less at the same
time. But the substrate control idea was
way more uh appealing to the scientific
community. Liked it much better. Didn't
really want to deal with this matrix and
mineral stuff for a while at least. So
until
1997, Margaret, my former boss, uh was
lucky with a Nature paper that was
titled mineral control of soil organic
carbon storage and turnover. So this
this then is an example for for
uh an attempt to address some of the
shortcomings that the substrate quality
idea had by replacing it with a better
master
control. Problem with that approach was
that it's not exactly a straightforward
predictor either. So and it would be so
uh the the uh if you
take mineral components from three
different soils here this is the clay
fraction uh then you you have to uh
accept that the ability of clays to
associate with carbon is much different
between the soils. So you can just say
which actually the the century model
does uh I take clay content and use that
as a rate modifier. It matters a lot
what kind of clay you have in
there. So what do we make out of this?
What's what where do we go from here?
Um a contest of the master controls does
not seem to be the best strategy here.
So remember in the beginning I I took
some time to show that there is no
problem to come up with at least 30 or
40 individual
um factors that would qualify as some
sort of control. So picking one and and
focusing on one of these controls is is
not apparently not the best strategy.
Um and be why because in both cases the
evidence in support for the importance
of that control was largely
correlative. The
it the the
researchers saw this correlation the
lignen nitrogen ratio and the uh the
amount of of litter left perfect you
know straight line. you you go out do
some experiments out there and and you
have 10 data points and you get a
straight line. How often does that
happen? It must mean something, doesn't
it? Yeah.
And but but the fascination with this
type of of result
then makes us makes us so confident that
we do not dig deeper.
So are we doing enough to identify and
understand mechanisms and causes behind
assumptions that we use to inform carbon
cycle models? I'm positing here we are
not and you are the generation that has
to change
that brings up the issue of
causality. So how do we get at causality
in carbon cycling? But what what what
are ways to uh make this work? So the
controls actually are
descriptors. The the thing that we need
to understand we we don't need another
label. We already have 30 or
40. What what we need is understanding
of the system, the machine, the
engine, reciprocating our turbine. That
that type of understanding is what we
need. And a good way to approach this or
the way that I am to I am I am proposing
here is uh to look for where the soil
comes from evolutionary
adaptations. So the number relevance
connectivity of controls our 30 catalog
of 30 controls can they be seen as a
consequence of systems design which
would have if if this in any way works
out it it would mean if you get an idea
of the principles behind systems design.
How how is the the soil as a uh uh a
place where carbon is processed? How how
is that designed? how is it laid out?
What are the guiding principles? If if
we know that we may be able to get at
the causalities that we are missing in
these old
correlations.
So what what I'm saying here is in
disagreement with the the views that
geologists have about soils.
Geologists uh uh take soils as the the
the interface between a planetary body
and what is beyond and they do not
require life to be involved in the
formation of soil. This understanding of
soil when I say soil evolves with the
ecosystem goes back to this idea
of that burner. I'm I'm sure others as
well have uh put forward that when soil
formation really took off on this planet
when plants started to evolve when when
the algae came out of the water and
inhabited the land that is the moment
where we should start talking about
soils.
So if we follow that premise and again
uh the the the geology community folks
who like to find soils on Mars they they
have to do without trees and out roots
and so that's a different view of
things. Evolution has created flow
through reactor systems with unique
reactor design and carbon processing
strategies. So that would be the causal
the key to
causality reactor design carbon
processing strategies. So something like
400 million years ago a few algae
started to inhabit the land surface. The
these little algae evolved into proto
plants which uh developed proto roots
which by the way from the first day were
uh working together with microisal fungi
and with bacteria because they were
there first. And so as a result the
matrix gets transformed and when you
allow the plants to become more
complicated and more powerful as
biogeeochemical machines then you get
these systems and it is relatively
uh easy
to um envision
that when you change the ecosystem here
that would have effects on uh how the
soil is is functioning They have
different inputs. You have different
quantities of inputs. You probably have
a other uh biota. And so you get a
different type of reactor design and
different carbon processing
strategies. That now means the controls
are the result of how the the system
works. You don't approach the problem by
asking what does temperature do to the
system. You approach the problem by
saying how does the system work? Oh, if
I raise the temperature to 50 degrees,
that means such and such. So, it's a
it's a a a reversal of the the line of
thinking. The basis for this is the the
fact that within any ecosystem, there's
co-evolution of above ground and below
ground
biota. The decomposers are there because
of the plants. That's the idea behind
this. And it's not my idea. It's
Eastwood at all. the interesting paper
the the science paper is only four or
five pages but the supplementary
information are I believe 70
so you
really so this
is if soils evolve to decompose organic
carbon at the rates and in the sequences
required to support the
ecosystem that that puts into question
ideas like uh oh I have a uh certain
lignos cellulose that should decompose
at a rate that is typical for lignos
cellulose. That's what our models do
right now 76 days lignos cellulose if
the
system has evolved in a to deal with
lignos cellulose in a certain way then
the system determines the
characteristics of the system determine
how long this lignoselos takes to be
decomposed. So it's no longer an
inherent property of the lingo
cellulose.
So system evolution here is a a dune in
beautiful
Oregon and this is grat student Adrian
Gallo taking a picture and only about
500 meters away from this dune is a
older dune and you see how that soil has
evolved has shown some some uh E horizon
ABS horizon so that's an incipient
uh spot sooul this is a very uh early
antisol
And in the course of this development
the is there's change of the mineral
matrix. It's consumed. Minerals are
destroyed. Uh new minerals are formed
and things are rearranged in the soil.
Structure is changed. So so the reactor
design this is a different reactor than
this. It does different
things and that those things that they
that are happening different here
influence the turnover time of the
organic
matter.
Oops. Yeah. This this whole matrix issue
must be seen not as a static entity but
as a dynamic adaptive part of the
ecosystem. So the the mineral matrix is
actually shaped by the biota.
which is which is the the major force
that that makes the soils function in
different ways. So a a very crude uh
idea of how this works is you need
water. We uh all agree with this water
comes slightly acidic because you have
CO2 in the in the air which dissolves in
the water and that makes it mild acid.
This then allows for weathering of the
minerals. You can have small reactive
weathering products and then they can be
mineral partners of mineral organic
associations and the intensity along
this
path varies. what you get here. Uh
moisture also allows things to grow,
microbes and plants and then when when
plants grow for example they generate
root exodates which are
acidic really acidic and that then uh uh
augments or or amplifies processes down
here. So you have more growing here, you
have more change here. You get the you
get the idea. You you make
this a a a thriving active part. You get
uh I have the bad word here humis uh
because it's in every book. This can be
decomposed and you again making
something acidic and this again then
influences the the the properties and
the shape of the mir. a highly dynamic
system. Uh you take vegetation out, you
change the intensity of processes, you
mess with the microorganisms, you change
the intensity of processes.
And it should it should illustrate the
the contention that this is not very
well predicted or described by saying
lignen
or cellulose are are decomposed within
50 days. So yeah, I I I change the
importance of any of these arrows and
that number will not uh
uh have any any
uh uh connection with reality. So where
are we? Current research practice is
centered on understanding controls and
their
interactions which can be paraphrased as
understand the control to understand the
system. That is how we all have been
brought up. This is how how our modelers
work. They they want us to figure out
how a a algorithm that describes how the
control equation influences turnover
time. But would it not be better if we
accept that controls and their relative
importance evolve with a system to put
more effort into understanding systems
design
and such in in a way that we can derive
the relative importance of controls for
the governance of the system. that would
turn the thing around understand the
system in order to understand the
importance of the control. So if you are
interested in temperature sensitivity of
organic matter decay well you need to
understand how decay works and then you
will be able to understand what happens
when you manipulate the temperature.
the the way we are approaching this
right now is from the other
end systems design. So what does that
mean? Soils are different. So like I
just said u in koalas we have different
soils than you guys have here. So there
is a uh an obvious difference between
soil type but even within one soil you
can uh identify regions where the the
process regime is completely
different. So let's look at the litter
layer here. Uh this is a loose pile of
substrate like walking into uh Starbucks
in the morning. Everything's there. You
just grab it. well
airrated oxygen plenty. No need to come
up with any fancy physiology or so. Uh
easily accessible to mobile decomposers.
Yeah. The the a a a force that we tend
to forget very frequently. Meoporn are
those are the ones that chew the large
pieces down to the size where the bugs
can then do business. U so they are
abundant here. They can crawl among the
leaves and twigs and they and they are
fast. They are usually the first ones on
the
scene susceptible to perturbations and
to fluctuations of driver. A tree falls
down, crashes on the forest floor. All
this this little paradise is is uh
anihilated uh or it doesn't rain for 3
days, the the moisture holding capacity
is basically not existing. So it dries
out very so the amplitude ecological
amplitudes are large. You need
adaptations for that basically.
Let's go a little further down. A
horizon. This is actually the region uh
where you can say the
ecosystem does its recycling. So this is
the recycling facility of the ecosystem.
Um you have an active input of co-
metabolites through root exodates. So
the the plants they have they have no in
I mean plant cannot think and an
ecosystem does not evolve in a direction
chosen by the ecosystem. It's all
adaptive. So you excuse my language when
I say uh the plants can uh support
business by putting exodates out. There
are regulatory mechanisms that allow
them to do that is in in an adaptive
fashion. Um the the point is that as
long as you have these plant roots, fine
roots, you can really speed up things.
You you have you have something that is
absorbed and protected or it's it's a
large chunk. You can you can support uh
decomposition processes by by meta
inputs. You have a wide choice of
catabolic pathways. Everything's
everything's going here. uh you have
access to catalytic metals and reactive
surfaces because you're already in the
soil. You don't have that in the same
extent here in the litter layer because
you don't have the metals and you don't
have the
minerals and the the
the oscillations in oxygen supply are
somewhat dampened because the moisture
holding capacity here is much higher
than than here. Uh but it's it's it's
still it's still cycling. Once in a
while you go through a redux cycle and
you can recycle those redux sensitive
metals that you that you can use utilize
as
catalysts. Only when you get down here
then you are in the
desert. But that is again that qualifies
as a completely different operating
conditions condition for a reactor. Low
substrate
concentrations. A bit of substrate here,
a bit here, a bit here, a bit here and
the micro here in the center. How how is
this supposed to work? the the you
cannot do very quick organic matter
turnover under such conditions. U few
organisms lack of co metabolites because
no roots anymore reduced pore space
because often you have clay formation uh
at those depths and that will clog your
pores. Uh it's difficult to get oxygen
down there and you have uh the issues of
accessibility that I just pointed
out.
So this is what I mean with
understanding how the system works and
then ask yourself now when I am let's
say I am in this in this in this desert
in the in the in the subs soil and I put
a chunk of wood down there uh is is it
really appropriate to say this turns
over in 76
days as a as a as a substrate specific
parameter? I don't think so. So in our
zeal to understand controls on carbon
cycling are relying too much on
correlative evidence. Progress may come
from bottomup approaches that seek to
identify the causality that I'm giving
you here the what you already heard in
your u first statistics uh
uh class.
So what I what I really want to
emphasize
is it it's worth to to accept the fact
that soils do not just look different
but also work different especially when
it comes to carbon cycling. The next
generation of models and the next
generation of scientists needs to
emphasize the causalities behind soil
process. Don't do the same thing that
our fathers have done.
Now when you when you see that straight
line is that okay I have a straight line
great that is certainly going to be a
paper but be honest to yourself yeah be
honest to yourself do do I really
understand what's going on here have I
tested whether my assumption is really
the the mechanism behind this or am I am
I going the way of cheap sales and if
you're ever in a position to support
some sort of modeling exercise be
especially careful with the causalities
thing. Yeah, a a golden sentence to
conclude and uh yeah, paradigms must be
continuously challenged and checked for
compliance with coalis. Doesn't that
read beautiful? Okay, thank you for your
attention.
[Applause]
Well, I need to admit that I'm not a
modeler and uh I also need to admit that
I have enormous uh u confidence in uh
the the possibility of technological
advances. So I I remember that when I
entered the field 20 years ago um we
modeling model exercises were were done
on supercomputers. Today that's you
don't need them. One of the major
constraints was storage space at that
time and I understand these constraints
have gone down but I also remember that
the computational
uh complexity of models was an issue and
so not knowing what the most recent
developments in this field are. I think
um the the argument that the models need
to be simple which I completely
understand and I think
uh there is no reason to try to
overexlain things. We we we know this
from other phenomena. When you can
explain something using three variables,
then there is no need to throw 30
variables into the picture. In fact,
principal component analysis is a tool
that we all often use to to bring down
the number of variables because it's
then easier to make sense of what we
see.
So um my attempt to talk around your
question is now going on for one and a
half
[Laughter]
minutes. Um but what you what you get
from from this is I think uh there is
probably some uh some slack in what on
the computational side can be done. So I
I think we should not be afraid uh to
add parameters or add algorithms to our
modeling attempts. Um but to what extent
that can be realized is a little bit
beyond my area of
expertise that okay thank you.
So I have
friends, I have modeler friends and they
have they have uh uh played with not
just decomposing organic matter but
breaking organic matter down into
certain functional
categories and that seemed to be a
useful approach that has been published
last year I think in geocientific model
developments obscure
uh journal. Yeah. So if if you are
interested in detail, I I'm happy to
share the source. Yeah.
Thank you everyone. Let's thank Marcus
again.
Thank you.
This has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu.