this is a production of cornell
university
thank you nina and good afternoon
everybody thank you for joining today me
today for the seminar
um so to give you a little overview of
what we're going to be talking about
today
we're going to i'm going to talk a
little bit about just very briefly
research in botanic gardens in general
i'm getting the master's in public
garden leadership so i want to kind of
give a perspective on that and then i'm
going to jump into some research i
helped out with at the morton arboretum
in chicago last summer
and i'm going to finish up by talking
about some of the research i've been
involved with while here at cornell
so in botanic gardens there's been a
history of research that's dated back
about 500 years now with the earliest
iterations of what we'd actually
consider a botanic garden
there was a research focus at these
institutions the first kind of botanic
gardens that we really considered seeing
in the in the
world were what was known as the physics
gardens and these were gardens that were
associated with universities and usually
primary and primarily were focused
on teaching students about medicinal
plants and
for for doctors who were studying so the
first gardens to be established were in
italy at the university of pisa
and even from back in this date
we see that research has been an
important part of what they do
stepping into the more modern day
some of the research that we see
that has kind of traditionally happened
at botanic gardens has really been work
mostly around systematics so looking at
phylogenetic relationships of plants and
classification particularly with plant
or exploration
and the work that was going on of
bringing plants from other parts of the
world and classifying them as well as
floristics floristics being looking at
plants from the perspective of
biogeography
and the distribution of the different
species and what affects speciation
in this way and this work has of course
been supported by herbarium work the
drying of physical plants to do this
kind of taxonomic description but then
also increasingly with living
collections so bringing seed back or
living plants and growing the modern
collections and using them for this type
of study
kind of more some more modern focuses
that we're starting to see
more gardens putting emphasis on is
definitely conservation biology and the
disciplines that go on within that
chicago botanic garden and missouri
botanic garden being two examples of
gardens that have a strong focus on
plant conservation and the associated
fields
and of course horticultural research has
also been an important topic that
botanic gardens have played a very
active role in
like i mentioned particularly with plant
exploration going to new parts of the
world bringing plants back and then with
that subsequent plant introduction
and when we grow these plants on in our
living collections we start we also give
us an opportunity for plant evaluation
such as disease screening or pest
screening and this is in many ways tied
into plant breeding programs and
really gardens have started to become
more of just a place nice place to go
visit and see plants from around the
world but we're starting more and more
to consider them as what we would
consider a germplasm repository where
these wild collected plants are
representations of their wild
populations which can then be used for
study conservation or plant breeding as
i mentioned
so that's a very brief overview overview
of research in botanic gardens and with
that i'm going to transition in to talk
a little bit about the work i did at the
morton arboretum
for people who aren't familiar with the
public garden leadership program between
your first and the second year all the
fellows in the program go to
somewhere in the united states
and participate in an internship
i found myself at the morton arboretum
for a number of reasons they've got an
excellent plant collection that i was
very interested in interacting with
but the more in arboretum to give a
general overview is 1700 acres so quite
a large garden and it's more than just
the arboretum they focus on more than
plants they have natural areas as well
as prairies a number of formal gardens
too such as a children's garden which is
a great way to diversify your gardens to
get different types of audiences to come
and visit
and they also have some other
specialized gardens like a hedge garden
fragrance garden
they have a 27 million dollar annual
budget
employ over 350 employees including
part-time and seasonals
and this garden was established in 1922
by joy morton and people will typically
know the morton name
as the as the salt empire and people
that
in that industry
and at the morton arboretum they've got
many thousands living plants but they
have four uh
4 100 different specific taxa so
different species or subspecies growing
on the ground
and the warren arboretum was an
interesting place to go because of their
living collections and because it is
such a widely visited garden
but they also have a very well developed
research program at the morton arboretum
and they focus on a broad number of
disciplines
from plant systematics some of our more
traditional research we'd find in
gardens to forest ecology
actually robert fahey bob fahey who's
the son of tim fey he's who some folks
might be familiar with and natural
resources works there they also focus on
plant conservation arboriculture root
biology
and the lab i was most interested in
working with was the urban soils lab
so dr bryant sharon brock heads up the
mass soil science laboratory and what
makes their lab a little bit interesting
is they have a number of different
areas of research interest but they
really focus on urban soils and urban
ecosystems as their central focus
such as in urban ecology and
biochemistry and assessment and
remediation of urban soils they also do
some focus on forest management as well
as prairie studies and these two kind of
last two areas the prairie ecology and
forest management
are is actually a lot of the research
that gets done physically on the grounds
of the morton arboretum so that's
something has something that makes them
a little different as well is that they
use their landscape and view their
landscape as a living laboratory
and to give a kind of overview of of
what bryant's lab looks like because it
is a little different than what we tend
to see
in the academic setting is that bryant
has been there for five years
he's done he's published 12 publications
and done 53 presentations at this point
but one of the major differences is that
there's only two employees in the lab
his lab manager and himself
and he's works with graduate students
but not specifically as chairs for
committees more kind of tangentially
like the way he's worked with me
and he does sit on some committees but
where he kind of makes up the difference
in productivity that graduate students
will bring to a lab is in his use of
volunteers so in five years he's used
his hat ended up having over 150
volunteers in his lab as well as 41
interns it appears
yeah and he'll enlist he'll enlist
anyone that he can including his
children um to do lab work
um
and this is something that is you know
volunteers are something that botanic
gardens heavily used to to help fulfill
their work and their missions and this
is just one example because it's an
interesting one of how his lab can still
be very productive but in a slightly
different context than what we may be
familiar with
so jumping into urban soils which is
going to be what we talked about for the
remainder of this talk i'm going to read
this definition because i think it
really sums up what urban soils are
urban soils are non-agricultural
man-made surface layer more than 50
centimeters thick that have been
produced by a mixing filling or
contamination
of land in urban or suburban areas so
really what we're talking about here is
we're talking about soils that aren't
agricultural aren't found in a natural
ecosystem and typically in one way or
another are adversely or are impacted by
human use or human presence
and why is this an important area of
study
it's important in area study
particularly in the united states
because in the next 40 years we're
projected to have five percent more
urban areas in the united states alone
and humans have unique impacts
that alter the soil's biogeochemical
processes and really make them a
distinct and unique system
so in surveys of urban soils that have
been done
we tend to see a suite of
characteristics that we will find such
as high bulk densities decreases in
organic matter poor structure
high ph
low water holding capacity
decrease in aggregate stability
inadequate soil depth for root growth
and a decrease in microbial biomass
so when i was at the morton arboretum i
specifically helped out with the chicago
urban forestry study
and the chicago urban forestry study
was a joint study between the morton
arboretum and the u.s department of
agriculture
and there was two main pis on it it was
bryant sharon brock in the urban soil
science lab as well as bob fahey in
forest ecology i'm primarily going to be
talking about this first area
the second area
robert fahey was mostly looking using
dendrochronology techniques to look at
how the urban forest was responding to
uh different differences in
different climatic events so
particularly drought he wanted to see
how the forest is responding to that
and the justification for the study is
that there had been no comprehensive
study of carbon storage that had been
conducted in an urban system based on
different land use types
and then looking at the soils both in a
shallow 20 centimeters as well as deep
up to a meter in depth in some places
deeper than that even
and this is important because in the
urban environment
soils themselves make up the single
largest terrestrial sink of carbon with
up to 64
followed by vegetation which are two
factors that we considered in the study
so looking at about eighty four percent
of all the carbon that cycles in the
urban system
and the study that was conducted in two
thousand by jogobi and jackson they
looked at uh three different natural
land
ecosystems land types and looked at how
carbon was distributed within the top
centimeter of soil based on these three
three land types and what they found
from this initial study was that in
troubling
you had a larger percentage of carbon
distributed in the deeper part of your
soils
on one end of the spectrum while in
forest and forest lands you ended up
with carbon primarily in your top 20
centimeters of soil
and this was mostly explained in the
shrubland systems as by how deep the
roots were going and turning over in the
soil and with the forest like in
deciduous forests with leaves or coarse
woody debris accumulating you find a
higher carbon in the in the top 20
centimeters so
brian kind of looked at this idea
and and thought about where he could
where he could move forward with it and
the two types of carbon that we wanted
to look at in these systems were organic
carbon as most people will be familiar
with or carbon that's derived from a
living source either plant or animal and
living in dead microorganisms
but he also wanted to look at inorganic
carbon which in soils typically reforms
to carbon found in a carbonate form
which is derived from mineral parent
material and
in urban systems in particular organic
inorganic carbon is is more of a
question of protection than is about
sequestration
with all the disturbances that go on
urban ecosystems by
exposing these inorganic carbon
deposits you can actually create a
source for carbon into the atmosphere
versus a sink as we may think about with
our organic carbon
so there's a number of factors in
particular that affect carbon cycling
within these soils and what i want to
point out here is that all the ones that
i put stars next to so from here on down
are different factors that can be
affected by land management or by
just how we we use our land our presence
on it
and so carbon cycling within the shallow
part of our soil is primarily derived
from organic carbon we see high rates of
turnover here
and these are sensitive to human
management and typically found in your
organic or your a horizons
we're deeper beyond 20 centimeters it's
a slower turnover rate you find more of
your inorganic carbon sources
and you can also find organic sources
and this is where you start to find your
a horizons your e horizons
and your b horizons as well
so to understand the framework of how
the moon arboretum wanted to construct
the study looking at carbon based on
land use they they went back to a study
that was conducted in 2010 also
supported by the morton arboretum
in 2010 the morning arboretum conducted
a tree census of the chicagoland region
and what the tree census was is they
selected the seven counties around
chicago as well as the city itself
and they generated 2076 random plots
they went out to each of these plots and
they looked at
the characterized plots based on two
sets of criteria they looked at the plot
formation so what was the land being
used for
as well as percent tree cover shrub
cover
and the shrub species and then also when
they found trees they would look at the
trees specifically they would
characterize the species the stem
diameter
tree height crown height and its general
health how much missing foliage or
dieback had occurred
crown light exposure and as well as
distance to infrastructure or other
buildings and they took all this
information
and they put it they used it in the i
tree model which for people who aren't
familiar with this is a model created by
the usda and used by urban foresters or
city planners to quantify the structure
of urban forests within a municipality
town
and what this model does is one it gives
us a breakdown of all the different
species and and how much
canopy cover perhaps you're finding
within within your city but it also puts
terms
it puts the in terms of ecosystem
services derived in a monetary value as
it can be a way to justify having an
urban forest and maintaining it and
diversifying it
so they use this model and created all
this data and so bryant took this
information and they decided to
for this carbon study to take a subset
of these different land use types
so
these are all the different land use
types that we looked at
in the greater chicagoland region that
we wanted to assess for carbon cycling
in those systems
so we took a number of different types
of samples we took deep samples using
this it's hard to see in this picture
a large soil sampler that takes samples
down to a meter in depth we took shallow
samples down to 20 centimeters
as well as our litter layer whatever was
primarily on the top of the soil
and we brought these back to the lab and
based on we look at each of the deep
soil profiles based on horizons and
characterize them based on color
ph
texture
bulk density soil moisture
we would also take our litter extracted
and we would set them up and extract any
of the invertebrates
as maybe an additional part of the study
that they'll be looking at in the future
so we looked at carbon in three
different ways
we looked at our inorganic and organic
carbon with elemental analysis and gas
chromatography and we looked at our
organic carbon particularly in two ways
one is particular organic matter and the
other one is using active carbon i'm
going to talk about these these two
tests
so particular organic matter
is a way of quantifying and looking at
organic matter based on size so what you
do is you you take your organic matter
and divide it from your your sand silts
and your clays and you fraction them
into different size classes
each of these signs there's four
different size classes three are
represented here the other one being
smallest organic matter that's
associated with your salt your silts and
your clays your organomineral complex
organic matter and the theory goes is
that the the
the depending on the different size
classes each size class has a different
residency time in the soil
with anywhere from our litter soil
organic matter for being yes less than a
year
or or to our organomineral complexed
organic matter being anywhere from 400
to a thousand years
bryant had done our previous study in
the past where he where he looked at
time since disturbance of sites so how
long it had been since a site had been
in an urban ecosystem had been kind of
created or established and looked at a
particular organic matter and found that
this course
particular organic matter particularly
on the one to two years was a very good
indicator for
microbial biomass microbial biomass
carbon as well as nitrogen
mineralization so this information
if you
could be helped to use and figure out
nitrogen
calculations for street trees is the
three one so this is one way of looking
at or organic matter that the sharon
brock lab is very very fond of and the
other technique that we used was the
active carbon test
so for folks who are familiar with the
soil health test here at cornell this is
the preferred method that they use it's
a potassium permanganate oxidation
process and this has really started to
become in favor for looking at our
uh our labile organic matter our organic
matter that turns over quickly in the
soil because it's really easy to conduct
it's on a colorimetric scale
and they've known that it's sensitive to
changes in management techniques
so
we see that it correlates well with
basal respiration
aggregation and microbial biomass
and so all this information that the
sharon brock work lab is working on is
going to be
cycled into the i-tree model itself and
used to build a carbon model for soils
based on land use type
just like the i-tree model had been used
to create ecosystem services
for above-ground biomass
so that about sums up the work that i
did at the morton arboretum or was
involved with and i'm going to
transition now
to talk
about the research i've been doing while
i've been at cornell
so for folks
that saw me spoke earlier this year what
i've been working on while i've been
here i've been working in neenah basic
and don rakow and harold van ness on the
scoop and dump technique of soil
remediation
and this technique is
pretty much just what it sounds
we we come in we take compost we put it
on impacted soils or compacted soils at
a rate of six to eight inches and then
we come in with a backhoe physically
lift it up
and drop it
and what this creates is a heterogeneous
soil mixture that landscape plants can
be directly planted into
and then after that after the planting
mulch is added every year as you would
find in most
landscaping contexts
and this technique was developed based
on
two kind of studies the first one being
a study done in 1991 by kai rolfe who
came in without adding organic matter
just using a backhoe to physically
fracture soils and what he found when he
did this looking at soil quality he
found that soil bulk density decreased
that poor volume increase and soil
resistance so using a pentrometer in
that soil also decreased
secondly a study done finished up in
2007 by nina basic and angela
rivenshield looked at using different
types of organic amendments and seeing
how those affected
soil bulk densities and soil porosities
and that's how we came up with using
this uh 33 organic matter as an ideal
amendment
so the scoop and dump technique has had
a legacy of practice on the cornell
campus for we're going on to year 14 now
at this point
every year in neenah basics creating the
urban eating class the this is a
year-long course and site establishment
of plants and woody plant id
the the class will design create and
install a new garden
and
we had been doing this technique for
more than 12 years when i started for 12
years when i started and it has been
used to restore sites such as some
people will recognize this this is
outside of mann library when it was
under construction
and severely impacted soils
were
occurred during this process
and here's a picture taken even a couple
years ago of what the landscape looks
like now
and another one so we we had seen that
anecdotally we knew it was working we
had some some research to back it up but
we wanted to take it another step
further and really see what the changes
in soil quality had occurred
based on using this technique
so in the first part of our study
we selected six sites representing 12
years
to be studied for our in our scoop and
dump soils and we selected four sites
that were in close proximity to our
study sites that had gone through
similar disturbance regimes
and could be used as a control or as a
contrast
and we used the soil health test to look
at physical biological
and chemical aspects of the soil in our
initial study
and the way we sampled is we would we
would dig into our scoop and dump soil
and we would sample that and then we'd
go below our scoop and dump layer
into our subsoil
and we'd also sample that and then for
our controls at we would take samples at
equal depths to our scoop and dump as
well as our subsoils
so looking at
soil resistance so coming in with a with
a calibrated penetrometer and doing it
all shortly after rainfall so very close
to field capacity for soil moisture
we saw that in our scoop and dump soils
that we started to see root limiting psi
or root limiting resistance i should say
in our scoop and dump soil right around
25 centimeters in depth
compared to our unamended soils we found
them right around nine centimeters in
depth so about a three-fold increase in
available root
depth
that we are finding in our remediated
sites
as i mentioned we look at this study in
two ways we looked at it in a
compare and contrast with our
unremediated to our immediate sites we
also looked at it over time since we've
been doing this practice for years
and over time we saw that
bulk density decreased over time
with your zero being over here
we also noticed that our or we found
that our potentially mineralizable
nitrogen
had increased over time
as well as our active carbon
and this was exciting to see and
certainly make sense with the
potentially mineralizable nitrogen
active carbon active carbon being a food
source for soil microorganisms
and
organisms that are involved in nitrogen
mineralization with the potentially
mineralizable nitrogen increases we see
and the the aggregate or sorry the bulk
density increase was also exciting to
see particularly with our increase in
aggregate stability we were saying that
we were
creating lower bulk density soils but
they were also being maintained by this
improvement in structure improvement in
pore space
so to summarize the other findings we
found from this initial study
we found also increased aggregate
stability
we found increased available water
holding capacity
increased total organic matter
increased potentially mineralizable
nitrogen
bulk densities
as well as active carbon
and this is kind of a common scene of
what we would find in many of our sites
this site had only been installed one
year when we looked at it but this is a
profile difference between our scoop and
dump soils compared to the subsoil and
you can see you know we found this all
across the site that once we get down to
that subsoil which had higher bulk
densities typically we would see the
roots just start to move sideways
instead of continuing to move down
so we took all this information and we
wanted to
think about how plants were grown in
this type of environment and do a study
to follow up what we learned in our
first section
so with that we came up with a soil
container study we wanted to conduct
to look at how the plants
how plants themselves would respond to
these different soil mediums
so
we
hypothesize that plants grown in the
scoop and dump soil
will have increased biomass and this
increased biomass will be correlated
with our reduced bulk density our
improved bulk density
and then we also hypothesized that
because of our increased water holding
capacity the plants growing in our scoop
and dump soil would have a
better capability of of dealing with
drought
particularly in stone model conductance
as well as photosynthesis
compared to our unamended soils
so we took a subset
of the sites we used before we selected
three sites
and we selected three controls that went
along with them and we went out into the
landscape
and we took large pvc cores
and
and in in this case we used a how to use
a backhoe to drive these into the ground
and pull them up
and this is the best available technique
we have getting as close to undisturbed
soil samples as as possible
perhaps a slight over estimate but it's
the best we work with
we didn't have to use a backhoe in our
scoop and dump sites because the bulk
density was decreased so it's a little
easier to sample
and so we selected a woody plant to
grow in them we selected ficus benjamina
and we wanted to use we ended up using
ficus bender mono one because it's known
in tropical regions of the world for
being a street tree
as we can see in this picture here
and we also want to use it to get around
the winter dormancy issue if we had
selected a north american temperate
species which would have been ideal but
we were working over the winter so
so we selected ficus benjamin evergreen
and had tissue cultured plants donated
to us from
sunshine horticulture in florida
all very pretty consistent size when we
got them
so we collected these soils outside we
brought them into the greenhouse for a
short period
and planted the ficus directly into the
different types of soils
and shortly after that we moved them
into growth chambers
and allowed them to grow for three and a
half months before we decided to conduct
our drought study
in the end we ended up using 15 soils
that had been remediated and 15 soils
that
had been remediated of the scoop and
dump in 15 that had not been remediated
for our study and we subjected them to a
period of 26 days of drought
and before we started the study what we
did is we got the plants up to field
capacity so we brought them up to a high
point of water holding and then let them
drain and then wrap them in bags so that
really all the only water that would be
lost is through transpiration and not
evaporation
so our measurements that we wanted to
look at in the study were root and shoot
biomass
total leaf area
and leaf water potential at pre-dawn
and the the soils characteristics that
we wanted to look at were gravimetric
water content volumetric water content
and texture water holding capacity total
organic matter
and bulk density
in terms of gas exchange we looked at
photosynthesis
as well as stone model conductance
so what we ended up finding from our
study
was that our leaf area in our scoop and
dump soils over here was was greatly
increased now almost
two-fold compared to our unamended soils
so much more leaf area
we found that our root dry weight was
significantly increased in our scoop and
dump soils compared to our unamended
soils
as well as our shoot dry weight was
significantly higher in our scoop and
dump soils compared to our unamended
soils
we also looked at bulk density
since this has been a major question of
our study
and we found that in our scoop and dump
soils
they were significantly lower than our
unamended
and for folks that aren't familiar bulk
density bulk density is a measurement of
weight over volume so grams per
centimeter cubed
and
a study done by data on warrington had
established a relationship between
different textural classes and root
limiting bulk densities and what they
found is that for your sands you can get
up to bulk density is around 1.75 grams
per centimeters cubed before you end up
finding reduced bulk densities and for
silts and clays it's around 1.4
so considering
again that our scoop and dump soils were
well below this 1.4 threshold was very
good to see and then our unamended soils
are definitely getting into the range of
root limiting bulk densities and we
don't have the textures back from our
study yet
but we'll be able to look at those
compared to these once those final tests
are completed
so we did our linear regression looking
at our dry weight shoots with our bulk
densities and we see a clear
relationship here
and if we overlay this with our
different types of treatments our scoop
and dump soils on the left here
and our are unamended we see a clear
relationship between the bulk density
and
this improved scoop and dump creating
allowing for more shoots to be grown and
this line here represents root limiting
bulk density
really strikingly
kind of cutting them right down the
middle there
so we saw this relationship as well with
our roots
here's with the overlay again
and we also saw this relationship
with our
leaf area
and again with this overlay
and so when we destructively harvested
these we obviously noticed certainly a
much larger volume of roots in our scoop
and dump comparatively to our unamended
soils
but one pattern that was very consistent
here are pictures from our unamended
sites was you can see from how i'm
holding up these roots right here
is that in our unamended soils
right here is kind of where we we
planted where the plug was that we
planted into the soils themselves and a
very consistent pattern where the roots
growing up across the top and then
escaping down the sides of the
containers right down here in an area
that had perhaps a little extra space in
it or did not have the same type of bulk
density as we found in the soil so this
was a very very consistent pattern and
um one that's interesting to think about
as we you know if we since we did this
in containers in the landscape roots
probably wouldn't have this they
certainly wouldn't have this container a
reduced area where they'd be able to go
down so we actually think that our roots
are a bit of an overestimate compared to
our scoop and dump
it was also very interesting to look at
the root exploration in our scoop and
dump soils we really saw that our roots
were really exploring and taking
advantage of this increased structure
with our aggregate stability
and able to find those poor spaces and
really work their way through and it was
interesting pulling them apart because
it would take a lot more work to break
up the aggregates and actually
free the roots from the system
compared to in our unamended soils where
pretty much you'd start to break it
apart and the soils would just all fall
away the plant was not holding very much
onto them
because of this decrease in structure
and root exploration throughout the
soils
so looking at our leaf water potentials
this is days of drought on the bottom
here
we see that
as in both the unamended and the scoop
and dump soils that that really there
wasn't much different in how these
plants were responding to drought in
terms of leaf water potentials and we
certainly saw a strong spike after day
of our potential starting to get really
negative at this point
and this was a fairly consistent pattern
that we saw with our photosynthetic rate
and our gas exchange measurements as
well
where both the plants there was no
significant differences in over the
course of the dry down experiment
showing a difference in photosynthetic
rate
as well as
stone model conductance
was also
had no significant differences between
the two
and
we started to think about this and look
at this we also looked at like i said
water loss of the soils themselves over
time
and the red up here is scoop and dump
soils and the blue is unamended and this
is a cumulative water loss over time
and with this what we see is that uh the
scuba dump soils
did in fact hold and lose more water
compared to or unamended which was
cooperated with our available increase
in available water holding capacity
where we lost uh
0.098 kilograms of water over the course
of 26 days well about a little more than
half of that
in our unamended soils just 0.65
kilograms of water loss
and looking at our
water loss between days we also saw that
as there were significant differences
between days 1 and day 6 16 in terms of
amount of water loss between days with
our scoop and dump soils losing more
water compared to our unamended and then
that
that difference no longer occurs after
day 21 and day 26.
and so looking at all this it it starts
to make more sense that even though our
scoop and dump soils held more water and
we did see an increase in both root
growth as well as total leaf area that
there was a increase in stomatal
conductance and increasing in
transpiration which really seemed to
explain driving this pattern between our
different soil amendments
and
with that i'd like to thank my committee
and everyone else who's been a part of
my research progress here as well as the
morton arboretum and i'm happy to answer
any questions
i just wanted to make sure i was
understanding i said it seemed to me
like you had two types of comparisons in
your um study of the scoop and up so so
one was the
unamended versus the scoop and done but
then also the scoop and dumps against
each other over time
so so okay
it was so quick that i didn't quite
catch it so you saw
increasing potentially mineralizable
nitrogen and active carbon and
decreasing bulk density the longer over
time oh that's so interesting so
um so what what do you make of that
well i think the
the bulk density certainly makes sense
with with you know the previous work
that kind of all had done in terms of
loosening the soil and maintaining
that that loose as well creating more
pore space and
it also you know thinking about the
increased in aggregate stability
once the soil had been loosened and
aggregates are starting to form that
increase in structure
certainly makes sense in terms of
holding more horse space between the
different aggregates and creating a less
bulk
environment in terms of the
active carbon
i think that was trying to make sense
with the huge amount of organic matter
that we input initially as well as the
continuum
or more
preferential for microbes to live so
over time as we continue to add more
organic matter
so it kind of seems like that initial
remediation like sets of motion kind of
a virtuous cycle like once you have
better aggregation it can
sequester more carbon
yeah oh cause i mean i would expect the
immediate difference between the two
treatments but that increase over time
is very interesting well that's
something that you do tend to see also
in
like i mentioned the study that brian
and chairman before we looked at time
since disturbance
that um
after
uh
around 25 years you start to see
soils start to cycle back and have a
natural adaptive cycle so even without
doing too much to your landscape you end
up with
soils without having to you know drink
something
um i have a question about the
that same part of your study so
did you have the same species in all
these landscapes so clearly your plant
material would affect your soil
characteristics as well particularly if
that landscape has been established for
some period of time so were you always
sampling near the same species or in an
area with no plants or how did that work
we totally
we ran transects through our plots and
then went at certain intervals to reach
one so we weren't as conscious of
looking at individual species
this first study was more of just a
survey to look at what you know really
what the changes in storm quality have
been and so looking at it in a more
efficient comment you know
13 14 years ago retrospectively
every year
one single species and all of that
but
we we didn't do that so we didn't quite
have enough and that was something that
we didn't think about trying to look at
in terms of
looking at some of the plant responses
since they all received received very
similar management over the years but we
couldn't find any selections that were
the same because part of the reason we
create these last tips is to create
diverse
learning opportunities for students in
the class
so
you know and maybe a more traditional
context of what we have on the point we
could be better same species that we
find in our
in our kind of normal landscapes outside
of
uh the things in the dump soil had
higher transpiration rates and larger
leaves why wasn't the water potential
lower
and why wasn't photosynthesis low
you're drawing more water on tan yeah i
mean for
you know well i think it makes sense if
we think about the total beef area
in terms of stomatal conductance at
least we had greater leaf area in our
scuba dub soils almost twice as much so
that was driving transpiration
what should have blown off more water
and make the soil drier
right
but okay so our oil but our soils had
more
even so even though they had more meat
area um we had higher water holding
capacities in our dumb soils
so
yeah
so i had a question on a totally
different topic that you also touched on
so you talked about the importance of
volunteers in the botanical gardens
research and i'm really interested to
know what you think about um
if and how um the principal
investigators in context like that can
create a valuable kind of educational
and or professional development
experience for those volunteers for
those volunteers i mean i can see how it
could be
you know very much a kind of front work
thing
where you don't get much out of it but i
can also see how you could shape it to
be something really transformative yeah
and that was interesting about brian's
lab in particular because of all the
labs at the morning routine he took
advantage of volunteers like everybody
else and the type of people that
volunteered were really across the board
from
um you know like he got his kids in
there maybe they didn't volunteer
from from people who are in you know
college looking to gain experience too
you know he had retired chemists in this
lab
and just wanted to do you know do
something with their time and take their
skill and put it to put it to use and so
for him it's become a very effective
tool and also he's
he's been able to tap into a lot of
resources and because of having these
people with
such depth of knowledge
yeah i don't know exactly but it's it
isn't it's a it's a you know at botanic
gardens there's this kind of nutrition
in the history of the fact
you know i've tried to think about how
to how to apply it into other contexts
because potential articles are mission
based organizations that people are used
to
and visiting and having a kind of
experience that and it's a little
different than what we see in the
academics so it'd be great to see the
campaign
thank you very
this has been a production of cornell
university on the web at cornell.edu