This is a production of Cornell University
&gt;&gt; As Nina just demonstrated,
soils are composed of
different percentages of different size particles,
sand, silt, and clay.
We have a technique we can demonstrate now that will give us
an approximation of those representative percentages.
Those percentages are indicated on the USDA texture triangle,
which we also have with us here.
This technique that's going to give us
an approximation of the percentages,
is going to give us an indication of the soil texture.
By running through this flow chart here,
we're going to end up with
a rough estimation of the texture of these two samples of soil.
We have two samples here and I'm going to
start with this one here.
We're just going to run through the process on our flowchart.
It starts with taking a small amount of the soil in the hand.
This is soil texture by feel or by
hand and we're going to sort the soil a little bit,
removing sticks and stones,
elements larger than the largest particle of sand
that do not form part of the overall textural composition.
I'm just pulling out the stones,
some of these are just large particles
of soil that are glued together.
I'm just going to remove those.
I'm trying to get down here to the basic composition of soil here.
I'm just sieving them out, filtering them out.
That's pieces of gravel here.
Once I have what is pretty much just the soil left,
these are just field soils,
just dug, I'm going to wet the sample.
I'll place just a couple drops
and the goal here is to form a ball.
I want to get a ball of soil
that's roughly putty-like in consistency,
something that holds together.
I'm just trying to keep wetting until we
get there. A little more soil.
We want a little golf ball size
so we have enough to run our diagnostic on.
I'm mixing it in my hand.
What we're going for here is we want the soil to form a ball.
This is the first part of the test,
if it will form a ball.
There we go. We're pretty close. Little more.
You know you're just about there when your hands are covered in dirt.
Now reading through our flowchart,
the first question it'll ask is,
will the sample form a ball when squeezed?
I'm going to give it a little squeeze and it retains its shape.
If it then wants to just shatter and fall apart,
following through the diagnostic we end up
with that your sample is sand.
This is not just sand.
We move on.
Then the next part of this test is to try to form a ribbon.
The ability of the soil sample to form
a ribbon and hold it is going
to be a measure of the percentage of clay.
To form a ribbon, you can take the sample
in the palm of your hand like this and you start to
squeeze and feed it out and you
want it to break naturally and fall to the table.
There it goes. You do that a couple
times and each time estimating the length.
Here we have about three-quarters of an inch.
Put it back into a ball form.
It's dried out a little bit in my hand.
Feed it a little more water.
We don't want water to be squeezed out.
I'm going back to forming a ribbon,
squeezing it out, and so this time we had about an inch.
We'll just do one more ribbon.
And we'll take the average of the three.
There it goes. It shattered when it hit,
but just under an inch.
Now following through our flowchart here,
diagram and reading, yes,
we have a ball and the ribbon formation,
we had an inch or less so we're in the loam category.
The next part of the test is to estimate
the percentage of grit or sand in the sample.
I'll take little bit of it,
put the rest aside.  About teaspoon or two
here and I'm going to wet it in the palm of my hand.
This process is intended to flatten it out.
Estimate the percentage of sand
as a factor of how gritty the soil sample feels.
The diagram asks us,
does the sample feel very gritty,
equally gritty and smooth, or very smooth?
Just going to give an estimation here.
It's somewhat gritty and somewhat smooth.
It feels somewhere in the middle.
The diagnostic has led us to the conclusion then
that this sample is a loam,
and so I'm going to listen to
the sample and see if I can hear the sound of the grit rubbing.
Yeah, and I can hear it just a little bit.
It's somewhere between a loam and a sandy loam then.
If we turn to the texture triangle,
we can actually then convert that diagnosis
into percentages of the various particle sizes.
Reading here, we have
a sandy loam being
composed of something around 20 percent clay max,
and somewhere between 70 to 50 percent sand
and a loam being as low as 30 percent sand.
We're probably somewhere down in
that 30 to 40 percent range below sandy loam.
Let's try the next sample.
By appearance alone, there's not really much we can tell.
There's no way to visually
distinguish these two soils in terms of their texture here.
But by running through this soil texture by feel,
we should be able to make some conclusions.
Let's make sure we get all the last sample off.
Again, we're going to sort the sample
a little bit, remove some roots,
make sure it's sufficient quantity there to get
our ribbon and wetting the soil.
Little more, it's still not quite consolidating.
Little bit more. Yeah, that's
trying to form a little film on my hands so we should be there.
You don't want to oversaturate it.
Going back to our flowchart,
the first diagnostic is to see if the sample will form
a ball and here we have
a nice ball and under a little pressure from the finger,
it doesn't fall part,
doesn't shatter so we know we don't have
a sand sample as we suspected.
Give it a little squeeze.
Stays together, stays put so it's not a sand or a loamy sand.
We're going to move down into the next step,
which is the ribbon forming process and
get teed up in my hand and start feeding it out.
Right away I can tell that it's forming a longer ribbon.
This one broke when it hit,
but there we have maybe an inch and quarter.
Run that three times.
I'm just going to let it naturally just feed
over my forefinger until it wants to fall.
There may be almost two inches.
Just one last sample.
Maybe
about an inch
and a half average, just under that.
Reading across, we've gotten into the clay loam category.
Now we need to estimate the amount of grit in the sample.
I'm going to take a small portion of it in the palm of
my hand and re-wet it in order to form a film,
so I get a sense of the percentage here.
Recalling that this relates back to
the percentages of the various particles in the texture triangle.
Already I can tell there's just some grit there certainly,
but I'm not feeling as much as
the previous sample at all and I'm listening.
There's a little bit of sound of friction,
but not a lot.
Certainly less than half
so we're more on the smooth side of this one.
Reading down somewhere between
clay loam and a silty clay loam so let's see,
going over here to texture triangle,
finding a clay loam here and a silty clay loam here,
we can tell then that somewhere between 30 to 40 percent clay.
We didn't move the percentage of clay very far but it definitely
changed the characteristic qualities of the texture of the soil.
It becomes more smooth,
more capable of forming a longer ribbon,
with just a little bit more clay,
and then just that small amount of
adjustment change this soil texture for us, our diagnostic.