this is a production of Cornell
University there we go um so I'm really
excited to share this project with you
all today um especially as um I'm here
with plant scientists and
horticulturists and experts in
greenhouse and high tunnels um as you'll
see why that's important um uh to use
those things to help us educate about
climate change and um ultimately we're
hoping our goal is to have a positive
impact but we want to do something a
little bit different um so I'm the lucky
one who gets to speak to you today but I
have two collaborators um actually I
have lots of collaborators on this
project and I'm going to highlight them
all at the end but here's a few of us
here at the site but key to this effort
um has been Chris wean who um has now
left the project unfortunately but we
keep drawing trying to draw him back in
as often as we can and then Josh Sarah
from landscape architecture who uh the
three of us um served as the principal
investigators when we started um putting
this project together and are Josh and I
are continuing to work on this with a
host of other
folks so um before I tell you about the
garden itself I wanted to give you a
little background at least from where we
were working from so you have some
context
for uh where we were coming from and
what we were trying to do and as I think
most of us are aware we um climate
change is one of the biggest challenges
that we're facing and this is a slide
that I pulled from NASA when I was
initially preparing this when they were
saying that January has broken all
records um that has quickly been uh
eclipsed by all the records set in
February for being the hottest uh let me
make sure I say this right
the most anomalous warm month ever
recorded So February broke all of
January's records so we know that this
is an issue and there's lots of
scientists on campus who are working on
this um but what we also know is that as
the public there's um a disconnect
between the knowledge that we have about
climate change and our willingness to do
something about
it so in talking about in looking at
what other Gardens were doing
so plantations as the public garden of
Cornell we wanted to know what was
happening out there and a lot of work uh
has been done on plant conservation
efforts specifically and looking at um
how we conserve plants either in insitu
or
exitu programs um two of the recent ones
that have just been released is the New
England wildf flower Society recently
put out this habitat based approach when
they profiled their five key habitats
for the Northeast region and and are
discuss the environmental issues that
are facing each habitat and um
discussing the impacts of stressor such
as climate change are likely to have on
those an international organization
called Botanic Gardens conservation
International is looking
at um climate change on Plants the
impacts on plants and their ecosystems
or at the cellular level and this report
uh lists how the impact of climate
change will affect animals AFF humans
who depend on them but also provid some
recommendations for how to Stave off
Extinction or to work towards these
um issues that are being
faced probably the most predominant way
that public gardens are educating about
climate change is through phology
studies and looking at things like
project Bud burst or project Bud break
and um they're doing it in a few ways
one is by using their own plant records
which Public Gardens are well known to
have very detailed and accurate records
and a lot of gardens are using these
records to record the times of first
Leaf out and the first bed Break um but
they're also now looking at installing
plants uh on a what called a
phenological monitoring garden and
looking specifically at specific kinds
of plants and how they're flowering at
different times and then they're also
involved in uh citizen science efforts
which train volunteers staff uh school
children to go out and record the date
of first Bud break or Leaf break within
their
communities and then the other way that
um we're familiar with were are um ways
in which Gardens are
interpreting P climate change and their
outreach program so in terms of
interpretation the American public
garden Association is working to develop
a set of templates that are based on the
most recent climate science about
climate change um providing information
that Gardens can develop their own
interpretive tools for or there are
Outreach programs such as the community
climate action program at the Chicago
Botanic Garden which takes slightly
different approach and goes out into
communities and works with groups that
are traditionally not represented in the
climate change programs and they go into
the community they work with these
Community groups on issues that they're
facing that are related or are the
result of Cl climate change and look to
find assets that this community can use
to solve problems and so are really
taking it at a community level approach
and then there are educational Outreach
efforts such as the fair child challenge
which is out of a fair child tropical
banic garden in Miami that is uh K
through 12 environmental science
competition and many of the topics that
are addressed in that um through art and
literature
through debates um are focused on
climate
change so um in looking and trying to
find out if anybody else is doing
something called a climate change Garden
we came across this effort at Syracuse
University and in 2014 they installed
what they're calling a climate change
Garden that will track how plants will
adapt to global warming and they planted
33 different species of trees and shrubs
some of which are adapted to Central New
York and some which are adapted to
warmer regions and they will be
monitoring the to see if there are any
changes in health and the Vitality of
these
species
so I'll also share that uh the executive
director of the American public garden
Association saw what
we see and feel and that is that public
gardens really are uniquely positioned
to be as he says the place to learn
about and experience climate change and
that public gardens are places where
visitors can make local connections to
the global issue and this was something
that um really is something that we were
very interested in that we didn't we
appreciated the phenological studies and
the phenological monitoring Gardens and
the Outreach efforts in fact we're
trying to partner with the Chicago
Botanic Garden on that community-based
asset approach that I described but what
we were looking for was something that
was demonstrative that was experiential
that was interactive it was compelling
to visitors that somehow gave them a
sense of what climate change um
is expected to do and what impacts it
would have locally and in looking at
this and in going through the project
for a couple of years um we recently
came across a paper from uh perspectives
on psychological science that was
written to address how public engage we
can improve public engagement in policy
efforts toward climate change and just
briefly I thought I would share some of
these because they are in line with some
of the things that we're trying to do
and some of the goals that we have which
is that um we value experience over
analysis so a lot of the climate science
that's put out there a lot of what's
seen in the media a lot of the articles
that are written or even interpretation
we're seeing at Public Gardens is very
analytical we're putting lots of
Statistics out but as individuals um we
do have an analytical side of our brain
but we also um we react to our gut and
so if there was an opportunity to really
highlight relevant experiences how
people may be experiencing current
effects of climate change or are seeing
patterns to build on that the other one
that really jumped out was this out of
sight out of mind and I think we may
have all experienced this in this that
climate change is some future phenomenon
it's not going to happen in our lifetime
and it's happening across the world to
somebody else other than ourselves and
so how do we make that how do we change
that perception and one of their
recommendations is to emphasize what's
happening now and what's happening at a
local and Regional level and the last
one which I didn't highlight here but I
think is really important is this um
idea of how we are motivated to act and
we are either motivated at an inst
extrinsic level you know there's some
carrot there waiting for us or from an
intrinsic level and what their study
found is that there is this deeply held
motivation that we have intrinsically to
want to make the world a better place so
they recommended tapping into that
somehow so we haven't quite figured out
now but we'll come back to
that so what we decided to do was come
up with what we are calling a cre
creative experiment and it's not a true
experiment in the way that we're all
used to thinking about control and
experimental but really we wanted to
figure out if we could create a garden
or some kind of experience within a
garden that would inform visitors about
climate change would physically
demonstrate what we might expect um in
some future not too distant future um
that would use plants as a lens to
communicate what these impacts are
likely to um to look like and that gave
visitors some way to really experience
this and even to interact with um these
changes that we are
seeing so we've um came up with a way to
do this and our approach was to um look
at it with from an environmental control
standpoint a plant response standpoint a
visitor response standpoint so the
environment Al controls this is where
Chris ween came in and his love of high
tunnels he said you guys at plantations
need a high tunnel and so that's kind of
where we started um but really he was he
was advocating not just for us to have a
high tunnel but that he felt that it
could be a tool to approximate F some of
the predicted future climate conditions
and then as horticulturists and as
gardeners and at a public garden we
really wanted to have plants as the lens
and wanted to see if we could find
plants that would show effects of
temperature and pre ation and could be
good communicators of what we're
expecting to see and then ultimately
we're doing this so that we can have
some impact on the visitors that come
through and you know at on a spectrum of
what we want to do from goals it's one
increasing their knowledge of and
concern of but for me it's always about
some intent to act some making that
world a better place and I think my
colleagues would agree with that so
enter the high tunnel and and we
received uh an initial Grant from the
toward sustainability Foundation to buy
a high tunnel and install it and so this
is uh was installed it's a 24x 20 and
12T high high tunnel um col covered with
um a poly ethene e film and while there
are lots of other devices some far more
expensive that can approximate more
accurately the effects of climate change
we were drawn to the high tunnel because
it's relatively inexpensive and we can
regulate temperature uh because of the
radiation and the ventilation and that
uh we could also control
irrigation so in addition to
constructing the high tunnel we also
constructed 12 raised beds 4x6 beds both
outside the garden outside the high
tunnel and inside the high
tunnel
and we in installed a tempature sensors
both inside and outside the tunnel this
we are using an onset computer model u30
hobo to take both the air temperature as
well as soil temperature and measuring
the active radiation during the growing
season and then what we set out to do
was to create what we we called the
garden of today um in the outside bed so
they would experience the temperatures
and the precipitation and the
temperature the climate changes of today
and then we wanted to approximate some
future climate and we selected The
Garden of 2050 and we did this for
several reasons one is when we in um
invited Jonathan Schult who is a
professor of communication to um work
with us on this project he was saying
you know you really need to put a date
on it otherwise it's that future distant
future it's never going to happen date
and that date of 2050 really gives us
something not too distant that we can um
understand 34 years is not that far away
hopefully many of us will still be alive
then our CH we can imagine our children
in this climate so um that was one
reason the other reason is that we are
using the nerta climate report and
within this report which is um full of
lots of good information but um in
particular there are climate models and
they're based on the 2020s the 50s the
2080s and the 2100s so we the this time
frame gave us um a clear model to work
from and this is the report that I just
mentioned and this is an assessment that
provides information on climate change
impacts specific for New York State and
even more specifically for various
regions and we are here in turn that on
as you can see in Region 3 and there are
climate projections for temperature
precipitation sea level rise heat waves
cold events intense precipitation
extreme events and storms so we were
using this
um report to uh get at those projections
so what are they um starting with
temperature that for the 2050s we are
expected to see an average annual
increase of between 4.4 and 6.3
de um there are expected to be an
increase in days over 90° fah um up to
days and we're going to have a greater
frequency and duration of heat waves so
3 to six consecutive days over 90
degrees or
more and we're expected to have five or
um three to six of those heat wve
durations lasting five or more
days and then our annual precipitation
is expected to increase by 4 to 10% now
this increase right now is looking at
winter that increase will happen
primarily over the winter and that
actually in this late Summer and the
fall there'll be a decrease in that
precipitation um and we're also expected
to have some increase in frequency and
intensity and duration of extreme
precipitation
events so looking at all those
projections um we started we installed
the Garden in 2014 and this is the
garden itself just to give you a sense
of where it's at it's located in the
botanic garden bowl of Plantation
it's in what's known as the pounder
garden and it sits within the southeast
corner of that
garden and um we spent the first year
primarily installing the high tunnel as
I showed you and getting the beds in and
um figuring we did minimal
interpretation we were having lots of
discussions about how we would interpret
it and um but in talking about the
plants we were very ambitious in this
first year and we selected six different
categories of plants to display
and walk you through those uh this first
one that's pictured here is uh a
temperate species that would have an
earlier and abbreviated growth period in
the high
tunnel um second bed was landscape
plants that would grow well in the high
tunnel but not be Hardy outside so as a
Southern girl I was really excited to
see this lacroma in there didn't last
very
long um and then uh having more
temperate species that would have an
earlier and abbreviated growth period
period unusual species of tropical
origin that would grow well outside in
but not um in the high
tunnel um no it would grow well in the
high tunnel but not so well outside and
these were things like okra peanuts
cotton Malibar
spinach and then we did a varieties of
peppers several different
varieties and then tender perennials
things that would grow well um in the
tunnel but not so well outside the
tunnel and this was an interesting
watching how um people interacted with
these plants was very interesting and
this this Garden this particular bed um
a couple of anecdotes both for myself
and for the student who is working in
there is that when people saw this they
were like climate change Bring it on I
can grow this here now they were really
excited so this when we're talking about
plants as Messengers a little bit later
we always come back to this one about
being being clear about what kind of
message we're um trying to convey
and then this is the interpretation we
had for the first year which was very
simply um a welcome sign mentioned a
little bit about the garden and what we
were trying to do there we did have a
brochure with a detachable survey and
invited folks to walk around and Inter
our idea is that they would interact
with the garden and tell us a little bit
about what they felt about the quality
of the plants inside and outside so the
flip of this had um an inside the tunnel
and asked them to rank and then had
these directed questions and we put out
surveys they were all gone at the end of
the season but we only received nine of
these uh detachable surveys back um and
from that we saw that these open-ended
questions didn't work so well people did
tend to fill in the the quality but not
so much on the on the open-ended
questions and then we had staff or our
we've had several interns work in the
garden and they documented their
observations uh both about the garden
but also about the visitors that were
there and the kinds of questions and
interaction that they
had so there were a couple of lessons
that we learned from this first year uh
that we've take we took on to for this
last year in
2015 and so as I mentioned it was we
really were getting started planting the
garden seeing how well it would work um
what we did see is that in the high
tunnel we were able to get um even
though it was not severely restricted in
terms of the ventilation uh we were able
to get an increase in the the
temperature higher inside the tunnel
than outside the tunnel and we also
observed differences in plant growth
inside and outside and um I just
mentioned to you about the visitor
survey results or lack thereof that we
got
and um but also probably one of the most
striking things was how people used the
site or didn't use the site and I'll try
so this is where that sign was that uh
the interpretive sign and with the
brochure but in order to get into the
garden you either had to go up this step
walk around this planting of corn and
bypass the high tunnel which everybody
wants to walk into at first or you had
to enter from some other part of the
Garden or jump up off this probably two
feet um retaining wall so it we weren't
really able to direct the experience and
how people moved through it and there
wasn't a lot of signage that said this
was the Garden of today this was the
Garden of
2050 so enter what we did last year
which was to um improve the visitor
experience and go into that first so
this is a fairly accurate rendition of
that was done by Maru Jabar who is a
student in landscape architecture to
really help us redesign The Experience
so that visitors understood what they
were coming into and what they were
seeing and with the exception of this
Arch which isn't in the garden we did
install some new steps so people could
come directly into the garden and then
we displayed a sequence of interpretive
messages um along with what we call
focused information tags in the garden
and just to give you a sense of what
that looked like um here at this first
space and this is what it looked like as
you walked up to it uh we tell you a
little bit about the garden itself a
little bit more about some of the
science behind it what we're hoping to
do in the garden very clearly say this
is the garden of today and this is the
garden of 2050 and give you some of
those Graphics that um student landscape
architecture helped us develop to convey
some of this information which if you
read it in a paragraph it's pretty hefty
um but she worked really hard with us to
graphically depict that so it was more
visible especially when you look at some
of the interpretation which um studies
that say most people spend maybe two
minutes if we're lucky looking at a
sign so then um before they enter the
garden we wanted to stop them and tell
them a little bit about the plants they
would be seeing in these Gardens
and when I mentioned we were very
ambitious about the plants that we had
in the first Year's Garden um what we
one of the things that our students saw
in her observations is that it was very
um daunting there were lots of plants to
look at and the messages and doing a
comparison between six different
categories and what ended up being 36
different plants was um pretty
overwhelming so we narrowed it down to
two categories of plants nectar resource
plants and vegetables and Grains and
then we tell them a little bit about why
we're interested in looking at these
plants and then we tell them a little
bit about um that there are these what
we call we call them focused information
tags we're trying to call out something
or Draw their attention to something or
get them to
interact and then when they get to the
back of the garden before they enter
into the garden of the future we wanted
to give them a chance to record some of
their observations so this is one of
those
and then before they enter into the high
tunnel we tell them about what they're
about to enter into so again we're using
some of those Graphics that were
developed to say what Does The Garden of
2050 look like what are you expected to
encounter and then we have this um
chalkboard where we can call attention
to what is happening within the garden
and so at this particular time we were
initiating a heat wave um trying to
trying to initiate a heat wave we um are
we we tried to be S uh follow the
projections and had six heat waves uh
over the course of the 2015
season and then finally as they exit
exit the garden we wanted to give them
some uh another opportunity
to share their observations so things
like
this and then give them a little uh give
them some way to learn about more about
the garden and then we gave them a
takeaway brochure which um is based in
large part on the work that David wolf
did in his chapter about gardening
sustainably and a changing climate and
he was very generous with this work to
um give our visitors something that they
could leave with that gave them some
tools to do
more um so the other thing that we tried
to do in addition to improving the
visitor experience was really to tune
the tunnel and in this case we um didn't
get quite the increase that we were
looking for in 2014 that was consistent
with the projections for
2050 um so we really wanted to figure
out how we could tune that tunnel to get
the temperature increase the average
annual temperature increase of 4.4 to
6.3 uh we also installed in 2014 we were
manually rolling up the sides of that
high tunnel to restrict the ventilation
to get the temperatures up and last year
we installed um so you see there's the
manual
um and when you have to do that a couple
of times a day it's not hard but it gets
gets to be a lot of work so we um
installed some we automated them and
I'll talk a little bit about that
Automation in in a few
minutes and then we really wanted to
figure out and test and identify plants
that could be our Messengers and whether
they were susceptible to the impacts
that we were seeing with climate change
or if they were showing resilience um to
them and looking at um how they would be
affected by temperature and eventually
precipitation um whether they had
accelerated growth or syence Bloom time
differences stress or uh stress related
diseases and could we interpret those uh
in a way that our visitors would
understand and that we could attribute
to a temperature or precipitation uh
change in precipitation or
temperature so um as I mentioned we
focused on grain crops and we want what
we wanted to do is tie the um this idea
of the
food food is going to our food plants
are going to be affected by climate
change um and in some cases we know how
but in some cases we don't know how so
we thought we would start with grains
since so much of our diet is based on
grains and then we would have other
plants that are common in home gardeners
home gardens so in these beds here we
have uh barley wheat and
oats
and what
we we know about at least with wheat is
a it's a short-lived annual and under
increased temperatures it could grow
faster and have reduced yields and so
that's something that we could interpret
um in this case last year we had uh some
disease that affected
the the wheat and we don't know again
why this was the case but this is
something this is something that we're
trying to tune in terms of um
understanding it we also tried beans uh
in the garden both inside and outside
side and as I mentioned that we went
through six heat waves and when these
beans were setting their flowers we had
one of those heat waves and so what we
ended up seeing was a split set of the
beans which we have beans of different
sizes because at higher temperatures the
beans will drop their flowers which for
a home Gardener may not be a big deal
but from a production standpoint could
have a real impact in having seed uh
fruit of different sizes
and both the grains and the beans were
done relatively early in the season so
it gave us an opportunity to try out um
another set of crops so we tried out
lettuce and um we had different
germination rates inside and outside of
the garden so we're recording those and
this is a different set of uh varieties
of lettuce that were planted in the bean
beds and then for the other final food
crop we had uh peppers and wanted to see
what kinds of differences we could
expect
there then the other set of plants were
our nectar resource plants and we did
this by early blooming flowers uh late
blooming summer flowers and then fall
blooming flowers so this is the early
summer flowering plants things like Iris
versicolor the manota the
pensum and wanted to see what kind of
impact that they would have and this was
another way that um instead of just
pointing out things we were asking for
visitors to to comment on their
observations and with the exception of
the first set of checks in both of these
which is US putting it on there so
people know what to do um you can see
that our visitors generally recognize
the difference between um what they were
seeing inside and
outside and then these are the late
summer flowering plants so two different
varieties of scus and a
panum and again trying to draw attention
to what we were seeing
um and help our visitors see that so
here we're asking them to count the
flowers um inside and outside see if
they can notice a
difference and then finally we had the
fall blooming plants so we had solidago
cleone and a common wood Aster and um in
this case excuse me we um had this poor
Clon that was being over um competed by
the
solidago and we simply say here uh this
Clon is having a hard time competing
plant communities in the future may
change as some plants better adapt to
new
conditions so the other thing that we
did last year was to uh in to work with
Jonathan Schult from communication to um
really get serious about a visitor
survey we saw limitations of our initial
one and we wanted his help and his work
is working with public perception of
climate change and he's a statistician
and so lots of good things to offer and
what we did with this uh visitor survey
is that we asked some general questions
about knowledge people's knowledge their
concern their opinion about climate
change and how it's caused when the
changes will occur and the likelihood
that they would take some action and all
of these questions are based on um
previous UNP polling data whether it's
Gallup poll or ABC News polling um New
York Times polling and this is so that
we can we can use our results and we can
compare them to what's being pulled on a
national
level we also then asked some very
specific questions to our project things
um about what impact we would have on
local plant communities uh those nectar
resource plants the local crops what um
people could expect in 20150 do are they
recognizing the changes that we're
likely to see uh what is it what is
going to happen specifically in central
New York wanted to understand if they
had they felt like they had access to
Reliable information and
then if they were seeing any differences
between the plants inside and outside
and whether the signs that we had up uh
were of
help and so our initial results um just
saying that this was a pilot test we um
didn't launch it till the very end of
the season we only had 43 precip
participants and most of those were
students from communication uh so they
were had incentive to participate we
also um had tour takers folks who came
on tour of plantations who are willing
to do it and with that with only having
43 participants we don't have as John
says not enough statistical power to um
say anything but he was and these are
his words initial indications are that
there's something detectable
happening so um he he was very
encouraged by what he was seeing but he
wouldn't say anything more than that for
this se but he's on board for for us to
do this next season so talking about
that and what we plan to do uh we
are again working on refining what we're
doing we're not really changing the
plant material uh very much we want to
refine that Garden experience and
looking at um the interpretation and how
people navigate through the garden and
um we want to see if we can uh find
Tunes to the tunnel and whether we can
eventually replicate this so in terms of
the garden um and the tunnel
one of the things that Josh was
successful in doing was um partnering
with um a professor from the Department
of biological and environmental
engineering Pete maretto who is working
with us to build as best I can call it a
widget um that will take the temperature
from that computer sensor the weather
station and monitor what's happening
outside um know what we want to have
happen inside in terms of average annual
increase but also these heat waves and
it will take take all that information
and it will do what we want and he's
told us that we can even have a heatwave
button on this so that those side the
sides of the tunnel and the vents and
the doors can be automated to ventilate
the the tunnel to have the kind of
controls that we're looking for to meet
the the projections that we're hoping to
replicate the other thing um we're
trying to do is once we get that
temperature dialed in is to figure out
how we can um start to include
precipitation so right now we've only
been working under one the one variable
of temperature and seeing if we can
raise the temperature in the high tunnel
enough to meet what's being projected
and to see what kind of impacts that
will have on Plants but we know that
precipitation is going to be a big um
issue for plants and so we're talking
about how we might do that with soil s
uh moisture sensors but also with hand
watering and um drip irrigation things
of that nature
we really want to get the plants right
um we are trying to as I said use plants
as Messengers and we want to make sure
that the plants that we're using will
have some effect and that that effect is
the result of either temperature
precipitation and that they are have the
ability to be observed and that we can
interpret that
observation so this is something that
we're continuing to work on and
certainly if you have suggestions or um
comments about how some which plants
might do well um our team's already been
talking with folks like Thomas bjorkman
and looking at broccoli perhaps because
of its um the effect the temperature can
have on
it and then um we're also really wanting
to look at how uh we can have that
impact on visitors and if we if we're
having an impact um what is it and why
to what extent and if we're not having
an impact why not and what can we do to
change that
um so we are as I mentioned really
aiming for a more robust sampling of our
visitor survey of the visitor surveys
but what we'd also like to do is to do
some visitor observations of how people
are in the garden what kinds of
questions they have are they making
observations um if we're able to do some
interviews with visitors we'd like to
get that qualitative data as well as the
visitor data survey data um and
ultimately what we'd like to do is to
figure out if this is a project that we
can replicate that other Gardens or
other organizations can um do their
Gardens relatively inexpensively and
have the same kind of impact for their
region and use this as a tool to help
visitors understand about climate
change um and so I just want to um share
some words of thanks I mentioned Josh
and Chris at the beginning but there's a
host of other folks who are working on
this project with us to folks like Donna
Levy who's going to be managing the
garden for us this season Sarah fella
who really has been instrumental in
helping us with the interpretation for
this program the gentleman there on the
bottom your left is Jonathan Schult from
communication and then Nina bassic and
David wolf have also been um agreed to
work with us and collaborate with us on
the project to really help us understand
some of these things that we're still
looking to figure out things about
plants what effect the we're having on
plants and and what's the reason for
that effect and some of these irrigation
issues so we had a great meeting last
week and are very excited to have them
working with us on this and then there
are a host of folks at Cornell
plantations um who you know without whom
we wouldn't have this program either
they are out there installing this
Garden helping us find plants sourcing
the material and then we've had a host
of really phenomenal graduate students
people like Emily rer and Julie Romeo
aldez I don't have a picture of who was
the the Young who did all those Graphics
that I was showing you and then uh Mike
Roberts who is also an employee at
plantations but he's now working on a
masters in looking at climate change so
this is not a one-woman show except for
today and then um I just want to uh
recognize the support that we've gotten
financially from the toward
sustainability Foundation the ainson
center for sustainable future for
Cornell plantations and the department
of landscape architecture who've um made
this possible possible so with that I
will end and be happy to take any
suggestions or questions or comments
that you might
[Applause]
have yes yeah I you know actually Cally
looking at the plants it looks like
plants did better in the tunnel than
they did outside the tunnel I think
there really the choice of plants is
really going to be critical really and
one of the things like you mentioned
that jumped out at me is Iris vers is a
oblate wetland plant you might want to
take that out it's a it's not going to
be it's it's a wetland plant and so
you're in a a situation where probably
won't do better in either either
situation so just a think I mean
thinking about those plants that really
are going to show what you want CU just
looking at it says hey they did better
in the tunnel right and this is this is
some of the the visitor observation that
we had and um I mean I I picked those
photos to show the plants um there are
other photos that show the opposite of
that but if you're going through the
Garden on that particular day that's
what it looks like and that's what it
says and we have that effect where with
the um all of those tropical plants
we're like oh this is cool bring it on
right I'll be Sonia how are you dealing
with rain inside the P tunnel so we um
have a water gauge um outside measures
rainfall and what we've been doing is me
is watering the same amount inside the
tunnel so we have a gauge on the hose
that Waters so that we're at this point
keeping the soil moisture equivalent in
both outside and inside so you're
watering the soil if not sounds like you
might not be watering the foliage well
be a big part it is a big part right and
this just recently came up that when
you're hand watering you're you you're
cooling the plants right by and if
you're got it on the foliage and how are
we doing that so what we were discussing
last week is if we can get D Irrigation
in there that would be
all the better and we might even be able
to control it and make sure that they're
they're equivalent if we want to keep
them equivalent we can do that but if we
want to say okay it's a heat wave and
it's a drought then we can withold
water grant uh Sonia similarly in terms
of the plant material selection you've
selected plants for inside the high
tunnel that have a warmer range in
general might you also have a set of
plants that are typically found in more
cooler ranges um um you know to to show
them being heat stress in that future
scenario right so the the plants that um
we had in the 2014 season had that we
had some that would show stress under um
cooler temperatures they wouldn't make
it through the winter but then they
would also had plants that were um more
temperate here more uh adapted to this
climate but in the second season we we
didn't go to that extreme in terms of
having all those different kinds of
plants um but it's it's a constant
conversation that we're having about how
to evolve especially with the plant
material and are we not only telling the
story of how things are going to be
adversely affected but are might we also
be telling the story about resilience
and how we're we're going to have to
adapt to this at some level and so maybe
we can bring in some of these plants
that are being bred for bber
temperatures and how might our Farmers
or agriculturalist use them here or even
home
Gardener so I know that um a goal of the
garden both in terms of the things and
interpretive signage is to increase
awareness among visiting public of the
reality and seriousness of climate
change typically an even higher goal is
to move visitors to action so is any of
the future interpretation going to
address actual actions that people can
take well yes that that's the ideal and
the only thing that we have right now
that's doing that is the brochure which
provides
um information as I mentioned from
David's chapter that gives gardeners a
tool either how to adapt their Garden or
things that they can do to mitigate
using their Garden for climate change um
you know some of our future you know
Blue Sky discussions have been um having
another high tunnel and showing how you
might adapt things you or things you
might mitigate in your garden and what
impact that has
so You' mentioned that you know there's
some hope that this serves as a model
that can be used in other Gardens and
I'm curious if you have heard of have
other Gardens contacted you about this
program um or have you had an
opportunity to present this model or you
waiting to fine-tune it before doing
that um very good question and no we
don't we don't really want to wait I
mean part there's part of that is we
want to make sure it's good but we also
want that feedback in terms of what
other Gardens are likely to do so
something that that would res um work
with well for them do they have the
space do they have the funds even at
relatively inexpensive a high tunnel is
still $10,000 and plus all the other
plant material and beds um but we were
so at the American public garden
Association they're aware that we're
doing this and to they're serving as a
clearing house for others who are
interested and so through them I've been
contacted quite a bit by other gardeners
and in fact was invited to speak at um
last Summer's Botanic Gardens
conservation International about this
project and was ask be a part of climate
about how Gardens can um educate about
climate change and then um I will be
presenting at The Summer's um apga
seminar the the there's and then we were
invited to participate in two Grant
programs about climate change education
and that this would be a model that we
would be sharing um and talking with
other Gardens about so keep our fingers
crossed on those and there also will be
an article that Sonia has authored about
the climate change Garden in the next
issue of Public Garden Magazine along
with
Josh yes um I was just curious what the
state was with uh the the widget that's
monitoring and doing all that I was in
Pete's class last semester which we it
was sort of a loose Collective of
students working on that project and I
know Pete has uh left and taken a new
job so I was just curious but right
right well thank you because um the
reports that we were getting even though
I don't understand that's why I called
it a widget cuz I heard about it I like
really sure how it works but it sounds
very exciting um and Pete and Josh
really understand it um so Pete although
he's left to go to another position he's
still in town and we're actually meeting
on site um later this month for us to
figure out how to install it so along
it's it's electrical powered but we'll
have a solar panel that will power it so
we can walk the walk with what we're
trying to do as well um and so hopefully
it'll be installed by the end of April
and then we'll be using it for the
season yeah come down and see it you can
help us interpret it your name
afterward well I want to thank Sonia for
a fascinating seminar and I think we all
need to make the track down the hill to
see the climate change Garden this
growing season
will this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu