foreign
drosophila is a small vinegar fly native
to Japan it was first seen in the United
States when it was noted in Hawaii in
the 1980s the fly reached the mainland
in summer of 2008 when it was brought to
central California during this first
year spotted Wing caused an estimated
500 billion dollars in Damages with some
Farmers recording crop losses of up to
80 percent
fly quickly traveled across the rest of
the country and is now widespread
throughout the U.S and has also been
seen in parts of Europe Australia and
New Zealand have imposed quarantine
restrictions on Washington State
cherries but as of yet no other
preventative measures are being taken to
guard against further spread of this
insect
spotted Wing was first seen in New York
in the fall of 2011 but because the fly
is relatively new to the Northeast their
damage has been difficult to quantify
however since we are now aware of the
threat that the fly poses their
populations are being monitored
spotted Wing is very similar to the
fruit flies that we are all familiar
with however these slides have a
serrated ovipositor allowing the females
to lay eggs in under ripe fruit unlike
other drosophila species which can only
lay eggs in over ripe or rotting fruit
females can lay up to 16 eggs in one day
and over 300 eggs in their lifetime
which can be up to nine weeks long
Studies have shown that up to 13
generations of flies can be produced per
year and adults are capable of
overwintering
a respiratory horn also called a sting
shown here indicates the of position
site of the egg eggs hatch within three
days and larval feeding immediately
begins adulthood can be reached after
only eight days level feeding causes the
collapse of fruit tissue leaving The
Telltale indentations and berries
indicating that the maggots are present
this damage to the skin of the fruit
also makes it vulnerable to bacterial
and fungal infection
when fruit that contains these eggs is
harvested within two days the maggots
will emerge making the product
completely unmarketable
right now the only way to control
spotted Wing is through the use of full
coverage sprays directed towards
controlling adult populations there is
currently nothing that can be done to
salvage fruit that already contains
developing eggs
sprays must be applied weekly and it is
encouraged to use a variety of
insecticides with different modes of
action as a way of preventing resistance
however this is not the ideal way to
control a pest as pesticide application
here is based on a time schedule as
opposed to an IPM approach this results
in heavy spraying which is both costly
for farmers and bad for the environment
farmers are also encouraged to closely
monitor their fruit and harvest it
immediately once it reaches ripeness and
also to dispose of infested fruit
the good news is that male flies become
sterile at 30 degrees that New York
State's natural cold temperatures may
help limit their population growth and
protect our fruit as scientists continue
to study spotted wing drosophila and
make discoveries such as this we will be
able to develop a better Pest Management
strategy for the future