this is a production of Cornell
University
I pleased to introduce today's speaker
step on mentally learn before I go
through the formal introduction though I
wanted to introduce some work that he
did in my lab earlier on so Stefan
actually came to Cornell to work in the
tank Scilab where he stayed for a couple
of years and then he came to my life to
work on the project I'm about to
describe
to explain what he did I have to explain
how I got tenure because this slide
explains what I did during my assistant
professorship
because he came to my lab right after
that
so we were what we were interested in
this question of cytoplasmic meals early
and gently encoded fertility restoration
this is one of the reproductive
isolation methods of plants used at the
time I was assistant professor we didn't
actually know quite cytoplasmic genome
was encoding this trait of cytoplasmic
male sterility but it was chloroplasts
and mitochondria we didn't know what
gene was doing this and we also didn't
know anything about this nuclear
included fertility restoration gene that
could restore the pollen development to
this plan so what my lab did was look in
petunia to try to find the gene was
encoding cytoplasmic male sterility so
if you have a
fertile line with the
recessive allele of the RFG it's 40 if
you have a recessive allele in with the
CMS cytoplasm it's sterile you see the
lack of Poland about another one and
then if you have one copy of the
fertility story you get a normal fertile
plan
so what we found was that there is a
toxic protein encoded by an abnormal
gene in my condom and a day and that
sterile plan and the RF allele prevent
expression of this toxic protein so
that's what we knew and that's how I got
tenure was that finding but then when
when I came here and Stefan enjoying the
lab we wanted to find out with the RF
genius at that time we didn't know what
RF genes were so what Stefan did was an
amazing effort to try to identify that
RF teen and Petunia which is our normal
system at the time there was no genome
for petunia there was no high-throughput
sequencing there are almost no genetic
resources to step on it and develop
those all from scratch including a a
buyback library all the markers and
after a a an effort that took three
success of two-year USDA grants he was
able to figure out what the RF gene
encoded he found that it coded in tow
truck of peptide repeat protein this was
the founding member of these
this protein family for these restores
and it's now known that most restore
genes implants are
PPR so-called PBR protease you hearing
more about them in sedation because in
organelles it's a small world but it's
it's now known these puppies are now not
to be a large family of RNA binding
proteins that controller can help gene
expression and this protein turns off
the expression of that toxic gene and
that toxic protein
so Stefan then moved from working on
this
petunia RF projects to working on RNA
editing and that's what he's going to
describe today step on Goffe his
bachelor's degree in biochemistry at the
University of Science and Technology in
Montpelier plants and an MS degree and
agronomic science at the inn Romney
swollen too loose and then a PhD in
molecular genetics at University cloud
Bernard lyon in France as I eventually
came to
Tanksley lab first in my lab and he's
recently been promoted to be a research
scientist in the department of molecular
biology and genetics
thanks for in for this very nice
introduction ok now I have my little to
the shoe can stop so I'm going to tell
you today about the unraveling the
complexity of plant RNA editing
machinery and in the first slide I just
an overview of my talk with a little
background about what plant RNA editing
is and then are we identify some of the
components of this plant elitism which
is the molecular machinery responsible
for this modification and we use the
three different approach genetics
biochemistry approach and then what I
call a moto G and I will illustrate what
I mean by that in during the talk and in
the last part of my talk i'll tell you
about new editing factors which have not
been published yet and the future
direction I want to take my research on
so
it's blocked oh
so because I'm not using the right one
ok
so our editing is a common type of RNA
processing and it occurs in many many
species and under very different
mechanism so it happens in various
trypanosome squid plant which is going
to be the topic of my talk today and
even as human being in plant the it's a
post-transcriptional modification some
transcripts either sit cited in being
modified to you reading and this is
restricted to only the organelle genome
so here the arab adopts this is the plan
for them you working on and so in the
chloroplast about 40 seas are modified
to yuri Dean and in mitochondria in the
same phenomenon except is much more
frequent over 600 seas are modified to
origin in the mitochondrial genome and
the reaction that that is responsible
for this is a germination where the
amino acid here is in a city cited in is
replaced by a keto group and thus the
saturnine is modified to you reading so
very often people are wondering why
plants edit and so in implants in the
plant world this is a corrective
mechanism that allows the plant or the
functional protein
because the the
the amino acid after editing is actually
encode a more concept amino acid and
also you can create start or stop codon
and ear I give you an example of plastic
transcript and the HD where the start
codon in the ACG so it's not a start
column but upon editing vc is modified
to urine in and thus start codon is
creating and that allows the of course
the protein to be translated so this is
an important mechanism for plants
development because no editing most
article on most article on no protein
and so the loss of editing really
results in many different and various
phenotype depending on where it occurs
so here in this example I this is an
editing newtons which is unable to edit
a specific see on the transcript that
encodes the plastid RNA polymerase and
as a result this mutant can see is very
sent and as is not autotroph and has to
be run on a sucrose medium but in our
favorite Newton's in the lab so this
this mutant plants is unable to dt the
specific see on a sec d plastic
transcript and you can see that there is
no obvious phenotype associated with is
defect in editing compared to the
wild-type and
here I give another example and this is
a mitochondrial
mutant in editing so these little plant
is unable to lead to seize on transcript
that encode a small ribosomal protein
and as a result the translational defect
and so these branches are obviously a
slow growth phenotype and then when the
defect in editing occurs in very
important position in the essential gene
it's an embryo if of the plant is not
able to make it
so i told you in the introduction that
not all the seeds are edited to you read
in the specificity only for TCS IDT
dinner in a plastic and around 600 so
definitely not all the fees i heated and
so this the specificity is really
dependent upon two elements first
there's this element which is a small
ribonucleotide sequence which is a
upstream of the seeds to be edited and
so in this video figure i showed that
theses don't add this assignment so they
won't be edited this he possess this
assignment and so you will be modified
to origin but that's only a part of the
equation the other obviously is trans
factor that's gonna recognize this
element binds to the CC element and then
process the sea and modify it were you
reading and so in this complicated slide
that was done some time ago but by a
postdoc in the lab Charles
the this side showed that this trans
factor that we call plant editor is
actually a small
protein complex so what Charles did he
extracts protein from chloroplast and
then sighs fractionated them on the size
exclusion chromatography and so this is
all the fraction from the the big one
for the small one and then he sa each
fraction for editing activity and so I
don't want to go into deterrent to the
essay just for you to understand is that
these bands the morning turns his band
and the more active for eating is the
fraction and so this van the number 13
is the is the most is where the band is
most intense here is the just
quantification of this band and this
band is again is a comprised between 200
and 400 kilo dalton thus demonstrating
that its plant elitism is a small
protein complex and so the game in the
lad was trying to find the components of
this plant elitism and because I'm a
geneticist at that time I was working on
on CNS but I also developed this as a
side project and these are a different
ization of
arabidopsis shot from above and the the
point of this slide is just to show you
our diverse these plants are in the size
and morphology of there was that leaves
and so looking at this pan I thought
that maybe also they were differing in
the way they edit their seeds and
actually that was a good guess otherwise
I won't talk about it and so with the
previous that was years ago 10 over 10
years ago with a postdoc in the lab and
launched a teeny we study this
particular
transcript ECB 206 which is called also
CC NB and we we were interested we focus
on this transcript because it's the
transcript that possess the highest
number of a DDT that's about 40 seas
that are edited so in one experiment we
could potentially look for difference
between these two widely used as asian
runs very and columbia at 40 position
along the transcript and
here is an electropherogram and you can
see that this position the columbia is
more edgy than the director because the
T peak is higher in Columbia that it is
in the in Landsberg director and once
once you have a difference in parent
I'll ization that's almost the end of
the story not really but in arabidopsis
because then you can use many genetic
resources other people have crossed
these two these two guy and so you can
use the progeny to study the segregation
of this differential extent in the
progeny and that's what we did several
times and a I just show you an example
so we found that one of the gene
controlling these differential editing
extent was actually in in this area
which is on chromosome 2 and with a wall
tonight was an undergrad doing silly
faces sorry with me what Walter did a
screen many many hundreds of progeny
coming from the cross between landsberg
and Columbia and these are this progeny
this plant and they are recombinant
because they have inherited part of the
genome from i'm going to try sell to
shake from lands bearing in blue and
part from columbia in red and and then
what Walter dds a the editing extent of
all these progeny is for coming in
plants and so again if they were edited
like Columbia River red like a red tie
blue and then it's a regression of the
phenotype on a genotype you just have to
look at matching colors and the matching
colors are just between these two
recombination point and there there was
only one gene that we call rm14 required
for efficiency of mitochondrial editing
so we were pretty convinced because
there was only one gene that was the the
gene and this gene again is a PPR as
maureen told you in the introduction the
restoration of fertility is also a PPR
PPR because went a tripeptide repeat
that's the only time i'm going to tell
it it's composed by a repeat which are
35 I mean long and in addition this
protein content some extra motif at the
c-terminus and
so in order to demonstrate that these
this gene was really disappointing was
an editing factor we looked at the
mutant DNA insertional mutant and we
found one and then we compared the level
of editing instant in the homozygous
newtons which add this T DNA which
disrupt the expression of this gene and
the almost arias wild-type and yes there
was a significant difference in the
level of imaging stand for this
particular side thus demonstrating that
rm1 was really the editing factor
recognizing this mitochondrial site so
that illustrate the genetic approach
which was pretty cumbersome so here the
so we're going to build up the model as
a puzzle so this PPR protein and a lot
have time to show you the evidence but
the other one that are the recognition
factor they recognize the season event
and bind to it and they are found both
in the crop last and in the
mitochondrial editors oh but there are
other other component because I told you
at the very beginning but that we knew
that the this elite ozone is about 200
and 400 kilo dalton and the size of the
PPR is way below that so we knew that
there were other components and so the
way we decided to chase this component
and that's a work that I did in
collaboration with Wade error who used
to be a vc MV student in in the lab so
what way did he put a
flag on on one of the our favorite PPR
factor called rare one and then using
antibody
against this rare one it was able to
immunoprecipitated the all complex and
then with the collaboration with the Van
Wyck club where we were able to identify
one of the components of these complex
as being required for RNA editing factor
interacting protein 1 and so because
this reponn was member of these complex
obviously we wanted to know whether it
was also an editing factor and so as
usual we looked at gdna mutant and we
found two while which was in in the in
the central and as I told you before
obviously these protein this gene is
essential gene because we were unable to
recover homozygous mutant for this new
talent but luckily for us we are also a
cdna inserted in the promoter and we
were able to recover almost i goes
newtons and you can see that this plant
is very effective in its development and
then by using bulk sequencing we were we
analyze all the ad term meaning all
these the ADT's in the chloroplast of
the plastid and in the mitochondria and
what we found was that this mutant was
effective in about a third of this
plastinated inside meaning that the
level of editing in the mutant for this
site was much reduced compared to the
wild-type but more importantly about
three quarter of the site in the
mitochondria were effective and about
100 was really the the level of editing
was not even the detectable by Bach
sequencing it was gone and that was a
very exciting result because it was the
first time that
member I mean a component of the plan
todito Sam was not a PPR protein rip one
is not a PPR protein
so then we wanted to know because the
PPR I told you bind recognize and bind
the RNA so we were wondering how the
specificity work for a point what its
targets because it doesn't affect all
the all the Seas many fees but not all
of them and that was a work that was
done by tau tau son was a produced plant
bio grad student working in lab and what
style showed by using East library that
actually the recognition of our free
porn for its target was mediated through
its interaction with a recognition
factor and so in order to make you
understand what I just said I have this
little animation we're here you can see
that in the power blast kyosho Darrell
one interact with rip one sorry rip
interact with the rare one it also
interact with another recognition factor
called CR 28 I'm not responsible for his
name and then but then rip one doesn't
interact with here 21 and so when the
new in the mutant rip one is not there
anymore or is very reduced and then only
the site that for which reprod interacts
with the recognition factor are affected
in the mutant the sides for which rip
one doesn't interact with the
recognition factor does don't see there
editing little effective in the mutants
and what's true in the chloroplast is
true also in the plastid and
tell showed also that rip one was able
to a modular eyes by Easter hybrid okay
so that's all this story that the second
part was to illustrate the biochemist
call approach in order to identify
components of the plants elitism and and
now I'm going to tell you about the
amala G and what I meant by that is that
rip one is a member of a small tiny of
protein in the arabidopsis there are
nine members
this is good so r upon which we found
was a involved in mitochondria and plus
TD editing and there's all these factors
and I identify them by using
software and this broke we call in the
rib motif it just amuro G block we don't
know really what the function obviously
they are important because they are
conserved in the rib family and then of
course we were wondering are any of
these other protein also editing factors
and so and this time instead of using
bulk sequencing I develop a
method based on a next-generation
sequencing to analyze Newton's or
silence tissue from this from this other
gene and so briefly it's very easy
method where I use a specific primer for
all the organelle jeans so is is the
real RNA and some RNA are edited more
than other and then I do rt-pcr and then
this thing are you know cdna whether you
eat transforming tea and then I share
the cna and use these shield fragments
to build up alumina library and then I
just align align these rates on the
genome and then I just count really then
the number of thread being t or blue
being c and the ratio of red rubies need
a very accurate measure of the level of
editing and that
collaboration that I did with the robot
bukovski was a bioinformatician here
so I use these methods to analyze the
mutant and and silence tissue in this
other member and i found that rib to and
replying were preceded in character
while rid three and repay or my token
you're dissing factor
but also using these motifs to integrate
the database i found that there was this
weird protein that we call on 14
organelle RNA recognition motif
containing protein 1 and it's a weird
one because
it has a duplicated REEP REEP domain
which is also truncated you can see
there's some other blogs are missing and
in addition it has a motif and c
terminus which is called RN for RNA
recognition motif and so we were of
course interested to know whether this
on one also was an Indian factor and so
as usual we
looked at the GDN a mutant in the first
exam and so you can see that this plant
is really morphologically okay but when
we surveyed the editor we found that the
mitochondrial item was not affected but
the placidity term was effective in each
mutant and about two-third of the
editing site where they were reduced in
the newton with 12 side which had a
major loss of editing and
again we were interested so I told you I
don't know if you remember that this
protein here as
22 part rip rip that's how we identified
it and the RM and we were curious to
know which which part is important for
the editing ability of this protein and
again that's a work that was done by a
towel so here I show the 12 side that
are severely reducing the editing
instant in a mutant so the bar the blue
bar is the level editing in a white hat
but very high and in the mutant very low
and so what's tau did was to present he
transformed protoplast for the mutant
first with the reprint and when he did
that nothing really happened and when we
did the same experiment with the RM it
was able to complement most of the site
at least partially and so that was the
and to our surprise actually because we
were expecting more than repaid to be
involved in anything because that's how
we identify this protein but actually to
our surprise it's the are and parts of
this protein that was responsible for
the editing each of these protein
so and then as for rip 1 tau using East
why breed
studied all these on one was recognizing
is target and it's the same story as 401
the the recognition is mediated through
its interaction with the with non
recognition factor which are PPR and so
again in the in the in the mutant when
on one goes down only the site for which
on one interacts with the PPR see there
editing extent to go down in the mutant
not this one because again on one
doesn't interact with real one and also
tell showed that on one was interacting
with other non
editing factor from the rib family reap
so now we are
we just add other parts in the puzzle
the reap members the aam one for the
chloroplast and if I put on one touching
the RNA in this model it's because by
with collaboration with the back lab
I've shown that this on one has some
specificity for the RNA target and this
is a GF gel shift assay and you can see
this is one of the one of the target of
m1 and thus nice ships compared to a
non-target and this now we have a new
student at Andrew in the lab was going
to study more deeply these the
recognition and the binding of on one
for its RNA targets
okay so this is for the chloroplast what
about the Mitel so again the defining of
these are M being involved in editing
open a new a new or all area for us to
explore because the iron is very
frequent motif in the protein world and
in a bit of ceaseless about 200 protein
that contain this RN and so I'm sorry so
we could have you know use brute force
and and test least one with proteins
that's much work and so we're trying to
be smart and what we did was a video
genetic analysis of the based on the RM
motif of all this protein in arabidopsis
so this RI motif is about 18 amino acid
and what we
observed was on one this new editing
factor was part of this specific played
continuing about 20 members and
obviously the
question then was are these also
potential editing factors so we got a
grant with maureen that just ended up
for which more in what the main pii was
the copy i but lucky for us we just got
a new brand for which now I'm the P I am
wearing is the copy I and so here now
i'm going to show you
the work from Shaolin was a grad student
in the lab and
just finished and so she study a this
clade of on protein and so that's
another way to represent all these
proteins so with the funding father is
on one so it has the reprint RM and all
the other protein which belong to
displayed and they do because the RM
found in his other arm are very similar
to the RN found in on one and so what
challenge shown during a
PhD was that on two three and four when
mitochondrial editing factor and the m6
is a plastid in fact random chicks has
not been published yet and I'll talk
about that at the end of my talk and
some of these other
member also possess extra domain glycine
rich domain
so here are just going to show you an
example of
showering work again same story she out
to demonstrate that um three was a
mitochondria leading factor she looked
at the mutant and she got a mutant in
the Texan and then she compared the
level of editing in mitochondrial side
actually this this all three is involved
in the control of editing of twenty
percent of the mitochondrial side over
100 side but er just show only two so
here is the level of editing extent in a
white type in grain and in magenta in
the mutant and you can see this is a
very significant difference level of
editing sent between the white side in
the mutant and the same is true for this
other side then what cha indeed was to
complement the these mutants by putting
a functional functional on three under
the control of 35s promoter and you can
see that she was able to restore the
level of editing and increase it very
significantly when compared to the
mutant the leveraging was from around
forty percent for this site to about 85
to 90 percent in the transgenic plant
and then we were wondering I told you
that the four on one what was important
was the RM motif and
another repeat and i'm free as to motive
as the RM and the glycine reach motif or
domain sorry and and then we of course
were wondering whether it was the same
story as four on one whether it was the
RM domain or the glycine which domain
that was important for the editing
ability of this protein and so what
shall indeed was to again so here's a
mutant for a specific site and its low
edited about fifteen percent when she
when china the all flanks on three she's
able to restore the editing level two
forty five percent and when she used
only the RM again she's able to
significantly increase increase the
level of editing extent thus again
demonstrating that what's important for
the editing ability of this protein is
the RM motifs
okay and then as usual she was
interested to know whether these these
new editing factors was part of the
editors amande was interacting with
other non editing factor and here I just
show you an example see she used by a c4
bimolecular fluorescence complementation
and so she put half of your pure four on
each part of the protein that she wants
to study the interaction on three and in
this case rip one and if they interact
then he will bring the two part close
enough so that they are able to
fluoresce and so then she did that in
eco sheeana and
this is a negative control so these are
in red of the auto pure sent from the
chloroplast from the chlorophyll and
here is a close-up you can see that this
nice sports fluorescence when she did
this experiment demonstrating that all
three and rip one can interact in planta
so now now what's true for
for chloroplast is true also for
mitochondria so you have PPR you are
bleep and you are also on okay
and then we steal an interrogation mark
here as you can see and so we now also
worked on again by towel he did like use
the same strategy as why did but he put
a flag on the on one and
immunoprecipitated eat and then again
with the collaboration with the
transferrin week
and we determined by mass spectrometry
that one of these protein that was
pulled down with on one was 0 z 1 z 1
for organization or one because this
protein contains zinc finger motif and
because Ozzy one was
immunoprecipitated with on one again we
were wondering whether Ozzy one was a
leading factor and as usual we looked at
the DNA insertional mutant and this time
unlike on one these mutant is not very
happy that's the mutant here so it's an
albino it's small and it has to be one
on sucrose medium and when we looked at
the editor of this mutant what we found
is that the majority of the plastid
editing side were affected in this
mutant and because this Aussie one was
identified for its interaction with on
one we were wondering whether there was
overlap in the site under the control of
these two editing factor and yes
actually the majority of the site 21 are
cedar editing incense severely affected
in both m1 and the Aussie one mutant
so Ozzy one belongs to a small family of
protein there's four members and again
this is a little diagram of how they
look like with the homology block and
the only really non motif is as I told
before he's a sinking a motive in this
light blue turquoise Ozzy one possessed
two of the zinc finger motif oh sorry oh
g1 or g2 as 20 z three 3 &amp; 0 0 4 and
then of course the obvious question to
ask because he worked for it works for
all of these other members also editing
factors
so now I hope I convince you that the
planted is awesome our complex protein
small but complex which contain several
protein so
and that also they contain the same
protein in both the mitochondria ID
tourism and the progress PPR which had
the recognition factor that bind to the
target rip on an Aussie Aussie has been
just demonstrated in Pro procedures are
not yet in the mitochondria
okay so now in the last part of my talk
I'm going to tell you about a new
plastic editing factor on six
OOP yes anaam 6 actually as the
from the start we had a strong
presumption that this was also an easy
teen factor because the RM found in this
protein is the most similar to UM one so
again what we did was to study
editing mutant sorry mutant t-dna
international mutant and when we use SDS
pcr sec this next generation
based approach to study the editor of
these mutants we found that there was no
mitochondrial editing defect but there
was plastic editing effect so again here
in green is a level of editing extent in
the white type in magenta in were in
mutant for this particular protein on
six and you can see that this strong
reduction of anything in stand for this
side accd from one hundred percent goes
to thirty percent even more pronounced
for this I'd PSB f77 for which the
editing goes from one hundred percent to
five percent and just to show you that
it's not affecting this this other side
for which the same level of editing
instant in the white type and in the
mutant and it is another way to
represent the reduction it's the the the
the difference reported to the value of
the other white type so you can see that
the the side that explain the most
drastic reduction is this site on PS DF
so as we were as n decide this these
mutants are
shorter growth phenotype and also
detecting the photosynthetic efficiency
and so as we were working on this
Newton's actually we found out that
another
group was working on this mutant yan liu
and but she's a photosynthetic person so
she did not use the same screen to to
identify this Newton and that's that's a
word basically this wet floors and it
shows that the this mutant is affected
in this a photosynthetic efficiency
again shalin showed that objects was
part of these plastics and elitism by
studying its interaction with non in
fact I was by FC and ear I just show a
few example of arm sixth
interacting with rip one here and there
are with the OC one year and there and
so I told you that mostly there's two
sides which are affected in the mutant a
CCD and PS BF and eighth and so and this
phenotype too and so the question was
which which side is responsible for the
phenotype and we had strong presumption
that it was the PS BF defect in editing
because we add a mutant in the lab which
is affecting in the acc d and i show you
a picture at the very beginning of the
talk and there's no phenotype associated
with these mutants so in order to
demonstrate that the PhDs deflecting
editing was responsible for the for this
phenotype small growth and
photosynthetic
deficiency what he indeed was a pretty
cool experiment she took PS BF and with
the g genomically encoded and she
transformed a plant mutant and so you
can see here it's translated and here in
green is the transit peptide that allows
the protein to goes in a chloroplast and
again this red meaning that the this
protein is already edited
and then by doing that she was able to
at least partially complements the
defect the morphological defect where
you can see you have to trust me but the
even though these transgenic plants are
not at the level of the white side they
are much better and much bigger than the
than the mutant and also the
photosynthetic efficiency even though is
not at the level of the wild-type is
much better than Newton's and so in
other words that demonstrating that the
defect
of picea PS BF editing is a one
responsible for the the morphology
morphological defect we observe in
English mutants
so in summary I hope that today I
convince you that the plant it is ozone
is complex and contain at least for
protein families for the plastid so the
PPR which are the recognition
sorry the PPR the ribs which are also
called moss the arms and the O's but
only three protein families have been
identified of sofa in the mitochondrial
editor zone and they are the same the
PPR the more ribs and the arms also the
plant elitism is really diverse in its
composition not only in ppl at the
content because the PPR differ for every
side you got the ugly the recognition
factor but also in regards to these
other components there are other rib and
for instance so today I told you about
20 m 1 and m 6 which are plastic aging
factor and the side another control of
difference the two sides mostly affected
by the m6 mutants are not affected by
the on one mutant so in other words they
are editors am classically to them that
content on one and order that contain
object depending on which side the gonna
modify and m6 is a unique usual on
protein because it really recognized a
very small number of targets only really
two mostly to when other or all the
other on the plastid or or mitochondrial
really recognize and affect many many
sides
[Applause]
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell edu