this is a production of Cornell
University if you think of other plants
around the world that do things in this
spectacular fashion Hawaiian silver
swords for example um the Giant puya
from from Bolivia and Peru um other
examples uh the the century plant the
giant Agave from our own deserts these
plants are like salmon right they live a
long time they reproduce once and it
exhausts and kills them the act of
reproduction what's remarkable to me
about this is that it's it's marshalling
that kind of energy and that kind of
floral display but it gets a chance to
reproduce over and over again and that's
what we were discussing before you all
arrived as to like how does it balance
its energy does it does it engage in
just really extraordinary photosynthetic
rates and photo and photosynthetic um
you know productivity in ways that those
other plants can't all of the plants I
mentioned uh either grow at high
elevation in the tropics or on desert
islands and so the problem there is not
photosynthesis because they have lots of
sun it's that it's drought you know and
these plants don't have that problem
they're they grow in rainforest and and
and they're not limited by moisture so
it also as another lesson it reminds us
that plant reproductive strategies are
also limited by where they live what
kind of soil they're on what kind of
environment they're in Etc
so so there's another another thing that
we're looking to to to to study this
time around um we tracked as you can see
in this in this sheet uh we tracked the
odors that we've studied in other plants
and that we expected to see that have
been other people studying this plant
and Publishing their results and so we
weren't shocked by anything um some of
our faculty Carl Nicholas for example
smelled the fishy odor um uh on the
morning after and asked you know is it
is there an amine in there and and sure
enough they're the very low levels of um
compounds that were very sensitive to
trimethyl amine is kind of rotting fish
odor uh and what we've wondered this
time around is is that actually um a
volatile coming off the pollen grains
because it started showing up in our
study when the pollen was available in
the inside the flow so this time around
we we might like to collect some pollen
and do a separate scent collection from
the pollen itself and the reason why
that's of more than trivial interest is
for the animals that are getting Co
covered and coated with pollen um it's
very important that they don't groom
okay one of the reasons so a question
that com commonly arises when we look at
this plant is why is it so
large why is so big why is it so
overstated anything in nature that's
that's exaggerated or overstated is
interesting to us um and one of the
things that people suggest is that the
population density of these plants is so
small they don't grow in groves right
there's one here one there um that they
have to advertise from a distance to get
their pollinators to find them the
second time the third time because it
doesn't work unless they get duped two
or three times in the process of of of a
week um and so one of the things we've
wanted to know is um how does that
transition work from from male from
female stage to to male stage the the
flies have to fly with the pollen on
their bodies they might have to fly 500
meters or a kilometer or two or three
kilometers to find the next one of these
before they can enact you know they can
complete the the the loop and and
enclose the loop on pollination uh it's
important that they don't groom the
pollen off their bodies while they're
doing that okay and if you watch insects
as much as we do a lot of insects are
fastidious they'll hit four or five
flowers fly to a perch sit on the perch
and then brush themselves flies are very
good at this where you've all seen them
kind of do this with their hind legs and
their for legs and clean themselves off
they have brushes on their legs to clean
their antenna so they can smell they can
right um our moths that we study we
study these very large Hawk moths that
visit night blooming flowers like the
Darwin's Orchid from Madagascar that
Paul has shared with us in years past
they're they're slobs they don't groom
and they're gypsies they they fly tens
of miles a night so they're a dream for
plants because they don't waste the
plants pollen investment in them and
they're able to move pollen long
distances without wiping it off their
bodies
so um here we're kind of interested in
in that that the male part of the of the
plant too um are are the insects leaving
at dawn the following day and if and are
they doing so with pollen on their
bodies and is there something about the
odor of that pollen that might you know
make them more likely to leave it where
it
is this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu