this is a production of Cornell
University it's so so so chamber flowers
like this I should say have evolved all
over the world this is weird enough and
it would be worth it if this was the
only one but the but the thing that that
strikes me as a as an evolutionary
biologist as really interesting is that
you know Southeast Asia has these and
the genus amorphofalis as Paul knows is
found across the African Tropics as well
as the Asian Tropics so it's a large
genus that's gotten around but there's
also arisal loius okay this is a very
ancient group of vines 200 300 species
of them around the world a very ancient
pan tropical distribution they make trap
flowers also they just hang them up in
trees they look like pieces of dead meat
they're not appealing but they're
fantastic okay they also trap their
pollinators um the other plants in the
um uh in the skunk cabbage family that
you're familiar with all form trap
flowers okay there are some really funky
U milkweeds from South Africa including
hoodia the plant that several of you
know as a kind of appetite suppressant
um you know uh growth industry these are
succulents that look like cacti but
they're actually
milkweeds you know so so the compounds
that that we studied last time um in
this plant that we were able to identify
using you know analytical chemistry are
actually relatively simple I'll I'll
pass this around and you can look at it
this is a Time course with clocks to
show you what time of day we were
collecting scent and then I've basically
tracked five molecules in here um ones
that are highly indicative of carryon
mimicry or dung mimicry in plants and
the point I wanted to make was that this
happens around the world every continent
has a carry in flow they're just not
always is this big okay but what they're
tapping into with volatile sulfides with
phenol and crol and indol things that
you smell in in in feces of dogs or cats
or or or or or herbivores like cows and
horses um those are Universal signals or
cues rather they that are highly
reliable indicators of the presence of
rotting meat or a feces and so all
across the planet there are animals that
use those resources as dist as they are
to us as places to lay their eggs and
grow their young okay and so those guys
are trapped we call it a sensory trap
for them to be good mothers blowflies
have to find rotting meat or feces they
have to find it at just the right time
before the yeasts and molds take it over
um and not too early so that it's not
ready to be digested yet by their their
grubs and maggots so that's why forensic
entomologists are so important that that
they can track you know how long a body
has been dead by you know the stage of
development of the blowfly larae because
the females always make the right choice
as to when exactly to lay the eggs and
at that exact moment there's a signature
of heat of carbon dioxide and these five
molecules that I'm going to show you um
and those are her template that's how
females choose the plants have have
picked that lock they've broken the code
okay and what what Paul will show you is
that you know these plants whether
they're in poinsettia family whether
they're in the Rokia family whether
they're in the the arum family whether
they're in the milkweed family they've
all converged on the same chemistry now
there's other aspects of these that are
really interesting why are they blotchy
red patches of red and green why are
some of them really hairy I mean you can
speculate as to you know a really choosy
blowfly female would want you know a
hairy dead body to to overos it into
right and a lot of the flowers are
chambers with holes just as an orifice
like an ear would be a great place to
lay eggs in a dead body if you were a
blowfly female or a burying Beetle or
something okay but but beyond the gothic
horror of this what's really interesting
is that it's a way of life okay there's
the decomposers of the planet that keep
that keep the ecosystem cycling use cues
chemical cues like this to make their
choices and what these plants are doing
is
they're code Breakers okay they found a
code that can't be faked except they're
faking it and the pollinators have to
come because if they
ignore chemistry that good they're going
to miss out potentially that it's not a
cognitive Choice they're making but but
they have been selected to respond to
big dead meat and that's what this is
this is a dead elephant
okay that's the way we see it at the
moment now there's other
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu