and I have that it is
101 if the rest of
you um want to just try to vote and then
I'll close these polls
getting a last minute flurry of people
signing on that's wonderful hopefully
everyone can
hear and I do want to introduce myself
um I'm Laura McDermot I work for Cornell
Cooperative Extension in the Capital
District region and do um vet and small
fruit extension education and I'm
working for Dr Marvin pritz on the
northeast IPM funded webinar um series
that we're putting on with a great deal
of help from invited experts throughout
the Northeast region so uh our thanks to
the Northeast IPM Center for their
funding assistance and to all of the uh
research researchers that will be
hearing hearing from over the next um
several months and also um my great deal
of thanks go to my colleague Kathy heyen
Reich who is has been instrumental in
trying to get the um press releases and
all the pr out for this series and for
Dr Marvin pritz guidance in it um so
let's get on with it the first uh
session that we have scheduled today is
alternative strawberry production
methods and it features um um two guest
speakers uh Kathy gem who's the senior
extension associate associate at
pennstate University Kathy has a
background in vegetable and fruit
nutrition and has been integral to Berry
and plasticulture research in the state
of Pennsylvania so we're really happy to
have her and I'm actually going to let
her begin our um begin our talk here in
just one second and I'm jumping ahead
slightly I want to make sure
that everybody sees um these additional
resources that are listed here and those
are things that you can uh access by not
clicking on they're not live um links
but you can cut and paste them into your
browser if you're interested in in any
any of those resources and it just in
case people are still not aware of how
to do this if you have a question please
type in this skinny box at the bottom of
the chat and either hit return or hit
send message
arrow and I'm just getting um a little
feedback from Sue that the sound keeps
breaking up I'm sorry Sue I um I wish I
knew how to fix that and hopefully it
it's not breaking up for other
folks my audio and I'll give you a ring
all right um so let me move now into the
classroom and I'm going to introduce
Kathy demek again a senior extension
associate at Penn State University and
I'm going to turn off my um talking and
give a call and I'm gonna um just turn
this over to Kathy Dem well all right
I'll jump into this um at this point if
anybody does have questions or anything
um feel free to type them in if we end
up um getting too many questions in and
it gets um too distracting we may end up
um holding them for the end but for now
I'd say if there's anything that I'm
talking about that's unclear to you
please feel free to just type something
in and I'll try to um not get um myself
too far off track on things all righty
um what I want to talk about here is
Northeastern approaches um that are used
to growing strawberries on plastic now
most of the information does apply to
Northeastern United States for those who
are um a little west of here um there
were some folks from Ohio for example or
in the midwest um most of what I will
talk about would apply to those
situations as well so we're going to
jump into things here um you know the
most common reasons we get for why
Growers are interested in growing on
plastic um are listed here weed control
is probably the number one reason that
people give um when they're growing
strawberries and matted row production
um often they just get tired of trying
to deal with the weeds and the plastic
helps with that problem
there are some other advantages there is
um a shorter time to establishment than
you might have in matted row production
um typically you can plant during the
summer or early fall um and still
harvest the next spring so it cuts off
several months um that um during which
problems might develop typically you'll
get um better quality fruit primarily in
the area of size um but flavor can can
also be excellent with plastic culture
berries typically um the fruit will come
in um 2 to 3 weeks
earlier um but that really depends on
your management um that doesn't have to
happen if you're in a frost pocket there
are some things you can do to um to keep
the fruit from coming in too early a
frost is a concern for you higher
marketable yields um you may not
necessarily get higher total yields but
um if everything is managed well um
hopefully you will get a higher
percentage of fruit that is marketable
and your marketable yields will be high
higher than they might be in matted row
but again that's not necessarily true
either um berries will tend to pick
faster um in that if you have larger
berries um your labor costs can then go
down um for for berries that are picked
ahead and sold as ready picked and um a
lot of our Growers are getting a higher
price for plasticulture berries because
of the higher
quality now here's the disadvantages um
plastic culter berries are expensive to
establish if you were using plug plants
which um are the type of plants um for
which um the system was originally
developed for use with um they're
expensive at about 21 cents per plant um
and a plant population of around 15,000
plants per acre um the cost adds up
fairly quickly so you can you know spend
$3,000 on Plants Alone um it does help
if you have both Trickle and overhead
irrigation the trickle is a necessity um
overhead overhead irrigation will come
in handy in a couple of situations like
for frost control um and then plastic
mulch there's issues um with the cost
but also disposal um and and just the
environmental costs of using um a lot of
plastic can be an issue too the um one
other expense that's fairly large is a
row cover that can be as much as $1,500
per acre um depending on the road cover
you're using and management in this
system is is intense
so um you know there's some some
potential there if you aren't able to
keep up with what's happening in the
planting um where you can get into a
little bit of trouble and all that puts
it together into being a a a high-risk
um type of um situation but um there
also is a potential for high returns if
you can get everything working together
well so plastic culture as it was
developed for use um in the southeastern
United States um where B basically it
was adapted from production systems used
elsewhere um in that situation um
typically plug plants are used plants
planted during the fall either late
September or early October um in that
situation there really are less times
for there is less time for problems to
develop typically fumigation will be
used um there will be high raised beds
that'll warm up quickly U most of the
production is with either Chandler or
camarosa and it is used as an annual
system when we take it to the north um
typically um we'll need to move that
planting time um to be earlier either
into mid or late summer you may use plug
plants you also may use dormant plants
and we'll go into some particulars on
that Growers may or may not use
fumigation um if they can rely on crop
rotation um they may not need need
fumigation typically most of the beds um
that will be made for plasticulture here
are are lower than in the South um most
of the Growers will use um plastic mulch
L and bed raising equipment that they
will also use for vegetable
production and um Chandler still works
really well here but there are um some
other varieties that can be used and
typically Growers may carry plantings
over um for a second year so we will go
into that um more as well um just in
case um you aren't familiar with plug
plants this is what a tray plug plants
would look like so when I refer to those
you you know what we're talking about
basically they are Runner Tips that are
taken from Plants um rooted in um in
this case a 50 cell tray and then um
it'll be vegetative actively growing
plants that that um are
planted okay so um some of the
modifications we use for using this
system in the northeastern you um us
really depend on understanding how the
plant grows and responds to the
environment if we understand how the
plant is likely to respond um to
different techniques we might use that
modify the environment then we might
know what to change if um we need to
increase our yields further or just want
to try some different things so first I
just want to talk real briefly about how
strawberry plants do respond to the
environment um Runners are produced um
during periods when you have long days
and high temperatures um are our typical
summertime conditions
and um so what that means is when we
move planting dates up we may run into
some some issues with with Runner
production with having more Runners than
we actually want um under conditions of
cool temperatures and short days like we
have in the fall in the early spring um
you'll have Branch crowns formed on
plants and um those those are basically
you know side branches um on the mother
plant um each of those branch crowns can
produce one or two fruit TR
es and so we really dependent on having
those to Hive high yields from a
particular plant and then dur when we
have periods of short days and long
nights um that's when flower buds are
initiated that'll happen in the fall um
and also can happen in the early spring
as well this is something that isn't
strictly temperature dependent or
strictly day length dependent
temperature can affect this as well um
finally how the plant responds um Can
Depend with a car um cultivar and so um
this also explains why some cultivars do
better in some areas of the country and
not so well in
others and so like I mentioned um
modifying any components of the system
will affect how how the plants respond
um and what kind of yields we'll get so
you know in a nutshell when typically we
were using um plastic culture in warm
areas and we' use um plug plants planted
in the fall you'd end up with high
yields that would result from having um
numerous Branch crowns formed and um
also once those branch crowns are formed
you'd still have um a fairly long period
for flower butt initiation so you could
get high yields from those individual
plants planted in the plasticulture beds
in matted R production where we were
planting um dormant crowns in the
springtime um our yields are really
dependent on having full beds so you'd
have those Runners and daughter plants
produced during the long days of the
summer and then um flowerbud initiation
taking place on those plans during the
fall so even if we got an early fall if
we um just had a short period for flower
but initiation we still had a lot of
plants out there that could could still
give us high yields and all of that
might be you know a bit of an
oversimplification but that's kind of
you know um in general how you know some
of the thing how some of the things work
and um why we need to make some of the
changes we need to make so plastic
culture in cooler areas some limitations
we have we do have a relatively short
fall um a short growing season in
general and then um cold winter
temperatures and we need to modify some
things to deal with all of
these so issues on that short fall
season if we are using plug plants one
of um the first uh field studies we had
done was looking at planting date and
that's what we you know often recommend
people do when they're considering um
trying plugs in a plasticulture system
is determine their Optimum um planting
date for us in central
Pennsylvania um which at our research
Farm is hardiness Zone 6A just to give
you an idea of you know where we're
starting from on this um we needed to
plant our plants by the middle of
August this is an issue because there
just aren't enough plug plants available
early enough to supply the demand for
them um in in northern areas and even
when we thought we would be able to get
pluged plants um we didn't always get
them when we thought we would and so
what that meant was sometimes there
would be delays in planting um that
often frequently happened for Growers
and one thing we found was that for each
two we delay we had in our planting date
we basically cut our yields in half and
so you know that's that's a big problem
to have to deal with because you just
can't get the yields that you need to be
able to pay for the inputs um in that
kind of a
situation so we want to look at some
other alternatives for um what we can do
here okay if you um can't get plug
plants um you can try to root your own
plugs from Runner Tips that you can
order from nurseries that sell them even
then you can sometimes run into um
issues where the Nursery's um may not um
have the plants may not go into Runner
production um to the extent that they
need them to um due to just WEA
conditions or you know for some reason
they've had some sort of a failure and
um you just can't still can't get the
tips another option is to use dormant
plants that you can plant directly into
the um raised beds instead and then a
third option is to basically turn um
dormant plants into plug plants and so
we'll go into each of them just a little
bit Kathy I'm sorry for interrupting but
there's one question from Paul about
what is a plug plan it sounds like
you're going to talk about that here so
sorry for
interrupting yes um no no I'm glad you
did I I failed to notice that one okay
that is a pluged plant right there and
what that is is um well I'll go into it
a little bit but but basically what you
do is you take a tip off of um off of a
a a runner that is um you know on a
mother plant and then you root it into a
medium in a tray and so it'll look like
this little vegetative plant and we'll
go I'm going to flip back forward here
um into how you do that um pretty much
you need a Miss system now I'm not going
to go into all the details here because
that could be another you know 10
minutes in itself but um there is I I
I'll call your attention to it right now
I'm down the um small fruit Consortium
down Southeast
us um
www.sfr.org
um at that site um right there um what
you can you can visit it and there is
some information on on producing your um
own plug plants um we also had um an
article back in it um in Penn State
small fruit and vegetable G vegetable
and small fruit Gazette back in June
2004 that hopefully you'll be able to
Google or use a search engine for um and
find that article but it does give you
details on how to do this but basically
what what you will do is um either
either get Runner Tips from a nursery um
you may be able to produce your own but
you do want to absolutely make sure that
those plants are clean you don't really
um you know just want them to be grown
something that you've gotten that's you
know from a planting where they're just
running out into the row middle you'd
like to be able to keep them clean with
some sort of um
some sort of way to um keep them clean
perhaps using a landscape fabric or or
plastic um on the ground but what you do
is you will cut the tips um off of off
of the runners um you want to do that
when they're just starting to to unfold
their leaves it'll take about 35 days um
from the time you cut those plants um
stick them into a growing medium um
it'll take about 35 time days from the
time you do that until you have
um and until you have um a rooted plant
that you can use um you need to do this
um like say typically we'll use um trays
that have 50 cells in them you'll want
to use a media that's fairly well
drained you'll need a way to Anchor them
um hair pins work really well actually
for just um holding that little um
Runner tip down you just leave a little
stub on it you anchor them in keep them
under Mist um that you gradually
decrease over the period of about two
two weeks um and then um you just let
them harden off um or at least you wean
them off of the Mist and then um they're
good to go so um I just just do want to
point out that you do need to make sure
you have a clean source of those and
they are fairly um you know like say
fairly easy to root yourself but you do
need to have the time and some sort of
structure to protect them so you know
there are some inputs into doing that
um the second option which is probably
um the
best best option um for Northern
production um is to use dormant plants
um there you can plant them anytime from
June through
July and um the issue with that we
talked about how plants will Runner
during the summer is that once you're on
plastic you do need to remove the
runners during the summertime so they
can go um crawling off of the plastic
stick and root in the row midds where
you don't really want them um so that's
sort of an an issue um for for them so
you'll need to do that you still have
almost a year till Harvest Time the one
thing I do want to point out if you're
using dormant plants is that um
temperature really has a big effect on
the quality of those plants so if you
get them too early um and you don't have
the conditions where you can keep them
really cold by really cold we mean 30 or
31° we don't even want them up around 35
or
36° um because they they basically will
start to use up some of their
carbohydrate reserves um at those higher
temperatures so we really want them to
stay at the nursery or in a location
where they're kept cold enough um until
you can actually plant them we've had
some Growers get into trouble where
they've lost maybe 50% of the
plants um and and you know they'll just
you know be being in a real trouble at
that point because then they have
difficulty getting getting replacement
plans so um we do want to mention that
um there is a planting tool that you can
use and rather than um try to use any
kind of a mechanical planter or anything
like that we actually do recommend
planting those um by by hand and um
basically you will use um this tool
which looks almost like a nail Pooler a
metal nail puller that you might use um
to to push the roots down in
um into the soil and that works
surprisingly well what we do is just
poke holes in the plastic first to Mark
where they're going and then use the
tool to to push the plant roots down um
into the ground and again if you go to
the
www.sfr.org website there is an article
there where they have photographs um
demonstrating how you do this and um
that their um write up is actually for
fresh dug plants which are green plants
that we can't use this far north but um
but but the principle is still the same
and the root system still is very
similar so you know that gives you an
idea of of how it works and then if you
can um water them um after planting that
really helps with getting them
established when we've used dormant
plants um you know if if the plants are
in good shape to start with and we can
get them watered in we have very good
establishment with them and it's nice to
see the the note from Kip there that um
that he can get good establishment
too so it's you know not just us in our
in our research plots um where can you
get the planting tool I'm not certain
whether Norse Farms I believe Norse
Farms may have it or they may have
instructions on how to how to make one
um I know some of our Growers if you see
what the pictures look like um it's
actually something that is fairly easy
to make yourself and and I actually did
end up using our nail Pooler um which
was about a foot long metal you you know
metal thing with a V Notch um in the end
and it it actually worked pretty well I
was a little concerned I might chop The
Roots off with it at some point um but
anyway um I have seen that boy I'm
trying to think of Indiana Berry there
were a couple places with the nurseries
where I've seen planting tools um
advertised um one other thing I want to
mention on the dormant plants is that um
there is a lot of interest in using
apigy there had been research done in
Massachusetts and and um ah Marv than um
there there was research done in
Maryland Maine and Massachusetts where
they found that apogee did increase the
number of Branch crowns and decreased
Runner production and trials so there is
grower interest in that because it
results in in higher higher yields um
but that's not a labeled use yet so I
just want Growers to be aware of that um
we're hoping that in a short per period
of time within the well relatively short
period of time within the next couple
years um that we that label may come
through all righty so dormant plants
another Advantage with them is that you
do have a choice of cultivars um a wider
choice of cultivar than you might with
plugged plants but I want to point out
that not all of the cultivars um that
can be used or work well in matted rope
production may work well in um plastic
culture
um is there a similar product to apog
for organic users not that I am aware of
um to answer that question there
um yeah that's something we may just
need to to hold off on for a while and
you know see if there's some some other
way um of dealing with that for or
organic folks in the future but I would
be surprised if anything um came through
anytime in the near future on that um
let's say c that that work um besides
Chandler that our Growers have been
happy with um Wendy LaMore um Wendy's
got a really nice flavor I'm really
impressed with the flavor and the size
on that one Lam More's just done well
for us pretty much in every aspect of
production um size quality disease
resistance the the whole nine yards and
then D select and senica are a couple of
other cultivars Growers are using that
they seem to be happy with ones that
haven't done so well um for us early
glow um all the ones I have listed there
early glow Allstar Ovation van Hanah
Gaia viota um we've had Yi low yields on
those um some of them really kick into
Runner production on the plastic and so
though they might have been a great cul
ofar and mted rope production you just
end up with a lot of Runners um in in
plastic culture and not necessarily that
much fruit now one other thing you can
do if you have a particular calar that
you really like um as as a cultivar in
matted rope production you can um get
dormant plants in that cultivar and try
plugging your own plants just you know
give it a shot see how they do we do
have a couple of Growers who are doing
that the real challenge is getting the
plants into the cells um they do need to
trim the roots a fair amount um and it's
just you know enough to get them to fit
into to some sort of cells we use larger
cells a 32 cell tray um but the cell
depth can be an issue just get them down
in far enough now the advantages of
doing this is that you do know whether
your plants are going to survive or not
fairly early on um and so you know
you're just putting plants that that are
that are doing well out in the field um
it's easy to keep a close eye on them
it's easy to take Runners off you know
when they're right there um in a
condensed location plus you can treat um
pests but again that does require some
some labor and having a structure to
protect them now other approaches other
approaches growers in the Northern or
cooler regions will use I'm holding
their plantings over for a second year
um for a second harvest Year and that
that seems to work quite well you may um
have some decrease in yields and Berry
size but some of that is just related to
management um to keeping the planting
disease and insect free um and keeping
enough n um nitrogen and water water on
the planting if you do decide to try
that that um you'll probably want to use
a heavier plastic we use a 1.25 mil
embossed plastic and that gets us
through two years um just fine um you
don't have that much cost involved in
keeping them for second year because so
much of your cost is UPF front and
typically what you'll do if you want to
do that is mow them after Fring um we
don't we do recommend that Growers don't
try for a third Harvest year um
frequently folks will get through their
second year and think that plants look
prettyy good
but they almost always get into trouble
during that third year and um I'll
explain to you a little bit why we
sometimes have yield decreases in the
second year and why we definitely will
have yield decreases in the third year
um if you look at um how a strawberry
plant grows okay the crown area is
basically a compressed stem and you will
have new Roots growing right out of um
this area right where um the the the
crown area so you'll see some of these
new roots that are coming out higher and
higher on the crown as as time goes by
um as new leaves are produced this stem
will become longer um and taller and so
what happens is as it gets higher as the
plant basically gets higher out of the
ground um you do end up with more
problems with winter
injury and then besides that we often
end up with um some problems with um
insect and disease these build up um you
may end up with additional Branch crowns
and some smaller berries on them but
again if you keep the nutrition up there
um you know you that yield decreases
into a definite in the second year now a
couple questions can you wait till the
plants go dormant in the fall and snip
off Runners
um and start them in the spring I would
think that would be a little difficult
to do um you could you could give it a
try but I really doubt that the plants
would would go that long
um because if the plants are dormant in
the
fall you're still going to have a fairly
vegetative you know Runner there and I
really think it'd be a little difficult
to keep them in good enough shape um in
until the springtime even even a period
of three or four months I think might be
a little difficult to do Marv um if you
can um if you would care to wave weigh
in on any thoughts on that one i' I'd
appreciate your thoughts there and yes
um Richard's comment went on Oriental
Beetle that seems to be more of a
problem the further east you go we've
also had some problems with strawberry
root warm is one where we've had an
issue with um in in um carrying
plantings
over so all righty um one other thing
rowers will ask about um typically
you'll put on a fall row cover um if you
do decide to go with um fall um with
fall planted or well late summer or
early fall planted plug plants um and
you are delayed um you know what do you
do in that situation it is possible to
put a fall row cover on um fairly
early um typically we will say that um
you'll apply a row cover when the
temperatures when the high temperatures
for a day or they are either in the high
60s or low 70s day after day you can
move that up by a few weeks um and and
try to get a little more growth on the
plants um and
adjust
so yeah so Marv's comment um dig them in
the fall and plant them in the spring
that that may be um you know basically
the Runner Tips just just may not be the
way you would want to go on that um but
dormant plants um might be a be a way to
go there so thank you Marv um fall BR
cover
application um just coming back to that
if you do put it on early and I mean by
uh 2 to 3 weeks um ahead of when you
normally would expect your temperatures
to your daytime highs to be in the high
60s or low 70s um if you put the rad
covers on two to three weeks ahead of
that you can make ups for some of the
yield loss by um planting the plants or
plug plants slate but um you just never
make make back the old Bloss
completely one other thing I want to
point out is if you do that for some
reason it does advance the spring
harvest season and that could be either
good um or bad there's just this
carryover effect from putting row cover
on in September that carries over and
makes the plants actually Bloom um
earlier in the springtime and that's
that was something that surprised us a
little bit I also just want to throw out
the possibility um of growing day
neutrals on plastic just because um
we've been doing work with them for
about the last three years and they seem
to really really work well on plastic um
Seascape in
particular um and so you know if you do
have an interest in growing day neutrals
or and you think you have a market for
them um for offseason berries um you
know definitely the neutrals work as
well so this isn't a system that's only
for June Bears um J neutrals the
neutrals also work well in tunnels and
um which Lewis will be talking about in
a in a little while so um R protection
I'd mentioned are cold temperatures um
choices you can hope for a consistent
Rover that may not um may not do this um
and it looks like there there are some
folks who are growing the um the day
neutrals I want to take a couple
questions here um you know our market
for day neutrals really seems to vary
with who is growing them and where they
are located um some people have had you
know have been able to sell everything
they can produce others um you know are
having trouble moving them so just seems
to depend on the situation
yes the um for de neutrals we actually
are planting the plants in the
springtime and with what we ended up
doing was using dormant plants we
plugged them ourselves in April planted
them um in May and then could get good
yields off of them for that first summer
and then um we would carry them over for
a second year and get the production off
for the following Springtime after that
the size just decreased too much to
really um be happy with with the um just
the production after that point we're
just getting a lot of small berries when
we were getting into the second half of
our second year on
plastic okay coming back to our plastic
culture the winter protection um you do
want to use row covers if you're in a
fairly warm area meaning um you know
hardiness Zone 6A 6B or or slightly
warmer than that if you get into cooler
areas um it seem seems that straw does
does help a lot with getting the plants
through the winter just putting straw on
top alone hasn't worked that well for us
um it seems to work for some other folks
we've just had difficulty with it
blowing off and maybe it's just our our
lack of consistent snow cover um to hold
it down and and the fact that we have a
windy site where our research plannings
are what's worked better for us is using
straw underneath a row cover I do want
to point out that when you put straw on
the plasticulture planting at that point
you don't really get any you know light
into the plant anymore um pretty much it
you know brings any plant activity to a
halt there but um we'll put the straw on
later than we would on a matted rope
planting normally we will pull our rope
covers on during the fall to get that
get some increased temperatures and
plant growth during the fall and that
raises the soil temperatures and so it's
going to be later that the plants are
going dormant so we are actually have
always been very close to Christmas by
the time we put our straw on um so we're
really talking the end of
December to do that and um so what we
will end up doing is actually putting
the row cover on for the fall pulling it
off putting the straw down and then
pulling the row cover back over again
and you do want the plants to be fully
dormant when you do this so they should
you know have that reddish color to them
be a bit flattened um under the neath
the row cover before you do that
okay so the other issue um Frost
protection and that's not just a
northern thing that's that's anywhere
it's a problem everywhere but what's
really worked well for us is either
using overhead irrigation um and we'll
actually put the irrigation um
sprinklers on over um top here you can
see one of the lines I think right down
through there um over top of the row
cover and the advantage of this is you
can use the row cover for a lot of the
flas protection um and it's only really
once the temperature reaches close to
freezing underneath the row cover that
you need to turn on the overhead
irrigation so that's cut the amount of
overhead irrigation we need um to about
half of what would need if we didn't
have the row cover and um you can also
use a double layer of row cover that's
what I've gone to the last few years uh
our thickness on the straw layer um you
want that to be same as in a matted row
planting about four to six inches of of
fluffed straw over top of the over top
of the
plants so let's see we're going to move
on so what are our options for making
plasticulture work um in the northeast
or cooler regions using um plug plants
if they're available certainly is good
if you can get them early enough but you
know like I say there are some issues
with that um dormant plants is the other
option carrying them over for a second
harvest year seems to work well
consistently um and then you you can
also do plasticulture in high tunnels
but there you get into more costs and
we'll let Louis get into um to that a
little bit so I just want to do
basically a A Brief Review of what um we
would what we do um and some of the
things that we've talked about to to get
a plasticulture planning to work um in
some cooler areas you know you'll start
out with your field you do the soil test
do all the things you would for any
planting um except we'll normally work
in about 60 lbs of nitrogen per acre
which is a little higher than what we
recommend for matted row production make
our raised beds in Spring early summer
sometime um ahead of time so that you
have those ready to
go and then plant dormant plants um Mid
July works well for us you need to
adjust um that for other regions the
further north you go um seems to you
seem to need to go a little earlier
further south you can go a little later
um or use plug plants um and you can use
those from either tips um that you root
yourself or from dormant plants in mid
August or tips that if you can get them
from a nursery um go through um removing
Runners keeping the planting water um
apply rad covers in the fall once
temperatures um your highs get um you
know not out of the low
70s um apply straw mulch um um to get
them through the winter in addition to
the rad covers and then in the
springtime you'll take the straw when
your soil temperature is right around
40° same time um base not same time same
stage of plant growth as you might have
um in a matted rope planting just if you
start to see the plant starting to grow
it's time to take the straw
off and then you leave your row cover
there you can pull the row cover back on
if you want to advance Harvest you can
leave row cover off if you want to delay
your Harvest definitely you want to pull
your rad cover back on for frost
protection um have your overhead
irrigation ready to go at that point
we'll start fertig gating through the uh
trickle system um 1 to two pounds
nitrogen per per week seems to well work
well for us go through Harvest um if you
want to carry them over for a second
year you can basically mow um the leaves
off the plants and that's all you'll do
but then keep them watered um resume
some of the fertigation to get them get
them going you won't need R covers for
that second fall um because you should
have plenty of plant growth out there
already but you will want to protect
them for the winter and then you just
continue um once you get um you know
into that second winter then you'll just
you know go on through with removing
straw the following spring and
harvesting and that's it in a nutshell
so um um if people wouldn't mind I think
we're going to hold the questions till
the very end just to make sure that we
have plenty of opportunity for Lewis to
to speak and Kathy I want to thank you
that was
great um let me just quickly uh change
these um pods here and put ls's
presentation up
and I'd like to introduce our second
speaker um today Lewis Dr Lewis jet is
the associate professor of horiculture
and the extension specialist for
vegetables and small fruits
at the University of West Virginia and
he's also done a lot of work in Missouri
um he had a handout that will be
available for you folks at the very last
portion of our um session and that you
can download onto your own computer and
I'll make sure to point that out to you
and then one other thing that I forgot
to share with everyone um let me just
see if I can make sure
to show this if you can follow on my
cursor if you go to full screen for
those of us um for those of us who like
to see the screen really big I'm going
to enable you to change it yourselves so
each one of you can push full screen and
make it take up the screen and then you
uh don't look at the attendee list or
the chat but that's up to you to do to
do that okay um without further Ado I'd
like to introduce Dr
jet okay thank you Laura I appreciate
you inviting me for this um webinar
series uh on on strawberry
production and um I mostly work with
vegetables u in high tunnels but the
small fruits are a new area that we've
been we've been looking at and so I want
to cover some of the integrated crop
management techniques that um you would
typically um use if you're if you're
growing strawberries within a high
tunnel I think many of you know what a
high tunnel is but for those of you who
who haven't encountered one of these
structures they're they're really just a
an advanced uh way to extend the growing
season and particularly through the
Northeast the New England Mid-Atlantic
region there's a a major uh adoption of
this type of technology to to lengthen
the growing season and to exclude pests
uh particularly organic Growers find
them u a great tool for growing crops
organic Tech Ally without pesticide use
or limited pesticide use um and um here
in the um the Mid-Atlantic region in
West Virginia and even in the midwest
where I was at
before um we were able to extend the
growing season on most crops um by 3
months but if you be really creative
with these high tunnels you can actually
get three crops within a a 12mon period
um so you're you're able to grow a lot
of food um in a very limited space uh in
a um in a in a year so that's that's
that's certainly reason why they're
becoming popular they let you grow uh
crops that you normally couldn't grow at
your uh latitude or your region and so
it opens the door for growing crops um
out of their traditional season and even
varieties that may be sensitive to cold
weather um by putting them in a high
tunnel you're protecting them from
extreme cold and you're able to grow
them much farther north than what you
normally could and then finally they're
they're used to supplement field
production so many many Growers who use
these high tunnels use them mostly for
early season production sometimes late
season production but they're also
complimenting what they're also growing
in the field so there's just a
continual uh supply of food over a very
long period of time so that's why they
have
U Been rapidly adopted and there are
many shapes and designs on high tunnels
I've seen so many permutations on size
and and U inall designs and and and
whatever but but generally um they are a
solar Greenhouse uh you're trapping um
radiant energy from the Sun and you're
using that to as I said to to advance
the growth of the crop and and generally
um most people who who Define a high
tunnels claim they only have one or
should have only one layer of plastic
but I think the farther north you go uh
a double layer of plastic on a high
tunnel is is a a great
benefit
um so you know you could either have one
or or a double layer of plastic with the
structure so uh what they what they also
do is is I said um accumulate heat over
time and this is just a a temperature
graph of u high tunnel versus ambient uh
this happens to actually be one of our
strawberry
um High tunnels and without looking at
the the actual numbers what we found is
just a single layer uh a plastic High
tunnel uh increases the average daily
temperature from 7 to 10 degrees per day
so that's that's fairly significant for
for crop growth over
time we did a survey on U what is grown
in high tunnels and these are some of
the most popular crops um I think most
of you probably would expect crops like
tomatoes and salad greens to be widely
grown High tunnels because they're high
volume long season crops with high value
uh but strawberries are becoming a
popular
crop uh for high tunnels uh and also
other small fruit such as brambles which
I think will be discussed um a little
later on in this in this webinar
series um so there's a question on
finding a a reasonably priced
temperature monitoring
system um
well the one that we are using uh to
monitor
temperature uh is just a u either a
watchdog or a u what they call a hobo
Data Logger and they can log temperature
for you and we also use wireless
thermometers um to to uh uh monitor
temperature so I'm not quite sure the
price differences between those those
different uh different types
but uh as I'll talk about later
temperature Management in these high
tunnels is crucial U because one of the
benefits as I as I said is accumulating
heat but they're also manually vented so
it's up to the operator to control
temperature as much as possible so it
can either be too hot or too cold and
that can actually be detrimental to the
the particular crop so we're going to be
talking about strawberries and I think
strawberries um are perfect crop for
high tunnels mainly because um they are
an early season crop and um I preached
to my Growers here in West Virginia that
we need more supply of early season
crops and and berries fit very well
within that that mix um the big question
is whether they're profitable to be
grown in a high tunnel and that depends
on a couple factors which I'll talk
about a little later on as farmers
markets open earlier um you there is a
strong demand for berries so early
season berries um um there is a premium
price for them uh not quite as much as
there is for early seasoned Tomatoes but
it it is fairly U fairly profitable so
why grow High tunnel strawberries well I
recommend that whenever you you choose a
crop to grow in your high tunnel and
there are there are scores of props that
you can can produce in the high tunnel
it depends on your your particular
Market but there are really two things
um two criteria that I look at when I
when I choose a crop and it has to have
high value and also high high volume or
high yield potential and there are some
crops that have high value but don't
yield much per plant and that's that's
sort of a problem so remember those two
criteria as we as we go along uh we talk
about this
crop now a lot of Growers who adopt High
tunnels uh on their Farm as I said
earlier with the survey use it for
tomatoes tomatoes grow vertically they
they yield a lot of fruit per plant uh
there's a high there's a high price for
early seasoned tomatoes so um maybe
eight out of 10 high tunnel producers U
grow
tomatoes either either entirely in the
high tunnel or in combination with other
crops in the high tunnels but
strawberries could possibly be a good
crop rotation choice for tomatoes or
complement tomato production in in the
um High
tunnel now Kathy U mentioned different
types of strawberries the day neutrals
and the short day or June Bearer types
most of my work and experience with
Growers has been with the June bearers
although I think the farther north you
go um the day neutral types have
tremendous potential uh we have just
started a project this year with growing
day neutrals in in in the high tunnels I
don't have the data compiled yet yet but
I I think particularly these types of
crop these types of strawberries that do
well in cooler weather um would be very
well suited uh to farther north such as
the day neutral
types okay uh one thing that I I highly
recommend when you grow any crop in the
high tunnel is is to make sure that you
have the soil tested prior to planting
the straw uh the strawberries in the
high tunnel um and this is just a
picture of it's kind of hard to maybe
you see what it is exactly but
U let's
see but this area through here that the
white the white area uh the the Crusty
area is actually sort of salt deposits
that build up in the high tunnel uh from
repeated fertigation of U of different
types of fertilizers and I've had a lot
of Growers um U have questions about
that whether that is you know causing
the salt levels in the soil to be very
high so we recently tested this soil and
the so the salt levels are very high
right around the emitters but the rest
of the soil does not have very high salt
levels the reason I mentioned this is um
strawberries are very sensitive to salt
um they are they will show U they will
show
damage U you can see here they will show
damage U to the
tissue uh from Salt in injury I think I
have a picture of that in a moment this
is salt damage to u to strawberries some
of the margin on the crosis on the
leaves that you see here and U so if
you're putting down a a lot of
fertilizers in high tunnels particularly
amonium nitrate or Ura you could have a
salt build up or if you're using certain
animal based uh compost animal manure
based compost you can have high salts
too so just something to to be aware of
so have your compost tested um as I
showed earlier this is compost that we
put in our high tunnel or one of our
high tunnels um as a soil amendment it's
an animal manure based compost and uh
again like I said it's important to have
that tested either at the U your local
uh State uh land grant uh so testing lab
or private
lab
um is there a difference between ever
bearing and neutral strawberries uh I
think yes there is I know Marvin Prince
would have a better answer for that than
I would but uh most of the varieties you
know that we have looked at have been
strictly I think day neutral types the
ever bear types um which are still
um does everybody hear Louis now I I
lost him there for a second and I I
think you're okay now
okay good all right um the other thing
too to remember is if you are using
compost if you are inclined to use more
organic amendments is to have the
compost tested uh not only as I said for
salts but also for pH and other other
nutrients most composts is 1 to 2% uh
nitrogen it can be very high in
potassium and sometimes phosphorus uh
depending on the source and uh
surprising to some um folks it can have
also very high pH so using too much
compost can actually create problems for
crops like U like strawberry so but you
can also use synthetic fertilizers to
amend the soil now when we we grow crops
in the high tunnel um the crop is grown
directly in the soil under the structure
now I I have nothing against using
soless uh mixes and I know there's some
folks here that that use the uh compost
bags and which I think have great
potential particularly if you can't move
the high tunnel or you aren't able to
leech um the soil in the high tunnel
enough um through natural rainfall so I
see some potential for using soiless
systems in high tunnels um and I don't
entirely rule them out although you know
the majority of rowers are using the the
native soil underneath the structure to
grow the crop and if possible the U uh
the strawberry should be placed on
raised beds and these are these can be
made manually uh which we have a lot of
Growers do and then they um there are
some companies that sell a compact bed
shaper which makes a really nice uh
Crown bed that you can you can plan on
uh in the high tunnel so similar to
this or you can use a flat U flat row
system but generally I like to use U
raised bed the AL PL planning date U is
really dependent upon your region of the
country and U uh you know like I said
it's very difficult to generalize with
there's so many different different U uh
folks here on the in the
meeting but I think one way to look at
it maybe as a rule of thumb is to look
at your your your field planning date
and um the high tunnel gives you almost
an extra month so your planning Windows
expanded by three maybe perhaps 4 weeks
um over what your your field planning
date is for these these particular types
of strawberries so that's one of the
reasons why you know people like high
tunnel production is it gives you just a
larger
window um to u to get your crops planted
so as Kathy was saying if it's difficult
to get plugs that early in August in
early August or even Late July in some
regions well with a high tunnel you have
a longer plan window you can perhaps get
plugs a little bit later in the year so
um but the problem is if you plant too
late she mentioned you just don't get
the U uh the vegetative growth and the
flowerbud
initiation uh in the fall and your
yields are dramatically reduced so
sometimes it's trial and error and I
know some folks may be in your region
have been doing some research for
planning dates and that's that's
probably something you should look
at different planning um Arrangements on
um High tunnel strawberries uh go with a
two row bed uh or more but if you're
using a two row bed uh recommend putting
on two U two lines of drip tape uh on
the uh on the bed so for every row of U
of berries you have in the high tunnel
you should have one row of drip tape
because uh again you're protecting the
crop from rain and the crops entirely
dependent upon you for water so you want
to make sure that you're providing
enough water and nut nutrients to the
crop so um particularly if you move to a
three or four row bed on strawberries uh
you need to have you know three to four
drip lines per per
bed um so anyway that's U that's typical
planning Arrangement there some Growers
have tried four row beds and we have
tried it uh as well in some of our
research
the problem you get into with these high
tunnels is that you're looking at 2 to
3,000 square ft in the high tunnel or if
you move to a ha grve system where you
have you know multiple Bays you can have
larger area but the the inclination is
to crowd plants in there and I think
that's a mistake um because you can get
more production from less from an
optimal plant population than you could
by just really packing plants in tight
so that's what we found with the four
row bed uh on strawberry
is that you're actually you're paying
you're you're paying more for for extra
plants but you're not getting that extra
yield um so we have found a two or three
row bed to be optimal uh for um for
planting um in these these uh these
structures okay so how many plants can
you can you get in there you can get
anywhere from, 1500 to 2,000 strawberry
plants uh per Commercial High
tunnel and and this would be a typical
spacing uh I sort of like to go almost
equidistant uh between plants and
between rows 12 to 15 in between plants
and and the same the uh the same
distance between rows on the bed and
sort of a typical uh staggered uh
planning Arrangement like this and I
think that would be
ideal with of the bed can be anywhere
from uh 24 in to as wide as almost 40 42
in
wide and
um this is a four row bed with three
drip lines per bed and the plants are
very crowded in there and it's led
to some aphid
problems so Lis excuse me um uh shiaka
county has a question that I think is
pretty pertinent about how big is that
tunnel do you know the measurements of
the
tunnel well most of the tunnels that uh
that we've been working with or using
our research are 20 to 30 feet wide and
96 feet long so that's a typical okay
thank you and I think it looks like you
might be starting to talk about sug
weise's question um talking about
substrate systems that she asked and it
looks like you might touch on that
now well yeah I just my only comment
about it is I mean we have just started
this year growing um strawberries in um
elevated gutters and I don't have data
to share on that but you know there's
some interest in sort of the vertical
growing systems in these high tunnels
and um I think there's some potential
there but there have been some problems
with uh with yield um per plant so
someone needs to to really work up uh a
design where there's less U shading by
individual plants and the yield levels
are high uh you know from top to bottom
there was a recent article in the
vegetable Growers news I believe it was
in the June issue where the grower up in
Michigan was was looking at vertical
growing systems and actually he's he is
designed um system he thinks works but I
think that's some of the issues that we
need to to look at in the future is is
growing these plants more vertically
getting more plants and also getting
higher yield per plant because if you're
just growing a just in a flat system in
the in the soil as I said you can get a
fixed optimal number of plants but um at
some point your yield level has to be
high enough to make it
profitable um Capital cost per square
foot of a high tunnel um generally um
they're $2 to $3 per square foot uh is
is is generally what the average and
they I said there's a lot of variance in
in that estimate too because U uh it
depending on whether it's a manufactured
High tunnel or a homemade High tunnel U
the cost can be can be pretty uh pretty
wide but what a lot of our Growers have
been doing uh and I think it might be
the case throughout the the Northeast is
poaching U old greenhouse frames from U
nurseries or Greenhouse businesses that
are going out of out of business and
then using those frames for high tunnels
and all they have to do is just add a u
a hip board to it so that they can roll
up the side and get cross
ventilation okay so
um well I think it depends like I said
on a on a 30 by 96 High tunnel the the
one that we are about ready to put
plastic on in about 2 weeks it's
probably cost around
$7,000 uh with every every component to
it but um again like I said that that
that that price varies depending on the
on the manufacturer
um the varieties that you can choose
from are um you know they're Fair wide
group of
varieties these particular varieties um
are ones that are bred primarily for
plastic culture and of course you're
probably familiar with most most of
these uh Chandler Camaros and sweet
Charlie and Ventana and even Festival
those are the ones that we've grown in
the high tunnels but I I think there's
there's a lot of potential for other
short day varieties that c Kathy
mentioned such as the Wendy LaMore Dar
select and the cica um as varieties that
could be potentially later than these
varieties and so a mix of these
varieties plus some of those uh other
June Bearer varieties could give you a
longer production season but our our
most uh consistent variety has been
Chandler um and I know it's been tried
and tested in many regions of the
country but it it it seems that's not
Chandler in the picture there but
Festival actually but uh it it seems to
to have consistently high yields um and
the flavor that U most Growers like for
for uh for local markets so um but I
think the U the other varieties that
were mentioned uh could could certainly
complement Chandler as varieties to add
to your high tunnel so the uh the reason
I mentioned the uh plants um I me uh
um yes I was just doting the comment on
using the old hoop houses that were
modified I I think that's that certainly
is is the way to to uh start into high
tunnel production is to is to recycle um
frames as much as possible and U and and
and then that way you can you can
certainly cut the the the startup costs
because they're immediately profitable
and you can recover your cost within a
year and then if you want to you know
purchase a a brand new frame the
following year you certainly would have
the money to do it um just sort of
adding on to what Kathy was saying about
um plants for for growing strawberries
or plant sources or plant types um I I
mention this because um the single
biggest production cost of growing
strawberries in high tunnel is plant
costs um so you have some choices here
on different types of plants that you
can that you can uh use use you can buy
your own Runner Tips and and root the
plugs yourself and um or you can get be
root plants uh or you can get plugs
ready to plant and we we've done all
three so um the most economical uh is
probably going to be rooting your own
Runner Tips if you can get Runner Tips
in time but like I said because your
planting Windows been expanded by the
use of the high tunnel you have more
time to get plant material um for the uh
for your high tunnel structure
okay and these are some strawberry plant
suppliers laori mentioned the handout
that I um I have that companies this
presentation that all this is is is
listed within that
um um in that uh that
handout well okay the question was um
2,000 plants one pounds of strawberries
per plant um in the ground for 4 to 6
months that's that's approximately
correct I mean uh one pound per plant it
should be your your base your base yield
it should be the yield that you should
at least get um if you're not getting a
pound per plant um the economics just
don't U don't work out for high tunnel
strawberries so you should be somewhere
in the in the 1 and a half pound range
um I believe uh that actually with some
of these day neutral types although they
have a longer production season longer
picking season you can actually get
close to 2 lbs per plant but for these
June bear types you should be getting at
least a pound in order for this to cash
flow um and to to to make it profitable
for high tunnels because for every crop
that you choose in a high tunnel there's
another Cho there's another crop choice
that can replace it so they have to be
profitable uh for that to to be a good
choice uh just the cycle on on growing
the plants in the in the uh in the high
tunnel structure generally for the
varieties that I mentioned earlier such
as Chandler camarosa they're planted in
the fall uh and the planting date could
be anywhere from Late July through mid
September depending on your on your
region but they're planted they grow
through the fall uh the high tunnel
keeps them warm they put on good
vegetative growth they they they they uh
develop Branch crowns and then um row
covers are sort of interesting to use in
a high tunnel because um there really is
no exact formula for using them like
what Kathy was saying with the field uh
field
production um actually by using rad
covers in high tunnels you can get you
know very early flowering on some of
these varieties and um some of these
varieties such as sweet Charlie have
very shallow dormy or no dorcy at all
and so they will actually fly in January
or February if if it uh if it's warm
enough um so you can lose uh production
because of early flowering so you don't
want to put the row cover uh on these
high tunnel strawberries too
early um and we use a medium weigh uh to
heavyweight row cover which is 1 o to 1
and a/4 ounce um row cover we find that
to be most effective but um I I think I
think I can speak generally and say that
you shouldn't use a row cover in a high
tunnel before December I think that's a
that's a pretty safe uh thing to
say now we have used it um in our
project primarily for extreme freeze
protection so if the if the U ambient
temperature was going to get um below 20
fight we would be using row covers for
protection on that uh but we would not
keep the row covers on the on the
strawberries
continually um and we would use it the
following spring when um they begin to
flour so for frost protection so we were
sort of um using it uh intermittently
through the U through the uh the
season so um again like I said you don't
you don't want to to use it uh use it to
soon a lot of Growers use either the
floating row cover cover or we use a low
tunnel which is supported by hoops and
um either way is can be used although
you do get more uh heat built up with a
with a low tunnel versus just a floating
row cover
okay uh now generally when the plants
are going into dormy in December in the
high
tunnel um you know they sort of flatten
out and we like to see about four to
five Branch crowns on the on on the uh
the uh the strawberries and the the
diameter of the rosette uh should be
about 5 to 6 Ines in uh in length and
that's a
good you know starting point for how uh
how your plant should be going into
dormy problem that we had last year uh
with a lot of Growers is they U we had a
very cloudy fall and we didn't get a lot
of um of U growth in the fall so yields
were much lower this year here for a lot
of Growers so that that is something
that could could be a problem in certain
areas um if you plant too early in the
high tunnel you can get Runner
production um and that's something that
you don't want on plastic because these
these plants are grown on plastic mulch
under a plastic cover and there's no
place for the runners to root and you're
not creating a matted row so you want to
just have one Central uh mother plant
producing large fruit from five five
Branch crowns roughly 10 flowers per
Branch CR but no daughter plants so
you'll need to pull those daughter
plants
off probably a good indication that
you're keeping your high tunnel too warm
is you're getting you're getting Runner
production so uh that that would be an
indication of of maybe poor temperature
management which leads me into this
issue of temperature Management in the
high tunnel because this always
surprises Growers at how much time they
have to spend uh adjusting the vents um
in these structures so you see the vents
on on these high tunnels on the side and
um you know you generally want to keep
um the high tunnel on the cool side for
strawberries because they are a cool
seasoned crop so uh you know in days
where it might get warm and in in the
late fall or even winter days where the
temperatur can get warm um you know you
may need to vent it so U rolling up the
sides is not a is is not uh a bad thing
to do even in the uh the middle of
winter uh is there more heat
accumulation under high tunnels or low
tunnels well
U um the thing about that is using low
tunnels within High tunnels is extremely
effective so I mean you're you're going
to get it's sort of uh you know
synergism between the two that you get
even more but you had a low tunnel out
in the
field um you know they do increase the
the air temperature around the plant but
eventually they they reach the ambient
temperature much faster than what a high
tunnel would but when you put them in a
high tunnel you almost double the
effectiveness of the row cover so um you
know that's that's one of the advantages
of using low tunnels within within High
tunnels um okay so also as I said if
you're if you're not Ting your high
tunnel um adequately you can get
premature flowering um on some of these
varieties and um the flowers are
immediately Frozen and that's lost yield
uh from the
plant there are some Growers that that
will use backup heaters in high Tunnels
for a lot of crops and the backup
heaters that are used for strawberries
are only used for frost protection uh
but but generally if you use row covers
if you put your row cover on early
enough in the day before uh it gets cold
at night you can trap enough heat under
the row cover within the high tunnel to
prevent um damage from a frost or a
light freeze if temperatures got down
into the teens if you had a single layer
of plastic you would need a backup
heater uh to to prevent
damage okay so um then take uh routine
tissue samples I I highly recommend that
that's done primarily at at first
flowering uh the following
spring and uh we take about 20 U leaf
and pedal samples a per variety per High
tunnel that's usually enough to get you
a test and you can send it to either
your diagnos or your your soil Plant
Nutrition lab on campus or uh through a
private lab such as this pollination is
an issue on on strawberries and a lot of
crops within High tunnels because U the
flowering is um so
early that uh a lot of the natural
pollinators aren't active yet so
uh a lot of in our case in the
midatlantic in the um Midwest um these
high tunnel strawberries would start
flowering in mid to late March well
that's usually well before most natural
pollinators become become available so
uh the strawberries need to get
pollinated either by air movement or by
bringing in pollinators
yourself so uh the question was could an
overhead sprinklers be used for frost
protection in high tunnel um yeah I
suppose they could um although u i I
really haven't used a lot of overhead
watering in the high tunnel uh you most
of the the watering is done through
through drip irrigation but that
certainly is one one thing that you can
do I I suppose if you could keep the
water from freezing on the plastic uh or
anything like that that would cause any
damage to the to the U the uh poly or or
any the the structure like
that so U to solve the pollination um
issue you can purchase a Class C uh Hive
which has two or 300 drones in it um and
uh or you can actually get small nuke
boxes of honeybees but uh the U the uh
bumblebees are are very effective
pollinators for for
strawberries and if you don't get good
pollination or if the temperature is
very cool when it's a uh when they're
fllying you can often get misshaping
fruit which is uh something you you
don't want you want good quality uniform
fruit such as this this is all high
tunnel strawberries that you're seeing
now um and the frequency of harvest uh
generally for these these June bearing
types um
that you're looking at about a a four a
excuse me a 6 to 10 week period of
harvest but if you if you include day
neutrals in uh you can uh you can
certainly extend that some things to
consider on that's I'm running out of
time on The Pest Management is spider
mites and petritis grey mold spidermite
is the most chronic problem we've had
with growing strawberries in high
tunnels and this is some typical
symptoms of spidermites usually they
develop within a a specific uh
area the hot spot usually the center of
the high tunnel where it's warmest but
uh we have been doing work with uh uh
using predatory mites to control um
spotted uh spider mites in high tunnels
and it's been very effective the
threshold is five five mites per Leaf U
and by using fyto which is a predatory M
we were able to bring that threshold
down uh to or bring that KN level down
to below the threshold
so there's a perfect place to use
predatory um insects or mites is the
high tunnel because you an enclosed area
you have a very small space and the uh
the uh the insects or mites work very
effectively in those hot spots this is
particularly a problem if you're growing
mixed crops in high tunnels there's a
center a row of strawberries here and a
lot of different types of flowers you
can use predatory mites to control um
mites on not only strawberry but also
these other
crops we've used uh lady beetles too
aphids are a problem if you're over
fertilizing with nitrogen or if you have
too uh too much Lush growth on the uh on
the U the the plant this is petritis
grey mold which usually occurs you're in
Cloudy cool damp weather uh we like to
remove all the Dead Leaves as much as
possible this is substrate for Bettis so
uh you want to you want to keep those
under control there's some weed growth
that occurs typically winter annual weed
such as chick weed um occurs around the
planting hole that sometimes need to be
be weeded one of our other serious
problems is vs or Meadow mice and they
will get underneath the plastic they'll
overwind in the high tunnel and they'll
actually chew on the crown so um that's
that's an issue to face in the high
tunnels but you don't get deer damage uh
like this so uh there's one advantage of
the high tunnels uh for strawberry
Growers you do not get uh deer browsing
on the U on the there so um the yields
are 1.2 to 1.3 lb I'd like to be around
1.5 lbs per per plant if you can get
that yield level and you can get a price
of $3 to $4 per pound which is what most
Growers have been getting high tunnel
strawberries can be very profitable but
you have to get that yield level and you
have to get that price range if you look
at the handout it has all the production
costs and the different
returns for different prices and yields
on strawberries that you can look at and
see if you're actually uh making a
profit or not so I will close it there
and U certainly want to visit maybe the
Cornell High tunnel website and our high
tunnel website that uh sort of um
accumulates information from a lot of
different Louis thank thank you very
much um and I appreciate I'm sorry to
have to kind of move this along but we
have a limited time and I um what I'm
going to do here we're moving into the
final aspect of the talk there are three
polls that I'd love if people just
wanted to give some response um to this
information while we finish up and then
in the file share the upper right corner
are several different um one is the
handout that was sent to you in advance
uh from Kathy Dem and then the other two
are similar but slightly different um uh
handouts from Dr Lewis jet about high
tunnel growing and so you can upload
those to your own computer um the other
thing I want to remind everyone of is on
Tuesday September 22nd we have a um
insect uh strawberry insect um pest uh
discussion uh Dr Richard Kohl's from the
University of Connecticut and Dr Greg
lob from Cornell University are going to
be talking about
um root weevils and sap Beetle and
tarnish plant bug respectively and I do
hope um all of you will get that
announcement for connection and if you
can make it wonderful uh if you can't
just disregard the announcement but we
decided to start sending because we're
getting so much activity for the
registration it was just easier to keep
all of you in one list and send it out
um but before we log off if anybody else
has any questions for either Kathy demek
or Lewis jet um we could take those now
just for a couple of extra
minutes um I know there was one question
that was a asked several times um what
is the difference between uh oh Kathy
answered that great um no real
difference for between day neutral and
everbearing um Pro possibly day
neutral might not be quite
correct and
yeah um yeah all it is is really the day
neutrals aren't really day neutrals and
right now there seems to be moved them
all repeat flowering which okay great
that's good to know so proba all right
does anyone else have uh okay Heather
Bryant what is the optimum pH for
growing
strawberries do either of
you I can okay good that was what I was
going to
say
weally um is there any other questions
it looks like a couple people are typing
rapidly gwy Smith forever bearers if I
want to overwinter do they need to be
renovated like June
bearers no not on plastic
yep um no uh any other questions looks
like people have stopped typing and most
people have responded to the polls and
um I think that's it then we made it
just in the nick of time for the log off
and I really want to thank again the
Northeast IPM Center for funding this um
series of webinars I want to thank Kathy
demek of uh Penn State University and uh
Dr Lewis jet from West Virginia
University for their
participation and I look forward to
seeing all of you or some of you on
Tuesday September 22nd and if any of you
have any comments and would like to
email me please feel free to do that
thank you again for your participation
that
h
[Music]
okay Laura are you still
there
leis for