to we're
gonna person up there I'm sorry we're
going to start with Dr Marvin
pritz and Dr pritz is um holds a faculty
position at Cornell uh that has research
and teaching and extension
responsibilities his primary extension
he is the primary extension Leon for the
New York State producers and he's also
the chair of the Department of
horiculture and let me get his
talk up
here before Dr prit starts I do want to
let you folks know that I have um
enabled you to put the full screen on so
that you can do that if you'd like or
you can um keep it as a a shorter
screen and I'm sorry we seem to have
lost the chat box so let me see if I can
get that back I don't know what happened
to
that a few little things
here
all right so now we have the um ability
for you folks to ask questions during
the
presentation you can also just put the
full screen on and just listen and um
okay well happy Halloween everybody
going to turn it over to you and we want
to talk today about weed management and
berries and it's a topic that get lots
and lots of questions about uh we've
done some work on budgeting and
strawberries and we find that managing
weeds is the greatest expense that
strawberry Growers incur except for
actually harvesting the fruit and
sometimes when we've done uh analysis we
found it up to 70% of the labor cost
that Growers spend involves weed
management and part of that is because
we grow our strawberries under matted
row and we have Fields like this that
are pretty much bare F we put our little
strawberry plants in there and then we
hope that they produce Runners during
the year and fill in but when you look
at that field you find that there's lots
of be ground and lots of opportunities
for we to come in during that time that
strawberries are trying to grow and
establish themselves most of the
problems we have are in that first year
where there's a lot of bare ground in
the Strawberry Fields and we don't have
a whole lot of very good herbicides
although that's changing a little bit
now uh more recently we've gotten some
materials that Dr Blinder is going to
share with you in a few minutes but
we're going to talk about matad Rose
first so we have all this bearr uh
people go and they cut the flowers off
to encourage the runners to fill in the
runners fill in between the rows but
again even during this these first
several months there's a lot of bare
ground out there and a lot of
opportunities for weeds to establish
themselves particularly when we irrigate
and uh water the ground in between the
strawberries and we'll occasionally get
lots of weeds growing between the rows
and uh even more weeds growing between
the rows and then this is when we get
calls from Growers and I'll say what can
I do I've got weeds in my strawberries
well uh it's often pretty late to do
much about it by then but that's often
times when we get the call so what we
want to do today is sort of think about
some ways we might be able to manage our
weeds without waiting till we get to a
point like that now fumigation is
something that used to be a little bit
more popular than it is now part of the
reason for that is that fumigation
methyl bromide in particular is being
phased out and it's becoming very
expensive so Growers that used to use it
for weed management practice are finding
well that's just a little bit too
expensive for me to do that plus the
plastic is difficult to dispose
of the black plastic mulches are used in
a lot of annual production systems and
there's a photograph in Florida where
they use black plastic and that helps
control the weeds too but one of the
problems with that is is a disposal
problem and I don't know what it's like
in your state but just this month in New
York they passed a law that saying you
can't burn anymore no open burning and a
lot of Growers would dispose of their
plastic by open burning so we can't do
that anymore so this material is left to
accumulate if you don't have a way to
recycle it and
I did some calculations a couple years
ago for a presentation I was going to
give and I realized that strawberry
Growers alone use enough plastic each
year to circle the Earth 13 times so
that's a lot that's a lot of plastic so
the question that we're interested in is
are the ways of preventing weeds in
strawberries without using a lot of
plastic without using fumigation without
using a lot of
Labor there's really three strategies uh
pretty obvious one is deplete the weed
seed bank and prevent seed dispersal to
the field in other words try not to get
weeds into the field before you start
secondly prevent germination and or
establishment once you have the berries
in the ground and then thirdly uh remove
weeds that appear and unfortunately most
people wait till that third step and
then try to figure out how to remove
weeds that appear without putting a lot
of effort into the first
two one of the experiments we did a few
years ago was looking at replant disease
in strawberries and we had an old
strawberry field we took it out of
strawberries and then we planted eight
different treatments into that old
strawberry field and then we planted
strawberries after these twoyear
rotations in between the strawberries so
for example we had uh mode weedy
fumigation alphalpha mustard kale sweet
corn raw you can read the treatments up
there and we also had continuous
strawberry and then we took these cover
crops out and we planted strawberries
again and have a lot of data here on how
these plants responded and root
pathogens and everything like that but I
just wanted to show you the data on the
weediness of the treatments after these
cover crops and this would be in the
first year that strawberries were
growing so the First Column you see is
sort of a methyl bromide fumigation
treatment this is about as good as it
gets when you fumigate and implant your
strawberries very few weeds and some of
the treatments had a lot of weeds like
when you go right in with strawberries
and follow strawberries again or you mow
you don't do anything except mow the
weeds that doesn't really help a lot but
what I wanted to point out was that some
of these treatments like kale sweet corn
Rye rotation or rotation of mustards did
a pretty good job at managing weeds and
suppressing weeds in that first year and
it was certainly a lot less expensive
and had a lot less environmental impact
than methyl bromite fumigation so that
was a good
thing one of the questions we wanted to
ask ourselves or several questions but
when you have weeds and strawberries
like how much weed growth is acceptable
how much can a grower tolerate uh is the
only good weed a dead weed are there
times when weed growth can be tolerated
and there are times when weeds are very
competitive with strawberry plants so
the way we try to answer that question
was we took a first year strawberry
field and we divided up into plots and
we had uh weeds growing in those plots
for specific lengths of time and for
specific months of the year so for
example we had weeds growing just during
the month of June and then for the rest
of the season we removed the weeds by
hand uh just for the month of July just
for August just for September and then
we had combinations of two months and
then combinations of three months and
then we had weeds all year long and then
we let the strawberries go through the
winter and in The Following season in
the first year we harvested the plants
to see what impact the weeds in the
first year had on yields the second year
so here are some of the plot
see some are weedi and some aren't and
these are the data here the way you read
this is that if there's an X that means
weeds were present in each of those
months and so here we have weeds present
June July August and September basically
all year long those plants the following
year those plots produce one Runner and
292 grams of
fruit and uh you can see how this was
set up three months two months one month
but what so the first thing I want to do
is look at the one month periods so
these are weeds in June weeds just in
July just in August and just in
September let's go over here and look at
Runner production and we can see that
the later the weeds were present the
more Runners we had and the same way
with yields yields were higher if the
one month of weed pressure was late in
the season relative to one month early
in the
season we can do the same thing when we
look at a TW month period of weed so
here are weeds in June and July we can
look at our yield a little over th000
grams per plot but if we had the same
two months of weed pressure but later in
the season our yields were two and a
half times as much and we can see the
same pattern with Runners a lot more
Runners when the weeds were late
compared to when the weed pressure was
early and we can do the same thing for
three months of weed pressure uh very
little yield but when the three months
of weed pressure was later about three
or four times as much yield and we've
done this experiment for a couple of
different years and it's pretty clear
that in first year plannings early
season weed pressure is much worse than
late season weed pressure so getting the
weeds out of those first year plannings
early really can make a difference weeds
later in the season uh not so much of an
impact so how do you keep those weeds
out well we did it by hand but that's a
lot of work are there other ways that
you can use cultivation to remove weeds
early in the season when they're most
problematic well there are lots of
different tools out there to manage
weeds and strawberry Growers tend to use
a Rota tiller and herbicides but there's
some other tools out there that look
like they might have some potential in
strawberries so we wanted to see how
those those work so this is a standard
way that Growers cultivate their
strawberries they take a multivator road
tiller get down the rose but the problem
with that device is that on the
downstroke it compacts the soil and
makes a compacted layer about 6 in down
and on the stroke it just brings wheed
seeds up to the surface and lets them
germinate what would be better is if you
could do some shallow cultivation where
you're only cultivating the first couple
of inches rather than uh all the way
down and bringing wheat seeds to the
surface and some of these tools do that
these finger weers uh shallowly
cultivate around the plants now these
are onions not strawberries but you can
see the
principle gets right up close to the
plant these Flex T Harrows shallow
cultivate they don't bring weed Seas up
to the
surface and you just drive this device
relatively quickly over the field these
times vibrate back and forth and knock
the small weeds
out out of the
ground this is something called a Reggie
weeder and the way this works is you sit
in the back here and you pull along you
straddle the row and the operator pulls
these um Wheels in and out and they spin
and they move uh spin the weeds out from
around the plant so you can just move it
in and out as you go down the
row and this device here spins and you
can see it only cultivates real
shallowly and it doesn't bring weed
seeds up to the
surface we've had real good luck with
that in strawberries and then also this
device here which is called a brush ho
and the way this thing works it's like a
giant street sweeper it mounts on the
back of a tractor and these wheels spin
and they spin the weeds out as you go
over the row and straddle the row also
it kicks up a little bit of dust that
settles back down onto the top of the
row and it almost acts like a mulch
layer of
dust here you see it sweeping through
some uh cabbage and it kicks up some
dust it sweeps out the weeds and it
makes this layer of dust back on the
ground and here is the the brush ho
after it's gone over a young pled into
strawberries you can see it's done a
pretty good job of sweeping out the
weeds and that leaves this layer of dust
on the top which seems to prevent
subsequent weeds from germinating so I'm
going to show you some sequence of
photos here that look at some of the
different ways that weeds have been
managed in firste strawberries using
these different
tools so here's a a weed management tool
this is Devol after planting so you can
see the strawberry rose here and the
Devol was applied and then that was it
walked away from it couple of uh several
weeks later you come back and you're
getting some weeds going into
strawberries that's if you do nothing at
all this is sort of the standard way
that Growers would do it they might use
some Devol but then they would come in
with a multiv Vader and go through and
rotor tail between the rows and of
course that knocks down the weeds and
you're left with a situation like this
so it's pretty clean but it did use that
multivator and generally this area here
will regrow weeds very quickly after
you're done multiva as soon as it rains
again you'll get weed coming up in this
area
here this is a flex time Harrow this is
the one that I showed you that vibrates
when you drive over the rose it vibrates
the the small weeds out of the ground
and it does a pretty good job in the
first several weeks after strawberries
are planted you can see it keeps the
planting really clean here we didn't do
anything here no hand weeding we just
drove over it with the flex T Harrow
every few weeks now you can't let the
weeds get Too Tall or this won't work
the weeds have to stay small almost in
the codal stage but it's a good way to
cultivate
shallowly the difficulty we found with
this Flex Harrow that once the runners
start to form in a strawberry you can't
use it anymore because the runners get
caught up in the timeses and we get lots
of weeds at the end of the season if
we've used this Flex T Harrow it doesn't
it just stimulates a lot of weed
germination we get lots of weeds at the
end and we'll contrast that with the
brush ho where this is early in the
season and again very few weeds between
the rows and late in the season the same
thing very few weeds between the rows
even though these were not hand uh
pulled afterwards this is just a tool
the flex T Harrow stimulates we growth
particular after you're done using it
the brush ho seems to keep the weed
suppressed a little bit longer uh
probably because of that layer of of
dust that's formed on top of
that here's some data on the weed
biomass from these different treat
treatments the
multivator you know really knocks down
the weeds you don't get many weeds the
flex T Harrow uh gave us lots of weeds
and you saw a photo of that before that
even when we use the flex Harrow then
add herbicide we still get quite a few
weeds the finger weeder did a pretty
good job of reducing weeds same as a
brush ho so these were very effective
the herbicide alone you know doesn't
give us a whole lot of weed suppression
and but if you use an herbicide and a
multivator this is more or less the
standard practice that Growers use it
does keep the we down a lot but the
question is you know how much does it
cost to do that how many times you have
to go over the field and what are your
yields and so impacted by that so here
are the yields from the multivator and
you know reasonable yields here uh but
the yields are even better with a finger
weer and some herbicides even this Flex
T Harrow if we use it early on to keep
the weeds out and then use an herbicide
you know the yields are pretty high
remember these plots were kind of weedy
but they were weedy at the end of the
season not at the beginning of the
Season as long as we keep the weeds out
at the beginning of the Season you know
the yields can to be pretty high even if
they're weedier later
on if we go down here to the herbicide
you know the herbicide alone doesn't
give you enough weed suppression you
definitely get an impact on yield so we
can't just rely on herbicides to manage
our weeds and strawberries we got use
some cultivation too and here's a
standard practice herbicide plus uh the
multivator so although the brush ho and
the finger weeder were more expensive to
use than a single herbal side
application about ,000 each in terms of
all your labor and costs everything
going into that they're much more
effective at controlling weeds and
$1,000 worth of strawberries isn't that
much so you can easily make up for that
by using one of the these tools the
brush ho was also more effective and
cheaper to run $300 for the year than
standard cultivation because it required
far few passes only three passes through
the field and two hand weedings and no
herbicides and we were able to keep the
field really really clean whereas with
standard uh Roto tilling we had to go
through more times and we had to do more
hand weedings the disadvantage of a
brush ho is its initial
expense
so let's look at another strategy and
that's planting strawberries through
killed sods so rather than have a bare
field where you plant your strawberries
and then you wait a whole year for those
Runners to establish and you have all
that bare soil the idea here is almost
like no till planting establish a cover
crop kill the cover crop plant the
strawberries into that cover crop and
then see how well your Weis is depressed
and and how well the strawberry plants
grow so here's the
field you can see different cover crops
growing here here's Harry vet uh this
looks like Rye uh there's a bunch of
different types of cover crops out here
and so what we did was we grew these in
the fall through the winter the
following spring we sprayed them out and
then we planted strawberries in a narrow
sort of ribbon row into these various
mulches so you can see them going across
here
and we looked at what happened after
that so here's a planning of uh which
was killed side we added a little bit of
straw to the
surface and we added some
herbicide and pre-emergent herbicide and
it keeps the weeds down really really
well for that first year and you don't
have to go in and cultivate you don't
have to go in and add additional
herbicide here's a plot that had no
herbicide it was just killed rye and the
strawberries are planted into that
killed
rye and it's very clean here's another
plot very clean relative to some of
these other plots which are more uh
treated normally with some cultivation
and this is nut sge here a lot of this
is nut sge and it's a pretty bad weed
but you can see with this treatment here
uh it's does a pretty good job of
suppressing
it so again a closeup of ribbon row and
and
killed Rye residue and straw malts put
on top of that for the first year and
this is a second year planning and you
can see the with no hand weeding no
cultivation or anything no herbicides
the second year the plants look pretty
darn good considering that we didn't do
a whole lot of we didn't have a whole
lot of weed input into that so I think
that this is something that we can think
about and Growers should consider
particularly as the cost of some of
these materials go up the challenge has
been planting these strawberries into
the killed sod we had to do this by hand
uh we took the times off a rototiller
and left one little Ro one t on there so
we could do a little strip but more
recently they have some tools now that
actually can cut a Groove into the sod
and then plant noil into these killed
sods and it works a lot better than some
of the tools we used to have and these
are pretty new pretty expensive but the
point is the technology is coming along
that we ought to be able to do this in a
few years without a whole lot of
effort the last strategy I wanted to
mention was interplanted cover crops and
this would be something you do after the
strawberries are growing for a couple of
years again after harvest you renovate
the strawberries you mow off the leaves
you cultivate in between the rows and
then again you have this be ground
situation for the rest of the season
that you try to keep the weeds out of
and right after renovation you you mow
the leaves off you cultivate then the
recommendation is to come in and put on
sinbar or Devol or some material to keep
the weeds from growing in between the
rows we ask ourselves a question why
can't we plant something between the
rows that we'd rather have than a bunch
of weeds and if we plant that crop and
it's something that crowds out the weeds
but then dies itself it might not be so
much of a problem to have something in
there that dies off and doesn't allow
weeds to grow so here's a field where we
have weat the strawberry plants in an
established bed and between the rows of
strawberries we planted Sudan
grass you plant the Sudan grass after
renovation Late July early August it
grows up and then in late September
early October it dies because of frosts
come so then the following season or
actually later on that year you have
these strawberry rows you have a bunch
of dead residue in between them from the
sedan grass but you don't don't have any
weeds because the San grass displaced
them and in the following spring this
residue disappears over the winter or
you mulch the plants anyway with
straw and the following year you have
planting that looks just like this you
can see the sedan grass residue still
here but it's relatively clean from
Weeds so these are some strategies that
we've used to think about managing weeds
and strawberries without relying so much
on herbicides so just to review uh cover
crops or crop rotations to reduce weed
pressure before planting we find that
grain crops such as sweet corn are
really good in a rotation because a
couple of reasons one is they have a
very different growth habitant
strawberries so the weeds that grow
between corn tend to be different than
those that might establish themselves in
a perennial broadleaf plant plus you can
use herbicides on corn that aren't
labeled for strawberri so you can clean
things up pretty well with the corn
before you move into the
strawberries so you do a good cover crop
rotation you're ready to plant the
strawberries we find that your one or
two applications round up before you
plant the strawberries uh works well to
kill the perennial weeds because once
you have strawberries established it's
very difficult to remove weeds from them
particularly perennial weeds because
strawberries are a broadleaf perennial
plant and most of the weeds we have are
broadleaf perennials and there's not a
lot of selective products that can
remove
the bad broadleaf weeds and leave the
broadleaf plant that you want
alone thirdly you know Focus attention
early in season if you have limited
labor
and limited time the best use of that is
to remove those weeds for the first two
or three months that the strawberries
have been planted and not later we've
also looked at this in the subsequent
years what about managing weeds and
established plantings and we found the
same thing that once a plants are
established um you can weeds have very
little impact on subsequent yield it
might look bad and it looks like oh
there's lots of weeds in there but the
impact they have on strawberries after
they're established if you can keep the
weeds out that first year get the
strawberries in the ground and get them
well established you can have weeds come
in and it won't impact your yield unless
you have tremendous weed pressure so
they're really good ones they're
established and then some Alternatives
you know planting through those killed
saws I showed you using some of these
newer
cultivation tools that cultivate
shallowly don't compact the soil and
don't bring wheed seeds to the surface
they're good and then there's a bunch of
herbicides that work as well and we're
going to be talking about those in just
one
minute also keep the areas mowed around
the plantings don't blow allow weed
seeds to blow into the planting from
Fields uh close by that are producing
weed seeds and then this whole concept
of using interplanet cover crops
particular with things like Sudan grass
or oats things that winter kill I think
has a lot of
Promise so the question is are you able
to use less straw for winter mulch if
you have Sudan grass inter planted into
berries theoretically I think that would
be the case what we found is that the
sedan grass actually uh it doesn't hold
up real well uh to the winter and part
of that reason for that is we don't let
it get tall so it doesn't get real Woody
and lignified so when you only let it
when you plant it in early August and
grows 2 or 3 feet high it's not real
Woody so it does break down pretty quick
what we found is it really helps hold
the straw on the row even though it
might not allow you to get by with less
straw it does help hold it on the rose
and keeps it from blowing off when you
do mulch in early
[Music]
December so with that Laura why don't we
put up robins and if anybody else has
any questions for Marvin here while I
change things around a bit that would be
this is the time to
ask you're a quiet group today must be
Friday
okay we got some people typing so okay
hold on I'm doing the same same problem
I had before
I
we
all right let's get this back where it
needs to be uh Robin I'm sorry I don't
know why we're in the beginning get you
to the beginning there we go all right
um we've got a few people typing uh so
why don't we just give them just a
second and see if there's some questions
for Marvin before I
introduce Robin um I don't know if
they're typing a question or if they're
talking to each other it's hard to tell
okay all right here we go we have a
couple of questions um Marvin Jeff Hall
asks if renovation would be the same
with side ground as
bearr yeah with the sod ground we
actually don't have sod between the rose
of strawberries that grass is the Sudan
grass is an annual grass and it's only
planted of after July and it's only
growing for a couple of months so it
doesn't really establish the S like you
might think of it it actually dies off
and that's why we want it so by the time
fall comes we have you know some residue
on the ground but the sedan grass is not
living so it's not the same as saw
ground and uh for small farmers with
their crops that would grow well
interspersed within Berry rows I don't
think so for
strawberries uh strawberries are low to
the ground and anytime you uh plant
something that PR produces shade
strawberries don't like it and you have
the rose planted so close together
anyway at four feet that I don't think
it would really make sense to plant
something between strawberry rows now if
you're talking about blueberries and the
blueberries are small uh you might be
able to think about that but not for
strawberries uh the corn byproduct we
used uh a maze uh corn gluten Mill as a
pre- merging herbicide we tested that we
found out that in strawberries it works
quite well
in a dry year but when it rains a lot
and it's a wet year that corn gluten
Mill also has a lot of nitrogen in it
and it actually uh made our weed problem
worse so if you can predict the weather
you can uh determine if it's good to use
or not but at least um in our situation
anytime we had a wet year uh we got more
weeds from the fertilizer in the the
nitrogen in that product than we did uh
when we had a dry year well I could jump
in here we do have a link to to Robin's
um website that gives sources of those
pieces of cultivation equipment and
that's on the final portion of this um
webinar so there is a link that Dr
belinder has there that you can get some
more information about
that uh our experience with different
soil types is somewhat limited you know
I think stones are more of a problem
than uh soil type in our experience and
I will say too that when we were looking
at planting in sort of killed sod uh
Sandy soils work a lot better than
heavier clay soils Robin do you have any
comments on the yeah hold on a
sec I can comment on the um brush hose
in the different types of
soils can you hear me initially when we
got the brush hose they came from Europe
and we were told that the guards were
supposed to actually be run one inch in
the the soil and you can't do that with
Stony soils which we have here at the
research farm so we purposely raised the
guards so that they were above the rows
by about an inch to an inch and a half
which is one of the reasons we get the
dry movement of the dry soil that
creates that layer that doesn't let the
weeds emerge through it um so we have
not had any difficulties using this
machine on either Stony or eel silt type
soils the problem we have run into is
that when they're very wet
then the brushes pick up too much of the
soil and it's very difficult to clean
them um we have another comment that uh
from Thomas crowy about serum Sudan
helps with nematodes and better soil
health and thank you very much Thomas
and um there was a question from Brent
about of the killed covers are there
differences in Fruit WRA problems the
following
spring
okay uh we the kill covers are their
differences in Fruit rot problems the
following spring not in terms of the
fruit rot itself but in the root rots
yeah there's a lot of differences in the
pre-plant cover crop how that affects
root pathogens but I'm not aware of we
haven't found anything and I'm not aware
of data that show an effect of a
pre-plant covered crop on fruit rots the
following spring all right great um
we're going to move now into um Dr
binder's presentation Dr Robin binder
holds a faculty position with the with
Cornell University in the department of
horticulture and she focuses her
research and extension programming on WE
control in vegetable and fruit and uh
we're very happy to have her um she's
recently back from a trip to India and
um Dr belinder thank you very
much
uh good afternoon I'm pleased to have an
opportunity to visit with you
um I have to say right up front that I
only picked up fruit in n in
2006 and I have been focusing largely on
developing data to support new
registrations of herbicides particularly
for the planting year of strawberries
and so what I will be showing you today
is some of the work that we've been
doing and are trying to move into the
registration
process
what you see on the screen is a list of
the ones the herbicides which are pretty
much currently registered for
strawberries uh prowl H2O was just
recently registered in 2007 and so some
of you may not have had much opportunity
to look at that it's currently
registered for a pre-plant
pre-transplant at least one day before
transplanting and then subsequently can
be used between rows as long as you
leave 35 days before
harvest the goal
2XL is registered for use in
strawberries but it's a rather strange
registration because it only allows use
pre-transplant 30 days and only in the
very first year it cannot be used
subsequently which makes it somewhat I
think hard to imagine
using we are going to as you'll see
later working with the new product gold
tender um which is not yet registered in
strawberries and that has some other
problems associated with registration
but we will talk a little bit about that
later Chateau is now registered for
pre-transplant applications as long as
it's going to be done on plastic it can
also be used spring and fall when the
plants are
dormant obviously many of you have used
de de deanol some of you have used stol
and some are i'msure using sinbar it's
been around a long time uh post
emergence 24d has been around forever
aim is now registered as a
pre-transplant burndown or to row midds
using uh protective Shields Stinger is
now registered on strawberries which I
think presents quite a good combination
of weeds that can be controlled with
that and then select also now known as
select Max and post can also be used for
specifically controlling post emergence
emerged uh grass
weeds wrong one
we are currently looking at this group
of herbicides
for applications in new
plantings uh dual Magnum any you I'm
sure have used in other crops uh reflex
has been relatively recently registered
in a number of crops it's a
pre-emergence but it also has resid has
residual activity as well as some
postemergence
activity Spartan is a new one which is
currently registered in cabbage uh not
in New York state and I'll talk a little
bit more about that later gold tender
which is um a flowable formulation as
opposed to a EC formulation of the goal
and tends to be somewhat less injurious
when it's applied post emergence uh it
also has somewhat less weed control
because of the same thing but it is
being moved forward
slowly caparol is an old product
um it's actually labeled on carrots in
Canada and we're trying we're awfully
close to getting it registered on
carrots in the US as well it is a
triazine and so it has some of the
similar type characteristics in terms of
weed control as atrazine and as
prap Chateau which I have here as a new
evaluation as is already labeled for
certain uses uh we're trying to change
the use pattern somewhat on that and
prap is being considered for
registration because it's been
registered for many years in Washington
and
Oregon and now that it's going through a
re-registration process the company has
indicated that we can move forward with
trying to get it used in other parts of
the
country this will just give you a couple
of birds eye views of some of these
things uh this is a trial that we
actually planted in 200
eight and the data I'm going to show you
from that are from that trial um you can
tell what our weed pressures are like
you can hardly see the
strawberries and prowl H2O does a pretty
nice job at least initially it doesn't
last the full season but it does a very
good job initially and it does not hurt
the strawberry plants these are applied
the day before
transplanting here is the Dual Magnum
and we've got three separate rates there
and I have to say these were applied the
day after transplanting and you can see
we have pretty good weed control um we
did see a little bit of injury at the
highest rate but it did not last
long unfortunately in a year like 2009
when we repeated this but we put it on
pre-transplant and had huge rain events
very shortly after planting we did see
some significant stunting with the duel
and so one has to be a little cautious
as we go forward with creating the right
information for the companies to put the
information on the labels that there are
certain times and certain occasions when
there's likely to be more injury than
others um this is PRP however I have a
correction to make on this one I
didn't get to this before we sent it to
Laura so she couldn't change it the one
on the far right where it says PRP three
times at 0.1 pounds active ingredient
per acre is in fact not PRP it is sybar
bar um the one on the left is the
application rate which is currently used
in Washington and Oregon and it's
usually put on either 30 days
pre-transplant or some people are
putting it on in the fall again to
dormant in that case we did see a little
bit of early injury with this but really
not
significant a colleague of mine um Brad
majek in New Jersey who many of you I'm
sure know has suggested Ed that a better
way to do this is to apply PRP at three
separate times roughly two weeks apart
post transplant and as you can see in
this picture there is somewhat less
stunting in this we had almost no
stunting with this particular
application the
sinbar applied at three separate
occasions which I understand from Marvin
is done routinely in
Canada in our particular case did not
cause as much in the way of injury but
we also had grasp control problems and
it may be that the rate that that's used
at is a little bit marginal with regard
to controlling
grasses this is
Chateau on the on the right you have the
traditional application of 3 ounces
applied 30 days
pre-transplant and in 2008 we had quite
a bit of
rain and I would have to say that that
3o rate even 30 days prior to
transplanting caused as you can see
there sign ific injury applied one day
pre-transplant at onethird of the rate
you can see that we have very little in
the way of crop injury and we have
excellent weed control with both of
them here are on the left is reflex
reflex has a lot of potential for both
pre and particularly in strawberri
pre-emergence activity on a lot of
troublesome broadleaf
weeds however it can only be applied
prior to transplanting and subsequent
years it would have to be applied to
dormant plants because its postemergence
activity causes too much injury for the
crop the goal tender which is the
slightly safer version of go 2XL did a
pretty nice job and we do see some
injury in this but overall it's not too
bad we also tried some rather strange
off-the-wall new things kicks Sor is a
product that is being marketed by
BASF and at this point they're not
particularly interested in strawberries
but what we did find is that applied
pre-transplant in strawberries it
actually does no harm at all to the
berries it unfortunately has actually no
activity on grasses and that's what you
see there is
grasses bandor in the middle is a
product used in Europe on other
crops and even though kior and bandor
are of the same mode of action in terms
of killing weeds you can see that they
have very different behaviors in terms
of their sensitivity or their
phytotoxicity because band actually
totally killed the
strawberries and then lastly I
occasionally throw in things that I use
in other crops just for fun and so you
have lorox on the far right and in 2008
you can see there's no injury and really
nice weed control um this was applied U
immediately pre-transplant day before in
2009 however because as I mentioned
earlier with the Dual Magnum uh because
we got a lot of rain shortly after the
transplanting we did see more injury
this year with the lorox than we did in
2008 now this is one of two data
tables is it on okay what I basically
want to show you with this one is hand
weeding time over here oh this is the
hand weeding time this whole column and
what you should see here is that for
example although we had very little in
the way of injury here with the jewel
with the prowl we did have relatively
poor over the Long Haul weed control and
as a result your hand weeding time is
quite high sbar on the other hand as I
mentioned where we had virtually no
injury at all with those three
applications we didn't also have very
good weed control and so although we
have somewhat better weed control than
with prow by itself um shouldn't do it
that way I should do it out here okay we
do still have an appreciable amount of
time in terms of hand
weeding the prinet which had
initial
injury we begin to see better weed
control and now the weeding time comes
down and Chateau which has the absolute
shortest weeding time very very little
time it took because it was so good even
the three days application or the the
here it is the three times application
no I'm sorry the one day before
application here we still have excellent
weed control and very very little and
keeping in mind this is the first year
so this is a nonfruiting year so we're
getting extremely good weed control and
the Hand weeding time as I said Has Come
way down you have it it's with the Dual
Magnum you had again initial injury
relatively slight overall pretty good
weed control with all of
these and the weed control hand weeding
time
is intermediate let's call it that way
but still not too
bad
reflex again we have very little in the
way of injury good weed control except
for crab grass because it doesn't
control the grasses but the hand weeding
time is not
bad and then of
course kicks or which had very little in
the way of inj iny had relatively poor
weed control and so our hand weeding
time was back up with that
one we move to our next data slide which
is this last one this is yield data that
was collected in 2007 from a trans
planting trial in
2006 and I have to say that it was our
first time hand harvesting
strawberries and it took
forever I had Meer Marvin for all of the
work he's doing in strawberries you
couldn't oh it was amazing the crew was
real real concerned about the amount of
time we spent hand weeding or
handpicking the strawberries so the
yields I felt were relatively
variable both in terms
of numbers of Runners per plant as well
as the yields they're highly variable
the significance level is not
particularly strong there are some
Trends in the sense that um here
Chateau and gender you did see
particularly with Chateau a slight
reduction in the number of Runners and
also a reduction in the pounds and this
was with the case of
Jewel uh we also saw here significant
injury with this and we also saw a
reduction in the number of of the yields
per 20
meters uh with early glow
again overall the trends are not as no
noticeable this one with the gold tender
you do see a slight reduction in terms
of total
yields so then looking at the idea of
where some of these might fit into your
current practices uh PRL h2o at the top
is particularly good in controlling the
annual grasses it does also pick up
mustards percane and pigweed
species um if you have I don't see this
very often in Strawberry Fields but
Velvet Leaf is suppressed by it uh as is
Lamb's
quarters Spartan which I haven't
mentioned much up until
now is largely a broadleaf
weed um herbicide it's used pre-plant
plant and it can also be used in dormant
crops um for those of you from other
parts of the country that are not in New
York state you may see this registered
already or it will be registered soon
the New York Department of Environmental
Conservation or the dec has had some
problems with FMC because they're not
happy with water tests and as a result
FMC has not gone forward with
registering it yet in New York state so
that remains a little bit up in the air
Chateau um we would like to see it its
rate reduced so that we could use it the
the day before transplanting as opposed
to waiting for the 30 days um I also
would like to go back and revisit with
the company why they've got the plastic
on there because I think we can do it
with things without
plastic reflex as I mentioned um will be
good pre-transplant and subsequently in
other in later years could be used as a
dormant application is extremely good in
controlling several very difficult
broadleaf weeds particularly Ragweed
mustards Pig weeds and then dual Magnum
we've been trying to get that registered
off and on for some time uh particularly
because it controls nutsedge annual
grasses gallon SOA it also does a good
job on Pig weeds suppresses nightshades
and purc
Lane current registration status we have
done the residues for getting prep
registered and those will be doing going
through analysis this coming year so we
expect registration on that in
2012 dual Magnum the 2008 trials are
complete the res residue trials have
been done and we expect registration for
that in
2011 with that I'd like to conclude if
there are questions even there are a
couple of things Robin um Kristen callow
asks what what is the active ingredient
and reflex
okay the active ingredient in reflex is
fopen in Canada it's called
Flexar uh it is a poo
inhibitor it's related to Blazer okay
CRA hopefully that answers your question
um there's a question about the hand
weeding times whether or not that is on
a per acre basis but I think it's
actually on a smaller
basis
it's on a it's on a plot basis that's
120 squet is wondering if D Magnum will
have activity on
henbit I have very little experience
with henbit my guess is that it will not
have much activity on it okay great now
does anybody else have any questions for
either Marvin or
Robin it's kind of quiet there's
somebody typing here and I'll wait for
Brent to finish typing and then we'll if
nobody else has any questions we'll move
into the next um phase the final phase
of the
program don't be nervous gr we're
we're um Brent is actually asking me how
does soil organic matter affect activity
of some of these herbicides I know it's
a factor with
sinbar and can uh Robin can you address
that
the the higher the amount of organic
matter the more particulates there are
in the soil that the herbicides can bind
to and so that's why frequently you will
see on labels restrictions that if you
have mck soils you can't use certain
products and the reason is because you
either have to increase the rate
significantly or in order to get above
the level that's being bound up in the
soil so yes the higher the organic
matter the more the herbicides
particularly this pertains to soil
applied residual herbicides right great
so the more you have the higher the more
that will be bound up yes okay okay then
question about go ahead there's a
question about queenan's
Lays yes does anybody have any I don't
know actually I'm not sure what would do
a good job on that
either Marvin's shaking his head too
neither one of us has much background
with that um yeah a it's a a it's a
perennial um Brent also is asking he
says I'm thinking of very low soil
organic matter situations where sinbar
injures
strawberries so if in in fact there is a
really low organic matter would you ad
could you adjust the rate of sinbar
appropriately for
that technically yes if you're talking
very Sandy soils most labels divide up
their rates on the basis of soils and
they will have a sandy soil a medium
soil and a mck soil or a high organic
matter soil and those rates are usually
adjusted to that but yes you could do
that and then if you can see those other
questions there's a question about um
postemergence control of
chickweed uh my answer on that is
potentially
Stinger actually I think I did talk to a
grower this year that had um very good
luck with stinger on
chickweed I was going to suggest that's
probably one of the better ones at this
point and then there's um soil PH
affecting herbicide
activity I don't know about that soil
pH I don't think I know do you do Marvin
do you have any ideas on that I've I
mean the pH of the mix water would
but
answer uh Marvin is suggesting that the
pH might have an impact on microbial
breakdown activities and that's why it
might indirectly have an effect on the
herbicides okay um we've got another
question and we really got them going
here um I am contemplating planting
strawberries on lamps and sand mixed
with Palms mck ground that I have grown
sweet corn on for several years W PRP
and arrine herbicide residues affect
this so this is Marvin so on uh if
you're growing corn and you've used
atrazine and Prat before a real good way
to see whether it would be a problem
would be do do a
bioassay and you can use a couple of
things and but for strawberries you know
bean seeds are a pretty good indicator
if it cucumber seeds uh either one of
those so you get your soil and you plant
your cucumber your bean seeds in that
soil and then you get some soil that you
know you haven't treated that's kind of
like the same soil type and plant the
same Bean or cucumber seeds in that and
then uh bring it into your kitchen and
put it in the window SE and let it grow
and if you see differences between
between the two that might indicate that
there's some residue in the soil that
might affect your strawberries but if
the both grow the same and everything
looks normal you don't see yellowing and
so forth then it's probably safe to
plant but yeah atrazine uh can carry
over as can prin up so you have to be a
little bit careful about that all right
great Mario has a qu a question about
using prow and dual Magnum for the first
year the current registration effort for
dual Magnum is not focused on the year
of planting however I don't see us
having a problem with trying to get that
changed for the registration when we
actually get to it um both prow and dual
Magnum have good potential in the first
year in terms of safety on the
strawberries uh I think you would select
them more on the basis of which weeds
you knew had in the field because they
do behave somewhat
differently all right great and then
Thomas prowdy has a um comment that soil
PH will affect triazine herbicides and
thank you
Thomas and then Kristen callow um asks
if these presentations will be available
on the Cornell website and yes they will
be and the link to that was on the first
page and um I think I've included that
link as well on all of the login
information and if not I will try to do
that for further uh webinars let's move
into the Final Phase of this which uh
does allow you to look at some of the
other um other information uh as far as
things that you can download There's a
um information about cultivation tools a
handout that you can download onto your
own computer and then there's a
publication from atra on organic
strawberry production which might be uh
of interest to some folks also there are
web um URLs for some of these other
resources is for instances the n n enrs
excuse me production of vegetables
strawberries and cut flowers using
plastic culture uh there's a cultivation
tools Source um website uh that I
mentioned before and that URL is there
and then there's some compreh
comprehensive information about Berry
production that's the berry website that
I also had mentioned and that is your
site that you would go to to get um the
archived uh webinars
um I do want to remind everybody that
next Wednesday this coming Wednesday
November 4th is our first um weed
management uh webinar on uh for
blueberries and CR cranberries and we
have speakers uh Hillary Sandler of the
University of Massachusetts which is
going to she's going to be talking about
um we control on cranberries and Dr Eric
Hansen of Michigan State University is
going to be speaking more on blueberries
but we look forward to having those of
you who grow those crops to join us um
before I introduce the last pod I want
to thank Dr Marvin critz and Dr Robin
bellander for speaking to us today it's
a great topic and covered a lot of uh
territory so I want to thank you um I'm
going to open this last pod but if
anybody has any other questions before
we sign off I'd like you to do that um
just go ahead and type them in the chat
box and I have one more Poll for
you and if you could just if people
could just weigh in on this there's a
few people that have signed up but if
most of you could just vote quickly give
us some feedback about what was helpful
to you um that would be wonderful
and this is your chance so please don't
hesitate to give us um type in a
question if you've got it right in that
chat box we'd love to hear from
you
all right we've had uh got about 10 more
people that might want to
vote um while we're having people finish
up we have um a question from Lynette uh
who's looking for control for horse
metal and I don't know if Marvin or
Robin if you'd like to CH can you hear
us okay so we're not really sure of a we
were talking about the horse nle issue
we're not really sure of a label product
that works well on horse N I think for a
lot of
those like the wild carrot and horse n
all you really got to clean them up
before you plant strawberries cuz once
you plant it's really you're really
limited on what you can do after that
and then in ter uh someone commented
they can grow strawberries in between
blueberry beds for the first four or
five years sure and we mentioned that
earlier that on uh with more space in
between them particularly things like
blueberries you can't intercrop the only
thing I would say you have to be careful
with there is pH strawberries prefer a
higher pH in blueberry so uh you might
have to pay close attention to making
sure that the pH isn't too low for those
strawberries and the horse tail
equisetum uh none of us know what you
can do about that even Roundup doesn't
take that out before planting so I think
if you have horse tail you might just
not want to plant that field to a low
growing crop like strawberries and look
someplace else because you know save
that f for corn or something that grows
taller you're just not going to get the
hsea out with I don't know of anything
that works well on that that would even
that wouldn't harm the strawberry
plants all right um I've got uh Richard
fars typing in a quick question couple
more things uh if you haven't voted on
our final poll please please give us
some
feedback and if you also if you would
like to uh send me a note or give me a
call email me something if you have
specific comments that you'd rather not
type into the chat bar uh we're a third
of the way through these webinar series
and I would be really thrilled to hear
from attendees if they have some
suggestions for ways we can approve um
even other topics that in the future
you'd like to see covered in a webinar
type of format or things that you
absolutely hate about it we we need to
hear them all so don't hesitate to give
usack last question someone asked about
home Gardener suggestions I think a lot
of the things we talked about early on
in a presentation were appropriate for
organic Growers if you were referring to
herbicides for organic Growers uh
vinegar is going to be labeled pretty
soon as that's going to be labeled on a
lot of different crops that has burned
down action it's an organic product and
I imagine strawberries will be on that
label where you can use it between the
rows particularly to burn down uh annual
weed that start to come up it's a a safe
organic product for use on strawberries
and a lot of other
crops all right I'm going to close our
poll um I think shiaka county is still
typing I what can you tell us about
different formulations for 24d is there
such a thing as imen and
formulations around it comes with
different formulations you're referring
to 24d amine am i n e and that's a salt
product of 24d and it's not nearly as
volatile as some of the other 24d
products in other words it doesn't
vaporize and move as much so that's the
type that's recommended for strawberries
but having said that it can still uh
volatilize and move so you wouldn't want
to put it on strawberries if you were
near grapes because um even in using 24
damine salt you can smell it shortly
after that and Growers have had problems
uh that had grapes nearby uh so you want
to be careful about that in fact out in
the midwest they've had a real hard time
getting their grape industry started
because they use so much 24d on wheat
fields and and even some corn fields
it's a cheap herbicide and it's really
caused problems with the wine industry
out there so yeah be careful with it but
if you do use it on strawberries it's
one of the few broadleaf uh herbicides
that don't affect strawberries which or
a broadleaf
plant but be careful if you have grapes
or asparagus um uh growing around your
strawberry
field
okay all right I guess that's it for
questions thank you uh Marvin and Robin
very much uh I just want to let folks
know that once you're on the
registration list for the webinars you
will continue to get connection
information and so for you folks who are
just strawberry Growers
um you could just delete my my uh emails
when they come if you're you're not
interested but uh if you are interested
in maybe finding out a little bit about
these other Berry crops we'd love for
you to log on so thanks again for
everybody attending and um that is the
end of this
webinar
that