this is a production of Cornell
University um but I will I apologize to
those of you who were were here
yesterday that I will repeat one or two
things but I try and keep the repetition
to a minimum because what I want to talk
about today is is global atmospheric
change and how we how we might be able
to adapt crops to that particularly with
respect to Rising carbon diox side and
also try and explain why I think there
is mileage in trying to make those
adaptations um I should say at the
outset that I can only give this talk uh
because of the work done by past
graduate students Lisa rainsworth K
banaki uh will hay Jin wanju um and
posts Justin McGrath and venat sassen
and also um faculty colleagues Donald
and pine Kumar who've all helped um in
doing this work oh and Darren Drury who
was a postto working with me as well um
so this is where I work the Institute of
genomic biology at the University of
Illinois um in front of that are the
mororo plots the oldest agricultural
experiment outside of rothamstead
England um and I just wanted to show
this sort of connection that we have so
much of the fil work our show you is
done um very close to this location so a
lot of the work shows an interplay
between lab modeling and field work and
I hope I hope that'll be
apparent so what are we concerned about
um whatever is debated there is no
debate about the fact that the carbon
dioxide atmosphere in the carbon dioxide
concentration in the atmosphere is
rising um and it
really rising at a quite unprecedented
rate in geological history at the
present time um most of our crop
ancestors evolved in the average CO2
concentration of the last 10 million
years which was about 220 parts per
million today we're over 400 parts per
million so we're we're close to doubling
what those crop ancestors evolved
evolved in
um if we look at what is
driving climate
change in the atmosphere then CO2 of
course is the biggest contributor to
this but also methane nitrous oxide
halocarbons are an important part of
this and one that's often overlooked is
tropospheric Ozone most greenhouse gases
are heter Atomic molecules carbon
dioxide nitrous oxide but ozone also
behaves as a het Atomic molecule and it
absorbs him for radiation so it is a
part of the greenhouse effect when it's
in the
troposphere
um in the stratosphere of course it's
important in absorbing UV radiation and
our activities have greatly increased
ozone in in the
troposphere and that ozone is also toxic
to plant so it has a direct effect as
well as an indirect effect um other
aspects uh Aerosoles actually cause a
cooling effect um increase in cloud
cover as we warm up the atmosphere has a
feedback effect as well but overall the
anthropogenic effect is strongly
positive leading to um increased energy
in the
troposphere so that is predicted to lead
to on average A 1 to2 degre C
temperature rise by
2050 now
although precipitation is
rising um drought is also Rising because
with Rising temperature we have more of
AA
transpiration also the with increased
energy in the
atmosphere events become more
intense uh more if you like chaos itic
so this will probably also lead to more
drought events we think that surface
ozone today averages about 50 parts per
billion in the northern hemisphere we
think that will rise to between 60 to 90
parts per billion depending on whether
really controls proposed by a number of
companies really sorry countries bite or
whether they don't a lot of this Rises
actually south of us in the tropics
ically in East Asia as well but these
are really if you like three major Glo
four major Global change issues that our
crops will have to face by
2050 and indeed are facing already
because you know as I said the crop
ancestors evolved in a CO2 concentration
that is very different to the one we
have today and indeed tropospheric ozone
we think pre-industrial was probably no
more than 10 parts per billion today it
averages 50 parts per billion we
frequently see 100 parts per billion in
Central Illinois um
today so so what is the problem uh what
are the impacts of rising CO2 and how
might we adapt to Rising CO2 they're the
three things I want to try and look
at so again as I showed yesterday
our four major crops globally in terms
of if you like these are the crops that
provide over
2/3 directly or indirectly of human
calories um so maze is number one um and
it's C4 so it has a different response
to Rising
CO2 um rice and wheat on the other hand
a C3 very important as direct sources of
human calories and then soy very
important protein source so those last
three are all C3 crops and should
respond very strongly to Rising carbon
dioxide and as I showed yesterday um
we're responsible for the United States
produces almost a third of the world's
soy production a very significant part
of wheat production
and over a third of of maze
production now if we look at how we're
improving the yield of these crops then
if we take the historical trajectory and
we say well we ought to be able to
continue that into the future then we
would end up at this point by
2050 but what FAO and John F's group at
um Minnesota have projected is that this
is what we will need by 2050 so we
really need to get onto this trajectory
because staying on this
one will result in significant shortages
significant price increases that will
affect the poorest in the global
Community I should also point out that
um I've just added on here
casava casava is a crop which many many
small holders poor communities
particularly in sub Saharan Africa
depend on and I think these yield
improvements which we show for our major
crops are not apparent in some of these
M what we might call minor crops but
actually extremely important crops for
those those communities we we have
failed to improve those at the rate that
we're improving our our best crops or
rather shouldn't say our best crops our
if you like our top crops the ones which
particularly matter to the developed
World um the picture though is a little
bit worse because if we look at these
rice and wheat for example the same's
true of soy that if we look at during
the Green Revolution years then we were
improving average global yields by 30 to
40% per decade so a huge change in
global food supply the this really
eliminated the major famines that had
been seen in the
1960s so so the Green Revolution had a
huge impact at that stage but as we move
away we see that wheat and rice really
the yield improvements are are declining
and in fact in the last decade wheat
wasn't improved at all and rice is now
in single
figures now I just want to put up an
equation developed by John Monte at
rothamstead which explains at least why
we may be running out of steam with
genetic yield potential I yielder crop
will achieve when it's grown under
Optimum conditions so no diseases no
pests um adequate water and adequate
nutrients and what this tells us is that
the yield of a crop will depend on how
much sunlight is available for
photosynthesis by the crop um and I
should say here we're just interested in
the visible sunlight because that is all
plants use in
photosynthesis um how good they are at
capturing that light so what is the
efficiency with which they capture it
during the growing season how efficient
are they at then converting that
captured light
into um
biomass and then how good are they at
partitioning that biomass into the part
of the crop we care about so the grain
of wheat the grain of
rice and these are just data for soybean
crop on our University Farm modern
soybean crop growing on not growing with
irrigation but growing on a deep Midwest
soil where there's plenty of water
available and basically what we see is
that interception efficiency and
partitioning efficiency are already
remarkably High
and the these are um in the case of rice
and wheat these are products of the
Green Revolution that's really what we
changed in rice and wheat that
partitioning efficiencies went up from
30% to 60% interception efficiency
improved as well and if we really you
know look at these These are pretty well
hitting on their biological Maxima so
there isn't really much more we can
squeeze out of
those um but so what I should point out
is this number conversion efficiency and
this is really a very good number for
most crops a
3% is only a third of the theoretical
value so conversion efficiency
photosynthesis is one thing where
there's an opportunity still to improve
on um yield potential genetic yield
potential
so how does co2 tie into this what does
co2 do to crop
plants well from a theoretical point of
view the only way a plant can
sense CO2 the to the CO2 changes at the
levels that we're dealing with if you
put a plant in um 10% CO2 then you
change its pH and all sorts of things
start to happen but if you just for
example Elevate CO2 from where we are
today to where we think we be in the
latter half of this Century they're only
really two ways a plant can sense this
one is the key carboxylase in
photosynthesis
rubisco um is not CO2
saturated and it also um catalyzes a
process called
photorespiration
CO2 increases saturation of rubisco
and it inhibits that oxygenation
reaction which leads to
photorespiration so it's sensed at
rubisco it's also sensed of the level of
stamata and how this happens is not
fully understood but stamata will
close um in response to Rising CO2 and
we we don't know how much of that is
really a direct effect but if you strip
off the epidermis of many plants float
them on water subject them to elevated
CO2 you will see a closing response now
it was thought for many years um that
respiration was also affected by CO2
people took out there some of you may be
facil familiar with Lor gas exchange
systems or other gas exchange
systems they they put these on Plants
elevated the CO2 in the chamber and they
saw a suppression of respiration but we
were very suspicious that what's going
on is it's very difficult to prevent CO2
from leaking out of these systems
completely prevent it and um so what we
eventually managed to do was get a
manufacturer who could actually give us
a differential oxygen system um this was
about a year of work but so that we
could instead measure oxygen uptake
which is much more of a challenge
because because there is so much more
oxygen in the atmosphere but but when we
eventually got this working to our
satisfaction the the postto in the lab
who was doing it was saying well I'm
doubling CO2 and I'm not seeing anything
so I said well put through 1% CO2 and
see what happens he put through 1% CO2
and we saw absolutely nothing so we
published that in plant physiology and I
think the idea that CO2 is suppressing
respiration has gone away uh now so at
least we can whoop
sorry we can simplify what really a
plant can see in terms of CO2 now so at
the level of rubisco what CO2 is doing
is um CO2 of course is the substrate for
conversion of ubp to two mole ules of
phosphoglycolate in the Calvin cycle but
oxygen
also um reacts catalyzed by rubisco
because that's why there's the o on the
end of rubisco to produce glycolate if
glycolate is produced then the plant
recycles that back to PGA but in doing
so it loses a carbon dioxide it consumes
a great deal of um the nadph and ATP
generated by the Light reactions so it
imposes an inefficiency on the overall
photosynthetic process if you elevate
CO2 you do two things you increase the
saturation of rubisco with
CO2 and you competitively inhibit this
oxygenation
reaction so that that is why glass house
Growers it's worth their while elevating
their to
tomato crop with CO2 because they get a
a high yield precisely because of this
mechanism so it's harder when it comes
to fi crops though to assess what CO2
will do and so a lot of the information
we have comes from chamber systems green
houses um controlled
environments and also small Chambers put
over crops in the field but when you do
this even in the field situation you're
changing a lot of things you're lowering
the light level you're raising
temperature a little bit you're raising
humidity you're completely altering
coupling with with the movement of the
air and you've got Edge effects because
often the crop around the edges of this
has been knocked down and so lights
coming in from the side and so we we
were really basing much of our
prediction on what would happen on crops
on very AR official systems that
Monsanto or senta would never use plots
this size to decide whether their latest
trans Gene is is doing anything they
want an open crop field many of them to
do this and yet we're basically um
predicting our future on
experiments much smaller and much
simpler than industry would ever use for
its business
model so when I moved to Illinois there
was a chance there with particularly
with the university farm and a big
engineering school to do something
different and this was something
actually first developed for Oz work
with ozone and Atmospheric pollutants by
Andrew McLoud in the UK and then was
taken up by Brook Haven National Lab um
when I worked there in the early '90s
and then when I moved to Illinois there
was a chance to really refine that which
is what we did and um well what the
engineers did I didn't do it but but
basically what these systems do is that
here we have our soybean crop we do the
same thing in maze um and also this has
been done with wheat and rice um we've
given our design to groups in China
which have now done this very
successfully with rice but basically
what happens is if the wind is coming in
this direction it's sensed here um and
CO2 is released on the upwind side it's
feathered so that most is released
immediately up wind and then less as you
go to the sides and it's stepped
according to the wind speed as well in
the center we have a CO2 analyzer an
infr analyzer to check that the
algorithm is doing the right thing and
if it is over it backs it off if it's
under it releases more and so here you
can see a test of the system we switch
it on at this point and with Target is
550 parts per million and it it gets
within plus or minus 10% of that Target
for about 96% of the time over the
growing season this is an infrared image
oh sorry this is an infrared image and
of course as I said
CO2 causes partial stomatal closure so
the plants are transpiring less they're
losing less heat lat and heat therefore
they get warmer
and so you can see um that it's warmer
within the ring and that's fairly
uniform compared to the
outside um
now um one of my former students and one
of my former posts both went away from
Illinois and then came back as faculty
and they're now doing their own
experiments in this system and Andrew
leaky has developed a rain out shelter
system where actually his this deploys
at night when we get
about a two-thirds of our rainfall in
fact in the Corn Belt due to um
convectional storms so if if rain if the
thing senses rain it deploys a shelter
which collects the rain in the gut pipes
that away from the site and he imposes a
drought here car has developed uh an
open air heating system so he can raise
the temperature of the crop Within These
rings as well so we've now got CO2
drought and temperature
combined um So within the experiment
we've got those added on these rings are
about 20 M diameter so gives you over
300 square meters of crop so you can do
a lot of things with with that that you
can't do with a small system and so you
can look at everything from gene
expression to the final yield um
harvested with a small plot
combine we've so we have four of these
in soybean and replicated in maze they
in CO2 four in elevated ozone four
looking at the combination and then
controls and then we have split plots
with the temperature and drought
treatments we've also looked at a range
of cultivars in there as well
although for most breeders 20 6 is way
too small to really do any breeding
project but you could replicate this
technology up to much larger
areas
um so what did we find when we did this
under the open air well um and I should
say this has also been done with wheat
this was an experiment in Arizona this
was an experiment in Japan and there've
have been more of those around the world
but two to few I believe so this is this
shows um soybean and wheat data from
different chamber
experiments and so you can fit a line to
those against
CO2 but this is what we found in our
face experiment of course that's just
one CO2 level but basically we were
finding what we see under open air
conditions is about half of what have
been reported on average in chamber
conditions and with maze the picture was
even worse that this is the projection
from
chambers and of course many of these
plants are grown in but they're all
pretty well grown nearly all grown in
pots um and this is what we see in the
open air so no stimulation at all and
we've done this now over over 10 years
we still haven't seen a yield increase
um So Lisa answorth looked at this in
more detail that that was published in
2006 by 2008 there were twice as many
face experiments to draw on and she
showed again that what you see on in the
open air the nearest proxy to a farmer
field was only half of what was
expected it's the modelers I think are
still not convinced of our results and
even in the latest ipcc they're
suggesting that Rising Co two will
rescue us from the problems of rising
temperature and and drought I I don't
subscribe to that view and I think
we if there's doubt about it we should
be trying to look at how we could adapt
to it if we don't need it that would be
great but if we do it'll be too late if
we don't start doing something now so um
if we look at go back to John Monti's
equations
what we see is indeed conversion
efficiency at the crop level is
increased and that plays through to
yield but it's only about half of what
we think we should
get so how might we adapt to that Rising
CO2 and try and get the kind of yield
increase we think we should
obtain um
again we this is something we started
when I was working on the project but
Lisa answorth has now taken this much
further and what we're doing here is
looking at genetic variation in
response and so if we look at seed yield
of a range of cultivars we can see that
this basically means no response but up
here we've got
cultivars that are clearly responding
more strongly so it appears there are
some genetics there that could be
exploited to adapt the crop but really
to do do this you would need a m if you
like a much larger face system and you
probably need you'd need it in different
locations because we're pretty well in
the center of the soybean growing area
but there's plenty of soybean grown in
Minnesota plenty grown south of us
where growing season lengths conditions
are quite different but it does suggest
that this is something that could well
be exploited
um one of the
major um issues is really that around
this rubisco issue so we know from
Theory what should happen which should
be about a 30% yield increase and we can
sometimes see that in chamber
experiments but in practice we're
getting a lot
less um so as I mentioned
CO2 is if you like suppressing f to
respiration and enhancing CO2
uptake but temperature has the opposite
effect temperature makes rubisco less
specific so as temperature increases
rubisco becomes less able to
discriminate between oxygen and CO2 and
photorespiration goes up and if you you
model this from rubisco Kinetics put
that into a crop canopy what you see is
that this is the actual gain you get
with
temperature um sorry this is the actual
photosynthesis at the canopy level this
is what you could get if you eliminated
photorespiration and that gain that
difference becomes much bigger with
Rising temperature so we got two things
going on Rising CO2 and Rising
temperature working against each
other now
one way in which this could be overcome
synthetically is for example with C4
photosynthesis is one of those if we
could make these crops
C4 then we could overcome this problem
another way um and Morin Hansen and I
have both been involved in this area is
that c bacteria the ancestors of the
chloroplasts um also have these bodies
called carboxy s where which contain
their
rubisco they actively take up
bicarbonate into their
cells and they also um will hydrate any
CO2 as well so that out here you have a
high concentration of bicarbonate and no
carbon dioxide in this body called the
carboxysome they have Carbonic and
hydrates which catalyzes the conversion
of bicarbonate to CO2 so there's a very
high concentration of CO2 here which the
rabisco can take up because there's a
high concentration of CO2 they do not
have
photorespiration so there's an active
effort now to try and engineer this
system into the
chloroplast so that would be one way of
dealing with this Justin McGrath who's
been working with Morin and myself um on
modeling this system has has developed a
diffusion
um reaction model which really looks at
all these components and the sequence in
which this would ideally be engineered
but basically what he shows is in theory
if you could put this in to a crop plant
like soybean you could get almost a um
up to a 60% increase in CO2 uptake
now um will hay working with Tom
Clemente and myself put in just one cob
bacterial Gene whose function is still
really unknown but it there's quite a
lot of evidence that it appears to
improve CO2 access to
rubisco and so will'll put so will using
um soybean transform with this one
gene showed that photosynthesis was
indeed increased seed Mass was increased
and these are fi trials one of the most
important findings he made was that the
maximum efficiency of light limited
photosynthesis went up and this was
statistically
significant um and there's only
really three ways in which this is
possible you have a different rubisco
which seems highly unlikely because um
the large subunit at least is doesn't
have multiple forms um there's more
oxygen which again sorry less oxygen
which again is extremely difficult
because there's 21% outside so inside
it's probably 29
9% the only other way is to have more
CO2 at rubisco and so this seemed good
evidence that that was what was
happening um
just mention of course not everything is
predictable and I I showed examples
yesterday with pests of soybean one of
the other things we see with um and this
was a bit of a shock was that under
elevated CO2 and I hope it's apparent
there um it the crop is green at the end
of the growing season when it's yellow
outside and um in fact it should have
been the other way around because the
crop's warmer heat accelerates
development and it should have gone
yellow inside before it was green
outside and in fact the the engineer at
the site I was telling him tell me when
it goes yellow inside because I wanted
to take a picture of it and I kept
calling him every morning and he said no
no and eventually sheepishly said I
think it's green inside so so I said oh
that can't be possible so I went out
there and sure enough it was green
inside the ring and yellow outside so so
by boosting photosynthesis and
carbohydrate
Supply it appears that we've delayed s
essence of of the crop because this crop
is genetically identical you can see
it's all in the same
field um now this was very intriguing
because what we then found was
these are the TR these are the wild type
soybean same generation as these ones
which were transformed and at the end of
the season boosting photosynthesis
appeared to delay
sence so that was another very
interesting parallel they these trans
transgenic plants appeared just like the
wild type ones give them more
CO2 um
sorry I I move on from this but one of
the ways which we could adapt the plant
to Rising CO2 is exactly around this
issue of rubisco that if we um look at
the response of
photosynthesis to the CO2 inside the
leaf so we're eliminating a statal
effect in this diagram what we see is
that as we increase C 2 photosynthesis
increases rapidly then it reaches a
transition point where it rises more
slowly what is happening here is that
you're saturating the carboxilate
reaction of
rubisco and um then when you get to this
point you now become limited by the
supply of
rubp not directly by the supply of
CO2 but not sure how I've managed to do
do that
um good so um so but you can see there's
still a rise here and the reason for
this is although rubp is limiting
because you're increasing CO2 you're
progressively inhibiting the oxygenation
reaction so more of that limiting supply
of ubp is being used in photosynthesis
un Less in
photorespiration now if we
um what we tend to find is that current
CO2
levels so if at a given stomatal
conductance what'll happen is as we
increase
photosynthesis the CO2 concentration
inside the leaf will drop because
photosynthesis is removing CO2 the
stomates are limiting that CO2 so inside
the leaf you have lower CO2 than out
side at this point inside and outside
are the same and what we typically find
this point the operating point is very
close to this transition and that makes
sense the leaf has optimized its
investment in rubisco versus apparatus
for
regenerating um
ubp but now if we move out to an
elevated CO2 situation we've unbalanced
this that we we've now got um we've got
far more rubisco than we need and we're
limited entirely by the apparatus for
regeneration of
rubp So in theory what we could do is we
could decrease
rubisco and if you like we could have
the same photosynthetic rate but be more
nitrogen use
efficient cuz rabisco is about
25% of the nitrogen in the leaf so it's
a lot of nitrogen or we could use that
resource instead to increase capacity
for regeneration of
ubp and have for the same amount of
nitrogen have even more CO2 fixed now of
course a question you might ask is well
does the plant know this if you grow it
under elevated CO2 does it acclimate in
this way
um and these are data that carbonaki
took during his PhD work where indeed
the plant seems to know a little bit of
this and what he found was there was a
decrease in this initial slope and a
slight rise in the plateau but it was
nowhere near enough to reach the
theoretical
gain um so yeah I
should so um so one of the other things
we looked at was this issue of
regeneration and Jing wanu who was a
graduate student in the lab at the same
time as Carl uh worked with me on
developing a complete model of
photosynthesis where we represented the
whole system by a series of Link
differential
equations that we eventually got to
replicate what the leaf was doing in
terms of CO2 uptake in in
Vivo um and this just shows some of the
uh classic responses we see if you like
in one of these
cuetes uh this just shows that we could
simulate these responses with with the
model so these Dynamic
responses um we could then use the
system to
basically
optimize investment so we could say well
apply if you like an evolutionary
algorithm to say okay where should we be
investing to regenerate IP more
efficiently and it picked out in
particular this one enzyme sbpa but
there are a number of other changes it's
suggested fbpa as well fbp outlays all
of which we're now looking at in uh
particularly in tobacco but probably
will test in soybean and my colleague
Christine Reigns in England uh did this
with tobacco here are plants in the
glass house we put those out in our soy
face experiment and could replicated in
in the
field um one of the things we found
though was that and I'll skip over this
was that under elevated CO2 the response
was even greater and that got us
intrigued um you know and of course it
fits in with the theory I showed you
that it should be greater under elevated
CO2 so one of the other things we did
went back to with the model was to say
well it was curious that sbpa is a
really very small amount of the to total
protein in the leaf it would be in
theory it be very easy for a plant to
evolve more sbas at a very low
cost so we reran the model at 220 parts
per per million per billion per million
sorry the concentration under which we
think the crop ancestors evolved and we
sorry we looked at a flux control in
this was in the model and it suggested
well s Spas would invert in would have
no control over CO2 fixation under those
conditions but at
390 PPM it would have a strong control
at 700 it would be even more and rubisa
would be moving in the opposite
direction so that was consistent with
what we saw in these
experiments um I just very briefly
mentioned this but
another thing that we also have done
with modeling is rubisco appears to have
a tradeoff that this
specificity um factor I
where plant if you like we think that
plants have evolved to become very
obviously very specific for CO2 against
a very strong oxygen background so that
we find that crop plants tend to have a
specificity of 90 in in favor of CO2 but
as you go out to C4 plants where the
rubisco is in a high CO2 environment or
bacteria where they might be in anerobic
environments specificity drops but
catalytic rate
increases so the thinking is that to get
tighter
binding um catalytic rate has to drop so
there's a tradeoff and to cut a short a
long story short what we found was that
um you there should be an Optimum at any
CO2 concentration what we found was that
that Optimum was a specificity of about
90 a pre-ind uh
rather the 220 PPM in which the plants
probably evolved but today it's much
lower so there'd be a big advantage in
if you like getting in a foreign rubisco
which might have lower specificity but a
higher
Kat and indeed we we modeled this
amaranthus Ulus rabisco which is C4
actually fits these specs and in the
model it would give you about a 70% gain
for no increase in
nitrogen if you could replace the lower
canopy
rubisco um
with um a further different rubisco you
could get up to 30% gain
well when we did that that all seemed a
bit a pie in the sky because rubiscos
coded for in both the plasted and the
nucleus extremely difficult to put into
higher plants but this is a picture from
the paper in nature from Morin's group
and Martin par and rothamstead where
they've really shown you can take very
distant rubiscos get them into tobacco
and at least you can get the plants to
survive to to flowering so so these
things are becoming as the technology
moves forward these things are becoming
more and more
possible finally I just wanted to sort
of point out you can also apply this
type of evolutionary algorithm at the
canopy level and Darren Drury working
with me as a postto did this with again
soybean canopies and I won't go into all
the details of this but basically what
he showed was that you could
by changing canopy Leaf
reflectivity the angles of the leaves
optimizing those and also the number of
leaves you could get quite a significant
gain in carbon uptake you could also for
warmer environments you could cool the
canopy as well and so and we know now
some of the genes for example that
determine hinging of leaves so these
things are becoming possibilities we can
tie them in with phytochrome
responses promoters for phytochrome
responses so they do a different thing
at the top of the canopy to the bottom
of the canopy now one of the things it
predicted was that actually soybeans
produced too many leaves that if if they
invested in fewer leaves you would get
more gain and so of course we were
thinking of what
um what genotype might be available in
which we could test this um vat the
graduate student who was working with us
at the time was an engineer he'd done
the modeling so he wasn't in on the
conversations we had about
genotypes instead he started an
replicated experiment in the field where
he cut off every um fourth emerging
Leaf uh so that he was preventing the
plant from investing in
these extra leaves and what he found was
that sorry every third developing Leaf
what he got was a significant 10%
increase in yield there seem to be two
reasons for that one is that the canopy
actually has more lit more leaves than
it really needs so it's it's respiratory
load by having extra leaves actually
outweighs the gain of more leaves but of
course in an evolutionary sense this
might be beneficial icial because you
never know when a herbivore is going to
come along and remove half of what
you've got
um but in the farmers's field is a
disadvantage the other is by cutting
them off early you prevent the plant
from investing resource in that
developing leaf and it resulted in a an
increase in yield and we've done that
two years running now
um so it's involves quite a lot of
undergraduate time as well but
but um he also we we had a filled
assimilation chamber where we could
actually test out the idea that it
really is resulting in a higher net CO2
uptake as well as a high yield so as I
mentioned yesterday we with Gates
Foundation funding we've now got an a
chance to test many of these ideas in
the
field um and so to
summarize I think there is a very
serious problem that we're potentially
going to have a shortfall in primary
food
stuffs there you know there are
arguments against that but I don't think
we should be taking chances we should
prepare we should be ensuring ourselves
against an uncertain future both in
human
behavior um and in climate driven by
that um
the the potential yield increases of
rising CO2 are not fully realized in our
current crops but there are genetic and
biotech Solutions although fil
facilities are seriously lacking to do
that and we're just not willing to spend
what we need to spend on on those field
facilities which which would be a tiny
fraction of the cost we're putting into
other things doe just spent 100 million
near us in into the deep rocks to see if
it could capture a small amount of CO2
that that would be enough to pay for
breeding facilities at least three sites
around the country to actually adapt to
these problems and just again finish by
thanking all the people who've made this
possible particular I should mention
this is Yin wanu and Donal my colleague
has worked closely with me um Lisa
rinworth and Andrew leaky have mentioned
as well and
uh so Carl is somewhere in these
pictures but with that our finish and
thank you for your
[Applause]
attention this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu