this is a production of Cornell
University so I basically want to talk a
little bit about some of the work we've
been doing in Africa over the last few
years I think it's um both interesting
and offers a lot of um opportunity to
move forward on a lot of levels
um it really started off when um Charles
Wonga who many of you um made know in
this department joined my program in
2006 Charles is uh from Western Kenya
but came here on the Cornell
assistantship for horiculture in Africa
and this assistantship really involved a
lot of the research work actually being
done in the home country in the case of
Charles in Kenya or East
Africa so Africa is a is a different
place for many people some people think
it more of a kind of a safari
type of land where you may go on
vacation um or maybe a lot more rural
but in actual fact it's um it's a
continent that's going through changes
uh quickly and on many many different
levels um it it's probably changing in
many respects as much as any other part
in the world at this point in time if
you go back maybe 10 15 years uh it it
was very difficult to even uh
communicate amongst groups the Advent of
the cell phone has really taken over and
almost bypassed the whole kind of
central telephone
grid and now what you're seeing in The
Last 5 Years is really pretty
astonishing the amount of road building
that's going on particularly driven by
the Chinese and particularly in um more
of the Interior areas of the country
like Western Kenya in Western
Ethiopia when I started going out there
in 2008 some of the roads in Western
Kenya were appalling and it could take a
couple of hours just to get maybe 20
miles now they have um brand new roads
developed by the Chinese and you can do
that in maybe a fraction of the time
maybe 20 minutes or 30 minutes so a lot
is going on in Africa on a lot of levels
a lot is changing with populations uh
where people are
living um and just the movements of
people in
general if you look at the traditional
African
diet um it's predominated by corn which
you see pretty much everywhere and it's
served as a kind of a ground corn that
is called
ugari then this is typically served with
um some type of protein whether it's
Lake tilapia which is common around Lake
Victoria um or chicken goat for in
instance and if meat isn't available
then dry
beans but if you look beyond the Staples
of the carbohydrate and the protein the
next most common side dish that you see
from a vegetable standpoint are leafy
greens a lot of them are not the leafy
greens that we might expect or consume
here um the leaves of cow peas are
commonly consumed um the leaves of sweet
potatoes or even common Bean so there's
a whole different range of leafy greens
that are typically served in the African
diet
the availability of crops is also
changing um you can go to some
marketplaces now and you see crops that
you would never have seen 10 or 20 years
ago um in particular green beans or snap
beans as you can see
here uh in this case in the market
you're even seeing the availability of
broccoli even though it's very poor
quality um in amongst the more Staples
of things like um tomatoes and
carrots and the other thing that's
really being driven over the last 10 or
20 years um largely through the changes
in urbanization is the appearance of
supermarkets supermarkets popping up all
over the place where population centers
um are starting to
gather um in areas like Kenya you're not
having a population increase that's
pretty high over time uh but very
noticeable in the cities Nairobi for
example has doubled in the last 20 years
from 1.8 million to about 3.6 million or
higher
today so along with the supermarkets
you're starting to see uh a much bigger
diversity of vegetable crops in
particular um that's helping to
diversify and Advance the
diet so if you start looking at how some
of these farms are in this
area um they're typically very small
often times less than an acre there's
almost no mechanization on most of the
farms and they're typically predominated
by crops like corn and dry beans where
they may have a few plants say coffee
plants or some sukuma Wiki plants um or
perhaps a couple of
bananas um so this is
a farm that we uh were visiting at the
early part of Charles's project as we
were basically going out to speak to
people about some of the crops that were
grown some of the opportunities that
might exist uh for growers in this
area so we actually met up with um
people on a number of levels uh people
who are involved with government
institutions universities International
Institutions and also Outreach and um
Farm
uh in this case we were visiting uh
farmer Nia MSO in Western Kenya uh with
Dalma seunga who's a faculty member at
um MSO
University and then we had uh this guy
who's involved with Outreach and a
couple of Growers who in this case are
starting to look at snap beans as an
alternative crop for
production and you can get into
discussion with a number of The Growers
in this area this is one of the growers
in the MSO area here and they they're
very eager to find New Market
opportunities and way that they can
diversify the crops that they are grown
they know how to grow a lot of the
bagged staple crops like corn and beans
but they want to be able to move one
step further they want some Enterprise
opportunities some opportunities where
they can grow on some of their areas of
land some crops of higher
value and this is where um horiculture
and particular vegetables really start
to come into play
Africa is not the easiest of places to
get around it is becoming easier um
there's often times difficulty to get a
vehicle for all of the people and if you
have a vehicle that's not four-wheel
drive you can run into issues like this
especially when you're in farming areas
this is Charles actually testing the
depth of the water so we can get this
car through the
puddle so we went out to Kenya and
Tanzania in 20 2008 and we met um a
number of groups institutions and
Growers while deciding how we were going
to focus the efforts or we where we
could actually have some impact when
we're looking at East Africa from a
standpoint of Upstate New York of course
um in this case we're visiting the
snapbean production areas which are up
Northwest of
Nairobi um and this is Charles speaking
to a grower but we're also traveling
with uh the bean breeder from K Thea um
and these guys that are involved with um
irrigation and Outreach as some of these
crops are being set up in these
areas so snap
beans really came to the Forefront one
because we already work on snap beans
here in Upstate New York and the other
reason is that they're currently the
major Horticultural export crop for East
AA Africa at least the major single crop
if you take the whole floral industry as
a whole it would be
higher um but snap beans um grow very
very well in the Highland areas of East
Africa around um Lake Victoria and
they're really grown based on an
Enterprise basis for feeding into the
Western European
markets which may seem counterintuitive
why people uh growing crops in Africa to
export to high-end markets in um Western
Europe well there's a lot of benefits
that actually come back from this whole
Arrangement the first one is that snap
beans um have to be of a high enough
quality to be E Rated out of the country
so when a lot of these snap beans are
actually produced only about 30% of the
ones that are harvested actually make it
to Europe the other 70% of them start to
make it into domestic markets and this
is where you start to see people consume
green beans you start to see them in
local markets you start to see them in
supermarkets and then they actually get
adopted into um and as part of the
different
diets um the other reason is an economic
opportunity for The Growers snap beans
because they're um harvested as a fresh
market crop they have a lot more weight
than a dry bean would have so if a
grower is getting 20 Kenya shillin for a
kilograms of dry beans he could be
getting the same price for a kilogram of
snap beans but you can be harvesting
five times as many snap beans from the
same acreage as dry beans so you now
give the opportunity for Growers to
produce a crop that they're familiar
with common Bean but give them access to
a fresh market um
Enterprise which gives them um a lot of
opportunity to start um to earn cap
Capital um as part of their
operations and it it's had a surprising
effect in the area I mean I I speak to
Charles and we talk about the snapbean
areas in Kenya and he talks about how
you drive into these areas and you just
as you drive into them you see
noticeable increases in affluence of the
people who are actually living in the
areas where they produce snap beans so
it has become a very important crop and
it's even just on a government level and
the carry institutes they are very keen
to try and promote the production of
these as much as
possible they um they are grown on small
farms as you can see here this is a
small farm Northeast of
Nairobi um they're also grown at very
high altitude the reason for this is
that they're very sensitive to high
temperatures so a lot of the areas
around Lake Victoria are High Plains
agriculture areas people don't really
think of places like Uganda and Kenya as
being uh temperate type of climates but
if you actually look at the altitude of
the regions uh Nairobi is at about 1700
m campala is about 18800 M and A lot of
these areas that are up north of campala
and Nairobi uh are close to 2,000 M and
so even though they're very close to the
altitude to even though they're very
close um to the Equator the high
altitude means that you have in essence
a temperate climate I visited Nairobi
last July and the high temperatures in
the day were 70째 which was about 20째
cooler than here in Upstate New
York so it's actually um really good
climates with good irrigation for the
production of snap beans um as long as
you're at altitudes above about 1500 M
and the soil looks quite good the and
the soil and the irrigation is also very
high quality in most of these Highland
areas so the issues that tend to be
encountered um in these new areas that
are producing snap beans uh the
predominant issue is rust which is a
problem for uh plant biomass it's a
problem for Quality because the rust can
also get onto the pods which is uh a
very important issue for snap beins it's
an important issue for all Horticultural
crops we deal with marketable yield that
has to have sufficient quality when it
actually hits the
marketplace
um the other problem that we see if you
go down to lower altitudes uh this is at
about 1100 M at Homer Bay um and you can
just see from Charles's reaction and the
peach juice consumption the increases in
temperature that we're seeing by moving
down um a few hundred meters in altitude
so the issues that you have when you
move down to the lake Lake Victoria
region are ones that the temperatures
day and night are basically too hot for
efficient production of a lot of these
crops so we already started to look at
these two traits as the major
constraints to green bean production uh
when we were setting up this
project so we brought in collaborators
um that I've worked with in the past uh
Tim portel who some of you might have
recognized he was a graduate student
with Molly John here a decade or so ago
and also um Tallow Pastor corales uh
he's what you might call the world's
expert on common Bean rust spent 20 or
30 years at seat and he's now at USDA
Beltsville so Tim right now is based in
uh USDA in Puerto Rico and works on heat
tolerance in beans and tala works on the
rust
resistance so the rust is really a
problematic pathogen
whereever a common being is grown in
tropical and subtropical environments
it's not a major problem right here in
New York we sometimes see it at the end
of the
season uh but it is very severe it is
very limiting especially from a quality
standpoint for crops like
snapping so what we have with rust is
that we have many many different races
of it and this is what makes it
difficult to actually work with but a
lot of work has been done done in dry
bean in the past and some of this has
been transferred to snap Bean uh from
the genetic resistance standpoint so
there's there's approximately 13 genes
associated with rust resistance I say
approximately because um ur1 and ur2 are
perhaps lost and then they maybe have a
UR 13 and ur4
Gene um but the most interesting of
these and it's it's a very intriguing
Gene from resistance standpoint is the
ur11 and this is a gene that could have
a major impact on common beans worldwide
and it is being explored with multiple
programs um for its uh use in Rust and
what we see with that is that when we
have a rust pusle develop if there's a
resistant reaction it's normally a hyper
sensitive reaction in a gene for Gene uh
type of response where you see this
necrotic lesion ur1 is is very different
in the the resistance response is more
of a field-based
resistance so if the Spore lands on the
leaf it forms a very tiny colonization
that you really can't see unless you're
looking under a microscope because it's
less than half a millimeter so it allows
the pathogen to start to colonize before
the resistance comes in and you don't
have the classic HR response
this reduces The evolutionary pressure
um from a pest pathogen standpoint and
it actually makes the gene very very
effective against many of the races it
is actually uh of the 108 that are
stored USDA belts the ur1 gene is
resistant to 107 of the 108 races which
is pretty incredible for a major Gene
and a lot of it is related to the type
of resistant response we see
so the other trait that we're interested
in is um heat
sensitivity because snap Bean production
is essentially restricted to the
Highland
areas because of heat sensitivity and
what happens here is that if we have
moderate temperatures like in a
temperate climate we have normal flower
development but if you start to increase
temperatures uh particularly the
nighttime temperature it starts to
influence plant hormones the plant
hormones affect carbon
translocation and this affects the
reproductive capacity of the plant um
most predominantly high temperatures at
night affect the ability for the plant
to form functional anthers and to be
able to produce pollen so when you have
high temperatures the pods fail to
pollinate themselves and so you get a
big loss because of heat
and the heat sensitivity of snap beans
is the reason that these are really
restricted to these high altitudes above
1500 MERS where you have the more
temperate type of
climate so we've worked on heat
tolerance in beans for a number of years
I had a graduate student when I first
started here um Katie Martin rainy who
some of you may also know um she did her
PhD project on heat tolerance and we've
continued to work with Tim porch on this
as a collabor
um but we learned a lot during that
process about how we can actually look
for heat tolerance and how we can
actually test for heat tolerance and we
do have good facilities in Geneva from a
greenhouse standpoint we have these tall
green houses that are able to maintain
temperatures very well and we find by
going to a high temperature regime like
32째 day and 27째 night and then we
compare to an optimal house uh we can
see the optimal responses of plants to
heat stress to be able to select
breeding lines that are able to um
pollinate themselves and produce pods
under high
temperatures so during this process we
developed some heat tolerant snap beam
breed in lines uh that you can see up
here on the top left and we got two
lines from USDA in Beltsville that were
snap beans that had been developed with
the ur11 gene that we wanted to
introduce for rust and almost all snap
beans have the ur4 gene which
complements the ur1
gene so we initiated some population
development which included selectin for
heat tolerant plants in a controll
temperature environment which is a
greenhouse for a couple of
generations and
developing um inbred lines to the F5
generation
that we then wanted to test the presence
of the rust genes so we wanted to select
down lines that were first heat tolerant
but also contained or had brought in the
dominant gene for
ur1 so the ur1 is an important Gene but
it's also one that hasn't been
characterized for molecular selection
for example and working with rust races
is also very difficult because of the
ability to move them from even a state
to state um
from the standpoint of the risk of
release Etc so all of the evaluations
for rust resistance were done by
inoculating the breeding lines that we
developed and this was done in
collaboration with Tallow down in USDA
Beltsville so you can see here Charles
helping Tallow evaluate the responses
for ingression of these
genes and we were able to do these by
known responses of um of different rust
races so the identification of ur11 can
be done through its susceptibility to
race 108 but it's resistant to race 67
and vice versa the ur4 with its um
susceptibility to race 67 but um
resistance to race
108 so if we have a control line that
has neither the ur4 the UR 11 Gene we
see rust on both of the leaves as you
can see here and then breeding lines
were looking to identify lines so
multiple plants that exhibited the
resistance response to both ur4 and ur11
in the lines that had already been
selected for heat
tolerance so testing the materials in
the greenhouse um is a convenient way
especially if we live in Upstate New
York but we wanted to duplicate this and
see how theyve performed in a field
situation so this is where we've worked
with Tim on the south coast of Puerto
Rico where in summer it gets
um very hot for the entire season so we
have irrigated plots with drip
irrigation uh but we maintain High day
and night temperatures when we're
looking at the um the bean growth and
yield so growing these beans in the
south coast of Puerto Rico where they're
flowering in July and August puts a very
high level of heat stress on them so we
were able to test these lines in this
environment um at the same time that we
were looking at the African
trials and what is encouraging about
this is if we look at simple
correlations between work done in the
greenhouse and work done in the field
which are very very different
environments the two most important
traits for heat tolerance which is the
number of seeds that fill per pod was
highly significant and the total seed
weight that we get per plant highly
significant so the results that we were
seeing in the field in Puerto Rica
correlated in a very high way with the
traits of Interest with those that we
were selecting in a greenhouse which is
very encouraging because it's a rare
example of where controlled
environment um stress can actually be
duplicated in the selection of
plants so we also then had to try and
apply some of these materials in
introduce them essentially into
um some field testing environments in
East Africa and what we wanted to do is
take a selection of sites that were
going to range in
altitudes so we could take sites like
car katali which is a government
institution this is up towards campala
in Northwest
Kenya uh this is at 18800 M so this is a
very temperate very nice environment for
for production of snap beans the sort of
place that you would Target if you
wanted to produce vegetable
crops we started coming down through
temperat uh through um
altitudes MSO at 1500 and sabatia down
to our highest heat stress trial which
was at Homer Bay which is near Lake
Victoria uh a little bit less than 12200
meters AR rouer in Northern Tanzania has
um a fairly lowish altitude but it also
has some interesting Dynamics because
you have the Topography of the area with
the slopes means that you get a bigger
drop off in night temperatures so it
really reacts like an environmental
altitude that is a little bit higher
than it actually is with heat stress um
home Bay though this is definitely where
you get into a very marginal area from
the um from the temperatures that you
see for the production of this type of
crop
so in 2009 out of the six trials um we
had three we had a 50% success rate in
three of these trials and fortunately
this included the um high altitude trial
and the low altitude trial the other
three trials went down for um different
reasons not not always ones that you
would um expect uh kibos was attacked by
porcupines that destroyed the ENT tie of
plot which has nothing to do with any
kind of field
resistance um sabatia was a known site
that we planted at in collaboration with
seat which was a hot spot for root rots
so we expected this to go down we were
just seeing what sort of responses it
might have to a mixture of root rots and
then we had the MSO uh plot go down with
Bean flies but we did have very nice
trials with avrdc in aroua with uh a
site that has a strong connection with
sead you're actually at H Bay which is a
farmer training center and at k catali a
government institution in
Kenya um so we also as we were doing
these trials we also wanted to kind of
Advance some of the lines uh that we
were developing so they started to
replicate the type of bean that was
being produced in
Kenya uh the types of snap beans we see
here a very large Civ um meaning the
width of them they're about the size of
uh your finger perhaps s where those in
European markets are very slender um
long and they're known as French beans
and they are already the preferred type
for Western Europe
um Africa is an ideal place to grow
these because the um the high quality
that's demanded and the fact that
they're easily damaged really makes them
um an ideal candidate for hand
harvesting or hand labor and a lot of
Europe of course is mechanized so the
one thing that Africa has is a lot of
available labor and unlike a machine
that'll do a once over Harvest on a
field in Africa with a snap Bean field
you'll have people maybe go through and
pick the plants five or six times over
the course of development to pick the
ideal size of the
pods so we developed some appearance
with the initial
populations um that had three for heat
tolerance and one for heat sensitivity
but also one that were fixed with the
different rust
genes and then we started to uh develop
populations cross into three lines that
are targeted for Africa Amy and Theresa
are the most commonly grown uh varieties
terza has the rust Gene ur5 which is
quite effective in East Africa PV 712 is
a new uh popprint snap Bean that has the
ur1 Gene and then we also cross them to
a couple cple of um us cultivar msai
which is a small C for the US market and
Bronco which is the main Fresh Market
being grown in New
York we made a similar approach
developing all 20 possible cross
combinations selecting down for Civ siiz
heat tolerance and
rust and then in
2010 we basically
identified uh the sites that we thought
would work best for us
uh for evaluating these
materials so we ended up going in 2010
with a three sites with success in 09
Arusha H Bay and kitali and our
intermediate site which is between H Bay
and kitali and altitude at uh kerak
Omega which is another government
Institute and indeed we had uh very good
results here in the fact that we had
successful trials at all four locations
even though they had uh different levels
of pressure from
rust so this this whole process has been
quite interesting and it's enabled us to
form a lot of connections on a lot of
levels I mean International connections
government connections farmer Training
Center connections or even uh NGO
connections um and it really helps us to
start um looking at what we could
potentially do U being on the other end
of the planet but during the process of
these trials Charles was based in um
Western Kenya and he did a lot of the
evaluations for well how do these
materials develop actually perform if we
put them out in these Farms so there's
some interesting things came out of this
the heat tolerant parent lines that we
evaluated more from a comparable result
in
09 we found that when we go from the
High Altitude site to the high
temperature site we had very good yield
stability in appearance which we would
expect um with heat tolerant but we also
had very good rust resistance
this is actually um the rust resistance
response so there's very minimal drop
off and in the case of the ur11 that's
also the case so having the ur11 gene as
these three lines do we have very good
stability between a non-rust area and a
rust infected area those that don't have
the ur11 gene we see about 40 to 50%
drop off in yield because of the rust
that's present so the ur1 can make a
huge huge difference when it comes to
rust then if we look at heat if we go
from the High Altitude to the low
altitude site we have yield stability in
these appearance but now the ones that
have the rust Gene like the ur11 or the
ur5 they may have resistant to rust but
when you go to lower altitudes the heat
stress starts to knock the uh yield
performance down 40 50% so it really
demonstrates what we can do with some PR
simple work in a controlled temperature
environment to really make a major
difference to crops that are very
important for Enterprise and stability
for small holder Growers um throughout
East Africa and a crop that's definitely
expanding I when I visited last year
they're building a new coolant facility
outside kilamanjaro airport that is
similar to those at Nairobi and
alderette for export of uh cooled
vegetables so in the heavily rust
infected area these are the responses of
the lines that we have on a um Leaf
basis you can see that we see rust
resistance and then this is the type of
yields that we're seeing in some of
these breeding lines that we developed
these are the ones that we promising
having the rust resistance and you can
see if you take the yield from a plant
it's comparable with a Civ type with the
ur1 pop renor with Theresa um and they
actually were yielding much higher than
the variety
currently grown um that had the
comparative rust resistance so this is
um very encouraging for moving forward
and it's lines that we actually have
planted out again this year for
evaluation because what has already
happened during the process is when when
we were interacting with a lot of these
sites we started taking a wider interest
in really what's going on with
vegetables in Africa and what some of
the uh opportunities might be for thums
so one of the big one is sukuma Wiki
um sukuma Wiki is uh it's a kind of a
Portuguese trunca Brassica it's really
like a non-head in cabbage um it's
pretty much an ancient crop I mean it
may date back to Roman days and it's
something that's still grown in southern
Mediterranean areas it's a cabbage that
you basically harvest the plant during
the course of the season um and so it's
very popular in gardens in Portugal and
in fact um with a lot of the leafy green
changes that are happening with the
foodie market right now um some crops
like sukuma Wei and Portuguese truda are
already starting to take off with some
of the vegetable seed
catalogs but it is in the East Africa
community uh pretty much the most
importable important um leafy green
that's grown sukuma Wii is Swahili and
it translates as to the weak meaning
that if people are able to eat the
Brassica vegetable with their corn and
with the protein it allows them to have
enough food to last the week it's also a
very very important plant from the
standpoint of nutrition and
diversification of diet and it is really
consumed by um tens of millions of
people um if not hundreds of millions
throughout the Lake Victoria and East
Africa region and it's the the one
vegetable that people already know and
recognize um there's a lot of reasons
why people choose to grow this over say
cabbage um if you're harvesting it every
7 to 10 days during the course of the
Season you have uh a crop that's
available to you for the whole season if
you grow a crop like cabbage you might
have to put three or four months
investment into growing a crop before
you harvest it and it might be a crop
that may get damaged for any number of
re reasons that you put all of that
investment in without any type of
recovery so anyone that's in the East
Africa community is very familiar with
sakuma Wiki and the consumption of
it we had ended up meeting a lot of
people from a lot of different places in
this case this is this guy is involved
in Outreach and extension and and this
is in Northern Tanzania but it also
shows um where they're trying to
maintain some of these sukuma Wiki
plants to develop their own sources of
seed well based on the problems that
sukuma wikii has this is a very
dangerous game because contaminated seed
is the one thing that destroys crops in
these regions in particular Brassica
crops um so while there are efforts for
self seed production really um Rootin
seeds through East African seeds or some
of the outlet are the way to go
the problem is if you're a grower in
Africa it's not like going to a colored
Johnny's catalog or an internet website
to choose what you want to plant this is
an example of a seed store that uh
growers in Africa would go to very
predominated by the grains and very
little exposure to any kind of
vegetables or vegetable seed at
all and yet you're starting to see
diversification um not just on the
stands but throughout the whole
communities cabbage is a crop that is
expanding exponentially in some ways in
Kenya the seed CS of it are going
through the roof because of the
urbanization that's happening it's a
storage crop that works very well with
supermarkets so people are starting to
look at cabbages and Alternate to sukuma
wikii because of the storability and
perishability
issues but as with sukuma wi
the the M the main problem that we see
is black rot black Root's a bacterial
disease zanth theonis
campestris it comes in through the water
and through the seeds or seed
contamination forms these characteristic
v-shaped
lesions these v-shaped lesions can take
over the plants and destroy your crop in
the case of cabbage but even in the case
of sukuma Wiki they can be damaging 50
to 80% of the leaves and if you have
these v-shaped lesions on the leaves
they're not marketable they're then fed
to
livestock so often times you can lose
80% of your sukuma wiy crop because of
this
disease um and in cabbage it's even more
of a risk because you risk losing your
entire crop this is a cabbage field in
Tanzania and if you look closely you can
see um black rots starting to appear in
the plants uh but this is one at about
2,000 M near katali in Northwest
Kenya this is uh this is the grower here
uh he'd had success for a couple of
years and this is a field that is large
by African standards it's about four or
five
ACR this was all cabbage none of this
has been
harvested this is what happens to a
field when you plant cabbage with black
rot on the seed you get nothing which
was devastating for the grower and you
have a problem like that it may be a lot
of years before you think about planting
cabbage or vegetables again so the types
of crops that are grown are very
important and the issues with sales
distribution channels in Africa are very
problematic um there's three main
suppliers in Africa a lot going through
East African seeds but it's predominated
by by the South
Africans and it locks out a lot of seed
companies from
uh Mark in materials that would be uh
much more appropriate for
Growers so we started to discuss some of
these issues from a diversification
standpoint and what we could do U with
vegetable
brassas uh this is meeting in kumu um a
year or so ago but Charles who's now
back in Kenya even though he's uh sort
of working as a sweet potato breeder for
sip across Western Kenya and Uganda
um has now started up his own company
with um Dan
nanok um and it's really to try and uh
find underserved markets for seed in
Western Kenya um and so we started to
work with them through um a foundation
grant that we got from the Atkinson
Center and
sead uh to look at uh how we could
actually get some um Improvement of some
of the crops for these areas and also
look into some of the crops that perhaps
could be grown that aren't so uh with
Charles and Dan having set up um
Advantage crops limited this gives uh a
really important kind of penetration
into a highly underserved market and
some very unique
opportunities the the one that we
started to focus on of course was sukuma
Wii cuz such an important crop in Africa
we started making back crosses of race
non-specific black rot to this back in
2008 and it's an effort that it doesn't
require a whole lot of labor but it does
require a lot of time because brassas
tend to take about a year to go from
seed to seed with
breeding but we have been working on
black rot resistant in cabbage for a
number of years and so we started backd
draing it to sukuma Wiki because it is
the same species just in non-heading
type so we also started to look to well
what types of cabbage are actually being
produced in East Africa and what are the
varieties that are actually being
grown and part of the problem is access
to the correct
varieties this is a cabbage variety that
would have been grown in New York 30 or
40 years ago most cabbage varieties here
now are hot water treated for seed so
they have really very little Passover
black root from a seed standpoint but if
you do get black rot in the field you
see how the varieties start to come down
whereas a lot of the newer varieties
Thunderhead from reads um you know this
is a seus one blue Dynasty but you can
see the level of Black Rock resistance
in an inoculated field is significantly
lower so having access to resistant
varieties uh of cabbage as those markets
start to expand is also very important
not necessarily from us developing the
materials here but actually helping them
gain access to those types of cultivar
and
materials we're also looking from a
standpoint of the different types of
leafy greens that could be consumed we
we started looking uh while Charles was
here back in about 09 at a lot of
different leafy brassas there there was
a collection trip done in about 2000 um
right across the
southeast and it was was done with a
breeda who's a collaborator on a federal
project with me but also
um somebody who was really familiar you
know with the areas and
anthropology and they went around the
southeast and they collected uh about a
100 different land races of collards
that really vary dependent on all of the
different
communities um across the southeast and
a lot of them AC course African-American
communities so we planted these collards
and tried to start to Identify some real
variation in the leaf types and the
plant morphologies that were there from
these land races that had basically been
selected for quality and edibility over
a number of generations in the
US
so we've really started to look at um
not just the disease standpoint or the
alternative cul of our standpoint or the
alternative uh plant type but but we
also have to look from a standpoint of
education
and one of the hard cells is F1 hybrid
seed um people don't want to buy seed
that costs 10 times as much as the seed
that they've always grown or five times
as much but you could see a hybrid
sukuma Wiki here compared to a
non-hybrid just on a shio biomass
standpoint and sometimes paying some
extra money for the seed can double the
yields that you get off a lot of these
crops so there's a lot of areas that
need to be looked at and promoted to try
and get the right materials into the
hands of a lot of these Growers this is
at USA in Tanzania uh which is at an
afram site which is a nonprofit Venture
from east west seeds and uh rexb in the
Netherlands
we can also start looking at crops that
are not brass oraia this is Ethiopian
mustard and you can see the biomass of
this is significant where it's growing
almost 2 meters in height so these are
types of crops where you can really
start to exploit um both the yield and
the fact that there's um a lot of
openness to the types of leaves that are
consumed within the
diet so over the last three or so years
we've been doing trials here in Geneva
and what we've been trying to do is
identify a subset that we can introduce
and evaluate um some with some of these
partners and connection sites that we
have in Africa so we've been looking at
some breeding materials some varieties
but also um a lot of these accessions
that we've identified from the
USDA a lot of these we have in limited
seed supplies so we've had to develop
our own seed to um put forward as part
of these studies of course
some of them develop seeds better than
others this is a plant that we
vernalized and it's about uh 4 M tall
possibly the world's tallest barassa
it's it's actually a sukuma Wiki that we
just couldn't get to seed no matter how
much we
tried um and so we came together uh last
year in particular to see how are we
going to start to exploit these
Partnerships and and start to look at
some of these alternate types of plants
as they fit the market so this is up in
katali with um Thomas uh gubo who's our
collaborator at the K katali site uh
which is one of the sites we've been
planting at this year we've planted at
four sites in Kenya and two sites in
Tanzania and we're looking for a lot of
diversification of types not like you
might expect in the US which would be
more based on color and Aesthetics we're
looking at it more from a practicality
standpoint
so you have the crops that are similar
to what are consumed with sukuma wiggi
which is this kind of Portuguese trunc
UDA type where you get the Stacked
leaves that you would Harvest during the
course of the
plant um but we're also starting to
introduce a lot of stuff that is both
commercially available as F1 hybrids and
stuff that we've selected from the
collards that were collected from the
southeast of the US so this would be
kale which curious ious ly enough has
just exploded in the US market I I was
speaking to Dutch seed Sellers and they
say for 25 years we've had kale seed
anybody wants kale seed we have it
overnight kale seed sales doubled and
nobody has any kale seed anymore it just
came from
nowhere um this is um another type of
kale so we're just looking at how some
of these different uh Leaf morphologies
are really accepted from an aesthetic
and cooking standpoint with the people
and communities that we're targeting
this is a Russian tetrol kale that has a
little bit more Vigor some color in
it high biomass Collard that we've
developed and then some that vary in
just the color
size um the texture of the leaf just to
try and get feedback from people about
which of these leafy brassas they would
prefer um
this is more of a um standard Collard
type this has more of a veiny type of
look which probably looks a little less
edible but interestingly some of these
ones like this is a top Bunch this is
one of the top sell in F1 hybrid
collards throughout the southeast of the
US from beo seeds and jles is super
excited about this and how it may do in
the African Market but of course they
have no access to seed because they have
no access to to beo seat channels um
through the Distributors that exist uh
there's also a a new variety Bonanza
that is very similar to um a sukuma Wiki
type that is incredible for biomass and
also an F1 hybrid that very much fits
into the
community so this summer we've been
having trials at these sites where a lot
of these materials have been grown
they've mostly been overseen by Dan this
is at the hom of bay site with his
characteristic
tump and and we've included both the
cultivar the colard selections and even
the breeding lines or preliminary
breeding lines that we have so this is
materials we started in 2008 where we've
developed the non-heading sakuma Wicky
types with black rot resistance uh that
we're testing out there um and then
these are being an oent for uh pharmer
evaluations um in this case it was
actually some people from Cornell
associated with the mcnight group that
were passing through visiting for corn
but even small sites like this have
gotten some attention This Is the
personal assistant to the Ministry of
Agriculture in Kenya so you know you can
have some small sites experimenting with
some small plots but they they very
quickly can get exposure as important as
Agriculture and food is to the Kenyan
Community um unfortunately I was unable
to go in September because I had a um a
side impact Collision that dislocated my
kneecap unfortunately I had surgery a
few days later uh but I will be going
back this November and what we're doing
with these materials is we're replanting
them for not just Pharma trial sites but
we're Charles and Dan are also going to
be doing uh cooking trials with amongst
a lot of people to see how these
actually taste and how they're actually
received by the different
communities so going forward I think
that the opportunities are a really
pretty staggering um because there's
really a grounding of the only way to go
is
up um and I think that with Advantage
crops having being set up this actually
gives a a nice kind of um entry into the
market that's really heavily protected
to many respects and I was having
conversations with um a lot of the
people at beo a couple of weeks ago and
what we're trying to do is set up um
Charles and Dan with um the product
manager for Africa and Middle East so
they can act in some type of reseller or
agent capacity for beo seeds because beo
really have a lot of these kales and
cads and F1 hybrids that really are what
the Growers need not what they have
access to in the current
climate
um so as we go forward
I the trend in Africa certainly is
towards
urbanization the population is
increasing in Kenya in the last 20 years
it's gone up 50 60% the population in
cities has
doubled so it's very difficult to
support sustainable agriculture on very
small farms with corn and beans when you
having in population increases um
occurring at that rate it's making mean
a lot of people mve to cities so small
farms are no longer becoming sustainable
the opportunities for vegetables and
Horticultural crops from a
sustainability and Enterprise standpoint
um really are pretty phenomenal for a
lot of these Farms because so many of
these areas are at these high altitude
sites that have very much of a temperate
climate ideal for floral and vegetable
crop production and yet in a lot of this
land we're just seeing staple crops like
corn and beans being grown um so as we
go forward uh we hope to kind of be
involved with that and capitalize on it
um and this of course has been aided by
uh a number of supporters both for um
Charles's work which included assistant
ship for RO in Africa and uh Agra
support Alliance for Green Revolution in
Africa but more recently the support
that we've also had in the bras work
from the Atkinson Center academic
Venture fund and CAD with Chris Barrett
here
um I also of course want to thank my
group we do a lot more than just this
Africa work we have a lot of different
projects going on which is not easy to
uh hold together at times um this is our
summer group a number of us are
represented out at the back here which
are the people you might not recognize
as part of this
group um but that's just
really giving an overview of something
that is ongoing in many respects because
uh I plan to be out there in a few weeks
to see how some of these materials are
coming along and to really explore um
where we can go to take the next step
with this essentially so if anybody has
any questions
that's G I would urge that uh The
Establishment testing and sale of
adapted African card whatever you call
them and it doesn't matter what the
origin is but uh I mean find black Rod
is difficult but heat treatment can take
care of it and and as soon as a a local
industry can get going it doesn't have
to depend on imports from Beil I would
think that that would be the sustainable
solution I wonder to what extent you're
working in that direction it's difficult
to produce seed for cabbage in East
Africa because is the vernalization
requirement go to the higher altitudes
um but yeah the the there's a number of
things that really need to be addressed
it's Outreach and education to Growers
is very important the benefits of
resistant varieties or hybrid varieties
very important but also trying to move
through appropriate materials uh help to
Target some of these trads for some of
the materials Black Rock would be
important not just for cars and Africa
it's important um throughout the world
it's the major
limiting disease of
braus um there is a a strong and
bureaucratic link between a lot of these
groups like government and East African
seeds and some of the distribution
channels there's the T to be a very
strong presence of the Japanese
varieties in brassas s in particular was
one of the major distribut in Africa but
even the stuff that's that's rooted
really through a lot of the South
African apps they they predominate a lot
of how the sales actually work
especially from the hybrid variety
standpoint I think that some of the
props like less valuable or they just
run through
institutions like governments but yeah
hot water treatment of seeds could
really change the game U because that
field I showed you was devastating I
mean that was clearly a case of C
cabbage variety the the seat was highly
contaminated and when the variety
susceptible or resistant that's
something we even if was susceptible it
wouldn't be that
bad okay we really are out of time but
again Griff thank you so much
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu