this is a production of Cornell
University um today I'm going to be
talking about tea and the taste of
climate change I've been studying the uh
tea System since 2006 for me tea is a
really interesting way to examine human
interactions with the environment
because it is a plant system that humans
have managed for hundreds if not
thousands of
years um and I'm specifically focusing
on on um the impacts of climate change
on tea um as we know climate change is
impacting agroecosystems and farmer
livelihoods as well as the health
benefits consumers get from agricultural
products around the
world um for example um a longer
frostfree growing season can help
increase the production of specific
crops um and as previous Scholars have
shown um this really depends where you
are located geographically in the world
and it also depends on the specific crop
um that you're speaking about whether
it's rice or soy each plant behaves
differently and most previous Scholars
have documented or focused on looking at
the impact of climate change on crop
yield this is relatively well
documented um and what my study focuses
on with my collaborators is looking at
the impact of climate change change on
crop quality um which is a lot less
acknowledged um and the way I am looking
at this is through a coupled natural and
human systems approach where we have our
natural system of biotic and abiotic
factors um and then we have our human
system um of Traders and consumers and
Farmers um and sort of the link between
that is the Agro agroecosystem or our
food production system and the feedback
loop between the natural system and the
human system that I'm focusing on in
addition to yields is really crop
quality um and then the way that the
human system sort of takes that response
and then feeds into the natural system
is through their actual adaptation and
management of
agroecosystems um and then obviously
these agroecosystems do not exist on
their own they're impacted by exogenous
change such as climate change policies
as well as markets um and so that's sort
of the overall uh socio eological system
which I'm looking at um and really a
focus on crop
quality and crop quality is important um
as I mentioned before um because it's
not only yields that are important for
food security uh or for the amount of
money Farmers receive from selling crops
it's also the actual quality of those
products um so if you're thinking about
all of these sort of diverse food and
vegetables um it's not only calories but
it's also the micronutrients and these
micronutrients vary based on management
of the Agro
ecosystem um for example um a carrot
grown in an organic system versus a
carrot grown in a conventional system
may have varying levels of um the
secondary metabolites that provide the
main health benefits from consuming
these
carrots um and so if you're consuming a
carrot that has relatively low
concentrations of these secondary
metabolites you're also not going to be
getting the same health benefits and
have to consume more um of the same
product and um so I've sort of taken
that framework and applied it to looking
at the te system um to see the impacts
on um te in my study but really thinking
about Botanical quality more broadly of
both food and medicinal plants uh which
are Central to ethnobotanical system
so the overall objective of my study is
to provide quantitative data how and why
T qualties vulnerable to changing
climate conditions um and that's at the
natural level of the system and then the
resulting linkages to uh the social
system both economic as well as um
cultural um so I'm just going to go
through the main objectives of this
study
um and today I'm going to share how um
climate is impacting T quality and yield
I'm going to share some data from field
sampling as well as manipulative
Greenhouse experiments so I've been
using extreme climate events in the
field as a proxy measure for climate
events that are supposed to become more
prevalent with climate change um and of
course there's a lot of confounding
factors that occur with field sampling
and so I'm also coupling that with
manipulative Greenhouse experiments that
mimic um climate predicted or expected
climate factors um and then I'm bringing
those samples back to the lab to look at
the phytochemical
variation the second um objective is
then to take those same t- samples and
see the way the consumers are responding
to that variation in secondary metabolic
chemistry through sensory
analysis um and my collaborative we're
also doing agricultural economics
modeling um to look at how um climate
variables are impacting yields on a
larger
scale and the third objective is looking
at the way farmers are responding to
variations of clim climate variability
in their t- systems uh both based on
their direct observation as well as the
way they are responding to markets um so
if consumers are are perceiving sensory
variation in Te how does that impact
consumer buying decisions and then how
does that impact the way farmers are
managing their agroecosystems and what
decisions are they making based on um
consumer
responses and then finally the goal is
to take all of this varied
socioecological data and to construct a
model where we'll be able to simulate
the response of um T quality to variable
climate factors um and the goal of this
is to develop plans and policies um that
we can provide to tea Farmers um and
land use managers to better um adapt and
mitigate for climate
change so when I'm talking about te I'm
specifically talking about Chamilia
sensus and the the family um that is the
commercial Source um for all white green
oolong black and puer te so it comes
from this one single species and it's
the variation in the processing that
results in this diversity of flavor
profiles that we get but it is from the
same species um and census has two main
cultivars or two main varieties excuse
me the census variety which is a small
leaf or variety that grows in more
tempered areas and the ASA variety which
is the broadleaf variety which is is
considered the original variety that um
grows in tropical and subtropical
areas um and in addition to those
varieties there's also a lot of
diversity with lots of farmer land races
and Cult of ours the reason um
particularly in yam Province um in
southwestern China which is considered
the birthplace of the tea plant um so
unan borders Myanmar Vietnam and la and
in this area you see not just chamia
senses growing in the wild but also 11
other species that are closely related
to chamia senses um that farmers use the
germoplasm in their te systems for
ingression resulting in a lot of um
genetic diversity and having this area
be sort of the center of genetic
diversity for the tea
plant um these are a few farmer land
races so um with my background I would
say these are all chamia census for RIA
um and DNA barcoding would confirm that
um however the farmers that I work with
in unan have a different name for each
of these different um land races and
they also have different sensory
attributes or uses um for these even
though I'm saying they're all Chamilia
andensis variety OFA there's a lot
deeper ecological knowledge and use uh
by the farmers that are managing these
systems and they may have 15 to 20
different land races of tea within a
single Tea Garden of just a hectar so so
a lot of diversity and if you sort of
compare that to um our main um food
crops in the world um it's really
fascinating to see why and how Farmers
manage this
diversity um and um so tea plants can
you know tea leaves can grow to
different sizes um imagine one of these
tea leaves and furling in your teacup um
and that probably wouldn't happen so
much over here because usually when te
commercialized it's the young the new
bud and the adjacent two leaves are the
Harvest units for
commercialization however in indigenous
communities that have been managing tea
for hundreds of years um farmers do
harvest the older leaves which they use
to make tonics uh for immune boosting
and that's this is an example of that
Harvest um so tea in its native state
grows to be a a Tall Tree about 15 to 20
M tall and it grows in these beautiful
biodiverse forests um in southern Yan on
into Northeastern India in Burma and in
La um and then with human management
that sort of traditional Forest system
has transitioned so this over here is a
tagro forest um it still looks a lot
like a forest system um however it's
been intensified for tea production um
and some of the Woody plant species have
been removed from the system however a
lot of food and medical plants are still
maintained I had done an inventory of
about 20 m x 20 M plots and I found over
200 um food and medicinal plants that
were conserved within the space um by
the community for various needs um this
over here is a mixed crop system and um
it has tea and it's intercropped with
grains um however tea in most parts of
the world grows in monocultural Terrace
plantations um really for consistent
product and high yields um and so
there's a lot of different management
and obviously based on the different
management the phychem qualities of tea
also
vary and just another note on the
management of these systems an agro
Forest because it's relying on a forest
structure um doesn't need to have
agrochemical inputs like pesticides and
fertilizers because it's relying on
ecosystem Services provided by the
forest structure whereas monocultural
plantations even if they're organic
generally have agrochemical input
pesticides and um herbicides
Etc and as I mentioned um we're not
necessarily consuming tea for in large
quantities for yield um it really
depends on the the quality um and so if
you're a black black tea drinker versus
a green tea drinker um that variation is
because of the change in chemistry that
occur during processing um you might buy
high mountain teas versus low Mountain
teas um because you really uh have a
preference uh for specific
phytochemistry um so the main
phytochemicals um for tea that give its
health benefits are the polyphenols with
egcg being sort of the star antioxidant
compound which is gotten a lot of press
um and advertisement um and all those
different phytochemicals including the
polyphenols um and methyl xanthine
caffeine which gives tea stimulant
properties um theanine which makes tea
sort of a relaxant um all of these have
a specific taste which consumers are
able to perceive um such as Bitter Sweet
or bitter and sweet um and this really
varies again as I mentioned with
Environmental Management um and just a
little note over here on the bottom um
this shows sort of the evolution of tea
the historic use of tea was is
considered to have been medicine and um
sort of transition from medicine to a
tonic and eventually to a beverage
um tea leaves are consumed as a food in
some parts of the world um sort of like
a like a
salad um and T um I find it a really
compelling study system because it is
the most consumed beverage in the world
after water so it has really quite
widespread um utilization there's
hundreds of years of management and it
also plays an important role in public
health um because it provides a a
notable source of antioxidant
phytochemicals um and these are linked
to um different uh benefits in the human
body such as um
anti-inflammatory um prevention against
cancer as well as um for
cardiovascular um
health so T was um traditionally sort of
this the center of diversity as I
mentioned was in southern unon which is
over here um and because of these health
benefits provided by tea um it became uh
requested or uh demanded in communities
That Couldn't grow it so over here um
this red line basically is the um torse
Road um which is the book that Dr
Rodriguez had showed um and this is the
oldest te trade route of uh in the world
um and over here this is the Tibetan
Plateau this is Lassa over here um and
communities in the Tibetan Plateau um
live in pretty hard conditions where
it's really hard to grow fruits and
vegetables and they came to utilize tea
as a substitute for fruits and
vegetables um and that really is what
spurred the creation um off this old
historic Road um which Not only was tea
traded but lots of other
spices and medicines um and um and that
was sort of the first spread of tea um
and then as more and more communities um
began to know of tea and it was really
through Buddhist monks um um that spread
the consumption of tea um more and more
people began to incorporate into their
daily um
routine so I'm just going to share some
photographs from the torse road to give
you a better cultural context of this
area um this is an AKA Village it's a t
farming community in southern Yan where
I've been working since 2006
um and just some pictures of the torse
road
itself um so the last picture is um tea
being consumed um by Tibetan households
and it's been ched with butter um Yak
butter specifically so this is yak
butter tea has anybody tried Yak butter
tea yes how what's the flavor profile
for
you acquire
taste um and so I was mentioning earlier
how the uh the quality of tea varies um
based on environmental conditions and
this is just one example if tea is
harvested from um a low elevation versus
sort of at the top of the mountain um
data suggests that there is
phytochemical variation um and this is
why a lot of consumers um seek out high
mountain teas um and also the prices of
those are notably
higher um again we're looking at the
aagra forest versus a monoculture um and
some of the work that I had done for my
doctoral dissertation was to sort of
analyze um the difference the
phytochemical variation so this is an
Agra Forest um in an AA community and
this is um a
monoculture Plantation nearby um at the
same elevation and um we found that
there was um more than twice the amount
of um key catak and compounds for tea
procured from the Agro Forest um and
this may be because of many reasons it
may be because there's a lot more pest
pressures in an Agra Forest um or
because of shade trees or because of the
height of trees so a lot of different
factors which we're now looking at the
specific mechanism through Greenhouse
studies
H oh cakin are polyphenolic compounds um
that provide antioxidant um activity in
humans so it's sort of the link to the
health benefits um of green
tea and um these um so this is just the
variation based on the production system
and then based on geographic region or
the spe specific cultivar um the
photochemical is also vary in tea um so
in blue here we have all the different
sort of tea producing areas within
China and then as I mentioned before um
when you process tea from white tea to
black tea or post fermented po tea um
there's also a change in phytochemicals
um based on all the different processing
factors um so the main processing that
happens once tea is harvested is um
steaming it or pan frying it and this is
to deactivate the polyphenolic oxidase
that oxidizes the kaken compounds
rolling it to break down the cell walls
and remove moisture content and then
drying it and this really helps preserve
um the health compounds attributed to
the different teas and then variation in
these different processes um results in
all of these different types of
tea and um my previous work has shown um
as well as that by a lot of other
scientists that consumers can perceive
changes in t secondary metabolites um
and so this is a ranking of te 100
different teas and um the more the less
intensely rated tees also had lower
amounts of cakin as well as the methyl
xanthine
caffeine um and now I'm going to talk
about the cup of tea that specifically
drove my research um on the impacts of
climate change and tea um this is during
one of my first field seasons in 2007
and I was in a AKA household um drinking
tea after a long day of ecological
sampling um and then I returned to that
same house about 3 days later and the
East asiia Monsoon had hit um and we
were drinking tea again and um the head
of the household female says it has
changed the taste has changed um and I
was really curious what she meant um and
then her husband also drank the tea and
he also confirmed that the tea had
changed
um and uh what they were referring to
was that the East Asian Monsoon had hit
um and so they had sort of transitioned
from a spring Harvest to a monsoon
Harvest which is really attributed to
when the rains come um and uh and then
quality drops notably um and the prices
farmers get for their tea also drops um
and then when the Autumn Harvest is
basically determined by the retrieval of
the East Asian Monsoon and at this stage
the quality is perceived to increase as
well as the price that farmers get for
their tea so it really is an issue just
not just of the phytochemicals that
we're consuming but also the livelihoods
that farmers are getting from their
crop and after her husband um tested the
tea he determined the price to be about
half of that of the spring
Harvest um and this is just some data
showing how there's a drop in prices um
based on the different seasons
and that really made me start thinking
about the role that precipitation has in
Te quality and what does this mean uh
with increase or decrease precipitation
um that's occurring with um climate
change um and so the central tenant of
my study is um sort of looking at te as
an indicator species for climate change
and what this can tell us about other um
plants that we're using specifically for
the leaf um and then thinking about
taste um as a sense of climate change
and and its effects on food quality so
really thinking about the individual
consumer and the the role that they're
playing in um sensing climate change
based on
taste um and now I'm going to share some
data from the natural side component of
this
study um and so for the field sampling I
am working with my collaborators and
we're sampling at three different sites
in China or three different regions in
China which are different sort of
um kind of capture the different um
climatic conditions of major tea
producing areas in China um at each site
we have or location we have two sites a
high elevation and a low elevation site
we try to choose the elevations to be
somewhat the same um and um also the
cultivar that's in each of the systems
um is also uh We've accounted for and
we're sampling basically from 2012 till
2016 so it's a 5year study um um and um
you know and multiple Seasons within the
year and the goal eventually is then to
take all of the data on T quality and
yields um from these five years and
these uh six different locations um and
combine them to eventually um construct
our
model so I'm going to share data from
one of our sampling years um and this is
our very first sampling year and so this
was taken in just one location
uh where we sample basically across 15
days during an extreme drought period um
as well as the onset of the monsoon and
then during an extreme Monsoon
period um and over here we're looking at
the response of leaf biomass um from
during the drought to the monsoon so we
see an increase in both Leaf length as
well as um
weight um and then concurrently there is
a significant reduction in secondary
metabolite concentrations um from the
spring drought to the monsoon um so the
major antioxidant compounds that
determine T quality were shown to
decrease um and that work I I did in the
lab using um
hlc um as well as um some basic
bioassays and antioxidant assays um I'm
not a chemist and so that's why I find
collaboration um really to be um the
spice of life and very promising um and
fulfilling in my research um and so I'm
collaborating with some chemists who are
experts um at GC gcms um and so they
also um are looking at the same samples
um where they've developed this really
comprehensive tea library and um they're
looking at the specific volatiles or
Aroma compounds that determine T quality
and they also found that there were a
few more
um Aroma compounds um in the spring
samples or the drought samples compared
to the monsoon
samples um and so we found an inverse
relationship overall um in terms of our
Leaf weight um to secondary metabolite
concentrations um and um this suggests
um either a dilution effect and or uh
water stress to the plant
um and what does this sort of mean that
was just a seasonal study so what does
this sort of mean for larger climate
change um looking at um precipitation in
the field site shows that there really
has been historically um this looks at
data from 1980 to 2010 there really
historically has been this variation um
of uh precipitation throughout the year
and overall there seems to be a downward
Trend in precipitation at the study site
um which suggests that tea quality could
actually be getting better with climate
change however plants do have their
thresholds as we know um and so
precipitation becomes too low um this
may just um be detrimental to the plant
overall um and then looking at um that
was sort of annual precipitation um and
now looking at seasonal precipitation um
overall spring precipitation has
increased um since 1970 um about 15 to
20% of the study site um and then at the
same time um Monsoon precipitation has
also
increased um and the the decrease in PR
precipitation was during the Autumn
season and that's when um farmers are
not harvesting as much
tea um and then looking into the future
um future climate scenarios for the 2050
to 2079 period um shows that
precipitation is expected to decrease
during the Spring season so again
perhaps um this may impact te quality
positively if it doesn't cross the plant
threshold um and then during the monsoon
season it's supposed to be getting
wetter and so basically farmers are
going to be seeing variable impacts on
their te- systems um and that was only
just for one year sampling at once study
site um and our goal is to take that
sort of coupled uh climate and uh T
quality data for five years um at these
six locations towards really having a
better understanding and making a
stronger statement um of climate effects
and te
quality um and I had also only shown
data from one site and this is looking
at tea production across China
um and this is looking at temperature so
there's been an upper trend of
temperatures in all T producing sites in
China um there's also been um while
temperatures are increasing
precipitation overall in tea producing
sites in China is decreasing um and then
overall yields have been increasing and
this is um taking into consideration any
changes in
technology for tea
production um and
um in the field we've only sort of
looked at
precipitation um and um temperature
however there's multiple dynamics that
are happening of course in Agro
ecosystems and farmers are reporting for
example um changes in pest pressures um
different weeds um and then changes in
pollination Dynamics within their
systems um so in the future we plan to
look at these um a little bit more
carefully um and we're going to be doing
that also in manipulative Greenhouse
experiments and I find these experiments
really wonderful to um engage
undergraduate students because we don't
have to take students all the way to
China which is also a great thing to do
but we can also um have a little Tea
Plantation right there in the
greenhouse um and one of the
undergraduate um research projects
looking at um different variables
actually found that the interaction of
her biver with precipitation of set the
increased precipitation um and so when
we're just looking at a single climate
variable we may have one conclusion but
we when we actually look at the
interactions that are happening within
Agro ecosystems um one effect May offset
another effect um and interestingly some
farmers are um accounting for um pest as
a promising um strategy for when their
tea quality decreases so there's a
specific tea that grows in Taiwan um and
with the increased precipitation that's
happening during the monsoon season um
the quality is considered so low however
pest pressures are also increasing in
that area and instead of putting
pesticides as Farmers usually do they're
now actually letting the pests Pro
proliferate in their tago ecosystems um
because it sort of results in a
different change in secondary metabolic
chemistry and actually giving that tea a
slightly peachy or honey like Flavor um
and so these are all these different
sort of adaptation strategies that
farmers are taking um in response to
climate change or climate
variation um and now I'm going to share
some data from the human
system um so one thing that one of the
major components of the sensory analyses
and I don't have the data to share right
now um but I wanted to just show the
different types of sensory analysis that
we're doing so we're actually going to
be speaking to five different
populations um since there's a lot of
human variation and cultural variation
um on uh the way we respond or perceive
taste and our preferences so um one
population are tea Farmers Traders and
connoisseurs in China another one is an
expert tea panel at the te Research
Institute of China that's been trained
to really uh measure tea quality um and
then we are coupling this with um te
populations in the United States um one
is a tea panel at T University um and
then Western tea consumers um and
Western tea experts so really getting a
diverse group of consumers um to see
maybe only tea farmers and tea experts
are able to perceive this difference
maybe uh Western consumers aren't or
maybe they are so these are sort of the
experiments that we're doing right now
to see how notable are um who's actually
able to discern these changes in
phytochemical quality
um and another major component of the
research is really looking at the way
farmers are perceiving um climate
impacts on their t- systems so I'm going
to share some a little bit of
information from three sites in the bong
mountains of southwestern China uh where
I conducted semi-structured surveys with
three different indigenous groups um the
bulong the LA lahu and the
AKA and then I took that survey data and
um carried out cultural conent ensus
analysis um to look at variation within
a community and between communities um
and these are some overall patterns that
we have seen um farmers are reporting
that there is increased rainfall um
unpredictability as well as increased
temperatures um and uh farmers are also
saying that um they really perceive that
rain impacts te quality however they're
not really sure how temperatures
increase um or impact te quality
um and that's some information that um
perhaps our T project will be able to
show and um within these three different
indigenous groups um that all are in the
bong mountains we did find high degree
of informant agreement um on the effects
of climate change uh more recently I've
started to interview um T farmers and um
that aren't that don't own the land or
um these three indigenous communities of
managing tago ecosystems or their
communities have for hundreds of years
um so they really have this ecological
knowledge that that has been passed down
um and more recently in Eastern China
I've been interviewing tea Farmers that
are more landless laborers um that have
only been some of them only recently
introduced this tea system and they have
a very different understanding of the
way climate is impacting their tea
systems so it's not that all farmers are
aware of this um I'm really seeing that
it's you know the indigenous Farmers
have a very different understanding um
compared to um Farmers that have not
necessarily managed an aggro ecosystem
for that
long and um the farmers you know that do
that that are aware of it are also very
concerned on the impact that it has um
on tea prices um so we were seeing this
inverse relationship of precipitation
and T price
historically um and so how are Farm
responding to these different changes um
over here I've sort of summarized from
the coding of the data um some of the
different farmer responses to climate
change um so some Farmers have started
to um substitute different varieties and
make their Tea Gardens more diverse um
others are actually planting other crops
um just so they aren't putting all their
eggs in one basket um there is some U
modification of the environment with
technology and management for example in
places where they have really intense
droughts um farmers are starting to
think about having irrigation systems um
I had mentioned the example of um
letting pest proliferate in the field um
there's also alteration of post Harvest
processing um and so during processing
you can really also change the chemistry
um so some tees that were historically
processed as green teas are now being
processed as oolongs or blacks where
they're really taking advantage of
processing to um enrich in the flavor um
there's also some repurposing of the end
use of the product um and overall in
certain communities people are very
active in sort of thinking about hard to
how to Market um their products
differently um and then in some
communities people are abandoning their
tea systems um or they're uh relocating
the locations maybe to higher elevations
in the mountain um which they perceive
as having or being more of resilient to
climate
effects um and so I previously had
talked about these two different systems
um the Agra forest and a t monoculture
and a lot of the farmers who do manage
both systems um this this uh monoculture
system has really been promoted
throughout China um through government
extension the grain for green program or
policy actually gave Farmers um
incentives to um have this sort of
system and so in some communities you
see Farmers managing both an Agra Forest
as well as a monocultural plantation um
and the farmers that manage both will
say how their Agra Forest are more
resilient to different climate variation
that happens from year to year or from
season to season um and so looking at um
the drop in tea quality there was a
slightly smaller drop or notably um
smaller drop in Te quality um for Agro
Forest compared to the mon culture and
this is only sampling over one year so
we're going to be continuing this um to
see this trend uphol in more
sites um an Agra Forest also you know
provide a lot more economic benefits to
Farmers so this the blue line over here
is looking at the market price um at
this field site for Te from an Agra
forest and the Orange is looking at um
during the same season price for um
Terrace or modern culture for Plantation
tea so farmers really do have an
economic incentive um not just an
ecological incentive to um grow this to
grow teen Agro forests um and then some
of my previous work also showed that
Agro forests have um a little bit more
genetic diversity or notably more
genetic diversity than than Terrace
plantations um and so taking all of um
this all of this information that I
presented today
um just having you think as an audience
of the role of taste um as a um censor
of climate change and I'm not sure if
you personally or have had relatives or
friends um say that oh this fruit or
vegetable used to tast really different
before when I was younger and some of
that might have to do um perhaps with
the way it's cultivated or some of that
might actually have to do with climate
variables um so just something to think
about um and then specifically I'm
thinking about tea as an indicator
species of climate change but what other
crops um can we look at to be an
indicator species for climate
change um and then the role of adaptive
capacity in determining the um extent of
climate effects um and so there's one
body of work that really focuses on
mitigating climate uh change and the
other um work that really focuses on
adapting to climate change um so what
would it mean for
sustainability um if monoculture
plantations um transitioned to systems
like
this um and overall um I've been
starting to use this coupled model to
look at other systems as well not just
te quality um so I leave you with a few
questions is climate change changing the
taste and quality of our favorite and
our local foods
and what does this mean for Farmer
livelihoods and what does it mean for
the health benefits that we derive from
the specialty crops and for food
security um and more re recently as I've
been expanding my research uh using the
socio eological model I've started to
look at the impacts of climate change on
maple syrup quality um and I know
there's some really great research
happening here at Cornell um looking at
the impacts of climate change um on
maple syrup um and uh recently um my
collaborators and I got a USGS Grant to
look at this uh which is specifically
focusing on the impacts on quality
versus
yields and then in Montana where I teach
um I'm also starting to look at two new
systems which are huckleberries um and
fad cherries which are two agricultural
products that um the state really prizes
for its cultural identity
um and so I just wanted to thank you as
an audience for being here today um and
thank you so much Dr Rodriguez for
hosting me um and to Terror for all the
the coordination of this event um and um
also wanted to acknowledge my
collaborators it's a very
interdisciplinary collaborative project
um and that's very much uh determines
the nature of my work um students and
undergraduate students are huge parts of
of the research um as are the farming
communities that I work with um and then
of course um the National Science
Foundation for making the work possible
thank
you a change in the taste of tea over
the past like 15 years in green tea and
for the better and I'm curi well maybe
it's climate change but I um I'm curious
um does it come from different places
what's available to us here now
come from and does it come
from um less tasty
places so more and more for the United
States tea has started to come from um
South America like Argentina as well as
in Africa so a lot more tea is being um
sort of redirected from Asia to new tea
producing areas um so that's could be
one reason um is just like the change in
Geographic um
location could be one factor
and I guess also from where um companies
are sourcing um the quality of the tea
they're
sourcing yes the um I a study somewhere
where the rates of uh uh cancer of the
esophagus was was very high in in China
and it was partly related to the teeth
that they were creeping and and if I'm
correct the way they prepared is they
use extremely hot water is that is that
right so it really depends on the
specific type of tea but a lot of times
when people are on the goow they'll just
grab really hot water and put tea leaves
into like a thermos um and if people are
sort of drinking tea at home it's
usually not like that so there is a lot
of a lot of population that's sort of
drinks tea where the water is really hot
yeah
because basically the conclusions were
there was because they drank the tea so
hot plus of course the cat kins
themselves which can be quite damaging
so I'm just wondering whether you did
see any kind of high ratees of cancer uh
among this tea drinkers for example the
I guess I would say
inverse um in the communities that I
work with they they really don't have a
prevalence of cancer um yeah and and
it's not really something that's come up
in my research I'm not actually very
familiar with that specific study but
overall I would say the meta analysis
and reviews that have been done on
health benefits of tea um usually have
shown that it's been beneficial for
various Health outcomes obviously
depends on the type of cancer um so I'm
not actually familiar with that
study y whatever you call milk is
actually very beneficial in the fact
that it that's that's why the bricks you
know when they add added milk they had
less rates of cancer of the Esopus and
it was apparently related to the fact it
was precipitated some of the kakin and
they were not as as tox toxic so I'm
just wondering whether yeah so that's
interesting because a lot mostly the
cakin are linked to the health benefits
of the te so I would have to like that
yeah um while your data shows that there
are changes in precipitation patterns
during the monsoon season monsoons have
always happened so I would assume that
the quality and therefore the price of
tea harvested during or after the
monsoon has traditionally dropped for
Farmers yeah so I think it's always
there's always been sort of a variation
and it sort of now seems that the
variation is becoming larger with more
variation in climate event so it is
something that's always happened um but
it seems like it's becoming a little bit
more very
involved yeah
you showed a huge variation in price
between the plantation te and the Agro
Forest almost 10
fold what is driving this very high
price for the Agro forestry te and do
you see this difference when you do your
GC Mass sple absolutely so about more
than 99% of the tea produced in the
world is in Terrace Plantation so it's
less than 1% so one is just Supply it's
very low Supply there's very little AG
Forest te it's a system that's really
been replaced in the last 50 years um
and so the supply is really low and you
can't just create an AG Forest overnight
so even though monocultural plantations
par far might see oh that's really
attractive you can't suddenly have all
these in your system so what what are
the purchases valueing
what are the purchases valuing what what
makes a person 10 times more I know it's
scarcity but okay most people won't do
that just CU it's scarce there's
something there must be appreciated
right so I had just briefly showed sort
of the the difference in the figh
chemicals so these are just the patens
that are attributed to the flavor
compounds um and so um the flavor is a
lot more intense from AG Forest um and
you can I can definitely perceive it one
of the indicators of really high quality
tea if you don't have a gcgc or hlc um
in your kitchen is um The Taste lingers
a lot more when you have a tea from an
ior Forest it's called gone um and a
really high quality tea might have that
honey like taste back in your throat for
more than an hour um and so you can sort
of you know it resonates for a while um
and so that was one and then the second
one is around 2002 2003 and as you can
see the price of um Agro Forest T also
hasn't always been the same it's really
increased since 200 um two over here so
prices have really been increasing um
and in that period between 2002 and 2003
um there were a lot of reports in Taiwan
and Hong Kong of um Health negative
health effects uh from drinking tea
physiological respon
um and they were attribute to pesticides
and herbicides um in tea plantations so
it was really during that period that
people began to sort out organic tea um
and the U Agro Forest have absolutely no
chemical input and so um it was really
you can it tastes a lot better and then
people felt safer um and then te you
could you know there's High pesticides
it makes your throat sort of feel dry
instead of w
High what is the TCC
value for white tea versus the let's
sayong the other the value so really so
I had done um a study looking at there's
a lot of variation on tea so like not
all white te te's are the same not all
green tees are the same not all oolong
are the same within let's say just one
type of white tea like Silver Needle
depending on the manufacturer and how
long it's been for there's significant
variation um so a lot of the Main cins
and antioxidant compounds and tea
degrade after 6 months so those of you
who have a closet of tea that you've
been storing remember fresh is best um
unless it's poor tea which actually
supposed to get better with age what's
the best way to
store right so it's sort of the
traditional things for uh preserving
phoch chemicals which is sort of a cool
temperature um removing as much of the
air so kind this nice sealed um
container if you have a bag I usually
sort of like remove as much of the air
in the bag as possible if it's in a
really big container it's only a little
bit of tea put it in a smaller sort of
airtight container and then keep it out
of the dark keep it out of the
light
than this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu