this is a production of Cornell
University all right so thanks Peter for
that great introduction my name is Ted
kotch uh and for the past year or so
Peter and I have been working on trying
to understand the land use implications
of solar New York solar in New York
State uh what it's looked like up to
this point and even try to extend some
modeling into the future to see uh how
this uh new demand for renewable energy
is going to shape our
landscape uh so when we embarked on this
analysis we had a few simple questions
that you'll soon see were a little bit
more complex to get to the bottom of
than we initially expected um but our
overall goals were to identify where
solar is being developed uh across New
York State uh analyze the trends in
what's happening in terms of land use
for these sites so what were they before
they became solar farms uh and then
looking for into the future try to
quantify how much solar we're actually
going to need uh all the way across the
state in order to meet certain renewable
energy goals that are continuously
evolving and then you know if we get
good results from that what will the
land use implications be of that
quantity of solar so the overarching
context of this is the clcpa uh this is
a ambitious piece of climate legislation
put forth by New York State and uh it
has a slew of goals but the ones that
we're looking at are its goal to become
entirely uh carbon neutral or uh
decarbonized energy grid by 2040 so in
other words uh not producing electricity
through fossil fuel combustion um it
also mandates the decarbonization of
many key sectors that are currently
powered by fossil fuel so that's uh
transportation and space heating mainly
and then also uh it has the ultimate
goal of getting to complete carbon
neutrality by 2050 and so that means
that uh even if we are generating some
carbon emissions those emissions are
being captured within the state by our
forests and
soils uh so along with this sweeping
piece of climate legislation uh they
also put out quite a bit of analysis
that they um commissioned uh and this
graph here shows the uh expected energy
generation and the sources of that
generation from now until that future
Target of 2050 so each of these uh
colored bars represents an energy source
and the two key takeaways to take from
this are that a we are going to be
consuming vastly more electricity in the
future than we are currently uh so that
means that not only do we have to
replace these fossil fuel energy sources
we also have to add additional capacity
to accommodate things that are coming
online such as uh electric cars uh
electric space heating all these things
that currently take uh carbon emitting
fossil fuels that are ultimately going
to be powered by renewable
electricity and the second thing is
this uh large orange section in the
middle of each bar that's starting out
pretty small and getting very large by
2050 that represents solar so not only
is solar going to be doing a lot of
heavy lifting it is going to be the
dominant source of energy uh in in the
future uh so wind is pretty substantial
but um solar will be at least that's the
anticipation of New York State the
dominant source of
energy so before I get into our analysis
I just want to cover some jargon so that
we all know what I'm talking about um
first off capacity this is just kind of
the sticker value that people put on a
power generation Source in this case
solar uh this means uh the maximum
output of a solar site under ideal
conditions uh and this does not take
into account Regional or weather
anomalies um such as clouds or nighttime
or dust or Seasons uh this is just kind
of a blanket statement that can be
applied to a solar system in Arizona and
the same size system in New York uh if
we want to start to understand a little
bit about how a system is actually
performing uh we want to use capacity
factor and that just kind of
incorporates Real World um performances
of the site
uh finally uh I'll be talking about two
main Solar Technologies today single AIS
tracking uh these are sites that have
mechanical linkages and Motors that
allow them to follow the sun on one axis
so either east to west uh following it
throughout the day or uh north to south
but technically up and down um to follow
the sun um as it moves higher and lower
in the sky and finally fixed axes these
are sites that just don't move at all uh
they're at a single angle and they'll
remain
thatting so I don't expect you to read
every uh node in our analysis flowchart
but broadly um our analysis consisted of
synthesizing existing data creating a
few new data sets to fill in uh holes
where there was uh uncertainty in the
existing data modeling out um future
scenarios and um evaluating what those
could look like under different
conditions okay
so when trying to understand any sort of
system starting with the most easily
accessible data is a generally a good
start step um and in this case uh New
York state has a great treasure TR of
data that's publicly available where
they track uh most commercial siiz solar
sites uh with data including their
capacity um their output and performance
uh and their approximate location so
just by taking all this compiling it
together and setting a trend over time
we are able to see uh how solar has been
growing and what specific Trends are
starting to form so this graph here on
the right on the horizontal axis we have
years and on the vertical axis we have
um capacity in megawatts um so we can
see uh oh sorry the dotted lines
represent sites that are currently
incomplete and the um solid lines
represent sites that are done and are
not performing um red represents uh
fixed access sites and blue represents
single aess just in case you can't see
the Legend um so in the beginning uh
around 2016 when solar was first
starting to take off there's almost zero
single axis track sites um and then now
we can see in the developing sites that
those sit uh those single AIS track
technology is rapidly taking off and
even looks like it might start to out
perform fixed access sites uh in the
near future we can also see various
details on how long it takes to develop
sites um and what the rate of capacity
growth
is but as I said in the beginning our
main goal is to understand land use
implications of this of solar and we
can't get to the bottom of that with an
approximate Point location on a map so
we took it a little bit further and we
um found these sites in aerial imagery
and we traced their uh fence lines
manually to create a polygon data set of
about 150 sites that were randomly
selected um a key uh piece of our
analysis is that we're looking at the
fenced area of these sites so when you
look at a solar site uh the array which
is these uh vertical black lines here
surrounded by the blue boundary that's
going to be the most impactful part of
the site uh you know obviously there's
going to be a lot more shade underneath
that there might be some compaction from
the construction of the site um there's
certainly going to be dry and wet areas
because they're blocking rain and
concentrating it in specific locations
um but if you're a farmer if you're a
land developer you're going to look at a
site and say all right the only uh I'm
not going to be able to access the
inside of that fence the way I usually
would so for our intents and purposes
that fence line is the maximum area that
is going to be taken out of commission
for regular use by a solar site and this
is to my knowledge the first study that
actually looked at this specific
area we were also curious about uh
larger sites so these are sites that are
over 25 megawatts in capacity um I think
the nearest one that's kind of in this
scale is going in the Yellow Barn
project a few of you might be familiar
with that locally um and these are sites
that are hundreds if not thousands of
Acres I think mainly in the hundreds but
they they're very large so since none of
these sites have been completed at this
point uh we had to rely on site planning
documents so we Geor referenced those
blew blew them up to scale and then Trac
them as if it was a site on aerial
imagery and from this we were able to
understand a key parameter of solar
sites and that is power density so what
is power density that is a of how much
energy or how much power they are
producing for a given area and that's
important not just for developers who
are trying to get the most output they
can from the smallest area possible
because you have to pay rent on land um
but that's also important for those of
us who use land for things that aren't
solar Farms so um people who are
studying habitat um people who are
farming you know there's a lot of
reasons you want to get as much area uh
as much energy out of a small area and
so that is a trend that we've generally
been seeing uh more panels on smaller
Footprints uh and then digging into that
relationship with site type we're able
to see that surprisingly these larger
sites these 25 megawatt overs sites uh
they are performing the poorest um in
other words they are not able to produce
as much energy uh per given area uh and
then single AIS track sites somewhat
less surprisingly are also not quite as
good as fix ACC sites because they have
to be spread out a little bit more to
allow tilting to not shade the panels in
front or behind
them uh so this this plot shows power
density in megawatts per hectare um and
the three Technologies are on the
horizontal
axis uh so we had 150 sites we had their
fence boundaries that would have been
enough to start looking at what types of
land were underneath these sites uh but
really we wanted to get the most
comprehensive picture of where solar is
going in New York state as possible and
so to do that instead of meticulously
manually digitizing every site I could
find we got a computer to do it um we
took that 150 polygon data set and uh
aerial imagery from the USDA trained a
computer model to detect sites from that
imagery and then ran it on all of the
imagery in New York state for
2022 and the results of that are we
found about
509 sites um which occupy about 3,700
hectares of land and based on our power
density estimates we predict that they
were outputting at that point about 2300
megawatts of
power uh and as far as we know this is
the most comprehensive data set of where
solar is in New York there are several
different state and federal data sets as
well um but we found a lot of them are
uh pretty incomplete and only find about
half of the
sites so with this data set that we hope
is as comprehensive as possible we were
able to uh perform some land cover
analysis in other words looking at what
the land was before it became a solar
site and to do this we overlaid it
overlaid our polygons with uh a crop a
data set called the crop data layer
which is produced by the USDA and it
does a good job of trying to estimate
what each uh square foot or in this case
30 square meter 30 meter on a side cell
of area in New York state was whether
that's forest or pasture or grassland or
corn um and as you can see uh in this
golden bar here annual row crops were
the dominant previous land cover of all
these solar sites uh in fact that about
of annual R crop land was occupied by
these sites that we found uh that's
followed by hay pasture unfortunately
Forest uh and then some alphaalpha so
more high intensity um forage
crops it became more uh apparent to us
that there are some inaccuracies in the
crop data layer um unsurprisingly it's
difficult to tell what type of crop is
in any given area just from satellite
imagery uh and so we particularly found
that there's a lot of inaccuracy in this
uh pasture category and looking a little
bit into the literature we found a
report um that checked the discrepancies
between the census of a data that New
York and the federal government collects
every five years and this crop data
layer uh data set and they found that
there's approximately 650,000 hectares
of land in New York state that is
classified as active agricultural land
by the CDL but is actually what we're
calling former agricultural land um and
this is land that uh is probably
something you're all familiar with just
grassy Fields maybe somebody mows them
once or twice a year to keep them from
turning into forests But ultimately uh
they are not being used for commercial
agriculture which is our main focus and
what we're looking
at and so by by taking the ratios that
the study found uh on a crop by crop
basis figuring out that about 30% of
land uh considered pasture by the CDL is
actually former agricultural land we're
able to get to this uh 16% or 607
hectare figure uh long story short
essentially a lot of the land that we
are finding out or appears to be uh
active agricultural land May in fact
just be Gra fields and that kind of
makes sense if you're thinking about it
um farmers who have active agricultural
land that they're tilling or grazing or
uh paying are more likely to try to get
people to develop solar on the less
productive land that they're not
actually
using so uh there's a more to a given
area than just uh what it's being used
for so we also wanted to see uh what
types of uh soils are being um covered
by solar uh because you know just
because a piece of land isn't being used
for agricultural uses today uh doesn't
mean it couldn't be tomorrow and so a
good indicator of whether land could
potentially be used for agriculture is
its soil quality uh and for this we used
a data set um called the mineral soil
groups and this is uh a soil ranking
system developed by New York State
primarily for tax reasons um however
it's useful in the case of solar because
um there
are uh restrictions on what types of
high quality soils can be used for solar
sites and so for example if you're a
developer you're coming into a site and
you want to put a solar facility there
if it's over 50% highquality
agriculturally suitable soil there are
going to be penalties that you have to
pay for converting that out of
agricultural
production uh we found that uh the
dominant soil group that is being
covered by solar is uh mineral solar
group five which is right in the middle
of the scale from 1 to 10 with one being
the best and uh 10 being the worst but
there is about 44% of all land under
solar that is in this highquality
mineral soil groups one through four uh
range um and so that's not just an
indicator that we're losing a lot of
good soil to these solar sites but also
that these incentives that are in place
to try to dissuade developers from using
uh highquality soils they're not quite
working as well as we would hope they
would
be um so trying to get a little bit
Inside the Mind of the developers uh
because this is going to be what
ultimately informs where we expect solar
to go uh is the choices of developers we
started looking at uh the distance to
transmission lines it can be to a
million dollars a mile to run a grid
interconnect from a solar site to a
transmission line and so obviously
that's a lot of incentive for solar to
be built very close to those power lines
and we wanted to take a closer look and
we found that that is indeed the case um
just about every site uh was within uh
like five kilometers of a solar site but
there are a few um that ventured a
little bit further up to like 15
kilometers um so this will come back
later on in the presentation but
distance to transmission lines is an
incredibly strong predictor of where
solar is ultimately likely to
go we also took a look at slope of these
sites we found that uh in terms of uh
how steep developers are willing to
build on they're a little bit more
flexible than some of these other uh
site
characteristics so before I jump into
the sort of future part of this analysis
are there any questions so far I know
I'm unloading a lot of information on
everybody Lou I was just curious like if
you have a line this means that you can
hope to that line right there or there
has to be some sort of kind of a
conversion plant yeah so um if there is
capacity uh and if they the solar site
is large enough they will uh create a
substation to boost the voltage up to
what it's necessary for the
interconnection
uh an important point though is also we
did not model if these transmission
lines have capacity for solar so you
know sometimes they are in fact full
especially if they're these transmission
lines funneling hydroelectricity from
Canada down state um but yeah typically
uh the best location is next to a
substation because that's what's going
to get the power up to the necessary
voltages um but it seems like if the
site can just be really close to a
transmission line the developers will
build the infrastructure
needed oh yeah Hannah have some
interesting information at the beginning
that talked about how the single access
track was like took longer to finish and
was also less um efficient are there any
cases that you would want to use those
or like why have people been building
yeah so U maybe I didn't do the best job
of explaining the differences in power
and energy Dynamics so uh single AIS
track sites because they have to be
spread out a little bit more the rows of
panels themselves in order to avoid
shading uh they typically have what's a
lower power density um and so this means
that you know if you took the sticker
rating of every single panel in the site
and added it up divided it by the Acres
that would be lower however because
they're tilting to follow the sun they
actually do capture more energy
throughout the day than a fixed access
site and so when you spread that out
over a year their yearly energy output
is marginally greater than a fixed axis
say would
be uh any other questions oh
yeah so about the printed power density
also you mentioned that is for example
the solar panel orientation east and
west or sometimes the North and South in
that in that case the UN mention is the
same as of our density or beneficial to
tracking or the fixed case is the same
if could we just add the more parameters
of our solar panel the orientation is
the same are you asking if uh single AIS
sites that go uh east to west in their
tracking that sort of orientation comes
to the North and the South in that case
the what you mentioned before is the
same situation or different uh we didn't
look at within single AIS tracking sites
if the power production is the same in
the east west orientation as the North
South orientation um I think just about
every site that we looked at does track
um you know they run north to south and
they track east to west um so that's not
information I could speak
on
like yeah
yeah okay oh uh another question um I
was wondering could you go back real
quick to the the density side of the
power density uh sorry it's the remote's
a little
slow bad
question you mentioned that right the
yeah the the the fixed the fixed axis
yeah having now are these significantly
different these like sat and that that
oh yes yeah they are they are okay so I
just don't understand yeah the I guess
the the magnitude of a power density or
yeah so the axis is uh scaled pretty
narrowly so um um they are
not substantially different but they are
significantly different got um so yeah
the single axis uh sorry the large sites
they're like quite a bit poorer
performing than the other two groups and
then the single axis and the fix AIS
small sites
are closer yes
Peter I mean there's a lot of overlap
between the two there that's another
something remaining to be explored is is
there room to exploit
that variation can you push them higher
within that range what's controlling
that we don't know yeah so there is a
lot of variation in all these data sets
and that we think is primarily driven by
uh how developers build their fences I
think that's you know a pretty big
takeaway is that you can save a lot of
land just by maximizing your uh area
your panel area to fence area but
unfortunately you know we live in New
York it's a patchwork landscape people
are dealing with HED RS and outcroppings
and you know really the shape is not
going to be a perfect rectangle every
time so um but when you say like large
sites use less land the efficiency is is
primarily I guess coming from the
orientation of the panels like
maximizing area of land in and that like
that's why their power density is is
less than someone who has smaller land
so we don't actually have the ability to
you know get into how they're lower uh
in terms of power density uh you know
power density is ultimately a factor of
um the site Arrangement as well as the
panel efficiency so it could be that you
know when they are planning these sites
the developers speced out like really
poor performing panels and that's
skewing the data um so ultimately you
know since these sites don't exactly
don't actually exist yet you know we're
least confident in these results um and
you know that's that's probably the main
driver
thank uh you had a question too um yeah
how do the mineral soil groups map onto
the Sergo classification stuff is one
through four like Alpha sols and that's
you know I I did dig a little bit into
that um a while ago but uh mainly it's
just like a big chart and they take
every single soil group and map it to a
specific
um mineral soil group category yeah I
can say a little so this this was
developed uh in SCS by agronomist and it
it's based on yield potential for Maze
that's the short answer so multiple soil
types and and every soil type is ranked
but the basis is yield potential for
Maze I believe it's kind of like similar
to a New York state specific version of
the
nccpi except one being
better okay so
uh in this first half of the analysis we
found uh pretty good correlations
between uh land covariates and existing
solar sites and so we wanted to see if
we could take that and extrapolate into
the future um and in order to do that we
needed to answer a few questions such as
how much solar are we actually going to
need um how much area that would take up
what the land use trends that we're
currently seeing would look like if
they're allowed to continue and since
we're modelers and we're making up
scenarios anyway we deci decided well
let's get a little bit more imaginative
and see what happens if we start to
tweak some parameters of that and change
what the future outcome could look like
just to uh see the difference so getting
to that first question how much solar
are we actually going to need um the
state of New York with their handy
analysis that accompanied the clcpa they
gave us some uh benchmarks of what they
expect we will need uh so again this
graph is showing uh annual generation in
gwatt hours on the vertical axis and
year on the horizontal and they're
estimating that uh we will need about 95
terawatt hours per year of energy to be
generated from these utility scale solar
sites and they also estimate that that's
going to come from about 65 GW of solar
capacity so again there's that
difference between energy and capacity
um with you know terawatt hours being a
quantity of energy and 60 gaw uh or 65
gaws being uh
capacity uh unfortunately we found that
based on real world performance of solar
sites in New York state that it is going
to take substantially more solar
capacity to get to that goal of uh 955
tatt hours uh we found that it's going
to be around
86 uh gws of um single access tra sites
or um 96 gaw of uh fixed access
sites and um you know just to kind of
give you a breakdown of the different
capacity factors used in these models uh
the clcpa used a value of 22% which is a
pretty good day in New Mexico uh nerta
which is the New York State uh research
energy research and development
Authority they use uh in their models
values of 16% for ACC tracked and around
133% for fixed access sites uh this is a
lot closer to what we found when we dug
into the actual hour by hour production
values of solar sites in New York state
so we uh downloaded all that raw data
for about 340 sites uh we separated it
into single and fixed axis and we uh
looked at what those actual uh Power
outputs were year-over-year in relation
to what their capacity is and found
uh single AIS sites have a capacity
factor of around
13.2 and uh fixed axis are closer to 12
um so unfortunately quite a bit lower
than the optimistic values used um by
the
clcpa uh so uh these power factor or
sorry capacity Factor values were able
to give us this um range of total
capacities needed and as we've gone over
we have power densities so if you take
the capacity uh and the power density
you should be able to get an area but we
wanted to go a little bit further and
see if there are Trends over time that
we can tease out and apply because you
know the 2050 is still a good ways in
the future there's a lot of time for
technology to evolve uh and improve and
so we don't think it's realistic to just
assume that power density is going to be
the same uh so we want to see if there
are trends that we can fit to
demonstrate that it is improving um and
so this is a scatter plot of uh Power
densities of different sites based on uh
when they're built and again uh blue is
representing single AIS tra red is
representing fixed
axis and we're seeing that there is a
very slight uh positive trend um it's
not a very strong Trend uh doesn't have
a ton of great confidence but we can use
that um to give us a little bit of a
better understanding of what sites could
look like in the future and so if we
vary that Trend over time and we also
vary the starting point of what the
power density is now because there's
also a substantial amount of variation
in that data and simulate that thousands
and thousands of times uh we can do
something called a Monte Carlo analysis
uh and so this graph here uh represents
the probability of uh different areas of
solar in the future where the horizontal
axis
is uh total land converted to solar and
the vertical axis is uh the probability
density or how many of those simulations
ended up at a specific inclusion uh and
so this represents uh a stochastic range
of V values um with uh you know single
AIS track sites having the uh lowest
most probable area value and uh fixed
access sites having the highest so for
example fixed sites are most probable to
occupy about 100,000 hectares of land in
the future uh and that is you know a
substantial quantity of land um large
sites uh they have a bit of a wider
distribution of spread but you know
they're they're R around 990,000
hectares of land uh and the reason you
know uh if you saw in the first graph
that large sites are performing poorly
um and now all of a sudden they're doing
better than fixed axis uh that's because
the uh technology
in most large sites is single AIS tract
and that is improving faster than the
fixed axis in terms of power density
over
time um so we could have just simulated
a massive square of solar uh popped in
the middle of New York state t Ted up
all the area underneath it and called it
today but we wanted to figure out if we
could get a little bit more specific
about where these sites are going to go
um so we uh did something called
geospatial analysis where we took
covariates that we knew played some role
in site development and we took training
data which was all the sites that our AI
model found and we created a probability
raster of where solar would exist in New
York State uh we used something called a
maximum entropy model or Max ENT model
uh this is very similar to a random
forest model if you're familiar with
those except it doesn't require uh
positive or sorry negative training data
we can confidently say there is a solar
sight here but we can't say there's
definitely never going to be a solar
sight here so in order to get over that
little hiccup we use this particular
model we ended up with a probability
raster for the entire state of New York
where uh 100 represents Prime Solar
Development Area uh and zero represents
almost no chance of uh solar site being
developed and in this figure here um we
can see existing sites are sitting
comfortably in the green area say they
should uh we conducted the same uh land
land cover analysis uh as we did for the
existing sites on these polygons once we
allocated uh enough of that optimal land
for meeting that total area requirement
that we calculated with the Monte Carlo
analysis and we found that the
distribution of land cover types looks
pretty similar um you know in the
present we're looking at a lot of annual
rad crops hey in pasture that doesn't
really change much for the future um
so we we wanted to press the scales a
little bit see if we could um change the
future scenario to look a little bit
more um AG responsible and so we created
a scenario well we created many
scenarios but the one I'm going to talk
about is where we took mineral soil
groups 1 through four and annual row
crop land according to the CDL the crop
data layer and decreased their scores on
that probability surface rter and then
ran that same simulation again and we
were able to see that um pasture land
becomes much more um dominant of that
land cover mix if you take away high
quality soils actively till agricultural
land used for annual crops um but still
keep in all those covariates of distance
of transmission lines low slopes um Etc
you know you can start to see that uh
there is still uh decent land
available uh so these are our key
findings um we're running a little low
on time so
uh I will not bore you with reading all
of them but essentially we were able to
locate all existing sites across New
York State begin to understand what
their former land use characteristics
were and ultimately try to see if there
is a way that we could take those sites
learn from them and project out into the
future what the state is going to look
like when there are you know uh 100,000
or 100 gwatt hours of solar um across
the
landscape sorry 100
gws uh we also found that these sites
are using substantial agricultural land
um and that to meet these State energy
targets we are going to need a lot more
agricultural land to be converted to
solar unless restrictions are
imposed uh we also have further
questions that we hope to find out the
answers to at some point in the future
uh what land is consumed outside of
solar sites you know there's land that's
um uh
sorry it's called
um stranded land you know land between a
forest and a solar fence that's not
going to be available for farming um
there's also a lot of uncertainty in how
much solar energy we'll need because
we'll need a lot of energy in the winter
when solar panels are not producing a
lot um and we also are curious to see if
agricultural intensification can kind of
work from the other side to reduce some
of that potential food energy
competition uh this project would not
have been possible without Peter's uh
continual help and support uh and
strategy planning and um kind of keeping
me on track as well as a lot of U
manuscript editing Dave Miller also
helped with editing manuscripts and was
uh helpful in kind of figuring out the
more nuanced issues with my analysis and
then also Jennifer Whitman provided
feedback and manuscript
editing uh any
questions go
just in doing like a spatial analysis of
how much land is available in certain
regions like I've heard a lot of people
from Eastern New York to Albany region
very Progressive people be really
worried because their small band Alpha
Sals is being eaten up by
solar which is different than Western
York there's a lot more of that yeah
York like fton Mony County small amount
yeah we weren't able to incorporate kind
of like uh attitude towards solar into
the analysis I mean I can say
anecdotally that the Albany area is
developing very rapidly in terms of
solar growth and that's I think driven
primarily by access to both the north
south running transmission lines and
kind of the East West transmission lines
that fall I90 um so you know Regional
analysis of like what land is available
both for solar and what land is valuable
for agriculture is you know certainly
important um but it's not something that
we specifically looked at oh yeah
have you considered doing an analysis
that looks at where the abandoned
agricultural land is and tries
to a potential additional transmission
line to open up
access that abandoned land so that all
that that pressure isn't right there on
nice oil in the lake plane yeah so I
mean we're already experiencing gri
congestion it seems like we're going to
have to build a lot more transmission
lines if we're going to reach these
goals uh so you know optimizing where
those run in order to you know maximize
solar production while minimizing
agricultural land loss is a really good
idea and somebody should do that um but
you know it's it's not the kind of
expertise I have in terms of you know
land permitting or you know nism and all
the things that go into deciding where a
transmission line goes we did look a
little bit at uh you know where planned
lines are being run or at least uh are
planned to run and we found that you
know either running like down the bottom
of the Hudson River or on existing
corridors of existing transmission lines
there's not a huge desire to you know
Branch out into new territory and run
completely new routes um Peter yeah I'll
just chime in on that and you know we're
intensely interested in this former
Agland and have been for a long time
because it's an unusual resource most
places don't have it um unfortunately we
have no geospatial data about where
these are so we've done calculations for
a long time by difference so the
cropland data layer says there's this
much Agland the statistical surveys say
there's a smaller amount of Agland so we
think most of that difference is former
Agland but again we don't know where it
is you know geospatially so that's a
that's a big missing data set for all
kinds of reasons thank you uh so there's
a question on Zoom as well um I'm
wondering what you think of the argument
that instead of taking up valuable AG
land with solar solar is protecting
Farmland from Housing Development that
would make it permanently non-ag I've
heard
um yeah so again that's kind of a an
area that we didn't delve too deeply
into you know certainly a solar has a
long lifespan uh during which uh there's
little or at least substantially reduced
capacity for agriculture whereas a
Housing Development you know there's
really no uh crops that can be produced
in perpetuity you know other than lawn
um so you know I guess that's the
question of are we really going to
remove these solar sites in the future
um you know we're going to continue to
need energy indefinitely so I don't know
necessarily if solar is a less permanent
um land use although I will say that it
is certainly has the potential to be
less impactful you know it can be uh uh
housing soil enriching forages or it can
be grassland bird habitat uh I think it
does have more ecological value than
Housing Development but I wouldn't say
necessarily that it can be considered
less permanent before that
answer I have a couple question one the
first one is the more the macro scale is
there any special Trend where you would
have more solar plants closer to cities
or as soon as you reach the GR then
doesn't matter where you are yeah so um
the two things we looked into with that
are uh existing sites are less prevalent
I mean there are a fair number on Long
Island um but they are just less
prevalent as you get further south just
because the land value goes up um and
it's you know uh $ thousand dollar an
acre and rent doesn't really entices
many people um and then also a lot of
our future analysis was informed by grid
interconnection capacity so the New York
state electrical grid is divided up into
these zones and those zones have a
rating of how much electricity they can
transmit from one zone to another and so
essentially because the grid is a giant
funnel taking electricity down to New
York City uh the further south you get
the less additional capacity there is to
go from Zone to Zone um so that kind of
restricted the amount of solar that we
expect to be in the in the southern
around
would most likely be away from those b c
yeah
yeah kind surprised to see going from
forest to solar like how far back go
Forest would they cut the forest and put
right away yeah uh I mean you know
anecdotally I've seen that in person
also it seems like that's a pretty
common transition just from the data um
I have a feeling it's not the most
desirable scenario just because that's
you know expensive unfortunately I don't
think they're looking at it at an
altruistic level um but yeah that that
does seem to happen a fair
amount there's also a question in the um
Zoom about uh Brown fields and rooftop
solar so we did not look at rooftop
solar specifically there is about half
of all solar capacity at the time that
we started this analysis was rooftop um
so that's a substantial amount uh and
then you know also we've not only seen
um solar being developed on a lot of
brown Fields uh it's also primarily
selected by our future prediction models
um so yeah I guess that is certainly an
option although it seems to be uh
rapidly filling up all right I think
unless there are any other questions
I'll let you guys go
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu