this is a production of Cornell
University thanks we're going to lower
the lights because some of the slides I
think will show up better um thank you
Claus um and I'd like to thank Claus for
inviting me to talk with you today this
is my very first plant biology seminar
and I'm happy to have the opportunity to
tell you about some of our work now in
the title I include the word art you
know Art and Science because I I found
over the years that working in plant
tissue culture and transformation
there's definitely an art to it there is
a feel for with experience for what
should be done next and there's also a
lot of creativity involved but you know
as I think about it I think the same is
true for other areas of research as well
okay so these are some points that I'm
going to cover during uh during my
presentation I'll give you some
background on tissue culture and plant
transformation I thought giving you some
of the basics would be uh you know
really good before I launched into how
we develop the methods and giving you
examples of the projects Lisa Earl um as
class mentioned I did my graduate work
in her lab and before her retirement she
taught an entire class on tissue culture
and transformation so I have just a few
slides um to you know kind of put you on
that level so you understand why we do
what we do I'll use these current uh
projects as examples of how we develop
those methods um grape is the most
recent one in our lab we've been working
with Anor aall in at Cornell on esus and
um also as classus mentioned we're
working with sataria viridus which is
which is a C4 photosynthesis grass that
we're developing as a model species and
then I'll end by telling you some of the
next steps for those
projects so the way I see it there are
four components to development of these
methods um there's the plant tissue
culture and plant regeneration even
before we go into transformation we have
to have an efficient method for plant
regeneration and these are some examples
so this is potato so for potato we start
with plants that are growing in tissue
culture in test tubes which is referred
to as inv vitro and we put those stem
pieces on a medium that induces this
growth called Callis which is an
unorganized mass of cells somewhat
analogous to a tumor and then we tweak
that Medium to give the cells the signal
to produce plants and these little
potato plants are then removed from the
callus and transferred to a rooting
medium this is tomato um tomato we start
with Calon pieces that from seedlings
that are grown in culture and these are
all examples of plant regeneration after
transformation so you'll see that not
every piece of plant material is
regenerating choots and then for sateria
we start with callus that is induced
from mature seeds and I'm going to tell
you about that in more detail later and
this is what we use for the
transformation and again that callus is
put onto regeneration medium to um
induce these plants to grow once we have
you know a good system worked out for
the plant tissue culture then we move
into the gene transfer methods a
critical part of this and can sometimes
be a stumbling block is in the rooting
and acclimation to Greenhouse conditions
we of course work all this out before we
even try Gene transfer methods and
patients lots of patients um it takes a
long time to go from start to finish and
as you'll see when I uh talk about grape
we're sometimes working with very small
plant material that we have to use a
dissecting scope in order to do the
work so um when we start with
working out a new method we'll first go
to the literature to see if anything has
been reported for that particular plant
species if we don't find anything then
we look to see what is the most you know
the most closely related relative see if
there's anything reported for that if we
don't find anything which happens
sometimes we then go based on experience
and also a lot of trial and error to
find out the best combination to use so
for plant material we have a number of
choices um but for monocot what works
best are immature inflorescences mature
seeds and immature embryos for diecuts
you can pretty much try um any one of
these types of plant material uh one
part where we do spend quite a bit of
time also is working out methods to
clean up that material now that culture
medium I showed you in the slides
contains sugar because they need a
carbon Source since they're growing in
laboratory conditions and if you don't
clean up that material there a lot of
you the material will be overgrown by
bacteria and fungi and it will kill the
material so we use bleach um ethanol
sometimes antifungal antibacterial
compounds but there's really a fine line
sometimes between finding the right
method that will clean up the
contaminants yet not kill the plant
material um some of these systems are
easier than others but U for something
like um for the esus we spent a lot of
time trying to find the best method for
cleaning up the
material for culture medium components
um not every medium contains all these
components it's just an example of what
you can include in the med medium um the
major part of the U medium it are salt
formulations and those salts are like
nitrogen phosphorus potassium whatever
is needed to support plant growth and
culture there are a number of standard
salt formulations that we use one common
one is called migi and skoo or Ms but
there are even modified versions of Ms
so you can find um you can purchase an
MS medium that doesn't contain any
ammonium nitrate because some plant
species are sensitive to the ammonium
nit trate so there you know there are a
lot of parts to those salts that can
also affect the plant material one of
the most critical parts of the medium
are these plant growth regulators and
there are two um categories there are
oxin and cyto canines and these are an
example of some oxin and these are some
cyto so when we're working with these
methods it's not only the choice of an
oxin or cyto that can make a difference
it's the combination it's the
concentration it's the ratios sometimes
we'll start out in an oxin but then move
to a cyto so it really depends on the
plant species that we're working with
for a carbohydrate Source sucrose is the
most common but we do work with some
systems where maltose or glucose works
better jelling agents there are
different types of augers and gel and
gum and it sometimes it's really hard to
convince people that jelling agent can
really make a difference I think some
people think it's just not an important
part of the medium until we give them a
protocol and we say you have to use you
know a gel and gum to start out with
even though it's in it in its red and
then they'll contact me and they'll say
the method's not working and say all
right let's start troubleshooting and
then I find out that they substituted a
jelling agent that we didn't recommend I
like well really trust me you know the
jelling agent can make a difference um
there are also amino acids and vitamins
that are sometimes
required um activated charcoal kind of
like acts like an antioxidant when some
of the plant material will turn brown
when we cut it and put it in culture and
the activated charcoal helps absorb that
it also absorbs inhibitors that might
prevent plant uh
regeneration and um I you know I worked
at geranium when I when I was at
Sanford's and when we would cut the
pieces of geranium and put them in
culture they would just turn black so we
ended up looking at a number of
different types of antioxidants and
concentrations in order to prevent the
um the you know the phenolics from
taking down the material and there's
also coconut water now I don't see this
as as you know often now in recent
literature but in the earlier days
coconut water was used and you can still
purchase coconut water um through some
of the companies and it contains you
know a number of sugars growth
Regulators amino acids and some
undefined components that really can
make a difference in getting plant
regeneration or not getting
it now in developing a transformation
method where we spend the majority of
our time is in the plant regeneration
phase we don't start plant um
transformation until we feel that the
Regeneration part is very efficient and
what I would recommend is that at least
30 to 40% of your plant material are
regenerating shoes and that's because
when you do it an
agrobacterium infection not every cell
is
infected so if you have a system that's
regenerating a lot of shoes you have a
greater chance of recovering
transformance in the end so that's why I
would say if you have something that's
less than 30% don't even try it until
you get that percentage up so I'm just
going to all right um there are three
different meth that you can use for
transformation agrobacterium biolistics
which the gene gun and as um Claus
mentioned the gene gun was invented here
at Cornell and basically what there what
happens is there are Micron siiz
particles gold or tungsten that are
coated with DNA and blasted into the
plant cells there's also a DNA uptake
into protoplast if you have a leaf um
you treat it with enzymes that takes
away the cell wall you're left at the
protoplast and then there are methods to
um increase that DNA uptake into the
protoplast and our lab we use um
agrobacterium for all of our work we
find that it works perfectly fine um
it's a soilborne bacterium about 30
years ago a group of scientists um
decided that since agrobacterium is
engineering plants in nature it
transfers genes into plant cells to
produce the metabolites that it needs to
growth you know can they take that
bacterium from the soil and use it in
the lab to transfer genes of interest
and it worked and that was like the
whole start of plant biotechnology um
from there number of reports just
increased dramatically there are
different strains um that you need to
consider when you're doing the um
transformation you need to think of it
in a in a in a a plant pathogen
interaction there are antibiotics
depending on the um strain that you're
using that eventually will REM you know
eliminate that bacterium because if we
don't do that after a transformation the
agrobacterium overgrows the material and
kills it and um there's also different
phases of growth we need to look at and
concentration
so after we when we make an overnight
culture of AG bacterium we'll read the
optical density and um in general it's
about a 0 6 to 7 but for some species we
found we have to decrease that by 10
times U so we're using like 006 or 007
because it's just very sensitive to the
um
agrobacterium now vectors Um this can
really make or break a plant
transformation system um those are the
shuttles that were used in the
agrobacterium to transfer the DNA into
the cells we use um electroporation
there are different methods that you can
use to introduce that plasma DNA and
that Vector but we find that
electroporation works just fine for us
there are different selectable marker
genes and I'm going to go into more
detail on this when I talk about vectors
and those are genes that confer
resistance to antibiotic and also
herbicides and then we include those
components either an antibiotic or
herbicide in component into our medium
and there are different types and
concentrations and you have to look at
timing and you know there's a lot of
parts of this that you need to look at
for your particular plant species when
we're working at a new method we use
something called a reporter Gene we
don't jump into to just start using our
Gene of interest because sometimes genes
of interest can have a negative effect
on the Regeneration of plants it affects
the development so we start out with
these reporter genes there's one called
Gus which is beta glucuronidase and the
way this works is that if you have this
in your vector you do your
transformation the plants you recover
you can take pieces of leaves put them
into an assay solution if it turns blue
it's successful if not it's back to the
drawing board and there's also the green
fluoresence protein gfp the nice thing
about gfp is it's um as compared to Gus
when you put your material in gust it it
kills it but with gfp you can actually
monitor the progress of that
transformation by using a fluorescent
scope and we're starting to use more gfp
um construct vectors in our lab now
and then um the other part of the aggro
bacterium is the length of time with the
AG with with it um when we're doing a
transformation say we have those pieces
of potato stem pieces they're just
dipped for five minutes it used to be in
the older protocols they would leave
that material in for like half an hour
but that ends up having a negative
effect it stresses the plant material so
we find that a five minute dip is
perfectly fine and then it goes back
onto the medium for 2 to three days and
that's when the AGR bacterium attaches
to the cells and does the gene transfer
at that point most often it's in the
dark we do all of our um co-cultivation
in the dark but there are some reports
where they use light and it's also the
temperature during that period is also
important it's not surprising that
around 19 to 22 degrees Celsius works
best because again it is a soil
bacterium that's how it evolved and we
find that we've done comparisons of
temperatures and found that that range
um works the best okay so for vectors um
this is some examples of vectors and the
pambu one is a more complicated diagram
it's showing the restriction enzymes
that can be used for
cloning and then I have a more
simplified Vector down here called Panic
this was developed for switch grass or
panicum that's why they're called panic
and we've been using these panic vectors
for
sataria you can see that on this plasma
DNA there's this segment here that I'll
um discuss a little bit more in the next
slide and then on that back bone there
are also um a bacterial resistant Gene
for canamy and also this origin of
replication this origin of replication
can also be very important depending on
what plant species you're working on and
we found that to be true for
sataria this is a closer up view of a
vector and um what you see here is there
is a left and a right border and th
that's the sequence that the
agrobacterium recognizes agrobacterium
has endonuclear AES and those are the
sequences it recognizes to cut that DNA
at those points and transfer it into the
plant cells those vectors also contain
promoters I'm just using these as an
example there's all sorts of different
types of vectors that you can use this
is the NOS promoter driving the npt2
gene now the npt2 gene is a selectable
marker Gene and it confers resistance to
canamy the antibiotic so when we do our
transformation we'll put that canyin
into the medium and the reason we do
that is you know implant so say we're
doing a tomato transformation and we
have calan pieces just about every cell
in that Caledon has the potential to go
on and to make
plants and with a selectable marker Gene
only the cells that receive that npt2
Gene go on to make plants because we
have canamy in the medium if we didn't
do that we would have a lot of plants to
screen in order to find those few that
are really transformed and it can also
affect the efficiency of the system so
we do need to include um um a selectable
marker Gene and again it could be for
antibiotic resistance or herbicide
resistance this is another promoter that
is a common one called 35s you could put
your Gene of Interest here I've put Gus
there um because that's what we use for
developing methods we then electroporate
that into agrobacterium we grow an
overnight culture and we do a
transformation
experiment so these are some tools of
the trade for doing that there overnight
cultures we do the electroporation we
plate it onto the medium we use
toothpicks to transfer those colonies
into the liquid medium this is a freshly
inoculated culture it goes onto a Shaker
um overnight and then hopefully it um
you get growth and then we take this
solution centrifuge it down we get a
pellet and we wash it with a plant
tissue culture medium because the um
salts that are used for growing the
bacteria are much too concentrated can
have a negative effect on the plant
material so we wash that pellet with a
plant-based culture
medium um the next you know we as I
mentioned we'll work out the rooting and
acclamation to the greenhouse even
before we do transformation we certainly
don't want to be working out this out
with our precious transgenic lines um we
um always we prefer that we get the
rooting in culture before we transfer it
to soil we sometimes need to use a lower
salt formulation um oxin something like
tomato we don't need to use any oxin in
the rooting medium because it it Roots
readily um and also we uh there are some
systems where we use activated charcoal
because if we don't see rooting there
might be an inhibitor there that's
causing it to not root so we'll use
activated charcoal for the acclamation
to the greenhouse you know there are a
number of factors to consider not
surprising um soil type lighting you
different plant species that we work
with we have to use different types of
soil and um you'll see that these are
some sataria plants that are covered
with water bottles and the reason that
they're covered is that when we take
plants out of culture you know they're
in test tubes or they're in magenta
boxes and which are a culture vessel
that we use and um there's it's a 100%
humidity and the cuticle isn't well
developed the stomates are wide open and
if we transfer those to soil and we
don't cover them they'll wil and die so
um we had been using plastic bags in the
beginning but then someone had the idea
that you know people in the lab are
drinking water having bottled water and
Gatorade so we'd let's try those and we
cut the bottoms off the bottles and we
cover the plants after a few days we'll
simply remove the cap and then after a
few days more we'll take off the bottle
and then we wash those bottles and reuse
them so it's much better than plastic
bags because it was difficult to reuse
the plastic bags we had to cut holes in
the bags to gradually acclimate them and
then discard those bags so now we have
um a good supply of bottles um in the
lab so this is um a listing of the
plants that we have worked with and
those that are current the those listed
in the black text are those which are
current projects those in red text or
ones that were doing uh transformation
as a service so in my group I have
support from bti for two and a half um
two and a half people um to do
Transformations as a service and the way
this works is if someone is interested
say in tomato like Jim we do a lot of
work for Jim um they'll give us the
construct and we'll do the
transformations in the tomato and then
we'll you know give them the plants back
for their work and it's B it's a fee
recovery system um because we have to
repay that loan back to bti for what
they you know the money that they give
us to support this um service component
but then the other projects in the lab
are funded through different um funding
agencies and these um in Blu text are
ones that we have worked on on the past
but they're no longer active
projects so um I thought you might be
wondering like how long does the whole
process take from when I do the inection
until I can get plants back and when we
do our Transformations as a service
people are really anxious to get the
plants back and you know we do our best
to be able to you know to um give them
the plants and then they want to know
how long it takes so from the time saer
tomato that we do an infection of the
Calen pieces it takes about six weeks to
go from the infection phase to having
these little choots
regenerating then we transfer those
shoots to a rooting medium and if you're
interested in Fruit it takes about a
total time of five to six months to
recover red ripe fruit if you're
interested in just looking at the plants
for disease or insect resistance you
know it's obviously it's a much shorter
time for potato it's roughly the same
time frame um this month difference here
is because some potatoes take longer in
the greenhouse to produce tubers but
again we start with um infecting plant
potato stem pieces and then in about
eight weeks we have these little potato
plants that we can cut and root and then
we'll put them into the greenhouse and
produce tubers in pots but again if
you're just interested in the plants
it's a much a much shorter time
frame so that's it for your instruction
and plant tissue culture and
transformation um and now I'm going to
jump into the three projects to use
those as an example of how we develop
those methods so as I mentioned grape is
one of the most recent um projects that
we have in the lab and I wanted to work
on Grape since we started um the
transformation service specialist
knowing that grape is such an important
crop in New York state
and that I and you know there's work
going on in Geneva and I thought we
could really help um help those projects
along so this um started as a
collaboration with Gan Juan in Geneva
and he suggested that we work with two
model grap plants um one is called pixie
it's a dwarf Vine and these were
developed to help you know help
accelerate the great breeding programs
instead of having to go out to the field
and working with vines in the field
these lines can be grown in the
greenhouse pixie stays small it's a the
sport of Pon Noir and the reason it's
short it's because it's you know there's
a it's a mutant GI mutant and it affects
the gibberellin pathway so these plants
stay small the inner nodes are very
close um they're really dark green um
green leaves Scout is an experimental
line that was released by the USDA and
ARS in 2010 it flowers continuously in
the field in Greenhouse so you can see
how this would be an advantage for
research programs you have a continuous
supply of flowers it was developed by a
cross between ruby red and Asian an
Asian species and this is the makeup
here of the
scalp um and then genan Juan also
recommended that we start working with
Concord because it's again it's an
important one in New York state and it's
often used to make jellies and jams and
if you're interested in reading more
about um pixie and Scout there is a
publication that was put out by Cornell
that describes the background on that
plant
material so for grape there are two
possible sources based in the literature
on um for starting plant cell cultures
the one is immature infloresence and
that is what works best for wine grapes
and some others this method for the
leaves from plants in vitro does not
work um for the grapes they're used for
wine making but it's mostly seedless
grape types that work through this
method but again not all of them and
I'll show you why there are advantages
to using the leaf system as compared to
the immature INF fluorescent system so
we've been doing our work based on
reports by gray and Dey um we start by
inducing callus on the plant material
and then we look for something called
sematic embryos there are two meth two
ways where plant regeneration can happen
there's a sematic embryogenesis and an
organogenesis um I'll show you examples
of organogenesis later but for grape
it's through the sematic embryogenesis
meth um mode and when we started this we
ended up testing 14 different media um
formulations based on what we found in
the literature to find something to work
for Scout and Concord we're not doing
pixie yet but for Scout and Concord um
we had to look at different salts
different growth regulators and other
media components once we have that
callus and we have the sematic embryos
the sematic embryos or SE are
transferred to a maintenance medium and
this maintenance medium contains a high
level of sucrose um sucrose generally is
around 20 to 30 grams per liter in a
culture medium but for this medium we
needed a higher level at 60 there are no
growth Regulators in the medium and as I
mentioned before your jelling agent can
make or break a system um in talking
with um Dennis gray he said it's very
important to use this augur called TC
augur throughout the whole system to get
a good response for
gra okay now here's the fun
part so um so these are this is an
immature infloresence from Scout and
this is a dime we used as a size
reference so you can imagine with that
immature infloresence the size of that
um and what we end up doing with these
is we we treat the inflorescence with a
bleach solution to clean it up and
there's a lot of dissecting scope work
that has to be done because what we need
to do is take a Bud from this
inflorescence cut it open and then take
out the inside flower parts and what is
most important in this system is that
the filament stay attached to the anther
because that is where you get the right
type of callus the callus that's going
to give you that
embryogenesis it's difficult to keep the
filament with the anther um you know and
what we found is by taking out the
entire part here and putting that on the
medium we were much more successful at
keeping the anther um with that filament
we put it on the callous induction
medium the callus forms at the
connective tissue and then that callus
we again we're using a dissecting scope
and we're looking for these tiny little
white embryos that pop up these tiny
embryos are then moved to that
maintenance and it's actually a
proliferation medium and you can see all
these little embryos these sematic
embryos that have come up this in here
these little ones are what we called a
preemo and these are the sematic embryos
and it's these sematic embryos that are
used for the
transformation I don't know I'm really
fascinated um in a kind of a nerdy Way
by um by embryos by sematic embryos I
think they're really cute you know
they're very white and um it's really
it's fun to work with the systems where
getting sematic embryos so as I
mentioned there's a lot of um work at
the scope and this is Kate pigeon Kate
spends a lot of her time you know ex um
taking out the flower parts looking for
the sematic embryos and I asked her to
look at the camera to show that she can
still be smiling after all this all this
scope work but um you know in talking
with Dennis gray he said that you know
when he gives his protocol to people and
they then say we're having problems he
finds out that they're not using a scope
they're just trying to do it without
using a dissecting scope and it's an
important part of the process
so this is a closeup of some of the
somatic embryos that are on that
proliferation maintenance medium and you
can see these are more which as you lose
the term mature embryos and down here
and this is a closeup these are some of
the
pre-embryos so what we do to keep the
embryogenic system going is again using
the scope we'll select out these tiny
little embryos put them back onto the
medium and this isn't a black background
this is actually the charcoal in the
medium the activated charcoal and then
we'll take these embryos for
transformation and then leave these as
you know the source for getting more
embryos for for our
work so we haven't done a transformation
yet but we will be doing one in about
three weeks we needed to be able to bulk
up those sematic embryos until we had
enough to do a transformation and
according to um people I've talked with
and through the literature what we're
going to do is we're going to take one
gram of the Scout embryos the sematic
embryos um the more well-developed ones
we'll take one gram of those they go
into a liquid medium for two weeks on a
Shaker and then that solution is poured
through a c the smaller embryos will go
back into a liquid and then we'll we'll
pick off those larger embryos and use
those for transformation we're going to
use an agrobacterium string called agl1
agl1 is what's called a hyper virulent
um Agro bacterium there are other
virulent Agro bacterium out there that
you can use that you can get a you know
transformation but what we found is with
some of those other virulent
agrobacterium that they're really
difficult to eliminate from culture but
we find that with agl1 we get a good
transformation efficiency we don't have
a problem with eliminating the bacterium
and it also results in a lot of plants
that are single copy so it's important
to not have multiple copies in your
transgenic lines of your introduced
genes and agl1 um that you know we find
that we get a really high number of
single copies sometimes two copies of
the introduced Gene in our plant
material so for the vector we're going
to use the npt2 selectable marker Gene
we use gfp because we really want to
monitor the progress and Dennis gray
told me that within a week we should if
it worked we should be able to see the
green fluoresence protein expression and
then we're going to hope for the best
and and see what happens before we can
before we can move on so I I mentioned
that another method is um for doing
invitro leaves from you plant leaves
from invitro plants and we decided to
use this for Concord and the reason we
decided to use that for Concord is
because getting a source of IM um
immature inflores Ence was difficult
they're only at the right stage one time
per year so Gan someone in Gan Juan's
group would go out to the field to get
those inflorescences for us Ganan l in
itha he would drive to itha at the end
of the day I would meet him out front of
bti he would hand off a box of
inflorescences and we had that one shot
at getting you know trying all this
different media to get it to work so I
started looking in the literature to see
what else can be used and I found that
leaves can possibly use as I mentioned
before it's more successful for seedless
grapes but we're going to try it for
Concord and the way this works is we
take an A young chot from conquer plants
which actually we have now growing in
the greenhouse and then more dissecting
work um we go in here and take out the
small apical meristem that apil Mar
apical marem goes onto a medium and when
this plant is bigger we'll go ahead and
we'll take those leaves we'll put them
on in um a callous induction medium and
see if we can get embryos that way this
way we can have more of a supply of
material to bulk up the sematic embryos
that we need for our
Transformations okay that's great that's
where we're at and I'll tell you some of
the next steps later uh we're working on
Aus with anoro in um at Cornell and the
purpose is developed anog is interested
and he thinks that a community would be
interested in having um you know
milkweed as a model system and
transformation is an important part of
that being a model system
he identified seven different species
based on their chemical composition and
their insect interactions um so we
started with these seven different
species we really wanted to be able to
use invitro grown plants so they would
be clean we wouldn't have to worry about
cleaning up leaf or stem material every
time we wanted to do a transformation
but we couldn't get them to root the
milked just would not root in culture
and it used to kill me when I'd be on a
walk and I'd see a milk Reed growing in
a space between the sidewalk and a wall
I was like are you kidding me you're
going perfectly fine there and we can't
get you to root and culture um so I
could give a whole seminar on what we
tried um for rooting but we just we gave
up and we said all right we're going to
have to use plant material grown in a
growth chamber or a greenhouse for our
starting material cleaning it up was a
challenge um it was a challenge finding
that that kind of sweet spot where it
cleans up the contamination but yet
doesn't kill the plant material there's
nothing more you know disconcerting as
coming in and seeing a fungus growing
all over your
plates okay so these are some images of
the species that we're working with this
is the common one that you might be
familiar with that the monarch butterfly
goes through its life cycle on this is
um a tuberosa or butterfly weed and I
think they're just they're beautiful
here's some other images I've actually
started um a milkweed Garden at home
because they're really pretty I really
like the
kurava but this is how we get to see
them on a daily basis um these are some
some of the stem pieces that are you U
making callus on this callus induction
medium we use the Scopes to scan that
callus to look for the starts of plant
regeneration to make sure we're on the
right track with everything that we're
trying so when we see something like
this we get really excited because this
is the start of um the production of
choots now unlike grape which is sematic
embryogenesis this is
organogenesis and when we see this we
know that we're you know we're getting
to that point where we could recover
plants although sometimes were fooled
and they're actually roots and that's
pretty disappointing but um but this was
pretty exciting when we after trying all
sorts of different methods that we came
up with these little these little
shoots so because working with seven
different species was difficult and
plant tissue culture and regeneration
there's a definite genetic component to
it um you know species even closely
related species they they require
different um conditions and culture so
we decided to just focus on the three
now um that gave us the plant
regeneration first a key part of the
medium was using an antioxidant we used
DT um we used agrobacterium strain
lba4404 this is showing some Gus
response in the cultures and we've done
some recent real Gene Transformations
where we're looking at knocking down
koi1 expression and koi1 is involved in
defense um and right now Amy um who
works on the project is doing
characterization to see how far down
that koi one is is knocked down and then
we'll continue doing Transformations
with the other species the last project
I'm going to talk about is um the
sataria veritus project this started out
as a collaboration with Tom brell when
he was at bti and as I mentioned the
interest is because it's a model species
it has a small stature compared to
something like ma sorghum or sugar cane
and it's a C4
photosynthesis this is a fogy of the
grasses uh sataria viridus is here it's
a wild it's a wild relative of the
cultivated fox tail Millet and it's a
close relative of
switchgrass it has a lot of attributes
that make it attractive for a model
species it's a small stature you can
grow a lot of plants it's kind of like
the arabidopsis or the dcut world we can
grow a lot of plants in a small area and
what really we needed at this point was
to have a transformation method worked
out and Tom asked me if I was interested
and I said definitely you know we'll
take on that on that challenge so what I
did was I went to the literature first
to see um what uh if there was anything
reported for viridus and there wasn't
but there were reports for its
cultivated relative italica and they
started with mature seeds the only
problem with viritus is there's a dorcy
issue if the seeds are younger than 3
months old so we found that we had to
break the dormy we tried all sorts of
methods to break the dormy and what
worked out the best was removing the
seed coats and I'll show you in the next
couple slides how we do that the seeds
are then cultured on a um induction
medium we then clean up the coleoptiles
and The Roots and we transfer that to um
fresh medium and as I mentioned before
the importance of jelling agent when we
started out you know the italica reports
they used augur in the medium and what
we were getting with viridus was this
really sticky gelatin this
non-regenerable callus and um we just we
what we really wanted was this more
defined callus and I knew from my
experience prior experience with monot
that sometimes a gel and gum in this
case phyto gel actually works and when
we switched to that phyto gel we
recovered more of this more well-defined
regenerable callus you couldn't ask for
anything better for plant regeneration
just about every piece of callus
regenerates multiple choots we took one
choot and put it on rooting medium it
rooted well it tillered a lot and you
know it grew just fine so we knew that
we were now ready to do plant
transformation so as I mentioned to
remove the seed coats um we came up with
this nearly simple but it works um we
took a tray we have a rubber St ster we
got some rid plastic material out of my
kitchen drawers and we take put the
seeds and we rub that rubber stopper
over the seeds we were concerned that
maybe we would break a lot of the seeds
and wouldn't get good germination but we
got close to 100% germination and then
this is where more patients comes in
those seeds are um selected away from
those that have the seed coats and this
is what we use for the callous induction
medium for the transformation we started
with use this Vector this Vector has a
Gene for hygromycin resistance npt2 and
canamy don't work that well for monocots
as compared to dicots we infect the
callus with the agrobacterium they then
go to a selective regeneration medium
that has hygromycin in it this is a very
happy day in the lab when we have this
is our non-transformed control we put it
in gust no blue but when we put one of
the putative transformance into Gus
solution it turned blue and this is
showing some Leaf material from a a
control did not turn blue and this is
some these are some leaves from some
older uh transgenic lines now as I
mentioned we use that selectable marker
Gene because if we didn't this is what
we would end up with after we did a
transformation so we would have to
analyze a lot of plants in order to find
these precious few that are are really
transformed we wanted to see if we could
get this to persist into the Next
Generation so we um took some we let
some of those transgenic lines go on to
make seed grew them in the greenhouse
harvested that next generation which is
called the T1 AUM for Gus solution for
Gus with using the aate solution and you
can see again non-transformed control
and Gus expression in those
pry so it's um this is a timeline for
how long the whole process takes from
culturing the seed on callous medium to
having seeds harvested from your
transgenic lines takes about 21 weeks
but if we had that callus already we
could cut off six weeks off that process
and with monocot it's really difficult
to maintain callus long term and still
have it maintain that high
regenerability and when you do get
regenerants you sometimes see a large
percentage of albinos because the
transposons are activated but we um
we've decided to try it with sataria and
so far what we've seen is we're just
testing taking callus keeping it
longterm and putting it on regeneration
medium and it seems to be acting
differently than maze or rice callus and
that we're not seeing that hit on plant
generation and now we're going to try
some of that longer term callus on um
for
transformation okay so um I'm not I
didn't go into I'm not going to talk
about I have time to talk about our
crisper work in sataria but we have um
tried the genome editing by targeting
this flowering time Gene called
indeterminant one and what you can see
here is that these are the controls
empty Vector no Target in them and these
are two lines that were recovered you
can see there's a definite difference
and the flowering time so that was you
know a really good indication
phenotypically that we hit the right
Gene and it it's working and all the pro
all the lines now both the primary ones
and progyny are being analyzed to see
what types of mutations we had and the
and the frequency on know so that that
was been it's been a lot of fun working
with the crisper cast 9
systems so in summary I hope I've
impressed upon you all the work that it
takes um sometimes people don't
appreciate it and we you we do a
transformation service and like what's
taking so long how come we don't have
our plants I me that's rare but you know
there really is a lot of work that goes
into the system I have a great group
they're very patient they're very
creative and that's why we are
successful in in what we do so for the
next steps
um for grape we are going to do I
mentioned the transformation with gfp as
soon as we have enough embryos from
Concord we're going to try
transformation of Concord for the
esclipus we'll you know characterize
those koi one um knockdown lines and
we're trying to recover more of those so
we can have different levels of
expression and different transgenics um
improve the rooting and soil we've given
up on initro rooting and we're looking
at rooting in soil it's not great but
it's better than what it used to be and
we're also starting to work on the other
species of of the seven species for
sataria viritus we're actually looking
at other accessions besides the
a10.1 because you know I mentioned that
there's a genetic component to um plant
regeneration and also for transformation
and that we feel that if we can find
another accession where we can get
higher than 5 to 20% transformation
efficiency that would make it more high
throughput for us and as you know we're
looking at the long-term callous
maintenance so that we can cut off about
six weeks off the process and we're
going to expand our genome editing um
efforts so right now we're just using it
for mutagenesis to knock out genes but
we're looking at some of the new crisper
technologies that have come along to
activate endogenous genes and do some
Gene replac basement in those systems
and we're doing that both in sataria and
in tomato as well so with that um I have
acknowledgements this is my group who
make it all possible they're they're
great um patient and just put up with
some of my crazy ideas uh Cornell um Amy
is working with an Hog's group she works
with us as well she's very talented um
this is Gan Juan's group who've been
helping us with the grape uh the group
at Danford Center and in Minnesota have
been involved in the crisper work with
satar
and I um have a collaboration with the
group at the John inis Center and we're
some of that funding has helped support
our Improvement of sataria because we're
using sataria as a model for that
project and these are the sources of
funding for our group and thank you
[Applause]
guys um
medicago takes a long time to go from
start to finish that's one of the most
difficult parts and there's one genotype
that works best um so in the beginning
we had some problems because um they
were recommending one of the groups is
recommending using this eha 105 super
virulent Agri bacterium and we lost a
lot of material from overgrowth but when
we switched to agl1 we're able to
eliminate that so as long as you're
working with that one particular
genotype and you're willing to wait for
quite a while it um it's it's workable
it's doable not as easy as tomato um but
um but doable Randy you know what it is
about the different jelly
media yeah um you know I basically what
I've seen in the reports it's it's a
chemical composition but also a physical
composition to it ability uh exactly
like like um jite one of the gelang gel
gelang gums um it needs to it binds the
dilic cation magnesium and calcium in
order to gel and I learned this the hard
way when I was a graduate student and I
was trying some experiments with the
gelling agent I thought why should I
make up a whole batch of salt you know
medium with salts in it I'll just use
water and the gelling agent and I
couldn't get it to gel I was like why
isn't it gelling augre gels in water and
then when I did some more searching I
found out that you do need some of the
salts in there um and something like
tomato is does not do well on the gel
and gums because it doesn't have those
calcium and magnesium ions available to
it so we end up having to use an augre
based for that but again it's a chemical
and a physical a lot of it has to do
with concentration you know we look at
that also not just a
type with regard to your charcoal I can
say why you put that in to pull out some
of the phenolics but doesn't it also
bind some of the hormone material it
does right so if we're if we're working
with the medium and we see that you know
IAA works really well I'm sorry sorry
I'm sorry so um so Peter was wondering
he asked about the activated charcoal
that it can also bind some of the
hormones in the medium and it does so we
find that you know we'll work out a
system and we find out that something
like IA a certain concentration works
really well but if we then decide oh
there's some Browning or we want rooting
and we switch to using activated
charcoal we don't see the same response
as we did with the original
concentration so then we have to bump
that up and look at other concentrations
so yeah it can have an effect I ask does
the Maro butterfly feed on any of
species of milk weed that you're doing
and I asked because they saying my
butterflies are declining because people
are destroying
milked in their in their in their home
oh okay yeah I don't know if it does on
other other milk weeds I know that it
uses that one primarily but I don't know
I don't know about the others but but
I'm planting it in my garden now so I'm
trying to I'm trying to help out and and
we'll see but yeah they're very pretty
they're very beautiful but think people
think you know it can be a weed but um
in some Gardens but um the guy across
the street has wild milk weed and it's
just spewing the white stuff all over oh
yeah it can be pretty messy too I don't
but anything for the mon yeah that's
right yeah exactly so jyn is asking
about pyy level in the plant material
and when we go through that callus and
regeneration can that have an effect in
the end product and yes it can and some
plant species are more prone to it than
others so you'll see I think something
like pineapple where you'll see more of
a platy problem in regeneration and
transformation than some other systems
but um what some what some people are
doing is looking at doing chromosome
counts or doing some sort of an analysis
to see what the py level is is in the in
the resulting plants so so you have to
be aware of that for some plant species
because it can it can be an issue ises
that answer your question is it yeah
kind of a followup do you ever use
pollen to get a halfway cam we do so I
didn't talk about that but we have done
um you know cultures to be able to get
haid material and using pollen or
culturing anthers at a certain stage of
where the pollen development so we we
did we had a project with rice where we
were developing haids and actually I was
talking with um a great reader just
yesterday who asked me if we would
consider doing that with grape is
looking at haploids for grape because
and using a pollen system because you
grape is such a heterozygous um material
it makes it difficult but for both
sequencing and for doing their work but
if they had a Hao type grape that it
would really help Advance their work so
so yes definitely that that'll take some
work to try to get that
out don't any maze
orice I did maze is an undergraduate um
and um that was enough of an exposure to
maze no um the the pro um so actually
yeah sataria now but actually was
actually I kind of enjoyed it because we
um at certain times of the year they
would pull everybody in into a lab it
was an undergraduate you know work study
student and um from for Maze the
starting material are immature embryos
from and you have to have the plants at
a certain stage to have these immature
ears and then what you do is you cut the
um kernels and you go in you scoop out
the little immature embryo and it
depends on how it's you know oriented
that you'll get the right type of
callous and when we started our
transformation service someone David
Stern said what about doing maze I said
oh that's really tricky because you
basically have to dedicate Greenhouse
space to have the plants to be able to
do get your ears to get your immature
embryos so it kind of becomes a you know
financially difficult space difficult to
be able to do maze um so you know and
sometimes you grow those plants and you
don't have any requests for doing the
Transformations but you need to have
that constant supply of ears so what's
the difference between ma in CIA then if
you can use CIA just the seed not from
yeah it's something genetic and
physiological about about maze versus
Saria yes and rice and rice um you can
start with mature seed so mature seed
you culture it like um sataria and you
get that you know um you know you get
that embryogenic callus from it someone
asked me have you considered doing
immature embryos from sataria you saw
how those seeds are and I said I think
I'd have a mutiny on my hands in the lab
if I asked people to take immature
embryos out of those small seeds but
fortunately like rice the mature seeds
forar works you been asked to do Rice we
um did yeah we just did rice as part of
an NSF project a number of years ago but
I I haven't been asked um otherwise here
big deal yeah so nobody has asked us to
do it so so and what we did when we you
know when David asked me to start up the
transformation service is part of my
research program um I talked with the
project leaders at bti and I said what
are you interested in you know what you
know what type of crops would be
important for you and we based it on
their interest first and since that time
we've done work for people with like
Cornell and also outside of Cornell um
but rice hasn't been one of those that
we've done you know um I can't remember
which species it was where you used the
fil
yes
grap is there any particular sell that's
giving rise I'm sure there is I just
don't know if anyone has looked at it
because like in in rice um they've shown
and in in maze as well it's the skellum
where the callus originates from so I'm
I'm sure there's got to be a particular
cell type in that connective tissue the
reason I asked too is because um when I
want my students to look at myotic
chromosomes but we fail because we don't
have the right State what we can always
look at are the shape of the nuclei in
the fil they're so different there's
such a
variety oh that's interesting mhm yeah
so there must be something to that a
great Cor out in left field but in in
March it was announced that all
cultivated sweet potatoes have the genes
for aggro bacterium in them I was
thrilled and the wild ones don't so
there must and it was they thought it's
thousands of years ago that it got
infected what possible Advantage could
that agrobacterium have I agree I wonder
the same you know what you know what was
it through you not the wild species but
the more cultiv oh sorry I'm sorry I'm
sorry um I get so excited um there was a
there's um there was a recent paper that
showed um actually it's from the
international potato Center where they
were looking at sweet potato and doing
you know um kind of transcription
profiling to find out and they found
sequences from Agri bacterium in some of
the sweet potatoes I think I tested like
300 different types of sweet potato1 291
and that was every variety that they
tested that was a cultivated variety but
not the wild one so there must have been
some you know I don't know if the
cultivated ones or this Wild Ones had
some sort of resistance to the infection
cultivated ones that resistance broke
down um and then they were infected I
don't know if there's an evolutionary
benefit you know for the for the Agro
bacterium and the wild sweet potato and
the cultivated but um I got you know I
was happy because I thought okay what
are they going to do about GMOs now you
know with sweet potatoes and they have
these components of agrobacterium how
are they going to classify how are they
going to classify that so but it was
interesting incorp the genome one yeah
mhm yeah it's incorporated into the
genome it's true for mistl toes and
Oaks right mistl toes really there's um
at least five different uh segments of
the oak host that's now integrated into
the missile toe genome oh interesting
and it it might be this kind of notion
of recognizing s and
immunological yeah that could be oh
that's a question how easy sweet
potatoes to transform them should be
think it' be easy just get the tuber mix
it with aggro you're done oh guess you
to get plants back from it um but um but
we haven't worked with sweet potato but
you I think certain species are easier
than others but might be more amenable
to
it okay well thank you everyone
thanks this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu