he's a native New Yorker who spent more
than 30 years in the Turk grass industry
and was a golf course superintendent
before returning to grad school in
1986 he was recognized in 2001 by golf
Week Magazine as one of the 40 most
influential people in the game of golf
under the age of 40 he's not he's not
under
40 as honor he shared with Tiger Woods
and Jack
he's an international expert in golf and
sports turf management published
hundreds of Articles he's traveled
around the world lecturing on
environmentally responsible and
sustainable turf grass management uh
less Reliance on fertilizer and
pesticides he's appeared on CNN ESPN PBS
the Golf Channel and just in numerous
magazines USA weekend New York Times
Wall Street Journal um he's been a
visiting professor at the Swedish
agricultural University and um he served
as lead Turf consultant for New York
Yankees Green Bay Packers the Lincoln
Center for Performing on for arts and so
um he's got long lists here in addition
to his career in Turf Frank is married
and the father of three children a
triathlete member of his local school
board hospice volunteer little league
coach an Al
farmer so Frank thanks for joining us
and I think you're going to see why he
uh you might be wondering at this point
what's the link between living sculpture
and art and grass and he will be showing
you there'll be no doubt about
that yeah that's the first time I've had
to listen to that used to be really
short somebody my wife was nudging me
that I should write on there but then
there's the risk of sounding like a nut
do um as Marsha said
uh thanks to Mara and Craig and all the
people that work to put this on Max
downstairs um I'm really uh thrilled to
be here uh and I'm I have to tell you
spending most of my life as kind of a
functional Turf person um this has been
a real gosh I think we started this four
or five maybe was was it five years ago
you started with me in the art of
horticulture and what I want I want to
start out with the end and the end is
that the best part
about my involvement in all this stuff
has been how it stretched me I'm a very
you know I was a golf course
superintendent I'm not a big golfer I'm
really just a grass guy I've spent most
of my life I was born and raised in the
for section of the Bronx so I don't have
a lot of you know glorious grass stories
be Beyond pushing a lawn mower and
trying to get out to a golf course for
some open space so a lot of my grass
stuff both in golf and sports um filter
strips and functional things and now
alaca pastures has been very functional
and what I've liked about this work is
that it's really kind of stretched me a
lot and um and I think that's one of the
great things that comes at at doing this
work uh and that's why I was happy and
of course honored to be able to give the
opening talk because I think what you're
going to experience today is is is is
this stretching I mean there's a you get
there as a pile of dirt and a load of
grass and next thing you know it's
something and so I I look forward to
seeing uh I wish I I hope I get to be
there to see your faces at the very end
because I think as Mara said from
Longwood that's really the cool thing
about um this work and I hope that we
can uh just get you started with some
ideas uh to stretch you beyond uh what
you do
today so uh go back so we'll see a lot
of these kinds of pictures um uh this is
actually uh obviously near the London
Bridge this was a de a promotion for a
uh TV program in in the UK uh with a a
sculptured swimmer and mounded grass to
look like water we'll look we'll look at
this a little more closely as we get
into the form so we titled this The
Thrill of the grass and Craig Kramer uh
gave me one of these uh short stories
from WP canella which is the title of
his story and this story is about a guy
who goes on steel side from a field and
takes it home so it's really kind of a
fascinating story this is um U myin who
did their get nothing this is in the
Hudson Valley here newk and these are
just these Earth mounts uh that she done
there really easy to do um and and very
uh as as most of her work very symbolic
and of course what
what we're trying to do is to uh what
I'm trying to talk to you about and get
you inspired about is using uh Earth as
a canvas which is not unique to us here
but I think uh with Marsha's leadership
really I think have done some really
cool
things and of course we can be fairly
Whimsical um this is an artist down in
Texas who uh her lawn was dormant uh
Bermuda grass or dormant St Augustine
grass whatever the heck that crab grass
is you're growing down there f
um it looks much better with polka dots
sprayed on it and then of course there's
the functional aspect and that's where I
want to start this is what's been the
most comfortable for me um grass is
function this is uh in between the
strips on this tram uh where obviously
there's pavement they grass it and we've
been doing a lot of work with Nina
bassic uh looking at um uh the struct
this structural soil she developed that
they can grow Street trees on we're now
using it to grow grass on and thinking
about starting to replace these 4 acre
Walmart Mark parking lots with grass
parking lots that can then filter a lot
of the pollutants that would come off
the vehicles in the parking lot we're
nuts about grass in this country and I'm
sure you know that uh just in New York
state alone we have about 3 and a half
million Acres of turf that we would call
Turf m managed grass and we spend about5
billion a year in New York state about
75 to 80 billion nationally is spent
managing grass so we're absolutely nutty
about grass and you know I I think I
spend most of my career trying to figure
out how to help us not be so nutty but
the fact is most of that money is spent
by homeowners in and around their lawns
so some people go to
extremes take the alwn out pile up some
gravel and of course then you know on a
hot summer day you're going to feel
fairly warm matter of fact you may see
one of the more ridiculous things in
your life walking outside today if you
venture out at all uh if on this side of
Campus where we have some of our Sports
Fields there's a synthetic turf field
hockey field plastic grass that we water
four times a day with with only be
described as a fire hose sprinkler to
cool it off because it's so warm to play
on that the athletes can't stay on it
very long unless it's unless it's cool
off now functionally obviously this is a
moss mat you come out of the shower and
step on that that's actually not such a
bad deal and of course A lot of these
things you can buy or do
yourself now back to the functional part
I spend a lot of my time working at a
fairly uh you know with school school
districts uh regular folk trying to have
decent grass for the safety of their
athletes and then we get to talk about
how even at the professional level uh
managing tur for these athletes to
ensure their safety maximize their
performance and ensure their safety is
really critical this was of course a
game that the Pittsburgh Steelers played
a number of years ago where they brought
in grass and SED over an existing field
three inches of rainfall and it turned
into a muddy mess where the athletes
weren't safe at all so we spent a lot of
time trying to help uh clubs and
athletes uh have a safe surface to plan
now there is an aesthetic part to what
we do it looks you know what you do for
looks and this is actually one of our
research experiments where we're looking
at different forms of iron iron is one
of the really critical nutrients for
color in a in a green plant because it's
involved in the chlorophyll molecule so
if you really want to do something crazy
on your lawn and don't want to fertilize
it and we've done some work looking at
using iron as opposed to um fertilizers
that might contaminate water quality um
we found that iron is a really easy way
to get green grass without having to get
it to grow so much this is something we
were experimenting with now of course
golf courses we one could find some art
in this little practice facility that
was built and you start to see some of
the striping effects the inter with the
bunkers at different heights of cut
you've got a green a putting surface cut
at about a tenth of an inch a fairway
cut at about a third of an inch and then
you've got grass around the bunkers that
are probably cut at about two or three
inches so sometimes just different
heights can give you a very different
look this is the flower hole at the
Stevens Point Country Club in Central
Wisconsin where I used to work before I
came back to Cornell they changed this
floral display three times a year of
course I'm sure all of you are looking
at the flowers I'm always of course
looking at the grass U but the contrast
here between the colors in the you know
the Deep green of the grass and the uh
various colors of the flowers they
change this display three times a year
it takes about 14 employees the better
part of 40 hours to change the floral
displays here's one of my favorite
pictures this is Bandon Dunes or Pacific
Dunes Golf Course right along the South
Western Oregon coast it's a fairly new
golf course and what I love is how grass
kind of brings out the subtle wrinkles
in the earth here there was very little
done when this golf course was built and
designed by Cornell Al do this is a very
minimalist Golf Course um very little
was done here you can see they just kind
of threw some sand in places this is
just a beautiful piece of land that uh
they planted some grass over the the top
and there's very little management done
out there uh to keep this a playable
surface of course you can get ridiculous
with this and some people like golf so
much they do it in their office nothing
living there and then there's of course
the occasional fool who decides to Grass
his entire inside of the house and
sucking the fumes you can imagine why
he's so
happy and then there's the functional
aspect of room so we have a room inside
and here is a room at the State Fair the
New York State Fair last year um there
was a living sculpture demonstration
done there where they built a couple of
uh sitting chairs a little love seat a
couch which you will uh be involved in
working on
today and one of the things that we're
you know constantly you know obviously
it looks good right now you're going to
get to do something today that might
help it sustain itself sometimes getting
these things watered and keeping them
healthy um is a little tricky so we've
been figuring out ways of doing that in
a sustainable
fashion um I get to work in some fairly
ridiculous environments um this is a
project I've been working on for the
last five years associated with the 65th
Street uh renovation for Lincoln Center
uh the Lincoln Center development
project this is the conceptual drawing
that they started with about five years
ago and this is what it looked like last
week this is the juliard school right
here this is the addition to the Julie
art school this is Alice Tully Hall and
this is a $25 million lawn
roof which is going to be a park on top
of a restaurant on 65th Street so pretty
soon you'll get to see this uh In Living
Color if you live down in Manhattan or
wander down that way this is at Q
Gardens again
functionally grass can be a great thing
for
bleachers maybe for stepping stumes
maybe for just functionally having it in
your backyard for stairs up and down or
just giving you that cascading
effect and make transition to using
grass for forms this is at Dartmouth
College at
uh Dartmouth in in New Hampshire I can
tell you that one of the things that
guys like me struggle with is architects
who sit there draw on a piece of paper
and say oh isn't that look really cool
and then somebody's got to take care of
it the poor guy's got to you know have a
sprinkler that he has here to you know
everybody wants it green and he's got to
climb up here to trim this tip by hand
because you can't really get up there
with anything so um these do create
unique problems uh the students love
them but they are a unique uh uh
maintenance
situation now from a form perspective it
can be fairly simple these are little
indoor grass planters that you can get
on the web just to have out in your in
your
house the Chia Professor maybe this is
where your kids will start uh you can
use the uh little plant seeds that they
send you or you can use grass seed just
as
well and here's the swimmer again just
you know a matter of mounding up some
grass and making it look like the uh
swimmer making his way through and you
can see how intricate this is this
obviously the structure is the one of
the highlights here but you can see the
interaction with his face and the grass
there and the Mounds looking where his
hands are going in um it's just really a
fascinating display and again one of the
things about some of this artwork is it
doesn't stay around long you do it looks
really cool and then they take it away
and all that lives are the pictures
there's my project this is the moss
snake this is from that Turf Works book
by Paul Cooper Paul Cooper who we was
here a number of years ago that was very
pleasant in meeting him and he we took
some of these scans right out of his
book again nothing more than some Stone
and one of the tricks we use for Moss is
mixing it with in a blender with
buttermilk take Moss put it in a blender
mix it up with buttermilk and just smear
it on there and you know it grows on
rocks long as it gets a little bit of
moisture it usually will grow fairly
well
some really interesting uh structures
that you can do with longer grass uh as
well as planting grass over a uh almost
like a
topar now one of the things that I've
liked about this is you know when you go
start looking around for these things
you see how people use grass you know to
make a statement and this is at the
University of Illinois um they planted
these boxes to represent the age child
fatality statistics there's 3,000 Blades
of grass in a square foot and and to De
to uh recognize the
60,000 uh people per year under the age
of 12 who die of age so they use just
having the grass out there as a way of
honoring that U those
people and then just odd forms of
artwork inside uh a
structure that is basically suspended
from a ceiling with grow lights and sod
laid over the top of
it of course uh again you can use
plastic grass and this is an example of
that where they use some living plant
material for the bucket but the uh
carpet itself here is Synthetic
Turf this is the London Museum of
Art um and you can see the guy watering
it uh it's basically just a big pile of
grass
and um it's really fascinating at night
when I was there it was really really
amazing this is a chapel in
Czechoslovakia I'm not Czechoslovakia in
the Czech
Republic someone sent me this
one Craig sends me a lot of these but
you can see they put grass on the
outside as well as on the inside and you
can see it growing here and and
basically it's the kind of thing that
they do and then strip off and every
year will redo it and of course
completely recycle all the things that
are used to do it but the structure
itself is
cement and of course here's a little
topiary thing with some grass on it and
of course now you can start again in
getting into the Whimsical a little bit
um the giraffe uh on the lawn people
like putting things on their lawns then
we get into the whole animal range and
you'll meet one of our favorite animal
construction people Danielle today uh
this is again out of uh that Turf Works
book again uh if you can't have grass
alive there's a synthetic version of the
bull and here she is um one I think
really one of our stars um I remember
when she was taking Marsh's
class she showed up this was part of one
of her art of horticulture projects she
shows up in my office and um you know
talk about doing this and she has this
tray with her and on the tray are about
seven different farm animals and she's
got a cow a horse and a chicken and a
goat and a pig and sheep and she's like
this is what I want to do like okay I
don't I think we got to do
one let's try to do one and I think uh
it was really uh really epitomized kind
of the energy that she's brought to
doing this and um so this is again a
shaped pile of soil and she built this
head with chicken chicken wire and
stuffed it with hay and there's these
2x4s that are attaching it into the soil
pile and I can tell you of all the
graduations of the 15 or 16 graduation
weekends I've been a part of I've never
seen so many people gathered around a
single thing uh in my entire career here
everybody wanted their picture taken on
graduation weekend in front of Morrison
Hall and the C doesn't have a name is it
Daisy misty
misty and there's some more more of uh
Danielle's work now what what was
fascinating about this piece of project
is is it evolved it started out as green
grass shaped letters for the College of
agricultural and Life Sciences right
cows right out on the quad but then as
it started to die and go
dormant she spray painted it black and
white so it had a whole another
um life after it was still
living now here's this is how simple
this is this was uh Marsha's from a few
years ago one of her art of horticulture
projects with a bunch of students and we
had a couple of hours to do it my staff
um made gave us a pile of dirt and
that's what you'll start out with today
if you're doing this particular project
and then we get out there and we get all
kinds of people running side cutters
here I am
supervising and the idea was to create
this walk path um around this mound and
that's what it looked like when we were
done we cut the side from an adjacent
area we used water to kind of Tamp down
the path area and then laid some sod
over the top and there's the class of
the very
end this is the year the following year
the class uh wanted to try something
different so again we started with a
mount of dirt we made stairs um and at
the top they planted a door
which I have to tell you that the
Cornell Golf Course is right over here
the eighth hole and there was an
enormous amount of Interest matter of
fact when you come over the hill on the
a pole and you see this all you can
actually see is the door and you're like
what the hell is the door doing out
there and so uh this was really quite a
thing until a 50 mph wind came and took
the door away so it has not the door is
no longer there but the mound is still
there
now this is Marsha's project at Longwood
Gardens that uh basically uh again just
another form of soil and grass there was
a a mold made to shape the uh
pattern yeah and I just want to Alex
lavalo who um is really he had done the
design for this and worked on the
project with me is also one of the
Workshop present yeah and you'll see
Alex again in another picture here how
long did this live
that Liv a week a week and theyed
it but it's all
reusable okay now how about furniture
this is some of what you're going to do
nice little bed here and a
chair in the middle of Paris a little
little lawn chair sitting there and you
can see the size of it relative to
things around it's a fairly large
chair and you can do this in your yard
all kinds of lawn furniture you can
actually be fairly sophisticated about
it or you can just take a chase lounge
and lay some lay some grass over the top
of it nice and
easy some variations of sad sofas here's
a nice one integrated into a
garden you can buy a cardboard structure
fill it up with soil and plant some
grass over the top and that's available
at inh habit.com
fairly easy to do um something that you
could do in your own backyard
some Whimsical things these foam grass
blades that we found little sod end
table
here another bed maybe with some sheets
installed really fairly inviting I
think and then or something simple this
was one of our very first efforts that
Alex built uh this is one of the art of
horiculture students fairly simple
here's how it started out with a bare
area a pile of compost that the Cornell
grounds people brought over Alex to
shape it and then you've got a side
couch so fairly easy to do do you have
to mow these couches you
can um one of the things that we've seen
useful is maybe just a hand trim where
you sit yeah but you don't have to mow
it you can mow it uh mowing encourages
it to spread and get thicker but this
one's so small it could be done by hand
fairly easily yeah I would recommend
that or we have some battery operated
shears that we use too I I don't like
the idea of a string trimmer because
they're very difficult to keep level and
what happens if you've ever worked one
it really pulls it into the ground and
then you got these Brown half Moons all
over the structure now this a project
that Mara's husband uh did at one of his
old camps and here's Alex who you'll see
today um again you
know like Tom Watson said over the
weekend a bunch of old fogies right get
around piling up some dirt shaping it
with a little bit of moisture laying
some grass over the top and lo behold
you've got a couch to sit on how long
did that take that took about three four
hours there you go can you use grass
seed or does it have to be all rolled
out yeah very good question um you can
use grass seed but then of course you're
waiting but I would recommend on some of
these slopes that if you did that that
you use some kind of erosion mat because
of the the steepness of the slope even
gently watering it um is going to cause
some erosion but you can there's lots of
erosion type mats you can use or you
know even at the Garden Center they sell
the that seed mulch stuff you can just
pack that out like a mud pad if you
don't want to use uh a side now you can
cut s from one part in your yard and
that's what we did out at the out at our
Research Center where we did it with the
students we just cut it from one place
and Put It In Another
Place Another question sorry like the
more complicated CES is there Armature
inside um some of them like the there
was one where there are some you know
little pieces of wood or metal just to
kind of hold things together but
generally it's just piles of soil and
once the grass gets stabilized it really
holds it together
further this is a project that Alex did
down at the itha youth Bureau in honor
of Marsha and her husband Scott and
again this is the nice integration of
stonework with a little bit of a couch
here this is right in our little
downtown tberg our little uh this is our
little village where we live in up just
up the lake a little bit and again just
a pile of soil a couple of rocks at the
end I think you Tred time up here didn't
you had that work it didn't work it
didn't work okay it gets too much love
this couch we think the kids love this
little thing here and then some of
Marsha's students have done some lawn
furniture this is nothing more than a
flat of grow mix put in a greenhouse
with tons of Ry grass seed and you make
a little cushion and you pull it out of
the flat put it on top of the chair you
got a long chair how about an entire bar
not a bad deal this is one of Marsh's
students what was his
name Zack Zach yeah he was a maniac this
this is just a bunch of grass grown on
burlap that we slapped on top of a a um
structure he made on Wheels and there's
his little uh Tiki
Bar okay so what about mowing patterns
and you're going to see you're going to
have a little workshop about this this
is probably the easiest of all things to
do because it's simply a matter of
mowing the grass in different direction
or rolling the grass or in some cases
spritzing it with a little
water there was a I I I actually didn't
incorporate the picture um but if you
watch the Major League Baseball allstar
game which it doesn't look like many of
you would actually turn the major league
baseball allar game on but if you did
you would have seen the St Louis they
played it in St Louis and in the
Outfield they had an uh in the grass an
image of the Gateway Arch and underneath
it an image burned into the grass assass
of the state of the the state capital of
Missouri and they had these little
windows in there and was talking to the
grounds keeper maybe a month or so ago
and he just gets a little water spritzer
sprits the water into these squares mats
the grass down so it's folded in One
Direction different from the way the
grass is mowed and you get patterns nice
and simple at Yankee Stadium that's the
way we like it there much more
interested in winning baseball games and
having fancy patterns on the
grass but Dave Miller wrote a wonderful
book called picture perfect if you're
interested in this it's really an
interesting little read very simple how
to take care of grass very simply I knew
Dave when he was the grounds Keeper at
Milwaukee County Stadium where the
Brewers used to play and he was the one
that originally started a lot of this
craze that's going on in the um Turf
industry with regard to mowing patterns
Dave is now the grounds keeper for the
Boston Red Sox at
Park so we have we have uh sometimes
grounds managers who maybe have an acid
flashback or something you can imagine
what the athletes and of course if
you're sitting on the other side of the
field it looks completely
different here's the starburst uh again
at County Stadium this was popular there
at sha stadium for a while before they
closed up this is Frontier field in
Rochester and preparation for the AAA
All-Star Game a few years ago again
nothing more than just mowing the
patterns in different
directions this is Rosen blat Stadium
home of the College World Series with
some baseballs on it and it gets fairly
sophisticated um you can get fairly
sophisticated or fairly simple this is
um uh Corey Miller's uh drawing for her
dad dad can you do this and he went out
to County Stadium
and now sometimes people do some really
goofy things by accident this was a
person in Central Wisconsin who was very
worried about fertilizer running off
their lawn so her idea was put the
fertilizer in a drop spreader open it
all the way up run around the lawn and
put the water on really quick because
then it'll all get even right if you
just put it down there and water it it
runs off so much that it'll all get
even we got a call from this person who
thought this was a mold
running around the yard so you can do
these kinds of things just with a little
bit of fertilizer if you course you can
see the fertilizer doesn't move very far
from where you put it down but again it
doesn't have to be very complicated
here's a very simple pattern just mowing
in crop circles if you've ever read
Michael Poland's work particularly in
second nature where he has this chapter
called why mow um he talks about mowing
crop circles in his lawn and most people
can do this fairly easily really the
only requirement is is is to have some
sort of a roller or a tire on your
moment very simple little pattern here
in a community leaving an area unmowed
this is getting more popular now as
we're starting to realize the carbon
emission problem from our lawn MERS
we've on been on a real push over the
last several years now to try to get
people to reduce the number of times
that they're mowing their lawns
recognizing number one Lawns are
trapping carbon right green plants are
trapping carbon and that's really good
taking the carbon dioxide out of the
atmosphere but it seems a little odd
that we're also burning a fair amount of
carbon to keep the LA so we're
constantly working on ways of being more
sustainable keeping the turf healthy
enough so that it can continue to trap
carbon obviously when it's brown and not
growing it's not trapping much carbon
but at the same time not going crazy
with the mowing strategies so that we're
burning so much carbon here's one that I
found this a lightning strike in a golf
course Fairway you can see sometimes you
can get artwork in Turf that you have
absolutely no you have no reason you
weren't involved in it at all other than
you were there to take a picture of
here's that artist in Texas again as the
lawn started to Green up she liked the
idea of maybe just purple polka dots
here she is really just a fascinating I
mean I personally think this would be
really cool to live next to something
like this is that just regular spray
paint what kind what it's just uh it's
just they make um they make Athletic
Field marking paint okay that you can
put on the grass doesn't kill the grass
it's good for the environment well you
know relatively I I wouldn't say it's
good for the environment but it's
certainly you know titanium dioxide
often times it wouldn't be something I'd
want to necessarily disperse but
certainly it's degradable most of it
degrades okay and how how long would
that last well on the brown grass it
would last a fairly long time because
it's not growing on the green grass here
I would say at least three weeks to a
month oh it will it just disappear like
it grows off you mow it it blows up
would it rhyme if it started no it
sticks to the grass plants fairly well
it sticks to the grass plants fairly
well now how about some flyovers these
are this is a little bit of a stretch
for calling it Turf right but but really
some fascinating things this is some uh
Muk soil in Japan where you can tell
where they plowed a little and left some
of the crop but some of this stuff is
absolutely amazing this is actually from
Ellenville New York this is right down
here in the cat skills and you I don't
know if you can see them but you can see
some of the hang gliders people hang
glide over these
things um some really cool stuff here's
one of the Hang
liners a promotion for the American
Museum of Natural History Statue of
Liberty again you know not really of
course this is really just a a a a hay
field that was most but you could do the
same thing with a lawn if you wanted to
do it from your bedroom you could you
know get a stencil and Mark it out with
flags and go out there and cut some of
it low and you can do the same thing
there here's my favorite Sarah America
somebody that went to the trouble of
doing Sarah Palin in the middle of a the
middle of a Hayfield
so uh and this is one that we did this
is uh Mara one of Marsha's classes uh
this is our turf research facility um
Marsha did a one credit course um where
they worked on designing this thing for
Mother's Day and then they were flying
mothers for free uh in planes over to se
and so she actually produced a video
that I think you can get on her website
you think they made a video a DVD of the
production of this and you know some of
it's Mulch and you have hay bales and
some of this stuff here is nothing more
than black plastic that they put over
the top to ediate the grass so it gets
bleached you know if you just exclude
light from grass it gets white or yellow
depending on how long I mean eventually
if you leave it on long enough it'll get
brown but if you just leave it on for a
little while basically what you're
looking at is light starved grass so you
can do all kinds of things
with different shades of green and maybe
mulches and there's some hay bales here
and this was an area that she we we
killed out and they did a mapole or
something I think they it's a mapole in
the
middle this is along the coast of Oregon
they did a little Continental map here
with grass around it thought that was
kind of
interesting how about grass you can
wear right nean Marcus did a big thing a
few years ago on Garden at Tire made
some grass shoes again you know nothing
more than you know matted onto burlap
stapled on to a shoe this is again a
large sheet of burlap and you can see
here again the use of black plastic to
give that leopard effect by doing a
light excl excluding light from the
grass so you get that kind of leopard
effect on the grass coat itself here's
the garden party uh ad that nean Marcus
was running again hat pocket book
shoes how about
jewelry this is one of my favorites that
Craig sent me you can here's this little
guy making jewelry Spritz in his little
bit of grass making a fashion statement
here with a little tough of grass on the
end or grass Knuckles instead of brass
knuckles now here's what you need to do
these things burlap cheap grass seed and
Peep moss and you can make a
bag this is one of Marsh's students made
a grass pocket book here's a grass dress
how long would that stay green though
like or alive uh as long as you water
really if you put Miracle Grow on it I
bet you you could if you spritzed it
with Miracle Grow once a week and mow it
I'm sure it would live several months if
you gave it hanging out on the this be
something you put on the clothes line
when it's raining
right instead of pulling the clothes in
from the clothes line put it out there
when it's raining so would the soil run
I mean there's no soil oh okay yeah
soil's
overrated the burlap the burlap little
bit of pee
Moss we grow sod we have an I mean this
is not I mean yeah this is really cool
but we've been doing this for the last
20 years on black plastic accelerated
sod production is very popular in Europe
they'll use uh you know compost at about
an eighth of an inch throw a ton of
grass on it make a grass mat and use it
for go Ms or other areas that wear out
really quickly on the cross fields and
soccer fields so grass doesn't need soil
no wow not if you're prepared to give it
water and nutrients over the
top you ever seen it grow into cracks in
the sidewalk well yeah that's
true see how easy my job is so how about
some devices these are somewhat
whimsical
um this is this is Whimsical but it's
actually a reality what $112 million
will buy you this is the University of
Phoenix stadium out uh outside of
Phoenix Arizona where they often play
the Super Bowl and the national
championship and they wanted to be able
to have a grass field inside now I was
involved in 1994 at at the Pontiac
Silverdome project when I was working at
Michigan State
University where we developed an indoor
grass system to play the World Cup when
the World Cup soccer was here in
1994 and um uh basically what we found
is really grass can't live in these Dome
stadiums for more than 30 days so we've
had that's why you see a lot of
retractable Dome stadiums they got them
in Arizona and Seattle Milwaukee's got
one where the Dome Houston where the
where you know you open the dome for the
grass and then you close it so that the
creatures can be comfortable when
they're in there well they decided an
alternative to doing that in Phoenix is
to slide the field in and
out and there you go the field takes
about an hour and 40 minutes it's on
this massive structure here on railroad
tracks takes about an hour and 40
minutes to move in and out so when
they're not using it it sits outside and
basking in the sun with a little bit of
water and and when they want it they
roll it in
oh okay so next time you watch a game in
Arizona that's what you get of course
these are good uses for lawn mowers the
redneck riding mower how about
that grass
bike really nice with a grass jacket
there the integration of apparel and
functional
travel the bug the grass
Accord somebody that's probably smoking
some of the grass that using a little
bit of grass dashboard how about a grass
grass board instead of a dashboard grass
on the seats
dude how about this take your shoes off
walk on grass all
day and then there's uh one of the more
interesting things we tried this past
year is the use of grass as a fish
film this is some work that was done a
number of years ago where they took a a
grass canvas literally grew it on burlap
which is what we did and then um made it
dark and then exposed the uh this
picture here and then shot the picture
on the grass so that it would ultimately
develop the picture right because you'd
have different shades of light over the
top of the grass and that the picture
itself would develop over
time this is a again a grass canvas with
a overhead projector and a a Plexi
plexiglass pan of water dripping down
and so you had Stripes uh on the pan and
water dripping in and you could see it
on the grass
canvas here are some pictures uh again
big grass canvas with a picture shown on
it same here this is how it looked one
that looked was developed and here's the
one Marsha did in the library uh last
year this is uh two sheets of
burlap with Ry grass planted on it
tacked to some
2x4s put together you can see the wood
that's suspending
it and then we took a
projector computer image and shown
Gandhi on it we had this big black box I
don't have a lot of pictures of it I
should have it but I can tell you it was
the talk of the campus for about a two
we period because it had these little
black hole it had these little holes
drilled in this big black draped uh
display that was I don't know I don't
know how wide was it 12 about 12 by 10
12 by 10 kids could go up to it and look
and you had all these Gandhi peaceful uh
sayings all the way around it and
eventually it we think we need a
brighter light I think that's one of the
things it didn't develop as good as we
liked it did develop a little bit but
what we wound up doing and I don't have
the picture of it is one day I went in
there
with was who was the woman Christine and
we kind of brushed it and we used a
little bit of Lawn Lawn you know lawn
patterns with the same with the um with
the uh developing of the image on the
thing as well and after we took it all
away you could actually see Gandhi's
face which was prettyy cool
so with that as opposed to uh keep off
the grass my hope is that you know today
and Beyond this that you go and use
grass as a way of I don't know
expressing yourself as it as it's been
for me uh stretching
myself here's Fred I can't I want I
can't do this without saying thanks to
Craig if you don't know Craig you'll
some of you may have him today this is
Craig's dog Fred and there is nothing
looks as good as a black and white dog
on a nice green grass with a little bit
of
dandel so I hope that you have a
wonderful day today and I know you will
have a lot of people out there like
Danielle and Alex and Craig and Mara who
will be able to answer some of your
questions but one of the things that I
like the most about what this invol
involvement with this has not always
been that you know it's a way of kind of
expressing yourself artistically which I
never knew I had the ability to do any
of that um but also that it's living in
sustainable art this is not the kind of
work that has to damage the environment
any way working with the environment
it's an easy way to make sustainable art
that a lot of people can enjoy that you
don't necessarily have to go to a museum
to see so my hope is that you have all
those thoughts when you're doing this
work and really I think you're going to
have a wonderful day it could be kind of
sticky hot out there today too but as
figures after been raining all this time
do do you have any questions before I
turn it back over to
Mara Felder what kind of grass on the
jewelry what kind of grass on the
jewelry you know I don't really know I
think some of it was Moss but most
likely it's Ry grass because it grows so
quick it's pretty almost disposable I
mean it grows on
burlap we grow it on your hat that's not
a bad idea isn't
say no to Grass N I can't say no to
grass so it's no dirt it's
just grass on yeah grass on burlap right
just seed it really heavy and whatever
the hell at
it it's burlap and then M and I think we
didn't use Pete Moss for the CI thing no
that was just that was just gr on burlap
I mean burlap has a wall water hole I
mean it has a structure to hold water
now there different types of burlap too
we had a couple layers of burlap we had
did you have a couple of
layers yeah go ahead about how long does
that take to grow a
week it's really amazing just pointing
out weed it just because you think you
lay it down evenly and end up with a few
spots so we had to go back SE a little
bit more
water really beautiful just this perfect
in the middle of winter this green block
GR in prepared
the did you grow it on the 2x4s or did
you tack it on after we we tacked it on
before you tacked it on before
frame so it'll so the grass will hang on
a vertical surface it'll stick it Roots
right to the
burlap but how do you make it stick
initially a vertical no no no well we
grow it flat okay got and then we lift
it and once it gets some structure to it
you mow it once it gets some stru and
that's one one of the things that's
critical is when you're doing some of
these things it's really important to
mow the grass a little bit because that
encourages it to get dense it's somewhat
counterintuitive but by clipping it it
gets thicker it causes it to grow more
laterally as opposed to Growing straight
up how long did you expose it to the
overhead projector to get the was it a
week we need it to get brighter and we
need we needed a brighter
light yeah this might be kind of stretch
but um the whole idea with green roofs
is there any way that the grass instead
of siding we can possibly grow grass on
the side of our house
yes yes I mean it won't live unless you
give it water now you could you know use
the you can use warm seedson grasses in
some places where they won't need much
water right um but there's no reason to
think you couldn't just get established
on the and attack it to the side of your
house good or they can make a a matrix
structure of some sort that you could
use I mean they build straw houses right
straw bale
houses certainly sod roues are not
unique they've been doing them forever
right and the thing that's nice about it
is you can actually go up there and sit
as opposed to having SE them that you
can't touch or it'll
die it's it can be a little bit
functional as well which is what the
idea was at Lincoln
Center yeah we were talking earlier
about like the picture
the
mat no I actually think that's um that's
uh structural it's like gravel with soil
mixed in that they grew grass over the
top of so it infiltrates it I've seen
some things in parking yes you do and
they don't work very good it doesn't I
don't think so we've tried that a few
times and we haven't found that it works
so good yeah but it's I mean grass I
mean we really have the data now there's
no reason why we can't have grass
parking lots the trick with grass
parking lots is um we think that the tra
70% of a parking lot are the spaces
about 30% of the traveling lanes so the
traveling lanes will be something other
than grass so we'll make the parking
spaces grass and then what's critical
is that you
um that
you have the spaces on a diagonal
because what we've learned is when you
turn on the grass especially when it's
wet you can tear it so you want to be
able to smoothly go in and park the car
like that but other than that it's just
it's this gravel grass grown on gravel Y
and we watered it for a week when we
first put it in and we we have done less
than nothing to
we've done less I'm not we've done
virtually nothing to it and it's been
there we've had it out there for four
years we've been driving on it and
parking on it for four years now so you
could do that for your driveway
absolutely without question mow with
though don't you you could mow it but
you don't have to no is there grass that
grows a determinant height no well yes
grass will grow to a certain height
it'll flower if you don't mow it right
you'll get these wispy seed heads but
you can mow it a little bit so that it
doesn't flow and some grasses grow very
slowly and then flop
over so it's a special kind of grass
that grows on the gravel that you've
developed no we use tall fescue the same
stuff you're going to sod your things
with today really yeah I'm telling you
do I sound intelligent I'm telling you
you don't have to be smart to do this
this is as easy as it
gets I mean just a little sea a little
water and you got it
thanks very much I hope you have a great
day