This is a production of Cornell
University.
Welcome to the show. Uh we, as you can
see, we've got a couple of Cornell
folks, uh bunch of Cornell folks today.
Kyle Wickings, our soil insect
ecologist. Kyle will talk to us in a
minute. Um this is May, so we're gonna,
you know, we're going to get into this,
but um I want to say this is the insect
mashup show, Carl, for the podcast
listeners and the people who watch the
video. Everything you see here we are
going to talk about. So we are going to
get an hour's worth of information into
30 minutes. You're going to have to play
this on half speed to be able to keep
up. But of course we'll start with a
good dog picture. Uh Miranda Robin
Robinson and uh Dakota who made quite a
splash at the Mitsubishi Electric
Classic. This was a Champions Tour event
down over at TPC Sugarloaf. Um, so it
looked like that dog was uh playing
around with everybody, walking around,
had a pass. Love when the dogs get
profile. And of course, M. Casey putting
barley to work, cutting cups. I know
what it feels like. I cut 18 the other
day for the turf grass class. This is
out in Seven Canyons in Arizona. I've
been thinking a lot about automation a
lot, and we're going to touch it,
believe it or not, Kyle. I'm going to
put you on the spot a little bit to ask
you to speculate, but we start
continuing to see every time you look up
this week, the LPGA is playing out in
Ivans, Utah, the outside of St.
George's, and it's all mowed by these
automated mowers. This is the Black
Desert Classic, uh, down there in the
high desert of southern Utah. And then
on the left, something simple that again
I would have appreciated this week, not
having to cut 18 cups is getting a
DeWalt drill on this automated cup
cutter. Very Kyle, you got to look into
this for grub sampling, brother. Think
of all the years you've broken your back
just trying to break in to this thing.
Looks like it's mounted on a skateboard.
Yeah, it's it's on a nice metal pallet
because, you know, you just turn the
drill on and you push it down and it
works. Who knows? Anyway, like an augur,
huh? Above normal temperatures. We had a
warm week, right? Some places almost 12
degrees uh above normal. So, obviously
the season moved along quite a bit.
Soils are coming along with it. You're
in the New York metro area. You're
getting close to a lot of your soil
fungicide drenches for uh soil pathogen
problems. You're getting, you know, near
that. Certainly down. you're you're at
that at Philly and likely near that in
the New York metropolitan area. And
Carl, with that, we're starting to see
the real first spike where we're seeing
some growth. Um, let me ask you, how are
the plots going? How many times have you
mowed so far this year? So, so we just
put the first mow on tall fescue. And
this is one of the interesting things.
The the tall fescue is is slower to
green up and to start growing than the
adjacent pennial ryrass. I mean, the
ryrass has been probably for a week and
a half now. it's it's ready and and
going, but the tall fescue lags behind.
So, this model, you know, probably
reflects more that the tall fescue
growth sort of slow, maybe even like
bluegrass, Kentucky bluegrass, too. Um
whereas the the ryrass is probably in
that moderate getting close to high.
Okay. Right about now. Yeah. Perfect.
And that's why we like ryrass for
hightra areas in the spring. It's
exactly what you want uh this time of
year. Um it's been a little drier along
the southern coast down in Delm Marva,
Philly. Uh they're certainly had a
deficit the last week, but that's going
away. I think everybody's going to get a
little bit of moisture. We're going to
get quite a bit of moisture. And I
picked up on the dollar spot risk
estimate going up, right? Very
interesting little blip there. I was
waiting for this to happen. You know,
you got all this moisture in the system
now and you just waiting for a little
warm weather to kick it from pink snow
mold into dollar spot world. And so I
think this is a good time to start to
see if you can wait, right? It does this
model, you know, click in and say go now
because right now, right, Carl, you can
save sprays by holding off that first
spray at the and it looks like it's
going to be cool and wet moving forward.
So we're going to maybe grow out of it.
It might be some pressure. Uh but it is
something to consider when you think
about the M model. Thoughts on this,
Carl? Yeah, I think the the forecasting
element is really interesting here. You
see this increase in the slope of the
line, whether it's our model or the
Smith Karns. Yeah. And that's related to
sort of outbreaks. But if you see that
slope go up and then 3 days out, four
days out, it's cooling off and it's
coming back down. That's where I go
maybe, maybe we can be a little bit
That's not what we're seeing here,
though. No. And we're seeing that 7-day
average, that green line is steadily
growing up. So, I see that and I go,
probably not time to risk it in this
case. you got the high value turf you
want. So again, again, you know, we use
these a lot of times for the large area
applications, your fairways and things
like that. It's weed control time and
you can see the ideal conditions are
starting to build there. This is uh a
few days from now in in uh May 6. So you
can see up the Hudson Valley and
certainly most of south of the
Pennsylvania border with New York is
good to go on controlling these things.
And we're starting to see the
pollinators uh risk go up as well, Carl.
So, um here's the setup for you. Uh it
it it's that time of year where the lawn
is naturally flowering. We've got a guy
uh our pollinator expert here. I want to
do a quick hit on the no since it's mo
too. Yeah. And and we've talked about
this a couple years now, Frank, but the
idea is that we want to promote uh
beneficial habitat with this no M. Let
the grass grow, let everything flower.
Um, and I asked the the uh the AI I use,
hey, draw me a picture of what the
public perceives are the benefits of nom
versus a traditional lawn. And for those
not watching, there's uh we got the
flowers, sunflowers, a bunch of
different stuff in there. Butterflies,
bees on top, there's earthworms, there's
a bunch of stuff in the soil, too. And
in the traditional yard, there's a
couple ants running. Ants and worms.
Ants and worms. Worm. And there's a
worm. And and Kyle, you've done some
research on this. Everybody thinks about
the above ground insects, the
butterflies and the pollinators, but
you've looked at the below ground soil
biota. What's running around in there?
When you've looked at plots like a Nom
plot and a traditional yard, is this the
kind of thing you see or do you see
something different?
Yeah, it's actually the So far, it's the
exact
opposite. I mean, I don't obviously
we're looking at a traditional yard. The
yards we're looking at are really meant
to be similar to like a larger upstate
New York lawn, an acre or more. So
really, there's no inputs going into the
research plots we're working with other
than mowing. And we're looking at
everything from weekly mowing all the
way to an annual mow that happens in
fall, including no mo is one of our our
treatments. So, but comparing like a
weekly versus no mo, they don't really
look like this. In fact, it's kind of
the opposite. So, uh, there's a lot more
smaller critters that aren't shown on
here that we're kind of focusing on like
springtails, mites, and things like
that. Below ground. Below ground, right?
Because the focus, right, Carl, is on
the pollinators uh, above ground.
Comments on that, Kyle. Um, you know,
we're going to cover this a little bit,
but I want to get your two cents on not
mowing for the month as a way of
servicing pollinators.
Yeah. I so we got we've got data
flowering data presence absence of
flowering pre-post mowing and we've also
got some data on uh flower density like
five times throughout the season for the
last two years and you do get a spike in
May when you do that but what happens
after that is some of those nom plots
end up having less flowering than all
the other treatments do okay there's
some backfiring going on in the plan I
guess you know okay so you so so there
is some evidence that by not mowing for
a little
there is a benefit and that's just
probably a disturbance of the canopy
stuff as well, right? They start to make
it a habitat as as well as a uh as well
as just a place where they feed
in the above ground stuff. Yeah, I think
so. And we do see it show up in the
flowering presence that's there, but you
know, we see it also in if you uh mow
every two weeks. So it's it's not
necessarily it's just a a full month of
holding off on mowing. But yeah, it's
really what happens after that for the
remaining months where Nomay starts to
look kind of raggedy. So Okay. All
right. And and look raggedy also by by
not flowering and continually flowering
throughout the year, right? I mean when
we think about pollinators, we think
about that consistency of feed
throughout the season, right? Yeah.
Yeah. And I mean I think the idea when
this came about Nomo May in Europe, it
was well this is a window of time when
you need to provide those pollen
resources, right? I don't think that's
necessarily the month you would need it
everywhere. But uh that was the idea.
You know, we don't necessarily need
flowers later. You need it to line up
with when pollinators need those
resources coming out of overwintering
and spring. So that's really the idea,
but it just seems so sight specific
depending on what flowering plants you
actually have uh in the system. And you
know for us it's like bindweed and a
whole bunch of other problematic things.
So you know the other part of this is
the social aspect of it right this sort
of touches on your sort of view of the
lawn. Uh and people will consider it
ethical. Some people will judge other
people who don't cut their grass. Uh
there's a whole lot of sociological
things that I'm sure if I went anywhere
near social media, you could stir it
right up uh if you wanted to with this
particular topic. All right. So, so um
we also, you know, this tool, right,
that I passed over about this really
just follows a couple of the common
flowering weeds in the lawn. And and it
really is something you tend to think
about more in the spring because we
apply so many things in the spring,
right? We apply our pre-emergent, you
apply your early grub control, you apply
your fertilizer, you apply your
broadleaf, we I mean you you're making
on a lawn, you're potentially making
four applications of products to at a
time when the lawn will be likely
flowering. So that creates an issue. The
other issue is with rainfall coming,
man, the dumps with the heat feels like
we're getting dumped on. This is our
runoff model looking at the next bunch
of days. And there's definitely a window
in there from the 4th to the to the 7th
where you don't really want to be
applying. And statewide on the 6th
except for the northern reaches of the
state, right? This puts us to let me
look at my calendar. The six this puts
us into Tuesday. you know, Monday,
Tuesday, you really, you know, you're
starting your week as a landscaping
crew. You want to be very careful if
you're going out there in these regions
where the runoff risk is high. Now,
remember, this is a model, right, Carl?
It's mostly wrong, but sometimes useful,
right? It's always wrong, sometimes
useful. Always wrong, sometimes useful.
But how would you internalize this if
you had a spray on this day in the areas
where it was red? Yeah, I I for sure
high slope areas near water bodies when
when we see red consistently for several
days and when you look at just a weather
forecast on weather.com or whatever,
man, it's not going to be good to to
spray. You're going to lose not only
that running off into water bodies and
causing, you know, water quality issues,
but just effectiveness of the spray.
Like if you're going to go out and treat
for ABW adults or something and it's
raining and that material is going to
move, man, is it better to get maybe
little worse timing and leave the
product there where it's supposed to go.
Yeah. Or I got to if Monday's my spray
day, I got to spray on Monday. Kyle,
from your perspective with, you know,
maybe the first ABW adult treatment
we're going to get into here a little
bit, what would your thoughts be on,
man, I see peak adult activity, but it's
gonna rain, you know, should I put that
out? Yeah, that honestly that is exactly
what we're dealing with. I've put off an
adulticide application for a trial twice
now because of that. Like we're just
playing leapfrog in between rain showers
and you know those adulticides, they've
got to stay dry for like at least 12
hours. So if you can't find a 12-h hour
window, uh you could be washing it off
where it needs to be. So uh that's
exactly what we're dealing with. And
I've talked to a number of
superintendents who are like, man, I
don't know if I should wait longer. You
know, they're already delaying it a
little bit. And you know, a little bit
later is better than a little bit early
with these adult signs if you're going
to do them, but trying to be surgical
with them is so much harder when you've
got chance of rain throughout the day.
So, this is great. I wasn't even
expecting this and that and that's good.
Now, Kyle, here's the first quick hit
for you. This came up the other day when
we were out at Delhigh. Uh, somebody
said, "Hey, can I use my Roomba mower,
my autonomous mower to deal with
earthworm castings?" What say you?
Interesting. I've never seen them drive
over earthworm casts before. I'd like to
see that. I mean, they mow 24 hours a
day. I mean, they basically say, what
did he say, Carl? Uh, 12 on. No, no. 16
on, eight off. Yeah. Something something
like that. And And I'm I'm curious about
the the mechanism of the blade. It's a
razor blade. It's not smashing like a
real mower where you're sort of getting
the castings in between the reel and the
bed knife. It's just a razor blade. And
when we looked at the fairway over there
at Delhigh, we don't see the smearing
that you get with the real mower on the
fairways. And sort of and Steve Kurt at
Tesarora was like, man, that that might
be something useful. Um, and I tell you,
Carl, nobody's I'm I'm sure somebody's
thought of this. It can't be Steve and a
bunch of us standing out of Delhigh
coming up with this idea. But I got to
tell you to a certain extent. I'm I'm
just I just want put a little brush. Put
like four or five little things just to
go. All you got to do is knock it down
cuz I think there was consensus that the
blades will wear quicker if they're
hitting. I mean, these things are really
like old. You got to be old time to
remember the old Wilkinson double-edged
razor blades, right? That our fathers
and grandfathers probably shaved with,
right? That's what these things cut the
grass with. So, Kyle, here's our that's
our research idea uh for next year.
We'll start we'll start laying it out uh
right now because we have plenty of
areas that have worms and these are like
reliable solutions that solve a lot of
it. You don't have to have them on every
fairway. you just have them on the
fairways that uh where you have these
problems. All right, where are we on the
progress of preventing this vertebrate
damage, right? I let's you know,
everybody's talking to me about grubs.
I, you know, every place I cut in, even
if it's not peeled back, I see a soil
insect. So, I know there's grubs
everywhere, Kyle. I mean, my sense is
there's just grubs everywhere. The
populations have been pretty good, but I
don't have any trouble with those little
buggers. until these guys come along.
Where are we at with solving this? Are
we thinking about playing Led Zeppelin
Stairway to Heaven like it was suggested
many years ago? Where are we at? Well,
we still want to try that, but
everything we've tried so far with it,
it the the skunks and raccoons just
haven't played ball with us. They uh
don't show up for the concert and they
go elsewhere. So, that's that's been the
problem. But yeah, trying to use
something like soil vibration sound
itself or some kind of a deterrent or
mask on on these populations of white
grubs has been what we we've been trying
to get at. But yeah, getting a captive
population that wants to behave and and
take part in your trial has been the
main issue. Yeah, it's it's like human
subjects. It's like you got to go
through a whole bunch of stuff because,
you know, you got to treat the animals
right. All right, Car Carl, here we are.
We're to ABW.
Yeah. So, so Kyle, Kyle and I were
talking a little bit before we got on,
Frank, about um you know, when we look
at the the degree day triggers or the
phenological indicators for when is peak
adult activity and and for those who who
maybe don't know what we're talking
about here, annual bluegrass weevil sort
of the almost the best time to get them
when they're all sort of synchronous in
their population is when they come out
of overwintering and adults are moving
around. Some move early, some move late,
but there's sort of a curve that looks
like what I got here. Sort of a sigma a
sign curve here. there's some peak and
usually we think 110 120 grown degree
days or half green half golden for
Cynthia is when they hit that peak uh
and when I looked at the data just
yesterday oh man it's about going to be
about 110 degree days here in Ithaca
today uh I see half green half gold
there in the forynthia and then I
checked this morning on weevil track
which is a conglomerate of a bunch of
research like researchers like Kyle
taking scouting data and Kyle just says
hey it's it's stage one peak adult
activity in Corning So Kyle, all of
these things are lining up. The degree
days, the the phenological, you see it
out there. Um, so right now on paper it
looks like, hey, everything's just a a
standard typical traditional year. Is
that what you're seeing out when when
you guys are doing your sampling at at a
variety of courses? Yeah, we've mostly
been looking up on courses up along Lake
Ontario and then in the southern tier.
And um it did not look like this
originally. You know, things really
weren't lining up. We had degree days
advancing
uh at a certain pace and we couldn't
find weevils that seemed to be the
population really didn't look like what
you'd expect. We were well past 50 uh
degree days, closer to 90 and we were
still struggling to find adult weevils
on some courses that we knew had
problems with them last year. So, uh, it
things just seem out of sync. And when
it took comes to Foryia, you know, we
found so many FYIA this year that had
some kind of freeze damage on them that
there's very light uh, canopy on them.
So, what flowering they had, it was
really hard to assess much of what was
going on. And that's all over the place.
We just found really raggedy looking for
cythia. And the ones that were had a
better canopy, we couldn't find a lot of
consistency. There were some that had
green already, some that, you know, full
gold looked kind of questionable. So,
that didn't seem to line up that well
either. But, I'd say starting tail end
of last week, we last week is about when
we hit 110 to 120 like you've got here,
Carl, for most of the courses we work
on. And, uh, we started to see adult
activities seem like it was sinking up a
little bit. And I'd say we're kind of at
that peak activity window in the
Fingerlakes now. So, uh, yeah, it was
interesting. I look back through our
records and that same window happened
the first week of May last year, too.
So, okay. As messy as things seemed
coming out of winter, we didn't know
what was going on and nothing seemed to
be lining up, but it seems like it's
maybe behaving a little better now with
the delta. It's funny, Carl, haven't we
heard Andy Wilson, our pal at director
of aronomy at at Beth Page talk about
after all the years of keeping data,
he's basically got it nailed down to the
same week every year. for for his laral
his first laral application. Yes. And
that's one of the the next questions for
you, Kyle, is we sort of best management
practice is sort of to do the you know,
you've called it the three-step program.
You do an adult early because you know
that's when they're all coming out and
then you when when you first sort of do
the scouting and see the larve, then you
hit them with a larvaide. That's sort of
the first two components. And we think
that as you go throughout the year,
there's more
asynchronicity in the populations. But
the Beth Pageige guys haven't done an
adulticide for I don't know 10 years
Frank they only well they got pythroidid
resistance and I wonder if some of that
resistance might be gone if it's not
worth testing it again to see if the
populations built up but yeah they have
been using once they got the word you
know tournament golf course the black
course once they got the word that they
were resistant they've moved to other
strategies very effectively
and and Kyle you've you've looked into a
couple different treatment programs the
last few a couple of which have no
adulticide early and just a larvaide and
then another one later in the year and
you're finding that works pretty well,
right? Maybe contrary to what we used to
think about, hey, you got to get that
adult adult down. Yeah. Yeah. The work
we've been doing like a lot of other
turf entomologists and actually a lot of
other entomologists in general has been
looking at uh the new active uh
isocycloserum the what's going to be
plazelin from Senta. There's been a lot
of advertisement. What are they going to
call it? Planazelin.
That's the chemical name. What are they
going to call it? That's going to be the
product name. Oh, really? Plenaz. Oh,
that's right. We talked about this
during the state park thing. Okay. Yeah.
Yeah. They've just started advertising
it. So, it's it's uh it's kind of out
there now. But yeah, so that the attempt
there was to try and break this up into
sort of a two-stage window where you're
not so dependent on just going after
adulticides, you know, move away from
that. Um I guess you know we did try
some later stage larvicides only just
one application and it it can be
effective. We did find that even as
surgical as we were trying to be with
scouting and timing of everything like
really intense scouting we still had a
little bit of dam more damage show up
with that one than we saw if we did go
into with uh some kind of an earlier
larvaite as well. Um but we got
significant knockdown of the weevils. So
I I think it really if you put all the
eggs in that later stage larvicide
basket, it definitely does require
really careful scouting, but there's
certainly some courses that are really
successful at it. So yeah, the so the
scouting aspect is is one thing you'll
say and all the other anomologists will
say is you got to scout at your golf
course. Each golf course is going to be
different. Understanding how many adults
when you're doing the soap flushes means
peak is like again that's different
course by course. And when I think of of
uh you know courses like the Cornell
golf course here, Kyle, you've been on
there. We've got different types of
overwintering sites. Some meadow areas
out in the middle of the open. You've
got the woodland areas, very shady. Um
do you see superintendent who will do
scouting in these two areas and apply at
different times and and specifically out
and say, "Hey, I gota, you know, maybe
on Monday I'm going to have to go out in
the meadow areas because it's warmer and
then maybe a week later." Do you see
this? And is this a best practice that
you're recommending to folks? That's a
great question. We we've seen that kind
of a stagger before. Again, it starts to
sink up a little bit over time, but and
narrow, but we've seen a stagger like
that where we were finding them way out
in the rough on one green around one
green and on another they they were much
closer. And I don't know if it always
relates to how close the overwintering
site was necessarily, but we do see
that. Um, especially if there's one a
green that's much more shaded than
another that's exposed. But, uh, again,
back to like these really narrow windows
of time when everybody's trying to get
their tank mixes together and just make
one shot in spring for these
applications. I haven't seen anybody
consider trying to break up. They're
just trying to pick the date that would
be best for all of the spots.
uh that's what I've seen most of the
time, but they're definitely considering
that variability that we're seeing on
the um I mean I only know a handful that
actually go out and vacuum sample or do
soap flushes to try and gauge that, but
they're aware that there's variability
in the development uh of the adults. I
just I just saw a paper the other day,
Kyle, looking at comparing scouting
methods and actually concluded
surprisingly that the soap flush was
better than the vacuum method depending
on the height of the grass. uh that that
I saw in that particular paper. But I
want to go back to so I think you know
the soap flushing that we've been using
at Beth Page for the last decade or 15
years continues to be the easy peasy.
You got a you know two and a half gallon
jug. You put water in it. You squirt
some lemon joy. Continues to be the the
the surfactant soap of choice to
irritate them. Must be something in the
lemon chemical that's irritating them.
Um but I want to talk about the
overwintering sites. Uh, I know you
played around with this in the past. Um,
and I know, listen, when I was when I
heard Carl say this overwintering thing,
it reminded me, and man, only the old
guys are going to know what I'm talking
about now. Harry Nimchek, the old Ohio
State, the late Ohio State enemologist,
used to used to recommend walking in the
woods with the granular insecticide to
kill the, you know, in the overwintering
sites with Durban. We were probably
buying Durban back then or dazinon or
some some chemical. But I mean that's
where we've come from. People were so
desperate for a really long time. I mean
Pat Vidam spent her entire career
studying this one organism, right? So
it's not like we're making it into and
Ben proclaimed last year, yeah, I'm not
even worried about this no more. Right?
So so I want to hear about the over the
ability. Let's revisit the little bit of
work you've played around with in in
disrupting or messing around with o
potentially meadow areas or
overwintering sites that then would
affect damage and population the next
year. Yeah, I'll just mention first you
Dan Peek did some good work showing how
far on average into those natural areas
ABW seems to overwinter and it's a
pretty good depth in. I mean, it tapers
off quickly, but it would be a really
hard amount of space to actually cover
effectively, especially because you
almost have to make the assumption that
they're just kind of all along those
natural areas. You can't just surgically
pick the area, right? Not to mention the
whole non-target effect side of things,
but That's exactly right. Yeah. Yeah.
But, uh, yeah, so we we played around
with it a little bit. I was just really
curious how the way we manage,
especially grassy natural areas, how we
manage those might influence how well
the weevils overwinter. And we found you
can't really improve their you can't
really get better overwinter mortality
of the weevils, but you can make it
worse. You can make them overwinter more
successfully.
And the way to do that is leave all the
residue in there, like mow it and leave
it sitting or just leave it tall
standing. So getting that residue out of
the natural areas makes that a lot more
inhospitable of a habitat for the
weevils to overwinter in. So, I don't
know how common that practice is, but
taking the residue off of it, you got a
lot more violent temperature spikes that
happen in winter in those areas. I would
call it a best practice because if you
really are embracing those areas, you
want them to be as thin and wispy as
possible if there's any chance they can
be in play. So, harvesting the plant
material is the simplest way of mining
the soil for the nutrients that you have
no other way of getting rid of. I mean,
obviously don't want them to leech. Now
listen, I want to wrap up. We got three
minutes and Alrech published this paper
last year, Kyle, and you were talking a
little bit about it with the state park
guys. I want to give you a chance to
talk about th this sort of idea where
you go out on your own golf course and
you sample some soil and you make a
neode brew that you then apply and these
guys have found you get persistence be
for whatever. I'm going to leave this to
you. uh and it seems to be providing uh
some control. Can you talk a little bit
about this? I I grabbed this uh sort of
conglomerate image from the publication.
Yeah. Yeah. I think it's really
interesting. I think this is something I
thought about a lot following up from
Nelson Shields work in field corn and uh
wasn't doing it quite this way where
they were more bringing it back to the
lab and trying to sell their own
neatodes or whatever but uh that the
idea that you can take a population on
site rear it up and reapply it is a
really interesting one and I this was a
really cool paper so I think it shows
that we know that most of these golf
courses have some degree of insect
pathogenic neatode populations on them
so the ability to harness that and
re-releas release them back out is
really cool. I like how they tried it in
the fairways and in the rough, too,
because they're super different areas.
So, um it's pretty cheap to be able to
do like the the materials that that
Albert's showing here are pretty
inexpensive to get. It's definitely a
very different system to be able to to
dial in. We played around with this a
little bit in sod and we found depending
on the soil type, you can get the
nematodeses to persist pretty well even
through sod harvest. So there's there's
some interesting science to this that I
think is uh you know this just jumped
right out at me when you said it because
for years um we've talked about how
almost all these properties have to have
some suppressive effects. They're
looking for this now in the dollar spot
world, right? Ming just published that
paper recently on the potential for
soils to suppress uh pathogens. you
know, the idea that we could do this,
um, I pro I think probably scares a lot
of companies that might, you know, all
of a sudden not be able to do this, but
then I'm sure they'll build an industry
on how to do this automatically at your
property. This may be something to do
with all those hollow time C. See, I'm
wondering why do I got to take plugs?
Why don't I just c I got to c a damn
thing anyway. Bring up plugs, collect
the soil from that. Is that another way
to go here, Kyle? Is it just soil is
soil? Bring your plugs in and use that
to Yeah, we grow grass from it. They
generate putting greens from it. Yep.
Yeah, you can certainly collect those.
We we did that when we uh did some
verification work and brought the plugs
back. So, yeah, that that's certainly
something you can try. Okay. I think a
lot of it is getting, you know, if it's
going to be something that you have
superintendent do versus uh a service
provide like they'll collect rear and
give you your neatodes back versus
something you can just run in your shop
with a cheap cup of uh insect hosts and
then make basically screen out a
solution to spray back out would be
really interesting. I guess where where
it needs to go next is testing that a
lot of different soil types because
we've seen so much variability in how
well they'll persist and establish based
on soil type. I guarantee that stuff all
is thinking about too. So that really
how it's going to work on each Okay. So
as a as a as a last as a last word and
then we're getting out of here. Um are
there I is it pretty much the better the
soil, the more organic matter, the
better balance of air and water, you
know, uh the better neatodes. Uh, and
the worst compacted clay, you know,
dramatic soils, the worst for
nematodeses. Is that sort of easy? Like
if you got a pretty good healthy soil,
quote unquote healthy soil, nematodes
will persist. Yeah, we found that soils
if they persisted best on our highest
organic matter soils, soils that you
amend with sand, you get a little bit
better performance on. So, and compacted
soils, especially the work that we did
on school athletic fields and goal
mouths, doesn't work so well. That's
right. where the soil's compacted. Yeah.
All right, Carl, we made it. Kyle,
the got everything covered. Look, the
insect in insect mashup. The insect
mashup. Yep. All right. Good to see
everybody. Thanks very much. Thanks,
Kyle. Take care, everybody. See you next
week. Take care, guys. This has been a
production of Cornell University on the
web at cornell.edu.