this is a production of Cornell
University for filling break because I
know he's un sabatical now so it's nice
to have a wonderful inection and thank
you for having me here today talk to you
about my work where I'm going to
describe to you how we identified a
tomato receptor that we call felin
sensitive 3 Sensi 3 and it perceives the
pepti like 228 and activates immune
signaling and
tomato and so I just want to huge glad
with project and I want to especially
emphasize there were two post talks in
Greg's lab U Pat Bo and julan B who are
really helpful for this project uh we
couldn't have done any of the work
without CES strickler who's here today
thank you um who was a vir informaticist
who did a lot of uh data mining for us
and also we have two chemistry students
uh Josh pil and inish adori who were
really instrumental in some of our um
development of chemical PRS that I'll
talk to you about um so without that
I'll start by reminding you of the
overview of plant immunity and so we
have on the surface of a plant cell
these pattern recognition receptors or
PRS that are responsible for
perceiving pathogens and I'm going to
use the example of camonis which is a
bacterial pathogen and it has a felin
and a part of that felin is this
conserved region called micro Associated
molecular patterns or Ms that are
perceived by these cell surface
receptors and initiate inter cellular
signaling that include mise Cascades and
that lead to translational reprogramming
that leads to pattern triggered immunity
and this pattern triggered immunity is
important for inhibiting the growth of
pathogen of course pathogens have been
able to usurp the system through the use
of effectors specifically type three
effectors that are injected into the
plant cell by the type two secretion
system and these affectors once they're
inside the South can then interfere with
this pattern trigger immunity and in the
case of AVP and AV PTO two effectors in
ponus that we study in tomato these
specifically inhibit this pattern
recognition receptor complex activity
and so thereby it inhibits pattern
triggered immunity and now of course the
plan has to fight back and so in tomato
these two effectors are recognized by
the resistance protein complex PTO P
that then leads to affector triggered
immunity and um program cell death that
then stops the spread of
pathogen so today I'm going to
specifically focus on this very initial
events of recognition that's happening
on the plant cell
surface so in pattern trigger immunity
we have these cell surface receptors and
these are transmembrane receptors and
the majority of them these the ones I'm
showing today all have intercellular
protein Kinesis and these extracellular
domains so before in the last slide I
had FS2 which is probably the best
characterized ctor in plants for
immunity and so FS2 works with the
co-receptor back one and recognizes flag
22 which is a region of
FL now this is a fairly well conserved
uh receptor throughout plants but there
are several examples of receptors that
are found in very specific plant groups
or families so in the case of the efr
receptor that recognizes L 18 which is
from the elongation Factor Tu of MiG
this is only found in bre casate so
parabox another example of so these are
all examples of these locing rich pees
after light pesis which are indicated in
these little green uh domains we also
have other ones including the um lysm
domain containing proteins such as the
Cs which recognize kiten and I'll bring
up that this was a new receptor that was
just published yesterday um in plant
Immunology so this actually recognizes
LPS Li polysaccharides and it's receptor
is called Lore and it's a lectin estain
FR
receptes and so what's key and what's
sort of concerned in all of these is
that Downstream since these are all
protein chases they activate mes
Cascades they um include transcriptional
reprogramming and this all leads to your
basal
defense and so I want to talk a little
bit more about these two uh pepti is
called FL 22 that I already mentioned
and this other new peptide that was only
identified about a year and a half ago
from uh tomato cly 228 and this is also
from
felin and so for I'm step back for a
second and talk a little bit about
humanin receptors so it's been known
that there's actually two felin
receptors in Maman systems you have an
extracellular receptor called tlr5 that
recognizes one portion of felin and you
have an intercellular protein complex
that recognizes second portion of
theel what's kind of cool is actually if
you look at the structure and what the
Tomato receptors seem to recognize we
actually again have two portions the
flag 22 region that's recognized by LS 2
and we have a second region flag 228
that's recognized by a previously
unknown receptor
fs3 and so one early hypothesis when we
first identified this new man was well
this could actually both of these
peptides could be recognized by the same
protein so in other words the Tomato FS
to could just be modified in such a way
as to recognize both so we tested the
hypothesis pretty early on and what we
could find was in fact when you silence
Eis 2 and tomato and you treat with 522
you see a reduced response to this
peptide but there's no difference when
you treat with the flag 228 peptide so
this seemed to provide evidence that in
fact we have two different receptors in
tomato that are recognizing the same
protein but just different portions of
so just to give you some evidence that
flag 228 actually is functioning as a m
so that it's actually inducing a
transcriptional change in the plants so
um Anan rosley in our lab who actually
gave a talk I think back in the fall he
was uh did a lot of experiments working
with uh man juers tomato and looking at
the
transcript and so I just want to
acknowledge J Worley actually did a
reanalysis of some of this data and
that's what I'm showing you today
what he did is that what we see is that
looking at the number of genes induced
in tomato upon treatment with flag 228
we have more than
2200 but if we look and divide further
treatments such as when we treat with
sudam monus florescence which is a PTI
inducer 86 of the% of the genes that are
transcriptionally upregulated are
overlapping with the genes that are
upregulated with flag
228 so this sort of suggests that one of
the major pants in Flores is probably
felin again flag 228 treatment is giving
us that same
response when we treat with a a disarm
strain of Cy path ofart tomato DC 3000
we see that 90% of the genes that are
upregulated are overlapping again with
the like in je and this percentage goes
down in the fully bual 3000 because that
as I showed you previously is sort of
suppressing the PTI
induction and then if we don't if we
have a strain that doesn't deliver
affectors and doesn't have a fuelin it's
pretty much escaping recognition we're
not really getting an induction of PTI
in gen so when we looked at this
evidence this gave us um some confidence
that 228 treatment was inducing uh a
response in
tomato and so we were interested in
maybe figuring out what was going on and
I happened to be involved in a project
where we were screening um tomato
heirloom cultivars to see if they had
variation in their response to different
Ms so we had included flag 22 and
another peptide cs22 but I'm showing you
here the data for flag 228 treatment and
what I want to emphasize here is we saw
that there was one line yellow pair that
was tested that seemed to have really
really reduced responses to fight
228 and so I wondered was this an
anomaly what was going on and could we
actually find other cultivars that were
in fact having a IAL
response and so I went through and
screened about 200 different tomato
cultivars and also wild species of
tomato and what I could find was
actually several uh cultivars and a few
wild species EXs that had this reduced
response to flag 228
treatment and so again we have this
yellow pair tomato we have two pimpell
folium accession so this is the one of
the closest relatives to Tomato but it's
a wild species and then we had all of
these different tomato cultur bars that
all showed this extremely reduced
response and in fact when you look at
the response it really isn't anything
there that's just background and so we
were very excited and decided this
really set us up for a really nice
genetics
approach where I used uh yellow pair
fvar the non-responder as one of my
parents and the sanum Pilla fum La 1589
as my other
parent what was really nice is we
actually have genomes of both parents so
actually made the genetics really really
nice later on um so we have is we
actually did a a cross and looked at the
phenotype of the
f1s and so what we see if we treat the
flag 22 for either yellow pair the other
parent La 1589 or the F1 hybrid they all
respond equally well to FL 22 but now
when we treat the flight
228 yellow peir is completely
insensitive to the
but the LA 1589 and the F1
respond so now this set us up to do a
bul segregate
analysis so I showed you the phenotype
of the F1 when we went to the F2 we had
a nice segregation of the phenotype
where we had responsive plants and
non-responsive plants and so we pulled
the DNA from the responsive plants and
the idea was is that if we could go and
sequence the genomes we wanted to look
specifically for regions of the genomes
where we had Snips that corresponded to
only the yellow pair parent but not to
the other La 1589 parent and again
because we had the genome sequences for
both of these this actually ended up
being fairly
straightforward and so this is where
Susie comes in so we developed this uh
analysis pipeline I just want to walk
you through it so we again grouped the
susceptible plants and then we sent the
DNA off for um Next Generation aluminous
sequencing and then did sequence
processing of that data where she
trimmed the reads and filtered and then
she mapped those reads onto her yellow
pareno so that she could call those
Snips and then what she ended up doing
is looking for Regions where the senum
from Pell volum specific Snips were
located and then that allowed us find
some candidates so I'm going to show you
an example of what this output data
looks like and so for 11 of the 12
chromosomes this is generally what the
data look like we're looking at the
percentage of La 1589 nips and so if we
see no linkage to our trade of Interest
we should see
50% and that's generally what you see
obviously you have a little bit of
wiggling in the data but what we see is
generally a 50%
um snip ratio and so again about 11 of
the 12 chromosomes look like this one
chromosome instead had a suppressed
region where we had very very few La
1589 SS it's right in here and this uh
corresponded to about a 2.5 megabase
region and when we looked at the genes
there we actually found nine receptor
like kyes genes which was a our sort of
candidate protein that we were
expecting and so looking at these nine
genes I then designed primers looking um
at these different portions of the
genome and did a little bit of fine
mapping and when we looked at the re
combination we saw a suppressed re
combination around the region of this
one gene but not around these other
genes and so we very tentatively called
this one reate chise gene are putative
fs3
Gene um so tomato has been really nice
in the last few years in that we have a
lot of genetic resources that have been
developed so one of those resources
that's been developed out of Michigan
state is soul cap um Soul cap sequencing
and they took a whole bunch of different
tomato cultivars and ponella folium
accessions and they did uh snip calling
throughout the genomes and so we could
actually mine this data and what we
looked for was
um Susie first did a whole genome
analysis so she took all the Snips from
the whole genome and developed this tree
and what we could do is we had three
cultivars in that list that were
non-responsive so those three cultivars
are not related if you look at the
entire genome so again these are three
cultivars that don't respond if we just
take that region of Interest 10 meab
bases around that region we now see that
all of these uh cultivars now cluster
together so this again gave us some you
know potential evidence that perhaps
this region of the genome was of
interest for us and it could have like a
common um breeding history or a common
lineage we next then went to uh
different Salan of species so I pointed
out tomato of course responds to fly 228
treatment we also know potato and pepper
also respond but Funia do not and so now
we have genome sequences of all of these
so we can actually go into the genomes
and ask well do they have this one
candidate LS3 Gene and really
interestingly we have the Tomato fs3
candidate we have pepper and we have
potato but if you look petunia and
actually bamana do not have a clear
orthol for this Gene so this again was
some evidence suggesting that maybe that
this was the Gene and it was a newly
Arisen Gene that was not present in it
came about after um the Divergence of
petunia and Nana from the the
salanos okay so this is a whole lot of
evidence let's get back to the gene what
it is so it has two
exons and what we did is we sequenced
all of those uh um different cultiv bars
to see what was going on in this Gene
and what we found is that in yellow pair
the six other tomato cultivars and in
one of the pimpel folium ex sessions we
have four B PA deletion in the Gene and
so actually the one base pair deletion
is sufficient because that causes an
aberin
stopon and so we would predict actually
that in all of these cultivars and
obessions this is actually a
null and then we had one other that was
very interesting so in the pimpell
folium LA 373 we actually had what
appeared to be a full length encoding
Gene but there were four non synonymous
Snips and so you can actually see if you
go back to the
we see that this La 373 wasn't really a
null it seemed to have some response but
it was greatly reduced so this was kind
of another really interesting Al for us
to study but first before all of this we
have to actually show what is the what
is the gene doing what is it encoding
not surprisingly it's a lucing RIT Pete
receptiv so it has 27 extracellular
Lucen ritual PS a transmembrane domain
and a kind domain and now when we go and
actually look at what looks like on the
Ecto domain uh if you take the FS2 back
one flly 22 Co crystal structure and you
put the fs3 gene on it and thread it it
looks very similar but if you look at
the actual amino acid um um identity
it's only about 35% so while
structurally it looks similar because
again the Lucen Rich repeat domains are
pretty conserved as far as their
structure the actual amino acid
conservation is fairly low
and now finally putting it into planta
so what's nice is I can use those uh
yellow pear tomatoes to do some work in
tomato and what I first did was
expressed this fs3 gene into yellow peir
protoplasts to see if they're able to
now signal and so if I just Express fs3
we don't get any activation of M PES but
if we treat with flly 22 as our control
we do get activation um if we just treat
with the peptide we don't get activ
either it's only when we have the fls 3
plus the flag 228 that we actually now
get activation of M sign and just as a
control if you remember this efr and l18
pair that we can put this in tomato and
we also get signaling so this was
suggesting to us that the gene that we
had was probably the right Gene but we
wanted to do some further testing so now
we expressed LS3 in the Ciana benana
which you remember from the tree I just
show did not have a clear fls 3
orthologue and so if we put in fls 3 in
the flag 228 we get a nice response and
if we put in the efr and it's cognet
Lian L 18 we also get a response but if
you have the wrong receptor Lan pairs we
don't see any response so it's not that
just expression of fs3 causes
ad so we had some nice data that was
suggesting that um fsy could be the
receptor but we wanted to do some
further studies so going back to this
model what we had is um as I mentioned
we had this abert stop Cod on in in one
of our Le that really didn't do us very
much
good but we had this other nice o that
had four amino acid changes three in
Lucen R repe domains and when we looked
at that they weren't really um conserved
residues it didn't seem to be really big
changes but when we looked at this
fourth one that's actually in the highly
conserved p+ oneop we're doing a three
need to pring change and so I
hypothesize it was probably this amino
acid change that was causing this
reduction in response phenotype that we
were
observing um and then one other one I
want to mention is that um in kineses
they have a highly conserved ATP binding
site that's important for the actual
catalytic activity of the kise and so in
this case it said this Lys 877 so we
also use this amino acid to probe uh the
function of
fs3 and so now we started making
mutations
so we're looking here at total Ross
production if I put in fs3 into benana
and treat fly 228 we get response if I
make this ATP binding site mutant we
lose the response and also if I make the
three to Proline substitution that I
mentioned again we have a A reduced
response um that's sort of similar to
what we were seeing in the plant and
just to confirm that what I actually did
was um cloned out the other Al from the
LA 373 which we call fless 3-2 and
similar to what we were seeing from the
actual plant the the pimpel folium we
see a reduction in response but it's not
no response and in fact if we take that
alil and we mutate the proline back to
three we can restore wild type function
so this told us a couple of things but
it also really implied that the Kines
domain or kinese activity is probably
important for the function of F3
sign so so uh next we wanted to actually
show that we're getting an induction of
PTI and so what we did for these
experiments was we took benthamiana
plants we infiltrated the leaves with
agrobacterium that expresses F L3 and
then came back later and treated with
our peptide so this should induce uh our
immune
response we then came in eight hours
later and we
challenged uh the plant with our dc3000
in an overlapping Circle and what this
allows to do is that we look for whether
we have cell death in the overlap region
if we don't it means that we didn't
induce an immune response and so the
bacteria won if we were able to induce
immunity then we don't see cell death in
that spot and that means sort of a
plantform so this allows us to really
Pro whether we are getting an immune
response from this receptor and um
treatment or
not and so that's a horrible picture I
apologize what you can sort of see here
is that if we infiltrate with only yfp
and do the treatment you see that we
actually have the cell death in the
overlapping area the majority of the
time and this suggests again that we're
not inducing a clear immune response in
that
region if we take the inactive fs3 the
one that has ATP binding s mutation we
again also see that we have cell death
in that overlapping area thank you but
when we have the wild type fls 3 we
don't see that we have cell de occurring
in that region so that was suggesting
again that we were getting an immune
response that was being initiated when
we had LS3 plus the
cogn these experiments were done with by
Diane d in our
lab okay and last part of course is the
affector story because that's really
what our lab focuses on and so it's been
known that the affectors AVP and2
suppress fls2 mediated signaling and not
too surprisingly they also Suess fls 3
mediated expl um for both abp2 and for
avp2 and so this is something of course
we're really interested in exploring in
Greg's lab whether this is going to be
um the same as what occurs for fls2 or
if it's actually different and this is
something I think tiny and Simon are
going to be working on
shortly um and then we wanted to ask is
it iss3 signaling dependent on back one
and again fls2 signaling is so we would
expect that it would be but we needed to
do the experiments anyway so if we use
Bena and we either have a control
silencing or a back one silencing in
plants that are silenced for back one
and express fs3 we have a reduced
signaling and it's comparable to what we
see for efr so this was some preliminary
evidence back one was involved um but I
was able to recently do uh invivo
studies looking at um the existence of
fs3 back one in a complex using Co
precipitation and so if I have fs3 and
back one expressed in the same leak if I
immuno uh precipitate pulling on the
back one I'm able to detect
fs3 but if I have yfp instead and pull
on yfp I don't pull down the fs3 and so
this was again suggesting that we were
getting um fering back one to exist in a
complex together and I will say this is
actually after treatment with the
peptide and so again this is more um
something else we very interest in
studying as well but uh needs more work
and so last thing that we needed to do
in order to actually show that this is
in fact the receptor we had to
demonstrate specific binding between the
Lian and the receptor and so we did this
using some chemistry probes that were
developed through uh collaboration with
Frank schroers lab and specifically a
current post talk Jos belli and a former
postu in odor and they came up with
these very uh clever systems to put on
two important chemical moities the first
one is this diazine photocross Linker
and the second one is this alkine
chemistry gr and so we made two probes
our flag 228 and our flag 22 that had
what we call this our handle and what
this allows us to do is that with a
photo diering cross Linker we can use UV
light and this will coal attack and bond
to whatever's close by the alkine handle
allows us to do clip chemistry and what
this allows us to do is specifically put
on a tag but it lets us put on a tag
after we've done the experiment so that
the tag doesn't interfere with The
Binding of the probe to it of the LI to
its receptor and so we could show that
putting on this little uh chemical Group
which is actually about the one and a
half amino acids in size it's not very
big it didn't affect the activity of the
probes and so now we wanted to show the
bining so I'll walk you through these
experiments because they're a little
tricky
uh we first Express fs3 gfp in our
benthamiana leaves we then Harvest uh
microsomes and plasma membranes to have
an enrichment of our protein and to get
rid of a lot of the contaminating
cytosolic proteins as well as our um
chlorophyll because that would soak up
the UV radiation and prevent the
downstream analysis so we have our
microsomes that have our fs3
gfp we add our probe and any competitors
and so if our peptide binds to the
receptor again this photocross Linker is
now in close proximity so that we can
hit it with UV radiation and it now
photocross links so we now have a coent
linkage between our receptor and our
Legend since we have a gfp tag we can do
amuno precipitation to pull down this
complex between the receptor's leg ends
and now with this click chemistry handle
we can add on any tag we want but we
instead we're adding on biotin so we can
use a click chemistry reaction to add on
biotin
aide and then allows us to do
immunoblotting looking for either the
gfp or for the
bio so we first could show that the prob
chemistry was working so when we treat
uh with flag 228 in the presence of
eilis 3 we get a biotin label as you can
see through the stav and HP signal and
we have protein in both so the FL 22 is
not just aberly binding so it shows that
our Pro chemistry is specific and it's
not just cross linking
everything and we could also compete off
the signal so when we have uh our Pro
flag 228 in the presence of excess
unlabeled flag 228 we lose our signal
and we don't with the flag 22 so that
would suggest again that we had a very
specific receptor Lian interaction
between our flag 228 and our fs3 and
that we couldn't uh get rid of this B by
just adding any old peptide to the to
the
experiment and so just sort of in
summary what we have now is we have
identified LS3 which is the receptor for
flag
228 we've shown that it um the signaling
involves back one a co- receptor and
that activation of the signaling pathway
leads to the activation of mise Cades as
well as transcriptional reprogramming of
the
plant we showed that uh the signaling
involves the Ros
production and that the pseudomonas
affectors AVP and avp2 B can come in and
actually suppress the
signal and with that which was very fast
I'm going to go ahead and just again
acknowledge everyone in the group so um
again Pat did a lot of the Cross linking
experiments uh xong was really
instrumental in some of the genetics and
also the cloning of
theal Susie did all the bioinformatics
work which was totally essential for
this project as you saw uh Josh and
inish did the chemistry um we also
worked with Joyce and one of her TCH
Kate with um working with some cell
cultures and we also collaborated with
uh Boris benzer and his student Chris
Clark who were the ones who originally
were finding the flag
228 and with that I'd be very glad to
take your
[Applause]
questions this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu